<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0809" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18780901" TEIform="date">September 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">210-235</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--  <pb n="t.p. id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. VIII. NO. 9. SEPTEMBER. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID, THE SHAKER MANIFESTO (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE
                        UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY, MASS. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD.'» PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER
                        VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. 1878. <pb n="210" id="p2"/> CONTENTS. The chariot wheels move 211 Ann Lee 224 Answered
                        Prayer 213 Correspondence 225 "The good time coming" No. 1. 213 Shakerism 226 Clark's Comments 214 For the Children
                        227 Indians No. 7. 215 Book Table 229 The true, the good, the beautiful 21G "Champions of the Church" 230 The Labor
                        question 217 Selected 230 Christ's message 219 Home Topics 232 Father, Mother—God 220 Obiturry 233 Reminiscences of
                        practical life 220 Editorial Notes 233 Durable riches 221 Music 234 The Shaker Manifesto  222 ______t^. TEEMS OF
                        ADVERTISING. For one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column, " " $ 3. 00 one " " " $ 6. 00 page, " " $12.00
                        Continued insertion for three months, 20 per ct. discount. " six " 25 " " " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty
                        cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, * Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription wilt begin when order is
                        received.—No back numbers.</p>
                        --><pb n="211" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL.
                        VIII.—SEPTEMBER. 1878.—No. IX.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chariot wheels move" TEIform="index"/>THE CHARIOT WHEELS MOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Was there ever a time in the world's history of which we have knowledge, when the banner of
                            truth was so unfurled and borne along the highway of progression, as it is at the present?
                            Thinking minds are awake, and not only keep pace Avith the onward march of events as they
                            transpire, but are making diligent search for kevs to unlock the doors which will open the
                            treasuries of greater scientific knowledge, for the expansion of natural philosophy, and
                            spiritual unfoldment. And with marked avidity they come forward armed with the strength and
                            courage of the lion,— if not with the gentleness of the lamb— to meet in open combat the
                            fallacies of the past, with newly revealed truths of the present, and prophecies of the yet
                            to come. Do we not, in a degree, see in this the fulfillment of the vision of the prophet,
                            who saw the "four living creatures" bearing the "likeness of a man"—the progressive
                            spirit—resting not from their labors day nor night but rolling on the wheels of their
                            chariot, turning neither to the right nor left, but in one straight forward course breaking
                            down barriers to make a way for the reign of the Prince of Peace? Sectarian bigotry, false
                            creeds and dogmas, have ruled, and blocked the way of Science and Religion down through the
                            ages. Life-giving, effective agencies have also been slowly, but surely at work, growing
                            stronger and more forcible, weakening the walls of tho citadel of false theologies, until a
                            tidal wave is now sweeping over Christendom, which threatens to undermine the foundation of
                            the old heavens, and extinguish the fires of their terrible hells. Does not this betoken a
                            better state of things? May we not hope that the time is nearing when God will begin to
                            build His city with foundations firmly laid and so deeply rooted in principles of truth,
                            that nothing can move them? While Science is doing a marvelous work, through mortal agency,
                            revealing hidden forces in material things—touching the earth-life—it is evident that
                            spirits from the Resurrection spheres are also doing a great work. Natural, external things,
                            have their time and place ; but should not be suffered to occupy the whole ground and take
                            possession of the<pb n="212" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 213 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. interests of soul and body.
                            The life germs that are inherent in every human soul, are offshoots from the greatTree in
                            the eternal realm of spirit life, whose leaves never wither, and whose roots never decay. By
                            expansion and growth, the beautiful branches of a tree stretch upward into the sun-light;
                            even so will living, conscious beings wend their way to higher spheres of thought and
                            action, and form a joint relation to the first Cause of all intelligences. The great
                            question that arises at the present time is : What relation do we hold to our fellow beings,
                            and how shall we form a strong bond that will unite us in one common brotherhood and
                            sisterhood? When we are willing to work unselfishly in the cause of humanity, and base all
                            our acts of life upon true principles, that question will not be difficult to solve. To
                            accomplish this desired result, we need a heavenly baptism from celestial spheres of light
                            and life divine. Infidelity has reared strong castles in what is called Christian America,
                            and Its subjects have fortified themselves against a hireling priesthood, or any messenger
                            who would approach them with blood-stained creeds. They look into the popular churches of
                            the day, and see a hydra-headed monster, whose component parts, are Sensuality, Avarice,
                            Monopoly and Intemperance, sitting in what are styled the temples of God ; and reasoning
                            logically they ask, "What better is a sinning Christian, than one who makes no profession of
                            piety, and commits the same sins? Of what value is a profession ?" They turn with disgust
                            from empty creeds and false pretensions ! And yet they may feel a strong love for truth, and
                            reverence virtue wherever manifest, whether in Jew, or in Greek. The world will never be
                            redeemed by mere belief in any code of laws, or formula of doctrine. The hope of the race
                            lies in a living faith in God who is able to save from sin, all who are willing to be thus
                            saved : not by merely believing, but doing what is just and right. We need inspirational
                            power a constant intromission of divine essence or endowment from the Infinite; a faith that
                            requires correlative works. We may run to and fro in the laii'd, and speak as with tongues
                            of angels, and cry ulo here, and lo there," if we do not seal our testimony with righteous
                            works, it will avail little—be like clouds in the horizon that appear and give promise of
                            rain when the earth is parched, then disappear without sending forth the expected shower to
                            revive vegetation. Truth and Justice must form the basis of a Christian character. Upon that
                            basis we may rest the lever that will move the world. The power of Love,
                            outwrought—actualized—in deeds of charity, and obedience to the behests of conscience and
                            divine laws, will inspire confidence God-ward ; and fit us to be ministers to others, and to
                            bear the ensign of peace and salvation. Literary attainments, and intellectual endowments,
                            often fail of supplying the soul needs, or of giving a thorough idea of the spirit of the
                            age in which we live,— the causes which produce certain effects —and the necessary agencies
                            to remove those causes, and change conditions for the better. Light will comprehend, and
                            disperse darkness. Therefore, let us pray that God's angels may visit us, bearing shining
                            lamps to this sin-darkened earth, re-<pb n="213" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> vealing the sin of Sensuality,
                            which ai the parent of Intemperance : that evil alone, now causes untold misery in human
                            society as the tears of many mothers, who are thereby bereft of the com- forts of life ; and
                            as homeless, breadless children, will attest. Intemperance has become'so formidable, that it
                            baffles law, and human effort is unable to cope with it. It lifts its head high ; and the
                            conquering armies from the inner worlds are needed to strike a deadly blow. Carnal weapons
                            will never accomplish the much needed work ; spiritual agencies must be employed. To this
                            end many earnest inspirational prayers from warm hearted humanitarians have ascended, in
                            public and in private, that the inebriate's cup may be numbered among the things that were,
                            and the dissolute be reclaimed from the demon master, and made free; Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Answered prayer" TEIform="index"/>ANSWERED PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cornell, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>JANE CORNELL</byline><p TEIform="p">"Him that cometh unto me I will in no wise cast out.! Now weary with straying, O Lord I am
                            praying For guidance and strength, that I at length May safely reach home. The world now
                            forsaking my cross humbly taking O Father I come. But nature uprising with power surprising
                            My way doth impede, and shows me the need Of seeking thy grace. O Father relieve me, in
                            mercy receive me, And show me thy face. O Lord art thou heeding the voice of my pleading, My
                            soul's earnest cry, that thou wilt draw nigh To succor and bless ? For the power of sin and
                            the traitors within ;[• Do sorely oppress. O Savior attend me, in pity befriend me O lend me
                            thine aid, lest I be dismayed And courage I lack. And tremblingly quail, or through weakness
                            fail The foe to beat back. My sure refuge thou art, and I ne'er will depart From the foot of
                            the throne, till thou shalt make known Thou hearest my prayer. My cause still repeating, thy
                            mercy entreating, I will not despair. O soul shout for gladness! Arise from thy sadness! And
                            humbly rejoice, for a still small voice Whispers low to my heart, God's promise is sure, and
                            will ever endure; In peace now depart. O blessed assurance of thy love's endurance! To this
                            promise tender I now do surrender All lingering doubt. [made free "They who come unto me and
                            through Christ are I will not cast out." Shakers, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good time coming, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>"THE GOOD TIME COMING." NO. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The faculties of prevision and prophecy, like those of vision and ordinary speech, are common
                            to mankind. But the former, like the other intellectual faculties, are not universally
                            developed. The sensuous faculties manifest themselves early because of early necessities. In
                            the Divine economy, the internal powers are developed, from age to age, in accordance with
                            the exigencies of the age. Prevision has to do with events and not with the forms of things.
                            But because foresight, like the external sight, naturally demands forms to be presented to
                            it, future events are represented under various forms called symbols and figures. "Coming
                            events cast their shadow before." Symbols need interpretation to most minds ; what they are
                            intended to represent does not readily occur to all. For this reason sceptical persons are
                            inclined to reject all prevision and prophecy as the views and utterances of minds demented.
                            A Voltaire requires no better subjects upon which to exercise his wit and ridicule; and the
                            mere matter-of-fact scientist is content to remit all such IVLAJNJTinESTO<pb n="214" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER S14 m: ajsttwjssto . things to the realms of fancy. Laugh ter is a good thing
                            in itself—it make the heart merry; it is often effectua also in banishing errors and
                            supersti tions that cling to some minds in spite o all reason. Absolute truth is needed by
                            all, even though it should confound all previous conceptions. But ridicule and sarcasm are
                            not good substitutes for truth, though they may be used as weapons to comba error. They
                            cherish self conceit, while truth gives "quietness and assurance forever." Truth is eternal
                            and immutable ; its semblance is many-shaped but perishable. The phantoms that have borne
                            the name of truth have not been confined to the fancy realms of the romancer ; not a few of
                            them have occupied the fields that theological and scientific minds would have had us
                            believe contained only the messengers of light. So has it been all along the past ages ; so
                            is it still; and so is it likely to be for ages yet to come. But, in the beautiful language
                            of Bryant— "Truth crushed to earth shall rise again, The eternal years of God are hers ; But
                            error, wounded, writhes in pain, And dies amid his worshipers." Actually, however, truth has
                            never been "crushed to earth." Individuals holding a truth may pass from earth compelled by
                            violent hands, but truth itself continues to gain ground. Very gloomy pictures ha v e been
                            drawn by certain ecclesiastical limners of what they have styled the "dark ages," that is,
                            th.3 canturioj that intervened between the days of Jems Christ and his early church and the
                            present time. But the student of history discovers no greater mental or moral darkness in
                            those, than in the ages preceding. He may be disappointed that the beautiful,
                            heaven-descended precepts uttered by Jesus should have had no greater influence upon the
                            minds of the many thousands that professed them during all those centuries; but that they
                            did not gradually work and are not still working out a better state of things than
                            previously existed in the parts of the earth where they were promulgated is by no means
                            true. The leaven may have operated slowly, but it did not cease to work. Our modern writers
                            are accustomed to style the present age enlightened; but centuries hence, in view of the
                            many wars between Christian nations of the present age, and the numerous hostile sects into
                            which the professing disciples of Jesus are divided, the present may 30 classed with the
                            former "dark ages." It is the province of the seer to look into the future so as to be able
                            to present to other minds the glowing pictures that entrance his own. It is his provnce also
                            to view "the pillar of cloud by lay and of fire by night," by which Divine Providence has
                            guided the people hrough the wilderness of the past up to he present promised land, and
                            which is o lead them forward to a still "better country." The successes of the past are an
                            encouragement for the future. Groveland, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clark's comments" TEIform="index"/>CLARK'S COMMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">'For the priest's lips should keep knowldge, and they should seek the law at lis mouth: for
                            he is the messenger of \q Lord of hosts. But ye are departed out of the way ;<pb n="215" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 315 ye have caused many to stumble at the law; ye have corrupted
                            the covenant of Levi, saith the Lord of hosts. Therefore have I also made you contemptible
                            and base before all the people, according as ye have not kept my ways but have been partial
                            in the law." Malachi, ii: 7, 9. Therefore have I also made you contemptible. "The people
                            despised you because they saw that you acted contrary to your functions. This has happened
                            repeatedly since, to several classes of priests. Not maintaining, by purity of life and
                            soundness of doctrine, the dignity of the ministerial function, they became contemptible
                            before the people: their meagre preaching was disregarded, and their persons at last cast
                            out as a general loathing to the universe ! See what happened to the truly abominable
                            priesthood of France and Rome, 1796— 8. They were the sole cause of that infidelity, that
                            brought about the Revolution. They are now partially restored ; and are endeavoring to
                            supply by grimace, paltry superstition, and Jesuitical cunning what they want in purity of
                            morals, soundness of doctrine, and unction from God. They must mend or look for another
                            revolution. Mankind will no longer put up with the chaff of ^puerile and fanatical
                            ceremonies, in place of the wheal of God's word and worship." This commentary was written
                            many years ago. How true it has proved aocording to subsequent history ! What an overthrow
                            has taken place in Rome since then, what commotions in the old homes of Christendom! They
                            are literally passing, away. New heavens are creating to occupy their place and the end is
                            not yet. We still look for new heavens and a new earth wherein shall dwell righteousness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 7" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS, No. 7</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">human rights :—In the conquest of Canada by the English, the French had so much regard for
                            the rights of the Indians, they had missionary labors among them and had made considerable
                            progress in Agriculture, Mechanic Arts, &amp;c. and being unwilling to lose what had
                            been gained, they made the Indian question a speciality in that day. In their treaty of
                            peace with the English it was stipulated and agreed upon by both parties, that the rights of
                            the Indians should be respected that they should be made equal before the law with the white
                            man, that they should be protected in their rights, the same as all other English subjects.
                            This was accepted and ratified by the King of England, and he made it a permanent in-
                            stitution—an everlasting covenant. He issued the following order to all the governors in the
                            colonies more than 100 years ago. "Forasmuch as most of our colonies do border upon the In-
                            dians, and peace is not to be expected without due observance and preservation of justice to
                            them, you are, in our name, to command all Governors, that they at no time give any just
                            provocation to any of the said Indians that are at peace with us." Here we have the
                            fundamental law of human rights, clearly set forth and established in behalf of the Indians,
                            by the Government of England remaining in full force in Canada to this day. This may be one
                            reason why the Canadians have no war with the Indians. The following is the closing of the
                            spirit communication from Tecumwega : "There is another all important sub- M^JSTrBTSSTO.<pb n="216" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 316 THE SHAKBE ject I wish to speak of. The great spirit designed from
                            the foundation of the world to establish two orders of people on the earth—a natural order
                            and a spiritual order—but the great spirit designed that these should be accomplished
                            through a series of evolutions and progressive movements in the religious elements. Already
                            it has begun to dawn on the earth. You see some of its golden fruits and shining examples in
                            your midst. You will do well to copy after them. I highly recommend this spiritual order to
                            my red brethren, and in a special manner to those within the jurisdiction of the United
                            States, as they will be more suitably prepared for this work than those in the far west, who
                            are as yet unknown to the white man. As it has taken ages to lay the foundation of this
                            glorious work now begun, so it will take ages of the future before it arrives to its
                            meridian height of glory. In that day man will be governed by principle, and led and guided
                            by the law of love and kindness. Before the millennium can shine in its full brightness, all
                            wars, contention, strife, bitter animosities, thefts, and robberies, will have to be
                            entirely done away. In that day if a man is found guilty of violating the strict laws of
                            nature, it will be considered as much of a crime as murder is at the present day. Then will
                            universal brotherhood throughout Christendom, that the white man has so long looked and
                            prayed for take place. In that day the word heathen will not be known on the earth, for
                            every one will have knowledge of the mind and will of the great spirit. Marvel not at these
                            words of mine because they come from an Indian spirit, for the great spirit has called me to
                            be a prophet, though there are Indian spirits far superior to me. Many truths I could tell
                            you about the Spirit World, and even Planets much larger than yours, but a few at present
                            must suffice : There are Planets inhabited by a race of beings far more intelligent than the
                            inhabitants of your sphere. They have already arrived at the great millennium you are
                            looking for, although not so far advanced as the inhabitants of spirit life. The progress of
                            man's eternal existence is beyond the comprehension of the most learned in your sphere. Many
                            solemn and eternal truths might be spoken, but I must now close. I love the white man, and
                            own him as my Brother, although he has abused the Indian. So, kindly farewell, in love. Your
                            Indian Brother, Tecumwega." North Union Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good, the true, the beautiful" TEIform="index"/>The GOOD, The TRUE, The BEAUTIFUL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">The ancient Greeks, who did much to lift humanity from its primeval barbarism, found it all
                            the way an up .grade. Hence this Motto— Ohalepa ta Kala—in our language The Good, the True,
                            the Beautiful are difficult of attainment. The gospel of our blessed Mother Ann, with the
                            Order established by Father Joseph and Mother Lucy and ably sustained by their devoted
                            successors, enables us to give practical demonstration of the fact, that the Good, the True,
                            the Beautiful are attainable. We see it cropping out in our dear Gospel Relations. And in
                            proportion as we have an eye for the beautiful, become dematerialized in our soul states—all
                            earthly influences left behind—we behold The Good, the True, the Beautiful—nothing less. Mt.
                            Lebanon, iV". Y.</p></div2><pb n="217" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Labor question: the millionaire and the republic" TEIform="index"/>THE LABOR QUESTION, The
                            Millionaire and the Republic</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">As citizens of this republic, we have several grave problems to solve in reference to its
                            perpetuity. The effect of our system of finance, including usury, (one per cent is usury,)
                            on the creation of crime, requires serious attention. When the farmers as a body, invest
                            elsewhere than in their farms, trouble is not far off. The existence, and the rapid rise of
                            so many millionaires in our midst, is anomalous with the logic of a republic ; in the nature
                            of things they are the offspring of wrong conditions, and are clothed with power not
                            compatible with the general good. At their will, they can vitiate the sources of law and
                            justice; and when it suits their interests, can change commercial tallies, and tax
                            consumers, as the monarchs of the old world do their subjects. The relation of the employer
                            and the employed, increasingly presses itself on public notice. The late existence of
                            slavery was only a labor question. The idea that moral agents, citizens of a republic,
                            should be left by thousands, or even a single citizen, in the hands of millionaires, or
                            companies of capitalists, the latter parties being in possession of the enormous productive
                            energies of our times, and the former to do their will— glut the markets to repletion ; and
                            then suffer destitution from the very abundance they have created—thrown out of employment,
                            on to the labor market as a commodity! is an astounding crime against the republic. That a
                            moral agent, responsible to his own knowledge of right, to the Supreme Being, to his
                            fellow-citizens, and to all the demands of the republic, should be left to compete with
                            iron, steam, and steel, in the hands of these parties, is atrocious—is the hugest crime of
                            the nineteenth century. Just as sure as the labor question at the South was met, so surely
                            will the labor question at the North, press to be adjusted. If not ad- justed, then the
                            great republic—the hope of humanity—will prove a failure; which I think cannot be. Our
                            brethren of the late slave States would not listen to words of wisdom. Their persistence in
                            wrong culminated ; then He, who governs the moral universe by law, as He does the material
                            one, met them in their own paths, broke the yoke of bondage, and buried that form of human
                            vassalage r beneath the dead bodies of the oppressor, and with the havoc of war, destroyed
                            their ill-gotten property. Is there not a lesson here for us at the North? This
                            ever-pressing and momentous subject, if not settled in wisdom, may be solved as was that of
                            slave labor, in awful convulsions, dire calamities, and fearful destruction. With mer it is
                            a matter of deep concern, that the conditions of all the citizens of our loved republic,
                            should be favorable to its perpetuity. Would it not be well for those who have statesmen's
                            hearts, who feel the approaching future, to take steps in gentle ways and manner, and teach
                            us how to secure a healthful distribution of all the products of labor, and thus avert
                            impending evil ? Have we not one common Father? Why should not the blessings of civilization
                            be as equally distributed as the rain which falls alike on all ? Are not the accumulations
                            of wealth the fruits of modern civilization? If so, is it morally wholesome that it should
                            be IMLAJNrrF'ICSTO.<pb n="218" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 218 THE left to accumulate at some points to
                            fester into extravagance, and be withdrawn from others, causing want, discontent,
                            degradation and crime? Would it not be well for every producer to have an interest in the
                            fruit of his labor as has the employer, and so cease to be virtually a slave ? Is it ever
                            taken into consideration, that the domestic surroundings of men of wealth today, exceed
                            those of princes of the fifteenth century? while in this day, the surroundings of the poor
                            arc in many, very many cases destructive of health and life, and the means of living as
                            limited nearly, and more uncertain than of that century? Again, the wealth alluded to, is
                            the outcome of the intellectual labor, not of a class, but of society. Therefore, the
                            enormously productive energies of mechanical and chemical appliances belong of right to all.
                            They should be assistants, not competitors with moral agents as is now the case. The
                            ancients founded their republics under the light of other ideas than those of our day. The
                            peculiar relation of families to one another, and the existence of a lower stratum of
                            families in their societies, who had neither a hearth, altar nor priest; and of course, had
                            no religious nor political position, necessarily caused great difficulties. When these
                            occurred, there was no way to settle them but by overpowering the ruling families. Hence to
                            maintain social equilibrium, from time to time, those who had amassed much land, were either
                            killed, or driven off, and the land divided. In the histories of these republics, when
                            favorable aspects presented themselves, no doubt their pi-ofoundest thinkers favored a
                            somewhat just distribution of the land—and approximation toward Jewish equality. Land being
                            the source of human sustenance, of social and judicial equality; and a regulator of the
                            exchange, and values of commercial equivalents; to insure perpetuity to modern republics
                            every citizen should be a landholder, or have access to land at all times. To buy and sell
                            land, as we do a manufactured commodity, is to make those who cannot buy it, a commodity
                            also ; and is the veriest opposite of the idea of loving the neighbor as avc do self. The
                            Jewish idea was an approximation to Christianity—"the land could not be sold for ever ;"
                            only to the Jubilee. Under Christian ideas, land can neither bo bought nor sold. To do so,
                            is to make servants—slaves of our brethren. Kossuth remarked, "The Christian nation is not
                            yet." Therefore we have troubles enough, and more, and worse in prospect. The earth is the
                            Lord's not man's. The mission of this republic is justice to all; and is identical with
                            Christian -ideas and sentiments. Were the sages of antiquity to appear now, would they not
                            congratulate us, "that we were free from the demoralizing influences which bound them as
                            with iron bands? With them, families with their gods and priests, were little worlds in
                            themselves. Each family and its gods, were isolated from, if not antagonistic to, all other
                            families and their gods ; and in their wars sought the destruction of both. That now, we had
                            the glorious opportunity to accept the human family as a unit, and to have no god but our
                            Father who is in Heaven—who has given to all his children alike, the surface of this planet
                            for their sustenance, as he has SHAKER MyVlNTrFICSTO.<pb n="219" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER S1Q
                            given the air we so freely breathe.'' And further, they could say, "That to lend upon
                            interest, is to tax poverty; creates false conditions in society; is contrary to the feeling
                            of benevolence, and to all the higher attributes of our being; and repellent of the
                            injunction of Him whom we profess to pattern after—lend, hoping for nothing again." Can it
                            be said that the foregoing is impracticable ? Did not the founders of this republic, through
                            many sufferings, bequeath to us a social compact organically just? Having such magnificent
                            opportunities, shall we fail to render it so? Nay, let us advance a step, be more than
                            just—be beneficent; then it will be easy to be just. The time has indeed arriven for nations
                            and individuals to manifest to each other a divine humanity—to breathe forth into practi-
                            cability the inspiration of our loved neighbor, Emerson: "And each shall care for other, And
                            each to each shall bend, To the poor a noble brother, To the good an equal friend." Form
                            Committees. The ballot is in your hand. Put this matter through. Work cordially with all
                            classes. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's messages" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST'S MESSAGES</head><p TEIform="p">While musing on that wondrous love, Leading the Savior from above, Yearning o'er man in sin's
                            abyss, Giving e'en life, to save from this ; A form stood near, whose garment bright Seemed
                            woven as of holy light; Saying in tender tones, and sweet, "Would ye follow the Master's
                            feet?" "If His disciple ye would be, And would from sin thy soul set free, Ponder the words
                            the Master spake, Who follows me, his cross must take. "Seek ye to enter at the gate? The
                            way is narrow, plain, and straight Which leadeth to eternal life, But few who seek, endure
                            the strife. "Secure not treasures upon earth, Lest moth and rust corrupt their worth; Let
                            heavenly riches be your care,— The heart is where its treasures are. "Freely my gifts ye
                            have received, Freely give ye to those who need; The cup of water in my name, Shall its
                            reward of blessing claim. "Keep pure thy heart and clean thy hands, Keep, if ye love me, my
                            commands; When heavy-laden and oppressed, Come unto me, I'll give you rest. "Suffer the
                            little ones to come, The Father's love hath ample room; x\nd in my kingdom ye must be Like
                            babes, in spotless purity. And lest ye in temptation stray, . I bid you always watch and
                            pray; For, willing tho' the spirit be, Thy strength is weakness—trust in me. "Let not your
                            heart sore troubled be Believe in God,—believe in me. My Father's house hath mansions fair,
                            That where I am ye may be there." Then stretching forth a wounded hand, "Whither thou goest
                            by sea or land, My peace be with thee to control The raging conflicts of thy soul." Folding
                            his robe of dazzling light, The glorious form was lost to sight, Though as by evening
                            breezes borne Came echoing words, the sweetest known:— "I will not leave you comfortless,
                            For often shall my presence bless. Continue steadfast in my love, And thus my loyal servant
                            prove." As deepening shadows gathered round, My spirit knew a peace profound, And joyfully
                            the truth confessed—¦ Jesus himself had been my guest! Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My brother,' said the clergyman, 'do you feel charitably...'" TEIform="index"/>My brother,' said the clergyman, 'do you feel charitably...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"My brother," said the clergyman, "do you feel charitably inclined this winter?" "Well, yes,
                            if it don't cost anything," was the answer.</p></div2><pb n="220" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our universal parent— father and mother God" TEIform="index"/>Our Universal Parent— FATHER
                            AND MOTHER GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Why do men ransack the whole realm of language for words to describe Deity ? Does not the
                            term Parent convey the simple idea of the relation which God sustains to his creatures ? And
                            while we stretch our senses aloft to scan his attributes, should we overlook the divinity in
                            the innumerable grades of intelligences through whose instrumentality is imparted light and
                            life from superiors to inferiors ? While omnipotence, omnipresence and infinity are
                            incomprehensible terms when applied to one personal being, yet through the agency of myriads
                            of beings endowed with divine attributes, qualified and authorized to supervise the great
                            arena of material things in their construction and moral government is not the Divine Parent
                            ever present with them, all powerful; infinite in wisdom and full of tender mercies? In this
                            innumerable family of the beneficent Father and Mother—this immense chain of countless
                            agencies, endowed from the source of Wisdom, is not man included ? With that parental
                            authority which prevails through all the descending grades from the fountain of love to the
                            lowest germ of humanity, will any form of political government compare ? Can we contract our
                            ideas to a sectarian God? Do we prefer to believe that the Author of all things is such an
                            exclusive, passionate, partial egotist as some have described? Think you that eternity past
                            wa blank, until this orb was formed from nothing ? Were not Angels without number, old in
                            existence before this Earth grew ? Did not the Universe teem with life and intelligence,
                            time past inconceivable? May we not look up through these intelligences to an intelligent
                            God? In those who are clothed with Godlike virtues can we not behold a portion of this
                            image? Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscences of a practical life" TEIform="index"/>Reminiscences of a Practical Life</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crosman, Abigail" TEIform="persName"/>ABIGAIL CROSMAN</byline><p TEIform="p">I love to read from the pages of the Manifesto, the language of pure spirits, and witness
                            thereby the spiritual growth of elevated minds, devoted to the support of our sacred cause.
                            Most gratefully would I greet all, who have contributed in any way to aid the mission of our
                            little Manifesto ; which, though at present the number who hail its truths as the harbinger
                            of peace is few ; still, its banner waves in the breezes of victory, bearing the
                            inscription, ''onward upward," inviting all who will, to seek the joys of an angel life.
                            While reading the articles, under the title of, "what shall I do to be a Shaker?" reflec-
                            tions cited me back to the day when this question first agitated my youthful mind; and
                            though nearly sixty years since, I now ask myself the question, " Wliat have I done to honor
                            a Shaker life?" I learned from the New Testament that but few were willing to practice the
                            selfdenials which Jesus required of his followers then; and now through the second advent of
                            his spirit, a still greater sacrifice is required or we realize the painful reality " Ye
                            cannot be my disciples!" But how could I know that this redeeming power was vested alone in
                            Shakerism? Should I turn away sorrowfully, cowardly, shrinking from the cross because of the
                            inscription, "Sell all that thou hast?" Ml^JSrUHESTO.<pb n="221" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MLAJSTETESTO. 321 Not so; the confidence received in his promises by those who sought him
                            early; also the parental call, to "choose this day whom I would serve," awakened my
                            conscience and placed before my spiritual vision joys of a higher life. I was born Nov. 9,
                            1807. and when ten years of age my parents joined the Society of Shakers at Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y. with whom I lived until the age of fifteen when by my own request, I was admitted as a
                            member, leaving their parental roof, to enter the community of spiritual brothers and
                            sisters. At this period I became sensible that thus far I had been guided by the choice of
                            my parents, not by my own ; this caused me to investigate, both the principles and practices
                            of those claiming membership; and to compare the same with other professors of Christianity.
                            In this my exertions were earnest; desiring if possible to find a religion elsewhere re-
                            quiring less sacrifice, and giving as much assurance of salvation. But the tree being known
                            by its fruit, my hopes were blighted, finding as I did, precepts and examples at variance,
                            and their interest for each other veiled in selfishenss. These reflections, caused in my
                            youthful mind heavy struggles. But the bright star of practical Christianity—the embodiment
                            of truth, honesty and purity of life—illumined my pathway, convincing me beyond a doubt,
                            that the selfdenials practiced by true Shakers were the same as Jesus and his disciples
                            engaged in when upon earth, and these had commenced the new era made manifest in his own
                            words, Mark 12: 25. Thus, I found that to be in reality a follower of Christ, I must become
                            resurrected above all worldly habits and practices, even as he was. No one however useful or
                            talented, is allowed the right of membership, while violating in word or act their godly
                            profession. Neither are leaders in society allowed extra privileges for indolence or
                            selfishness; but share in hand and heart the servitude, burdens and blessings of their
                            brethren and sisters. I love a Shaker life, having proved its merits for sixty years; and
                            although it reTmires a full consecration of time and services, to our unselfish cause, I
                            have fully realized the Saviour's promised reward; nor could I deviate from this path of
                            rectitude, without grieving the inward monitor— conscience—which like the guardian angel,
                            watcheth with delight the soul devoted to purity. I wonder if my readers could explain to me
                            the cause of certain excuses made to Jesus, Luke 14: 18, especially the last excuse there
                            mentioned? Why does that relation if it is the will of God, debar any from enjoying the
                            greater blessing? Why not increase the joy by taking the wife along? He did not say, "I have
                            a sister and cannot come." We say, if you have a wife or husband, invite them to come and
                            share the universal love of kind brothers and sisters, living nearly as possible like the
                            angels, who "neither marry nor are given in marriage." When young I found in my heart strong
                            desires for selfish pleasures; but I also wanted to be a Christian; and in this condition I
                            prayed earnestly to be guided by the light of truth. Thus it is, today I have the pleasing
                            assurance, that, by the light of truth, and the testimony of the spirit, I hare been led
                            through a life of purity in the way our blessed Saviour made manifest, and am now able to
                            enjoy in a measure the fruits of the higher life. Groveland, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Durable riches" TEIform="index"/>DURABLE RICHES.</head><p TEIform="p">Having completed three score and ten years the tenth of September I felt anxious to bless the
                            Manifesto, its Editor, Publisher and every contributor, with a few lines of cheer; for I
                            read every number and feel really benefited thereby.—Rhoda Blake. Look not in the earth for
                            treasures that are hidden from "the wise and prudent," but strive to form by daily
                            watchfulness and care a kingdom of uprightness within, that will make home lovely and life
                            happy; give the feelings energy, with an increasing desire to do good; this strife is noble.
                            Goodness elevates the mind, and gives us personally a lofty SHAKER<pb n="222" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER idea of true dignity. We must reap and garner with all the intelligence of our souls,
                            the riches which will endure and furnish ourselves with excellent endowments that we may
                            have these to bestow on the needy; and as it were, unseemingly shed beauty, sublimity and
                            happiness through all the varied scenes of life ; for durable treasures will never fail
                            while earthly riches will perish. I often reflect upon the vision of Judge Edmonds, where he
                            saw the miser gathering and laying up riches by his side ; *'at length he turned to his
                            piled up cherished treasure, and found that it was all gone, he threw himself in despair
                            prostrate upon this useless emblem of his wealth, and howled wildly in the madness of his
                            disappointed cupidity." It was all left behind and nothing but a ferocious desire remained.
                            While our hands are employed caring for the wants of the body, our hearts must be expanding
                            in the free elasticity of spiritual elements ; and we must draw from the depths of the
                            Infinite that inspiration which will lead us on to new glories, new manifestations of the
                            durable riches, that are attainable and which it is our heavenly Father's pleasure to give
                            mankind—those treasures of knowledge which will raise them to a state of exaltation,
                            spiritually and intellectually, and give evidences of substantial truth that can never die.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The New Testament, being written at a much later period..." TEIform="index"/>The New Testament, being written at a much later period...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The New Testament, being written at a much later period, evinces the greater
                                    intelligence of its writers. But its Heaven and Hell; its Divinity of Jesus, and
                                    personal Devil; its vicarious Atonement, Miracles. Resurrection and Judgment Day,
                                    arc disappearing before the grander conceptions which the scholarship of the present
                                    century is teaching. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Duluth tribune" TEIform="index"/>Duluth Tribune</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto: some plain answers" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. SOME PLAIN
                            ANSWERS</head><p TEIform="p">From many plain questions, concerning "The Shakers" received by us, we are led to feel
                            surprised that simple Shaker life is not better understood by the masses ! We would make
                            some plain answers : There was a time when Shakcrism endured the sobriquet ol "disguised
                            impurity" as charged by the prejudiced. Now, when it is privileged to enjoy the notoriety of
                            unchallenged purity, the conclusion is arrived at by some, that the Shakers "must be very
                            weak to be so very good !" Thanks to God for such weakness. The questions, whether our
                            system is not unnatural, and would soon depopulate the world, are very natural, and just as
                            unspiritual and untrue. The fact that "all could not receive this saying," of Jesus, is no
                            truer than that only a few "are able" to be Shakers ; and so few, that there can be no
                            noticeable dimimition of population as a consequence, however much we might wish such ac-
                            tion of the few, would tend to an improvement of the race by those who are not able to be
                            Christians. One person asks: "Has God made a mistake in the institutes of nature?" We think
                            not; nor in his more valued instructions of the Spirit to "come up and live the life of
                            Christ." We state it as simply impossible for generative or flesh-loving men and women to
                            live the Christ life ; and if Christ's life is best, and we deem it so, then the grosser use
                            of "the institutes of nature" must be denied for better uses in communal, Christian
                            relations. Let those knowing no better use for 222 MANIFESTO.<pb n="223" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHARER 223 the propagative institutes, use them according to the highest conceptions of
                            right, for the productions of only sound minds and healthy bodies—and none others have any
                            right to be conceived nor born—then, and then only will God be honored by reproductions of
                            humanity, and honored then, only on man's animal plane of existence. But the rule now is,
                            scarcely without exception, that "the likeness" of God is dishonored through unlawful
                            indulgences, and Nature's commonest cry is : "I never knew you !" The Shakers instead of
                            decrying matrimony or reproductions admit that these should be lawful, earthly
                            felicities—very earthly—not heavenly practices. If there were nothing higher nor better than
                            these practices, then, we the Shakers, would engage in them ; but who is ready to blame us
                            for choosing a life so superior to the married, propagative sphere, as to find no com-
                            parison in happiness, even amid "ecstatic courtships"—whatever these may be ? We grant that
                            marriage and its consequences are honorable and legitimate in their place ; but we as
                            readily and positively assert, that there is nothing of "the higher life" in them; and in
                            the degree that "thy will be done on earth" is consummated here "as it is in heaven," we
                            opine that it will appear to many beclouded minds, that in heaven the angels do not engage
                            in such earthly felicities. If we can be fashioned after Angelic Construction no^o, who has
                            any right to object? Now, we will be honest, very honest in saying, that we are arxious that
                            those who "cannot receive" full Christianity into their life practices, but will live like
                            "the children of this world," shall so engage their institutes of nature "as directed by the
                            laws of Moses ;" for by so doing, they aid largely in the cumulation of Shaker material! The
                            laws of nature kept as they should be, even regarding "the population question," and
                            Shakerism is assured a populous and flourishing institution ! Our correspondents, and
                            others, must stop urging reforms in sexual indulgences, if they have any objections to the
                            growth of our institutions. There are many who are living, or striving to live "humble,"
                            married lives ; but to call such lives Christian, is a misrepresentation of, or insult to
                            the Angels "in heaven" for whose practices we pray, or pretend to pray "to be done on
                            earth," and from whence Christianity Avas derived ! Christianity introduced as a superior
                            relationship, brethren and sisters in Christ. We would ask where there is any contiguity
                            between such relationship and husbands and wives ? According to the language of nature such
                            admixture would be incestuous and unholy ! And so far from being a Christian institution, we
                            would ask wherein Jesus ever accepted it as such, either in his life or testimony, or when
                            any of his disciples ever had his union in so doing? As a civil institution, marriage ia
                            righteous ; as a Christian institution it is a misnomer and unrighteous. Marriago should
                            people the earth ; Celibacy peoples the heavens, wherever these may be; and regardless of
                            any objections these stand unalterably true. Exchanging marriage for celibate relationship,
                            paves the way for common property relations ; and for peace eternal. All contentions and
                            wars have their origin in the selfishness of the flesh— for land, women, or else. Do away
                                MANIFESTO<pb n="224" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 334 THE SHAKER with the spirit of mine, and the dawn of
                            peace begins immediately ; happier homes will result, and grinders of the faces of the poor
                            need not tremble because of so-called communists, who are only attempting to equalize t the
                            good things of this life unevenly shared by ungodly, unbrotherly monopolists. Shakerism
                            would open a peaceable arbitrament for all who would live above contentions. It would make
                            all equal sharers of burdens and blessings in this life ; bring down the mountains of
                            selfishness ; lift up the valleys of poverty and degradation ; while the strong and superior
                            would say and act towards the weak : "I am your brother." How far are we from such a
                            condition now? Just as far, as we are away from the simplest Christianity ; and we hold that
                            while marriage, private property, war, politics, etc. are right among the earthly and earthy
                            ; there is a superior call for "all who are able to live it," to come up to the plane
                            whereon Jesus stood—resurrected above marriage, sensual loves and lusts ; private property
                            and war—and thus realize that true Shakerism and radical Christianity are identical; and
                            these are "the power of God unto fuller salvation" than any thing else ever known.</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, sixth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE. Her
                            work, her People, and their Critics. Sixth Paper</head><p TEIform="p">When in 1620 the Puritans found a refuge in this country—when Massachusetts assured them
                            immunity from the horrid persecutions they had suffered for their faith in the Mother
                            country—none could then have thought, that they would, a few years after, engage in similar
                            or worse persecutions upon unresisting Quakers and Shakers ! But, while the name of Puritan,
                            unsullied by the record of whippings, brandings, hangings and burnings, of those as "earnest
                            for the faith" as they ever had been, would be a glorious affix for any people, history
                            sanctions the assertion, that Puritan as really means a holy horror, as the term Sioux means
                            treachery! While Ann Lee and company remained in Massachusetts, preaching to and saving
                            souls, and apparently in the measure in which they were successful in these, they were most
                            barbarously assaulted by the descendants of the Puritans. We are loth to present a lengthy
                            chapter of these horrors, but will name a few cases of outrage upon these unoffending
                            Shakers by the holy horror Puritans : While yet at Harvard, in the Square House, mobs
                            assembled armed with clubs, and ordered the Shakers to leave the place. The Shakers were
                            engaged in worship. Some of the mob rushed in, and seizing Daniel Wood, and in passing him
                            violently through a door, burst a blood vessel, causing consternation among themselves, at
                            which they then retired. Soon after a mob of two hundred men again assembled; finding the
                            Believers at worship and on their knees in prayer, they rushed in upon both brethren and
                            sisters, and beginning with Richard Treat who was nearest the door, they seized him by the
                            throat and delivered him to the company remaining outside. The report goes on to say : "Thus
                            they seized one after another, some by their collars, others by their throats, still others
                            by the hair of their heads, and dragged them outside. In this manner the brethren and
                            sisters were all seized indiscriminately, without any resistance on their part, and dragged
                            out with as little humanity as ravenous wolves would drag out harmless sheep. None but
                            devils incarnate could be so far divested of the feelings of common humanity as were those
                            engaged in this horrid transaction." They were now surrounded by the mob, beaten, and
                            ordered to march. Some attempted to plead for mercy and consideration, but were immediately
                            struck on their mouths with clubs. Some were aged and infirm and could not travel as fast as
                            their drivers MANIFESTO<pb n="225" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 335 wished, when their
                            pace was quickened by the strokes of whips! After driving the Believers for three miles,
                            they halted; "Now," said the leader, "we will have a little diversion." Seizing on one of
                            the brethren, they made him disrobe for a whipping. He obeyed; and kneeling, quoted: "Be of
                            good cheer, brethren, for it is your Heavenly Father's good pleasure to give you the kingdom
                            ;" and while yet speaking, and before any were ordered to attack him, one ruffian struck him
                            several blows with his whip; at this, another of the brethren jumped on to the back of the
                            kneeling brother, which act was followed by a most brutal attack upon both, with clubs,
                            canes and whips. The mob now had their hands full; for each of the brethren seemed
                            determined to save the other from the strokes, which fell fast and heavy. One of the
                            brethren began to pray, when he was seized and hurled against a stone wall with great
                            violence. "Did you stop the little dog from praying?" asked one of the leaders. ' 'No; nor I
                            couldn't unless I had killed him !" Such scenes as these were common and would fill a
                            lmndred pages like this-, to write them all in detail. One of the brethren, at another time,
                            was knocked from his horse by a fence rail; others were tied naked to trees and lashed; one
                            sister, was nearly strangled to death, by a mob which attacked them with whips and clubs,
                            while eating some bread and cheese ; it was with great difficulty that she recovered. All
                            the time the Believers remained in Mass, and Conn, they were subjected to the constant
                            abuses of violent mobs ; and to think that such scenes were enacted in these States but a
                            hundred years ago, by the descendants of those who fled from their native land be- cause of
                            persecutions, seems almost impossible to believe. And why was all this mischief attempted
                            and committed? Let the record of those days speak: "All these scenes had no other cause,
                            than that the gospel increased; the testimony against the flesh prevailed, and the fears of
                            antichrist became more and more alarmed. It could not endure a religion which threatened the
                            foundation of its Kingdom, by turning so many of its subjects from darkness to light, and
                            converting them from the error of their ways." None lost their lives; but it has always been
                            considered providential that some were not kilred. Many carried the results of fractured
                            bones, in crippled limbs and deep scars, to their graves. At the disinterment of Wm. Lee,
                            (brother of Mother Ann,) a few years since, his skull was found to have been fractured!</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter of acceptance" TEIform="index"/>LETTER OF ACCEPTANCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">[We should have been pleased to have had the appended letter of Elder Evans inserted in
                                our AUG. no. As it gives expression to the ideas of one of our prominent leaders, to be
                                elaborated upon by him at the Liberal League Convention, the letter will be in-
                                teresting. Elder Evans is a living, progressive man; and though his propositions are far
                                in advance of his day, are they not demanded, desirable and true? Ed.]</p><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="H. L. Green—Esteemed Friend, Have just received your cordial invitation to attend..." TEIform="index"/>H. L. Green—Esteemed Friend, Have just received your cordial invitation to attend...
                                </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline><p TEIform="p">H. L. Green—Esteemed Friend, Have just received your cordial invitation to attend the
                                    L. L. Convention to be held at Watkins, N. Y. in August. Upon this subject of
                                    National Reform, my whole soul is moved with deep emotion, caused by influx from the
                                    innner spheres of the Spirit World, which is, at this time, acting upon the earth
                                    sphere to inaugurate the Second Cycle of the great American Revolution. The founders
                                    of the First Cycle—the Signers—are all in the Spirit World. They rest not day nor
                                    night, until their revelational, prophetical ideal of a Civil Government is
                                    incarnated upon the earth. It is the hope of humanity, their trust in God that the
                                    Judge of all the earth will do right and cause those who rule their fellows to do
                                    right. The list of speakers invited to your Convention indicates the existence, in
                                    ourcountry, of true Sons and Daughters of the Signers— Infidels all—Infidel to false
                                    systgms of Church and State, religious and civil institutions that make men and
                                    women, capital and labor, enemies to each other, enacting laws that sin as with a
                                    cart rope. Let us begin the Second Cycle where the Signers began the First—at the
                                    bottom. Put the axe of Reform at the root of Society<pb n="226" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> eso THE
                                    SHAKER evils. They declared the inalienable right of man, independent of all
                                    existing laws o Great Britian and her thousand years of polit ical and religious
                                    experience. Let us declare the rights of man and wo man, of labor and capital—the
                                    right of hu man beings, not to the pursuit of happiness only, but to its permanent
                                    possession—tha all government should tend toward that enc —the good of all. As
                                    Jefferson, Paine and coadjutors removed one class of evils, so let us remove another
                                    class. We have made a good beginning. Slavery i abolished. Imprisonment for debt is
                                    abolished. Public lands are free to actual settlers. Homesteads are inalienable.
                                    Women have some rights besides that of being chastilet with a whip not bigger than a
                                    broomstick, applied by her lord. Let us make women citizens, limit the quantity of
                                    land to be owned by a citizen, thus increasing the number of freeholders and
                                    decreasing the material for armies and navie —landless people. Abolish all laws for
                                    collecting debts. Each town establish a homestead where all the weary can find rest,
                                    and all tramps plenty of work on the farm, or in the garden or shops. Have a
                                    communistic, uni. tary home of their' own, with brains to manage it. In a word,
                                    educate men and Avomen to take care of themselves. And educate one class to take
                                    care of the class that will not do it, and all will be cared for. Success to the
                                    coming, great Watkins Convention.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion of the future" TEIform="index"/>THE RELIGION OF THE FUTURE</head><p TEIform="p">It is peculiarly true, that however distasteful the gospel of Christ may be, as dispensed by
                            the tenets of Shakerism ; however decidedly the masses of people shun the idea of adopting
                            Shaker faith as their life line of conduct in Christianity ; yet nearly or quite all expect,
                            so soon as they shall have passed the boundaries of this life, to enter into re- lations so
                            similar to Shaker life on earth, as almost to appear identical! That which appears so
                            dreadful here, is acepted as being the constituent life of the heavens there. Why is virgin
                            celibacy so shunned, almost universally, by those whose religious teachings have decided
                            this to be one of the basic conditions of those in heavenly life? Why is this admitted to
                            have been the life of Jesus, the Christ, and admired in him, but considered a nonessential
                            in his followers, and ridiculed and despised in those who consider it essentially religious
                            thus to follow him? Truly, the religion of the future will be illustrated by having virgin
                            celibacy as a marked characteristic. In the heavenly world, it is a generally accepted
                            truth, that a universal brotherhood will prevail. There, private, personal, selfish
                            considerations will be ignored, and equality ensue, and conse- quently heavenly interests
                            enhanced. The lusts of the flesh, the pride of this life and the selfish spirit of mine,
                            will all be rejected as inharmonious elements to the formation of the Christian's heaven.
                            So, too, will peace prevail; because the elements of war have been cast out. No lusts, no
                            pride, no wars ; no hankering after worldly power, popularity nor possessions; hence, heaven
                            will oe the result. If such is the belief of religionists to- day, and we believe it is,
                            without an exception among professedly Christian ihurches, how different are such condiions
                            and life, to these same, now in exjrcise among all Shaker Societies? Our estimony is opposed
                            to the good and jad of generative, sexual loves and usts ; and why? Because, we have
                                givMANIFESTO.<pb n="227" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER iMLAJVIiniESTO. 227 •en these in exchange
                            for brotherly and sisterly relations of love, that exceed in value, any merely animal
                            indulgence. Rejecting and losing the inferior of this life, that we may gain a foretaste at
                            last, of the powers and blessings of the world to come. We are opposed to war, contentions,
                            etc., for good or bad uses. They are as unheavenly here, as they ever will be in spirit
                            life. The religion of the future will hot admit of war, strife, nor aught like carnal
                            resistance. The Churches of today, are very lax in their direct reference to the life and
                            teachings of him whom they claim as Lord and Head. Evasion seems to be the rule; Paul's
                            permissions to evade earnestly sought after ; while the pure. lovely life of the Christ—the
                            religion of the future—is admired, but not copied. Let the religion of the future, have its
                            dawn with us today. It will place self-denial, to all unspirited loves and lusts, over the
                            doors of our souls. We shall be nobler men and women ; Peace will reign; equality in all
                            good things be inaugurated, and our best love for God, be evidenced through our largest love
                            for humanity.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feet" TEIform="index"/>The Feet.—</head><p TEIform="p">Many of the colds which people are said to catch commence at the feet. To keep these
                            extremities warm, therefore, is to effect an insurance against the almost interminable list
                            of disorders which spring out of a "slight cold." First, never be tightly shod. Boots or
                            shoes when they fit closely press against the feet and prevent the free circulation of the
                            blood. When, on the contrary, they fit with comparative looseness, the blood gets fair play,
                            and the spaces left between the leather and the stockings are filled with a comfortable
                            supply of warm air. The second rule is, never sit in damp shoes. It is often imagined that
                            unless they are positively wet it is not necessary to change them. This is a fallacy, for
                            when the least dampness is absorbed into the sole, it is attracted nearer the feet itself by
                            the heat, and thus the perspiration is dangerously checked. Any person may prove this by
                            trying the experiment of neglecting this rule. The feet will become cold and damp after a
                            few moments, although on taking off the shoes and warming them they will ap- pear quite
                            dry.—Exchange.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/> For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter VIII" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP.VIII</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">At length after a rough voyage of three weeks, we reached one of the lee-ward islands,
                                Miyow; a little gem of an island which was very fertile. Here we laid off and on with
                                the vessel, there being no anchorage for anything bigger than a canoe; and here the
                                captain purchased an abundance of food such as Yams, Sweet Potatoes, Bread-fruit,
                                Oranges, and several Hogs. One of the hogs was wild and fierce, and on being loosed,
                                cleared the main deck of every body. A number of us ran up the rigging, some took to the
                                high quarter deck, and one man jumped over-board and swam to our jolly boat which was
                                towing alongside. The natives whose business it was to look after these animals, soon
                                rallied and slaughtered him. The flesh of these hogs is very sweet and good, quite
                                unlike the domestic animals of civilized countries, for they run wild on the island,
                                picking up their living from the abundant, spontaneous supply of nuts, roots, and
                                vegetables. After leaving Miyow, we called at Huheine, a large mountainous island, where
                                Tyreman and Bennett, two English missionaries first established themselves. I went
                                ashore in<pb n="228" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE the boat with the Captain, who left his wif, and
                                child there. In walking around, among the little cluster of native huts, I unexpectedly
                                met a young white man, with whom I had previously associated as ship-m:ite. lie had been
                                Steward for a six-month's cruise in the whale ship Phcnix, coming on board at Eimeo, and
                                being discharged there at the return of the ship from a cruise on the equator, or "on
                                the line" as the sailors call it. He was a native of Smyrna, and could speak Greek,
                                French, Italian, Spanish, and other eastern languages. He had learned the Tahiti
                                language, and seemed quite at home with the natives. The captain finished his business,
                                and set sail for Tahiti which lies forty or fifty miles to wind-ward. The day we reached
                                Parpatie was very fine, and the old native pilot Jim—as he was commonly called—or "Jim
                                the pilot," came and took our vessel into the beautiful harbor of Parpatie. Here the
                                schooner was anchored near an old hulk belonging to Captain Hall and his partner, the
                                American Consul. Our cargo of cocoa-nuts was discharged in this hulk, to be sold to
                                whale ships who came to this place in great numbers, to obtain provisions. We remained
                                on board the schooner but a short time after our arrival at Tahiti. A young man Edward
                                by name, who was a native of London, England, and who was one of our crew, went to Eimeo
                                where he had a partner who had cleared a little patch of land, and planted it with sweet
                                potatoes. There were three men in partnership in this little colony. The principal was
                                an English merchant from Sydney, Australia. Edward being absent a few days returned in a
                                boat belonging to Sanders, the trader, to visit his ship-mates. In conversing with him,
                                we learned that we could have the same wages to work for them, as we were having on
                                board the vessel, which was eight dollars a month; and as wages were small at the
                                Society islands, John and I accepted our ship-mate's invitation to go with him to Eimeo.
                                Collecting our little all from the vessel which had taken us from our lone, island home,
                                we went to the boat which wa9 to take us to our future abode, and had waited but a short
                                time when S.inders tho owner of the boat cam a. and appeared very much disturbed,
                                fearing we had left without the Consul's consent; so to satisfy himself that all was
                                right, he went to tho Consulate, and obtaining satisfaction wo accompanied him to
                                Einieo. Leaving Parpatie we passed through tho ruff into the open sea, and steered
                                forEinco, which looked to be a long distance to reach in so small a boat, yet we crossed
                                in safety. We hardly reached the snug little bay of Afraito when a heavy thunder shower
                                camo on. My brother, and James Martin— Edward's partner—crawled under the cuddy of the
                                little boat, while Edward and I went ashore and found shelter in a native house. The
                                natives were kind to us, and we talked with them as well as our limited knowledgo of
                                their language would permit. The rain poured in torrents, and wo remained all night in
                                the native house, which, like all the houses of these people waa very open on the sides,
                                but with an excellent tight roof, which is made from the leaves of »ume kind of palm. In
                                the morning we commenced unloading our boat, by carrying some great sacks of salt and
                                sugar to the house of the English missionary. Having had no breakfast wo were very weak,
                                and went staggering rip the graveled walk before the missionary's cottage, with the
                                heavy sacks on our shoulders, which caused much merriment among the natives who were
                                seated near their huts, comfortably wrapped in their Tappas, or native cloth, chatting
                                away very merrily at the expense of the white sailors, who were acting the part of
                                beasts of burden, in carrying stores of good things to Mitter Howe, as they called the
                                missionary. Well as I staggered along with my heavy load, I thought of the line things I
                                had heard at the Sabbath schools, of theso Evangelical missionaries on the Pacific
                                islands. I had left my home, father, mother, brothers and sisters, that I might visit
                                theso islands, and see these self-devoted messcnSHAKER, MANIFESTO. 228<pb n="229" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> IVEAjNTIPT'HISTO. nog gers of good tidings of salvation. Oh, I enjoyed
                                the thought of meeting these dear saviours, who had left home and f.iends to give their
                                lives for the conversion of the poor benighted heathen. Well, the above was my ideal of
                                the missionary, and now we were to meet them in their field of labor. The sack on my
                                shoulder was very heavy, and it was by our utmost exertion that any of us reached the
                                mission house; however, we got there and were met by Mrs. Howe, her face all aglow with
                                indignation, that the salt and sugar we had brought, got wet during the rain of the
                                previous night. Mrs. Howe was a largo woman, with an Anglo Saxon face. She talked very
                                hard about Mr. Sanders' carelessness in allowing her stores to get damaged. On telling
                                Sanders of the trouble, he pleasantly remarked that she should have some dry from his
                                stores. Now, this self-sacriflcbg missionary never offered us a bit of refreshment, no
                                water, •and never even thanked us f jr our exertions in waiting upon her. The air-bubble
                                burst, ray ideal missionary dissolved into air. Our ship-mate Edward had a native'
                                f.-iend Jit Afraito who cooked us a good meal which was served in native style. This
                                native was not a convert, but a fine looking young man, who proved himself more of a
                                true friend to us, than the lady, f,)r he gave us food and drink, while she did nothing
                                of the kind, but rather abused us for wli.it wo could not avoid. (continued )</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principles of light and color" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Babbitt, E. D." TEIform="persName"/>E. D. Babbitt </byline><p TEIform="p"/><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Complete preacher" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Punishment of sin eternal" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ the corner stone of spiritualism" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J.M. Peebles</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Champions of the church" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The principles of Light and color : By E. D. Babbitt, Mt. Ill Eighth St. New York. Price,
                                post pud, $4.00. Tin? book is already producing a decided sensation in the scientific
                                and cultured world, and contains probably a greater nnmb3r of rorriarkablo discoveries
                                than any om volusn of lEodcin times. It is issued in superb style on heavy tone...
                                embracing 57G royal 8vo pages. The demonstration for the first time of the form and
                                working of Atoms, of the basic principles of Chemistry, of the marvelous chemical and
                                therapeutical power of Light, Color, and other Fine and Spiritual Forces invisible to
                                the ordinary eye, by means cf which many of the mystic and heretofore unknown laws of
                                Nature and Mind stand revealed, is of vast importance as presenting new keys cf power to
                                man. The exact processes of Clairvoyance, Psychology, Statuvolence, Psychometry,
                                Color-Healing, and the invisible human Radiations, are given, and anew world of forces
                                disclosed. The cream of the discoveries of Robert Hunt, Dr. Forbes Winslow, Gen.
                                Pleasanton, Tyndall, and many others, as well as some of the choice things from Drs. J.
                                R. Buchanan, H. H. Sherwood, Pancoast, etc., are presented. The chemical and healing
                                power of all known elements is given by means of Spectrum Analysis as crystallized into
                                a science. The complete preacher, is a monthly periodical, issued by the Religious News
                                paper Agency 21 Barclay St. N. Y. We would call particular attention to the June No. as
                                containing sermons upon vital subjects, chief of which are the discourses of Dr. F. C.
                                Ewer which have created intense excitement; and the reply thereunto by Henry Ward
                                Beecher. The punishment of sin eternal : The same agency publish three interesting
                                discourses upon the above subject, being replies to H. W. Beecher, Robt. Ingersoll and
                                Canon Farrar, by Justhi D. Fulton. Those who have read the recently notorious utterances
                                of this trio, will be very interested in Fulton's replies. Christ tii^ cokneu sto;;;; o?
                                spiritualism, by J. M. Peebles, Cjlby and Rich, Boston, Mats. Every pamphlet that our
                                brother Peebles writes is chock fall of sound sense and good reasoning; and this one oil
                                the above subject, is no exception. The cita:jpions ok the church : By J). M. Bennett,
                                Editor of The Truth Seeker. Christianity, so-called, as judged by the lives of its
                                prominent uphold2rs, receives <pb n="230" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> S3O THE SHAKER througli these pages
                                the most keen and damaging testimony. Having reversed the intentions of the founder of
                                Christianity by making its name answer all purposes, too many have been found to use it,
                                specifically, for the basest, most selfish ends; and this work is a terrible expose.
                                Inquire for it by addressing its author 141 Eighth St. New York. Nora Kay : Proctor
                                Bros. Gloucester, Mass. This is a simple, beautifully written story of a child medium.
                                If true, it is a wonderful story; but if written merely for the romance of thought, it
                                will simply cheer and inebriate. Its price is only Fifty Cents; and while we should
                                judge, from its termination, it is too novel to be true, no great harm can come to the
                                reader, while passing with it a pleasant hour. "CHAMPIONS OP THE OHUEOH." Our brother,
                                J. M. Peebles, writes as follows : "There has just reached me from the office of D. M.
                                Bennett, editor of the Truih-Seeker, New York, a volume of 1119 pages, entitled, 'The
                                Champions of the Church, Their Crimes and Persecutions.' This is a very valuable work.
                                Any book or pamphlet that incites thought, leads to the study of history, and inspires
                                candid investigation, is serviceable to humanity. And this large and handsomely bound
                                volume will do this very thing. And yet, considering the contents, so pungent and
                                bravely written, would not this have been a more appropriate title—''The Champions of
                                Superstition and Bigotry'? The spirit of Christ is the very opposite of crime and
                                intolerance. And further, the general teachings of Jesus are against it. The genius of
                                true Christianity and the conduct of professed Christians should never be confounded.
                                Among several errors that should be corrected in future editions are these : 'Krishna
                                Crucified upon a Tree upon the Banks of the Ganges.' 'Sakya Muni Gautama Buddha claimed
                                by his Followers to have been Crucified upon a Cross.' The followers of Sakya Muni
                                Gautama never claimed any such thing, nor do they at the present time. Neither was
                                Krishna crucified. I attended the festival in his honor a year ago this month in Madras,
                                India. The procession was immense, and the arrow symbolizing his death was conspicuous
                                among the sacred images. Elphinstone's history of India, edited by Prof. Cowell of the
                                Sanskrit College, Calcutta, says, (chap. 3. p. 100.) 'Krishna's end was also unfortunate
                                ; for he was soon involved in civil discord, and at last was slain by the arrow of a
                                hunter, who shot him by mistake in a thicket.' " Any one wishing to understand the
                                difference between Jesus and Christ, and desirous of knowing the scriptural passages
                                that sustain Spiritualism, should send for Dr. Peebles's "Christ, the Corner Stone of
                                Spiritualism." Price 10 cts.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fill the lungs" TEIform="index"/>FILL THE LUNGS</head><p TEIform="p">Persons who take but little exercise neglect to draw the air into the lungs. This should
                                be accomplished by taking long and full inspirations for a short time, every day, while
                                in the open air. This practice would get the lungs into the habit of opening to the air
                                quite down to their base, and would make the breathing much more natural, as well as
                                effectual at all times. In the case of young persons, it would enlarge the capacity of
                                the chest, and add to the brief years of life.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True gentleman" TEIform="index"/>The True Gentleman</head><p TEIform="p">The following sketch is called the portrait of a true gentleman, found in an old manor-
                                house in Gloucestershire, England, written, framed, and hung over the mantel-piece of a
                                tapestried sitting-room:— "The true ggitleman is God's servant, the world's master, and
                                his own man; virtue is his business, study his recreation, contentment his rest and
                                happiness his reward; God MANIFESTO.<pb n="231" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE 331 is his father, the
                                Church is his mother, the saints his brethren, all that need him his friends; devotion
                                is his chaplain, chastity is his chamberlain ; sobriety his butler, temperance his cook,
                                hospitality his housekeeper. Providence his steward, charity his treasurer, piety the
                                mistress of his house, and discretion his porter, to let in or out as most fit. This is
                                his whole family, made up of virtues, and he is the true master of the house. He is
                                necessitated to take the world on his way to heaven; but he walks through it a fast as
                                he can, and all his business by the way, is to make himself and others happy. Take him
                                in two words—a Man and a Christian."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The first thing is to make your sermon plain..." TEIform="index"/>The first thing is to make your sermon plain...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The first thing is to make your sermon plain. Rev. Blomfield preached on the text, "The
                                fool hath said in his heart, 'There is no God.' " Wishing to find out how it pleased his
                                people, he called a poor foolish man to the pulpit and asked him how he liked the
                                sermon. The reply, which made Blomfield a sadder and a wiser man, was, "Well, sir, I
                                must say that I can't agree with you. In spite of all you've said, I think there must be
                                a God.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hindoo prayer" TEIform="index"/>A Hindoo Prayer!</head><p TEIform="p">"There is one thing, my God, which makes me very anxious. It is this. Having loved thee
                                as my Father and Mother, I now feel I cannot fear thee, as a transgressor like myself
                                should fear the great Judge. The fact is, I love thee, and yet I love and cherish my
                                sins too. Assuredly my love for thee is not genuine pure love. So, at least, says my
                                conscience. And yet I cannot believe that I do not love thee. Teach me, God, to har-
                                monize sweet love with chastening fear, that I may, wMIr loving thee with passionate at-
                                tachment, root out whatsoever is wrong in my heart. If I cannot fear thee, Lord, let thy
                                holy spirit so sanctify my inner nature that there may be left no cause for fear."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boyhood of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>The Boyhood of Jesus</head><p TEIform="p">"And the child grew, and waxed strong in spirit." How thoroughly human this is! It was a
                                real, true humanity, which in him was united to divinity. Here is a true Galilean child,
                                a real Israelitish boy. Here is the human nature in its process of development. Its
                                proper qualities are becoming, coming forth into manifestation, into full and evident
                                possession of their substance. There is a proper growth of healthy and perfect
                                childhood, advancing toward healthy and perfect and strong manhood. Was there in
                                Nazareth, think you, or in Galilee, a more resolute boy than Jesus? Had there* been in
                                Rome or in Sparta? He "grew and waxed strong in spirit." "The grace of God, which was
                                upon him," did not make him feeble and spiritless. There was in him the natural
                                connection between healthy bodily growth, and increasing strength of mind. As he climbed
                                thehills about Nazareth; as he plied the lighter tools in his, Joseph's shop ; as he fed
                                temperately at the table, and slept soundly under the roof of that home, which, if
                                lowly, we can never imagine untidy nor unwholesome—he grew, and as his frame increased
                                in size, and his limbs in vigor, his spirit waxed stronger day by day. It increased in
                                energy, in courage, in fortitude. We cannot imagine him rude, boisterous, turbulent,
                                ready to quarrel with other boys, nor to tyrannize over them, when he found himself the
                                stronger. But can you imagine him scared by any blustering young Nazarene, turned aside
                                from duty to human parents, or to God, by any rough boy's threats, or any proud girl's
                                sneer? Boys, true piety will not make you tame, spiritless, cowardly. Study your Bibles
                                to learn what kind of a boy Jesus was. To be tike him will make you both manly and
                                gentlemanly.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nelson, H. A." TEIform="persName"/>H. A. Nelson, D. D.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I never complained of my condition but once..." TEIform="index"/>I never complained of my condition but once...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"I never complained of my condition but once" said an old man, "when my feet were mre, and I
                            had no money to buy shoes; but [ met a man without feet, and I became cop;ented."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="232" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fish as food" TEIform="index"/>Fish as food
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Fish as food.—There is much nourishment in fish, little if any less than there is in
                                meat, weight for weight. In fact it may be more nourishing, because as a rule it is much
                                more easily digested. Fish is consid?red almost a spscifb against scrofulous
                            diseases.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value of food" TEIform="index"/>Value of food
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Vain? of foti.—0 13 prail of corn is equal, as food, to four pound? of potatoes and more
                                than equal to eight pound? i. cabbage, or to twelve and a half pounds of turnips. Meat
                                is not fattening, but is muscle yielding aud strengthening. Grains are fattening.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poisons and antidotes" TEIform="index"/>Poisons and Antidotes</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It not unfrequently happens that serious and distressing results are
                                        occasioned by the accidental employment of poisons, and it has occurred to us
                                        that we might d;gt; a service to some of our mubrs by presenting them with a
                                        brief and compendious li.-t of the more common poisons and the remedies for them
                                        most likely to be at hand : Acicfs—These cause great her.t and sensation of
                                        burning pain from the mouth d gt;\vn to the stomach. Remedies—Magnesia, soda,
                                        pearl-ash or soap, dissolved in water; then use stomach pump or emetics.
                                        Alkalies—Best remedy is vinegar. Ammonia—Remedy, lemon juice or vinegar :
                                        afterward, re Me and water or ilax^eed tea. Alcohol—First cleanse out the
                                        stomach by an emetic; then dash cold water on the head and give ammonia (spiiits
                                        cf hartshorn). Arsenic—In the first evacuate the stomach ; then give the white
                                        cf egg=, lime water or chalk and water, charcoal, and the preparation of iron,
                                        particularly hydrate. Lead—White lead and sugar of leaf. Remedies—Alum and
                                        cathartics, such us castor oil and Epsom salts especially. Charcoal—In poisons
                                        by carbonic gas, remove the patient to open air, dash cold water on the head and
                                        body and stimulate the nostrils and lungs by hartshorn at tha same lime rubbing
                                        the chest briskly. Corrosive Sublimate—Give white of eggs freshly mixed with
                                        water, or give wheat flour and water or soap and water freely. Creosote—White of
                                        eggs and emetics. Belladonna or henbane—Give emetics and then plenty cf vinegar
                                        and water, with a dose of ether if handy. Nitrate of silver (lunar caustic)—Give
                                        a strong solution of common salt and then emetics. Opiurc—First give a strong
                                        emetic of mustard and water, and then strong coffee and acid drinks. Dash cold
                                        water on the hend. Laudanum—Same as opium. Nux Vomica—First emetics, then
                                        brandy. Oxalic acid—Frequently mistaken fjr Epsom salts. Remedies—Chalk,
                                        Magnesia, or soap and water freely : then emetics. Nitrate of potash—Give
                                        emetics, then oopius draughts of flaxseed tea, milk and water, and other
                                        soothing drinks. Prussia acid—When there i: time administer chlorine in the
                                        shape of soda or lime. Hot brandy and water, hartshorn and turpentine are also
                                        useful.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hartford courant" TEIform="index"/>Hartford Courant</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Scientific American sends out a warning against the recommendation of using olive oil                                     for..." TEIform="index"/>The Scientific American sends out a warning against the recommendation of using olive oil for...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Scientific American sends out a warning against the recommendation of using Olive oil
                                far every species of poisoning. We have seen this recommendation going the rounds very
                                freely; and while we know that Olive oil is a very useful application in many cases, we
                                believe that reliance upon it as an antidote fjr all poisons, to be a mistaken and
                                dangerous expedient.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Milk as a preventive of white lead poisoning" TEIform="index"/>Milk as a Preventive of
                                White Lead Poisoning</head><p TEIform="p">A singular fact is given in the Jouroi.nl dz Medecine with regard to the effect of the
                                habitual use of milk in white lead works. In some French lead mills it was observed that
                                in a large working population two men who drank much milk daily were not affected by
                                lead. On the general use of milk throughout the works the colic vanished entirely. Each
                                operative was given enough extra pay to buy a quart of milk a day.</p></div3><pb n="233" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Syrup of coffee" TEIform="index"/>Syrup of Coffee</head><p TEIform="p">This preparation is of great use to those who have long journeys to make. Take half a lb.
                                of the best ground coffee, put into a sauce-pan containing three pints of water; •when
                                thoroughly steeped, pour off into another clean vessel and boil again until reduced to
                                one pint. As it boils, add white sugar enough to give it the consistency of syrup. Take
                                it from the lire; when cold, put into a bottle and seal. When traveling, if you wish fjr
                                a cup of good coffee, you have only to put two or three teaspoonfuls of the syrup into
                                an ordinary cup, then pour boiling water upan it, and it is ready fjr use. We have
                                proved it to be good.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Merrill, Granville" TEIform="index"/>Granville Merrill
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At West Gloucester, Me. July 4, <persName reg="Merrill, Granville" TEIform="persName">Granville
                                Merrill</persName> aged 39 years, 5 months and 14 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sasseen, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Sasseen
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky. April 12, <persName reg="Sasseen, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly Sasseen</persName>,
                                aged 77 years. She had lived in the order of Elders fir fifty years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hutton, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane Hutton
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky. June 4, <persName reg="Hutton, Jane" TEIform="persName">Jane Hutton,</persName> aged
                                nO years. She had been the Eldress of East Family for more than thirty years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Owen, Emily" TEIform="index"/>Emily Owen
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. July 9, <persName reg="Owen, Emily" TEIform="persName">Emily Owen,</persName> nged 71
                                years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kripe, Betsy" TEIform="index"/>Betsy Kripe
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Watervliet, O. July----<persName reg="Kripe, Betsy" TEIform="persName">Betsy Kripe,</persName> aged GG
                                years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Johns, U. E." TEIform="index"/>U. E. Johns
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky. July 28, <persName reg="Johns, U. E." TEIform="persName">U. E. Johns,</persName> aged 7G
                                years. A veteran Trustee, cf very many years' standing.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Huntington, Achsah" TEIform="index"/>Achsah Huntington
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H. July 28, <persName reg="Huntington, Achsah" TEIform="persName">Achsah Huntington
                                </persName> aged 82. A substantial pillar of the Church, and a worthy Christian
                                from early womanhood.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Krintz, Barbara" TEIform="index"/>Barbara Krintz
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, Ohio, Aug. 4, <persName reg="Krintz, Barbara" TEIform="persName">Barbara Krintz,</persName>
                                aged GO years.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">Bro. Benj. Gates is on a business trip to Europe. Will return, this month. Elder F. W. Evans
                            and the editor of The Manifesto attended the Watkins, N. Y. Liberal Convention. "The
                            Buckeye" mowers went through our large harvests without a break or ono penny's expenses ! We
                            arc sorry to record a destructive fire at Enfield, Conn. The losses consist of barns with
                            valuab.c contents; the cause, accidental. "To whom it may concern :" Editorial and Shaker
                            Chairs are made solely— Shaker Chairs we mean—by R. M. Wagan, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Denial" TEIform="index"/>DENIAL</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hayne, Paul H." TEIform="persName"/>PAUL H. HAYNE</byline><p TEIform="p">We look with scorn on Peter's1h:ic3 told lie! Boldly we say, "Good brother 1 you nor I, So
                            near the sacred Lord, the Christ indeed, Had dared his name and marvelous grace deny." O
                            fj'.ile boast! O haughty lips, be dumb! Unheralded by boisterous trump or drum, How oft 'mid
                            silent eves, and midnight chimes, Vainly to us our pleading Lord hath come, Knocked at our
                            hearts, striven to enter there; But we, poor slaves of mortal sin and care, Sunk in deep
                            sloth, or bound by spiritual sleep, Heard not the voic3 divine, the tender prayer! Ah! well
                            for us if some late spring-'idc hour Failh still may bring, with blended shine and shovrcr;
                            If through warm tears a late remorse ma}shed, Our wakened souls put forth one heavenly
                            flower!</p></div2><pb n="234" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning light" TEIform="index"/>MORNING LIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. 1. The glorious morn is dawning; All hail its blessed 2. Accept the cross
                            with pleasure ; Nor murmur by the light! Come home ye weary, wand'ring, Now ends the gloomy
                            way, Whatever be thy measure, The sum which thou must night. The radiant orb of glory,
                            Now rising full in pay. O may the promised blessing, Thro' faithfulness be MANIFESTO. <pb n="235" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 235 view, Bespeaks the gladsome story, That
                            Christ is come thine, Salvation's prize possessing, Thy crowning theme to you. Come home,
                            ye wand'ring souls, divine. Salvation's sound most sweetly rolls. In desert wilds no
                            longer roam, Ye wand'ring souls, come home,</p></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <pb n="236" id="p28"/>
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>AD VERTISEMENTS. Tlie Societies at Canterbury and "Watervliet luive nscd tills J^Ti. for many years, and they
                            unhesitating. ly rcoinmend it its a good, reliable article; of good col r, flows freely, and docs not fade.
                            Vrayiia,rL Voyes, Boston. Editorial Notes. "We arc using a number of The Bickfohd Knittinq Machines; and they
                            are very satisfactory indeed, Being among "die wonders in I his age" of machinery. Their utility and expedition
                            iu business should be experienced by all, at no small cont. Material fir Fences of wood variety is getting
                            scarce. "We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or rely on the metal ones oii'cred us by WashBURN,
                            MOEN CO. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the bent Wateh Wheel; but we are at no loss to say that the firms
                            ot Leffel & Co. and N. F.Buri;h:im, who enter into friendly competition in our columns, are both most
                            honorable. We find Stinson and Co. very honorable ia their d2aling. Try them. We hope "everybody and his in
                            ighbor" will send us six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for two copies post paid. It is a
                            pretty book. Pleaso procure it and present it to your friend. We are able to spenk of the various agricultural
                            implements of Wheeler & Mi lick Co., and of Westinghouse manufacture. We have tested their Threshers and
                            Towers for years, and found them unexcelled. We would call especial attention to tlie new advertisement, of N.
                            F. Burnhun. As enterprise is ever praiseworthy when applied as they apply it, let every or.c lend this firm a
                            token of praise. If any can do better for the furnish of Dry Goods, etc. than can be done at Win. M. Whitney
                            & Co., wo would be pleased to hear from such party. Take choice and clioose soon from among (ho most
                            beautiful musical instruments advertised in our column?. Quite a number of families are the happier o-day for
                            taking our advice, and b lying tlieir Organs and Pianos of - well "read and you will know." D. II. Fonda,
                            tha most cnlorprising of Druggists, etc. can be relied upon by parties, near by or distant, who are in want of
                            anything m his Hue, wholesale and retail. Try him, prove him.  - »o» -Any parties who would learn how we make
                            6Tich good, "gilf-edgod" butter, must read an article entiled " Gill-Edycd LutU r ifaki r."
                            - (iillott's Pens arc unequalcd by any other steel pen; xnd we deem hi-! No. 332 e~[ual in every
                            thing bat vear, to the best gold pen. Cct Gillott's Pens. MATHEWS' CARRIAGE MART CONCORD, N. H. Manufacturer of
                            and Dealer in fine Car' riages and Sleighs, secondhand Carriages gt; and Sleighs constantly on hand. Best
                            Bargains in the City.
                            - :_______________________„________....._________,__________ t Pianos,
                            Organs, ; SEND FOIR. OXaXJ3E3Tn? c«3 SOKT'2B Illustrated Catalogue REDUCED PRICE LIST, i 2G.» IllVffiU HV.
                            'fltOV, IV. Y. Solid Rubber Type. Cases containing 130 movable letters etc., with complete printing apparatus
                            $1.25 by mail, sample of type f and circular 5 ets. Address, i P. L. CALIAHAM, 8 High st. Salem, lass. !<pb
                                n="237" id="p29"/> A D VER TIS EM EN TS. SHAKER'S WINDOW SASH LOCK!. A new device for securing ventilation.
                            SIMPLE AND EASILY MANIPULATED, ADJUSTABLE TO ALL WINDOW SASH, SAFELY IIOLDING EITHER AT ANY POINT, WITHOUT
                            MARRING PAINT OR VARNISH. It consists of a clamp bar let loosely into the left side of the windoAv frame, having
                            two small lever eccentrics attached thereto by a screw or rivqt, at the center where the sash comes together.
                            The strip which holds the sash in place is let on the eccentrics, the lever or points only being visible. If a
                            parting strip is used it should be cut off at the bar, so that the top may be used at pleasure. By pressing on
                            the points the position of the eccentrics are changed so as to press against the IoAver sash, causing the catch
                            on the end of the bar to pull against the top sash, thus locking them so tight that it is impossible to move
                            either without opening the points. Also, the eccentrics, if desired, may be put on the left face of each sash
                            frame, in which case they will perfectly lock and tighten the sash and destroy all shaking and rattling by winds
                            or otherwise. In this case the eccentrics are visible. The strip must be sawed off from the lower eccentric
                            upwards, the thickness of the eccentrics, so that it will work against the under frame. When the sash is too
                            loose to be tightened by the eccentric, tack two bits or a strip on the right-hand edge. In short, it i3 the
                            simplest, safjst and best sash lock in existence, and needs only to bo seen to be appreciated. Sample sent by
                            mail for twenty-five cents. South Union, Logan Co., Kij. S. J. RUSSELL.<pb n="238" id="p30"/> AD VERTISEMENTS.
                            GENUINE SINGER SEWING MACHINE REDUCED THIRTY DOLLARS IN PRICE! Look Out for Cheap and Inferior counterfeits of
                            our Machine. To get a Genuine "Singer Sewing Machine," buy only of our authorized Agents, and see that each
                            Machine has our Trade Mark stamped on the arm. SPECIAL NOTICE! The Singer Manufacturing Company takes pleasure
                            in announcing that during the months of January, February, March and April, 1878, the sales of their genuine
                            Sewing Machines Avere sizty per cent, greater than during the corresponding months of last year ! It should also
                            be remembered that we sold 20,496 more Sewing Machines in 1877 than in any previous year, notwithstanding the
                            great depression of general business. Could there be stronger evidence of the hold these unequaled Machines have
                            taken upon public regard? Don't waste money on any cheap counterfeit! Send for Illustrated Circular and Price
                            List. THE SINGER MANUFACTURING COMPANY. Albany N. Y. Office 39 North Pearl St. FAMILY SOAPS. By C. BERKLEY
                            JOHNSON, Senior member of the late firm of E. A. & W. WINCHESTEB. The character and quality of E. A.
                            & W. Winchest er's Soap is fully equal, in every respect, to its former Standard. Its Style is plain. It
                            is not garnished with Showy Labels. It recommends itself by its excellence. It is designed for family use more
                            than for trade. Trade generally demands something cheaper, consequently inferior. Address, 0. BERKLEY JOHNSON,
                            16 Chatham St., BOSTON, MASS. Wholesale Dealerin STATE / V-/OC / 2 ilREET ALBANY, UST. "ST. SPECIAL NOTICE. Any
                            of our friends desirous of a Bickford Knitting Machine, will find it to be to their advantage to consult the
                            Publish' er of The Manifesto. <pb n="239" id="p31"/> AD VERTISEMENTS. Shaker Sash. Balance, A PEErECT BALANCE AT
                            ALL POINTS. Supersedes Weights & Boxes, Durable, Ornamental, and never outof order. From the Scientific
                            American. Our illustration represents a very simple and ingenious device, which does away with the usual cords
                            and pulleys on windows, making one sash balance the other. It is cheap and readily applied and will afford all
                            the means of ventilation that side- weights do. Samples by mail for $1.25—Agents wanted. Address. S. J. Russell,
                            Patentee, South Union, Kt. Washburn & fifloen ManTg Co. WORCESTER, MASS. Sole Mamifoctursrs East of
                            Chicago, of A STEEL Thorn Hedge. No other Fencing so cheap or put up so quickly. Never rusts, stains, decays,
                            shrinks, nor warps. Unaffected by fire, wind, or flood. A complete barrier to the most unruly stock. Impassab'e
                            by man or beast. TWO THOUSAND TONS SOLD AND PCJT UP DURING THE LAST YEAR. For sale at the leading hardware
                            stores, •with Stretchera and Staples. Send for illustrated Famohlot Also Manufacturers of all kinds of IRON AND
                            STEEL WIRE. A Speciality made of TINNED BKOOM WIEE. Plain Talks UPON Such is the title of a Shaker Pamphlet,
                            intending to exhibit, in brief, Shaker Polity and Principles ; being answers to ever-recurring questions
                            concerning The Shakers ; also answering '' What shall I do to be a Shaker?" Cost Price, Five Cents, postage One
                            cent. Address, The Editor of The Shaker Mani- festo. JOHN WHITZEIJEY. Manufacturer of SHAKER BROOMS, Shirley
                            Village, Mass. AGENT 3TOR. "The Shaker"—monthly-60 cts. per annum. "The Divine Afflatus"—10 cts. per copy. "The
                            Shaker's Answer"—6 cts. per copy. "The Divinity of Humanity"-3 cts. per copy. Liberal cLisootirLt in
                                quantities.<pb n="240" id="p32"/> A D VER TISEMENT. Improved Shaker Mangle. This Mangle is very heavy and
                            strongly built; runs smoothly, and performs EXCELLENT WORK AND IS EASILY KEPT IN REPAIR. Even to Laundries
                            already supplied with STEAM CYLINDRICAL MANGLES, This machine is a i/ery necessary addition, as it is more
                            economical. Wo confidently recommend this as the BEST BOX MANGLE IN THE COUNTRY. N. A. BRIGGS, Shaker Village,
                            K. H.<pb n="241" id="p33"/> A D VEBTTSEMENTS. To Our Palsons Everywhere: Anything you desire, or may wish to
                            obtain in the line of BJr.y CfooriM, Carpet, {boys as netl as pirls,) J8.«'a«1.v Warte fcuit«, go to, or send to
                            the Whoixsals & Retail Empoiiica of "\V. M. ^Vliitxioy Co., ALBANY, N. Y. G&WTM! gfaag. aim Oq^
                            SCHENECTADY, N. Y. Tinitrters of Marine, Stationary ttndToriable Steam Enr/ines nnrf hollers. Blutker Broom
                            Handle Laihex, (Ihe Lest Lathe in Marl; t.j Engint* /,„¦ F,nit w,,rk, cutting ami Steaming fc.l, drielng
                            Tlireshiwj Machines, Jc. from 1 horse, in 10 hor.potrer. Stixafor Pr;«!) List. MEDAL MACHINES, BJASS
                            AOSICTJLrTSiL \702SS. fc MlELICIv CO. MANUFACTUKEKS OF Threshing Machines, Horse Powers, Shingle Machine* Ilorsc
                            Forks, Sujkey Horse Rakes, &c. ALBANY, N. Y.. Gardner & Co., Solo Manufacturers &
                            Patentees of CHAIRS AMD CHAIR-SEATS, Railroad-Car Saats, Sattees for Churches, Halls, Etc. OFFICE AXD SALESROOM,
                            376 PEARL ST., NEW YORK. factories, 330,332,334, E. 61st, St.<pb n="242" id="p34"/> AD VERTISEMENTS. I/END
                            HEADER,if you are in any way interested in BEES or HONEY, we will, with pleasure, send you a sample copy of our
                            Monthly "GLEANINGS IN BEE CULTURE.', Simply write your address plainly on a postal card and ADDRESS. A. I. ROOT,
                            Medina, Ohio. (£ f" *«. ff rt nper day at home. Samples worth $5 free 4)0 1U 4*ZtjAddress Stinson & Co.,
                            Portland, Ma TRY SHAKER'S CORBETT'S SARSAPARILLA, For Purifying the Blood; best Medicine at all Seasons. Ask for
                            it at your Druggists. Maynard & Noyes, Boston. BY Wm. a. hinds: This book contains, in brief a succinct
                            account of all the Communities now in America, and is a valuable, almost invaluable accompaniment of the
                            students of moral reform, and political economy. Price 60 cts The Shaker Manifesto for 1878, and American
                            Communities §1.00 GOL| Any worker can make $12 a day at home. Cost'y Outfit free. True & Co., Augusta.
                            Me. GIJLX En«« BUTTEB MAKER. - THECOOLEYCREAMER Raises all the cream the milk contains inside of 10 hours in its
                            greatest perfection, With the Least Amount of Labor. 4®1* The only perfect system of Butter-Making. Send for
                            Circular to Vermont Farm Machine Co. Bellows Falls, Vt. JSndorsed by The Shakers. JglP*Answering advertisement:
                            Please mention The Shaker Manifesto. SPECIAL NOTICES. PKIOELESS DISOOVEKY. A SURE CURE FOR PILES. A. sure cure
                            for the blind, bleeding, itching, and ulcerated piles has been discovered by Dr. William, (an Indian remedy,)
                            called Dr. William's Indian Ointment. A single box has cured the worst old chronic cases of twenty-five and
                            thirty years' standing. No one need suffer five minutes after applying this wonderful soothing medicine.
                            Lotions, instruments and electuaries do more harm than good. William's Ointment supports the tumors, allays the
                            intense itching (particularly at night after getting warm in bed), acts as a poultice, gives instant and
                            painless relief, and is prepared only for Piles and nothing else. Thousands of cured patients attest its
                            virtues, and physicians of all schools pronounce it the greatest contribution to medicine of the age. It matters
                            not how long or severely you have been suffering, you can be cured. Mr. Joseph 1 Ryder, Cleveland, Ohio, writes:
                            I suffered for years with Itching and Ulcerated Piles, tried remedy after remedy advertised, and consulted
                            physicians in Philadelphia, Louisville, Cincinnati, Indianapolis and this city; and spent hundreds of dollars,
                            but found no relief until I obtained a box of Dr. William's Indian Ointment some four months ago, and it has
                            cured me completely. I had a part of the box left which I gave to a friend of mine who had doctored with many
                            physicians, and as a last resort went to the noted Hot Springs, Arkansas, for treatment. He informs me that the
                            Indian Ointment has also cured him of the Piles. It is certainly a wonderful discovery and should be used by the
                            many thousands who are now suffering with that dread disease. 4Eg"-$10.000 Reward will be paid for a more
                            certain remedy. Sold by all Druggists. Dr. G. W. Frazier, sole proprietor, Cleveland, O. DON'T NEGLECT A COUCH.
                            or Cold, when 25 cts will buy a bottle of Dr. Frazier's Cough Syrup at any drug store. It has wrought a complete
                            change in the Cough Medicines, is pleasant as honey and always cures. TO CONSUMPTIVES. 4SKDr. Frazier's Cough
                            Syrup used in connection with Dr. Frazier's Root Bitters will cure consumption. Standard Steam Laundry,
                            Cleveland, O., Oct. 30, '76. Dr. Frazier. Dear Sir: I feel it a duty I owe to suffering humanity to write you.
                            For some time I was sorely afflicted with a cough, raising bad stuff, with every symptom of being a confirmed
                            consumptive. I tried different medicines and cures without finding relief; I also consulted three of our most
                            prominent Cleveland physicians, the last one of which pronounced my case serious, and informed me that I could
                            not live more than a few months. About this time, hearing of your wonderful success, I commenced taking your
                            Syrup in connection with your Root Bitters, and was at once benefited, and after using the medicine some two
                            months I find myself entirely cured. TORENCE DUNN. 48rMr. Dunn again writes, under date of Aug. 4, 1877,—Dr.
                            Frazier, Dear Sir: I endorse your medicines more strongly than ever from the fact that it is now nearly one year
                            since I was cured. My lungs are to-day strong and sound, having no return of the dis- ease. The above Medicines
                            speak for themselves. DR. G. W. FRAZIEIl, Proprietor, Cleveland, O. For sale by all Druggists.<pb n="243"
                                id="p35"/> A D VER TIS EMEN TJS. For Laundries, Hotels, Asylums and other large Institutions.
                            Preferem-eg-iven in Report of Judges at the Centennial Exhibition, Medal and Diploma Awarded. Patented July 23,
                            1877. N. A. Briggs Shaker Village, N. H. AND SMALL NAILS, OP BVBEY SIZE, .A-ISTID VABIETY MADE BY American Tack
                            Co., Fairhaven, Mass. lSFFEL WATER WHEELS. With recent improvements. Prices Greatly Reduced. 7000 in successful
                            operation. HNE NEW PAMPHLET F02 1377. «,cnt free to those interested. James Leffel 8s Co, Springfield, 0. 10Q
                            Liberty St., N. Y. Cifv. $66 a week in jour own town. Terms and $5 outfit free. Address IT. Hallett &
                            Co.,Portland, Mb. JO HIST &. KAtJLBACK, Jr. & CO. WHOLESALE DEALER IN WEST INDIA GOODS AND
                            GROCERIES of all kinds, Of unexceptionable quality and low prices, AT 138 and 13O WATER St., Boston. Special
                            attentionpnid to Teas Spices. DEALER IN TUBS ffe 3QH.OOMS Also, SHAK3BR PAILS. In ordering please mention the
                            Shaker Manifesto. Henry Mayell, 43O, 428, Broadway, Albany, M. Y. Dealer in all kinds of first class Rubbeb
                            Goods—Boots, Shoes, Blankets, Belts, Gossamer Water-proof Clothing, and everything in the Rubber line that can
                            be named or thought of Goods of maximum value at minimum prices. Go to, or write to Mayell's ; and all bargains
                            will be satisfactory. Remember the numbers. SHAKEIi FLANNELS & KNIT GOODS, CORN BROOMS &
                            BRUSHES. Address, N". A. Briggs Shaker Village, N. H.<pb n="244" id="p36"/> f Geo. W.. Prentiss & Co.,
                            HOLYOKE, MASS., MAKTTFACTTTBERS OF IRON WIRE. THE WESTINGHOUSE 'riir«'*hina.ti.icIijik"* & Honte Powers
                            ^rial. I .. Orders solicited for TIJWED BROOM WIRE, quality guaranteed., v 'Threshers.for all .sizes of Horse
                            Powers and Steam,; Lever Powers for 4 to 10 Horse, inwl Endless Chain Powers for 2 and 3 Horses—and Engines from
                            4 to 10 Horse Power. All with late and important improvements. Send for Circular*. ti\(;iioimi: &
                            Schenectady, N. Y. AUTOMATIC Family Knitter. For full particulars and lowest prices for the Best Family Machine
                            send to BiCKFORD Knitting Machine Mfg.Oo. BRATTLEBORO, VT. HENRY CUMMINGS, MANUFACTURER & DEALER IN
                            SHAKER BROOMS, PAILS,TUBS; OLD GRO"WTH PAILS & TUBS a specialty. Also all grades of second growth Pails,
                            Tubs &c. HENEY CUMMINGS, Enfield, N. H. "Please send for price list &c. ' $2. SELF-INKER UCH
                            ARM" Press Size 2x3 ^nches—100 long Printing letters, Ink, Roller, Reglets, Leads, Type Case, Cards, and Outside
                            Case—AMi tor $H. For variety of Larger Presses send 'tamp for Catalogue. "IV. C E£vuu« Agt; X. Mintli St.
                            Pliila. Pa. jgQT'Parties answering advertisements: Will you please mention The Shaker Manifesto? WATER WHEEL
                            FRENCH BURR MILLSTONES, General FLOUR 31131,31, and I»jV3?3DK 3H331.31* Machinery. And full line of mill
                            furnishing. The AMERICAN TURBINE WHEEL produces the best average percentage of any Turbine ever known. Large
                            illustrated catalogue sent free. ADDRESS, STOUT MILLS & TEMPLE, DAYTON,OHIO. FOR THAT RHEUMATISM. Try
                            Dr. Dean's Rheumatic Pills, the old, popular standard and efficacious remedy. Ask for them at your Druggists.
                            MAYNARD& NOYESAgts, BOSTON. % Wo. 5 Beaver Block . Cor, SOUTH PEARL & BEAVER Sts, ALBANY, N. Y.
                            A large, assortment of Watches im(l Spectacles constantly on liand. Hepairiny in all its branches. F1IME.W H.
                            Off-jra ths greatest passiblo at trac HI lirTT tions in Chickering's, GLUE IT Steinway,«fcIItxlncs' PIANOS and
                            KSTEIT OBKM8. Don't fail to ./rite for Catalogues and Prices— Warcrooms, TJao y, US. TC. THE AMERICAN
                        TTXRIBUNTE</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>