<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0201" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18720101" TEIform="date">January 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-8</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME J AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH THE
                        LORD. Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas, Editor.
                        SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., JANUARY, 1872. No. 1. Fiktv Cents per Akntjm.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming millennium" TEIform="index"/>The Coming Millennium</head><p TEIform="p">The Shaker, to its friends of 1872, greeting, with thanks to its friends of 1871, and to the press, by whom it
                            has been received with so much courtesy, and treated with so great tenderness, if not kindness, these are due in
                            an especial manner. We feel that the mission of The Shaker is coincident with that of Jesus and his twelve
                            apostles in the year one. Jesus, when perfected, represented a sphere that was " far above all heavens." The
                            twelve apostles represented the kingdom of heaven upon earth as it culminated in the Pentecostal Church. The
                            condition of the world, to-day, is strictly analagous to what obtained under the Roman empire : The same general
                            expectation of some radical impending change, something that would overturn and supplant existing systems. Then,
                            as now, science dominated over religion; skepticism over theology; inherent abstract rights over organized
                            wrongs. Spiritualism and spiritual manifestations permeated society through and through. A more subtle and
                            powerful spirit, that should effect the long-lookedfor revolution, and the agents through which it would
                            operate, had already been in their midst for a generation; the many knew it not, and the few who did, were
                            opposed and persecuted. The kingdom of heaven, as established within and among the apostles, and in a more
                            expanded form after the death of Jesus, was a condition where good and evil, light and darkness, were mingled
                            together; yet where the good, and true, and right, predominated over their opposites. Jesus, who founded this
                            kingdom, has been worshiped by millions as God, because the race has ever identified the most perfect
                            correspondent of Deity, with which nature or the mundane world furnished it, with God himself. The twelve
                            apostles personated the twelve foundational principles of the Christian system; and they also embodied in their
                            character the fundamental principles of the Jewish dispensation. " Other foundation than these, can no man lay"
                            for the coming millennial order. The past twelve numbers of The Shaker have been devoted to the eluci- dation of
                            the above named principles, and of the history of their effects upon and among mankind. These comprise the
                            mission of Jesus, and of the twelve men whom he has immortalized, by whose means have been effected the
                            revolutionary turnings and overturnings of all human, earthly institutions for the last eighteen centuries, from
                            the year one to 1770. The spirit and principles of the Christ-world, commingled with worldly elements, have
                            hitherto ultimated themselves only in man governments. About the year 1770, another influx from the
                            Christ-world, coming down through the spiritual world, there using as a medium the Pentecostal Church, which was
                            removed from the earth when the compound heathenChristian governments, made its continued existence impossible,
                            except in the disjointed, distorted form of the monastic orders, and in the two witnesses, struggling to
                            preserve the seed of the " kingdom of heaven " on earth, and chanting a continual prayer for its reappearance.
                            In answer to that universal prayer, " the kingdom came" at the time appointed, as demonstrated by Cummings and
                            Shimeall, and thousands of the literary and religious chronologists—the great lights of Christendom—about the
                            year 1770. But this time, the agent unexpectedly proved to be a female, and not the reappearance under the
                            physical resurrection doctrine of the identical man Jesus. Through this female, the dual nature of Diety was
                            revealed, and formed a. proper logical basis for all governments of a dual humanity, in accordance with which
                            seventy pentecostal communities arose in America, being cotemporary with the United States Government. The
                            history of these two governments will run parallel like the history of Esau and his descendants—the Mohammedan
                            powers ; and the history of Jacob and his posterity —the Israelitish powers, or Jewish people. The Shaker, or
                            spiritual order of celi- bacy unites, as was never attempted by the monastic orders, the two powers of human-
                            ity—male and female—in one community, under a parental government of father and mother, as types of the Father
                            and Mother God. The second, or United States Government, or natural order of propagation, will ultimately be
                            fashioned after the pattern of the Mosaic nation in the wilderness, and in their early history in the land of
                            Canaan. The same principles embodied in the Jewish laws respecting property—right to the land, agriculture,
                            dietetics, physiology, and of the sexual relations pertaining to reproduction, and the rights and privileges of
                            woman. The same knowledge and use of spiritualism, as the only legitimate war agent, also as an agent for the
                            discovery and punishment of individual criminals, as well as ungodly nations. Thus will the Millennium be
                            actualized on the earth, by the Christ-spirit acting through the agency or mediumship of the Gentile Pentecostal
                            Church. The prophet " saw the hands of a man under the wings of the cherubim "—the earthly government for the
                            order of propagation subordinate to, and protected by a spiritual order, as the spiritual order will be
                            subordinate to, and protected by the earthly order—individualized identities, like Esau and Jacob ; yet like
                            them brothers, " the elder serving the younger." Esau possessed the physical power, Jacob the spiritual. In the
                            earthly government, the. Lord shall rule in righteousness; for men and women will be equally represented in
                            offices, as in the taxes and burthens. The love of God towards their children, sons and daughters of their own
                            creating, will cause the life elements to be common and free to all. External " wars will cease to the ends of
                            the earth," because the reproductive powers will be under governmental control, for the production of perfect
                            men and women. Hence, the war power will be transferred to the earthly government in the spirit world; as
                            illustrated in the history of Israel. The powers and principles of both orders, as they exist in the spirit
                            world, are seeking to incarnate themselves upon earth, in the Shaker Church and in the United States Government;
                            by the divine Spirit, through the agency of Spiritualism, this will be accomplished, and " the powers of the
                            world to come," are even now working mightily to this end. The talented, but erratic Francis Train, is a
                            spiritual medium for the much abused and down-trodden Irish, who have passed into the spiritual world, in an
                            unsubdued worldly spirit; they seek vengeance on <pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. their enemies in this world;
                            and in a re- bellion of their countrymen, they would stimulate and instigate them to acts of rapine and
                            violence, congenial to their own passions. Victoria Woodhull is a medium of the other sex, for the corresponding
                            mission to Americans. These two, according to their own predictions, are the next presidents of the United
                            States. They will be largely assisted, from the other world to realize and fulfill their own prophecies. At a
                            public dinner, given by the Emperor of Russia, he confessed with the simplicity of a child, what was confirmed
                            by the Empress, and other members of their suite ; that he was influenced by spirits, through the American
                            medium, Home, to emancipate the twenty millions of serfs: and that the spirits helped and sustained him in the
                            accomplishment of the arduous undertaking. Prince Albert and Queen Victoria were spiritualists; and skeptics are
                            calling her crazy, and seeking to dethrone her upon that ground. Lincoln and Stanton were spiritualists, to our
                            personal knowledge; and to the spirits, were due the emancipation of slavery, and the final success of the
                            North. England, to-day, must recognize the power of the spiritual world, and bow before it, by letting her
                            government be fashioned after the "pattern shown in the Mount," or share the fate of France. She has "taken the
                            sword" externally, and is perishing by it. Her priests, for the salvation of her soul; her doctors, for the cure
                            of her body; her lawyers, for the protection of her property; her army and navy, for her defense against her
                            enemies (created by her own wickedness), are eating her up. Her own sons and daughters are her worst enemies,
                            being despoiled of their inherent rights. These, inspired from the unseen world, through its thousands of
                            circles, are enthusiastically demanding that none shall possess who do not help to create. They claim the land
                            as belonging to the English, the Irish, the Scottish, and the Welsh, without distinction of sex. In a word, the
                            time has come for the founding of the spiritual order, in England; and parallel with that, will go forth
                            spiritual agents, that cannot be over-awed, overreached, over-powered, nor checkmated by human authority or
                            subterfuges; " untii the Lord rain righteousness upon" the earthly government of England, foundec upon
                            millennial principles. As before stated, both the earthly anc spiritual orders and governments are now in full,
                            successful operation in the spiritua world; and, unless human beings on earth can overthrow and destory these,
                            the influences therefrom will continue to descend to earth, as " refreshings from the presence of the Lord," and
                            demanding the restitution and restoration of all truth there concentrated, that "God has ever spoken by the
                            mouths of all His holy prophets " among all nations, and among all peoples, since ;he world began ; until every
                            true principle that has been, and every prophecy of good that is to be, shall also be concentrated in ' this
                            generation." And the little Shaker will yet, more than heretofore, become a medium of " the Spirit and the
                            Bride, who say Come; and let him that heareth, say come," and work out their own salvation, by helping to build
                            the temple of the Lord —a Celibate Church on earth, and to establish the millennium among the nations.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility and prayer" TEIform="index"/>Humility and Prayer</head><p TEIform="p">O Heaven .' we seek thy choicest gifts Of matchless worth, and beauty rare— The gifts of sweet humility, and
                            prayer. O, may we walk where these abound, And seek the blessings Bowing there— The joys of true humility, and
                            prayer. All graces pure, may we possess, The spotless robe which ang-els wear— That's framed in deep humility,
                            and prayer! May Heaven's sacred gems adorn The crowrn, which by the cross, we'll bear— Secured by labor, faith
                            and hope—and prayer. Far down in Zion's peaceful vale, Let every child of God repair— There bow in praise,
                            humility, and prayer. United in true Christian love— Joined, heart and hand, we'll gather there, And pour forth,
                            in humility, a prayer, That will ascend, unto the throne Of him, who sits in glory there. To bless all souls,
                            who ask of him, in prayer. O precious gifts ! divinely given, Blest seasons here—foretaste of heaven ! "We'll
                            cherish these with love and care, And trusting in Humility and Prayer.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Emily Smith, Mt. L.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prospective era" TEIform="index"/>The Prospective Era</head><p TEIform="p">The Fatherhood and Motherhood of man, is God; his pristine home is Heaven! Widely strayed and lost from God, man
                            has been wandering in the dark mazes of folly and sin for ages ; his soul sighing, pining, dying. In tender
                            mercy to the wandering children, God hath long since sent forth to man a degree of light, a pole-star (His
                            revealed Will), a compass (conscience), and guide (Christ's example), to lead the wanderers home. But, as on the
                            physical plane, man, when lost, travels in a circle; so, in like manner, man's progress mentally, and especially
                            spiritually, has been circuitous, or, at best, spirally, for unnumberec ages. While reason teaches that the leas
                            fatiguing course in the pursuit of truth anc heaven, is direct, yet, the whole history of man's progress, thus
                            far, shows his travel to have been spirally, as round a cone; and though convinced that the easiest means of
                            ele- vation from a low state of degradation is directly up the even grade of an inclined plane in other words,
                            pursuing directly from one stage of virtue, to another, still more excellent yet man's travel, out of nature's
                            loss, has been undulating; sometimes asscending the hill of redemption, then descending again towards
                            legradation, loss and shame, seeming to weary of direct elevation even in the attainment of )liss. Asa
                            consequence, thus far, the progress of he race in redemption and virtue, has been slow and tedious; but a
                            brighter day is dawrf- ng, and cheered by the rays of its rising sun, et us, by their light, review the past and
                            discover the development of the future weal of lumanity. In man's onward career in redemption the ' Te deum" of
                            the Adamic dispensation has aeen passed. The impressive mellowing tones of the Sacred Anthem of the Noachian
                            period lave died away, having lifted man a little to a laigher level of earthly righteousness. The needful but
                            sober song of Moses, with its Levitical harmonies and stern legalities, is still rolling its echoes back and
                            forth upon the worldly order, yet on the generative plane, giving tone to moral law, and pointing to a higher
                            standard of excellence. While the sweet angelic song of the Lamb (the testimony of Jesus Christ), is heralding
                            its ringing inspirations, and with its trumpet-tongue calling together sin-sick souls to meet with the
                            assemblage of Angels in the Kingdom of God, singing the joyous anthem of " Peace on earth, good will to all
                            nations." Angels in Heaven and saints on earth are chanting the welcome tones of a present salvation from sin,
                            and the soul-thrilling rhapsodies of the Angel-life lived here on earth! While the worshiper at Zion's shrine is
                            filled with prophetic inspirations and heavenly visions of the glory of this prospective era in man's
                            redemption, the multitude err in still lingering in the dispensations of the past, feeding on dried fruits from
                            the ripened harvests of by-gone eras ; hence their religion is powerless for salvation, insipid and uhrefreshing
                            to the soul. While God's increasing work is moving on for the harvesting of the ripened clusters of the vines of
                            the earth (natural families), cutting them off from the generative life, with all its righteousness, and
                            preparing them to become garnered into the kingdom of God. This is the work of the angels, seen by the
                            revelator, John. Let us look to the betokening signs of the swiftly advancing approach of this kingdom, and find
                            an inspiration of encouraging hope; while the Day of the Lord, to the worldly man or to the halting Christian,
                            is a day of darkness and no brightness in it; because such see only by its advent the loss of carnal pleasure
                            and self-will, with all that weds and tethers the soul to an earthly sphere—a worldly life. Jesus said : " Ye
                            can discern the face of the sky, can ye not discern the signs of the times ?" Man's soul and spirit, as well as
                            his physical frame are longing and yearning for their development and redemption from the thraldom of the curse
                            of sin. God hath provided the means to answer this demand; humanity is seeking them, and will enjoy them, and
                            the day of its advent and power is dawning; this is the prophecy written on all the phases of man's progress
                            that have been passed through, and now borne on the foreheads of the van-guard of human redemption. The rapid
                            strides of man's modern progress 2 <pb n="3" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. in science and art, ministering to the
                            development of physical and mental comfort, is prophetic of a parallel rapidity of the march of spiritual
                            progress to satisfy the yearning and and pressing demands of the soul. Revealed religion has been given of God
                            to bring man's soul home to its Creator; yet, like every gift from God to man, it has been subjected to
                            adultery! Everything that man hath touched he hath adulterated! But one of the paean strains of the Mosaic song
                            was : " Thou shalt not commit adultery j" and our Saviour hath come to fulfill that law. Let the Children of
                            Zion be glad, for there is a growing evidence of the redemption of his pledge! The adulterated religions of
                            human production, numbered by hundreds, have, one after another, perished from the view; and the remnant are
                            rapidly coming into disrepute, because of their want of salt. But, in them all, there have been elements of
                            salvation which will all be conserved by that religion of full and free salvation sounded forth in the " Song of
                            the Lamb" on Mount Zion! The scientific discoveries and developments of the day, as the electric telegraph,
                            steam locomotion, etc., are all sympathetically linking the kingdoms of the earth ; and their powers are yet to
                            be felt spiritually, as really as now, physically and mentally; for they are giving character and tone to mind,
                            and through mind to the soul. They are developing a universal interest in human prosperity not bounded by
                            national caste, color nor education. They are contributing to the development of a sensitiveness of spiritual
                            feeling—a quickness of receptivity of goodness. The angels of God are pouring out an inspiration that will
                            fledge the wings of the soul, and render it impatient of a plodding pace in the work of redemption from sin; and
                            soon the progressive march of religious truth and power will be seen moving with an electric speed to satisfy
                            the quickened soul's demands. It is the prophetic promise of the coming era. The progressing man is not, will
                            not, cannot be satisfied with a religion that leaves the soul unfitted for Heaven. The adulteration of religion
                            has been so great that even the element of spirituality has been drained from its cup. The manifestations of
                            spiritualism in these prophetic days throughout the world, is the usher of a new soul-life into humanity—a life
                            in God. And although in its varied phases of progress, human folly and sin are manifest also, discovering that
                            adultery hath likewise set her hostile plough into the fruitful soil, yet angels are sing- ing the song of Moses
                            from Sinai; and, quickened with gospel fire from the heavenly altar, are ringing out: " Thou shalt not commit
                            adultery;" and many souls will hear and heed its heavenly trumpet. There is a spiritual baptism of heavenly
                            fire, a spiritual life in the consumption and death of a carnal life, now kindling in the elements of religious
                            power, that is destined to consume the world of iniquitous adultery, the birth of the creations of fallen man !
                            Its advent is near ai hand; it is the power of the coming day of the Lord, now speedily approaching. This
                            destruction of the world—the corrupted nature of man by the fire of the cross of Christ, is the "end of the
                            world," predicted liy our Lord and Saviour; it is the prophetic boon of heavenly jromise, clearing the way for
                            the building of he kingdom of God on earth, as his will is done in Heaven; while the consumption of ;he literal
                            earth by elemental fire, as the grand climax of the judgment day, is an invention of luman theology never
                            recognized by the counsels of God. But, in the judgment day of the Lord, now dawning, " Light is sown for the
                            righteous;" peace for the pure in heart; joy and rejoicing at the judgment throne for the souls whose books of
                            life by themselves are opened to God's witnesses, by an honest confession of every sin, and whose repentance is
                            witnessed by the fact that they go forth to duty in life, and " sin no more." The theology of man's adulterated
                            spiritualism hath broken down the barriers between sin and righteousness, hell and heaven, and reduced to one
                            common level of justification the sinner and the saint; the common and enormous evils of humanity, with the most
                            exalted righteousness, purity and godliness manifest in human life; but God's law to man has been operating to
                            separate to Himself all souls who would obey his voice through his anointed teachers, and come away from the
                            sinful state of man; and God's work is not to be thwarted by an avalanche of human theology, affirming that "
                            Whatever is, is right," making God the author of sin ! God recognizes sin in the human family, and man as the
                            sinner; and the subject of suffering for it, is not himself, nor some foreign devil; but the devil of man's own
                            erring self-will! And the light of the day of God now dawning, discovers a clean separation between him who
                            serveth God, and him that serveth him not; and a wide distance between the world of wickedness, and the kidgdom
                            of God and its righteousness ! It discovers a real, veritable hell; and, though not the theological lake of fire
                            and brimstone, yet a state of soul- sufferings and agonies, of disobedient and rebellious sinners, grievous to
                            contemplate, and terrible to endure ! It reveals a veritable heaven, and that upon earth, too, the state and
                            dwelling place of the pure in heart, who crucify the nature of sin by rigid self-denial, and sacrifice sinful
                            pleasures for the higher joys of immortal life. The inspirations of "the song of the Lamb" are leading forth a
                            people out from the worldly plane of generation and lust; separating them from the elements of carnal life, an
                            soul death, to be, not only God's people, but God's pecnliar people, zealous of good works; the objects of his
                            peculiar favor and blessing; not the bounties of partiality, but the just rewards of righteousness and godly
                            obedience. These are they who stand with the Lamb on Mount Z ion, clad in white robes—the righteousness of
                            saints. These are arisen with Christ from the sink of human corruption by following the Lamb whithersoever he
                            goeth; these are the redeemed from among men, on the generative plane, and dwell in the kingdom of God; in one
                            perpetual, glorious day—the day of the Lord Almighty—whose sun of righteousnes and heavenly light and glory
                            shall set no more forever !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earth-growth—soul-progress" TEIform="index"/>Earth-Growth—-Soul-Progress</head><p TEIform="p">"God formed man of the dust of the around, and ireathed into his nostrils the breath of life, and man ocame a
                            living tiOlll." Gen. iii. 8. It has been, to some, mysterious, when people of strong minds dispute the scripture
                            which says; God formed men of earth, and the great book of nature proves it. Our race, animals of every grade,
                            and vegetables of every species, are simply dust. Taking a view of the decorations of royalty, the pride of
                            palaces and cities, endless forms of fancy and fashion, heaps of gold in a thousand coffers, with all things
                            terrestrial which man becomes wedded to, " dust they are and unto dust they return." When man enters wedlock, by
                            labor and care he may surround himself and his house- hold with treasures and comforts, but they return to dust.
                            When he plants the germ for another existence, we must remember it was created by a natural law fashioned from
                            his subsistence. The mother grows that germ into infant maturity on the subsistence she draws from the same
                            great reservoir through all the changes of gestation. Thus, by a changeless law, she clothes it, strengthens it,
                            and forms it into a being which, like Adam the first, is created from the dust. Thus all nature declares that
                            God not only formed the first man of the dust, but his whole race by generations are drawn from the dust as he
                            wras. We may also easily discern that unborn millions icithout form still lay in the dust waiting to be called
                            forth, to be constructed and reconstructed by natural law into living specimens of individuality. When an infant
                            is forming into life, God, through the agency of a mother, breathes life into it, till it comes into the world
                            and can do so for itself; then it gradually becomes a conscious or living soul, as dark, natural and depraved as
                            the beings who gave it existence. God is in the very breath that quickens the infant into life, as it did Adam,
                            and that breath finally inspires all to feel that they, too, become living souls. The poor Indian and the
                            Scriptures declare that God is in the atmosphere or wind, and they are right; for our first parents said: " We
                            heard the voice of the Lord God, walking (among the trees of) the garden in the cool (margin or wind) of the
                            day." From that period till now, the man of earth receives his revelations through nature's elements. The
                            skeptic, when raising his understanding no higher than the foregoing, rests at ease in Infidelity. But there is
                            a brighter page in the chapter. Man in his male and female capacity is emphatically the tree of the knowledge of
                            good and evil. The germs for the whole race of Adam, body and soul, were placed in the earth by an all-wise
                            Creator, to come out from the lowest earth-state, and arise to the highest heavenly state, that they might pass
                            through all changing scenes and study all truth and law, from the lowest to the highest known to men and angels.
                            In his first lessons he can comprehend natural law, morals, intellectual science; and with the intuition of a
                            seer can feel immortality struggling within him. Paul, under heaven's own inspiration, gives us the key to
                            unlock the formation of the first 3 <pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. heavenly world we are to enter, when he says
                            : " The invisible things of God are clearly seen, being understood by the things which are made." Or, in other
                            words, the next higher state, which to the earthly man is invisible, is mapped out and fashioned like this. This
                            being the infant; that, the higher school of knowledge. Ministering angels reach down from thence to help all,
                            who in this world cry for assistance. From this invisible source, sages, bards, seers and just men receive
                            divine illuminations. Prophets, apostles, witnesses and leading messengers in God's orders, from age to age,
                            have been privileged often to stand face to face with higher, more advanced spirits from the better land. These
                            messengers of progressive truth, from regions of light, consolidated into heavenly form, have given to better
                            men and women, beautiful revelations of priceless value to advance and raise up the race. God's suffering
                            children, through all ages, have joined hands with these messengers, and have been helped up step by step 'till
                            they have with Abraham caught a view of the holier city which hath foundations; and as Daniel declared : " Many
                            of those that sleep in the dust of the earth shall awake," and arise to a holier resurrection by these heavenly
                            visitations.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Leonard</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social life" TEIform="index"/>Social Life</head><p TEIform="p">A large number of persons who have visited Shaker Societies during past years, as well as the present season,
                            have written lengthy articles, in which, from their own stand-point, they have striven to delineate the mode of
                            worship, manners, habits, and life of the Shaker fraternity. Some of high intellectual culture, and progressed
                            spiritual ideas, have been candid in their statements, and as far as they had time and opportunity to gain
                            correct information, were truthful and just, as historians. Others, less candid and more unprogressed, have
                            failed to appreciate our efforts in the work of moral and spiritual reform, and have sought, more to please the
                            fancy of the novel-loving multitude, and pander to the tastes of the fashionable elite of the community, rather
                            than to do justice to their own better feelings, or to those whom they ignorantly, if not willfully undertake to
                            represent. But we observe, as old theologies give place to reason, and sectarian prejudice disappears, there is
                            not much controversy between the Shaker who reasons, and those whom reason is shaking. Thanks to the powers
                            above—the good ministering angels, who penetrate with their candle of truth many a darkened chamber, arousing
                            the latent energies of souls, filling them with neAV light and kindling a fire that will eventually burn up the
                            world in them. As the spiritual life of the believers is hid from the natural, superficial observer, so also is
                            their social life a paradox, for both are closely allied, and belong together. Tt remains for those who have
                            participated in the benefits of this social, communistic life—who have performed the duties pertaining thereto,
                            and who, by practical experience, know its worth, to speak concerning it. Our social interests demand that we
                            build each other up in our most holy faith; that we labor in spirit for divine power, for light and truth from
                            on high, for new life, which bids us lay aside the death-garments of sin and heed the spirjt's voice that calls
                            : " Come forth !" Also, to devote our physical strength, unselfishly to build up the new earth upon which the
                            heavens must rest. " Hands to work and hearts to God," is our motto. This consecrated labor is sacred; whatever
                            is done, should be done with the view of honoring God, having reference to the upbuilding of his work, and
                            promoting his cause in the earth, by forming a humanitarian home—a home for the body and the soul. Holiness unto
                            the Lord is the inscription which everything should bear in the saint's home. The benefits derived from this
                            social relation are many; friendships are formed that are true and lasting. In prosperity and adversity, in
                            sickness and health they never fail. Those who are devoted to true principles, are also devoted to those who
                            love and abide in those principles ; and they are as guiding stars through the journey of life, shining the most
                            brilliantly when the storms of lite are severest. Thus do we reap, by the relinquishment of the natural
                            relationships of earth, a higher and more enduring substance of love, emanating from a fountain that is never
                            dry; for from thence floweth "the river whose waters maketh glad." Some view the self-denying Shaker's home as
                            drear and lonely, filled with disappointment; just as though the greatest amount of happiness is derived from
                            self-indulgence! When, in reality, that is the greatest cause of misery; and the source to which inharmony,
                            unrest and sorrow may be traced. Carnal or unchristian pleasures find no place in the social life of the
                            Shakers. Many infer, from the fact, that as the marriage relation does not exist on the plane where we have
                            chosen to dwell, every enjoyment, intellectual and social, is abolished. This is a very natural and unspiritual
                            conclusion. We not only sing, " I want to be an angel," but we are working out the Angel character, so that we
                            may sing and act as do the Angels—live as they live, and we find no sadness in it—it is real pleasure! Social
                            life among the Shakers is free and broad, bounded only by the law of chastity, which is not bondage, but freedom
                            to those who from true principle seek the higher life on a spiritual plane. It is not strange that Celibates
                            among the Shakers to-day, should be ranked with Celibates of the past, who were necessitated, in order to keep
                            their vows of chastity, to seclude themselves in some recluse of the mountain, lonely cave, or gather within the
                            cloistered walls of a monastery, wearing sad countenances —fearing to smile, lest some unhallowed influence
                            should creep over them. Not so with those whom resurrection power has baptized, and lifted up from the natural
                            into the spiritual order. Innocence and simplicity form the credentials to this new spiritual home, as truly as
                            to the desired, future home in the spirit spheres. Mutual condescension supports, and gives impetus to healthy
                            action in the brotherhood and sisterhood, and we often feel that all of God's unperverted creation rejoices with
                            us in j this pure, harmonial home. The birds chaunt :heir musical lays, the mountains break forth mto singing,
                            and the little hills rejoice on every mde. The heavenly messengers, who guide and guard this goodly heritage,
                            are seen " leaping upon the mountains, skipping upon the hills," and we fear not to leap and skip with them. "
                            O, for a thousand tongues to sing Our great Redeemer's praise."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White, Mt. L.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Animadversive" TEIform="index"/>ANIMADVERSIVE</head><p TEIform="p">Our leader, in Sept. No. 1871. has been the subject of much valuable criticism ; our object being1 therein, to
                            urge the necessity of worshiping the Christ-principle, and not the person of Jesus; and to worship this
                            principle in whom, and wherever it is manifested. The critics have almost invariably concluded, with us, that
                            Jemawai not, but hecame'the Christ—the first born of many Christs—our exampler; and Saviour only, as we follow
                            his example. The following ' 'child of promise,1' from The AmyjSpiritualist, bearing on the same subject, is
                            from the pen of that exalted spiritualist, J. M. Peebles.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus a sinner!" TEIform="index"/>Jesus a Sinner!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Religions originating in the past—all more or less ideal—rest upon the testimonies of tradi- tion. The credulous
                            are the most devoted. In the ratio that knowledge increases, faith di- minishes. Those who know the most believe
                            the least. The conflict of the ages is upon us. The dead, stoutly refusing to bury its dead, the mouldy
                            yesterdays are in close battle array with the vigorous, out-pushing to-days. God or no God, Jesus or no Jesus,
                            immortality or a dreamless nonentity—which ? This weird drama, involving the political, social and religious, is
                            becoming deeply interesting. The tendency js towards the utilitarian. This speaking present, bristling "whys"
                            and insisting upon proof, demands the practical and substantial. All successful religious movements must poise
                            themselves upon principles and point to facts—well-authenticated facts, as well as appeal to reason and
                            sentiment. Men generally cultivate the reasoning and women the emotional side of religion. Right balance evolves
                            high moral power. Jesus, a gentle, beautiful and womanly man, was a religious Jew. All religious S}'stems of the
                            past had their sacraments. Baptism in some form has ever been considered a sacrament. That distinguished Avriter
                            upon "religious beliefs," S. Baring Gould, M. A., says: "Baptismal ceremonials include all purifications. The
                            idea that man is held back from perfect union with God by his imperfection, uncleanness, sin, is Avidely
                            diffused and manifests its existence by water, blood and fire baptisms." The waters of the Ganges were believed
                            to have a purifying effect. Under its rippling surface old and young were plunged. In Egypt, proud of her Nile,
                            the dead were washed from their sins by Osiris; and accordingly, upon Sarchophagi, Osiris is represented pouring
                            water upon candidates in a kneeling posture, just as they enter the land of shades. The Zend ceremonials of the
                            Persians abound in the uses of baptismal waters to wash away sin. " Every purification," said Servius, " is made
                            either with water, or with fire, or with air." Paul speaks of Israel as having been " baptized in the cloud and
                            in the sea." Even the Romans practiced the rite of baptism; and Juvenal criticised and satirized those who
                            sought to 4 <pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 5 " wash away their sins by dipping their heads thrice in the Tiber."
                            Jesus, a Palestinian Hebrew, born subject to the requirements of the Mosaic law, must needs be baptized for
                            purification and the washing away of sin, according to the Israelitish understanding of the ordinance. But, if
                            he was not a sinner, why should he have submitted to baptism by wrater ? Matthew says : " Then went out to him
                            Jerusalem, and all Judea, and all the region round about Jordan, and were baptized of him in Jordan, confessing
                            their sins." Mark assures us that, " John preached the baptism of repentance for the remission of sins." And in
                            this wilderness John baptized Jesus in Jordan. Therefore, as baptism'was understood to be the " washing awa}r of
                            sin," it is clear that Jesus was a sinner! Nothing upon theological grounds could be more absurd than the
                            baptism of a saint. Sinners, and sinners alone, were called upon to repent and submit to baptismal
                            purifications, or the washing away of sins. Many scriptural passages besides those re- cording the impulsive "
                            scourging of the moneychangers," and the rude " cursing of the figtree," point to the imperfections and sins of
                            Jesus. The apostolic assurance that he should " come the second time without sin unto salvation," has some
                            reference, at least, to his first coming as the " child that grew and waxed strong"—the child both of promise
                            and prenatal tendencies. " Call not them me good," said the Nazarene, " none is good but one, and that is God."
                            Good and evil are rclationally opposite, evil being synonymous with imperfection and sin. The New Testament
                            further declares that Jesus " learned obedience by the things he suffered." Obedience is the most effectually
                            learned by disobedience. The child learns to keep the finger from the candle by first burning it. The suffering
                            consequent upon violated law, is teaching both severe and sound. Some can seemingly learn in no o:her school. "
                            He was made perfect," writes an apostle, "through suffering." The phrase "made perfect," implies previous
                            imperfection, and imperfection is sin. lie was also called " the first begotten from the dead ;" but how
                            begotten from the dead unless himself " once dead in trespasses and sins ?" From the 'recorded textual teachings
                            that Jesus refused to be called "good;" that he scourged the money-changers ; that he cursed a fig-tree; that he
                            learned obedience; that he was made perfect; that he went to John to be baptized of him in Jordan, as did other
                            Sj'rian sinners from Jerusalem and all Judea, '* confessing their sins "; there is no other legitimate inference
                            than that he was a sinner—our elder brother and fellow-sinner, Jesus, "touched with our infirmities!" Mark
                            well—we have been treating of Joshua, the carpenter's son, whose name, when Grecianized, became Jesus. Not a
                            word have we written of Jesus Christ. This opens a new chapter. The word Christ signifies the Messi- anic, the
                            anointed, the consecrated. Christ, or the Christ principle, is divine. After Jesus was baptized, confessing his
                            sins, the " heavens were opened" and the Christ spirit from the heaven of the Christ angels, descended upon him,
                            and a voice came saying, " this is my be- loved Son, in whom I am well pleased." Now we have Jesus Christ "our
                            cxampler," who ministered true love and sympathy. The sermon on the Mount stands out unequaled. Its burden is
                            blessings; its inspirations love. To love those who love us is simply reciprocity, and may be prompted alone by
                            policy. But to love our enemies—to love and do good to those who hate us, is principle, is Christ-like. Thanks,
                            then, be unto Christ, who giveth us the victory.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's will be done" TEIform="index"/>God's Will be Done</head><p TEIform="p">Say to the torrent : "Stay thou on the hill !" The torrent replies : " I'm obeying God's will." Say to the
                            rivulet, murmuring by : " Be still for a moment!" and it will reply : " I must not, I will not, I cannot be
                            still, '¦ I must be in motion, and doing God's will!" Say to the sunbeam : ' 'Withdraw thy bright ray '"' The
                            sunbeam replies : " God's laws, I obey." Then sa}* to the whirlwind, uprooting the trees— To the hurricane
                            raging, or the mild, whispering breeze— To the river, the lake, or the ocean : " Be still!" Their response is
                            forthcoming: "We are doing God's will I" To the tear, as it wells from the grief-stricken heart— Or, with joy
                            overflows, as rich treasures impart— How idle, how needless, how fruitless and vain, To say to that tear : "
                            Return thou again I" That tear, in the language of heaven, will say: " Created I was, God's laws to obey." The
                            vitals, which, panting for the life-giving air— The heart with its throbbings, and the sigh of despair; The deep
                            pangs of remorse on the guilt-laden soul— How vain the endeavor, these things to control ! Those pangs, and
                            those vitals—that heart and that sigh, In emphatic language, will surely reply : " Unyielding obedience, by
                            night and by day, " To the mandates of God, we are taught, and obey!" From the smallest of insects, revealed to
                            our sight; Or the greatest of angels, in power and might— Or the earth in her orbit, the sun, moon or stars, Or
                            great Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus or Mars— All matter, all being, all spirit shall say: " Forever the mandates of
                            God we obey!" Then how foolish, self-righteous, irreverent in man, To think, in his wisdom, to better the plan !
                            Bather learn to be humble, to love and to pray— The laws of his Maker to know, and obey— To feel it his duty,
                            his privilege, his shrineTo say: " Thy will. Father, be done, and not mine !''</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frost, E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. Frost</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progression" TEIform="index"/>Progression</head><p TEIform="p">What does this word mean ? It means change from a lower to a higher condition. Politically, it means to leave
                            behind old party issues and join hands with those who are the most advanced in the great principles of reform;
                            and were we to predict, we would say that the party destined to rule America is that party who are the most
                            progressive, and that party will yet be made up of the most progressive of all parties,without regard to sex or
                            color. Progression is the spirit of the age and order of the day—to advance forward is the watchword !
                            Theologically, it means to leave behind old stereotyped creeds of false religions, which had their origin in the
                            dark ages, and which stand directly opposed to the increase of light and truth, which are dawning upon the
                            earth. It means, that when we have considered the truth and meaning of any proposition, however new, if it tends
                            to purity and is accompanied with the evidence and accords with our reason and highest convictions of right, we
                            should implicitly believe and obey, however contrary it may be to our former opinion or that of others. Morally^
                            it means to leave behind all bad habits, lying, fault-finding, back-biting, evil speaking one of another; all
                            dander, proceeding from envy, should be laid aside. " Thou shalt not bear false witness against they neighbor "
                            was a command in the Jewish decalogue, and should not be violated by those calling themselves Christians.
                            Spiritually, it means resurrection—a rising out of the flesh into the spirit; out of the earthly into the
                            heavenly ; out of darkness into light; out of ignorance into knowledge; out of the rudirnental into the angel
                            order; out of persons into principles ; out of the human into the divine; out of malice and hatred into charity
                            and love; out of sin and selfishness into a life of purity and holiness. Just in proportion as these principles
                            are carried out practically, mankind will progress into one universal brotherhood and an enduring peace. This is
                            what we call progression in the right direction.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. Prescott</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What do we worship?" TEIform="index"/>What do We Worship ?</head><p TEIform="p">Editor of " The Shaker :" My Esteemed Brother ik Christian Fellowship :—Recently, while re-reading the editorial
                            in the September number of The Shaker, in which the question is put, " Which shall we worship, persons or
                            principles ?" I fell into the following train of thought concerning worship : If we ask, What is worship ? the
                            answer would undoubtedly be : Giving the heart's strongest affections to some object earthly or heavenly, human
                            or divine. The element of worship is inherent in every human being. Objects of worship are many and varied, from
                            savageism to saintism. The pen of the historian has made a pathway up through a labyrinth of strange experiences
                            during the ages past; and aided by the reflex of present revelation, natural and spiritual, we are enabled to go
                            back to our antecedents, and learn somewhat of their status, habits of life, and modes of thought, and thereby
                            can measure the discreet degrees of growth, from point to point, or from cycle to cycle, in human progress. It
                            is said that " God created the heavens and the earth, the sea and the dry land," and gave his decrees concerning
                            them, and pronounced all very good as they came from his hand. " The heavens declare the glory of God, and the
                            firmament showcth his handiwork," sang the sweet psalmist of Israel, while he called upon the sun. moon and
                            stars, the hills and mountains, rivers and streams, birds of the air, the fishes of the sea, and the beasts of
                            the field, to praise God, all of which, in their turn, have been deified and worshiped by man. Is what we call
                            idol-worship, whether in the form of a molten calf, an image, sculptured from the rock, the sacred beasts and
                            birds, or the sun and his satellites, the grossest form of worship ? Many of the heathen Gods were, without
                            doubt, only symbols to the worshiper, pointing to a higher divinity; we will call them materialistic worshipers.
                            And, inasmuch as God pronounced the matter good which they afterwards converted into genii, perhaps it is not so
                            much wonder after all that they fell into error and displaced what God had put into <pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE
                            SHA.KER order, and made confusion in the elements, just as thousands of ignorant, undeveloped children have
                            done, who did not comprehend their parents' designs. It appears to me, that whatever uplifts the spirit above
                            the sensuous plane of thoughts and action most effectually, is the most worthy of the heart's affections; and
                            whatever leads to sensuality and those passions which God did not create, and never pronounced good, which are
                            fed and strengthened from the hells beneath, should be the most abhorrent to an intelligent, human soul. Some
                            individuals are constitutionally more devotional than others ; thus it is with nations; but, taken as a whole,
                            we are all worshipers in some form. Worship is a component part of our being; and all have an ideal god or gods,
                            before whom to bow and pay homage. Not the lowest worship is that which "sees God in clouds and hears Him in the
                            winds." In this enlightened age and nation, where there is so much freedom, expansion of thought, and religious
                            culture, would we not spurn the idea of making brazen images for worship ? And yet are there no sculptured works
                            of art extant to-day, which are not only admired but worshiped ? If the knee does not bend before them, the
                            affections are placed upon them. How many, in our own time, consecrate their lives and give their power unto the
                            god of war, and seek to satiate their ambitious desires by becoming heroes in battle ! and with hands yet
                            dripping in the blood of those who were innocent of crime, and had never done an injury to them or their
                            country, but who were forced to the cannon's mouth by the cruel mandates of the war-power—how such will exult in
                            their conquests, and the people throughout the length and breadth of the land, sing praises to them, and do them
                            great honor! Where is the Christian's God while all this is being enacted ? Do we say that antagonistic elements
                            have so convulsed the ruling powers of earth, that this is mercj^'s means to establish justice and equity in the
                            land; and that such mighty upheavings and earth-throes are for the purification of the people ? Alas for
                            humanity's redemption, if it can only be wrought out by the sword! Again: Is not fashion the great Moloch of the
                            day ? and at his altar do not all, from the prince to the peasant, bow the knee and worship ? Is not honesty,
                            chastitj^, and integrity sacrificed there ? No matter how absurd and unphilosophical the fashion may be, those
                            who are not found in it are contemned; and, rather than endure the scorn of those who revel in luxury and
                            wealth, and crush with the weight of public opinion, they sell their virtue and go down to the chambers of
                            death! And while the god of war and the goddess of fashion are so faithfully served,* the fires of sensuality
                            will never be extinguished ; the hells will be supplied with plenty of fuel to keep them burning! But while we
                            look with deep pity upon those who, instead of standing in moral rectitude, on middle ground between the higher
                            and lower spheres, are descending downward below " the beasts that perish," we look with joy and hope upon a
                            large band of earnest laborers in the field of moral reform and spiritual progress, who are putting forth their
                            best energies to better the condition of humanity. The hosts, who inhabit the spirit realms, are marshaling
                            their armies, and preparing to do battle on the higher plane of spiritual truth ; not with carnal weapons will
                            they be found fighting, yet by the aid of spiritual power they will conquer. Ascending scales are already placed
                            by the united effort of men and angels, which reach from earth to heaven. Thousands of hands and hearts are
                            reaching up to angel spheres, crying: "Give us food that perisheth not; clothe us with robes such as angels
                            wear, even virgin purity, at the expense of all those worldly lusts which war against the soul's peace, which
                            have myriads of worshipers." While they reach upward, God's ministers of love are reaching down to clasp their
                            hands and lift them up to higher and still higher degrees on the upward scale; that they also may in turn become
                            ministers of saving power and grace to other souls ; and as they rise into the etherial and divine elements, the
                            clearer and more perfect their vision becomes, and the easier it is to comprehend the great Cause of all causes,
                            who dwells in the most interior heaven of all heavens, and is the central sun from which all light and truth
                            radiate and to which all converge, there the true God is worshiped in spirit and in truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Doolittle</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly love" TEIform="index"/>Heavenly Love</head><p TEIform="p">When man woke to life, from the plastic clay, he was but animal; when God breathed into his nostrils the breath
                            of love, he became a living soul. Without love, man would have been a savage, and the earth a wilderness.
                            Unrestrained by its benign influence, his bad passions would have become lawless depradations upon earth, and
                            the harvest of death, through man, would have kept pace with the harvest of life through his Creator. But, thank
                            God for the gift of His spirit of love, to soothe and restrain the perverse instincts of man's nature. As the
                            planets, with all their fearful velocity and awful momentum, are yet held, by the silent force of the sun's
                            attraction, within the path marked out for them by Deity, so with the bad passions of man; they are subject to
                            the law of love, and, however wide the sphere of their departure, they cannot resist her influence, and will
                            yield, even at their aphelion, to the omnipotence of her control. In the physical universe the law of gravity is
                            not more illimitable in its empire, nor more universal in its controlling influence, than the law of love in the
                            universe of sentient existences. Wherever being is, or space unfolds, There love exists, inspires, controls.
                            When the morning stars sang together for joy, love was there, as she will be, when their requiem is sung—ruler
                            of the spheres. All that God has ever made, loves and does him full reverence, save only man. Love is man's only
                            entirely unselfish attribute. He may be honest from policy; benevolent for the relief of unpleasant sensations
                            that wretchedness awakens ; beneficent for the glory following it; prayerful that he may avert hell, or purchase
                            Heaven; but to love and cherish his fellow man as himself, is to be more than human—this is divine. Love is a
                            true Mend that never forsakes us while God is with us. When our horizon is overshadowed with darkness, there
                            will love be to give each cloud a silver lining. Love with us, our star of hope shall never set, nor our skies
                            ever be without the bow of promise! Whose love rules, the skies are all serene; with moon and stars brightly
                            shining, as the greater and lesser angels that proclaim the glory of God. When hate usurps, then fierce winds,
                            dread thunders, red lightnings flashing, hold fearful revelry. Love is day, bright, beautiful; hate is night,
                            chaotic, fearful; love is life, glorious, immortal; hate is death, impenitent, terrible; love is the tropic with
                            its balmy breezes, spicy groves, sparkling fountains, singing birds and golden skies ; hate is the poles with
                            their icebergs and frozen solitudes, where the sun never rises, nor darkness ever sets. To love only those that
                            love us, our fathers, mothers, sisters, brothers, sons, daughters and friends, is purely selfish, and wholly
                            human; to recognize all mankind as our brotherhood, is Godlike; the one is the genial warmth oi the domestic
                            fireside, diffusing cheer and solace to ourself, family and friends; the other the sun— fit emblem of its
                            Creator—dispersing light and heat to cheer and solace the whole human race. To love those only who are lovely or
                            admirable, is equally unchristian. We must love all, and most especially those who would most profit by our
                            love. Wherever love will encourage the timid or reclaim the backslider, warm the cold, or melt the stony heart,
                            humanize the savage, or christianize the moralist, there is the place, then is the time, and those are the
                            proper objects of our love. Love is the mightiest of all magicians. At her touch the lion becomes a lamb; the
                            stubborn rock gushes with sweet waters; the dumb speak; the deaf hear; the blind see; the desert buds and
                            blossoms an oasis of beaut}--, and man and angels rejoice that Jesus died not in vain. God made happiness, and
                            the only conditions on which it is attainable; and man might as well attempt to stay the comet in its flight, as
                            to attain happiness on any other terms. God's law of happiness is love. Waken the illustrious tenants of the
                            tombs; the renowned lawgivers ; the all-conquering heroes; all who Avorshiped at the temple of fame, and they
                            will tell us that the dazzling heights they had attained above their fellow men, only enabled them to observe,
                            the more conspicuously, the road to happiness they had so vainly sought, winding through lowly valleys down
                            beneath their feet. They had toiled from youth to age for fame as the most certain means of happiness, and died
                            broken hearted, that they had lived in vain—in vain because they had only learned how to use, not love their
                            fellow men. Their dearly-bought fame, like their shadows, followed them only to the tomb, and disappointment is
                            the only epitaph upon their monuments that the touch of time has not obliterated! Love has a magnetic atmosphere
                            of its own, that attracts to itself everything good and pure, and repels everything unholy and impure. In the
                            presence of one filled with pure, heavenly love, we cannot but feel its inspiration, and become better by its
                            influence. <pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKIER. 7 Jesus did not convert his followers by his eloquence, but won them
                            by his love. When he spoke to them, with the force of reason, of their lost condition, they only feared him;
                            when he spoke to them with the power of love, they adored him. In the ministry to his fellows, love is the only
                            agency confided to man that is irresistible in its force, and infallible in its operation upon the human heart.
                            Armed with this, he goes forth a conqueror, and doubts flee before him as darkness before the rising sun. Like
                            caloric and electricity, love permeates all things—no heart so hard but it will penetrate—no spirit so stubborn
                            but it will subdue. Steel and gunpowder may kill the body, but cannot harm the soul; they may subjugate, but
                            cannot reform; they may afflict, but love is the only power that can save the world. If we would that our
                            pathway'' through this world be one of pleasantness and peace; that our every pulse shall throb with joy; that
                            all the golden hours that may come to us here shall be laden with happiness; if we would that our eyes be opened
                            that we may see, and our ears unstopped that we may hear the angels of light, as they sing the songs of the
                            redeemed around the throne of God, then let pure, heavenly love be and abide with us, and become our guiding
                            star to the better land—;from the spheres of the lustful and unregenerate.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. Leggett</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love to God" TEIform="index"/>Love to God</head><p TEIform="p">"With all thy heart." Love is natural to the human heart. Extremely difficult is it, if not impossible, to find
                            an individual that does not cherish affection for some person or thing. It matters not into what paths of error
                            and sin one has strayed, there is still in the inmost soul a spot that is capable of being affected by the
                            sweeter emotions. Is it necessary to refer to more than one example to prove this statement ? Can the gall of
                            hatred be more intense in bitterness than that engendered by religious bigotry ? And yet, when indulged in to
                            its utmost limit, its innocent victim recognized, by his prayer for the forgiveness of his murderers, pleading
                            their capacity for something infinitely better. Love is as varied in its kinds as the individuals who exercise
                            it, and of every possible degree. How strong is the affection of some mothers for their children! They are
                            ready, at all times, to sacrifice their own lives for the welfare of such. But in others how weak the tie that
                            binds them to their offspring! What indifference to their welfare, if not positive aversion towards them! And
                            yet these same parents will exhibit an enthusiastic admiration of a dress, a flower, or a piece of music. It is
                            said the celebrated Madame de Stael could pass through a country of the most enchanting natural scenery, without
                            being attracted in the least by its loveliness. And yet she was a woman of wonderful natural endowments, and of
                            great culture. She possessed a love of the beautiful, but it Was that beauty which is dis- played in man rather
                            than that which is without him. Intellect possessed charms for her that external nature did not; and she could
                            be enthusiastic over that which pertained to hu- manity—its antiquities, its literature of all kinds, its past
                            history or present condition. Love will increase by cultivation, not in the same degree in all, for there must
                            be recognized a natural difference in the faculty of loving possessed by different persons as in everything else
                            pertaining to human nature; yet it will " grow with one's growth and strengthen with his strength," if carefully
                            and constantly cherished. It is often very feeble in its manifestations, and its possessors, instead of fanning
                            into greater life the pure flame, allow it to become wholly obscured by carelessness, or else, by their
                            excesses, to degenerate into that which is altogether unworthy of the name. "Love suffereth long and is kind,"
                            but that which is allowed to take its place soon changes to aversion and hatred. Genuine love is free from every
                            taint of impurity, and those who possess it in its fullness " love each other with a pure heart fervently." Love
                            always has goodness as its supreme object; hence God, who is love, is the Supremely Good. The human heart that
                            is im- bued with love cannot fail to love the Infinitely Good. It recognizes God everywhere, and adores him with
                            an unerring instinct as well as with the force of the highest reason. It perceives the Adorable in created
                            beings, especially in such as by increasing culture exhibit the divine traits in their greatest perfection,
                            whether physical, intellectual or moral; and in loving them, love the Divine. It perceives him in the various
                            divinely established relations—father, mother, sister and brother; but especially where these relations, by the
                            purity and permanency of the connecting ties, shadow forth those subsisting in the eternal abodes. It sees him
                            in the outward universe—in the unnumbered worlds that move forever around and among each other with so nice
                            adjustment; in the sublimity of mountain scenery; in the beauty of field and forest, lake and river, tree, shrub
                            and flower; as well in the varied sounds that charm the ear, the colors that delight the eye, or the fragrance
                            that pleases the sense of smell, as in those things that appeal to the inmost faculties of the soul—purity,
                            truth, meekness, kindness and benevolence. The emotions enkindled by the contemplation of such things are all of
                            a joyous nature. Love is joy to the soul. It is quietness and assurance forever. There is nothing in it
                            debasing, but that which is perpetually elevating. It changes from glory to glory by the inspira- tions of the
                            Divine Spirit; so that its first degrees, or the feeble flickerings of its primitive light, become lost in the
                            splendor of that which succeeds them, and which will forever succeed; for love to God, Avho is infinite and
                            eternal, must be perpetually increasing, and the soul whose love at first seemed weak and variable, will,
                            ultimately, by constant growth, become strong and unchanging in love as God himself, so that he could no more
                            transgress the divine law, or fall short of its requirements, than he could annihilate a world. Such is the
                            nature of Christian love, thai which was manifested by Jesus Christ while upon the earth, and which has been
                            experienced by multitudes who have followed him in the regeneration, or the new life of love. This ove is
                            consistent with everything that is excellent in the universe, and is incompatible only with sin. "All things are
                            yours," is the emphatic language of the Apostle addressed to Christians. All things, whether on earth or n
                            heaven; for he whom they love with unceasing adoration has all things in himself—an nflnite store—which he
                            bestows Avith unstinted land upon such as are "made partakers of the Divine Nature, having escaped the
                            corruptions that are in the world through lust."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious organization—shaker homes" TEIform="index"/>Religious Organization — Shaker Homes</head><p TEIform="p">A retrospective view of past eras shows that erring humanity has wrought much in harmony in the world, and
                            builded that which must be pulled down and cast away to give place to something better, more enduring, as the
                            race advances to more progressed conditions. The past has had its prophets and prophetesses; with eagle eyes
                            they pierced the future; and while their hearts were touched and quickened by inspirational power, they foretold
                            the coming of a day when the Highest would begin to show his city which in the Apocalypse is called tlie New
                            Jerusalem. God's city, builded in the heavens, coming down from Him to earth, " where discipline should be kept
                            in peace," and the sound of war would not be heard, and wherein Wisdom would hide his treasures from the
                            carnally wise and sensually corrupt, and reveal them to the pure in heart, and the meek should possess them. And
                            the Apostle Paul, by faith, saw a perfected, organized body, having one Lord, one faith and one baptism, in
                            perfect unity of feeling, having progressed beyond the childhood condition of being tossed and carried about
                            with every wind of doctrine; a body having many members working effectually for the increase of the whole, in
                            one fitly joined compact. Such an organization, founded upon divine revelation, is beginning to be known, and as
                            in the harvest the wheat of the husbandman appears, so in due time God is revealed as Father and Mother. No
                            longer we cry Abba, Father; now, true, legitimate sons and daughters are brought forth and commenced to build
                            the New Jerusalem according to the pattern formed in the heavens. The lessons of past ages have not been wasted.
                            The present is a time of deep searching and inquiry, and to a great extent, of religious aspiration; and
                            thousands are positive dissenters from all popular creeds, and are seeking for an organization that shall
                            combine the efficienc}r, purity and simplicity of the true church of Christ. The light of divine truth is
                            shining upon humanity, and a spiritual power is at work that will shake the false systems that man has builded.
                            Those who inhabit the New Jerusalem, or Shaker Order, must leave the old, and become new creatures in Christ,
                            having their affections placed on things above—forsaking the accidental or partial relationships of earth, and
                            forming the perfect Christian character by living like angels in the resurrection heavens. The ties and
                            affections which bind kindred relations together on the natural plane, are good and <pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 8 THE
                            SHAKER. useful in their place; but that which was even once glorious, by the law of progression ceases to be
                            glorious, as that which is freedom to-day may become bondage to-morrow. The spiritual elements are full of
                            signs, which give promise of a greater fulfillment of prophecy than has yet been given—" the heavens
                            hasteth"—the angels work, and mortals must work. The spirits call for more of the angelic, less of the Adamic.
                            We need to learn to " dwell in everlasting burnings," until selfpride and all that is not godly and true is
                            consumed in the soul. Those who learn to praise God in the fires of truth, will become so purified and refined
                            as to reflect the image of the purifier. Such, whether on earth or in the spirit spheres, will form a heavenly
                            home of peace, founded upon eternal principles.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knight, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Knight</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>The Shakers</head><p TEIform="p">PAST—PRESENT—FUTURE. Shaker life contains nothing so mysterious but which can be fully understood by its
                            subjects. It makes no promises of rewards, nor punishments, excepting the effects of practical life as led by
                            mankind in particular. Whoever can look for the just recompense of their doings, without that expectation of
                            favor, mythical theologians instruct, are men of reason, far removed from superstitious, man-made creeds. And
                            this class have made, are sustaining, and are ripening to sustain, the Shaker Order. In the autumn of 1776, a
                            half-dozen individuals, from England, entered the wilderness of Watervliet, N. Y., built their log house, and
                            began a life of religious communism, similar to the primitive Christians, relying upon direct communication from
                            the angel-spheres for the knowledge how to do and to be. They had a testimony to impart, that they knew would be
                            very unpalatable to all, excepting those who had become so thoroughly disgusted with sensuality, and who felt
                            themselves lost to all spirituality; with no hopes of gaining power over that nor improving in this by adherence
                            to the theologies of the times. Fortunately, of this number, there were a few. The times seemed unpropitious for
                            their mission. War was uppermost in the minds of the people. Their gospel taught purity and peace; and those
                            who, from religious motives, would not fight, were despised, fully as much, as are those in our times who will
                            not marry from the same motives. Since the days of Jesus, the world has never seen a Church begin and succeed,
                            which had so little worldly sympathy, nor whose future seemed so full of despair. This " little flock " boldly
                            enunciated their testimony—which, cutting keenly those desires worldly people love best, raised a storm of
                            persecution; and, for years, they suffered abuses that the people of to-day would hardly believe. The Church
                            grew. Its adherents were a noble class of people, religiously inclined—from that class that were " poor in
                            spirit" and in temporal things. By united efforts, industry, and complete trust in Providence, they soon had a
                            competence, and in less than thirty years inaugurated fifty or more communities, or large families, containing
                            more than a thousand persons, with real estate exceeding a million of dollars' value. Their object was two-fold
                            : First, the accomplishment of their own salvation, beginning with their thoughts and feelings, and continuing
                            to the ends of their fingers—and they found much salvation worked out at their fingers' ends. Secondly, they
                            determined to found institutions where those, who were overtaken by the same convictions as themselves, could
                            gather together and more successfully achieve the practical results of the cross—Salvation. To the Shakers of
                            the past, THB SHAKERS OF THE PRESENT owe a wonderful debt of gratitude. Countingback fifty years, and those
                            things that were necessarily neglected, in order to establish homes for the body as well as paths for the soul,
                            began to appear as possible and necessary. Schools for mental discipline began to assume an importance, second
                            only to those valued seasons—deep labors for the purification of the heart. Still the same motto is held now, as
                            of yore : " Seek first the kingdom of God," before expecting " aught else should be added." And could our
                            ancestors have gained for us, an advancement of soul equal to the homes they have provided for us (and this
                            anti-christian idea, " Jesus paid it all, etc.," is very preva- lent), then we might, long since, have added
                            many things which those not of us complain because we have not, and do not realize the wherefore. We have,
                            unreasonably, been charged with despising progression into the arts and sciences of the day. " Have you
                            libraries, pianos, Greek, Latin, and aesthetic literature arid manners ?" is the very common inquiry ! But, "
                            What is your soul-advancement?" is abroad, begging investigators ! Little as we have progressed into music,
                            letters and arts, we yet realize how true it is, these things do not bring purification—it is "the spirit,
                            Christ, that giveth life !" and other specifications of education are secondary, And we have an eternity to
                            acquire them; we never expect to die! We are, at times, the subjects of a withdrawal of spiritual light; the
                            present is such a season with the Shakers; but as surely as morning succeeds the night, and spring the whiter,
                            so surely do we know an increasing light is at hand. We need not half the faith, fortitude nor endurance our
                            spiritual ancestors had, for with our very favorable surrounding comforts we can " wait upon the Lord " in all
                            confidence, though many have permitted their lights to grow dim, and themselves "to go out from among us."
                            Darkness does not reign supreme, as in some past Shaker-history it has so appeared; we are more favored; we are
                            just as hopeful; and the world at large needs our testimony, much more than we need members I We are supposed to
                            be wealthy by many : excepting the millions of dollars' worth of real estate we possess, this is not true. The
                            majority of Shaker Communities have a very lean bank account—in fact, many individuals in New York city could
                            buy out the whole number of Communities, if ice would sell! Just why we do not make more money, must be left for
                            another article to show. We are already experiencing the fulfillment of our founder: " Souls will flock to you
                            like doves to their cots, by hundreds and by thousands !" and we have seen more than this number flocking to
                            Shaker principles for years ! and, at the same time, we have too many flocking to our temporal doors, who have
                            only those seven principles at heart—five loaves and two fishes. Of THE SHAKERS OF THE FUTURE we need only say a
                            few words. Reasoning from causes to their effects, we will not be charged with speculation. We are witnesses of
                            ripe scholarship, in all that adorns earthly life, very common among the people : Arts, sciences, mechanics,
                            aesthetics, etc., are educating the masses. These are finding their theology is not religion; that religion has
                            salvation in it; that salvation will appear as a positive necessity ; for they will be touched by the quickening
                            power of the Spirit of God, that will cause all earthly acquirements to appear as dross in comparison to the
                            salvation of the angel-life. Spiritualism will be the science of a new condition ; and, all other pursuits
                            neglected until this condition is reached, the use of acquired abilities will return, and together with their
                            souls, be consecrated to the pure purposes of God. We are few and ignorant now; by-theby we shall be the many
                            and of the most wise on the earth ! And as, in the spiritual heavens there are more souls than in earth and hell
                            together, so Avill these heavens baptize and consecrate the useful of the earth. And none need fear our
                            numerical force, any more than our poverty of numbers; for " Christians never did, never can fight."</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker..." TEIform="index"/>Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Bound copies of the first volume of The Shaker, may be obtained by application to the Resident Editor. Price, Two
                            Dollars ; extra binding, Three Dollars; unbound, 75 cents. ny parties sincerely solicitous of a thorough
                            explanation of Shaker views of religion; and who would willingly bear the expenses, in transitu, of a Lecturer,
                            to discourse upon "Religious Communism; " or "Ann Lee and the People called Shakers;'' may communicate with this
                            office. G. A. Lomas, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oliphant, Mary E." TEIform="index"/>Mary E. Oliphant...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Deceased at Mt. L., Nov. 1. <persName reg="Oliphant, Mary E." TEIform="persName">Mary E. Oliphant</persName>, aged 26.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O'Hare, Jane Ann" TEIform="index"/>Jane Ann O'Hare
                            </head><p TEIform="p">" '• " " 26, <persName reg="O'Hare, Jane Ann" TEIform="persName">Jane Ann O'Hare</persName>, " 26.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lannuir, Margaretta" TEIform="index"/>Margaretta Lannuir
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Deceased at Shakers, N. Y., Nov. 29, <persName reg="Lannuir, Margaretta" TEIform="persName">Margaretta Lannuir</persName>,
                                aged 70.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to ansiver Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans. Mt. Lebanon,
                            Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon
                            Mabeo, West Pittsfield, Mass. 11 Stoughton Kellogg, Thompsoiiville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham,
                            Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass.
                            " Nehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co., N. H. " John B.
                            Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas.
                            Clapp, Union Village, WaiTen Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio,. Shakers. " Stephen
                            Ball, Dayton. Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. K. Eades, South Union, Logan Co.,
                            Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>