<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1004" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18800401" TEIform="date">April 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> APRIL, 1880. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies.
                        OUR HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" ''Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS
                        ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880. The Shaker Vol. X. No. 4.
                        60 Cents Per Annum </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="73" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is home?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS HOME?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizaette" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZAETTE SUTTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Webster defines the word, and yet we are not quite satisfied with it as merely the " house in which we live."
                            One has said ; "Home is not only four square walls." Another says: " Home is where there are friends to love
                            us." We can but accept this, because it is the most congenial to instinct, as well as to our cultivated tastes.
                            We cannot say that home is the work of artisans, though the arrangement of the structure may be altogether
                            lovely, grand in form, in color and value, every thing tidy and full of neatness to the eye. We admit that all
                            this lives in imagination, with a wish to be gratified, and which moves to action, and forces its way in home
                            objects. Home is anywhere where there is an interest in the soul for high purposes. There are classes of people
                            who distinguish themselves apart from society, with no appreciation of outward embellishments, who have homes of
                            intense interest and profit. The recluse in the mountains ; the hermit in a solitary cave ; the secluded monk.
                            They never tire of devoting themselves (in their way) to restrictions in worldly show and ambition for the
                            radiance of divine light and influence, proving that that home consists in peace of mind — in living for an
                            object, and that, a virtuous, self-denying one. Moral excellence creates a home, and secures limitless comforts
                            and associations of true happiness; but "excellence " is never granted to us but as the reward of labor. It
                            requires, indeed, much strength of mind to persevere in habits of industry without the pleasure of perceiving
                            those advances, which, like the hand of a clock, whilst they make hourly approaches to their point, yet proceed
                            so slowly as to escape observation. " The groveling narrow mind, with little or no conception of a future state,
                            sustains itself, by low, inferior means; it neither sees nor feels the bliss of home culture in its truest
                            meaning. Broad minds have no rest nor peace in small circles ; they must inherit the earth scientifically, as
                            well as the heavens spiritually. They expand with every new and appropriate development, socially, morally,
                            intellectually and spiritually. Progress paves their way to all useful knowledge, and hope arises with every new
                            step taken toward the summit of perfection. Life fraught with good intentions, noble themes and high aspirations
                            for pure principles, makes home, and not the fallacy of art within mortared walls. With our mortal existence,
                            based upon immortal life and its controlling power, our home is made <pb n="74" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            beautiful— it is all fitting for the nobles of earth, whatever their profession, caste or emoluments have been.
                            Classics are not without their power in building up the New Earth, as well as the New Heavens. All pervading is
                            the spirit of truth ; it lives in the hearts of men and women, and needs but the genial rays of the gospel sun
                            to quicken it into action, thereby harvesting individuals from nature's realm into the kingdom of Christ. We
                            need not go to the homes of earth in a worldly life, for a compensation of joys, incident to a heavenly home of
                            unsurpassed merit and worth. Genuine happiness is found in home sacrifices, in patient hearts who toil in love
                            and sympathy for the whole household. We need not follow the mourner along life's way for a cordial of hope and
                            cheer; for the resurrecting power is in every Christian heart, preparing it for the enjoyment of a perfect
                            heaven. My dear friends, this being New Year's day a retrospect of the past year may aid us somewhat, in the
                            fulfillment of obligations in the future. If, with the eye of faith, we see failures in the time that has been
                            allotted us for improvement, let us hold ourselves in greater subjection to principles in this year which we
                            have just entered upon; remembering that the statue of the perfect man and woman is attained only by slow
                            gradations of travel, study of food and patience. Our experience teaches us that the first victory over a
                            weakness or fault renders the succeeding ones easier, until the combat is really desired for the gain of
                            conquest. We must not place our hopes on impossibilities and think to conserve the elements of the world, and
                            still be in the cause of faith and victory. The limits are sure ; we cannot be in possession of both at one and
                            the same time. We are called into a Christian life, let us pursue it with an honorable spirit and not be baffled
                            in Christian attainments ; divest ourselves of the old and put on a new attire of love and goodwill to all in
                            this new year ; strive to live so that the beautiful will be present at all times and in all places.
                            Home-serving principles go before all others in this enlightened age. The more we enter into the duties of home
                            the more our influence is felt for its improvement. If a sweet temper guides our steps, pangs of remorse cannot
                            follow ; if we light up every department of home with a smile, a word of cheer, affectionate encouragement and
                            enduring friendship, how can we fail to acquire noble conditions, in which we can say with the one of old, How
                            goodly are thy tents, 0 Jacob, and thy tabernacles O Israel.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts suggested by reading 'the Shaker's answer'" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS SUGGESTED BY READING "THE
                            SHAKER'S ANSWER."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nye, Joseph W." TEIform="persName"/>Joseph W. Nye</byline><p TEIform="p"> I've read your " Shaker's Answer " with great care, And think your argument is strong and fair ; It well
                            maintains the cause which you defend And my congratulations here I send ! Your calm and cogent reasoning doth
                            prove You well have studied Christ's great law of love, Which men to practice have been ever slow, Preferring in
                            the world's "broad road" to go. How long alas, will mankind go astray, And in their blindness miss the better
                            way ? Your plan of life based on the word inspired, Alone can bring the blessed time desired By bards and
                            prophets of the olden time, Who then foretold it in their strains sublime ; The era grand when all shall know
                            the Lord, Live by the spirit and trust in his word. When groveling sense, and appetite and pride Will be by all
                            God's children thrown aside, When to the higher life all men will turn And of the meek and lowly Saviour learn,
                            Who teacheth us all fleshy lusts to spurn ; The new and better way when will men find, Which works no ill to
                            body or to mind ? The law of progress, potent in its sway, Will bring all men Christ's precepts to obey ; And
                            those who now the higher law embrace Are benefactors of the human race ; Blessing themselves and all their
                            neighbors too; Alas, that here we find so very few / They are the "little" which the whole will leaven, And make
                            the earth a foretaste sweet of heaven ! Then glory like a shining robe will fall Upon the earth and " God be all
                            in all;" Filled with this spirit all the earth shall be, As waters spread and fill the mighty sea! 74 <pb n="75" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 75 Then every eye shall see come down to men The bright and shining New
                            Jerusalem ! Keep on your way dear " Shaker friends " so-called, By no rude opposition be appalled, But " shake "
                            old errors till their sway shall cease And men shall live in harmony and peace ! Fkiend Whiteley : During the
                            visit of my daughter to Fitchburg last summer, she stopped awhile at your village in company with Mrs. H-----and
                            daughter. Upon her return home she expressed much pleasure in regard to her visit to Shirley, and brought me
                            your (Shaker's) "Answer" which has prompted the above lines. " May the Lord bless you and keep you, and cause
                            His face to shine upon you and give you peace." To which Sarah heartily responds. Lynn, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruits of the harvest" TEIform="index"/>FRUITS OF THE HARVEST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> For many long and weary years, as I stated in my last, I continued to struggle against my lower, rudimental
                            proclivities, observing the serenity and perfect spiritual repose of many who had long preceded me in the
                            Christian warfare : and yearning and longing, with groanings and earnest prayers, to enter into that eternal
                            rest with them, which I was fully convinced they had entered into here even in this life. I was well convinced,
                            from constant association with them, they had had no reason to wait the scenes of a future life to realize the "
                            powers of the world to come," with its saving, comforting, healing inspirations ; for a measure of these I was
                            often made to feel for a season, by impartation from them ; sometimes in such effusions of love and power as to
                            drive all insinuations from the side of my lower instincts, far away from me even "into the uttermost parts of
                            Egypt," and leave me as it were, translated to the highest Heaven of peace and tranquillity. The exact process
                            of my experience has been, in regard to this spiritual exodus from rudimental to higher planes, that the seasons
                            of temptation have gradually shortened, and the seasons of releasement and invulnerable triumph lengthened,
                            until at last I enjoy the very same state of immunity from temptation and sorrowl looked upon in others with
                            such longings and deep yearnings of spirit in other years — others whom I was sure had entered into deep
                            spiritual rest and at-one-ment with the spirit of God. How it might have fared with me had I been practically
                            unsettled, wavering and vacillating, I cannot say ; it would probably have postponed the good days of final and
                            effectual victory for years ; but from the first day of my religious experience, I am not aware of having
                            yielded to lower impulses of soul or body once. I seem to have entered a serene and delicious region of
                            everlasting consolations which are to be met on every hand — precious fruits of the higher life — pleasure in
                            doing good — enjoyment of sweet purity— love toward brethren and sisters — cheerfulness and gladness in all
                            duties, together with the hundred fold of houses, lands, brethren and sisters; and above all, the actual
                            fruition and experience of that eternal life and peace which I was formerly only able to hope for. or to enjoy
                            the realities of, but for a very little season at a time. Now it is a constant " well of water, springing up
                            unto everlasting life." I often dream of reoccupying those old battle grounds of former years, only to wake up
                            and find the blissful reality of releasement and immunity from them forever. Moreover, having kept a journal of
                            my entire life-history, both of the scenes of sorrow and temptation and the delicious afterdeliverances of joy
                            and ensuing peace and restful sense of victory, I often read over those lonely pilgrimages; those times and
                            places of refreshment, and feel like the mariner who hears the far-off boom of the ocean storm, but is safely
                            and cozily moored, far from its dangers forever. 0, that men would prove the words of Jesus Christ and Ann Lee
                            to the end ! How immeasurably transcending all the pleasures to be enjoyed upon the poor, low plane of
                            rudimental existence. If these encouraging words will nerve any Zion traveler, old or young, to the glorious
                            struggle for life eternal, I shall <pb n="76" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. be many times rewarded for the
                            pains I have taken to write them. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>SELF-SACRIFICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Strowbridge, Evelyn" TEIform="persName"/>EVELYN STROWBRIDGE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Among the many essential qualities which constitute the true believer's life, perhaps there is non3 more
                            important than self-sacrifice. Human nature in its present perverted condition partakes of many evils; but
                            selfishness is the all-prevailing sin ; for its pernicious influence unquestionably bears sway, much impeding
                            humanity's nobler development. Mind is the propelling power that prompts our 'actions ; unless this is attuned
                            to its Giver, a God of benefice and love, how can we progress toward the higher courts of justice and purity, or
                            attain that culture of soul that will prepare us for the society of angels ? It seems evident that there must be
                            a subjugation of self-will, a reconciliation to divine command, a dissolving of that selfhood which has so long
                            stood as a detriment between the soul and its maker; and this can be wrought only through self-sacrifice. Jesus
                            taught us how to do. He said : " Except ye deny yourselves and take up your daily cross ye cannot be My
                            disciples." Herein is contained the whole truth whereby we can become reconciled to our divine Parents. When
                            through Christian faith the effulgent rays of divine light reach and reveal the lone, meager condition of the
                            soul, then there is an inward longing for something higher, nobler than self ; a desire for something superior,
                            which neither the world nor its votaries can give. 'Tis then we would turn to the broad field of self-sacrifice
                            for comfort and employ ; here we find multifarious duties which pertain to the present life and need our willing
                            hands to perform ; and here, too, we find " labor that is worship and prayer," for it requires the undivided
                            energies of the whole heart to properly execute it. The soul, it is said, "does not feed on dust," but being of
                            divine origin it must forever subsist on the inexhaustible supplies of the spiritual kingdom. Self-sacrifice,
                            when applied to spiritlife, works inwardly. " Behold I set up a new kingdom within you ;" it takes on the yoke
                            of Christ, and implies strict obedience to the highest convictions of Christian duty. Thus, daily deeds of
                            self-sacrifice, wrought in humility and prayer, will continue to deepen and broaden the soul in the happifying
                            realities of divine truth, until there is no room for that which would defile or separate the soul from its
                            divine Creator. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One man—one christ—one god" TEIform="index"/>ONE MAN - ONE CHRIST - ONE GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> The use sometimes made of words in a language confounds the senses, and misleads the understanding. Much
                            theological controversy and discussion is ofttimes simply the result of a want of knowledge by the reader, or
                            listener, of the meaning the writer or speaker had in mind when using the word or term considered. The
                            scriptures abound with tropes. To illustrate, slightly, we refer to the scriptural use of the words "All;"
                            "Judea;" " region;"" in the sentence: "Then went out to Him all Judea, and all the region round about Jordan." "
                            All," meaning simply a large number ; " Judea" is a country ; it could not go to Jesus ; the same of "•region" —
                            an extent of country; this could not go to Jesus; but these are figures of speech, meaning the people of Judea
                            and the region. Again: "Let the floods clap their hands, let the hills be joyful together." " The ploughmen
                            ploughed upon my back, they made long their furrows." Such, and multitudes of others, being tropes. "Moods"
                            meaning multitudes of people ; and " hills " dignitaries of peoples ; "ploughmen" meaning chastisers or
                            persecutors. Thus also the language of Jesus: " Go ye into all the world, and preach the gospel to every
                            creature ;" the term " all the world " having reference to a wide region, within the bounds of the apostles'
                            capacity; and " every creature,'* meaning all classes of people, capable of re76 <pb n="77" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 77 ceimng the testimony; not to the lower orders of animal creation. In speaking of the human race,
                            the genus homo, both scriptural and secular language alike use the word Man in a bi-sexual sense, meaning both
                            man and woman; also the myriads of the human race. In this sense there is but one man — a race of beings. This
                            meaning of the word Man is also used in expressing perfect gospel unity and love, freed from the divisions
                            engendered by violations of God's laws. Thus, as sung by [the poetess: "In thee* the veil (of separation) is
                            rent and gone, And love is sweetly flowing; The male and female are but one To full perfection growing." This is
                            synonymous with the scripture language : " In Christ there is neither male nor female ;" meaning generatively.
                            Conformable to the foregoing, there is but one Christ; Christ meaning the Order of intelligences constituted by
                            being anointed agent to minister the ligJit, knoioledge, and power of salvation and redemption from the nature
                            of sin to the family of man. This Order of intelligences, whether two or more, constitutes the genus Christos.
                            But, at the same time, we understand this Order to embrace both male and female, and that the female man was as
                            really chosen and anointed, made Christ, to perform the Christ service, as was Jesus, the male ; thus adapting
                            the characteristics of the gospel's savory plan to all the intricacies and delicacies] of human nature. In the
                            foregoing summary, also, we speak of One God, meaning the Supreme Parentage of Creation — a Divine Father and
                            Mother, constituting the genus Deus. — The God Order! But there are other forms of expression by which a person
                            might be misled who is unacquainted with this idiom of the English language or with the theology of the
                            revelation of God, as manifested by the Second Appearing of the Christ Order in the female, thus revealing the
                            Motherhood of God,—-to suppose that this theology taught numerous Gods ! Thus, as we have the scripture language
                            : " And God said let us make man in our image and likeness," * Man, purified by the fire of truth. meaning God,
                            constituted of the principles or attributes of both sexes. To render this sentiment entirely unambiguous, except
                            in the foregoing signification of the use of the word Man, the language should be : " And the Gods said, let
                            us," etc. And since " He that hath the Bride is the Bridegroom, " in like use ofjlanguage we should say, " And
                            the Christs said, no man cometh to the Father" (and Mother) — God, "but by " us, instead of " Me." But at the
                            time Jesus said " Me," in the above sentence, the Bride Christ had not been revealed. The Man — Jesus Christ —
                            revealed the Fatherhood of God, and the Woman — Ann Christ — revealed the Motherhood of God. Thus the Christians
                            of the primitive Church were only " Children of God by adoption." If there was a perfect Christ Order in the
                            spirit world previous to itB advent through Jesus and Ann, it was beyond the knowledge of the inhabitants of
                            earth ; perhaps beyond the ken of Jesus when He uttered the foregoing sentence, and further said : " I am the
                            way, truth and life ; and he that climbeth up some other way, the same is a] thief and a robber." "All power is
                            given unto Me in heaven and in earth." The word " sphere" is also sometimes used so as to mislead for want of
                            qualifying expressions ; it is a word ofmany meanings, but a prominent one is " An Order of beings." This use
                            and understanding are sometimes confounded as referring to the character of beings. Thus the angel sphere is
                            often understood to mean exclusively good angels ; whereas angels, as an Order of beings, are by no means all
                            good ! There are devilish angels. But in the sense of an Order of'intelligences, we may appropriately apply the
                            term " sphere" to Deity —The Divine sphere. To Christ —The Christ sphere, meaning the abode of all spirits of
                            the Christ Order, male and female. Thus, also, may we use the terms, Angel sphere, Human sphere, etc., referring
                            to orders of intelligences. ^But if Jesus was the " First begotten son of God," and for a time, " The only
                            begotten son of God ;" if he was the Second Adam, the Lord from Heaven, a quickening spirit ; " the beginning of
                            the Creation (New Crea- <pb n="78" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 78 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. tion) of God," of whom it is written: "
                            When He bringeth His first begotten into the world. He saith : ' Let all the Angels of God worship Him;' " was
                            He not the beginning of the Christ sphere \ At least, as far as revealed to mortals? Both Jesus and Ann had,
                            while on earth, as real a mission to souls in the spirit world as to those in time. Mother Ann was known to
                            spend much time when her soul was exclusively exercised in labors with souls in the spirit world. And if the
                            myriads of souls who entered the spirit world waited thousands of years for the advent of their Redeemer, it was
                            no more for them than for those of the same race on earth. All the human family wait still for the immense
                            progress of future ages, in the same manner. But our Mother Ann's testimony was : " All souls will be privileged
                            with a knowledge of this gospel testimony, either in time or eternity." Shakers, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God is God" TEIform="index"/>GOD IS GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Organized — or unorganized ? That is the question to be answered. One asks, perhaps somewhat contemptuously, "
                            If God be an organized being, can a tailor make God a coat ? " It might be answered—not only have tailors made
                            God a coat, but artificers have previously made the God who was destined to wear it. Does that prove that God is
                            unorganized ? Can the human mind conceive of a thinking, knowing, intelligent Deity that is not an organized
                            being ? Canst thou search out the Almighty? Canst thou comprehend the Most High to perfection ? Shall not God,
                            who made the human eye, see ? made the human ear, hear ? the human heart, shall not He and She understand ? Can
                            we see but with the eye ? hear but with the ear? or understand but with the brain ? It is by successive stages
                            that the mind of man progresses to a perception of interior spiritual truths. In the first stage we have
                            Fetichism— a rock, a tree, a serpent, is endowed with life, as a ghost-frightened boy turns a burnt tree into a
                            hobgoblin — it is worshiped. In the second stage, we have Idolatry. Of the most precious, costly [material he
                            possesses, man makes an image of his highest ideal of a human being, whether male or female, and clothes it as
                            his fancy directs — then he falls down and worships the God he has made and clothed. In the third stage the
                            progressing man constructs a mental image of his progressed God — and worships it. Still again, the man
                            endeavors to form a conception of a Spiritual Being — a God" who governs the universe of worlds filled with
                            accountable beings like ourselves — as a king or queen governs a nation or nations. Why not ? No ruler is
                            personally present throughout all the parts of the realm governed. The Queen of England's ^dominion is not only
                            from sea to sea, but from one end of the earth to the other. She rules over congeries of nations without
                            personal ubiquity. Cannot God do the same ? All political power is from the Queen. All intellect, knowledge,
                            faculty to perceive, power to be, think and act, is of God. Is it not glory enough for God to be recognized by
                            all the rulers in the universe of worlds immeasurable, as the central force, or fountain, from whence all their
                            power is derived ? Are not all governments founded upon this idea? God is, and God is dual — the great Father
                            and Mother of all sentient souls. If we apprehended Deity entirely aright, in extent and quality, how could we
                            progress to further knowledge — grow in grace and in the knowledge of divine things ? If God be the unorganized
                            nature of the Materialist, or Atheist, why should not those who hold sincerely to this view, say so in good,
                            plain English ? Who is an Atheist? " One who disbelieves in the existence of an intelligent Supreme Being."
                            Supreme means " the highest in authority.'' Intelligent means " to be endowed with the faculty of understanding—
                            to know." Being is an intelligent, immaterial existence, or spirit." Each of these parts of speech, when applied
                            to Deity, implies that above all rulers, there is <pb n="79" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. one who is the
                            ruler of rulers — above all intelligent beings, is one who is superior to all others. And above all beings,
                            there exists a Being who embodies more knowledge, reasons more logically, understands more perfectly, knows more
                            positively than any, or all other beings that exist in the worlds and spheres of matter, mind and intellect — a
                            supreme, intelligent dual being — God. Inasmuch as all the intelligence we know any thing about, from man,
                            upwards or downwards, is possessed and exhibited by organized beings, we are incapable of conceiving an
                            existence of intelligence in an unorganized elementary state. Mind, will, purpose, intention, design, plan,
                            rule, love, affection, and an organized being, are inseparable concomitants, equally with air and sound, weight
                            and atmospheric pressure. They indicate brain, and brain means senses, faculties — in a word, a ,fully organized
                            form. Atheists, disbelieving in a supreme, intelligent Being — God — should not seek to evade consequences by
                            still using what, to them, is an obsolete term — God — when what they do mean is nature — the nature of
                            Materialists and Atheists. It is, to say the least, disengenuous. As the duality of Deity is dependent upon the
                            personality of Deity, as an organization, Atheists, denying such personality and organization, are, of course,
                            quite logical in denying such divine duality. Thus the question recurs — can an infinite, omnipresent,
                            omnipotent unorganized God know any thing more than nature knows, or than any one of the natural elements
                            knows—as the wind, fire, sea, or an earthquake? Can such a God—-unorganized— have any design or scheme of human
                            redemption? Has it any wisdom to ride the whirlwind of human passion, or to direct the storm, through force and
                            violence? By wisdom rightly directed, the Kingdom of Heaven is achieved. The least being in existence is
                            superior to an unorganized God — even as a living dog is superior to a dead lion. To assume the affirmative that
                            such a God could know, or do any thing, appears as absurd as to say there is a part, when there was no whole, a
                            member where there was no body — an effect, when no cause had existed to produce it. Beginning on earth with the
                            lowest organism, reasoning logically up to man — from man upward — will it not lead us up, through sphere within
                            sphere, as the soul within the body, to a Supreme, Intelligent, Dual God, as an organized Being, like ourselves,
                            whose image we are? Is not God the brain of the Grand Man, that the Swedish Seer declares the universe to be
                        ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is virgin life contrary to law? no. 1" TEIform="index"/>IS A VIRGIN LIFE CONTRARY TO LAW ? No. I.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p"> This inquiry is presented to a numerous class — rich and poor, religious and irreligious, learned and unlearned
                            — all ready to affirm, and quite sure that the life lived by the Shakers is contrary to the ; great command, "
                            multiply and replenish," etc. The unanimity displayed by the whole class is remarkable. They see nothing in this
                            question but " the great command," being quite oblivious to the fact that functions abused annul the right to
                            exercise them. And that the last order of a general in command takes the precedence of the former order. Hence,
                            to the woman, " Thy desire being not to fulfill the law of use, but to thy husband, thy conceptions shall be
                            multiplied, and he shall rule over thee, and in sorrow shalt thou bring forth." To the man, " Thorns and
                            thistles shall the earthly man bring forth, and in the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat bread." These words
                            truthfully portray the present condition of humanity. Evasions of the command, " In the sweat of thy face shalt
                            thou eat bread," has torn empires into pieces, and thrown their civilizations to the winds, and now is the cause
                            of untold human suffering within the British empire alone. More than twenty millions of persons have perished
                            from this cause during the present century. Hence all human governments are unstable. The evasion of this
                            requirement in our day by a portion of the people of the Southern States shook modern civilization to its
                            center. The settlement of the " great conflict " by the people of the Northern States 79 <pb n="80" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            80 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. has left a tremor in the heart of every Euro pean monarch. And Ireland — gaunt anc
                            hungry Ireland —has but to shake her lank and toil-worn finger and England's princes tremble in their palaces.
                            Why so ? Because in the sweat of the laborer's face they have eaten bread. [There is a growing feeling in the
                            minds of many that man has lost all right to procreate ; this feeling is predicated on the facts attendant on
                            procreation and without reference to inspirational revealments. This feeling is fully sustained by the
                            scriptures, not merely by an isolated passage, but by special enactment and 'concurring texts — "If a woman has
                            borne a man-child she shall be unclean seven days ; and for thirty-three days she shall continue in the work of
                            purification. When these days are fulfilled she shall bring a burnt'offering, and a sin offering, and atonement
                            will be made for her."] In summing up the whole matter'as regards the primal and subsequent commands in plain
                            English the terms are, " You Adam and Eve have broken the conditions of the primal command — have chosen to
                            replenish the earth in your own way, without reference to the well-being present or prospective of your
                            offspring; hence the earthly man brings forth thistles and thorns in abundance." Setting aside the consideration
                            of "all commands and penalties, I purpose to show from the spiritual constitution of man, and from the awful
                            consequences "of replenishing the"1 earth" irrespective of hygienic and providential laws, that a virgin life is
                            not contrary to either natural or revealed laws, but in harmony with them. First. Man is in possession of and
                            manifests a two-fold life — an animal life, represented by animal emotions ; and'aninner/a higher life,
                            represented by the emotions of benevolence, mercy, and aspirations Godward. Secondly. Adam and Eve are the
                            type'of the animal man ; within their province lies the work of procreation ; but " the day thou eatest thereof"
                            contrary to law " thou shalt surely die, shame shall cover thee, and in anguish shalt thou bring forth." A
                            correct delineation of the present condition of man. kind. Additional evidence that law has been, and is
                            violated, is found in the numerous diseases, especially the sexual, which afflict humanity. Ihirdly. Christ was
                            the type of the new — the inner man : " This is my beloved Son in whom I am well pleased." He was not of the
                            world ; His life (not His death) constituted the resurrection. He lived a virgin life, and all in His life are
                            as He was. And wherever two or three are gathered together in that life they constitute a new order of human
                            society — the resurrection or Christ order ; having property in common ; the strong bearing the burdens of the
                            weak as do the Shakers. " By their works shall they be known." Fourthly. Can the new man marry and be given in
                            marriage and follow Father Adam, the old man, and still be the new man ? He cannot; that which is flesh is
                            flesh, and that which is spirit is spirit ; that which is animal is animal, and that which is divine is divine.
                            These are contrary the one to the other. To live as Christ lived — be angelic and fulfill the desires of the
                            flesh and of the mind too are an impossibility. Therefore a virgin life is according to law being a condition of
                            the divine—the Christlife. Fifthly. Was Jesus who took on Himself the nature of His brethren whom He came to
                            redeem a celibate ? He was. And did the members of the Pentecostal Church live a virgin-life ? They did. As
                            proof thereof they had goods] in common and abstained from war. This virgin order of society existed about two
                            hundred years. Had they married there would have been among them a plurality of centers of affection and of
                            interest, consequently a community of goods could not have been maintained, and peace much less. Sixthly. Are
                            the so-called Christians of to-day lineal descendants of the Pentecostal Church ? They are not. They are the
                            lineal descendants of the children of this world. They marry, hold private property, take advantage of one
                            another, fight a great deal, and quarrel generally. It was aid of them, by one of themselves, " That Aere is no
                            peace in the church, in the meet- <pb n="81" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 81 ing-house, in the school-house,
                            in the sewing circle, nor anywhere else among them." Seventhly. Should the Adamic man cease from committing sin
                            and propagate in acoordance with law, would he still be the old man ? He would still be the old man, beautiful
                            in his order, but of the earth earthy. Eighthly. Can any infer that it is in accordance with the higher nature
                            or life in man to be heavenly while he is in the body ? I can. It is heavenly principles worked out — embodied,
                            which constitutes heaven. Such principles, when operative, will bring forth heavenly fruit without reference to
                            locality, whether on earth or in the spirit land. In heaven they do not marry ; therefore if heaven is ever
                            found on earth neither will they who are in the kingdom marry; they will live a life of purity, assuming a
                            virgin state as a first condition that they are not of the world — that they have left the kingdom of Adam.for
                            an order which is not after the will of the flesh. Ninthly. You have quoted from the scriptures showing that
                            celibacy is a condition of the higher life, but what manifestations have been presented in the history of our
                            race that a virgin life is a condition necessary to the fulfillment of human wants and desires, aaid wants and
                            desires being in ac cordance with any law of man's nature ? We can only know of law by its manifes tations, and
                            that there is a law in our nature responding to a virgin life is evident ; it has cropped out in all ages from
                            the earliest historic times; it was manifested in the theraputse of Egypt, among the Jews in the Nazerites, and
                            was developed as a permanent institution in the communities of the Essenes. It may be traced among the Brahmins,
                            and Ascetics of India, and also in China and Japan. The order of the vestal priestesses in the Roman temples
                            lasted about a thousand years ; no persons could have been more trusted than these females were. This virgin
                            order gave sanctity and power even to pagan worship, and shows the innate veneration of the human spirit for a
                            life of absolute purity. The monastic orders of Europe speak of its existence from the days of the apostles down
                            to the present hour, a period of nearly two thousand years. And a class of heretics (so-called) by the Catholic
                            church boldly declared that law to be written in their hearts, and they lived it out in their lives. Lastly. The
                            Shakers of America are living respondents to that law in our nature, a law of the inner life ; that absolute
                            purity of body and spirit is a condition necessary to the fulfillment of their wants and desires; and is an
                            essential preliminary to their happiness, namely the manifestation and life of God in their spirits. They
                            believe that all may enter into a heavenly state by cultivating heavenly principles, and that it is their
                            mission tokeepan open door for all who live as Jesus lived, and walk as He did walk. Christ was the first born
                            of many brethren ; so Ann Lee by entering the resurrection order (as did Jesus) being baptized with the same
                            spirit, she became the first born of many sisters. The Apostle Paul, the representative of many millions, in
                            speaking of the law above referred to, said : "I feel a law in my members" — animal passions —" warring against
                            the law of my mind " he thanked God and gloried in the cross, as a way of deliverance from the emotions of an
                            animal nature, and responding practically to the law of his mind — the higher — the life of God hid in every
                            human spirit; he lived a virgin life. The natives of Mexico before being invaded by the Spaniards never heard of
                            Paul nor of the virgin life of the PentecostalChristians who abstained from war and held goods in common—an
                            order of human society after the law of the spirit of life as it is in Christ Jesus. They never heard of such,
                            yet they from the law written on their hearts responded to the fact of an inner life and to the dignity of the
                            person who lives according to its law. On the invasion of their country they took prisoner a certain person ;
                            they discovered that he was a celibate; this to them was a matter of great interest, and they sat their wits to
                            work to test how much of a celibate he was. Having exhausted their ingenuity and found him steadfast they then
                            reverenced and almost worshiped him. They had found a man who for a high purpose restrained the emo- <pb n="82" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. tions of his animal nature, and the inference was that he was a superior
                            being, and so he was ; his life was a response to the law of the higher life, and their admiration was a
                            response to the latent higher life within themselves. When any person ceases to respond in reverence to the
                            manifestations of self-denial in individuals or in a people they may assure themselves that they are under the
                            power of animal emotional life and have taken more than one step in the downward road of degradation
                            appertaining thereto. The sentiments of the natives of Mexico were identical with those of Paul and the millions
                            he represents. From the four quarters of the globe we have concurring testimony that wherever man has progressed
                            beyond being a mere animal, the law of the higher life has broken forth. First in history is Asia, for thousands
                            of years celibacy has nourished on her soil. In Africa, in the dark sublimity of Egyptian history, there stands
                            forth celibate institutions. Europe, for more than two thou sand years, has responded to Asia and Africa in
                            similar manifestations. And, strange to say, before Columbus touched the shores of this western world the people
                            of Mexico and Peru had each their civilizations, and among them also the law of the higher life broke forth in
                            celibate institutions. Having these abundant evidences in view is it not due to the testimony advanced to affirm
                            that a virgin life is founded on a law in our being, the divine element in humanity, which, when operative in
                            human spirts as in Jesus, will bring forth manifestations of God the Father as did the well-beloved Son. He in
                            living the higher life became a son of God — ceased to be a son of Adam — died to his animal emotions which he
                            had in common with men. Hence Jesus Christ stands at the head of the new creation, even as Adam is at the head
                            of the old. The idea that a virgin life is a contravention of the Creator's plan in creating man is a one-sided
                            thought, and a low estimate of man's ultimate destiny, and is neither sustained by the nature of man nor by the
                            analogy of created 'things. Jesus in all His more important teachings made use of natural things to illustrate
                            those of heavenly life. He likened the kingdom of heaven in its various phases to corresponding natural objects,
                            and showed that human beings were as much the subjects of being reaped as the grain they sowed.
                            ---------------4--------------</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="She rattles the Shakers" TEIform="index"/>SHE RATTLES THE SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harter" TEIform="persName"/>MRS. HARTER</byline><p TEIform="p">[From Seymour Times.] BY If Jesus our exemplar be, How few true followers we see ; None with Him are life
                            partakers Except it be the modest Shakers, Who live content with no estates, And are like Him strict celibates,
                            But whether that be more divine, Remains unproven we opine. Now let us pause and reason here, To make the
                            subject still more clear, Whether God, the wise Creator, Really was an earnest Shaker ? A Shaker god could have
                            no heart, In making man a counterpart. And why should he His mind perplex, With fashioning the fairer sex ? If
                            when He bade the man to take her He had replied " Nay, I'm a Shaker," The whole creation would have failed Had
                            Shakerism then prevailed, And where, O where in earth or heavens, Would now exist dear Elder Evans? He'd not be
                            here to teach reform For none of us would e'er been born ; Nonentity would be our doom And nowhere our eternal
                            home. 'Twas well for woman and her maker, That the first man did not Shake-her, But if that be religion true
                            'Twas just as needful then as now ; All nature's demonstrations prove That God created all through love, And
                            love attracts and correlates And through this law God procreates ; Then why condemn with such persistence The
                            law that gives us our existence ? Nay, do not nature's God demean, By calling His just laws unclean. Where
                            unperverted nature leads, The highest happiness succeeds.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Open letter" TEIform="index"/>OPEN LETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morton, Lizzie" TEIform="persName"/>Lizzie Morton.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Why, my dear sister, Mrs. Harter, What'n the world can you be " arter ? " Putting us Shakers so above you And
                            all your neighbors who so love you ! But true it is, the life-partaker Must first become an honest Shaker. Now
                            let me tell you, my dear madam, That when God made the first old Adam, <pb n="83" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 83 He had in view the second man To introduce the better plan, The spiritual to substitute, And raise
                            mankind above the brute. By leaving off the old profession, In this you'll find is true progression ; But
                            keeping still the counterpart, To love in spirit and in heart; But having animals outgrown, We let the animal
                            alone, And live in truth, Christ's higher life — Still love the woman, but hate the wife — Still love the man —
                            the husband hate, Conditions us the higher state. Below, the counterpart to find, We guess and guess, then " go
                            it blind ;" And then what must we women say ? " In all things 1 will thee obey.'1 Thus take our counterpart on
                            trust — Become a slave to lordly lust — To come and go as he may choose — To wash his feet or tie his shoes. We
                            cannot be among the ris'n, But soul and body both are his'n — Thus " fixed to one peculiar spot We only
                            propagate and rot." With all our pledges, vows, and loves, We can't rise higher than the doves ; And all
                            delights we fondly cherish How very, very soon they perish ! Your inferential reasoning's good For all who want
                            that kind of food — A little nest, and a little love-y —¦ A little egg and a little dove-y — And vine and bud,
                            and breeze and blossom. Are on the line of pig and possum — Thus live and die and know no better Than to be
                            enchained in nature's fetter. But we in the celestial city Look down on such with earnest pity. Now, sister
                            Harter, I'm not sportin' Of me, I'll tol'rate no such courtin' Not while my name is South Union, Ky., Feb. 23,
                            1880.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very plain Shaker letter" TEIform="index"/>A VERY PLAIN SHAKER LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">Elmina D. Slenker: Respected Friend — Thee says: "I have read thy book ;" but thee needs to read it again. Thee
                            not understanding it, compels me, although I regret it, to speak more plainly. Thee should have quoted the parts
                            from which thy opinions were drawn. As it is, I will have to follow thee, as the hunter would, by tracks left in
                            the snow. The most of thy reasons for preferring indefinably infidelity to definable Shakerism are mine for
                            preferring the latter. " It believes in truth wherever found [either natural or spiritual]. It binds no one to
                            follow gods or christs or man or woman. It does does not say, believe this, that or the other, on pain of
                            damnation. It does not scorn any innocent pleasure of body or soul. It is true, liberal, generous, considerate
                            and reasonable." All this the book teaches which thee has "carefully read." But infidelity itself seems to be
                            "creed-bound." It does not allow its adherents to touch the realm spiritual. If they do, they are pronounced
                            fanatics and excluded from the brotherhood. If not so, why is it fighting every thing spiritual the whole world
                            over ? It is " not so comprehensive" as Shakerism, which embraces both the natural and spiritual, allowing to
                            each its appropriate place. It leaves all to be free, to believe and do as they mey elect, admitting all to be
                            justified before God who act up to their highest light; this also the book teaches. But it cannot change fixed
                            and unalterable law. It cannot cause a particle of matter to occupy two points in space at the same time ; but
                            it could do this just as easily as it could cause any one to occupy the generative and regenerative plane at the
                            same time. Can we be censured for not doing impossible things? It seems because we cannot alter this law, which
                            stands philosophically in the fixedness of things, positively unalterable by any power in heaven or earth, we
                            are to be considered fanatical and " creedbound." The two planes and orders are as distinct and separate as
                            things can be. They are illustrated in the book by lower and upper floors — one plane for generation, the other
                            for regeneration. Now, generation means to procreate, as animals do ; regeneration means to create anew; that
                            is, to take the procreated and make them new creatures — create in them different, nobler and higher impulses
                            and aspirations, and giving the soul the entire ascendancy over and control of the creature ; which is not the
                            case on the plane below, where the passions control and run riot, in spite of internal remonstrance. Who, then,
                            can consistently blame us for not admitting that generators occupy as high a plane as do the regenerators? <pb n="84" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Shakerism leaves all free to accept the guidance of any person or
                            tbody of persons, and does not consider them " slaves and fanatics " for the exercise of this freedom. Christ is
                            the Shakers' pattern, but they condemn no one for choosing another, or for choosing blind Nature. Is infidelity
                            more liberal than this ? It reaches not above matter, saying, " look to nature," and not to God, the cause of
                            nature. " We are here without our consent. Let us take all the pleasure and enjoyment that our natures crave." "
                            One world at a time, ladies and gentlemen ;" " follow no one, be your own judges, be free; any other course is
                            slavery and fanaticism." " You need not trouble yourselves about 'laying up treasure in heaven, "where thieves
                            cannot steal,' till you get there." " ' A bird in the hand is worth two in the bush ;' enjoy yourselves here ;
                            let the future take care of itself, if there is any future; go it while you're young, etc." This is infidelity "
                            defined." But after all this it turns preacher, dons the sacerdotal robe and really gives some good advice. " Be
                            kind, be charitable, be generous; help the poor and needy," etc., etc. This the Shakers have been doing the last
                            hundred years and more. It continues: " Why follow Christ, when the all-powerful voice of nature demands the
                            union of sex ? " But be careful, don't indulge too much, keep it on the " honor line." This is good lower-floor
                            advice; but does the priest himself keep it on the honor line ? Thee asks : " Who are Christ and Paul, that they
                            should judge for me and thee ? Is not nature the better guide ? " When thee tells me what nature is, I will then
                            answer the question. Thee says : " Please do not take me for a sensualist in the exaggerated sense, but let me
                            plead for a pure and temperate gratification of all innocent pleasures."' I would be most happy, indeed, if I
                            could avoid considering thee a sensualist, even moderately ; but Shakers claim for themselves the enjoyment of
                            all pure and innocent pleasures. The difference in us would be in classifying them. The sensualist is one who is
                            devoted to sensual pleasure ; thee takes and advocates this position, saying: " I go for the present and its
                            possibilities." The restraints thee [recommends are only to heighten their enjoyments, not for any higher or
                            spiritual purpose. So, then, thy happiness is merely animal, just such as animals enjoy, the acme of which is
                            the sexual tact; but even this leaves its sting behind. Thee is consequently wholly ignorant of the higher
                            happiness which the unsensual and spiritual-minded enjoy, and which is imperishable. I will freely admit that
                            the union of sex in marriage, which thee speaks of, would be irresistible were it eternal. The nuptial hour —
                            the vows — the priestly ceremony-—the thrilling touch— the feast, the music and the dance — the five senses in
                            bewildering and dazzling blaze, form a perfect oriflamme, even with the golden spear through the heart; but from
                            this very hour the blaze diminishes — grows less and less as beauty fades and trials come, till it nickers and
                            disappears, which all the kindling-wood brought to the altar fails to nenew ; we despairingly stir the coals,
                            then the embers, again and again, producing some warmth, but colder, and colder, and colder they grow, until
                            nothing is left but cinders and ashes. They are dead. But the spiritual and regenerative increases, grows
                            brighter and brighter, and stronger and stronger, time without end. Its life is eternal. Now, which? The true
                            follower of Christ occupies this higher ground. Am I now understood ? Thee asks: " Are not body, soul and mind
                            so closely related that what benefits and pleases one, just as surely affects the other in the same degree 1" I
                            answer, by no means; all philosophers agree that spirit and body are distinct and contradictory substances. The
                            body loves sexual lusts, when the spirit is disgusted by them — the body has the pleasure, the spirit the pain.
                            The body may be sick, the spirit well. The body may be burned at the stake, the spirit rejoice. All these are
                            undeniable. If Epicurus meant what his language conveys,I indorse the most of what thee has quoted, but the
                            difference between us is, that while we " quiet the passions by subduing them, thee subdues them by gratifying
                            them ! So thee should not have quoted Epicurus to sustain thee. But thee further says: " It is not for Shakers
                            84 <pb n="85" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 85 to purify the race by regeneration." How does thee know ? If
                            purified at all, it must be done either by generation or regeneration; generation has been trying its hand "
                            fast and loose " for some thousands of years and has proved an utter failure. Suppose we now agree to try
                            regeneration. Should it fail, then our case will be hopeless. Thee adds, " A few reformed drunkards will never
                            make a temperate world," what then ? will the moderate drinkers do it, or must we depend on the drunkards
                            themselves ? Thee proposes to get all the passions " on the honor line" by moderate usage, but thee will find
                            that there is no cure for drunkenness, occasioned either by the wine of the grape or the wine of fornication,
                            but that of total abstinence ; no sensualist can be reformed by a moderate sensuality. Badly as we may hate it,
                            total abstinence and separation from the companionship of such is the only sure remedy. Shakerism does not say,
                            no marriage and no children, but says marriage and children for those who desire them ; but in order to escape
                            the stigma of sensualism, they must be as orderly at least, as are the birds of the forest — I mean no offense —
                            please permit me to be plain. Any contact of the sexes, married or unmarried, for mere pleasure is sensuality ;
                            who, then, on the lower plane is clear 1 Shakers contend that marriage is not Christian because its founder was
                            not a generator, but a regenerator. The work of the former is below, and performed in the dark ; the work of the
                            latter is above and performed in the light. The one is absolutely the works of darkness, the other the works of
                            light. Now please do not cal] us " creed-bound " because we cannot blend the two into one. This would be as
                            impossible as to blend light and darkness together. To persons coming up and standing and walking in this light,
                            it is impossible for them to do any thing in the dark, for there is no darkness there to do it in. I am
                            wondering now if I am plain enough to be understood. Thee thinks " Shakers must marry or come to nothing ;" bnt
                            they could not marry without coming to nothing ! This has often been predicted by moderate drinkers in the last
                            hundred years. Marriage un-Shakerizes and un-Christiauizes all who engage in it. But there is nothing to hinder
                            any from marrying who so desire. There is no element up in the regenerative world of light adapted to it,
                            nothing in harmony with or congenial to it; therefore as the door is open and the stairway clear all such go
                            below of choice. But the regenerators, who can blame them for looking upon such with the eyes of the good
                            apostle, who in his coarse language compares it to the " dog returning to his vomit, and the sow that was washed
                            to her wallowing in the mire I" I trust thee will have charity for this plainness of speech, as it seems I
                            cannot be understood without it, as all I have here said is contained in substance in the book which thee has
                            carefully read. That the Greek philosophers and stoics avoided sexual indulgence to promote vigor and bodily
                            health is true, and a strong argument in its favor. That the idea took visible form in our evoluting world and
                            was taught and lived by the Essenes and others and failed, is no evidence of it not being elevating to its
                            devotees. In all history the virgin state has stood high,if not above every other condition. Witness the virgins
                            who watched in turns by night and day the sacred fire on the altar of Vesta ; but I need not cite cases. History
                            is replete with them. It is by no means a marvel that Christ took this highest ground, not for the body but the
                            soul, He is the first in our world's history that touched bottom. Leaving the body He comes directly to spirit
                            elevation and says : " Whosoever looketh upon a woman (married or unmarried) to lust after her hath committed
                            adultery in heart." Not one before Him ever touched this ground. If the thought, motive, look and action are the
                            same in the married as in the unmarried, the sensuality and the adultery are the same. So all the efforts on the
                            part of scribblers to place Jesus on a level or a little below " fifteen other crucified saviours," in order to
                            save their lusts are futile, as none who preceded Him ever entered the soul-world as did Jesus. His acceptance
                            of all that was good and true before Him, which His followers now do, goes to His credit instead of His
                            disparagement. Thee says : " A marriage <pb n="86" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. of one man to one woman
                            seems to be the highest outgrowth of our civilization ;" this is true of the generative and rudimental plane.
                            The only advantage man, on this plane, can have over the birds, is, he can build a finer nest—that's all. As to
                            his " honor line " being equal to the birds, we dare not affirm. The birds obey the law of nature ; but of the
                            species homo, where is the pair on the rolling planet that so govern themselves ? It is a shame to say it, but
                            they cannot be found. Oh ! would I not be thankful to be able to make one exception ! But none are so temperate,
                            none so self-governed, none ? no, not one ! Thee says : "Offer your young men and maidens a good home, love and
                            marriage, and how many would refuse them 1" Of this I cannot say, but I have known fortunes offered and refused.
                            Thee says : " Knowledge alone has the key to the door that must be opened for the entrance of the goddess of
                            love and purity," By speaking of the physiological only, thee seems to recognize no other. There are two
                            distinct kinds of knowledge, intellectual and spiritual; it is improper to apply physiological knowledge to the
                            spirit, this pertains to the body. The difference between animals and man is this, the former are
                            animo-intettectual, the latter besides the animal are intellecto-spiritual. All humans who have no spiritual
                            knowledge are directly on the line of intellectual anr mals. The infidel who recognizes this has put one foot at
                            least on the round of the spiritual ladder, making further ascension possible. Thee thinks I " overdo till the
                            good becomes evil." Good cannot become evil; but thee says we are " so bound up by creed." Why, sister, we have
                            no creed, unless it be to vie with each other in doing good. But we must have order in the regenerative as thee
                            must in the generative ; without which order the celestial heavens would become a bedlam ; but we are the freest
                            of the free, as all our bonds are self-imposed, bringing a happiness which the world of generators know nothing
                            of. -While below they are fettered and bound by unbreakable chains, imposed on them, for which all their
                            pleasures are not quid pro quo. Their very souls are paralyzed by the deadening stroke of that " triple bolt,
                            the world, flesh and devil," to whom life, vigor and true happiness cannot be restored until they " pant for the
                            higher state of righteousness as the hart for the water brook." Then if they will hold up their beseeching hands
                            they will rind angels on the stair-way to help them up, saying, " come up hither;" and when rescued, the tongues
                            of angels cannot express the joy they will feel at their soul's deliverance. This is no fiction, but a reality
                            now attested by a cloud of witnesses, in whom Christ has appeared for the redemption of the world.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eads</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nihilism - socialism - Shakerism - which?" TEIform="index"/>NIHILISM - SOCIALISM - SHAKERISM WHICH?</head><p TEIform="p">Ed. S. Manifesto : Though absent from you in body, I am often with you — and " the Zion of our God"—-in
                                spirit, with you in moral travel, and with you in your earnest efforts to rightly educate and build up a
                                divine humanity, golden with moral beauty, purity and love. Traveling, as I do, staff in hand, in nearly all
                                lands and climes — Russia, France and America— I cannot well fail of hearing the ringing words Nihilism,
                                Socialism, Shakerism — a trinity of unlikes! But what is Nihilism, and what do Russians mean by it? They
                                mean j ust this : anarchy — destruction without reconstruction. The existence of God, the national
                                government, religion, morality and family laws are to the Nihilists equally odious, and should be utterly
                                destroyed. Because "nothing" as it exists suits them, they are called Nihilists, maintaining " that no one
                                should be bound by laws, or even moral obligations of any kind, but that everybody should be allowed to do
                                exactly as he pleases." But I prefer to let Michael Bakunin, the father of the Nihilistic movement in
                                Europe, speak for himself. These are among his published words : The world is a lie. The lie must be stamped
                                out. <pb n="87" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 87 It is our mission to destroy the Lie ; and, to effect
                                this, we must begin at the very commencement. Now, the beginning of all those lies which have ground down
                                this poor world in slavery is God. For many hundred years monarchs and priests have inoculated the hearts
                                and minds of mankind with this notion of a God ruling over the world. They have also invented for the people
                                the notion of another world, in which their God is to punish those who have refused to obey their degrading
                                laws here on earth. This God is nothing but the personification of absolute tyranny, and has been invented
                                with a view of either frightening or alluring nine-tenths of the human race into submission to the remaining
                                tenth. * * * Tear out of your hearts the belief in the existence of God; for, as long as an atom of that
                                silly superstition remains in your minds, you will never know what freedom is. When you have got rid of the
                                belief in this priest-begotten God, and when, moreover, you are convinced that your existence, and that of
                                the surrounding world, is due to the conglomeration of atoms, in accordance with the laws of gravity and
                                attraction, then, and then only, you will have accomplished the first step toward liberty, and you will
                                experience less difficulty in ridding your minds of that second lie which tyranny has invented. The first
                                lie is God. The second lie is Right. Might invented the fiction of Right. When you have freed your minds
                                from the fear of a God, and from that childish respect for the fiction of Bight, then all the remaining
                                chains which bind you, and which are called science, civilization, property, marriage, morality and justice,
                                will snap asunder like threads. Let your own happiness be your only law. * * * The only revolution which can
                                remedy the ills of the people is that which will tear up every notion of government by its very roots.
                                Having this object in view, the Revolutionary Committee does not propose to subject the people to any
                                directing organization. The future order of things will doubtless originate with the people themselves; but
                                we must leave that to future generations. Our mission is only one of universal, relentless and
                                terror-striking destruction. If the above doctrines and iconoclastic theories were not begotten of the devil
                                and cradled in the " hells," to use a term of Swedenborg, then devils and hells have no existence. And yet,
                                such principles and such abominable atheistic teachings and political theories not only find a response in
                                the hearts of certain bumptious Americans, but they quite generally crop out at the " Free-thinking"
                                conventions of Materialists. But is the Socialism of Germany, or the Communism that so often boils and
                                bubbles up in France, preferable in any way to the Nihilism of Russia? Arriving in Paris, on my first tour
                                around the world, I saw the signs of war and Communistic vandalism. Think of it : the Commune shouting "
                                liberty, fraternity and equality ! " and yet murdering the clergy, firing the city of Paris, and
                                obliterating all evidences of former genius and culture! Possibly the Thiers government was a little
                                oppressive ; but did this justify the cry of the mad multitude, " Repeal all law I" —" Fire the churches ! "
                                — " Suppress the newspapers!" — " Abolish marriages!"—burn the museums,the libraries and the granaries, and
                                other atrocities of the Commune ? Lest I be thought partisan and partial in arraigning and condemning such
                                phases of Nihilism, Socialism and Communism of the old world as are finding sympathizers in this country,
                                permit me to quote from the late Brooklyn speech of Hon. E. B. Washburne, ex-Minister to France : When the
                                National Guard became mutinous, unfortunately the government did not act at once and disarm it at whatever
                                cost. It took no resolute steps in that direction, and the spirit of insubordination grew by what it fed on.
                                * * * * The insurrection of the 18th of March, 1871, was the commencement of an orgy of blood and crime,
                                incendiarism, cruelty, ruin and desolation, in the presence of which the world stands aghast. It was on the
                                morning of the 18th of March that the Government had attempted to get possession of the heights of
                                Montmartre and retake the cannon which were in the possession of the National Guard ; but that movement
                                utterly failed, for as soon as the National Guard and the Government troops came within sight of each other
                                the Government troops fraternized with the guard and refused to fire upon them. By four o'clock in the
                                afternoon the insurrectionist forces practically controlled the whole city. They had seized two gentlemen,
                                General Clement Thomas and Lecomte, bringing them to a mock court-martial in a little room. They were
                                condemned to death, and immediately shot in an adjoining garden. The Government, seeing the desperate
                                situation.without <pb n="88" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. any means of defense, immediately left Paris
                                for Versailles, leaving the National Guard in absolute control of the city. * * The men put in power by the
                                Commune had neither honesty, ability, nor executive capacity. There was no weight to be given to the talk of
                                these men that they were fighting for their liberty and municipal rights. It was a fight merely for power
                                and plunder, and to free themselves from the restraints of law. Governed by no principle and having no
                                regard for public right, they bawled for a Republic; but their first act was to murder General Clement
                                Thomas, a republican all his life, driven out of France as such, by Napoleon, at the coup d'etat of 1851,
                                and only returning to his native land after eighteen years of exile to offer his sword to his country in the
                                hour of her direst need. The reign of the Commune was the force of desperate and wicked men, unlimited,
                                unchecked, unrestrained by any human power. The most infamous and bloody decrees were issued by the Commune.
                                Fortune, business, public and rjrivate, every industry, labor, financial enterprise, were all buried in one
                                common grave, and there was everywhere devastation, desolation and ruin. There was the commission of every
                                outrage, plunder, imprisonment, robbery and every species of persecution. * * * The governing power during
                                this period was a body calling itself the Commune of Paris, and the members were the most desperate and
                                debauched scoundrels in all the purlieus of the city, but many of them highly educated and cultivated men.
                                They were far more infamous than the same class of men in the worst days of the Roman Empire, whose names
                                have been consigned to eternal infamy by the pen of Tacitus. The orders of this body were instantly and
                                summarily executed by the National Guard, fed, pampered and corrupted, ever ready to carry out its infernal
                                behests, restrained by no fear of the laws of God nor man, and with appetites whetted for plunder and blood,
                                murder, burning, imprisonment and torture. They burned down the Tuileries and the house of Thiers ; they
                                burned the Hotel de Ville and the buildings of the Ministry of Finance and Police, and the Legion of Honor,
                                the great palace of the Court of Cassation, and overturned the Column Vendome and at last endeavored to burn
                                the whole city. I quote thus largely from the records and doings of Nihilism, Socialism and French Communism
                                that the chasm — the varied contrast between those theories of ambitious worldly men — sometimes called "
                                progressives"— and the true genius and logical outcome of Shakerism, alias law, order and spiritual growth,
                                may appear the more wide and appalling. The primordial principles of Shakerism, if I rightly understand
                                them, are purity, peace and a united inheritance. These principles are permanent and unchangeable, and
                                accordingly the divine church of the ages built upon them—the Apostolic church warmed by the pentecostal
                                fires of spiritual truth, was and necessarily is conservative— that is to say it conserves the good and the
                                true of the past, while it appropriates all that is good and wise and true in the present. If I correctly
                                read the world this is the drift period—the age of unrest. The old order of things is unsettled, and the
                                noisy and pretentious flock to the front. The solid-pillar men in every age are retiring and quiet. I feel
                                quite sure that since our civil war America has been waxing worse and worse, morally and spiritually. The
                                war-shadow, through reflex action, is still over us, an irreligious, unprincipled " Socialism " is being
                                diffused through the land, indulging in such sentiments as these : " Away with all restraint," " the
                                passions should have free play," " let nature take her course," " be independent," " be free." These
                                impulses and teachings are the dogmas of demons. There is a class of spiritists, and certain ex-Shakers, who
                                are everlastingly dilating upon " liberty " and " more freedom." These do not seem to distinguish between
                                liberty and license, between law and the disorderly elements of a wild, uncultivated nature. Freedom is a
                                curse to mean, uncultured, impulsive, and unbalanced men. Only angels can safely live in, and breathe the
                                atmosphere of absolute freedom. This persistent shriek for freedom is often ill-timed. There is not a
                                blood-sucking mosquito this side the "dismal swamp'" of the South,but that says, " give me freedom." There's
                                not a prowling wolf in the forest, but that says, " away with the walls that inclose the sheepfold ; give me
                                freedom!" There's not a brawling inebriate — red-faced and profane, reeling out from the liquor den — that
                                does not say, " give me freedom — I have an inalienable right to drink, or put into my 88 <pb n="89" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 89 body what I please." None can fail to see that this is the boast of
                                the brute — the reasoning of the animal rather than the man, or the angel. That truly great English writer,
                                Ruskin, says: You hear every day great numbers of foolish people speaking about liberty, as if it were such
                                an honorable thing; so far from being that, it is, on the whole, and in the broadest sense, dishonorable,
                                and an attribute of the lower creatures. No human being, however great or powerful, was ever so free as a
                                fish. There is always something that he must or must not do ; while the fish may do whatever he likes. * * *
                                Throughout the world, of the two abstract things, liberty and restraint, restraint is always the more
                                honorable. It is true, indeed, that in these and all other matters you never can reason finally from the
                                abstraction," for both liberty and restraint are good when they are nobly chosen, and both are bad when they
                                are basely chosen; but of the two, I repeat, it is restraint which characterizes the higher creature, and
                                betters the lower creature ; and, from the ministering of the archangel to the labor of the insect — from
                                the poisinsg of the planets to the gravitation of a grain of dust—'the power and glory of all creatures, and
                                all matter, consist in their obedience, not in their freedom. Freedom with its proper limitations is well,
                                and so knowledge is well, but this persistent search for knowledge, rather than for wisdom and moral truth,
                                is to be numbered among the follies of the age. The highest significance of the universe is not the
                                gathering of shells — not the collection of dry facts; nor the study of rigid physical laws; but in studying
                                a living humanity, and seeking the baptismal light of heaven, that sickness may be remedied, poverty
                                abolished, penitentiaries transformed into schools of reform, the moral nature of the masses quickened, and
                                the Christ-spirit of love, and peace, and purity, made the crowning glory of a resurrected humanity.
                                Shakerism, seen in connection with the incoming cycle, is all rainbowed with promise, and aflame with the
                                light and the love of God. Power does not consist in numbers. The gulf stream, in comparison with the ocean,
                                is small; it sometimes seems as though the ocean would swallow it up; yet there it remains in the ocean, but
                                not of the ocean; there it remains an everlasting river flowing steadily, bearing the choice treasures of
                                the tropics to colder climes — changing temperatures, modifying the swift-footed winds, spreading the
                                greater blessings of summer warmth — and all as a potency and promise of golden fruitage and a waving
                                harvest. So with believers, in the world, but not of the world — so with truth victorious in the end. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles Harnmonton, N. J.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Queries to a Boston materialist" TEIform="index"/>QUERIES TO A BOSTON MATERIALIST</head><p TEIform="p">Respected Friend : I have read your article " Jesus and the Gospel." The inquiry is not whether Jesus of
                                Nazareth ever lived, or had an immaculate conception, or that His mission was attended with supernatural
                                manifestations. The inquiry is: Can you and I live a divine life now ? If in the nature of things we cannot,
                                would we be able to form a conception of a divine life? or would the ideals associated with the character of
                                Jesus ever exist ? How is it that this Judean peasant cannot be dismissed from our minds? From the days of
                                Voltaire to our own, a period of intense analytic action, continued efforts have been made to stamp Him out;
                                but the more of that there is done, the more He is present. Renan, and a host of others, try to strip Him of
                                every thing supernatural. I object not, yet this same Renan declares that " without Jesus of Nazareth all
                                history is incomprehensible." You are acquainted with the nature of things, what do they say in this case ?
                                First: Man exists. Secondly: Emotions are the forces of his being. Thirdly: They are dual — animal emotions
                                represented by the propensities, and divine emotions represented by manifestations of benevolence, mercy and
                                aspirations after, and a growth into these divine attributes. All human manifestations refer themselves to
                                these emotions, and must be either Just, Satanic, or Divine. Each has its own organic law. The Just, is the
                                love of self, and others as self. The Satanic, is the love of self at the expense of others. The Divine, the
                                love of others at the expense of self. Allow me to repeat the inquiry: Can you <pb n="90" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. and I live a divine life now 1 I answer in the affirmative ; and that it is in accordance
                                with the nature of things to do so whenever we shall so choose. But it is not in the na" ture of things to
                                be Satanic and Divine at the same time. Therefore, if you or I will be divine, we must come out from under
                                the power of the emotions represented by the propensities — die to them — rise out of the Satanic, through
                                the Just, into the Divine In short, be unearthed. We are so covered up with animal, earthly conditions, that
                                the divine in us can hardly breathe. No need of that; when we get ready we can rise up and shake these
                                conditions off. Why not now ? When you do, you will be the peer of the man of Nazareth ; and be ab]e to
                                understand and to judge of Him. Otherwise, you are not His peer, and cannot judge Him. Truly your friend.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Fraser</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is Christ's example a safe rule of life?" TEIform="index"/>IS CHRIST'S EXAMPLE A SAFE RULE OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> It is a beautifully growing truth, evidenced by numerous contributions, finding their acceptance by and
                                through the religious press, that Christianity is a life, and not merely an assent to this or that
                                particularly formulated creed. It is also a beautiful subject for thought, to consider, that were Jesus
                                living with us to-day, to what denomination could he and would he give his indorsement ? It is a satisfying
                                fact to our minds that Jesus, instead of entering into any organization, bound by creedal limitations,
                                simply lived a superior life to any other life previously lived, and this life is the genuine of
                                Christianity. He faulted not the laws of Moses; he did not seek to build a church upon the ruins of Judaism;
                                but rather urged those who sought eternal life to " keep the commandments ;" after which, if any " would be
                                more perfect" than the law taught, then "come and follow me." It would be very well for those who use
                                trenchant tongues and pens in denunciation of other denominations than their own to recollect, that it was
                                many years after the death of Jesus before the formula of a Christian creed was thought of. That Jesus never
                                intimated the necessity of any. That he simply lived the Christ life, and lovingly invited " all who were
                                able to come and follow " the same. It is but fair for us to admit, that there are other religions than that
                                of Jesus Christ which contain many elements of great salvation. The promise of God to Moses to remove all
                                sickness from the midst of his people was fulfilled most astonishingly, by the greatest salvation from
                                physical disorders unto all who kept the Judaical Law ; and it is a truth too frequently lost sight of, that
                                before Jesus accepted any as fit companions for his discipleship, that he " healed them " of their physical
                                infirmities. Giving credit to the law for the physical salvations it insures to its faithful adherents, we
                                pass on to the higher salvations and redeeming qualities of genuine Christianity, found by simply following
                                Christ's life. Regardless of the apostle's creed, or any and all other theological arrangements — and were
                                they all lost in the labyrinths of oblivion perhaps it were better — we assert Christ's life to be the only
                                genuine Christianity, and one that is so safe to believe in and to follow, that not only all the salvations
                                which 90 <pb n="91" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 91 Jesus experienced will inevitably succeed, but the
                                redeeming features of the Christ will be attained unto thereby; and moreover, that neither the salvations
                                nor redemptions of Christ can ever be obtained, excepting by living Christianity as Jesus lived it. While we
                                claim for the Shaker faith directions therein unto " a higher life " than any predecessor of Jesus ever
                                taught, we do not claim that any nor all are lost who do not fully live it, excepting that the loss is by
                                comparison — they are not so fully saved nor elevated unto Christ life. We Shakers simply live as nearly
                                like Jesus as we are able, because we deem it the very best life for us ; that it is a safe guide unto
                                heavenly realms of thought, feeling and action, and which no other life differing from that of Jesus can
                                lead us unto. We know the world at large differ with us, not in the theoretical admiration of the beautiful
                                life of Jesus, the Christ; but in accepting the necessity of living like Jesus, to obtain what he obtained
                                by so living, thus showing a practical admiration. We strive to be content, amid the jeers of a sneering
                                world, that we have chosen the better part, in following Jesus through all of his self-denials, and are
                                rewarded, abundantly, with salvations and redemptions which none, nor all worldly wisdom nor pleasures can
                                secure to us, inasmuch as we unselfishly follow the Christ. So far as we are concerned, we know Christ's
                                life is best for us ; and that is our only creed, our only Christianity. It is a safe guide to live by, it
                                is safer to die by, and therefore we present it as best. While striving for the full attainment of the
                                higher life and its complete redemptions like unto Christ's, we would ever be reminded that Christian life
                                is as broad in its Charity, as it is elevated in its love of heavenly things. That it is heaven brought to
                                earth ; and that there is in it no possibility of our being too narrow in our views to be well proportioned
                                with our elevations. The full manhood and womanhood of Christ are known by a broad, boundless virgin purity;
                                by an ever-pervading and boundless peace spirit; by a universal love for all mankind, and with desires for
                                their enlightenment that Christ's life is simple and genuine Christianity, and that this is the best and
                                safest religion known ; that those who will to live it, are made welcome to all the salvations and
                                redemptions which heaven has ever promised, and that these are possible on the earth. As truly as we know
                                that two and two make four, so truly do we know that a genuine Shaker life, with its practical Virgin
                                Purity, its Peace, its Brotherly love, and Freedom from worldly taint, lead to the same happy results which
                                Jesus Christ was resurrected unto, and that for all who " are alia" to live it, it will prove to be a
                                genuine and most active Christianity, and this is safe, this is best. -fe</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Starving Ireland" TEIform="index"/>Starving Ireland</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> It is a sorrowful fact, but we are forced to the fear that it is too true, that Roman Catholic
                                ecclesiasticism has more to do with the starvation of Ireland than aught else! The inquiries are pertinent:
                                Why are the four <pb n="92" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 92 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. counties in which Roman Catholicism greatly
                                predominates caused to suffer so much more than "all the rest ? " Why is it, that Scotland, with a poorer
                                soil, and the same, unjust,rental system active, is and has been exempt from the ravages of starvation,
                                while Ireland's wails have been so frequently heard across the seas? Let Roman Catholicism confess its sins,
                                beginning at the Head, and being reformed, its children will not want nor cry for bread.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pope on marriage" TEIform="index"/>The Pope on Marriage</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> In a recently issued encyclical letter of Leo XIII, upon the sanctity of marriage, the following curious
                                passage occurs: * * * " Jesus Christ, the author of the New Testament, transferred marriage from a natural
                                function to a sacrament, and attributed to his church all the legislative and judicial control of it as a
                                binding instrument!" Now we know, as far as the Pope can tell us, who it was that first made marriage a
                                sacrament in the Christian Church! The records of the New Testament had informed us of the Virgin Celibacy
                                of Jesus, and of his demands upon, all of his disciples, to forsake marriage, war, private property and
                                worldly entanglements. We are therein made aware, also, that his immediate disciples did " forsake all to
                                follow him; fathers, mothers, wives, children, houses, lands, and even their lives after the flesh." And in
                                the absence of any information therein as to who changed this Christian arrangement, the flesh-loving
                                "followers" (?) of Jesus will render thanks to the Pope. We opine, however, that the New Testament account
                                of Christ's life and teachings will take precedence of the Pope's, and that all sensible professors of
                                Christianity will simply admit that marriage, private property, war and worldly contamination, nowhere find
                                any recognition as elements of Christianity in Jesus nor disciples, but were compromises of Paul's with the
                                ''foolish Galatians" and " carnal Corinthians" of his day, and whose successors demand these privileges now
                                as ever, as an assuagement to their worldly, but unchristian lusts. Mark the distinction : " The children of
                                the world marry; " but my children— "the children of the Resurrection J&gt; — "I am the Resurrection — do not
                                marry," but live heavenly, like the angels ; very much as the Shakers profess to and ought to live. The
                                Shaker Manifesto in its turn issues an older, original, Christian, encyclical letter : Marriage is not of
                                Christ ; nor the works of marriage; but belong to the worldly order, the followers of the first Adam.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Active friendship" TEIform="index"/>Active Friendship</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> It is with feelings of deep gratitude that we turn often to view, as models of unselfishenss, those who
                                continue the staunch friends of The Manifesto ; and who give so many reminders of their genuine friendship
                                by generous helps to this office in the circulation of this, our little missionary sheet. Without the
                                possible hope of any pecuniary reward (and while a very few illiberal unShakers are using their little
                                opposition to obtain an unenviable reward), are rendering much missionary help gratuitously, thus "lending
                                    <pb n="93" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 93 to the Lord," who will not fail to make returns with
                                interest. While we thus render partial thanks to those unselfish enough to confer upon us every little help,
                                we would also inform those receiving specimen copies of The Manifesto, that it is by and through the efforts
                                of some very true and unselfish friends. If any would be glad thus to help us according to their ability, we
                                ask a kindly reading of " Special Notice " on cover, and particularly that part addressed to the " Liberally
                                Inclined." And to those receiving sample copies, we would respectfully ask of those who are able to send us
                                their subscriptions.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This number" TEIform="index"/>This Number</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Of the Manifesto will be found full of grand articles from talented contributors. Could we present such an
                                array of truths invariably, we would willingly lay our pen down. We call especial attention to articles from
                                Elders A very, Fraser, Eads and Evans. Barring the antique style of pronouns. Elder Eads pays some
                                gentlemanly blows for our side as against his talented Quaker Materialist, whose letter was too lengthy for
                                our space. That " Lizzie Morton " we more than suspect is the same who answered Charlotte Cushman more than
                                forty years ago, and the conclusion of which verily seemed to be always in Charlotte's mind: " And when some
                                flattering knaves around your pathway tread, Just think of what a Shaker girl has said!" We have no
                                apologies to make for the music, it is simply splendid and beautiful.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boys wanted" TEIform="index"/>BOYS WANTED</head><p TEIform="p"> Boys of spirit, boys of will, Boys of muscle, brain and power, Fit to cope with any thing — These are wanted
                                every hour. Not the weak and whining drones That all troubles magnify — Not the watchword of " I can't," But
                                the noble one " I'll try." Do what'er you have to do With a true and earnest zeal ; Bend your sinews to the
                                task ; " Put your shoulder to the wheel." Though your duty may be hard, Look not on it as on ill; If it be
                                an honest task, Do it with an honest will.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Explaining a text" TEIform="index"/>EXPLAINING A TEXT</head><p TEIform="p"> A little girl saw hanging in her Sundayschool room this text on an illuminated card : " Let us not be weary
                                in well-doing ; for in due season we shall reap, if we faint not." She caught the idea of its teaching, and
                                in attempting to repeat it at her home she gave a somewhat free rendering in this form: " Don't you get
                                tired in doing good ; for if you don't faint away, by and by you'll get your pay." The truth as she put it
                                is worth bearing in mind.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Camel and the miller" TEIform="index"/>THE CAMEL AND THE MILLER</head><p TEIform="p"> Did you ever hear the fable of the camel and the miller ? One night a miller was waked up by his camel
                                trying to get his nose into the tent. "It's very cold out here," said the camel. " I only want to put my
                                nose in." The miller made no objection. After a while the camel asked leave to have his neck in, then his
                                fore feet ; and so, little by little, it crowded in its whole body. This, as you may well think, was very
                                disagreeable to the miller, and he bitterly complained to the forth-putting beast. " If you don't like it,
                                you may go," answered the camel. " As for me, I've got possession, and I shall stay. You can't get rid of me
                                    <pb n="94" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 94 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. now." Do you know what the camel is like 1 Bad habits ;
                                little sins. Guard against the first approaches,, the most plausible excuses, only the NOSE of sin. If you
                                do not, you are in danger. It will surely edge itself slowly in, and you are overpowered before you know it.
                                Be on your guard. Watch.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust a boy" TEIform="index"/>TRUST A BOY</head><p TEIform="p"> During the session of the late Episcopal convention in Boston, the Bishop of Louisiana, in crossing the
                                Common, met a boy, whose face he fancied, and, calling to him, asked him if he had any thing to do just
                                then, to which he said no. " Are you a good boy 1" The little fellow scratched his head and replied : " I am
                                not a very good boy. T cuss a little sometimes." That candid answer inspired the bishop with confidence, and
                                he then said, after giving his name and address: "I want you to go to a certain place and get a bundle for
                                me and bring it to my hotel." There will be a charge of eight dollars. Here is the money to pay it, and half
                                a dollar which you will keep for doing the errand." On his return to the hotel, the bishop's friends laughed
                                at him for his credulity, telling him that he would never see the boy or the bundle or the money again ; but
                                in half an hour the young chap returned, bringing the bundle and a receipted bill for eight dollars and
                                a-half, the bishop having made a slight mistake as to the amount that was due. " How did you manage to pay
                                the extra half dollar?" he inquired. " I took the money you gave me for the job. I knew that you would make
                                it all right." And " all right " it was made, and I have no doubt that the confidence that was reposed in
                                that boy, because of his truthfulness, will do him good as long as he lives.—Bishop Glarlc.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fitly answered" TEIform="index"/>FITLY ANSWERED</head><p TEIform="p"> A young city fop, in company with some belles of fashion, was riding into the country a pleasuring, when
                                they saw a rustic looking country lad at work by the roadside. Thinking it a fine opportunity to show his
                                wit to the damsels, by sporting with the poor boy's ignorance, he accosted him: " Ca'n you inform me, Mr.
                                Zebedee, how far it is to where I am going, and which is the most direct road ? " Poor Zebby, not the least
                                daunted, but with the most sober and composed face, said: " If you are going to the gallows, it is but a
                                short distance ; if to jail, it stands but a few rods this side; but if only to poverty and disgrace, you
                                are now approaching your journey's end ; and as for the most direct road to either, you are now in it, and
                                cannot miss the way." The dandy dropped his head and drove on. When fine clothes won't treat rusty ones
                                politely, it's a sure sign there's a fool in them.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Obituaries</head><p TEIform="p">We are necessitated to announce the demise of three of our very faithful and prominent members; and as we do
                                so would express the hope that there may be three others as determinedly active to sustain the Cause of
                                Christ, to step in their places, thus keeping the ranks solid, and presenting an attractive array towards
                                any who may be feeling for more Godwardness than than they can find elsewhere.</p><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fairbanks, Nancy F." TEIform="index"/>Nancy F. Fairbanks</head><p TEIform="p"> At Harvard, Mass., Feb. 28, , aged 73 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lawson, Ann" TEIform="index"/>Ann Lawson</head><p TEIform="p"> At Groveland, N. Y., Feb. 27, , aged 72 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thayer, Sewell G." TEIform="index"/>Sewell G. Thayer</head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, 0., Feb. 27, , aged 78 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>RECEIVED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">From Isaac Auger, $10.50. From Melinda Ilubbard, $24.00. From Herman Muller, a gift of $5.00.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A king's jester was once asked..." TEIform="index"/>A king's jester was once asked...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A king's jester was once asked, " What kind of a place do you think heaven to be ? " "A place," said he, "
                                where nought but good is spoken of the neighbor." " And in what," it was again urged, " does its supreme
                                happiness consist ? " " In the feeling that no one will slander me there, and that, if I have any faults, it
                                will be so unfashionable to speak of them, that I and all will soon forget them."</p></div3></div2><pb n="95" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecration" TEIform="index"/>CONSECRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>Joseph Parker</byline><p TEIform="p"> Harvard, Mass. 1. Here's my heart, to God I give it, Voice and tongue to praise his name; 2. I've a conscience
                            thus protected, Worth a throne and diadem; 3. I have feet with God they're walking, For with gospel peace
                            they're shod; 4. I have ears to hear the story, Men and angels love to tell; I have life, to Him I live it,—
                            Hands, to Him devote the same. I've a mansion well selected In the New Jerusalem. Most familiarly Tarn talking,
                            As I take my walk with God. Eyes to see the rising glory, Which shall Zion's triumphs swell. I've a field, to
                            sow and reap it, And must reap what e'er it grows; Hence I have in this connection, Thus prepared a happy home;
                            I have tho't, the greatest pleasure That the Universe can sing; I have pray'r, to God I make it, While mine eye
                            His throne surveys; I've a paradise, I'll keep it, For it blossoms as the rose. Such a home, that my affeetion
                            Does not. will not, cannot roam. There is no material treasure, Which can such posessions bring. I've a golden
                            harp, I'll wake it, To a song of endless praise. I</p></div2><pb n="96" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Another cheap series of popular reading..." TEIform="index"/>Another cheap series of popular reading...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Another cheap series of popular reading, in the quarto form of the " libraries" so much in vogue, but
                                containing books of a high order of merit, has been started by I. K. Funk &amp; Co., 21 Barclay street,
                                New York&gt; under the title of the Standard Series. It begins excellently, the first number (price, twelve
                                cents) containing the full text of the Eev. Spurgeon's John Plough man's Talk, or Plain Advice to Plain
                                People — and also Carlyle's well-known essay On the Choice of Books. The second and third issues will be
                                Thomas Hughes' The Manliness of Christ (price, ten cents), and six selected essays of Macauley's (price,
                                fifteen cents). The type is large and the impression neat; and the numbers are issued in a stout paper
                                cover. The above firm seem determined not to be outdone by the publishers of flashy literature, so far as
                                the cheapness of the better material is concerned. Let the mind " reach after heavenly things,'' and try the
                                above.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Another of the new periodicals..." TEIform="index"/>Another of the new periodicals...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Another of the new periodicals established at the beginning of the present year is The Practical American, a
                                large illustrated monthly paper of thirty-two pages, containing intelligent and serviceable articles on
                                subjects connected with manufacturing and building. It is edited and published by Dr. P. H. Vander Weyde, at
                                34 Park Row, New York, at a dollar and a half a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words of us" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS OF US</head><p TEIform="p"> That invaluable periodical, Foote's Health Monthly, reminds its thousands of readers that : " The Shaker
                            Manifesto is the title of a twenty-four page journal which comes to us regularly as an exchange. It is the
                            official paper of the Shaker societies in the United States, and serves a useful purpose to their members as a
                            medium of thought exchange; but the interest in it is by no means limited to them, for it contains exposition of
                            Shaker doctrines and customs that makes it very readable to all who are interested in various phases of religion
                            and experiments in communistic living. The Shakers are much misunderstood, and often misrepresented by those who
                            attempt to tell something of them ; and any one who desires to become rightly informed concerning their
                            institutions, ideas and customs, cannot find a better way than by sending sixty cents for a year's subscription
                            to The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y." And that very big light in dark places— the noble and chaste New
                            Jerusalem Messenger, New York, thus compliments and copies us : " The Shaker Manifesto does not believe in the
                            doctrine that the death bed is the supreme moment when the usefulness of a religion may be tested. We append the
                            following sensible words : ' One of the strongest arguments favoring Christianity has been that no one has
                            regretted its practice on the death bed. We present a stronger and strongest; no one having lived it, and
                            enjoyed the purity and excellence of its radical features, ever wished to live or die by any other life
                            doctrine. . . The death bed is no place to create a criterion, but the active, healty, good sensed man or woman
                            can tell the truth more effectually.'"</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oh, he whom Jesus loved..." TEIform="index"/>Oh, he whom Jesus loved...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier" TEIform="persName"/>Whittier</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Oh, he whom Jesus loved has truly spoken ! 1 he holier worship, which God deigns to bless, Restores the lost,
                            and heils the spiritbroken, And feeds the widow and the fatherless. Then, brother man, fold to thy heart thy
                            brother ! For where love dwells, the peace of God is there; To worship rightly is to love each other— Each smile
                            a hymn, each kindly deed a prayer. Follow, with reverent steps, the great example Of him whose holy work was
                            doing good : So shall the wide earth seem our Father's temple, Each loving life a psalm of gratitude. Thus shall
                            all shackles fall ; the stormy clangor Of wild war-music o'er the earth shall cease; Love shall tread out the
                            baleful fires' of anger, And in its ashes plant the tree of peace." </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A sweet temper, a pure heart and clean lips are better evidence of God's grace than any profession of godliness" TEIform="index"/>A sweet temper, a pure heart and clean lips are better evidence of God's grace than any profession of godliness
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A Sweet temper, a pure heart and clean lips are better evidence of God's grace than any profession of
                        godliness.</p></div2><!--
    				<pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>