<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0405" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18740501" TEIform="date">May 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="33" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <p>Vol. IV. No. 5. F. W. EVANS, Editor. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY, Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y.. May, 1874: Fifty
                        Cents veh annum</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERANCE</head><p TEIform="p">" Not by might, nor by power, but by the Spirit" intemperance is being suppressed. The
                            movement has a spiritual origin. There is, in the Spirit World, an organized company of men
                            and women, who are appointed to the work of suppressing intemperance, in this country. It is
                            their mission — Woman has been, by intemperance, the chief sufferer. It is meet that she
                            should be the medium of " the powers of the world to come," for its removal. If woman will
                            be content to be the instrument, and not aspire to the Leadership, in the work, prosperity
                            will attend her efforts — for the cause is of God. la her hours of trial and doubt, let her
                            look to God — not to man — and all will be well. Attending a temperance meeting in New York,
                            on the 11th instant, there being present Dio Lewis, Gayland G. Clark and other master minds,
                            nothing more favorably impressed me, than the recognition, by the men, of the fact, that the
                            women should not look to them, as leaders ; but rather to their own inspirational
                            impressions. Woman is at school — to-day she is doing the very thing that man has said, for
                            her to do, would spoil her as woman. Appearing in public — learning to organize — what shall
                            keep her from the Polls ? Who may exclude her from the Courts of Justice, or Halls of
                            Legislation 1 What power shall let, or hinder the Millennium from being realized through
                            such instrumentalities, and by those agencies, that it is alone possible for God to
                            establish a Millennium ? Private virtue is the Granite Rock, upon which the structure of
                            public virtue can safely rest, without fear of settling. Unless the individual women who
                            compose the praying bands, do, in truth, commence the reformation with themselves, by
                            contrition and repentance, their labors, with others, will be in vain. Not being in the
                            Lord, their prayers will be as sounding brass and tinkling cymbal. What we possess, we can
                            minister. When women have suffered and been helped, they can suffer and help others. "Come
                            not at your wives,"—was an injunction of the Ruling Spirit of the Hebrews, to them, when
                            they fain would come near unto God, to be indued with power from on high, in order to
                            overcome and conquer the Canaanites. Gome not at your Husbands, should be the word, in all
                            praying bands, to those women, who would prepare — arm themselves beforehand — to fight the
                            battle of the Lord against the sins of the world, and the giant sin of intemperance in
                            particular. Thus can they say — We have set you an example. Follow us, in self-denial — We
                            are refraining from things as dear to us, as are the things, to you, that we ask you to
                            sacrifice — things as pleasing to our lower, sensuous nature. Then will they speak as having
                            authority — as capable of charity. And they will cast out evils, that go not out, save by
                            fasting and prayer. When the praying women fast from the lusts of their generative nature,
                            they will be weighty in word, and mighty in work, against the minor evils of humanity. Who
                            shall go forth to the battle — The Young Women of the Princes of the Prov- inces. Let them
                            enlist at once in the effort to overthrow the saloon keepers. As soon as the Mothers have
                            inaugurated the movement, in a place, if the Young Women will take it off their hands, and
                            let the Mothers remain at home, in prayer, a double blessing will ensue. At once the Spirit
                            will lead the Young Women to discard many extravagant and false things, about their persons,
                            that now disfigure them, and which disqualify them for active sevv.ice in their appointed
                            field of labor — of battle. The time saved from personal disfiguration will be ample for all
                            their public duties. Sexual purity agrees with simplicity and utility in dress, like the
                            verb with its nominative. Also, I would suggest — modestly— that all mourning dresses be at
                            once omitted, and all useless and vain funeral trappings and ex- penses be abolished, and
                            that the money thus saved be appropriated to purchasing praying dresses for out-door labor.
                            Be ye temperate in all things. Temperance in drink is but one item in the bill of reform
                            that has now begun to roll over America. If the American women will yield them selves to the
                            influence coming from the higher spheres in the Spirit World, a new era will begin, that
                            will, in its unfolding, be of vast national import. Let the women be j ust what they seem to
                            be, and seem to be just what they are — God fearing women — and after the young women have
                            passed through the present disciplinary, preliminary phase of education, a portion of them
                            will become good wives and mothers in the New Earth, and another portion will arise into the
                            New Heavens — the Resurrection Order — to go no more out forever. By my spirit, saith the
                            Lord, the redemption shall come. Let woman look, labor and pray for the wisdom from above,
                            not for that which cometh from man — the wisdom from beneath, and by which man has been so
                            largely guided in organizmg and conducting all so-called civil government; and, in due time
                            she will vote, with man's consent, and sit by his side in courts of justice and halls of
                            legislation. The Millennium dawns !!</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear shaker and shakeress:" TEIform="index"/>My dear Shaker and Shakeress :</head><p TEIform="p">Your continued administrations of Gospel Truth, being a necessity, your friends, who are
                            legion, expect more of the Truth, as it is in Shakerism, from you, than they can get
                            otherwise. This being the fourth year of your labors, we associate it with the "fourth
                            dispensation," under whose benignant enlightenment, our Social Order is established. Your
                            words of counsel, of warning, of cheer and comfort, have fallen, in many places, in good and
                            honest hearts, with singularly healing and soothing effect. May a strong band of holy angels
                            have a supervising influence over your very existence, and instill, more abundantly, through
                            its consecrated Editors, a new Life — The Pure Life of the Spirit — as our New Heavens are
                            to be peopled with a spiritual people. Let your voice, in clarion tones, summon the guests
                            —" Come, for all things are now ready." Zion, in all her branches, can bear replenishing,
                            with redeemed souls, or those who feel the necessity of being redeemed, from their evil
                            natures. Not only do our present established places require filling up, but a further
                            increase, in the near future, will demand more establishments. Spread your wings, ye angelic
                            messenger of good tidings. Rest not, till earth's inhabitants have all heard the good
                            tidings you carry. There is a rest for the people of God. All, who will, may come and
                            partake, and work out their own salvation. No " atonement,"— no war — no slavery—neither
                            physical bondage, nor spiritual bondage — or bigotry. You are charged with the support of,
                            and have well maintained, a higher standard of religion than any other publication. From
                            this extreme southern home of Shakers, receive our meed of commendation, which we cheerfully
                            give. Your mission, to sow the good seed, and to rend the veil of wthe covering cast over
                            all people — tlie flesh — is one of vast importance to suffering humanity. Shakers Wanted.
                            100,000 Shakers wanted, soon as convenient. None need apply, who cannot shake, or learn to
                            shake themselves free from all prejudice, all wrong, all sin—all evil of every name and
                            nature. But, all, who apply, bringing with them the following credentials, will be welcomed,
                            as inquirers, and given every facility to learn of this doctrine, whether it be, or be not,
                            of God: 1st. All honest people. The dishonest would shut their eyes and say, there was no
                            light. 2d. All wishing to live a pure virgin life. 3d. All looking for refuge from the
                            social evil. 4th. All looking to community life, for happiness. 5th. All expecting to work
                            out their salvation. 6th. All who wish to attain the highest good, in this life. 7th. All
                            who will control their appetites and passions. 8th. All who will confess their sins and quit
                            sinning.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hurlbut, Samuel" TEIform="persName"/>Samuel Hurlbut, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><pb n="34" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological treasury" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL TREASURY</head><p TEIform="p">TAKE HP THE CEOSS. The Gospel, or Mission of Jesus Christ, stands in rebukeful antagonism to
                            all mere human systems of theology. And the originators and supporters of such systems ought
                            to be ashamed of ever thinking that Jesus could approve of what these leaders, with their
                            followers, allow themselves to engage in. There is not a single feature, which distin-
                            guished the Pentecostal church, that is not discountenanced by the majority of churches
                            calling themselves Christian. To this sweeping charge we will endeavor to attach equally
                            sweeping evidence. Where, among modern churches, can be found, in practical operation, the
                            cross that Jesus bore against generative lusts and relationship, against wars and fightings
                            which come of those lusts, as against the monopolizing selfishness, inseparable from the
                            natural order ? Is not fashionable Christianity the desideratum of the multitudes who follow
                            on to do evil ? Is not union, with some popular sect, needful to success, in the process of
                            adding house to house, till no place is left for the homeless poor ? Wherein would carnal
                            mammon worshipers desire a change in New York churches, or in church theology 1 Great is
                            Diana of the Ephesians — cry the craftsmen and craftswomen, who are made rich with the
                            abundance of money contributions. To have a subxtitute to bear the cross/or us, may be
                            comforting to the worldly professors. But they who deny themselves, and bear a daily cross
                            against all the lusts of the flesh and mind, bear their own burthens, work out their own
                            salvation. No substitute is needful nor desirable. The folly of living in sin, is apparent.
                            To misinterpreted atonement must be ascribed grave errors. By it many souls have been robbed
                            of salvation — salvation from actual sin. The cross of Jesus saves others just as it saved
                            him. A man or woman may be saved by faith alone, from sins they daily repeat, when an oven
                            may be heated by snow-balls. To comprehend, somewhat, the extent to which the cross of
                            Christ has been evaded by our modern Gentile Christianity, let us revert to the model — the
                            Pentecostal church. In Jesus, a virgin life was requisite toconstitute Him a Christian. And,
                            without exception, his immediate disciples adopted that rule of life. Those, among them, who
                            had been married, became as brothers and sisters to each other. They who were single so
                            remained. Hence, the Pentecostal was a virgin church. When Paul permitted marriages among
                            the Gentiles, he did it under this protest: " I would that all men were as I am." These
                            Gentile churches have annihilated the virgin cross, and instituted marriage as one of their
                            sacraments, in direct antagonism to both the first and second Pentecostal churches. Through
                            the life of marriage the cross is abandoned — a life is saved — eternal life is lost. Peace
                            is far from the sects who marry, as is the cross ; those who marry being the proper ones to
                            do the fighting. The community system of the model church exists no where among marrying,
                            fighting Christians. These do not seek each others' good rather than their own ; nor live
                            together as brothers and sisters, faring and sharing alike the fruits of each other's labor;
                            calling all things — not mine and thine — Ours. The community cross and the non-resistant
                            cross are abrogated by marriage. Hence, it is a worldly and not a Christian institution, and
                            many go in thereat. The world over, there is an inseparable connection between marrying,
                            blood-shedding churches and worldly civil governments. What a contrast between these and the
                            practice of Jesus under instruction of the Christ spirit. Let all desist from pressing into
                            our constitution the God of these people, until they cease to worship the Heathen Deities —
                            Venus, Mara and Bacchus.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Eld. G. A. Lornas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good news" TEIform="index"/>GOOD NEWS</head><p TEIform="p">"Of the increase of His government and peace, there shall be no end." One of the most
                            pleasant features connected with the Gospel work is, that there will be no end to its
                            spiritual unfoldings. It is to be forever a new revelation to those who love to walk in the
                            light. We may pass from faith to faith on our Heavenly journey, without fear. No barrier can
                            impede our onward, upward march. Angel minds may have preceded us, on the way to the
                            Kingdom, from whom we can, and gladly will, accept the discipline which insures our safety,
                            and harmonizes us with the life of Jesus Christ. It becomes our privilege to sit as pupils
                            in the spiritual school, accepting the divine mission from those who are in advance of our
                            position, we embodying their life in our own souls, and as faithfully transmitting the same
                            blessing, to those who accept the work of the cross at a later date. From the first
                            ministration of God's Law to man, there has been a gradual increase of divine revelation of
                            " government and peace," adapted to the condition of those who were separated from among
                            men, to be denominated His chosen people. The good old prophet understood this, when he
                            said, " Of the increase of the ministration of God's word there shall be no end," and we
                            live to attune our minds to the spirit of this prophecy. We have no reason to believe In-
                            finite wisdom will be indifferent to the successful,prosecution of his own work, knowing, as
                            we do, that finite minds will exert every faculty to acquire a desired object. Jesus
                            understood this fact, when he said : " Think not that I am come to destroy the law or the
                            prophets." He accepted the Mosaic dispensation, as one phase of God's work for the de-
                            velopment of human souls. The law was no less essential for those who became his disciples,
                            than it had been for the children of Israel. As Jesus received increasing spiritual light,
                            he unfolded greater spiritual truths to his followers corresponding with that light. While
                            the teacher, Moses, justified his followers in hating their enemies, Jesus, with a deeper
                            love for humanity, taught all who would walk with him, to " pray for those who despitefully
                            used and persecuted them." Admitting that the spirit of God was manifested in the two
                            dispensations, there was evidently a great increase in the latter, agreeably to the words of
                            the prophet — of the peace and government — to which there was to be no end. Our Gospel
                            privilege embraces within its boundary lines all the testimony of Jesus. To enter this
                            sphere of divine light is to be under the spirit of progression — in an endless increase.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Eld. Henry Blinn, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science vs. faith" TEIform="index"/>SCIENCE VS. FAITH</head><p TEIform="p">" Science shall free Itself from the influence of Religion and Faith. Faith is a hindrance to
                            Science." Carl Vaght. Is it of Religion and Faith, as exponents of creeds and forms of
                            worship, blind beliefs in dogmas, in themselves uncertain or useless, that the above
                            assertion is made ? Or, does it apply to Faith and Religion as elements of Christian life
                            and practice ? Can true faith hinder science in her endeavors to unfold nature's laws, or
                            cloud her accumulating array of facts in unbelief ? Is it not equally as necessary to
                            distinguish the true from the false in treating of religious faith — a perfect theory — as
                            it is in the unfoldment of nature's laws by mere science, and are not the issues involved,
                            as vital to the interests of man ? We think they are. When scientific investigators would
                            darken counsel by words without knowledge, and seek to becloud with doubts, and darken with
                            unbelief, faith — religion and the historic record, the Bible, — they undermine their own
                            foundation — Spiritualism. There is no possibility of keeping science — an orderly
                            arrangement of facts — and Faith — religion — apart. Honest, truth-loving, patient
                            investigation, correctness of observation, precision of statement and logical deduction,
                            belong to one as to the other. The scientist, be he materialist, deist or pagan, whose
                            writings and life evince love for humanity, will not be tabooed by the spirit of our age,
                            which judges the tree by its fruit and not by the name it chances to bear. What is faith? A
                            belief — confidence — prescience. What is that instinct which permeates animal life from the
                            coral to the human 1 If we deny God, in any of his works, do we not deny him in the whole
                            creation ? If we accept God in man, have we not the key to science ? Science will have made
                            her most wonderful discovery, when she acknowledges the source of all knowledge —faith — as
                            her Lord and master — the soul of all things in Heaven and upon Earth. The dual principles
                            of male and female are not more inseparably associated and connected in man, their highest
                            tangible exponent, down to the nomad, or chemical affinities of nature's laboratory, than
                            are Religion and Science. Creation is alive with change and progress. Cosmical
                            affinity—chemical attraction—developes into instinct an offshoot of the dual parent cause —
                            Father and Mother — God. Intuition in man, oft-times precedes investigation and knowledge.
                            It is the law that pioneers the soul in all growth. To be destitute of the power of impulse,
                            would be the death of all deaths. Impulse is the power to be, and to do. Faith, is the soul
                            of spiritual life in man. It insures eternal progress. It is the evidence of things not seen
                            — the substance of all good things hoped for. If ye had faith as a grain of mustard seed, ye
                            should say to this sycamore tree, be thou plucked up and'planted in the sea. That is but a
                            statement of the possible. And in our day of the probable — pro- vided there be cause.
                            Faith, without, or unaided by science, can better comprehend nature and her laws, than can
                            science, while warring with faith, see beyond her facts. As an art, faith must be classed
                            among the " lost Arts." 34 <pb n="35" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEE8S. 35 When Huxley, Darwin, Spencer
                            andVogt, have discovered the source of life, they will be as learned as the way-faring man,
                            who although a fool in science, has seen God, with the eye of faith—through purity of heart.
                            That which is hidden from the materialistic wise and prudent, may be revealed unto babes in
                            science. Finally, it is to faith, above instinct, intuition, or mere science, that all
                            truth's investigators are indebted for what we, as humans, have been, are, and are destined
                            to be in the glorious future.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, G. H." TEIform="persName"/>G. H. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvest home" TEIform="index"/>HARVEST HOME</head><p TEIform="p">Then gather up the useless tares, Convicting Angels bind, And cast them in the Gospel fire,
                            And thus release your mind. For now the reaping time has come, And Angels shout the Harvest
                            Home. Now if this work you truly do. And are indeed sincere, Then Gospel peace will freely
                            flow, And you will have good cheer. For now the reaping time has come, And Angels shout the
                            Harvest Home.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vam, F." TEIform="persName"/>F. Vam, Watervliet, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Captious criticisms" TEIform="index"/>CAPTIOUS CRITICISMS</head><p TEIform="p">Amid the avalanche of letters we are receiving, comes one from an unfriendly stranger —
                            woman. She criticises the Shakers, and their paper — The Shaker and Siiakeress. Friends, who
                            feel an interest in the success of the little monthly, confer a favor by pointing out its
                            defects and errors, whether grammatical or typographical. They do it in a kindly spirit. Of
                            enemies, essaying to instruct us, the least we require is, that they do it in style as
                            chaste, in language as correct, in as good honest English, as that which they criticise. She
                            credits us with being " well-meaning, and staunchly moral." We would willingly spare a good
                            deal of literary ability from some of our cotemporaries, to have the same said, truly, of
                            them. Our critic charges, as a fault, that the Society reserves the right to charge ''
                            casual visitors," for entertainment. While enquirers, for practical purposes, are made
                            welcome, the gossiping pleasure-seeking multitude, are not welcome. Nor are such as travel,
                            seeking to live upon the labor of others, making a Shaker community a place of common
                            resort. Our Society is not a public establishment — a free hotel, or boarding house, for
                            curiosityseekers. Nor for city people, seeking " an out in the country," at little expense
                            to themselves. It is our home. The class who importunately demand free fare at our hands,
                            would be the last to convert their own homes into free restaurants for the use of all
                            strangers who choose to call upon them. The rule, that correspondence is open to the Elders,
                            is especially obnoxious to our feminine critic. We publish that rule to deter just such
                            people from joining the Shakers. Those " who creep in among us unawares," to spy out our
                            liberties, who desire to carry on private correspondence with parties in the outside world,
                            in whom they have more confidence than in their Brethren and Sisters in the Lord, should go
                            out from among us. They are not of us. Such persons we do not confide in, because they do
                            not confide in their spiritual relations — their community associates. Thus, the want of
                            confidence is mutual. These should hang upon the tree of nature, until they have progressed
                            up to the Order, where '' that which is without, is as that which is within," "and where the
                            male, with the female, is neither male nor female." Those wishing to live in the selfish
                            order of single persons — isolated individuals — as well as those who have progressed to the
                            family — me and mine order — have our free permission to devote their talents, wealth and
                            affections, to upbuild that order. They may toil for No. One, or they may marry, raise
                            children, and buy and sell for their other selves. In these relations, the privacy and
                            secrecy, appropriate to the selfish, normal life, is in order. But, when they weary of such
                            contracted circle — such narrow sphere — and seek a higher life in which to expand their
                            affections and usefulness, they must come to religious communism. Again, our critic asks, *'
                            Are you a progressing people — a light to the world in literature ? " We rejoin — The
                            Shakers, at present, make no pretensions to high scholarship among the literati. Having
                            sought to be honest, industrious, temperate in meats and drinks, cleanly in person and
                            morals, as a basis for religion, rather than to be popular and learnedly great. In the
                            practice of these virtues, we find happiness and contentment. " The social evil" is far
                            removed from our borders. Neither the poor, the naked, nor the hungry are to be seen among
                            us. Peace and innocence abound. So far as this is " light" and " progress " to the world,
                            they are welcome to it. But the credit is to Shaker communism—a community of interests, and
                            a community of ideas, feelings and affections, being one.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warm feet" TEIform="index"/>WARM FEET</head><p TEIform="p">Beloyed Editob — At the risk of being thought trifling, and telling people what they already
                            know, I beg leave to remind them, through the Shaker and Siiakeress, of the secret of warm
                            feet. Many of the colds which people are said to catch, commence at these extremities ; and
                            colds are not the worst effects of damp feet. Persistent neglect, in this respect, produces
                            disease of the internal organs, which once chronic, can never be cured. To keep the feet
                            constantly warm, is to effect an insurance against the almost interminable list of
                            disorders, which spring from " slight colds." 1st. Never be tightly shod. Boots, or shoes,
                            when they fit closely, press against the veins of the feet, and prevent the free circulation
                            of the blood. On the contrary, when they do not embrace the feet too closely, the blood
                            flows freely, and the spaces left between the leather and the stockings, are filled with
                            warm air. Those who pride themselves on having small, handsome feet, will perhaps, be
                            unwilling to admit this assertion. They are earnestly recommended to sacrifice a little vain
                            display, for the sake of comfort and safety, by wearing what the makers call easy shoes. 2d.
                            Never sit in damp shoes. It is often imagined, that unless they are positively wet, it is
                            not necessary to change them when the feet are at rest. This is an error; for when the least
                            dampness is absorbed into the sole, it is attracted further to the foot itself, by its own
                            heat, and thus perspiration is dangerously checked. Those who doubt this, may prove it by
                            neglecting this precaution, and their feet will feel cold and damp, after a few moments,
                            although, on taking off the shoe and stocking, it will appear to be perfectly dry. Also, the
                            feet may be too warm, inducing debility of the whole system, as they may be too cold, by
                            reason of being thinly clad, and yet not feel very uncomfortable, because they are drawing
                            heat from all parts of the body, the result of which may be a general cold, a pleurisy, lame
                            back, or rheumatism, according to previous conditions of the subject.—Ed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread vs. Whiskey" TEIform="index"/>BREAD VS. WHISKEY</head><p TEIform="p">Away back in my teens, near sixty years ago, I went to Quaker meeting — an evening meeting —
                            at the house of Benedict Robinson, in the now town of Milo, in our county of Yates, State of
                            New York, a land then flowing with bread and whiskey. Whiskey was as much one of the family
                            necessaries as bread. The corn and the rye had, from the beginning, been regarded as
                            whiskey. Nothing more, nothing less. The whiskey mills had begun on the wheat with no
                            sparing hand. The Spirit moved Caleb Macumber, of Farmington, Ontario county, a man of giant
                            frame, giant voice, giant every thing, and he arose with one hand in coat pocket, the other
                            behind his back ; he began to speak — "It — is — our — duty — to — be — thankful — for —
                            blessin's — as — well temporal — as spiritual. I — shall — take — for — the — subject — of —
                            my — discourse — vegetables — especially — that vegetable — of — which — we make — Bread —
                            wheat." His words fell like sledge hammers upon our ears. Not upon our ears only, but upon
                            our very souls. In breathless silence we followed the preacher. He told us that " in the
                            staff of life that land had been blessed above all lands ; that we had turned that blessing
                            into a curse ; that the day was not far distant when there would be a scarcity in the land,"
                            " and children will cry for bread." We didn't see it then. In less than two years we saw the
                            word of the Lord by the mouth of the prophet fulfilled to the letter. There was not bread to
                            be bought, and no money to buy it. Many families were breadless for weeks, and children did
                            cry for bread.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Queries" TEIform="index"/>QUERIES</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Frederick — To the query, " Will not this Second Christian or Shaker Church — this
                            Gospel of Christ — create its own literature 1", your answer, " Yea, and that right
                            speedily," meets with a hearty response in my mind, and suggests the following questions, or
                            rather, renews them : Shall old phraseologies, which should have perished in their using ;
                            and which only lead to error, and serve only to hinder and blind • be perpetuated by mere
                            force of habit ? Is it proper to use the term Jesus Christ, as the name of, and applying to
                            one individual exclusively, and that, too, in the masculine gender ? Speaking of Jesus, as a
                            man, should we gay Christ, He, etc.? Is Jesus, or is Christ, our Savior, or do we save
                            ourselves by obeying the Christ as Jesus did? In common usage, Jesus and Christ are im-
                            properly used as synonyms. Does this convey an intelligent idea? Shall we not accept the
                            dictum of Jesus, " The Son of Man " — " the seed of Abraham ; " and when mediating for the
                            Christ Spirit, " I came down from Heaven " ? Jesus said, " It is expedient for you, that I
                            go away, that the spirit of truth may come unto you ;" and you become mediators. " They
                            shall guide you in the way of all truth, and they will show you things to come." Which shall
                            we follow — the individual Jesus, or the Christ — the Spirit of Truth — the Comforter, which
                            glorified Jesus ? Which is more proper — going to Heaven, or bringing Heaven to us — making
                            Heaven ? Why not have Heaven within 1 Does not the term —" Adam's fall," relating to one
                            individual, thousands of years ago, <pb n="36" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 36 8HAKEE ^lND induce a feeling of
                            irresponsibility, and blind the eyes to Adam's fall of to-day ? Have we not all sinned,
                            after the similitude of Adam's transgression ? Since Spirits are no longer stigmatized as
                            Ghosts, would not Holy Spirit — instead of Holy Ghost — bean improvement? Would it not be
                            well to think, study and phrase our literature, to the understanding of the present living
                            age, and not pervert language and sense, through time hallowed customs ? If all, or any of
                            these questions can be answered, through the Shaker and Shakeress, more than one might be
                            enlightened.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="End of the world" TEIform="index"/>END OF THE WORLD</head><p TEIform="p">A prophet said —" An end, an end, has come." It is beginning to be considered as an
                            actualized fact, that this earth is periodically populated and depopulated. Various genera
                            of vegetable growths and different species of animals, organic beings, come into existence,
                            and passing away, become extinct; evidence of their existence only to be found in the
                            inorganic stratified layers of the earth. During the intervals of total extinction, the
                            globe undergoes necessary repairs, which fit it to again become the garden of plants, and
                            the field of animal life. We have evidence that this process of life and death is eternal.
                            The numerous and divers species now in existence on this planet have been running their
                            periodical race some thousands of years. The indications are, that many of the cultivated
                            species of plants and vegetables, and some of the domesticated genera of animals, have
                            passed their zenith and approach the winter of the ages. Also, there are races of humans,
                            who, like sick Turkey, are dying out. As witness the Indians and the Yankees, or New England
                            people, who, co-operating with this great law, are losing the love of offspring — becoming
                            extinct. Something may be done to prolong the lingering existence of these worn-out plants,
                            animals, and tribes of humans; but their dooms-day draws nigh, and new and superior classes
                            impatiently await their exit from the sentient scenes of life. I have heretofore given you
                            my views upon this important subject, and now allude to it, that you may see the great
                            importance of discussing it in the Shaker and Shakeress. Touching the human race, I think it
                            is the design of the Powers Above, who overrule mundane affairs, to bring forward the
                            younger races, and compel them to observe the law of animal reproduction, under the tuition
                            of the spirit of Moses — thus forming the new earth. While the older and worn out races will
                            be harvested by the spirit of Christ, into the new Heaven, or by Death, into the spirit
                            world. The unwillingness of men to marry, and of women to bear children, preferring
                            thereunto the horrid crimes of foeticide and infanticide, are signs in the old earth ; while
                            the growing dissatisfaction with individual and family life; and the spread of co-operative
                            ideas, and of a community spirit, are signs in the old heavens not to be misunderstood; that
                            soon it shall be truly said—an end, an end has come. Thus it is, progress for the younger
                            and undeveloped animal human races, and resurrection vs. death, to the already refined,
                            progressed, intellectual and spiritual kindreds, nations, races and tribes of earth. To
                            these the Revelator referred: " I saw an Angel flying in the midst of heaven, having the
                            Everlasting Gospel to preach unto them that dwell upon the earth." " And the Earth was
                            reaped." Man cannot cause the Sun to move in space, nor change the relation to each other of
                            the members of the solar system. He cannot make the seed to sprout out of its season, nor
                            make the oak to produce apples. Man must take the phenomena of nature as he finds them — as
                            they are. And in learning this, he learns truth and humility. He learns that what exists in
                            nature is true, and to value truth, that he must bow to what is — to what, in the nature of
                            things, he cannot change.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Poole, J. B." TEIform="persName"/>J. B. Poole, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happiness" TEIform="index"/>HAPPINESS</head><p TEIform="p">The desire of the Creator in bringing human beings into existence on this planet was for
                            happiness. We deal with facts—facts within the reach of mental ken. In this world, hap-
                            piness is the result of obedience to law— misery, of law's infraction. Why not so in other
                            worlds ? By universal law, cause and effect are bound together. No power on earth, nor in
                            Heaven, will divorce them. " The reward of every man's hand shall be given him." " Whatso-
                            ever a man soweth, that also shall he reap ;" and wisely so. The suffering, inseparable from
                            law's infraction, is the remedial agent—man's best friend, Heaven's best mercy—without
                            which, man might be an eternal transgressor. The writer of this article has had a somewhat
                            diversified experience—has been associated with men in various conditions in life— rich and
                            poor, wise and otherwise. He has now had a brief acquaintance with the Shakers ; finds them
                            the most law-abiding— physiologically, morally and spiritually—of any people of his
                            acquaintance, and, of course, the balance, Happiness vs. Misery, is decided in their favor;
                            not because they are a superior race of humans, but because of the advantages of community
                            over isolation, for self-disciplinary and other purposes, enabling to divide the cares, and
                            double the enjoyments—all that is worthy of the name of enjoyment—and thus preparing them
                            for happiness, in all future states of being, in the most rational manner conceivable.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hart, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Hart, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cold bathing" TEIform="index"/>COLD BATHING</head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Dio Lewis writes: Just now I am sorry to see that there is a reaction against daily cold
                            bathing. A medical man of my acquaintance cautions his patients against too frequent
                            bathing, for fear the oil may be removed from the skin. He tells them that twice a month
                            during the winter, and twice a week during the summer, are quite enough for anybody. A
                            well-known writer has recently cautioned the world against the removal of the skin oil by
                            too frequent bathing. This is an entire misapprehension. In hydropathic establishments, the
                            patients are sometimes bathed three or four times a day, but never lose the oil of the skin
                            in consequence. Pugilists, in preparing for the prize ring, are bathed two or three times a
                            day, and rubbed with rough towels by the strongest arms. Heenan was bathed three or four
                            times a day, and was rubbed by Donald and Cusick with all the power of their strong arms,
                            fifteen minutes at a time, and with the roughest towels and brushes, and yet the account
                            says when he appeared in the ring his skin was as beautiful as a baby's. If cold water were
                            used without soap, a bath every hour, with the hardest friction, would only increase the
                            secretion of oils. A more frequent objection — one urged by the patients themselves — is
                            that they can't get up a reaction. A lady said to me one morning : " I have tried this cold
                            bathing, but it always give me a headache; besides, I can't get warm for an hour." Many
                            others have made the same objection. Now, this is all because you don't manage right. If you
                            will manage as follows, the want of reaction and consequent congestion of the head and chest
                            will never occur again. Purchase a bathing mat, or make one by sewing into the edge of a
                            large piece of rubber cloth a half-inch rope ; on rising in the morning spring into the
                            middle of it, and with an old rough towel, folded eight or ten inches square, apply the
                            water as fast as your hands can fly ; then, with rough towels, rub as hard as you can bear
                            on until the skin is as red as a boiled lobster. This will take one minute, and leave you in
                            a delightful glow. I have never met any one who, taking tie bath in this rapid and vigorous
                            way, was not satisfied with it. — Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Position in sleeping" TEIform="index"/>POSITION IN SLEEPING</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is better to go to sleep on the right side, for then the stomach is very much
                                    in the posi- tion of a bottle turned up side down, and the contents of it are aided
                                    in passing out by gravitation. If one goes to sleep on the left side, the operation
                                    of emptying the stomach of its contents is more like drawing water from a well.
                                    After going to sleep, let the body take its own position. If you sleep on your back,
                                    especially soon after a hearty meal, the weight of the digestive organs and that of
                                    the food resting on the great vein of the body, near the backbone, compress it, and
                                    arrests the flow of the blood more or less. If the arrest is partial, the sleep is
                                    disturbed, and there are unpleasant dreams If the meal has been recent and hearty,
                                    the arrest is more decided ; and the various sensations, such as falling over a
                                    precipice, or the pursuit of a wild beast, or other impending dangers, and the
                                    desperate efforts to get rid of it, arouses us, and sends on the stagnating blood ;
                                    and we wake in a fright, or trembling, or in a perspiration, or feeling exhausted,
                                    according to the degree of stagnation, and the length and strength of the efforts
                                    made to escape the danger. But when we are unable to escape the danger — when we do
                                    fall over the precipice, when the trembling building crushes us — what then ? That
                                    is death ! That is the death of those of whom it is said, when found lifeless in the
                                    morning, " That they were as well as ever they were the day before ; " and often it
                                    is added, " and ate heartier than common ! " This last, as a frequent cause of death
                                    to those who have gone to bed to wake no more, we give merely as a private opinion.
                                    The possibility of its truth is enough to deter any ra- tional man from a late and
                                    hearty meal. This we do know with certainty, that waking up in the night with
                                    painful diarrhoea, or cholera, or bilious cholic, ending in death in a very short
                                    time, is probably traceable to a late large meal. The truly wise will take the safe
                                    side. For persons to eat three times a day, it is amply sufficient to make the last
                                    meal of cold bread and butter, and a cup of some warm drink. No one can starve on
                                    it; while per- severance soon begets a vigorous appetite for breakfast, so promising
                                    of a day of comfort.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The philosphers of India once possessed a book so large that..." TEIform="index"/>The philosphers of India once possessed a book so large that...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The philosphers of India once possessed a book so large that it required a thousand camels to
                            carry it. A king desired to have it abridged, and certain scholars reduced it so that it
                            could be carried by a hundred camels. Other kings came, who demanded that it should be
                            diminished still more ; until at length the volume was reduced to four maxims. The first of
                            these maxims bade kings to be just; the second prescribed obedience to the people; the third
                            recommended mankind not to eat except when they were hungry; the fourth advised women to be
                            modest.</p></div2><pb n="37" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: idleness" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: IDLENESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Idleness is the parent of destitution and want, the concomitant of vice, and the precursor of
                            blight and decay. Idleness is a great sin ; it is as sinful now as it was in the time when
                            the iniquity charged upon Sodom was " fullness of bread and abundance of idleness." The
                            creative forces of the universe are all the time at work, and by the steady and har- monious
                            action of all the parts great results are accomplished. And when we contemplate the
                            magnitude of the material earth and heavens, according to our limited capacity, and realize
                            how vast are earth's resources, and with what amplitude a kind Providence has provided
                            sustenance for man and all the lower orders of beings possessing animal life, and see with
                            what exactness all the evolutions regarding time and the seasons are made, we can but bow in
                            profound admiration, and we revere the creative powers which formed and perfected such noble
                            plans. And again, when we see how imperfect (comparatively speaking) are the works accom-
                            plished by man, how unequal are his ways, and how unjust is he toward his fellow man, a
                            sense of shame flushes our cheeks, and sadness steals over our spirits. And again, we turn
                            to find the image of the Creator in the created, and we fail to find the needed trans-
                            formation from the natural, which is first, into the spiritual and heavenly. And the words
                            of the inspired prophet are applicable, " My people have forsaken me, the fountain of living
                            waters, and have hewed them broken cisterns that can hold no water." Also, " The prophets
                            prophesy falsely, and the priests bear rule by their means ; and the people love, to have it
                            so." The present generation of people, have turned their minds to live by mentality and wit,
                            as far as they can find means to do so, without combining physical strength with the
                            intellectual powers, so as to produce a healthy individual and societal action. Scarcely a
                            century has passed away since America sought to throw off the tyranny of British rule,
                            because of unjust taxation, and she passed through a severe contest to free herself from the
                            strong hand of oppression, that strove by force of might to make right. England has her
                            landlords to-day, who hold their title-deeds to large estates ; but every one knows that
                            they have not gained those possessions by honest toil, and that the millions of landless
                            tenants, who work for a small pittance, and others who are forced, through lack of
                            employment, to steal, beg, starve or commit suicide, have been robbed of their rightful
                            inheritance to the soil. And America, young in years, but old in designing craft, is taking
                            rapid strides toward reproducing the same condition of things on this continent that she
                            protested against in the mother country ; and that, too, while some of the scars upon the
                            limbs of the veterans, who fought and bled on the gory battlefield, to make her a free and
                            happy people, and to prepare a home for the oppressed, are still fresh in the memories of
                            their children. Pauper institutions have become numerous, and the prison houses of free
                            America to-day are a living prediction of a sad future. They are inadequate to hold all who
                            are sentenced by the high functionaries of the civil law, to atone for crimes committed. But
                            do we suppose, that when all things are duly balanced, before that high tribunal where cause
                            and effect are considered, and justice is meted out without respect to position or dollars
                            and cents, that all the crimes against law will be attributed to satanic depravity on the
                            part of the condemned individuals ? Or will the ruling " powers that be," which are ordained
                            by self-seeking and ambitious men, who aim to live in luxury and ease at the expense of
                            others, be held, either directly or indirectly, accountable for a part of it ? Certainly the
                            foundations of society, in the earthly order, are out of course at the present time, and the
                            ruling of public sentiment is practically against good morals. How then can we marvel at the
                            spiritual dearth that is felt throughout Christendom at the present time ? There is a
                            learned and eloquent priesthood, who make long prayers and speak oily words in the ears of
                            the people. But the power of salvation is not theirs to give, for they do not possess it;
                            nor can they, while they sanction ¦war, which proceeds from the unsubdued passions or lusts
                            of men ; for, while they profess to follow the Prince of Peace, him who said, " My servants
                            will not fight," they strengthen the edicts of civil rulers who announce war, and direct
                            that in time of peace the nation must prepare to resent every insult, and retaliate by
                            returning evil for evil. How unlike the lowly Jesus, who said " Love your enemies." How can
                            the church dignitaries denounce sin in others, while themselves are the servants of sin ?
                            The truth is, the priests and the people are immerged in the waters of sensuality. Hence,
                            the giant sin of the land goes unrebuked both by precept and example. They who should be
                            ensamples to the people over whom they preside as spiritual teachers, are eager to grasp the
                            largest stipend, that they may live in luxury and ease, and recline upon their downy pillows
                            and velvety cushions six parts of the time, and a seventh part is spent in spreading a cloak
                            over the sins of the churchgoers, and " daubing the walls " of their costly edifices " with
                            unternpered mortar," and thus the so-called religious temples are profaned by a hireling
                            priesthood. We gladly acknowledge that rare exceptions are found; that there are suffering
                            witnesses of truth in the large body of ecclesiastics, who are waiting in hope and praying
                            in faith for the helper to come to Zion, we would not deny; and that they long for a change,
                            that the ponderous burdens now resting upon humanity may be lifted, and that sin-oppressed
                            souls may be freed by the truth. But, how can there be an effectual change, except by
                            individual exertion and self-sacrifice 1 The work of every new cycle or epoch has been
                            commenced by some individuals who have been pioneers, and have worked their way up-hill,
                            against prejudice and pre-conceived opinions, which are always contending forces against
                            true reform and spiritual progression. The dual nature in man, and in woman, is
                            contradictive ; while the animal and sensual seeks its life on the lower plane, through the
                            medium of the external senses, the spiritual part reaches upward to the higher spheres of
                            Divine light and love, where God's angels dwell, who constitute his ministry ; and all the
                            emanations proceeding from them will be like fire to consume the propensity nature which
                            produces sin and sorrow, while the soul is elevated thereby to purity of life and stability
                            of action. The aristocracy have degraded labor, and have practically placed a badge of
                            serfdom upon it; while idleness bears the mark of gen- tility and respectability. Hence,
                            many get their living by over-reaching, i. e., stealing in a respectable way, and are called
                            smart for so doing; while other persons steal directly, and are punished therefor. Shakers
                            are striving to elevate labor, by all taking part in it according to our ability ; and we
                            place the insignia of virtue and honor upon all branches of useful industry, and aim to have
                            our religion take all true science by the hand ; and we make honest labor a welcome guest at
                            our social circles, and make honorable mention of it in our spiritual feasts. We think the
                            Apostle Paul, was inspired with wisdom from above when he gave the command to the Thess, "
                            If any would not work neither should they eat," for it remains true to-day that "
                            slothfulness casteth into a deep sleep, and an idle soul suffers hunger." The Sisterhood of
                            the Shaker fraternity, send kindly greeting to all who are engaged in the Temperance Cause.
                            We recognize the present movement, as the commencement of a great Spiritual Revival. The
                            Mother in Deity, is now sending her daughters into the field to work. And if they will toil
                            faithfully, and perseveringly, their efforts will be crowned with success. We bid them God
                            speed 1 Our prayers and blessing are with them.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Practice" TEIform="index"/>PRACTICE</head><p TEIform="p">Benjamin Franklin said, " A good example is the best sermon." Practice, — not Theory, —
                            should be the motto inscribed upon the Christian's banner. True Evangelists, who are
                            anointed by the Holy Spirit, and sent forth to preach the Gospel of salvation to others,
                            must of necessity become evangelized themselves, by firstly making a practical application
                            of the principles which they would enunciate to others ; for it is easier to teach, than to
                            be taught; and human nature is the same in all ages, and in all nations. It would seem that
                            the same spirit that induced some to compass sea and land to make proselytes in Apostolic
                            days, without much practical good resulting therefrom, is rife to-day. Many run to and fro,
                            but they run in vain; because they do not " tarry until they are endued or anointed, with
                            power from on high." Some persons, as soon as they conceive an idea, and are intellectually
                            convinced of its truth, rush with a blind enthusiasm to teach others theoretically, while
                            they themselves need to be practically taught the first principles of what they are seeking
                            to promulgate. This feeling is innate in every human being ; and it grows with their growth,
                            and strengthens with their strength ; hence the necessity of self-discipline. The power
                            embodied in, and the influence emanating from, a person who will reduce to practice his
                            theories, are double the power and influence of one who is always preaching, and seldom, if
                            ever, practicing that which he preaches. <pb n="38" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 88 Teachers and theories are
                            multiplied in the land, and knowledge increases with greater rapidity than saving truth.
                            When there are more who are willing to solve great problems, by practically working them out
                            at the expense of self-indulgence, worldly honor, and pleasure, the real success in
                            reforming the world will be far greater than it has hitherto been. There is diversity of
                            minds, and various gifts adapted to the needs of humanity, and the work necessary to be
                            accomplished. But, unless those gifts and talents are sanctified to, and approved by the
                            Power which gave them, and honestly devoted to the uses for which they were given, their
                            potency is lost, and the design not accomplished. Many, whose voices are never heard in
                            public halls, but who are often found in silent prayer, and deep soul communings with
                            spiritual intelligences, seeking to know what they can do to insure their own salvation, and
                            to facilitate the growth of others in the Divine life, exert a powerful influence for good,
                            and do much towards evangelizing the world. Not one sparrow is forgotten, E'en the raven God
                            will feed, And the lily of the valley Heaven grants its every need. Then shall I, not trust
                            thee, Father, In thy mercy have a share? And through faith, and prayer, my Mother, Merit thy
                            protecting care ?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life, real and imaginary" TEIform="index"/>LIFE, REAL AND IMAGINARY</head><p TEIform="p">Life is a great drama, in which every intelligent being may take part to profit. There is
                            room on the stage for all. And if all would enact well their part, and honestly improve the
                            talent committed to their trust, humanity would comprise a brotherhood and sisterhood worthy
                            the name. But they who live chiefly in the imagination, are apt to picture great
                            accomplishments, and fancy how they could acquire royal honors, and erect pinnacles of fame.
                            Thus, while dwelling in the sphere of mental hallucinations, they are apt to be dis-
                            contented in the sphere of real life, and to exhaust their energies in repinings, because
                            circumstances are not molded to their will, and they cannot have a broader and a wider scope
                            to display their powers, and develop their plans ; and they seem to be unmindful of the
                            golden opportunities that are continuously presenting themselves, offering a wide field of
                            useful labor, worthy of their attention, and which invite, and even demand their service. In
                            this way time is wasted, and much work, that would tend to elevate and progress humanity,
                            remains undone. An individual possessing but one talent, who honestly puts forth his or her
                            efforts, and consecrates his or her life to noble purposes, will stand equally justified and
                            accepted with others, of five, or ten talents, who do the same. Will the true parent reject
                            the most simple heart-offering from one of the little group that clusters round the family
                            altar? Are not the least, as well accepted as the greatest ? And, if this virtue blossom in
                            the human, how much more in the Divine ! Will our Heavenly Father and Mother discard any
                            devoted endeavor, however small the capacity, if all is given ? We hear God's witnesses in
                            the ages past, together with our own reason and conscience, answer, Never. If we would live
                            the real, let us be contented to work within our sphere, and use the means that are within
                            our reach; and never seek position, rank or station, for appearance, or name ; but let our
                            ambition, or aspirings be, to do the greatest amount of good, by firstly improving our own
                            condition and surroundings, morally, and spiritually ; and then put forth our efforts to
                            help others do the same. What will caste, in society, or the honor which cometh from
                            mortals, amount to, without true underlying principles, as a basis of action, and, an
                            approving conscience ? It is the indwelling spirit — the mind — that makes the man or woman.
                            And, when the mortal part — the outward covering — is laid aside, we shall be judged by the
                            interior. The fair visage, or well formed contour and rich costume, will not introduce us to
                            the society of the good and the pure, in the land of realities. The constant vying, so
                            largely indulged in among all classes and grades of society, is a barrier to the true
                            development of the higher and nobler faculties, and brings spiritual dearth to the soul. In
                            this progressive age, the light of religion, reason, science and common sense, combine, to
                            show the pernicious effects of selfish ambition ; and should commend the life and example of
                            the Divine Teacher to our better feelings : " He that would be greatest among you, let him
                            be the servant of all," said Jesus. If actuated by a spirit of true humility, we shall
                            diligently employ what ability we have to do good, in our mission field, whether it be large
                            or small; when opportunity permits. Through culture and self-discipline, we grow new
                            strength and power, and thereby add to the original gift, or talent. Life is fraught with
                            toil, in every phase, and under all circumstances ; but contentment sweetens each duty, and
                            there is ample scope for willing hands and cheerful hearts. If we cannot mount the summit of
                            fame, we can silently collect the gems of wisdom which fall at the base. If we are too weak
                            to engage in the heaviest conflicts, and are incapable of bearing the most weighty burdens
                            and responsibilities of society, we can lend a helping hand to aid those who do, and sustain
                            and comfort them with gentle words and kind ministrations. The mighty oak may tower among
                            the clouds, while the modest violet blossoms beneath its shade, perfuming the air with its
                            fragrance. So may the least one of us, shed a benign influence in all the duties of life.
                            Then, let us seek to bring forth the fruit of a diligent contented mind, unalloyed with
                            indolence and selfishness, which would claim the reward that justly belongs to their
                            righteous neighbor.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Emma J." TEIform="persName"/>Emma J. Neal, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editress:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Editress :</head><p TEIform="p">I feel indebted to you for the continuance of the " Shaker and Shakeress." I have derived
                            much satisfaction and strength from it. I always hail its arrival with pleasure, and peruse
                            its columns with eagerness. I feel a divine inspiration from the truths it contains; and, I
                            trust it is a blessing to Believers— a cementing bond of union. And, I pray that it may also
                            be a messenger of glad tidings of joy to many souls, who are as " pilgrims and strangers on
                            the earthly plane, seeking a better country," or a better state of things than they have
                            hitherto found. I pray that it may be a power in the land for good — a dispenser of light
                            and truth — and make its well-timed visits to cottages, where the lone widow and helpless
                            orphans dwell; and that, through it they may receive counsel and the balm of consolation, by
                            learning how to flee the producing causes of sorrow. I am satisfied that there are many
                            truthseekers at the present time who are faint and feeble, because they do not find
                            spiritual food to nourish and sustain the immortal part; and who sincerely ask for light and
                            wisdom, that they may better understand how to walk more justifiably in this present evil
                            world, and to secure the love and blessing of God. And I have reason to believe that our
                            little " Monthly " is a valuable aid to many ; for I have heard repeated expressions, from
                            friends outside of our community, of their appreciation of its worth, as a means to convey
                            knowledge of our principles and life, to many who have hitherto known but little. As the
                            years of my life roll away, my thankfulness increases for the gift and power of salvation
                            from sin, that I find in my Zion home. And I often feel to say, " Beautiful is my home! and
                            its beauty is enhanced an hundred fold by Gospel kindred dear, whose bond of union is pure
                            and undejiled love. The banner under which we serve is Liberty and Peace! Through unselfish
                            devotion to true principles, the subjects of this work are raising the standard still
                            higher. And that it may wave in the breezes of Divine inspira- tion, and its brightness
                            increase until its glory shall be seen from afar, many heavy laden, sin-sick souls gather
                            beneath its folds, as children gather to the arms of a loving mother and to the strength and
                            protection of a kind father, is the prayer of your humble sister. I would unite with all my
                            brethren and sisters of the household of faith, and pray for more energy of spirit to
                            conquer self ; that we may be able to make a stronger covenant with God and with each other,
                            by greater sacrifices ; and gain more of the treasures of immortal life, and receive a new
                            name (or character), and become practically " kings and priests unto God " — mediums of
                            Divine truth to other souls, as it was given to us by our Gospel parents. We are called to
                            be saviors, to stand upon the mount of Zion, and have lamps well supplied with the oil of
                            truth and virgin purity ; to " be clad in garments clean and white" — to be increasing in
                            the knowledge that will make us wise unto salvation, and thus be able to diffuse that
                            knowledge to others. In this way, we may pull down the strongholds of evil without, and
                            strengthen the good in Christ's kingdom. And we shall be joyful in following the example of
                            the good physician of souls, who bound up the wounds of bruised and sorrowing hearts and
                            administered the balm of consolation. Let us do likewise, that we may drink at the fountain
                            of life and love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randall, Joanna" TEIform="persName"/>Joanna Randall, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World moves" TEIform="index"/>"THE WORLD MOVES."</head><p TEIform="p">In this age of advancing Science, and controlling Reason, we behold law and order brought
                            forth from the realm of mind and matter. The intellective genius of to-day, untrammeled by
                            the chaotic and blinding influences of superstition and ignorance, delves deep into the
                            mysteries of things, and finds the key of knowledge, which unlocks the vaulted treasures of
                            the earth, and reveals the cosmic forces underlying growth, action and harmony, so admirably
                            displayed in the face of nature. Who would now attempt to controvert the universally
                            accepted and. established facts appertaining to Astronomy ? Yet, only three centuries have
                            coalesced in boundless eternity, since the same facts were branded as false notions. The
                            teachings of the noble Galileo, relative to the Copernican theory of the earth's revolution,
                            were interdicted by Romish ecclesiastical powers. He was severely reprehended, and thrown
                            into prison, because he persisted in the belief that the " world does move." It was not a
                            mere fancy of the mind that led to the conclusion. He invented the telescope. Through that
                            wonderful instrument he scanned the heavenly bodies. Its powerful lens seemed to condensate
                            space until it almost disappeared. Then, was revealed to his extended vision., the fact,
                            that the scintillating stars were not mere luminous particles of light, sprinkled like gold
                            drops across the blue expanse, as they appear in the distance to the naked eye ; but, worlds
                            beyond worlds, similar to that on which we live; differing in magnitude, moving with
                            circumrotary motion, each revolving within a given sphere around a grand central orb ;
                            subject to the immutable laws of attraction, cohesion, and repulsion, which govern, and
                            harmonize the universe. No baseless hypothesis that had previously been cherished could
                            change his conclusion; for actual evidence had transfigured the hitherto dark and mysterious
                            regions into glorious realms of light where order and harmony reigned supreme. Nor could the
                            opponents of Science prevail to counterpoise his opinions, which tangible evidence had
                            placed beyond a doubt, or the power of circumvention. With transport of feeling he published
                            the glad news. And we see that the world continues to move, in more than one sense of the
                            word ; for the triumphal car of Progress overrides the narrow dogmatical sphere of
                            priestcraft and superstition ; and it will roll on with speed, over the yet trackless fields
                            of unexplored truth, leaving light in its path ; while waning error will sink into obliv-
                            ion, no more to rise in the glory that will flood the earth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="39" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philanthropy" TEIform="index"/>PHILANTHROPY</head><p TEIform="p">If philanthropy, as defined, means love, benevolence, and universal good will toward the
                            whole human family, where shall we find a word of broader signification, or one that will
                            include so much good, and exclude so much wrong? In scriptural language it is said, " God is
                            Love." When a human soul is filled with love, there is not much room left for envy and
                            hatred. True love will elevate the soul, and carry it away from the world, and cause it to
                            place its affections upon heavenly beings, and those things which are eternal in the Divine
                            spheres, where God dwells, and "is all in all." Love has its counterfeit; but it leads away
                            from God and fills the heart with impure desires —binds it to the false and vain — and its
                            fruits are manifest in deeds of darkness, in selfishness, retaliation and hatred — the
                            opposite of benevolence and universal good will. Those who possess this kind of love choose
                            to dwell in the world, their life and interest are given to support the principles which
                            constitute the world, which the Apostle defined thus : " The lust of the flesh, the lust of
                            the eyes, and the pride of life, are not of the Father, but are of the world." But all who
                            possess true and genuine love, have their home in the truth — their dwelling is in God. If
                            our hearts are aglow with philanthropic zeal, we shall strive to comprehend our whole duty,
                            and to exemplify the life and character of the baptized Jesus «in every act which we
                            perform; and we shall assimilate our feelings with all that is true and good, wherever it
                            may be found, and co-operate with every movement that tends to progress mankind toward the
                            ultimate for which they were created,! e.—a perfect at-one-ment with the Creator.
                            Philanthropists, in the truest sense of the word, will stand self-adjusted, and manifest
                            their sincerity by instituting a strict and impartial investigation of their own life and
                            character, giving heed to the Savior's injunction, firstly, " To cast the beams from their
                            own eyes, that they may see clearly how to pull the mote from a brother's or a sister's
                            eye." This will necessitate a cross, and will call Gospel faith into exercise ; but it is
                            vain for any one to attempt to evangelize others, while they themselves are in the wrong.
                            Eventually, all false coverings will be taken off, and every thing Will be judged according
                            to its merit, or demerit. Then, exaggeration of wrongs, or depreciation of virtue, will
                            avail nothing. Philanthropy will lead to tenderness of feeling, and to compassion for an
                            erring brother or sister ; and will teach, that if we would facilitate their growth, it is
                            better to throw a mantle of charity over their shortcomings, than to rebuke them in an
                            unchristian spirit. If we condemn faults in others that we approve in ourselves, we neither
                            love nor do the truth, and are not on a Christian basis, but are on a shaky foundation.
                            Pride and selfishness induce us to judge unrighteously; and in this condition we are not
                            fixed in our purposes, but are weak and vacillating, and are liable to be moved by any
                            adverse winds that may blow. When Love is at the helm of the ship, as we sail upon the sea
                            of life, we fear not the storms that may arise ; and Benevolence —an amiable, sympathizing
                            friend — will help to guide the vessel safely into port.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Ann Offord, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-denial" TEIform="index"/>SELF-DENIAL</head><p TEIform="p">It has been said, and that justly, that "there is no benevolence without sacrifice." It is
                            very easy to give that which costs us nothing, or that which we do not want; but, is there
                            any virtue in such benevolence? Is it not like sacrificing the halt and blind, under the
                            Jewish dispensation, which was said to be an abomination ? As Believers in Christ's Second
                            Appearing, we profess to have consecrated ourselves, soul and body, time and talents, all
                            that we have, and are, to the Work of God, and the cause of humanity ; but for this, " we
                            have received an hundred fold in this life," with the blessed assurance of eternal life in
                            the world to come. As I prize my precious privilege in the sindestroying Gospel, and feel
                            its pure consolation, I would gladly do something towards making known to those who are yet
                            subject to bondage, and the fear of death, how they may gain the liberty of the children of
                            God. I would prefer to be a tarry-at-home missionary; and I think that much knowledge of
                            Believers' faith and principles, may be communicated through the medium of our little paper;
                            and as many have contributed freely to its support, and have also made efforts to give it a
                            wide circulation, I thought that 1 would make a proposition to those who feel disposed to
                            unite with me, but more especially to those who are young ; that is, that we make a
                            free-will offering of some little idol, if we have any ; or, that we deny ourselves of some
                            luxury — or resolve to abstain from stimulating food, and drinks, that are not essential to
                            life and health, and thus help to roll on the little " stone (of truth) which is to become a
                            great mountain, and fill the whole earth." Great things often result from small beginnings.
                            " Bring all the tithes into the store-house," said the Lord by the Prophet, " and see if I
                            will not pour out a blessing, till there shall not be room to receive it." Every tithe will
                            be accepted; and, through sacrifice, prayer is made effectual. The Savior accepted the
                            offering of the poor widow, who " cast two mites into the treasury." The gift was not
                            estimated by the quantity which she gave, but by the sacrifice which it cost; for she gave
                            her all; and if we do the same, we shall likewise be blessed. We should regard the laws of
                            health, in a physical, and moral point of view ; and be temperate; using the things of this
                            life, as not abusing them; practicing strict economy in our Zion home — laboring diligently
                            with, our own hands — employing a portion of the proceeds in disseminating light, and truth,
                            by sending forth "leaves for the healing of the nations," in the form of the Shaker and
                            Shakeress.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>Ruth Webster, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bless one another" TEIform="index"/>BLESS ONE ANOTHER</head><p TEIform="p">Jestts said to his disciples," Love one another as I have loved you." If the example of Jesus
                            in this respect is fully exemplified in daily life, it will destroy selfishness, and
                            eventually " create a new heaven and a new earth, wherein shall dwell righteousness." " In
                            blessing we are blest." It is natural and easy for us to " love those who love us," but "
                            what reward have we" for so doing ? Christ said, " Love your enemies ; bless them that curse
                            you, and pray for them that despitefully use and persecute you." We, who bear the Christian
                            name, and profess to follow our blessed Gospel Parents, should be careful that we do not
                            violate our profession upon this point. Let us not be deceived. "We shall reap what we sow."
                            If we sow and cultivate Love and Peace, we shall reap Love and Peace as our reward. On the
                            contrary, if we sow Discord and Strife, we must reap the bitter fruits which grow therefrom.
                            If we follow the example of our Savior and return blessing for cursing, we shall be safe. "
                            When he was reviled, he reviled not again;" but patiently endured persecution. And when his
                            enemies bore false witness against him, and even spat upon him, he opened not his mouth in
                            his own defense. Are we willing to suffer like our blessed Master — like him " endure the
                            cross and despise the shame " — and like him wear a crown of thorns, if need be ? If we are
                            true Christians, we must follow him, and learn to be like him ; " meek and lowly in heart; "
                            and to love and bless one another in the truth. If this we do, the blessing of God will
                            never depart from us. Mary Middleton, Union Village, Ohio. The pure in heart shall see God.
                            What a sublime and beautiful promise. What holy inspiration must have possessed the soul of
                            Jesus, when before a gazing multitude he uttered that Divine promise ! A blessing was
                            pronounced on the peacemaker and the mourner —the poor in spirit—and the seeker after
                            righteousness; but the God-seeing are the pure in heart. One of our Gospel fathers, Elder
                            Wm. Lee, left his testimony concerning the means by which purity of heart may be obtained.
                            He said, " When I set out to follow Christ in the regeneration, I felt it to be my duty to
                            confess all the sins of my life, and then to forsake them ; and I felt such fear of God in
                            so doing that I chastened my thoughts, and every turn of my eye that was not after God. And
                            by this selfchastening, my eye became single to the honor and glory of God, and my heart was
                            made pure." And it is a happy thought that we have in our midst, to-day, Gospel brothers and
                            sisters who through self-discipline have become " pure in heart," and can see God according
                            to the promise of Jesus, who also " endured the cross, despising the shame," and said " Be
                            of good cheer, I have overcome the world." By thus doing, he became to us a Holy and Divine
                            teacher, whose bright example we revere, and whose sayings we delight to roll beneath our
                            tongues as honey for sweetness, and as bread for strength.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dodgson, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Dodgson, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Character" TEIform="index"/>CHARACTER</head><p TEIform="p">It is true, as has often been remarked, that human beings are "creatures of circumstances/'
                            to a great extent. But every individual, in a greater or less degree, has the power to form
                            a character independent of circumstances. All are gifted with the power of will and of
                            choice, and also possess the germs of a dual life — the natural and the spiritual — or of
                            good and evil. A child, both by inheritance and the influences to which its tender and
                            rapidly growing brain is exposed, may receive that which will quicken either the evil or the
                            good within it, which, without doubt, will have a weighty influence upon its future course
                            of action. But, as reason and the will-force are developed the immutable laws of cause and
                            effect are more potent than circumstances, and many are induced by the stronger, to control
                            the weaker, and to examine principles, draw their own conclusions, form their own plans, and
                            decide upon their future course of action through life. As the brain is moulded by the
                            spirit or mind, its present development will not be a bar to future change and growth into
                            the true, or the false, which will produce joy or sorrow according to its kind. Either must
                            be effected by the action of the will in co-operation with ministering spirits of whatever
                            class we attract to us. Character is not reputation, and cannot virtually be changed
                            thereby; nor can it be accurately judged by emotional feelings or impulsive words and
                            actions, but by the habitual neglect of, or adherence to, certain principles which may be
                            exemplified in the small acts of life, which help to form the real character. As the
                            majestic ocean is formed of little drops of water and its extended shores of tiny atoms, so
                            each silent thought, as well as thoughts uttered in word and deed, have a part in shaping
                            the character and destiny of individuals. Happiness is the desire of every human being, and
                            how to attain the desideratum requires a careful study of all the laws which pertain to
                            physical and spiritual life. How to attain unto true exaltation of character, necessitates
                            thorough investigation of principles, and careful scrutiny of motives, which prompt to
                            action, and of the rules by which we are guided. The natural life, in its perverted state,
                            is fraught with misery and sorrow. Its highest pleasures are unsatisfying, and will be out-
                            grown in the soul's progress God-ward. We need a divine unction, that will quicken the
                            spiritual germs of life in our souls, to enabl e us to form a perfect character. That will
                            insure to us imperishable wealth, joy and glory, and establish us in principles that are im-
                            movable, over which circumstances can have no control; and neither the hope of heaven nor
                            the fear of hell will dominate. We shall do right from love of right. Is it not a point of
                            wisdom for those of us who are young in years, and inexperienced in life, and are now laying
                            the foundations of our future characters, to mark well those who are more perfect than
                            ourselves, that we learn to imitate their virtuous examples and follow them as they have
                            followed Christ and walked in the truth ? If purity be the basis upon which we seek to
                            build, and Love our motto, it will be easy for us to assimilate our spirits with theirs, and
                            to harmonize with the pure and good; and with them to drink at the Love-fountains which
                            perpetually flow to earnest truth-seekers, like holy baptisms from the inner heavens.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Allen, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="40" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Land of love" TEIform="index"/>LAND OF LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">1. Veil not from us Holy Spirit, Beauties that are ever rife, In our future home of glory, Land of love and endless life. Lift the curtain from our vision, Fan the mists that
                            dim our eyes; We would scan the inner heavens And from earthliness a rise. We would take
                            the wings of morning, And explore the mountain's height; Or descend in pleasant valleys,
                            Seeking treasures free from blight; In a blessed sweet communion With the loved ones gone
                            before, We would clasp them nearer to us, Range with them the heavenly shore. 3. But we'll
                            bide our time in patience, And improve each moment well, In a life of consecration We will
                            labor to excel. Forming here a joyous heaven," By creating one within ; And a home of love
                            and beauty, Free from discord, strife and sin. 4. Then abide, O blessed spirit! Purify us
                            unto thee, That a tower of strength and glory To the nations we may be ; And our earthly
                            home foreshadow Our eternal home above ; Dwelling place of truth and goodness, Paradise of
                            heavenly love.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance movement" TEIform="index"/>THE TEMPERANCE MOVEMENT</head><p TEIform="p">It is a glorious work God has begun ; Hold sacred in your hearts its trust of power ; And
                            when some little vict'ry you have won, Let that but nerve you for the adverse hour. O, put
                            your faith in agencies divine ! That can inspire beyond all human strength. And " greater
                            works " than those of old, will shine Along your pathway's steep and rugged length. 'Tis
                            said a fearful river flows through hell; But, can it match the alcoholic tide, With rock,
                            and whirlpool, and demoniac spell, That scatter desolation far and wide? We may conjecture
                            that they are but one, Connected by a dismal open flume, Where raging rapids unimpeded run,
                            To dash their victims through that gate of doom. And, as we trace the world's broad winding
                            life, Our minds no darker, wilder flood can see ; Its miry banks with hideous reptiles rife,
                            Are shaded only by the gallows tree. It is no myth ; we know its burning streams That carry
                            blight where'er their currents flow, That bear away the hearts ennobling dreams, And sink
                            the soul in passions base and low. The waving harvests, that the Father will'd From year to
                            year, to show his mindful love, Are first usurp'd, then wastefully distill'd, To make his
                            blessing but an evil prove — To bring to earth the waves of liquid flame, Whose touch is
                            madness, and whose force is death; To exile man, from that parental claim, That fills the
                            soul with inspiration's breath. If, but the horse-hoof pools along the road, Miasma to the
                            sunny air exhale, Will not the river and its marshes broad, With deadly venom laden every
                            gale? O, woman, there is work that must be done! You have but enter'd on its weighty care!
                            Its darkest sands the hour of sin hath run, The morning dawns with incense of sweet prayer.
                            The day shall brighten on your faithful toil; The will of God within your hearts reyeal'd
                            Will give to them the balsam and the oil, By which the sad and wounded shall be healed. God
                            pleads through you; then let him freely speak, "Grieve not the Holy Spirit," give free
                            course. And you no more shall timid feel, nor weak ; He has prepar'd for you a strong
                            resource. For never In the his'try of Reform, Has man attained a more illustrious plane. He
                            nobly bears you through the conflict warm, His heart and hand your energies sustain. O ! we,
                            the sisterhood, who toil apart, To bring redemption to the earth below, Know how to prize
                            each brave and manly heart, That gives its might to evil's overthrow. Life is so mingled on
                            its every side — United efforts must its good achieve; The father may all lib'rally provide,
                            Yet, must the mother tenderly relieve. Go forth, as on a mission sent, Cloth'd with the
                            snowy robes of fervent prayer; That all who see you may to God repent, And seek his law —
                            his character to bear. Your own true purpose, like electric wire, Will flash conviction
                            through the harden'd heart; Your supplication like the altar's fire, Will holy light to all
                            around impart. May angel choirs assist you when you sing, And may the Comforter your words
                            impress, Until the desert in its blossoming, Shall bring your hearts the blessing of
                            success.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiveness" TEIform="index"/>FORGIVENESS</head><p TEIform="p">" Father, forgive them ! " The waves of the air Bore the sweet music of this holy prayer;
                            When in keen pain and anguish he writh'd, Drinking of gall this petition he breath'd. "
                            Father, forgive them ! " O, heaven inspire My soul to breathe forth the same pure desire !
                            Let its sweet music float down to my soul, Waking to being the same self-control. Whence
                            came this pow'r, this strength to control Waves of temptation, that peril'd his soul ? While
                            in the wilderness tempted with wrong, Kissed in betrayal, and mock'd by the throng. Here,
                            down the aisles of my heart's home, I find Essence of this love —forgiving—resign'd ; Life
                            is as sweet as the dew the bee sips, When words of kindness are found on the lips.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Wheeler, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian liberty" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN LIBERTY</head><p TEIform="p">Struggle yet, thou soul in bondage, Rend thy ties, and stand thou free; Find thy fair and
                            bright ideal In true Christian liberty. On and upward ever pressing, To enjoy still purer
                            loves; Holy independence gaining, Which the higher law approves. Holy independence gaining,
                            O prolong the joyous sound, Until ev'ry clime and nation With its gladness shall resound ;
                            Until ev'ry heart shall vibrate In this universal strain, Until hearts and voices (blended)
                            Join in Zion's sweet refrain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My creed" TEIform="index"/>MY CREED</head><p TEIform="p">I hold that Christian grace abounds Where charity is seen ; that when We climb to heaven,
                            'tis on the rounds Of love to men. I hold all else named piety A selfish scheme, a vain
                            pretense, Where center is not, can there be Circumference ? This I moreover hold and dare
                            Affirm where'er my rhyme may go, Whatever things be sweet or fair, Love makes them so ; 'Tis
                            not the wide phylactery, Nor stubborn fast, or stated prayers, That make us saints ; we
                            judge the tree By what it bears. And when a man can live apart From work, on theologic
                            trust, I know the blood about his heart Is dry as dust.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. Whittier</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happiness" TEIform="index"/>HAPPINESS</head><p TEIform="p">The conscious pursuit of happiness is found to be one of the most degrading motives in the
                            world. The objects are so various ; the points to be considered so numerous ; the
                            difficulties so unexpected ; the most worldly man is still so mysterious to himself; that
                            what we call happiness is to a very large degree provided for us or denied to us, as air,
                            sunshine, and water are, which may be said to be universally supplied, though there are
                            instances when each of these may fail us. The idea of what happiness consists in varies from
                            the briefest physical indulgence to the faith and patience and fortitude of the saint. The
                            extremes of the idea are as far apart as the clod of earth is from the star in the heavens.
                            A man might as well think of providing for the digestion of his food, or the circulation of
                            his blood, as of successfully keeping in view as a motive of life that infinitely various
                            condition of existence which happiness is found to be. The Epicurean descends to become the
                            epicure. The most determined and narrow-minded willfulness, the coarseness of sensuality,
                            the violence of the brutal, the heartlessness of the idle and frivolous, all come within the
                            limits of happiness, as one or another would define it. When our Master declared for
                            self-denial, both by precept and example, he showed that it is in lives of usefulness, deeds
                            of charity, labors of philanthropy, sentiments of affection, that the true good is to be
                            found. Not by seeking happiness, but by true work in the world, is human destiny best
                            wrought out.— Christian Register.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorial wants" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL WANTS</head><p TEIform="p">Wanted, for coming number of Shaker and Shakeress, one short, well written, well condensed
                            article, from each Society. By one, we mean one from Brethren and one from Sisters. To
                            secure this, each Family might write one article, as above. The surplus may be placed where
                            we often go for some choice contributions. In the Shaker are one hundred and twenty inches —
                            about six inches to each Society. In the Shakeress, there are ninety inches, being five and
                            a fraction to each.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>[Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Williams, Matilda" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Matilda Williams
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Williams, Matilda" TEIform="persName">Eldress Matilda Williams</persName>, aged 63; at
                                Watervliet, Ohio, Jan. 29,1874. A Believer 57 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bailey, Sarath" TEIform="index"/>Sarath Bailey
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bailey, Sarath" TEIform="persName">Sarath Bailey</persName>, aged 45 years ; at South Union,
                                Ky., Feb. 24,1874,</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wiskins, William" TEIform="index"/>William Wiskins
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wiskins, William" TEIform="persName">William Wiskins</persName>, aged 64 years ; at the
                                United Society, Harvard, Mass., formerly of Mendham, Suffolk county, England, on the
                                10th instant.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>