<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2903" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18990301" TEIform="date">March 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1899.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Several SOCIETIES,  their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF   THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OK
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish  to join it.            50  cents  a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 2819  Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
AND
SH AKERISM.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price,  15 cts.
MARCH,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The question of handling the wires and gas,
water and drainage pipes in great cities, and
even in towns, is becoming with each year
one of greater importance.   A prize was offered to the engineers of the United States
by The Cosmopolitan magazine for the
ablest article suggesting a scientific, economical solution of this problem.   The paper of
Henry F. Bryant has been selected by the
'committee as the one most ably meeting the
conditions.   It appears in the February Cos
MOPOLITAN.   Some Plays and Their Actors.
Without Prejudice, is a new department in
The Cosmopolitan.   The names of the contributors are not given, but in ths staff are
embraced the majority of the leading critics
of the country, including David Belasco.   It
is interesting to note that in these days of
competition in the magazine field the editions
of The Cosmopolitan have gone from three
hundred thousand for February, 1898, to three
hundred and fifty thousand in February of
this year.
Portraits and sketches of men who are now
prominently before the public abound in the
February Magazine Number of The Outlook.
Thus, there is a very fine portrait of Dr. N. D.
Hiliis, who succeeds Dr. Lyman Abbott as
pastor of Plymouth Church, Brooklyn; an illustrated article on Kipling by Robert Bridges
better known to many readers as the "Droch"
of "Life;" a finely illustrated article about
Kitchener of Khartoum; a Lincoln birthday
p ige that comprises a-strong original poem
a portrait and a picture of the house in which
Lincoln was born; a thoroughly readable
article by Colonel Thomas Wentworth Higginson about My Literary Neighbors; and an
article by John Burroughs on Nature Study,
which is in an entertaining way autobiographic, and has a portrait of the author.
Half a dozen or more other illustrated articles make up a number of unusual variety.
($3 a year.   The Outlook Company,.New York.)
The Journal of Hygeio-Thekapy for Jan.
1899 has a very excellent paper on the Science
of Life by T. V. Gifford, M. D.   "Proper habits
of life that are in accordance with Nature
must be observed in every division of life to
bring about a normal generation and its results, which are health, strength and happiness."   Publisht by Dr T. V. Gifford & Co.,
Kokomo, Ind.
Almost anyone would be interested in "The
Tales Tim Told Us."   Tim says, "I'm a Limerick man myself" and the author of the little
work of some one hundred and fifty pages,
Mary E. Mannix, gives us in an enchanting
form the legendary stories, as brought forward by Tim, the famous story teller.   The
Rival Cloisters stand first, and no one will
Wave the poor, fun-loving monks till the last
j word has been spoken.   Nine more stories
will be told with equal interest before Tim
bids a final adieu to his eager listeners.   Publisht at Notre Dame, Ind.   Price 75 cts.
Holy Angels.   We have just received from
the publishers a copy of the above named Religious Reverie, suitable for piano or organ,
composed by George I). Wilson.   The retail
price of this piece of music is GO cents.   All
readers of our paper will receive a copy of it,
by sending'iocer.tsin silver, or postage stamps
to the Union Mutual Music and Novelty Co.,
No. 20 East 14th St., New York.
The first hymn recorded in the New Testament is that wonderful "Magnificat" of the
Virgin Mother, "My soul doth magnify the
Lord."   This song, combining as it does the
promises of the past with the assurance of
present realization, is a prelude preparing for
the great symphony of Christian song which
comes swelling down through the ensuing
ages.   The "Magnificat" was the first of a noble triad, the song of the priest Zacharias-,
"Blessed be the Lord God of Israel," and the
song of one who, standing on the outermost
edge of this mortal life, cried out, "Lord now
lettest Thy servant depart in peace."   All
of these songs have stirred the great musi
cians of the world to their noblest efforts, ami
naturally so, since they tell of the very deepest, most sacred emotions of the human heait.
The hymns of the early Church are for the
most part shrouded in obscurity, but much
has been written of the medieval hymns.
Some of them are new editions, as it were, of
earlier hymns, as the "Pange Lingua" of St.
Thomas Aquinas, in which the opening lines
are identical with that composed by Venantius Fortnnatus in the sixth century.   The
"Pange Lingua" of St. Thomas which celebrates the glory of the Blessed P.ucharist, may
be regarded as one of the last great songs of
the unmutilated Church, when dogma was
not, as Luther tried to make it, distorted into
the mere fancifulness of symbolism, and the
heart of Christianity had not been lacerated
by the wounds of conflicting sects.Mary
Josephine Onaham, in February Donahoes.
The first twenty-five of The Prettiest Country Homes in America are shown in the February Ladies' Home Journal.   There will be
over one hundred of these photographs, and
they will picture in detail the most attractive
and artistic country and suburban homes
in the United States.   The pictures that will
constitute this series were selected from the
photographs of seven thousand of the prettiest American homes.   A competitive contest
for a photograph of the prettiest house in this
country brought a picture of every home having any claims to attractiveness and beauty,
and from these the very best for publication
in The Ladies' Home Journal exclusively.
Houses of all sizes, from every section of the
country, of various costs, have been selected,
and the series will be valuable for suggestions
to those who contemplate building a house or
remodeling an old one.--><pb n="33" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trifles" TEIform="index"/>TRIFLES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Trifles make perfection, but perfection is no trifle." DID it ever occur to you to trace the
                            happiest moment in your life to its foundation, or to question the cause of the deepest
                            sorrow you have experienced? Passing backward in thought, leaving behind the windings and
                            ramifications, you may be surprised to find how slight was its source. The turning-point in
                            many a life has been perhaps a smile, a hand-clasp of fellowship, when seemingly all others
                            passed by "on the other side;" a word of encouragement in the silence of despair, or a
                            whispered prayer in the hour of danger. In our rushing, ambitious life, crowded with much
                            that engages the mind only because it is beyond our power to attain, we often lose sight of
                            the glory of our possibilities, often forget the value of so-called trifles. We are quite
                            too busy to give attention to the little courtesies of life, too eager to be fortified
                            against the great trials that seem likely to assail us to be mindful of the little vexations
                            of every day, that consequently creep in and overpower usus who were so perfectly on our
                            guard against less insidious enemies. It is one thing to be constantly anticipating what
                            will never come, and quite another thing to meet what actually occurs, with patience and
                            discretion. A pivot is but a trifle, so common parlance has it, but if perfectly adjusted it
                            may balance a mighty weight. A helm is tiny compared with the bulk which is guided by its
                            skillful manipulation. A word is but a breath, but it may be freighted with fragrance or
                            with poison, with life or with death. MARCH, 1899. <pb n="34" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Faultless we cannot expect to be yet, but the fault of underrating the value of little
                            things will not long survive among the thoughtful. Thought urges upon us the responsibility
                            which attaches to the ever present imnutiie of life. It takes great minds to recognize the
                            magnitude of littleness, small minds seem to be ever dreaming of unattainable greatness.
                            Nature is not at fault in this respect. Her smallest works are often the most wonderful. The
                            beauty of the green sward is not marred by carefull}7 analyzing one blade of grass, indeed
                            it is enhanced by the knowledge that the whole is a multiplication of just such wonders. The
                            microscope reveals a world of beauties unknown to the naked eye. Note a snow-flake, au
                            insect wing, a rain drop. Who can do so without looking "through nature up to nature's God ?
                            " Campbell truly says, " 'Tis distance lends enchantment to the view," but there is a charm
                            equal, if not greater, in the analytic when compared with the synthetic. The stem of an
                            applehow tiny compared with the fully developed, juicy, red-cheeked fruit; yet by the
                            soundness of its almost unnoticed fibres, the magical union is established between root and
                            fruitage. Yet we grasp the fruit and despise the stem; and too often, alas, we carry out
                            this policy in the daily growths of our human life, unmindful of the cause in our enjoyment
                            of the effect, forgetful so often of the "bridge that carried us over." Only
                            occasionally'does a Washington, a Lincoln or a Napoleon arise. To one Washington there are
                            thousands of uutitled privates, but what could the General accomplish without that phalanx
                            that merges its conflicting ind v,dualities, into the one electric stroke that vitalizes his
                            verbal command ! A page in our national history ascribes the loss of a battle to the
                            disobedience of one man. A trifle? Perhaps so, but (/" so then just such trifles have moved
                            the world. The stroke of a pen is a little thing, but it may mean emancipation to thousands
                            of suffering hearts 01 it may seal the doom of a waiting convict. A "grain of mustard seed"
                            is in itself a trifle, but this quantity of pure Christian faith is a remover of mountains.
                            A sling and a stone in the hands of an unarmored David brought a sneer to the face of the
                            mighty Goliath, but when they were exercised "in the name of the Lord of hosts," they
                            accomplished no trifling work. Such trifles make history, such trifles make men. Our Savior
                            showed a beautiful appreciation of small things. The lily, the sparrow, the little leaven,
                            the cup of cold water, the branch iu the vine were great iu his divine sight; and while the
                            proud and haughty were allowed to pass unaccosted, "Jesus called a little child unto him and
                            set him in the midst of them" as a text to that wonderful sermon upon true conversion, in
                            which he let fall the words: "Take heed that ye despise not one of these little ones." The
                            two mites cast timidly into the Lord's treasury by the poor widow did not escape the eye of
                            the gentle Master ever so watchful for the springing up of the gospel seed which he had sown
                            so liberally in the heart soil all around him. The spiritual much that hallowed the giving
                            of the ma- <pb n="35" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 35 terial trifle called forth the approval:
                            "I say unto you that this poor widow hath cast in more than they all." The significant
                            lessons from Scripture, from history, and from the everyday battle fields teach us that no
                            thought, expression or action should be deemed trivial until its effect proves it so.
                            Someone has said, "Fidelity in little things is the great Lest of life." How true! Eisi
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Order of mediation, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>THE ORDER OF MEDIATION. NO. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lyon, John" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder John Lyon.</byline><p TEIform="p">T is well known that every time the Israelites disregarded the law which God had given them
                            through him, God manifested himself to them in displeasure and showed them by his judgments
                            that inasmuch as they rejected His anointed mediator, they rejected Him. When God found his
                            typical people outside of their order, He sent messengers to call them to their duty. He
                            sent angels, spirits and prophets, and if they rejected these, He would send His judgments
                            upon them until they were humbled enough to return to their duty. When they were found
                            beyond the order of mediation and blending with the world, God visited them as He did the
                            children of the world. They had no need to call in spirits either good or bad, to teach them
                            their duty; this was given to their mediator in his anointing, and there was the place for
                            them to look. The Lord said unto Moses, "Gather unto me seventy men of the Elders of Israel
                            whom thou knowest to be the Elders of the people, and officers over them, and bring them
                            unto the tabernacle of the congregation that they may stand there with thee, and I will come
                            down and talk with thee and I will take of the spirit which is upon thee and will put it
                            upon them and they shall bear the burden of the people with thee, that thou bear it not
                            thyself alone." And Moses told the people the word of the Lord and gathered the seventy men
                            of the Elders of the people and set them round about the tabernacle. And the Lord came down
                            in a cloud and spake unto him and took of the spirit that was upon Moses and gave it unto
                            the seventy Elders, and it came to pass that when it rested upon them they prophesied and
                            did not cease.Num. xi., 16, 17, 24, 25. God did not say that He would send seventy spirits
                            to take possession of the men, but told Moses that He would take of the spirit that was upon
                            him. The order of mediation was the rock which followed them, and this rock was the
                            foundation on which the typical dispensation stood. "If the foundation be destroyed what can
                            the righteous do?" It could not be destroyed as God had laid it, although the people of
                            Israel could and did swerve from <pb n="36" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE MANIFESTO. the foundation and
                            lost the blessing of God. God was faithful to his promises. "You only have I known, of all
                            the families of the earth ; therefore I will punish you for all your iniquities."Aino;-,
                            iii., 2. Moses told them that they would lightly esteem the rock of their salvation. He also
                            told them that they would sacrifice unto gods whom they knew not. "Of the rock that begat
                            thee thou art unmindful, and hast forgotten God that formed thee."Deut. xxxii. This the Lord
                            saw and he abhorred them. When they disregarded the foundation on which they stood, they
                            disregarded God, and if they attempted to worship God under the rites and ceremonies of the
                            law, it was an abhorrence in His sight, as He spake by the prophet Amos, "I hate, I despise
                            your feast days and I will not smell in your solemn assemblies." "Though ye offer me burnt
                            offerings, and your meat offerings, 1 will not accept them, neither will I regard the peace
                            offerings of your fat beasts. Amos, v.. 21, 22. When this typical people disobeyed God in
                            the order of mediation, they were left to reap the fruit of their own doings. Paul says,"Now
                            these things were our ensamples to the intent we should not lust after evil things as they
                            also lusted."Cor. x., 6. We have the plain evidence in this dispensation of types and
                            shadows that God was true to His promise. Moses did not sanctify the Lord before the people,
                            by acknowledging that it was God through him that brought the water out of the rock ;
                            instead of this he sanctified himself and his brother Aaron, saying, "Hear now ye rebels :
                            must vve fetch you water out of this rock?"Num. xx., 10. For this disregard he was debarred
                            from entering the promised land. Eli was a high priest and his sons were ministering priests
                            to the people, yet they were not suffered to go unpunished, any more than the lowest of the
                            people. It will be said that Moses, Nadab and Abihu, Aaron's sons, and Eli with his sons
                            were in the line of the anointed. Very true, and it shows clearly that God's order of
                            mediation can not be trampled upon with impunity by any class of people. It also shows that
                            each will be rewarded according to his works; to whom much is given, of him will much be
                            required. Nadab and Abihu, soon after they were established in the priesthood, trampled upon
                            God's law by disregarding the order given to them by the mediator; and fire came forth from
                            the Lord and destroyed them. The sons of Eli profaned the anointing that was upon them and
                            disregarded the law given by the anointed mediator. Their father knew this but did not
                            restrain them preferring his affection for his sons above God, till God's wrath fell upon
                            him and his whole house. 1 Sam. ii., iii., iv. The order of God could not be violated with
                            impunity, but God would sustain the honor of the order of His appointment. God said to Eli,
                            "Them that honor me, I will honor, and they that despise me shall be lightly esteemed." This
                            was verified by judgments that fell upon him and his house. Eli fell backward from his seat
                            and was killed. His sons were both slain in <pb n="37" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 37 one day.
                            Abimelech also was slain with eighty of Eli's line of posterity, and all were driven from
                            the priesthood. 1 Sam. xxii. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to sister Polly Lewis; Passing away of the ancients" TEIform="index"/>Tribute to
                            Sister POLLY LEWIS. PASSING AWAY OF THE ANCIENTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeVere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>By Cecelia DeVere.</byline><p TEIform="p">When the ancients of the city pass away, Sorrow gently mingles love with pain, And the sombre
                            portals dim and gray Vibrate with the angel's lifting strain. Golden latch and golden hinges
                            are not slow to ope, Aud our glorious banner's fringes glow with cheering hope, Yet we feel
                            a human sorrow and a human cross, And we know that earth's to-morrow holds our heavy loss.
                            Ah ! we miss the forms we cherished thro' the vanished years, Long for voices that have
                            perished 'mid our falling tears. She whose soul was pure and lowly as the sweetest flower,
                            With a faith divinsly holy walked in dauntless power, No display of gift or treasure brought
                            she vainly forth, Yet we could not guage the measure of her innate worth, 'Twas a daily
                            revelation in her temporal place, As her spiritual salvation shed translucent grace. In the
                            mart of custom standing, meeting with the world, Honor's highest mesd commanding e'en where
                            folly whirled. Lightest minds grew staid before her, wild emotions settled down, 'Neath the
                            halo shining o'er her, she was never known to frown. ''Dear Aunt Polly" strangjrs named her,
                            with a reverent look and air, While they felt the light that framed her was the circle of
                            soul prayer. Fragile form and quiet bearing yet a tower of strength, Labor's heavy burdens
                            sharing through her brave life's length. Round the loved ones she is leaving in her little
                            central home, We our tenderest thot's are weaving that some signal good may come. While the
                            ancients of the city are a potent unseen band, To life's changes bringing pity, and the wise
                            and helpful hand. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Count not that time lost..." TEIform="index"/>Count not that time lost...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Count not that time lost which is spent in holy meditation and prayer. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak well of all..." TEIform="index"/>Speak well of all...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Speak well of all, do good to all, and ill to none.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><pb n="38" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind remembrance" TEIform="index"/>KIND REMEMBRANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew D." TEIform="persName"/>By Andrew D. Barrett.</byline><p TEIform="p">AN atmosphere of love promotes harmony and favors health of body and mind. It fills the soul
                            with peace ; it encourages every ennobling function ; it carries with it the dignity,
                            gentleness and refinement of true culture. In the ebb and flow of the ever moving tide we
                            see a lesson of human life . We see that love must be the magnet in winning souls to God.
                            When the soul is so filled with love that it can go out to help the needy, it has reached a
                            degree of true culture far more exalting than all intellectual training. These thoughts have
                            been pressed upon my mind on hearing of the demise of our beloved Eldress Joanna J. Kahne.
                            As I was a resident of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., for some twenty-five years I became acquainted
                            with Eldress Joanna, as she quite frequently visited that Society in the capacity of a
                            minister. Her Christian kindness made a permanent impression on my mind, and increased my
                            love toward goodness and truth. Now the voice says, Go and do likewise. Olive Branch,
                        Fla.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Growth" TEIform="index"/>GROWTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>By Fidella Estabrook.</byline><p TEIform="p">Ake you growing, daily growing in the likeness of the King? Does His love, so strong, so
                            lasting in your heart with fervor spring? Does the life of Christ, our Savior, thro your
                            life with brightness glow? Does His spirit dwell within you? Do you daily, hourly grow? Are
                            you growing as the seedling, sending forth strong roots of prayer, Gaining strength and
                            careful guidance from eternal sources there? Are you pushing to the sunlight leaves of
                            earnest, Christ-like deeds, Are .your plants of worth and beauty, or but tares and worthless
                            weeds ? Are you growing as the lily, trustful, pure, in grace each day? Caring not for
                            coming morrows, pushing upward all the way, Leaving death, and doubt, and darkness, looking
                            to the light above, Catching rays of richest blessing, and reflecting beams of love? Are you
                            growing in the Savior? Are you drawing from the vine His own strength, His love and power,
                            making truly His will, thine? Are your tendrils ever clinging to the promises, so sure ?
                            Will the harvest yield the fruitage that forever will endure ? <pb n="39" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 39 Are you growing in His meekness? Are you growing in His love? Never resting,
                            never doubting, pressing toward the realms above. We must die to selfish pleasures, die,
                            that true life we may win, Only by complete surrender does the perfect life begin. Perfect
                            life'tis found by growing, first the seed, then blade, then ear, Each one perfect in its
                            forming till the perfect fruit appear. Growing, when the days are cloudy, growing when the
                            hours are bright, Since we ever must be growing, may we grow but in the right. Growing thro'
                            the bitter trial clean and pure, from self-life, free, Growing with each well-borne testing,
                            moi"e, O Savior, like to thee. Growing, when the storms of sorrow beat in tempests, far and
                            near, And when God's rich Bow of Promise writes above us, "Do not fear." Growing in His
                            peace, so precious, rooted, growing, deep and free, E'er abiding in His presence, I in
                            Christ, and Christ in me. Hidden in His life, forever, may my life His glory show, By His
                            cross in daily bearing, I to perfect stature grow. And when dawns the day of harvest, and
                            the reapers shall appear Gathering to the Master's garner souls from out earth's garden
                            here. Tho ours may not be the blossom, or the fully ripened grain, Yet may we be found still
                            growing, till perfection we attain. West Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Holy spirit" TEIform="index"/>THE HOLY SPIRIT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">HOLY, set apart to the service of God, sacred. Free from sinful affections. Pure, guiltless.
                            When about to leave the world, Jesus said to his disciples, I will not leave you
                            comfortless. I will pray the Father and He shall give you another Comforter, even the Spirit
                            of Truth that she may abide with you forever. I have yet many things to say to you, but ye
                            can not bear them now. But when she, the Spirit of Truth is come, She will lead you into all
                            Truth. She will glorify me, because She will take of mine and declare to you. She will show
                            you things to come. People who uphold a system which excludes woman from all ministration in
                            holy things, falsely represent the Holy Spirit in the masculine gender, whenever referred to
                            as a personality. In Hebrew, the language of the people who first used the term, it is
                            feminine, and so regarded by the Primitive Christians, as the best informed writers and
                            scholars, like Farrar and Westcott, agree. The attempt to falsify the record is an'artifice
                            of Antichrist to exclude woman from her rightful place and office in the work of redemption.
                                <pb n="40" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 40 THE MANIFESTO. Any class of people that holds woman in bondage
                            to man, whether by marriage or legislative enactments or by public opinion, do thereby prove
                            that they are of the world, and the spirit of the Lord Jesus is not in them nor with them,
                            for where the spirit of the Lord is there is liberty of body, soul, mind and conscience. The
                            only free conversation which Jesus had with a non-Jew during his ministry, that we find
                            recorded, was with the woman of Samaria. To her he confided this important truth,God is
                            Spirit, not a spirit. The hour cometh and now is, when they that worship the Father, must
                            worship Him in Spirit and in Truthor in the spirit of Truth, for the Father seeketh such to
                            worship Him. The last sentence conveys the impression that such are few. They must first
                            receive of His Spirit. Then only those who are thereby drawn to seek Him, will retain, or be
                            found in it. He says in JoelI will pour out my Spirit upon all flesh created in my likeness.
                            That is, after certain days, evidently after all our sins are purged away in the judgment.
                            Jesus sent the woman of Samaria with a message to her people. It was a woman also whom he
                            first commissioned to bear a message, after he came forth from invisibility to be seen only
                            by witnesses, chosen before, of God. Ann Lee was a chosen witness, anointed with the Holy
                            Spirit of Truth, who purified her own temple by the word of God and the daily cross,
                            abolished in her own person the curse of the great transgression, brought life and immortal
                            ity to men and women who had sought it in vain in the nominally Christian churches, and
                            became the free, joyful Mother of spiritual children, who keep the commandments of God, and
                            have the testimony of Jesus against all sin. These are the woman's seed who crush the
                            serpent's head of fleshly lust, or sexual attraction. For this is the grim giant which
                            stands till conquered between every soul and its final inheritance with saints in light. It
                            must be overcome and destroyed by the daily cross, or it will enslave the soul, prevent
                            advance to the higher, and eclipse if not destroy all prospects of happiness in a life to
                            come. All who have escaped victors from the Beast described in Revelations, through
                            obedience to Mother Ann's testimony, do bear witness in their lives that her testimony is
                            true, and they are many in one Holy Spirit of life everlasting. She did, what Jesus said the
                            Comforter would do, convict the world of sin, of righteousness and of Judgment. Of sin, by
                            reproving certain actions as sin which the world does not condemn. Of righteousness, by
                            works of righteousness which she obeyed and taught others to follow. Of Judgment, by making
                            souls feel the necessity of self-judging and confessing their sins before an appointed
                            witness, and forsaking them forever. Those who do this escape the post mortem judgment of
                            condemnation, because in so doing they pass from death unto life while clothed in mortal
                            bodies. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="41" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Illustration" TEIform="index"/>AN ILLUSTRATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Abraham Perkins.</byline><p TEIform="p">AMONG- the good words spoken by Elder Henry C. Blinn in our Service, I was deeply imprest
                            with his reference to the testimony of Eldress Polly Reed of the Ministry of Mt. Lebanon,
                            who years ago said to us in this place, that we are to be individually our own Elders, yet
                            we realize the liability to so construe and apply it in a manner as to remove us entirely
                            from the foundation of genuine Christianity. The remark was simply and altogether an
                            illustration of the making of Christian life practicable by so cautiously guarding all our
                            thoughts, words and acts, so completely controlling our spirit, that no emanation or
                            influence from our lives should leave a blot on our character as Christian disciples or work
                            weakness in other souls by drawing them into a condition of independence, thus removing from
                            the school of Christ its members, who are to become as children easy to be taught and to be
                            subject to the order and polity of the institution. Elder Henry carefully added in his
                            remarks, the necessity of a pilot at the helm, a guide to preserve the harmony of the body,
                            which among the truths of the gospel is an essential item for the safety and redemption of
                            the Christian traveler. To the disciples of Jesus, it was his closing and special charge
                            that his baptism was to be their baptism, his life and testimony they were to handle and
                            preach, giving the assurance that he who accepted and received it receiveth him and Him that
                            sent him. No clearer revelation could be given of the order of a central ministration in the
                            house of God, unto whose teachers he gave the power of loosing and binding on earth as is
                            the order and law in heaven and the means alone for heirship and rightful claims in the
                            heavenly kingdom. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfect through suffering" TEIform="index"/>PERFECT THROUGH SUFFERING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">A cloud o'erhangs my way; I can not see ; A darkening trial fills my soul with dread, And
                            every doubting step my feet must tread, Leads but to labyrinthsuncertainty, Where weird-like
                            shadows flit unceasingly. O faithless heart! O blinded sight that's led Where phantom shapes
                            their ghostly presence shed. Anoint thine eyes with faith and thou shalt see. Shalt see the
                            cloud fringed with hope's radiance bright; Shalt see thy woe an angel sanctified, That
                            gently leads tliee on through sorrow's night, If thou but calmly trust, in faith abide, Ope
                            wide thy soul, let in the holy light, And lo ! thy inner life is glorified. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="42" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MA.ECH, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLIGATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50 A
                            cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">January. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1898. 25.45 1.25 in.
                                S}4 ft. 1899. 26.8 1.125 " 17 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 54 above 0. Lowest " " "
                                " 6 below" Number of rainy days " " 3 " " snowy " " " 2 " " clear " " " 12 " " cloudy" "
                                " 14 Jan. 1899. It can not be said of this month, we have nodeaths to record,at 11
                                o'clock a. m. Jan. 15, Sackett Root. At 7 o'clock 45 min. Jan. 31, Sister Mary Hazzard.
                                At 5 o'clock p. m. Jan 14, Sister Polly Lewis. January has been a very sickly month in
                                our Community. Very few have escaped its malarial attacks. Once in thirty-three years or
                                there abouts, our planet is subject to be afflicted with some kind of disease which ends
                                the mortal life of an unusual number, as the records show. February is destined to be a
                                sickly month and thus far it has been. Temporalities in the business line are
                                prospering. We have the major part of our year's stock of fire wood at home ready to be
                                sawed. We have 175 tons of ice securely housed ready, when summer comes, to cool our
                                milk and broth. Men are working on the State Road, building the bridges and putting in
                                the 4 ft. cylinders to conduct the water in the ravines under the road bed. Our highway
                                roads are rather changeable, wheeling intersperst by sleighing; at times the snow would
                                be dissolved and the sleighing would be destroyed. At present six inches of snow covers
                                the ground and sleighing is used in transportation. Calvin G. Heed. South Family. Feb.
                                1899. Cold continues loud winds blow And anon comes down the snow, Shall be glad when
                                winter's through, Wintry days are never few. Oh! for summer days to come When we hear
                                the glad bird's song, When again the earth is seen Not in white, but robes of green. La
                                Grippe has past through here and shaken hands with many in this section; we hope he will
                                soon depart never more to return; he came uninvited, and uninvited he will go, an
                                unwelcomed guest. Our dear Eldress Annie has been shut in for a few weeks; a patient La
                                Grippe patient but through the skillful management of our local physician, Dr. Cleland,
                                she is daily improving much to our satisfaction, we trust she will soon be restored to
                                health and activity again. TERMS <pb n="43" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 43 Since our last
                                writing we have witnest the ascension of three of the "Ancients of the City," Sisters,
                                Polly C. Lewis, Mary Hazzard, and Sophronia Dole. Sister Sophronia was one of a noble
                                family w ho united with the Community atSodus, and with them removed to Groveland in
                                1836, where she lived a long and useful life doing good to all around her. Sister Laura
                                Dole is the last surviving member of that family; years of faithful service has rnarkt
                                her record, we trust that peace and prosperity may attend her declining years. One by
                                one they're passing on, Friends we long have known; But we'll meet them all again In our
                                spirit home. Genevieve DeGraio.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1899. We endorse without reserve all thatBr. George H. Baxter has stated in February
                                Manifesto in reverencing the character of those departed saints, but would kindly
                                suggest the following amendment. While it is beneficial to the individual soul to
                                contemplate the example of those who have past over to the other side; be it resolved
                                that we will not wait for that time to arrive but remember those pure and brave souls
                                who are at present in the battle of life and gather from them that blessed inspiration
                                which flows from those exalted lives and who are waiting patiently to be seen and
                                appreciated. Those who have past to the evergreen shores faithfully performed their
                                duty. We are here to perform ours; to be strengthened by their noble example. But to
                                those weary and overburdened souls who are ready to give their lives for the truth, a
                                kind word and a sympathetic look is accepted with a blessing; let us give it in
                                overflowing measure. Day by day as we watch old Sol's advance as he moves northward, we
                                are reminded that time is swiftly passing and soon Spring will be here with her
                                inspiration in song-birds and flowers, and with toil on the farm and garden. The efforts
                                that have been made in the later years to lift agriculture and horticulture out of the
                                rut where it was supposed any ignoramus who was not fit for anything else could be a
                                farmer or gardener, are bearing excellent fruit. Farming is classed with the most
                                advanced scientific attainments, where brains and an intellectual training, as well as
                                physical development are the factors that make the successful farmer and gardener.
                                Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1899. The past few weeks we have battled with humanity's enemy, La Grippe, who crept
                                in among us and placed his debilitating power upon many of our folks. At date of
                                writing, Feb. 8th, La Grippe has less weight and ve are seeking his speedy banishment.
                                On Jan. 80th, the bell of Immortality pealed forth its notes of "Come up Higher" for our
                                loved Sister Zelinda Smith, who for many years honored our North family with Christ]y
                                culture and faithful work. In her life we have an example of nobility safe to imitate.
                                On the following day, our valued Brother Thomas Steadman, responded to the higher
                                summons. Sixty years of noble consecration to our cause, forms his priceless diadem. As
                                overseer of our large barn and stock, he ranked the best. In that realm where man is
                                judged, not by scholarship, position or profession, but by his life acts, Brother Thomas
                                will reap a rich reward. Two more vacant places. Upon the horizon of coming events, we
                                perceive the on-coming messenger for others who must soon pass beyond Eternity's curtain
                                that obscures from our sight the "Land of Souls." Even death has its message to us not
                                only hope for better things, but also as old laws and materiality pass away work for the
                                readjustment of society's conditions to the new changes less individual strength
                                createth. <pb n="44" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 44 THE MANIFESTO. If we as a class are to keep our
                                Godgiven estate free from the monopolizing greed of the world, and are to pass on
                                God-ward, we must work as the heart of one for the good oi all. Waste no time soaring in
                                the heaven of sentimentalism, predicting evil and debating upon non-essentials, to the
                                neglect of the spiritual and industrial parts of our body politic. Let us train
                                ourselves to greater endurance in fulfilling the responsibilities which the honor of our
                                Church demands. George II. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1899. Candlemas Day dawned "fair and clear" so, according to the prophecies of the
                                ancient weather-wise, we are still to expect winter. One storm came into line on the
                                7th, as if to verify the time-honored couplet; "If Candlemas Day dawn fair and clear
                                Beware, for winter has not been here." At date, 14th, the elements are conspiring to
                                furnish us with an old-fashioned blizzard, which opened its first act Sunday a. m. It
                                brings one keen disappointment on its snowy wings, however, since it necessitates a
                                postponement of the longanticipated visit of our beloved Central Ministry, who had
                                agreed to be with us on the 15th. Still, "the storm will not always last," and our
                                loving welcomes are safely deposited in the bank of Heart and Home, which issues all
                                payments with compound interest. Despite the inclemency of the weather our worthy
                                Brother, John Bradford, has found his way from Enfield, N. H., and ii now securely
                                environed with us on the hill from which, happily, there is no escape for him at
                                present. We are always much pleased when our good friends call this way, and when our
                                influence is not strong enough to hold them we willingly accept foreign aid even when it
                                takes the guise of huge snowdrifts. Jessie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1899. The balmy breezes for the past two months are having a salutary effect upon
                                the fruit trees of Florida. The peaches in many sections of the state are in full bloom
                                and some blossoms have even fallen. To pass through an orchard of one or two thousand
                                trees, and inhale the sweet fragrance, is a thing to gladden the heart of every lover of
                                nature. The last orange crop has nearly all been gathered, and the nursery men are now
                                fertilizing the trees for the coming crop. Sweet potatoes will not be ready for market
                                before June. The long, dry season since last spring prevented their growth. If our crop
                                of potatoes does not mature in one season, it is left in the ground and begins a new
                                growth the coming season without the least injury. Every year tells a little better for
                                the lands we are cultivating. We are now trying our luck on a crop of onions and from
                                present appearance we anticipate a good crop. Hope on, hope ever, is the motto for
                                Florida. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of sister Sophronia Dole" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of Sister SOPHRONIA DOLE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, Louise" TEIform="persName"/>By Louise Bussell.</byline><p TEIform="p">Our Mother has crost the dark river, Been called to an eternal rest, And joined with the
                            angels in singing The song of the ransomed, so blest. Like a ripened sheaf, she was ready,
                            Her toils and her labors were o'er; And gladly she heard the sweet summons To rest from all
                            care evermore. She spent a long life in God's service, Was one of the faithful and tried; A
                            pillar of strength, she was ever A soul who all sin had denied. Her words were like balm to
                            the weary, She blest every one in the right, Gave courage and strength to the doubting And
                            bid them to walk in the light. <pb n="45" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> Tl IE MANIFES TO. 45 And now as we
                            tender love's tribute, How brightly her virtues do shine, Inciting us onward ard upward, To
                            joys that are pure and divine. And O, in our hearts is erected, By her life so noble and
                            pure, A monument strong in its structure, For truth is its corner-stone sure. We love thee,
                            and bless thee, dear Mother, For the seed of good thou hast sown; . And for all thy toiling
                            and sowing A harvest for thee has been grown. Go, reap the reward of thy labors: The angels
                            have welcomed thee home, I hear them proclaim the glad tidings, No more on the earth shalt
                            thou roam But ere thou dost enter the portals, Kemember the toilers below, And wave o'er our
                            pathway thy mantle, Thy love and thy goodness bestow. O, help us to live for the gospel, To
                            swerve not from duty's straight line, To carry aloft the bright banner, And work for the
                            cause that's divine. We want to be blest with a fullness, Of goodness, of mercy and love, We
                            plead for a power that is mighty For the strength which comes from above. That we may be
                            true to our calling Be workers in Zion's rich field, Devoting our all to God's service, That
                            our lives rich blessing may yield. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Elder Henry:--I mail you the following..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Elder Henry:--I mail you the following...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mt. Lebanon, January 8, 1899" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Jan. 8,
                            1899.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Henry :I mail you the following poem thinking it may please and interest some of
                            the many readers of The Manifesto. It teaches a most valuable lesson, one we should ever
                            keep in view on our journey through life. Kindly your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Polly C." TEIform="persName"/>Polly C. Lewis.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Always some one below" TEIform="index"/>ALWAYS SOME ONE BELOW.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Higginson, Ella" TEIform="persName"/>By Ella Higginson.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> On the lowest round of the ladder I firmly planted my feet, And lookt up in the
                                    dim, vast distance That made my future so sweet. I climbed till my vision grew
                                    weary, I climbed till my brain was on fire, I planted each footstep with wisdom Yet
                                    I never seemed to get higher. For this round was glazed with indifference And that
                                    one was glazed with scorn, And when I graspt firmly another I found under velvet a
                                    thorn. Till my brain grew weary of planning And my heart strength began to fail, And
                                    the flush of the morning's excitement Ere evening commenced to pale. But just as my
                                    hands were unclasping Their hold on the last gained round, When my hopes coming back
                                    from the future, Were sinking again to the ground, One who had climbed near the
                                    summit Reacht backward a helping hand And refrcsht, encouraged, strengthened I took
                                    once again my stand. And I wishOh I wishthat the climbers Would never forget as they
                                    go That, tho weary may seem their climbing, There is always some one below.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal of Education" TEIform="index"/>Journal of Education.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food we eat" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOD WE EAT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">The position that is occupied by the human family in its claims for existence is, indeed,
                            very peculiar. Just how far man has adhered to the original plan, will no doubt, be very
                            difficult of solution. If we can entertain the thought that the race came into existence on
                            the same plane as did all the beasts of the field, the birds of the air and the fishes of
                            the sea, and that each order accepted the food that nature provided, then we only have to
                            study the other animals to see what would naturally be the drift of the human. While the
                            beasts, birds and fishes, in all probability, eat very much to-day as they did on the day of
                            their creation; man by having a progressive mind, has made many changes. <pb n="46" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 48 THE MAN]FES TO. Tiiis may well become a quandary in the minds of those who are
                            interested in what man shuu'd eat. If lie wns intended for an herbivorous or graminivorous
                            animal he has ct rtaiivy departed to a sad extent from the oii.;inal plan. II it was
                            nn'icip.ited that he would become an omnivorous aniiiial, and appropriate as food every
                            thing that he could obtain on the land or in the sea, then his present position may be more
                            readily understood. Specialists can easily work out a theory in accordance with their
                            religious or scientific views, and after long and labored dissertations it may prove
                            satisfactory, especially to themselves, that man was made to subsist entirely on the fruits,
                            vegetables and grains. Another class, equally as religious, and no less intelligent, are
                            positive that man was made to live on a mixed diet and to accommodate himself to that which
                            happened to fall into his possession. The first theory is strengthened by Biblical
                            authority, "I have given you every herb bearing seed, and every tree in the which is the
                            fruit of a tree yielding seed; to you it shall be for meat." It is also claimed in defense
                            of this position, that the teeth of man are made for the eating of the varied kinds of
                            fruits that are grown in the vegetable kingdom. The advocates of the second theory, place
                            man among the omnivorous animals whose food is obtained from both the animal and vegetable
                            kingdom. If an animal crossed his path, it was at once slaughtered for food, and if fruits
                            were to be obtained, they also were accepted. This class also quote the Bible as a witness
                            of the position they occupy, and say that one of the first acts after the creation of man,
                            was the slaughtering of some animals, and the skins were made into garments for those who
                            lived in Eden, and in all probability the Edenites ate the meat and Noah's first offering to
                            God, on leaving the ark, was the fat and blood of slaughtered animals. Soon after this date
                            man seems to have become a universal scavenger in accordance with the Biblical
                            command,"Every moving thing that liveth shall be food for you." Certainly all believers in
                            the Bible and in flesh eating should have respect to this remarkable provision of food for
                            man. Whatever may have been the divine plan in regard to the human economy, it is safe to
                            say that we are quite well informed of the custom that prevails among us at the present time
                            and our health and prosperity claim our earnest and special interest. Those human beings who
                            inhabited the earth, on the first days of creation should have no more influence upon us in
                            regard to our food, than in regard to our language or our general habits or customs. Mankind
                            has grown, through thousands of years of valuable experience and the savagery of eating and
                            drinking as those did, either before or after the flood, would hold us among a class of
                            semi-civilized beings. The moral quality that has been developt in the mind of man, has
                            given rise to many questions, and the subject of food preparation must find its legitimate
                            place as essential and imperative for the prosperity of mankind as are the questions
                            concerning right and wrong in civil cases or in matters of religious belief. If we look at
                            the several classes of animals, we find them as they always have been so far as we may know;
                            the herbivorous eating the same kind of food as in the day of their creation, while the
                            carnivorous or flesh eating animals continue to devour all they can capture. Even this
                            savage, animal nature has had a place among some of the races of men and they have
                            signalized themselves as cannibals by even killing and eating their own species. Aside from
                            the mere habit of taste, one creature may be as acceptable as another and essentially so as
                            it was the command of the Bible, that "Every moving thing that liveth shall be food for
                            jou." The world is not so old but this command still continues more or less in active
                            operation, as the Christians and Heathen contend with each other to see which shall secure
                            the largest number of moving things to be used as food. We have only <pb n="47" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 47 to interest ourselves with this subject, in order to iind that so late as
                            the closing of the 19th century, but few things live and breathe that are not appropriated
                            by man as food. Even tlio it should be proved, that man did for thousands of years live as
                            an omnivorous animal in common with all other creatures of that same order, we are
                            interested to know that a change came so soon as it did to give evidence of a better way.
                            (To be conti.iued.) </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food and teeth" TEIform="index"/> FOOD AND TEETH.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"It is a remarkable fact," said a prominent New York dentist recently, "that
                                        the teeth of the poor are stronger and usually last longer than those of the
                                        well-to-do classes. The reason for this is that what food the poor give their
                                        children is of a variety that goes to make bones and teeth. This food consists
                                        of the outside of all the grains of all cereal foods, that contain the carbonate
                                        and phosphate of lime and traces of other earthy salts, all of which nourish the
                                        bony tissues and build up the frame. If we do not furnish to the teeth of the
                                        young that pabulum they require they can not possibly be built up. It is the
                                        outside of corn, oats, wheat, barley, and the like, or the bran, so called, that
                                        we sift away and feed to the swine that the teeth require for their proper
                                        nourishment. The wisdom of man has proved his folly, shown in every succeeding
                                        generation of teeth, which become more fragile and weak. Our modern flouring
                                        mills are working destruction upon the teeth of every man, woman and child who
                                        partakes of their fine bolted flour. They sift out the carbonates and phosphates
                                        of lime in order that they may provide that fine, white flour which is proving a
                                        whitened sepulchre to teeth. Oatmeal is one of the best foods for supplying the
                                        teeth with nourishment. It makes the dentine, cementum and enamel strong,
                                        flint-like and able to resist all forms of decay. If you have children never
                                        allow any white bread upon your table. Bread made of whole wheat ground, not
                                        bolted, so that the bran, which contains the minute quantities of lime, is
                                        present, is best. Nothing is superior to brown bread for bone and tooth
                                        building. Baked beans, too, have a considerable supply of these lime salts and
                                        should be on every one's table, hot or cold, twice a week."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brutalizing and infamous" TEIform="index"/>BRUTALIZING AND INFAMOUS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Massachusetts has the first law prohibiting vivisection in the schools, and
                                        in defence of it W. W. Niles, the Episcopal bishop of New Hampshire, says: "The
                                        torturing of dumb animals in the presence of a class of young people for the
                                        purpose of instruction is inhuman, brutalizing and infamous. Far better is it
                                        for both society and the individual that the scholar should know nothing that is
                                        taught in the schools than that he or she should be thus degraded and turned
                                        into a brute. The monster in human form who could give such an exhibition to
                                        young persons or defend it in another ought not one hour longer to be tolerated
                                        for a teacher of youth. He ought to be dismist instantly, and a superintendant
                                        of a school board who could tolerate such a wickedness ought not longer to be
                                        suffered to misrepresent a community of menand women. Words fail me to express
                                        the horror with which doings of this kind fill my soul."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal Transcript" TEIform="index"/>Journal Transcript.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weaving" TEIform="index"/>WEAVING,</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Yes, I'm a weaver, and each day The threads of life I spin, And be the colors
                                    what they may, I still must weave them in. With morning light there comes the tho't
                                    As I my task begin My Lord to me new threads has brought, And bids me "weave them
                                    in." <pb n="48" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 48 THE MAN1FES TO. Sometimes he gives me threads of gold,
                                    To brighten up the day; Then sombre tints, so bleak and cold, Thiit change the gold
                                    to gray. And so my shuttle swiftly flies, Wi'h tlm ads both gold and gray; And on 1
                                    toil till daylight dies, And fades in the night away. 0!i, when my day of toil is
                                    o'er, And I shall cease to spin, He'll open wide my Father's door, And bid me rest
                                    withiD. When safe at home in heavenly light, How clearly I shall see That every
                                    thread, the dark, the bright, Each one had need to be!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian Advocate" TEIform="index"/>Christian Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My best" TEIform="index"/>MY BEST.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I may perform no deed of great renown, No glorious act to millions manifest; Yet
                                    in my little labors up and down I'll do my best. I may not paint a perfect
                                    masterpiece, Nor carve a statue by the world conf est A miracle of art; yet will not
                                    cease To do my best. My name is not upon the rolls of fame, 'Tis on the page of
                                    common life imprest But I'll keep marking, marking just the same, And do my best.
                                    Sometimes I sing a very simple song, And send it onward to the east or west: Altho
                                    in silentness it rolls along, I do my best. Sometimes I write a very little hymn,
                                    The joy within me can not be represt: Tho no one reads the letters are so dim, I do
                                    my best. And if I see some fellow-traveler rise Far, far above me, still with quiet
                                    breast I keep on climbing, climbing toward the skies, And do my best. spirals of
                                    paper are wound around each interior telegraph wire. The cost is much less than
                                    rubber. an auction in London, 400,000 skins of humming-birds were sold in one week.
                                    My very best, and if at close of day Worn out, I sit me down awhile to rest, I still
                                    will mend my garments if I may, And do my bestIt may not be the beautiful or grand,
                                    But I must try to be so careful, lest | I fail to be what's put into my hand, My
                                    very best. Better and better every stitch may be, The last a little stronger than
                                    the rest, Good master! help my eyes that they may see To do my best.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Womankind" TEIform="index"/>From .</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hardin, Tabitha A." TEIform="index"/>Tabitha A. Hardin
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Tabitha A. Hardin, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Jan. 24, 1899. Age 78 years. Sister Tabitha has
                                been a member of this society for more than sixty years. Of her we can say, "She hath
                                done what she could." J. W. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Zelinda" TEIform="index"/>Zelinda Smith
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Zelinda Smith, at Enfield, "NT. H. Jan. 30, 1899. Age 79
                                years. It was the birthday of Sister Zelinda, who had been feeble for several months.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steadman, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Steadman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Thomas Steadman, at Enfield, N. H. Jan. 31, 1899. Age 77 years, 8 mo. and 16 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dole, Sophronia" TEIform="index"/>Sophronia Dole
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sophronia Dole, at Watervliet, Ohio. Jan. 31, 1899. Age 84 years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hazzard, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Hazzard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Hazzard, at Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. Jan. 31, 1899. Age 87 yrs. 2 mo. and 19 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ward, Maria L." TEIform="index"/>Maria L. Ward
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Maria L. Ward, at Hancock
                                Mass. Feb. 1, 1899. Age 82 yrs. 0 mo, and 2 days. Sister Maria came to live in the
                                family in 1881. I. R. L. 'At Thin</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MA NIFESTO.
Lincoln arose! the masterful great man,
Girt with rude grandeur (juelling doubt and
fear,
A more than king, yet in whose veins there ran
The red blood of the people, warm, sincere,
Blending of Puritan and Cavalier.
A will whose force stern warriors came to ask
A heart that melted at a mother's tear
These brought he to his superhuman task ;
Over a tragic soul he wore a comic mask.
He was the South's child more than of the
North;
His soul was not compact of rack and snow,
But such as old Kentucky's soil gives forth,
The splendid race of giants that we know,
Firm unto friend, and loyal unto foe.
Such birthrights all environment forestall,
Resistlessly their tides of impulse flow.
This man who answered to his country's call
Was full of human faults, and nobler for them
all.
Henry Tyrell, in Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly
for February.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Invention,
fciril/PArchseology, Electricityliri I Til
liLllOChemistry, Mineralogy,fitAL I II
Health, Hygien, Mdioine.
Formerly Boston  Journa   of Chemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contains a large number of Short, Easy, Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he knew little or nothing of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers with a similar name.
the :;-::.:::;, covenant.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
S6 vcrtil
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds. Price 5 cts. each, postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
K Visit to the
Monthly,   $1.60 per year.    Newsdealers,   15   cts.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.
LILLAKD & 00.,
108 Fulton St., New York.
4=Mention this paper for a sample copy.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
f EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER.U. S. H
Liberally   Illustrated   with   half   tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the loveliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,   15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIONS,
DANIEL'S & ST JOHNS
48 page pamphlet.     Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio.
EXPLAINING
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
ROYAL
Powder
Absolutely Pure
Makes the food more delicious and wholesome
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
SHARER  HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore T^liroat and all
oases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Luna;s or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Abthor Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.   Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.36iBroadway- New York
Branch Office, C25 F St., Washington, D. C.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious ba"sis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule'the life of the individual for the protection of his own gOul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Pric-, 10 cts.
HOW TO HAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying yon from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
HAVE YOU "'COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once.for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>