<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0612" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18761201" TEIform="date">December 1876</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER Official Monthly.—Published by the United Societies. WHLA.T IS TRUTH P" "THB ETERNAL
                        RKLIHSrQTTISIIMENT OF ERROR.** Vol. VI. a. A. LOMAS, EDITOR. \ SHARERS, I Y, DECEMBER, 1876.
                        SHAKER TILLAGE, 11 N. A. BRIGGS, PUBLISIIEK. No. 12.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-rule" TEIform="index"/>SELF-RULE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O'Connell, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>JULIA O'CONNELL</byline><p TEIform="p">" He that hath no rule over his own spirit, is like a city that is broken down, and without
                            walls." This sentence is presented as an inward monitor and an external mirror. Often lias
                            its truth flashed before me in private thoughts. If we will suppose every thought of our
                            lives planted and grown to fruitage, how many of us would be willing to gather such a
                            harvest, or even be willing to stand afar off and gaze on the distortion ? Yet, when we
                            distrust the peace of others by giving rein to an envious, jealous or fault-finding spirit,
                            how surely are we growing unto a harvest, what we even refuse to look at as a reward ! " The
                            walls of the city broken," our self-respect wanting; the love that is of God dying within
                            our souls, having measured unto us in return, what we have meted out to others. But there
                            are other means of failing to " rule our spirits" than by the planting of briers and
                            thistles in the hearts of others. May we not indulge in melancholy and moroseness until our
                            spiritual sun is darkened? Our friends turn foes and our whole lives revolve in gloom. Is
                            there not a possibility of losing control of our own spirits, by such an over-anxiety for
                            others, that, in imagination their existence and presence seems to be the axis of our own
                            lives ? Being willing even to dwell in the shade, rather than hide the sun unto them ?
                            Sacrificing, beneath this very partial influence, not only deserved pleasures, intellectual
                            rights, but dwarfing besides, the growth of the spirit and preventing its approach unto God
                            ? Aggression from unholy impulses; consecration to a narrow, unchristian partiality; these
                            break the walls of our city. Who said that having rule over the spirit was greater than
                            taking a city, had a correct understanding of human nature and its inclinations — knew so
                            well the seductions of perversion; how willing the flesh and weak the spirit; how little by
                            little the walls of the city may be broken, until the valley of desolation is wofully
                            reached. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Does God want his name in the Constitution?" TEIform="index"/>DOES GOD WANT HIS NAME IN THE
                            CONSTITUTION?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">While a clergyman, or even a Christian has a quid of tobacco in his mouth ? Does He want His
                            name put into the Constitution^ while the government receives a large revenue from the
                            traffic of the lower regions — the liquor trade ? Does He want His name voted into the
                            Constitution by hands that could neither cast the first nor the last stone at that gigantic,
                            black sin which is mildly called the " social evil ? " Does He want His name put into the
                            Constitution by any who go through the miserable sham of sanctifying a system of marriage,
                            whose soul-grinding and body destroying slavery, the broken constitutions and early graves
                            of American women so directly testify against ? Does He want doctors, who poison
                            constitutions with drugs, to put His name into a paper document ? Does He want lawyers, who
                            " devour widows' substance," who only administer full justice to their own pockets, and for
                            a pretense, make profession of Him, to negotiate His name into the Constitution ? Does He
                            want any Judas Iscariot, of high or low degree, who sells republicanism here, and the hope
                            of the downtrodden abroad, for pieces of precious metal, or for United States' bonds, to put
                            His name into the Constitution ? A society that, through monopoly, crushes some of His weak
                            children down to wretchedness, and drives the rest along the road of crime, where the jail
                            and the hangman's rope are liberally provided; that takes the sword and forgets to love
                            mercy, and remembers not the injunction to depart from iniquity upon naming the Holy Name—a
                            society that practically denies the power of God and the principles of Christ, need not
                            blaspheme these names by putting them into the Constitution. We sometimes read of confidence
                            men ; but the most astounding and unblushing confidence men, are those engaged in this
                            present Church and State scheme. It is melancholy to contemplate at this time, when there is
                            work to be done, that faithful, earnest laborers are being called away to help these
                            designers to overthrow the good which has been effected during the century— that priestcraft
                            is once more coiling itself around the life of a nation, and if it is not shaken off,
                            history will repeat itself. There is but one way in which the name of God can be safely put
                            into the Constitution: Let there be an amendment that in God's name, the name of God and
                            Christ will be forever kept out of that Instrument. Let those who would honor God, be
                            peacemakers ; and they shall be called the children of God ; and if they would be disciples
                            of Christ, by this will all men know them; if they have love one for another ; and if they
                            would be high priests unto God and humanity, let them not only preach the gospel to the
                            poor, but so preach the gospel that there shall be no poor; " for the earth is the Lord's
                            and the fullness thereof;" and all who dwell thereon are " Heirs at Law to their Father's
                            Estate." " For all ye are brethren." It is mockery to put God's name into the Constitution
                            while His children are thus robbed. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visionary Dream" TEIform="index"/>VISIONARY DREAM</head><p TEIform="p">Or Interview with the Spirit of Brother Daniel Moseley, on the Night of Aug. 12, 1876. —o— He
                            seemed to have a chart of his whole earthlife, each point of particular significance was
                            marked. He said, " when I came into conscious being in the rudimental sphere of existence,
                            unlike the majority of youth and children of the present age, I was shielded from many
                            temptations to which they are exposed, and was at times much exercised in mind in regard to
                            religion, and I entered the gospel crucible, before being caught- in the meshes of the
                            grosser sins of the world ; but the world proper was in me, and my deep, soul struggles were
                            many. When I had contested the enemies' claims and gained some point, I thought to rest a
                            while on laurels won ; but there was always a spirit near to urge me forward to engage in
                            other battles, and win still greater victories. Thus I went from point to point in my work
                            and travel, and after passing through many life and death struggles, and many seasons of
                            judgment, there came to me, one great day of judgment—one general review of all the
                            transgressions of my life, of which there had been a record kept in form of a chart. There I
                            saw all the good and evil, the just and unjust thoughts and doings toward myself and others,
                            a sight of which caused me both joy and sorrow." At this point, Elder Daniel Boler stepped
                            in ; " ah," said brother Daniel Moseley, " there is a man who greatly resembles his elder
                            brother Daniel, in the work assigned him to do in the field of gospel labor, in so far as
                            courage and unflinching determination to do, and to suffer are requisite in performance of
                            duty, leaving fears and doubts in the wake, behind the great ship." Elder Daniel Boler
                            smiled and said, " where are all our worthy veterans — the old saints who served in the army
                            of the Lord? Whither have they gone or hid themselves ? Of late I have been searching to
                            find them?" " Well," said Brother Daniel Moseley, " for this very reason it is a wise
                            arrangement that we pass within the vale, out of sight of mortals, that they may not stay
                            their minds too much upon past events, nor upon their predecessors in the gospel work ; but
                            fix their minds and give their energies to present duties, and to perform the work of their
                            own day and time."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette Doolittle</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="First thing a truly religious man should seek to be is..." TEIform="index"/>First thing a truly religious man should seek to be is...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The first thing a truly religious man should seek to be is a perfect animal. Holiness,
                            wholeness of body and perfection in bodily structure are the first triumphs a religious man
                            can win. To be strong with all possible strength ; to be beautiful with all possible beauty;
                            to be perfect in that which is least, as a stepping-stone to perfection of that which is
                            greater, is the first ambition of intelligent piety.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Murray, W. H. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. H. Murray</byline></div2><pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialism—spiritualism, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALISM-SPIRITUALISM. NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline">TO. 
                            <persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">TnAT there is so great obscurity respecting the continued existence of man after his physical
                            disorganization, is to many a sufficient reason for rejecting the idea altogether. Why, they
                            ask, should a matter of so great importance to man be involved in so much darkness as to
                            leave him in doubt? The answer, oft repeated, that there is no more obscurity respecting
                            this matter than almost every thing else in the world, and that truth, though not coy, yet
                            loves to be sought after, and ofttimes, earnestly, is not satisfactory to certain minds. The
                            indolent mind will still ask, why the necessity of this incessant work ? It is true, the
                            materialists are not all idlers, mentally. Some are distinguished for their profound
                            investigations in the arcana of nature ; and to many of those who trust to others to do
                            their own thinking, it is a sufficient reason why they should call themselves materialists,
                            because these philosophers, these scientists, are such. These have searched nature through,
                            and nowhere have discovered the fountain whose waters give immortal youth. With their
                            hammers they have broken the primitive rock ; they have searched through the secondary and
                            tertiary formations, and lo, it is all material! They have put it into their crucibles and
                            reduced it to its original elements, and still there is nothing but matter. Besides, the
                            definitions that have been given to spirit by those claiming to be teachers in all spiritual
                            things have not tended to enlighten these matter-of-fact minds. The Infinite Being himself
                            has been metapJiysicised into something impalpable, intangible; so that the question might
                            very properly be asked: " Canst thou, by searching, find out God ? " It is not unreasonable
                            that the scientist, if he cannot " find out the Almighty to perfection," yet should be able
                            to lay hold of something substantial, something that shall satisfy his investigating,
                            reasoning mind that there is a " Potency in nature," a Reality capable not only of forming
                            the unnumbered worlds in the universe, but also of sustaining in existence forever each
                            intelligent being found in them. Those who regard themselves as set for the defense of
                            spiritual truth do not help such by getting angry and calling hard names. Denunciation never
                            converted an ignorant errorist; certainly it never can convert thinking, investigating
                            minds. Religion, so called, has many sins to acknowledge at the confessional of truth — the
                            greatest absurdities in doctrine, as well as the profoundest mistakes in the attempt to
                            convert man to what is deemed the truth of God. Spiritualism, to show herself
                            heavendescended, must be clothed in garments of light; must be able to convince the judgment
                            of candid, thoughtful minds, and confound the errors of unreasoning ones. She must be able
                            to prove herself something more substantial than the gods which the old poets have invoked,
                            or the shades which they have evoked. If not clothed with the materiality of flesh and
                            bones, to be seen and heard, felt and handled by the corporeal senses, yet to be made
                            manifest unmistakably to the inward consciousness as though she possessed these external
                            attributes. There are thousands calling themselves spiritualists who claim to have as clear
                            and definite knowledge of certain things pertaining to another state of existence as they do
                            of those pertaining to the earth. But there are thousands of others, of thinking, cultivated
                            minds, who have not this knowledge, and who deny that there can be such. This being the
                            case, it does no possible good for the former class to berate the latter as ignorant or
                            selfconceited ; nor for the latter to upbraid the former as superstitious, easily imposed
                            upon, and willing to be duped. Candor is becoming to both sides, which both have lacked too
                            long. The earnest spiritualist desires to impart the knowledge which seems to him of so much
                            importance to those who have it not, and it seems to him that it should produce as powerful
                            an effect in other minds as in his own. But the facts do not accord with the seeming. There
                            is nothing, then, for him to do but to wait with patience for the day of triumph ; to seek
                            for new displays of truth, as well as new methods of imparting what is demonstrated truth to
                            his own mind. Patience will work for herself a perfect work, even among the ignorant, the
                            indifferent, the indolent, the scientist, the philosopher, as well as the fearful and
                            despairing. " Hope, the charmer, lingers still behind," to encourage all, and point all to
                            the opening portal of endless life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Uses and abuses of adversity" TEIform="index"/>USES AND ABUSES OF ADVERSITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">To make man — both moieties — the first grand essential is a mother — a mother who knows her
                            rights and maintains them. The next essential is a father, as law-abiding, in sexual
                            intercourse, as animals in general. Prosperity is good — we like it. But luxury and idleness
                            never made a man. Adversity is just the thing we do not want — but what could we be without
                            it? Its uses are to make us strong in self-reliance, to sanctify our powers and consecrate
                            them to the common good. adversity's abuses. Strong cider, tobacco and other things to
                            stultify — stupify the sensibilities. Other undignified acts might be named — but we will
                            let somebody else do that. To presume that our audience can never know any thing only just
                            what we tell them, is rather presuming. Long sermons, like long newspaper articles, are
                            behind the age.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music, no. 12" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC-NO. 12</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAS. G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Concluding Remarks. — To clear up the subject of congregational singing, which was touched
                            upon in the preceding number, it is here asserted that all persons, old and young, with much
                            or little talent for singing, who expect to take part in church, should be constant
                            attendants at singing schools and other gatherings for musical rehearsals; and furthermore,
                            they should not only take part upon all pieces designed to be used in church, but should lay
                            aside their own personal judgments and notions of singing, and conform strictly to the
                            directions of a leader. This being the case, other things being equal, there is much to
                            warrant reasonable success in congregational effect. Not that perfect development of harmony
                            would become apparent, for this would be utterly impossible, but that sufficient results
                            might be reached to insure safety to the true choir, and reflect no material dishonor upon
                            music as an art. Although the objection is often raised that God requires the best at our
                            hands and hearts, it should not be inferred that those particularly favored with the
                            greatest music talents are the only ones to address the great and good Creator through the
                            medium of song. Indeed, were this the case, it would be strikingly characteristic of the
                            Calvinistic principle of election engrafted into the beautiful and divine art of music —
                            that some were elected to sing, while others were doomed to perpetual exclusion, however
                            desirous they might be to possess the talent. From a phrenological stand-point the writer
                            views the illustrations of the various faculties of our mental organization, but fails to
                            find in a single instance a neglect, on the part of the divine Architect, to insert the
                            faculty of music. Still, the observation is made that, in certain mental organisms, such and
                            such faculties are small, but not entirely wanting; hence there arises a chance for more or
                            less culture and development of each and every faculty of our mental being, music not
                            excepted. Under these considerations the writer fosters the belief that in any congregation,
                            in almost any parish or church, there may be found, oat of every twenty individuals,
                            nineteen that are sufficiently talented to become, by close application to music culture,
                            good and reliable singers, capable of forming- a choir that, as a whole, though termed
                            congregational, would better by far redound to the beauty and glory of church worship than
                            would a select choir, set apart exclusively for singing, whiTe a majority are sitting by
                            with closed mouths, accrediting great honor to the talented few, and seemingly unmindful of
                            the Divine Presence they had assembled to worship. From these remarks I would not be
                            understood to infer that no select choir should ever be heard or known to exist in a church,
                            as evidently there are some church pieces, or portions thereof, so characterized as to be
                            rendered far more impressive when performed by a few voices only, than they otherwise could
                            be; but such renderings should be considered mere exceptions to the general rule. The fact
                            should ever be apparent that church worship should be conducted on a principle, the basis of
                            which should be sufficiently extensive to meet the demands of a religious community as a
                            whole. By way of appendage to this series of articles I would add that the various points
                            taken up, as bearing upon the subject of music, are drawn mostly from scientific facts.
                            Portions drawn from the stand-point of personal experience only may not all bear the test of
                            superior reasoning; hence such parts are only fit to be left in the dark abyss of
                            forgetfulness, while the author professes progress, ever onward and upward, grasping the
                            true, and leaving the false, actuated and inspired by the beautiful motto, "Ever pursuing,
                            EVER STRIVING TO BECOME." Thus animated with the love for higher development in the lovely
                            art of music, the explorations in this great field will become deeper and broader as the
                            mind continues its reSH A-KEIR. <pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE 91 searches after truths which,
                            though now seem lost in hidden mystery, will yet be revealed in as perfect light as those
                            numbered in the revelations of the past. Trusting and sincerely believing the "wheels of
                            progress" will be ever kept in motion, bringing new and increasing light into every
                            department of useful knowledge, I close, for a season, my essays upon music, and bid my
                            readers an affectionate farewell.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer for Zion" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER FOR ZION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>OTIS SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p">Pour out thy spirit upon needy Zion, Sustain all thy children while humbly they plead— Help,
                            Lord, O help them, and send faithful laborers To work in thy vineyard, for great is the
                            need! O, God of the harvest, replenish thy garners With choicest of fruit from the mountain
                            and plain— And fill every court in thy holy dominion, Like rich golden fruit on a
                            well-clustered vine. Hear, we beseech Thee, Oh heavenly Father, The remnant who've passed
                            through the flood and the fire! O God, Thee they serve, and they bow to no other, Thy word
                            and Thy will is their whole soul's desire. Protect and preserve Thou, the holiest treasures
                            With which in Thy temple Thy wisdom appeal's— The Ark and Shekina, that royal insignia— A
                            witness perpetual, Jehovah is herb! God of the widow and fatherless orphan, Whose vigilant
                            eye views each sparrow that falls, Thy mercy and favor to Zion now lengthen; Thou art her
                            deliverer and her all hi all! Yea, here for salvation Thy name Thou hast raised, For
                            kingdoms and people, afar off and near, The Laws of Mount Zion on tablets engraved, To which
                            every nation on earth must give ear. Now, even now, Lord, diffuse without measure, The power
                            of salvation and eternal life! Renew the baptism of spirit and fire, That Zion may win in
                            this terrible strife? O send forth Thy heralds to every nation, And call, that the
                            slumbering to judgment appear— To enter through Jordan's rich stream for salvation, O God,
                            unto Zion, in strength do draw near! Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clouds" TEIform="index"/>CLOUDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MABTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">The sun in its splendor rose early at dawn, Revealing the beauties of meadow and lawn ; For
                            every green spear with a crystal drop gleamed, As on them the golden shafts silently beamed;
                            Yet, if as by magic, in earliest day, The glisten of diamonds had vanished away. The
                            brooklet came laughing from out of the wood, As if 'twere intent on a mission of good ; So
                            full were its waves as it dashed on its way, It sent up, like incense, a beautiful spray,
                            But ere the sun reached its meridian course, Its volume and motion had lost half their
                            force. The lake in its beauty (so placid and still) Lay down at the foot of a steep, wooded
                            hill, Yet sunbeams were glancing just over the crest, And lighting the ripples that danced
                            on its breast, Exerting the while a mysterious sway, Which seemed to be drawing its moisture
                            away. The river rolled on 'neath the sun's vivid rays, Kefiecting a glory too bright for the
                            gaze ; But soon was seen rising a mist, light as air, And where was it going? O! who shall
                            tell where ? Up, up it went floating, and sped o'er the hill, An omen in future of good, or
                            of ill. The ocean swelled grandly, its billows rose high, As if any power Its strength could
                            defy; Yet subtle the force, and electric the glow, That meets in its majesty wide ocean's
                            flow. The air is just tensioned with heat, to draw up And take a good drink from old
                            Neptune's great cup; Away goes the nectar ambrosial and free, Alike from the fountain, the
                            ocean and sea. The atmosphere gathered, but could not retain The volatile vapors it held for
                            its gain ; So upward they rose In e.thereal space, Where cloudland so changeful in fancy we
                            trace, The sprights of the wind, bound for mischief the worst, The gathering mists in
                            confusion dispersed. Soon the face of the sky from the east to the west. Was covered with
                            waves like a white foaming crest, But, fitful as fancy, and fleet as a thought, Behold, what
                            a change in the aspect is wrought! Like a fleece of white wool, just clipped from the ewe,
                            The clouds are spread over the deep vault of blue ; Now gathering closer, they tower on
                            high, And rest in their grandeur against the clear sky. There's reared in the distance a
                            castle so bright, It gleams as if raised by the spirits of light; Too soon it has vanished,
                            and mountains of snow Are rising, then melting beneath the sun's glow. There are chariots of
                            fire, and steeds of the wind, Which leave in a moment no traces behind; Then argosies,
                            freighted for some distant shore, Fold up their white sails and are heard of no more. There
                            the Elephant's seen, and the White Polar Bear, The Seal and the Walrus float out on the air;
                            And thousands of wonders which meet the trained eye, No conjuror casts in his magical die.
                            With signs of the weather this realm is replete — They are heard from the lips of each
                            friend that you meet; " There are bars in the South," or " the morning sky's red, Which will
                            surely bring rain on the traveler's head." Well founded this maxim, "If rain goes up
                            hopPi"g, Then rain will assuredly come down a dropping." The farmer will tell you when
                            cloudless the sky It often betokens a storm brooding nigh ; With keen observation to science
                            allied, The action of winds and of clouds are descried. Savans have explored this most
                            wonderful field, And facts that are noteworthy carefully yield; Seven species of clouds are
                            described with their names. The result of the knowledge one scientist claims. First Cirrus,
                            the cloud formed the highest in air, Resembles the tresses of light waving hair, A change of
                            the weather it seems to imply, Rain, if it increases ; wind, if it keeps high ; Fine weather
                            if fringes descend from below, And melt away quickly beneath the sun's glow. Next, Cumulus
                            forms in a low atmosphere, In dense, convex masses 'twill often appear; By the wise it is
                            called the fair cloud of the day, Beginning when morning shines over our way. Its maximum
                            reaches when Sol's at its height, Then melts when approached by the shadows of night. Now
                            Stratus will nearest earth's surface be found, In flat sheets extended above and around, It
                            forms when the sun has just passed from the sight, And is termed, by its coming, the cloud
                            of the night. Its mists may be seen o'er the river and plain, But does not betoken the com
                            ng of rain. The days that oft follow this cloud of the night, Are always remarkably tranquil
                            and bright. Cirro Cumulus forms in the atmosphere high, Consisting of groups of small
                            cumuli; At different heights in flat strata 'tis seen Reflecting the brightness of days
                            sunny sheen. In some latitudes, in the winter 'tis rare, But in summer betokens the days
                            that are fair. 'Tis the beautiful cloud, some call "mackerel sky," With its tints at the
                            sunset no painter can vie. Cirro Stratus spreads out like a layer of sheets, Which is apt to
                            descend if disturbance it meets; When high o'er the zenith, a light, gauzy shroud, But near
                            the horizon it forms a dense cloud ; 'Tis changeable ever, though calm seems the air, And
                            indicates rain, though the weather be fair. When low in the sky, it is seen to descend, The
                            rain will soon follow its course to attend. If the weather is cold a "Scotch mist" it will
                            form, A " hat " on the mountain peaks if it is warm : At first it appears like a mere hazy
                            light, Which envelops the moon in a circle at night. Atmospheric disturbance it seems to
                            foretell, Yet on all its changes we'll no longer dwell. Cumub) Stratus is small cumuli,
                            United by itratus like clouds, dense and high, Called indefinite clouds, whicn to earth
                            ne'er descend, Unless in their changing with others they blend. If they rise in huge masses
                            of singular form, Precursors they prove of a dark thunder storm. If Cirrus appears at the
                            time, high in air, The weather which follows will not then be fair; But if Cumulus Cirrus
                            above shall appear. The rain will soon pass, and the weather be clear. The cloud we call
                            Nimbus, prepared as it lowers. Descends to the earth, with its copious showers. O cloudland!
                            so varied, so old, yet so new! Through fancy and science thy glories we view ; And while
                            we're discerning the signs of thy face, The skill of an infinite artist we trace. Ever
                            learning sweet lessons of wisdom and love, From scenes all around us, below and above. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Community principles as a part of Christianity" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNITY PRINCIPLES AS A
                            PART OF CHRISTIANITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chase, Nelson" TEIform="persName"/>NELSON CHASE</byline><p TEIform="p">" Then Peter began to say unto him, Lo, we have left all and have followed thee." " And Jesus
                            answered and said, Verily I say unto you, there is no man that hath left house, or brethren,
                            or sisters, or father, or mother, or wife, or children, or lands, for my sake, and the
                            gospel's," " But he shall receive ^ hundredfold now in this time, houses, and brethren, and
                            sisters, and mothers, and children, and lands, with persecutions ; and in the world to come
                            eternal life." Mm* 10: 28, 29,30. Fkom these sayings of Jesus, we begin to date a foundation
                            for community life in the church of Christ. The principle was carried out in the life and
                            character of the little band of twelve who followed Jesus when upon earth, and the principle
                            was confirmed and established by the church at Jerusalem at the day of Pentecost, when "
                            they were all filled with the Holy Ghost," and " were of one heart and of one soul; neither
                            said any of them that aught of the things which he possessed was his own; but they had all
                            things common." Acts 4: 31,33. Hence we are to understand, a religious community is a
                            community of interests, embracing a people whose possessions are the property of all ; all
                            having a voice in its management, subordinate to a head. A man owning a farm has the right
                            of its direction. It is under the control of his family, subject to the head of said family.
                            It is under his control to stock and improve it; otherwise, it is an object neither of
                            attraction nor interest. In communistic societies the spirit is not changed, the principle
                            undergoes no revolution, the effect is consequently the same. If community means simply a
                            people drawn together as a convenience for economy in the business acts of life, having no
                            religious principle interwoven, the interests of the body being held by a privileged class,
                            whose duties required their talents and labors for the support and protection of the body
                            which had no voice in the institution, no right to ask, why do ye so, it is no other than
                            master and slave, bond and free, producing caste, high and low, rich and poor. The
                            government differs widely from a theocracy, remote from Christian authority. It is
                            oligarchy. Community, as a part of Christianity, is designed to take hold of the selfishness
                            of man; otherwise, self remains unsubdued. Individuals personally assuming independent
                            control of community interest cannot be in the work of governing or destroying in themselves
                            a selfish animal nature; on the contrary, they foster and nourish it, causing SHAKER. <pb n="92" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. greater development and growth, thus choking and destroying
                            even the Christian virtues; not only preventing themselves, but other pure-minded souls who
                            would not be selfish, from the enjoyment of that to which they are justly entitled. As one
                            interested in the unfoldment of greater truths, in an open door for the increase of
                            righteousness, I ask for myself, for my brethren, yea, for all men, that we cultivate
                            without reserve and with greater zeal, more love, more union, the basis of all that is great
                            and good. Let us combine with the principle of community of interest, that of the true
                            virgin character, each one working unselfishly for the encouragement, the strength, the
                            comfort and good of every other one, laboring in our souls to become purified in spirit;
                            first, condemning wrong in ourselves, ignoring slander and backbiting, laying aside every
                            weight and the sin that doth so easily beset us, and putting away from our hearts all that
                            tends to produce hard feelings. Here is our protection, our justification. Here we find
                            peace flowing like a river, bringing to our souls life and joy eternal. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Awakening" TEIform="index"/>AWAKENING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cornell, Jane A." TEIform="persName"/>JANE A. CORNELL</byline><p TEIform="p">See o'er the hill-tops the sunlight is breaking; Adown in the valley its golden beams fall;
                            Souls from the darkness of sin are awakening, Answering the voice of the Christ-Spirit's
                            call. All through the night, with most gentle entreating, He hath called unto sinners, in
                            mercy and love; All the promises sure, of the Father repeating, Hath pointed to mansions,
                            preparing above. Awake now O Zion! and shake off thy slumber! For lo! there is wafting from
                            every shore, The great witness-clouds, which no man can number; And soon drooping low, it
                            shall rest at thy door. Arouse, then, 0 Zion! fling open thy portal! And put on thy garments
                            of beauty and might, For see now approaching are spirits immortal, Who humbly are seeking
                            for guidance and light. They are weary and famished, for long have they wandered In paths of
                            transgressions and highways of sin; In riotous living their substance have squandered; O
                            stretch forth thy hand now and gather them in. For Oh! they are coming, repentant and
                            chastened, A sense of their loss doth each bosom oppress; And to thee, as unto a mother,
                            they've hastened, To pour out their sorrows—their sins to confess. Prepare them a greeting,
                            receive them with gladness, O spread them a banquet, kind welcome accord; Speak comforting
                            words, consoling their sadness; They come not unbidden, they are guests of thy Lord.
                            Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Characteristic prayer" TEIform="index"/>A CHARACTERISTIC PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">O, Divine presence, Thou whom we call God— Oh, angels and ministering spirits! Oh, common
                            instincts of a divine humanity, grant to regenerate badly generated Spiritualists ; grant to
                            revivify and quicken their religious faculties; to expand their selfish natures, and warm
                            their cold stoical hearts with heavenly love, and especially grant, Oh, Immortalized
                            Intelligences, to so touch and inspire the souls of all the stingy, niggardly, pennypinching
                            Spiritualists of the land, that they shall cheerfully open their pocket-books and liberally
                            support such genuine mediums, such trance and inspirational speakers as the heavenly hosts
                            have raised up to demonstrate future existence, to heal the sick, comfort the afflicted, and
                            wipe away the tears from the mourners' eyes. Amen. Thus, our dear, noble, self-sacrificing
                            and ever benevolent Brother, J. M. Peebles, prays for Spiritualists. Are there not some
                            other persuasions that would be benefited by employing his generous spirit to pray for them
                            ? Let us reflect.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly — 60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHIUST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Would you" TEIform="index"/>WOULD YOU</head><p TEIform="p">Become a Shaker ? Yield not to the impulse without fully considering the demands of Shakerism
                            upon you, and its immediate and ultimate consequences. 1. Settle all just debts; reconcile
                            by compromise, or to the utmost, creditors who have trusted you. 2. Are you sin-sick ? Not
                            only desirous of no more sinful indulgences, but so heartily disgusted with sins of the
                            past, that a clean, clear confession of the same would be of all things most desirable, and
                            which would prompt a repentance, that means no more returning to the sins confessed ? then
                            come and be a Shaker. 3. Are you able to be " like unto a little child," subject and willing
                            to be taught; interposing nothing that would prompt egotism or personal superiority, nor
                            aggrandizement ? You are ripe for the harvest interpreted by Shakerism ; "Ask and ye shall
                            receive." 4. Are you ready to become a brother or sister the rest of life, as a Christian
                            substitute for husband and wife ? Does the celibate condition of those anointed as Christ
                            strike you as superior to the best, even perfected, system of the earthly, sexual relation?
                            5. Are you willing, anxious, to enter with your wealth and poverty; your physical strength
                            and weakness; your talents and your deficiencies ; with your worldly ambitions and spiritual
                            aspirations and convictions, into the furnace of trial, probation, approval and unreserved
                            consecration? The "Door" is opened to your knock. 6. Do you love peace better than unholy
                            strife? Would you give kind words for harsh ones ? Could you resist the temptations to
                            resentment ? Would you willingly part with unphysiological conditions and unspiritual
                            desires, the relinquishment of which would cause you to shun the policy of the hypocrite and
                            accept the principles of the peacemaker ? Do you look for conditions not to be found in a
                            worldly life, even in its best estate? "Seek, and you will find" these where true Shakerism
                            is illustrated. 7. Count the cost: No more of the worldly, fleshly, " old creation." A new
                            life is expected ; but so clean, clear, simple and without ostentation, that a child can
                            comprehend and accept it. To leave the elements of the world, however good; and to accept
                            the "living-sacrifice" practices in life that will prove a baptism of the new man and woman
                            — Christ! Would you be a Christian ? Compare the Christianity of Jesus with the above
                            presentation of Shakerism, and then, Would You?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Distinction of shaker communism" TEIform="index"/>DISTINCTION OF SHAKER COMMUNISM</head><p TEIform="p">Our communism with certain classes of people unjustly bears the reputation of being bigoted,
                            narrow, and too recluse. From these we are receiving constant invitations to enter into
                            deeper sympathies with other organizations, multiplying so rapidly in this age of the world.
                            Our communism means more than an earthly competence and home. It attaches itself with grave
                            importance to those superior elements which determine that we are ultra religionists. There
                            is a salvation derived from temporal cooperation ; but this is only a minor salvation,
                            compared with the grand feature of salvation from the great paucity and bondage of our sins.
                            Distinction from organizations which live on the animal plane of life is a positive
                            necessity of our existence as such religious people. We cannot in conscience, having the
                            perpetuity of our celibate principle in mind, join hands with those who are seeking sensual
                            delights by an opposing conduct. With us, the struggle to maintain for the spirit the
                            mastery over the flesh, is an all important one. For this have we separated ourselves
                            physically from worldly associations and policies ; for this, only, have we entered into
                            compacts with each other in our various gospel homes — the better to triumph over the "lusts
                            of the flesh, of the eye and the pride of life." Active sympathy, even to a limited extent)
                            with communists engaged in the continuance and exercise of unchristian practices, however
                            good such practices may be, judged from a worldly standard, would be to us a return to what
                            we have vomited — the dabbling again with uncleanliness from which we have been washed and
                            resurrected. Said our great leader in substance: " I am not of the world, so be ye not so
                            conformed." To us, that great light is a directing testimony in present and future life, and
                            unmistakably says : Be virgins ; love one another, with that superior love which seeks the
                            maintenance of virginity in all unselfishness. Be peaceable — an outgrowing condition from
                            genuine virginity. Keep unspotted from all worldliness. Occupying, as probationers, a middle
                            ground between the heavens and the earth — attempting with some success, a heaven on earth —
                            we are casting from us as fast as possible, the barnacles that prevent a living progress
                            toward the community spirit of advanced conditions. We look hence to the spirit land : large
                            homes for kindred spirits — made so by similarity of life hereafter. Experiencing the larger
                            spirituality from an entire absence of the practice or passions of the reproductive
                            elements; from .whatever engenders worldly strive ; from selfish relations of single or
                            marital promotion, and from the hampering influences of political combinations and worldly
                            copartnerships, we find it an utmost necessity that we maintain a peculiar, superior and
                            unflinching distinction from those whose theology teaches, and whose sense of religion
                            permits, indulgences not born of the spirit of Christ. The testimony of Christ is not
                            aggressive, per se. As an illustration : Jesus lived as a Christian should; in all purity;
                            in communism; in peace; in distinction from the world. His injunction was, " Go into all the
                            world and preach these," with the ever winsome, inviting spirit of the Christ: "Let
                            whosoever will, let them come." No compulsion ; no prevention. " Herein is the Christian's
                            comfort ; if you desire its fruits, sow no more to the flesh, but to the Spirit." We rejoice
                            at every effort communism makes for the alleviation of humanity, and it has made many
                            already ; but we, seeking the communism of the heavens, cannot commingle with the merely
                            earthly, communistic elements, now becoming so popular. Our com92 <pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/>
                            munism admits of but one class. Our bishops, our elders, trustees, deacons, rank and file,
                            are required by our community contract to live similarly and after the purity and
                            unselfishness of the heavenly church. As oil and water will not of themselves blend ; as
                            flesh and spirit will not thus agree ; so we, determined to maintain our distinction for the
                            sake of superior spirituality, give no consent, nor will admit of any element that would
                            inaugurate a harmony, that will cause our clean garments to trail at all in worldly
                        lusts.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and its mission" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER AND ITS MISSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are in receipt of frequent evidences that The Shaker, true to the purposes for which it
                            originated, is an educator in the societies of believers, and particularly a comforter to
                            those sin-sick souls " not of our fold as yet." From brethren and sisters throughout our
                            Zion home consoling evidences of appreciation greet our ears and encourage our souls. But
                            unmistakable proofs come out occasionally that The Shaker, true to its mission, is being
                            found by " the lost sheep " of spiritual Israel, and by such is hallowed as the morning
                            star, at least, of a new, spiritual day. One lady in New York accidentally (apparently) was
                            handed a copy. Becoming more and more interested, she determined to present a copy of volume
                            VI to each of her near relatives (quite a number), because " I know of nothing better that I
                            can offer them as reading," etc., and adding a few of the kindest words of appreciation to
                            the publisher, determined to be a life subscriber. Another lady in Cambridgeport, Mass.,
                            perchance found a copy of the Octobp:r number. In a letter to the editor she says: " It is
                            only a year since I first knew of the existence of such societies as the Shakers. I tried to
                            obtain more information of them, but failed, until last week I obtained the October number
                            of your paper. After carefully perusing its pages, I feel strongly impressed to become one
                            of your number, for I now am assured I am directed by God to do so. 1 find, from the reading
                            of your paper, what the principles of Shakerism are, and that I have been led to adopt these
                            in my past experience, and am striving to live them entire. True, these views have so
                            separated me from the world and from m y own family, that I stand alone; but I am determined
                            to live this life, that to me is right. I am twenty-six years old, unmarried," etc. And
                            there are many such, only needing the animating torch of The Shaker to lighten and quicken
                            their perceptions, conceptions and convictions, thus making them workers for the cause, and
                            living testimonies of an exceedingly righteous life in the midst of their fellows. God has
                            not forsaken the world. Go, little Shaker! "In the morning sow thy seed, and at evening
                            withhold not thy hand." The heartfelt necessity of such a medium as The Shaker for a
                            missionary, and the constantly recurring evidences that it is dutifully at work, are alone
                            sufficient inducements to " toil on, struggle on," with none other ' recompense of reward."
                            If this world is ever ransomed and regenerated by the resurrection of individuals to
                            Christ's life, it must be " bought with a price," and those having the gospel must pap it,
                            and work for it. We personally care exceedingly what course others may take, and that those
                            who would be good men and women everywhere might lend us their active sympathies, and share
                            with us the burdens of missionary gospel duty, which, however unremunerative financially,
                            are rich with satisfaction and justification. Go and come, little Shaker, and God speed thy
                            efforts! </p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our prospectus" TEIform="index"/>OUR PROSPECTUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With this issue, Vol. 6 of The Shaker closes. Vol. 7 will begin with an enlarged form, and
                            with a purpose of increased interest and usefulness. Its patrons have decided that it must
                            not rest on laurels won,— that the present is not the time to discontinue efforts put forth
                            for the regeneration of the race. There are multitudes who would seriously miss The Shaker,
                            should it" rest from its labors ;" while with not a few, such discontinuance would prove an
                            unequaled catastrophe. We have large reason to be very grateful to its many friends, for
                            their disinterested efforts in its behalf; and for their words and deeds of cheer to both
                            editor and publisher. We are confident that we will make Vol. 7 even more acceptable than
                            its predecessor. New themes of exceeding interests will be introduced. A department of "
                            Social Life Sketches " of the Shakers will be added. The department of Music will be
                            continued with much improvement. A continued notice will appear in every number answering
                            the question: " WnAT SHALL I DO TO BECOME A SHAKER ? " We ask for the continued company of
                            our present subscribers; earnestly hoping they will aid us in circulating truth, by
                            assisting in the enlargement of our subscription lists. All may rest assured that no pains
                            will be spared to have every department of The Shaker an advance upon the same of 1876, and
                            that no departure from its main purpose — the illustration of radical, Christian truths —
                            will for a moment be considered.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">Unless individuals are more than casual observers, the subject of Communism will appear in
                            statu quo, or on the wane. But we have assurances — moral, social, political and, more than
                            all, spritual — evidences of our senses — that Communism never ranked so highly, nor was
                            ever more ardently desired, numerically speaking, than to-day. The majority, however, embody
                            in their desired resolutions of organization, so many elements of human, perverted
                            selfishness, that if organizations are born, it is too frequently to die after an ephemeral
                            existence. Nevertheless, good will come of all these. Those who would be Shakers — members
                            of a " new creation "—" children resurrected " above the " world," are invited to read "
                            Would You ? " in another column. Therein is embraced, in epitome, the whole cross of Christ,
                            according to our understanding of the gospel introduced by Jesus, the Anointed. To bread and
                            butter thieves — those whose lives embrace but the seven constituents — five loaves and two
                            fishes — such paragraphs will prove a bitter pill and be refused. But to the sincere seeker
                            after the Christ life — to the weary and heavily laden with sin, "Would You" will prove the
                            "pearl of great price," and be accepted as a rest, worth more than worlds without it. The
                            grandest phase of human development presented to our humanity is the evolution from the
                            sensual to the spiritual; from selfish to unselfish benevolence ; from Adamic followers to
                            Christ disciples; from men and women, subject to anti-christian impulses that make and
                            people the earth, to the conditions of resurrection, representing the Christ in Jesus, and
                            by the possession of which, " heaven on earth," is already begun. To be a Christian means
                            more than mere profession. It means a " new creature" with whom " old things are done away,"
                            and the evolution into practices not sustained by fleshly indulgences. Who are Christians in
                            deed? Not until mankind love their neighbors better than themselves, will the pendulum of
                            progress impress the mind with true Christian demands. While " doing unto others as we would
                            they should do unto us " is very golden, the entire crucifixion of selfishness in behalf of
                            the brotherhood can set no bounds; and this can alone rouse the soul from the mere letter of
                            the rule to the most wholesome, heavenly consecration. Before the crooked stick of perverted
                            humanity can be made as straight as the golden rule, it must be bent and retained in excess
                            of what that rule demands.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flying visit" TEIform="index"/>A FLYING VISIT</head><p TEIform="p">Shakers, N. Y., November 12, 1876. My dear W. —You are aware that important business of The
                            Shaker called me to the city of Concord, N. H.; and being only twelve miles from the
                            beautiful Shaker Village at Canterbury, I made this my home for a couple of days. I am very
                            happy to state to you that an almost perfect system of finances and spirituality makes this
                            Society a model of neatness, comfort and heaven on earth. Here lives the living publisher of
                            The Shaker. Everywhere improvement was visible. Paint has been spread by unsparing hands.
                            Repairs had made things appeal- as good as new. New buildings for threshing and the storage
                            of ice were in progress of erection. The people here are a noble colony. Nearly one hundred
                            persons in the Center Family, and the majority between sixteen and forty years of age ! It
                            would be difficult to imagine a scene, where loving kindness, living industry and devotion
                            to good works were more prominent than here. Order reigns supremely. I attended public
                            meeting on Sunday, and addressed the assemblage in my unqualified manner. The accompanying
                            testimonies delivered by word and song were many, and spiritually effective in the extreme.
                            I learned of an interesting feature at this place. Every " turn " of the sisterhood in the
                            kitchen department, began and completed a literary periodical for the month they were so
                            engaged. Casually looking over the "Cook's Manual," I found it contained some very good
                            recipes, excellent articles on a variety of sub" jects applicable to the department in which
                            the editor and contributors were engaged, such as "Cleanliness, Economy, Patience," etc. I
                            found under the head of "Accidents," the number of dishes that had been broken, etc. In its
                            numerical department I found the number of loaves of bread, pies, cakes and biscuits that
                            had been made during the month, and a funny paragraph under " Obituary," informed all that
                            an unusually "large rat had departed! " This periodical is read to the family every month. I
                            thought it an excellent feature of the kitchen. The singing of this Society is, perhaps,
                            unequaled; and the greatest pains are being taken to give thoroughness in musical education,
                            both vocally and instrumentally. Some have thought, my dear W., that Shaker Societies must
                            rely on adult converts from the outer world for their maintenance, and have carelessly
                            referred to the uncertainty of youth among us. But while all youth must be tried and proved,
                            and thus, many have chosen the inferior life of the flesh, rejecting the superior
                            spirituality of a Shaker life, it must be remembered, how very large the majority is among
                            us, of those whose lives have never been stained by worldly grossness ! You and I, and many
                            scores we know full well, are among this number. I have not only no objections to the conTHE
                            SHA.KER. 93 <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 94: T H 111 S H A. K E R . version of adult converts to our
                            faith, but ardently desire the large accomplishment thereof; yet the youth of our Zion vie
                            with such " equal to the best steel." I dropped in on Shirley Village, and was surprised at
                            the vivacity and youthfulness of its many, beautiful Believers. The large number to whom
                            good Eldress Sophronia presented me, encouraged me to make you happier by the narration; and
                            the earnest of love manifested for these dear young people by their seniors, seemed to say:
                            "Shirley depends on the faithfulness and dutifulness of her young people!'1'' How pretty the
                            village! How exceedingly kind her people! "I was a stranger, and they took me in," almost
                            "killingone with kindness! " Howells might well have said, after all, "The half of Shirley's
                            virtues cannot be told." I stopped at Harvard; and before I could beg their hospitality, I
                            was assured the whole village was mine while I remained ! I was hungry, tired, homesick; I
                            was fed, rested and made most happily at home by these God-fearing, soulloving Christians.
                            My joy, in sweet repose, at Harvard's expense, was sufficient to induce the belief, that the
                            clean, Shaker bed, is a missionary element too frequently unrecognized. Harvard, perhaps, is
                            unsurpassed in the neatness of its appearance. Passing along the avenue that separates its
                            dooryard, all the buildings appear to be in the most perfect condition, and each seemed to
                            waft a most loving invitation to the sin-sick soul, to accept of it as a haven. The
                            unbounded kindness of this people bespoke that God was here; and I believe with Titcomb,
                            that " God loves these Shakers;" and "admires" them and their surroundings, regardless of
                            Titcomb. Having to wait several hours at Springfield, Mass., I learned I could reach
                            Enfield, Conn., spend two or three hours, and return before my train left for the west.
                            Twenty-eight minutes from Springfield, through a beautiful country, convey you to the
                            nattiest depot of this country, upon which "Shaker Station" is most prettily lettered. This
                            depot is a Shaker production, and is most complete in all its parts. At this depot, was
                            Elder George Wilcox, holding the reins, that guided the horse, so beautifully chestnut, and
                            so brilliant of movement, that we confessed our envy, while we moved at the rate of twelve
                            miles the hour! Truly, we were puzzled to know, whether the horse made the happiness of his
                            driver, or the benevolence of the driver made this horse invaluable. Enfield is building the
                            house or dwelling of Greek-cross figure, and of mammoth proportions! The people need it. In
                            the center family, nearly ninety souls reside; and most of these are under forty years!
                            Count again, on the side of Shaker youth! While every thing else wears the happy look of
                            home, a large, convenient dwelling at the Center, is a most welcome and needed structure.
                            Some thirty men were adding to completion, a building that will contain above its foundation
                            stones, nearly three quarters of a million bricks! And passing, with that discreet, almost
                            angelic Shaker — Elder Thomas Damon — over its capacious apartments, I was led to
                            congratulate the young and old of this branch of our Zion on their soon to be enjoyed
                            mansion; and would give notice to "the weary and heavy laden" that "there is rest for you"
                            at Enfield, Conn., if you will pay the Christian price. Excuse my length of letter, dear W.,
                            but I have flown almost home; I alighted at Hancock, and a fine young man, driving a fine
                            old horse, invited me to ride "as far as he went." In his endeavor to find me out, and my
                            sudden appreciation of taciturnity in preventing the disclosure, we had ascended the
                            mountain, through the beautiful Shaker village of Hancock, when my host then thought of
                            those who awaited his return. I descended the hill to Mt. Lebanon! And now, dear W., let
                            your heart beat in unison with mine at the approach! Beautiful scene! First I meet the
                            South, then the Second, then the Second Order of the Church, then the Church Family itself!
                            All seems complete. The ruins are gone. A mansion replaces the good, old house of yore. The
                            "Ministry's Home " is well named, even if I give it. The people here are in happy mood,
                            ascending scale, and in harmony. I hear sweet songs — I stop for a moment at the door of
                            "Lyceum Hall," and fifty voices are being trained by a Boston "Coliseum" director. We said
                            "lucky, happy youth" — count three times for youth — and passed on to the stately North
                            Here, hospitality multiplied by many numbers, was showered upon your unworthy brother. Here,
                            you will find the presentation of between eighty and a hundred souls, bound heavenward, and
                            but few wanting the necessary "wedding dress." Here preside Elder F. W. Evans and Eldress
                            Antoinette Doolittle; and here, songs and happiness flowed to my soul unnumbered and
                            unmeasured. January number will contain a beautiful hymn, "Over the River," from this place.
                            Oh this grand, novitiate order. Of these things I could write ad infinitum, but visit these
                            and you will find a noble people, followers of the noblest of leaders.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Albert, George" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Albert</byline></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Boston minister who makes much of the higher Christian life, boasts that he..." TEIform="index"/>A Boston minister who makes much of the higher Christian life, boasts that he...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A Boston minister who makes much of the higher Christian life, boasts that he has
                                    not voted for ten years. Useful man !</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Investigator" TEIform="index"/>Investigator</bibl></cit> Tins slur is from the Investigator, which is continually illustrating the unchristian
                            worldliness of the clergy ! We say " useful man," and mean it—useful, so far, in repeating
                            the example of unworldliness in the Master, Christ, which the clergy are scarcely anywhere
                            noted for. We only wish that the clergy would progress in such " usefulness," until they
                            would be to their flocks what Jesus was to his — an unworldly communist; a virgin
                            peacemaker! Wherein is the Christian rea eon why Christians should not " FOLLOW " the Lord ?
                            and the especial reason, why Boston ministers, and all others, should not be bright, living
                            examples for the people, in all that pertained to Jesus, the Christ? Ministers, herein is
                            the correct atonement — herein the true resurrection — herein the works, combined with
                            faith, that demonstrate genuine Christianity.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, October 30, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, October 30, 1876</head><p TEIform="p">E. W. Laws, Esteemed Friend : Your letter of 21st inst., at hand. We begin to see eye to
                                eye. Why not ? To my perception, your heart is more elevated than your understanding. It
                                should be so. Feeling has no fellow — not even reason. Your inquiry, " What would become
                                of the world, if all were Shakers," is as pertinent as it is common. " The oranges upon
                                an orange tree do not all ripen together. The natural man and woman are as green fruit
                                on humanity's tree. The first Adam and Eve— father and mother of the generative order —
                                soid. The second Adam and Eve — father and mother of the resurrection order — reap.
                                Jesus was cut off from the earth, by the Christ-spirit, so that none could declare his
                                generation, nor exclaim behold thy son, or daughter. Does it seem incredible that God
                                should raise the dead — resurrect natural man and woman, before they leave the body— a
                                kind of first fruits of the resurrection, as the apostles and early Christians were wont
                                to call themselves ? Shakers are first fruits. The great command was not to man only,
                                but to all the animal kingdom. Goals obey it. The multiply and replenish law is inherent
                                in natural man and woman, as in other animals. It is obeyed with as much fidelity by
                                such as never heard tell of the statute, as by pious bible readers We, upon whom the eud
                                of the generative earth has come, obey the new commandment — " love one another," — not
                                as husband and wife, but as brethren and sisters. When wars shall cease to the ends of
                                the generative earth, by want of food and room to be, it will be manifest that such
                                types of humanity as are able to receive the higher law, should live the virgin life.
                                And thus genuine Christianity will redeem the earth from depopulating crimes, and
                                furnish checks to excessive population. Two orders of people are coming up. To which
                                will you belong ? Of the new earth, generation will be the corner-stone, but a man will
                                not touch a woman save for offspring. In the new heavens, man does not touch women,
                                generatively, at all. It is as natural for a highly developed intellectual man, like
                                Swedenborg, to live a celibate, as for a highly developed spiritual man, like Jesus, to
                                forsake father, mother, brothers, sisters, houses and lands, for Christ's sake. Then his
                                father, mother, brothers, sisters and children are they, who through the Christspirit,
                                have the word of God and obey it. They are a community, like the Angels in Heaven, for
                                they are in Heaven. In love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memphis, Tennessee, October 20, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Memphis, Tenn., October 20,1876</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor At.uert— Moved by the spirit this calm, quiet autumn morning, I feel inclined
                                to have a little pen-and-ink talk with you. Have you tried to listen ? Before me lies
                                the October number of The Shaker. It is a gem — clean, tidy, terse, and spiritually
                                speaking, well put together. One is half inclined to say, that such a sheet might be
                                transplanted to paradise, to be there read by the saints that daily gather in and around
                                the golden gardens of God. Not that it is perfect, for perfection does not pertain to
                                earthly productions — "first the blade, then the ear, and then the full corn in the
                                ear." It may be all summed up in the word, cycles! Surely, The Shaker is a missionary
                                going " into all the world " (or ought to), preaching the gospel of purity, of peace,
                                and a Pentecostal community of interests. Those in the "outer court," reading its pages,
                                often speak In its praise. No truth perishes, no good word is lost out of the universe.
                                The missionary, therefore, is a moral necessity. Jesus recognized this fact. The
                                apostles were missionaries. The martyrs and the saints of bygone ages were missionaries.
                                God's angels to-day are missionaries, ministering to mortals under the influence and
                                inspiration of the Christ-spirit. As yet, there are spiritualists, and possibly Shakers,
                                who are opposed to missionary work. Their actions, if not their words, prove this to be
                                the case. " We have good friends, a good home, a good gospel, let us sit down and enjoy
                                it." Exactly, and so the commonest dog, acting quite as rationally says, " I've got a
                                good thing, a good nice bone, and I propose to sit down and gnaw it!" Such selfishness
                                is to be expected of the dog, but not of man made in the image of God. True greatness is
                                based upon moral goodness. And all great, noble full-orbed souls, having found the
                                "pearl of great price,"—pure and undefined religion — necessarily desire to aid others
                                in finding it. And here comes in the desired principle of self-sacrifice. The
                                Philadelphia conference of spiritualists, denominated the " new departure," has created
                                a tremendous stir in the ranks of spiritualism. Stagnant pools need stirring. And
                                thunder storms purify the air. It is questionable whether the stiff conservative
                                quietness, characterizing headstones in grave-yards, is desirable. The "new movement "
                                meant organization, order, and religious culture, nothing more, but that was too much
                                for most spiritualists. It is quite impossible for them to see the difference between
                                religion and theology, a creed and declaration of principles, the spirit-world and the
                                Christ-heavens of purity and holiness. In brief, multitudes of spiritualists, like some
                                Shakers, stand upon the material and phenomenal plans of life. Delighting to indulge the
                                passion for curiosity, and to witness the prodigies attendant upon physical
                                manifestations, they forget the apostolic injunction, "leave the first principles and go
                                on into perfection." Admitting the truth of the cradle-bed tale, that " a cat jumped
                                over the moon," did that phenomenon squelch the slyness and thieving tendency of the
                                cat? did it remove any treachery from the great cat-king- <pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE S H
                                A. K E R . 95 dom of America, or did it enlighten, morally benefit and spiritually save
                                those who witnessed the wonderful phenomenon ? Jesus spoke in parables, may I not write
                                in them ? It is my sorrowful privilege to meet spiritualists of twenty-five years
                                standing, and some Shakers too, who are half-a-dying to see a spiritual phenomenon — a
                                wonder, a marvel, a sign ! We want "to know," for "knowledge," say they "is the world's
                                saviour." There was never a more villainously untrue sentence spoken than this. Why, the
                                most known, are often the most wicked men. Forgers are fine penmen. Ruloff, the linguist
                                and mathematician, of Ithaca, N. Y., killed his wife and child. Dr. Webster, the scholar
                                and chemist, of Boston, murdered Parkman. To-day there are over forty graduates of
                                colleges in the Penitentiary located at Auburn, N. Y. And yet "knowledge is the world's
                                saviour! " Did a knowledge of the world, a knowledge of the arts and sciences, save
                                these criminals? To announce, is to refute such a position. I would not be understood as
                                being an advocate of ignorance, far from it; but Christ, that is, the Christ principle
                                of love and truth, purity and holiness, leading to a well-ordered life, that is the
                                world's saviour. To this end the apostle taught that in Christ " were hid all the
                                treasures of wisdom and knowledge." The masses are too material. They dwell more upon
                                the shell than the soul of things. Selfishness is the world's curse. Unselfish love, and
                                a willing sacrifice, these lead to the golden gates of the city immortal. Human life is
                                a journey. Jesus baptized his pathway with tears. Our travel may be a cross, our limbs
                                may grow weary, our hearts may become faint, and our souls cry out for angel-helpers, as
                                we near the hill-top —where there are awaiting the faithful, crowns of glory. I mean to
                                close the door tightly against temptation, and run with patience the race set before me.
                                My love to all. Most truly thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M" TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>AGRICULTURAL</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Austrian system of making sour hay is very simple" TEIform="index"/>The Austrian system of making sour hay is very simple
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Austrian system of making sour hay is very simple. It consists in digging
                                        long graves or trenches, four feet in depth by six or eight in breadth. The
                                        newly cut clover and grass is crammed into the trench and tramped tightly down.
                                        When the trench is quite full, so that the contents are a little above the
                                        surface, the whole is then covered up with a foot or fifteen inches of earth,
                                        just as a heap of potatoes is covered. Prof. AVrightson states that the
                                        preservation is complete, and the wetter the fodder when it goes together the
                                        better. No salt is mixed with the grass. He further states that this "sour hay"
                                        affords a capital winter fodder, and when cut out with hay spades it is found to
                                        be rich brown in color and very much liked by stock. Pulp left in the
                                        manufacture of sugar from beet is also preserved in the same way, and, it is
                                        stated, will keep fresh for five or six years. Although Prof. Wrightson does not
                                        say so, still we imagine that green vetches may also be stored by the same
                                        method. When we formerly referred to this matter, we expressed a wish that some
                                        of our readers would make a careful trial of the Austrian mode of preserving
                                        green fodder.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London times. " TEIform="index"/>London Times. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Greasing wagons" TEIform="index"/>Greasing Wagons:</head><p TEIform="p"> A good wagon costs a considerable sum, and it should be taken proper care of, and made
                                to last as long as possible. Few persons understand the importance of thoroughly oiling
                                the axles, etc., of wagons and carriages, and still fewer know which are the most
                                suitable lubricators to use, and the proper way of applying them. A well-made wheel will
                                endure ordinary wear from ten to twenty-five years, if care is taken to use the right
                                amount of the proper lubricator ; but if this matter is not attended to, a wheel will be
                                used up in five or six years. Lard should never be used on a wagon, for it will
                                penetrate the. hub and work itself out around the tenons of the spokes and spoil the
                                wheel. Tallow is the best lubricator for wooden axletrees, and castor oil for iron. When
                                oiling an axletree the spindle should be wiped clean with a cloth wet with spirits of
                                turpentine, and then apply a few drops of castor oil near the shoulder and end. When
                                greasing an axletree, just enough grease should be applied to give a light coating; more
                                does more harm than good, by working out and damaging the hub. Coal ashes have a
                                wonderful effect upon pear trees, especially those growing in light soil. The ashes of
                                last winter were used around the trees in liberal quantities, and those so treated have
                                outgrown any thing in the orchard. Some that were even sickly, and apparently ready to
                                give up their hold on life, have been restored to perfect health by these remedies.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Western farmer says he has cured and preserved his broom-corn crop" TEIform="index"/>A Western farmer says he has cured and preserved his broom-corn crop
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A Western farmer says he has cured and preserved his broom-corn crop in a superior
                                condition, by cutting, and, in six hours afterward, piling it between layers of hay.
                                Stacking in the western country is the rule, and he claims that the hay was both roof
                                and ventilator.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coloring Butter:" TEIform="index"/>Coloring Butter:</head><p TEIform="p"> "We use butter with its natural color only. All coloring is a useless fraud, unless
                                selling color is useful, and we are sorry to know that some otherwise reputable Farm
                                Papers give the fraud a countenance and recommendation.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Horse-sparer" TEIform="index"/>A HORSE-SPARER</head><p TEIform="p">The German War Minister has lately caused experiments to be made with an apparatus devised by
                            M. Fehrmann, and called a Pferdeschoner (literally, horse-sparer). "It is meant to diminish
                            the fatigue of horses in drawing vehicles, as also the chances of rupture of the shaft or
                            traces. It consists of a number of Indiarubber rings separated from each other by iron
                            rundles; the whole is contained in a cylindrical metallic case, and a metallic rod, fixed to
                            the last rundle and traversing the case, is a means of compressing the caoutchouc rings. The
                            length of the system is 0.30 m. (about a foot). Two are required for each horse. They are
                            interposed between the traces and the trace-hooks, thus forming an elastic pad between the
                            horse and the weight to be drawn. In beginning to pull, horses do not make a gradually
                            increasing effort, but generally precipitate themselves on their traces with a sudden shock,
                            wasting their strength and probably doing injury. Fehrmann's apparatus remedies this, by the
                            gradual compression of the caoutchouc rings. The initial effort required of the horse is
                            less, and then it progressively increases." According to the report of the experiments, the
                            effort required under various circumstances is diminished from 18 to 40 per cent by the use
                            of this contrivance, which is certainly a sensible one, and ought to come into general use
                            throughout the world. It is simple and inexpensive withal.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Community ideas" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNITY IDEAS</head><p TEIform="p"> "The family should be a community. To make it truly so, there must be common interest. Alas,
                            for that household where the father's business, the mother's social cares, and the
                            children's sports and pleasures, are not shared by each other! Then it will not be strange
                            if the expenditure is out of proportion to the income, and if the companions and resorts of
                            the children are evil. Happy that home, where the cares and joys are so divided that the
                            former are not oppressive and the latter are multiplied —where the hearts grow closer as the
                            years roll by, so that the separations which must come to every family are only bodily, and
                            therefore temporary! "—Arthur's Mag. A little common sense, digesting the above paragraph,
                            teaches a lesson which individuals, if dullards or determined self-seekers, would not learn
                            until, so far as their lives are concerned, Communities, Shaker Organizations, etc., came to
                            an end. The one-man or one-woman power is a disorganizer, either in families or societies —
                            a combination of families. Whoever has attempted it, has either experienced a success in
                            inevitable disruption of the unselfish determinations of societies, or in his or her own
                            personal degradation. If there exists a curse for any, there remains a very unpleasant
                            reward for one who uses the consecrated labors of others for sinister, selfish — and when it
                            arrives so far—devilish ends!</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK NOTICES</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prof. Huxley in America" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Huxley, Prof." TEIform="persName"/>Huxley</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conflict between Darwinism and spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>The Conflict between
                                Darwinism and Spiritualism</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J.M. Peebles</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Prof. Huxley in America: This is one of The Tribune's extras, and is sold in sheet for 10
                                cts., or in pamphlet 25, etc. It is made up of verbatim reports of that great
                                philosopher's lectures in this country. His three lectures on Evolution are embraced in
                                this Extra. The issuing of these cheap pamphlets may be a money-making operation ; but
                                it is one of the best means of spreading knowledge, and the knowledge much needed by the
                                people that has yet been discovered. We call especial attention to what Huxley calls the
                                " Milton Hypothesis." Address, The Tribune, N. Y. S. R. Wells &amp; Co. have just
                                issued a very unique little volume upon "How to Sing," and by some it will be considered
                                an indispensable companion. It purports to be a dialogue between Preceptor and Pupil,
                                and treats upon a great variety of musical subjects, pertaining particularly to the
                                voice. As our readers are very interested in this subject, they will address the
                                publishers, at 737 Broadway, N. Y., inclosing 50 cents. </p><p TEIform="p">The Conflict between Darwinism and Spiritualism" is a pamphlet written by our friend and
                                brother, J. M. Peebles, and published by Colby &amp; Rich, 9 Montgomery place,
                                Boston, Mass. The telling blows which this brightest light of Spiritualism gives in
                                favor of his favorite theme, is an assurance that if any one can settle this conflict,
                                it is J. M. Peebles. See Adv. P. Garrett &amp; Co., publishers, Philadelphia, are
                                issuing a series of volumes, each of which contains one hundred selections from the
                                choicest literature of our times. A copy, No. 4, we have been favored with. Among the
                                100 pieces we find the almost inimitable poems, "Betsy and I are, Out," and Phebe Cary's
                                "Nearer Home," either of which is worth the price of the book. 75 cents, cloth ; 30
                                cents, paper. Bound volumes of The Shaker, for 1876, can be procured at this office ;
                                sent post-paid, to any address, for $1.10. First come, first served. Order before
                                January, 1877.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science" TEIform="index"/>SCIENTIFIC AND USEFUL.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Repeated experiments have proved..." TEIform="index"/>Repeated experiments have proved...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Repeated experiments have proved that, in schoolrooms lighted by windows on both sides,
                                the children suffer more or less from injured vision, and so important has the subject
                                been considered in Germany, that a law has lately been passed forbidding such windows in
                                schools.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testing the purity of water" TEIform="index"/>TESTING THE PURITY OF WATER</head><p TEIform="p">Some experiments have been recently made with a very simple process, to test organic
                                impurities in water, that are worthy of further trial. The process consists in filling
                                half-pint bottles with the water to be tested, and then adding one gramme (about 15
                                grains) of powdered sugar. In one experiment, boiled distilled water and no air remained
                                unchanged for fifty days. In another, impure water assumed a milky hue in two days, and
                                in three days had a froth on top. These experiments are easily repeated, and they may
                                prove valuable in pointing readily to wholesome and unwholesome water. The milky
                                appearance is the result of the development of certain fungoid growths.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Organization of spiritualists" TEIform="index"/>ORGANIZATION OF SPIRITUALISTS</head><p TEIform="p">The Spirit world, through their medium, Jesus, has spoken plainly and concisely of the
                            principle that shall govern in the "New Order," and spiritual era or dispensation which we
                            find recorded in the 20th chapter, 25th, 2fith and 27th verses of Matthew, and culminated in
                            practical operation with his followers at the Pentecostal period, recorded in the 2d chapter
                            of Acts. To give up all for each others' sakes, as the primitive Christians did, is what is
                            meant "For Christ's sake;" for Christ labored for others' sakes, or for equality for all,
                            which is natural and just, or spiritual. Hence in the "New Dispensation," God, a principle
                            of love and justice will be the only organizer; for we shall have a church without a creed;
                            a kingdom without a king; a state without a governor or a government, and dwell on the earth
                            as the angels or spirits do in heaven, or as the birds in the groves. Thos. Cook in R. P.
                            Journal</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cook, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith in God" TEIform="index"/>FAITH IN GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. 1st. Why thus fainting, why thus doubting? Let thy faith be firm in God,
                            Though the earth is in commotion, Smitten by affliction's rod. 2nd. Let the favored ones of
                            Israel, Zion's inmates one and all, Stand through every threat'ning peril, Faithful to their
                            holy call. 3d. Lo, the harvest season neareth, And the laborers — though few,— Shall be
                            clothed with strength and power, God's great work to carry through. 1st. Many souls, in
                            darkness groping, Soon shall hear the blessed sound 2d. For as saviours on Mount Zion, With
                            their banners wide unfurled 3d. Therefore, let thy faith be steadfast, Let thy light so
                            shine abroad, Of salvation, sweetly rolling Through the heavens all around. Ye must waft the
                            glorious ensign To a sorrow-stricken world. That its rays may guide the erring To the City
                            of our God.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This is not all" TEIform="index"/>THIS IS NOT ALL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">If for this only man were born— To eat, to sleep, to dream and die* With smiles to greet each
                            radiant morn, And frowns to face a lowering sky, To win more store of glittering gold Than
                            he can use, or others spare, Or fame to grace, when life is told, The triumph of some
                            thankless heir; To build, for pleasures by and by, A palace, in dreamland afar, Where clouds
                            ne'er dim the azure sky, Nor darken hope's bright-beaming star; Where dreams ecstatic charm
                            the night, And glowing schemes inspire the day, And darkness only pales to light. To show
                            both dreams and life betray; To love where love makes no return; To hope and no fruition
                            there; All life's rewards at death to spurn; This all, and who'd life's trials dare? This is
                            not all; beyond the spheres Where darkness circumscribes the view, And smiles are only
                            bright with tears, Far brighter worlds life's dreams renew: Beyond earth's bleak,
                            storm-battered shore, Where wrecks of life and hope decay, Suns rise that set not evermore,
                            And stars whose beams fade not away; There is the saint's immortal home, Where more than
                            faith dare hope is given; There earth's tired sons and daughters come, For peace and rest,
                            and find it Heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thousands have admired the sheep-skin mats..." TEIform="index"/>Thousands have admired the sheep-skin mats...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Thousands have admired the sheep-skin mats, so common among The Shakers. They are easily
                            made, none who can purchase a sheep-skin needs be without one of the mats. Wash the entire
                            skin In soap suds until thoroughly clean and white. Dry the same slowly. Pulverize equal
                            parts of alum and salt, and dissolve in warm water. Next saturate fine sawdust with the
                            liquid, spreading the same on the flesh side, to remain there until dry. Remove the sawdust,
                            and as the flesh side dries rub it until soft. The Shakers have proved that the "bobs" or
                            fruit of the common sumach compose the best dye for black, elegant and durable. The "bobs"
                            are brought to a simmering heat for a day or two, in an iron, kettle, when the dye is fit
                            for use ; the iron of the kettle being sufficient to set the color—a rich black.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Joy of incompleteness" TEIform="index"/>JOY OF INCOMPLETENESS</head><p TEIform="p">If all our life was one broad glare Of sunlight, clear, unclouded ; If all our path was
                            smooth and fair, By no soft gloom enshrouded ; If all life's flowers were fully blown
                            Without the sweet unfolding, And happiness were rudely thrown On hands too weak for holding
                            — Should we not miss the twilight hours, The gentle haze and sadness? Should we not long for
                            storms and showers To break the constant sadness ? If none were sick and none were sad, What
                            service could we render? I think if we were always glad We scarcely could be tender ; Did
                            our beloved never need Our patient ministration, . Earth would grow cold, and miss, indeed,
                            Its sweetest consolation. If sorrow never claimed our heart, And every wish was granted,
                            Patience would die and hope depart — Life would be disenchanted. And yet in heaven there is
                            no night, In heaven is no more sorrow! Such unimagined new delight Fresh grace from pain
                            will borrow — As the poor seed that underground Seeks its true light above it; Not knowing
                            what will there be found When sunbeams kiss and love it. So we in darkness upward grow, And
                            look and long for heaven, But cannot picture it below Till more of life be given.
                        Waverly.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor of the shaker:" TEIform="index"/>Editor of the Shaker:</head><p TEIform="p">Please accept our thanks for the publication of article on " Social Impurity," in the
                            September number; also for editorials, uBy WThose Authority," "Tenor of the Churches, etc."
                            Such radical truths are doing good, and are exerting a powerful influence in the world. Go
                            on, my brother.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>T. S. Prescott</byline></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A late writer in the Country Gentleman..." TEIform="index"/>A late writer in the Country Gentleman...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A late writer in the Country Gentleman is enthusiastic over beets for milch cows. Having
                            beets and carrots to feed, his experience caused him to abandon the carrots, they tending to
                            fatten, while the beets produced amost satisfactory lacteal flux. Vegetables should never be
                            cooked in iron pots unless the latter are enameled or otherwise coated internally.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We should be exceedingly slow to conceive of God as having a body..." TEIform="index"/>We should be exceedingly slow to conceive of God as having a body...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We should be exceedingly slow to conceive of God as having a body ; we should beware of any
                            imagination that anchors Him down to a spot, or that makes Him a kind of colossal man. In
                            the earlier stages of our Christian experience it may help us to conceive of God as on a
                            throne, like a king, and having a human figure ; but the prayer and wish of a Christian, and
                            the tendency of Christian growth, should be toward deliverance from such childish
                            conceptions of Deity, and to have an idea like to Stephen's, that God is not body but
                            Spirit, that heaven is not a big house or palace with a monstrous throne and an outlying
                            city of splendor round about it, but that God is the universal and all-pervading fashion,
                            and habit, and energy of it.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Murray, W. H. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. H. Murray</byline></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To Bible readers, the following items may possess some interest..." TEIform="index"/>To Bible readers, the following items may possess some interest...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To Bible readers, the following items may possess some interest: A day's journey was 33 and
                            1-5 miles. A Sabbath day's journey was about an English mile. A cubit is 22 inches, nearly.
                            A hand's-breadth is equal to 3% inches. A flnger'sbreadth is equal to 1 inch. A sheke.1 of
                            silver was about 50 cents. A shekel of gold was $8.09. A talent of silver was $538.32. A
                            talent of gold was $13,809. A piece of silver, or a penny, was 13 cents. A farthing was 3
                            cents. A" mite was less than a quarter of a cent. A gera was 1 cent. An epha, or path,
                            contains 7 gallons and 5 pints. A bin was 1 gallon and 2 pints. A firkin was 7 pints. An
                            omer was 6 pints. A bath was 3 pints. A GOOD and simple furniture polish consists of a
                            little Castile soap scraped into a pint of warm water. Add three tablespoonsful of sweet
                            oil, heat, and apply while hot.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="King, George H." TEIform="index"/>Geo. H. King
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At White Water Village, O., <persName reg="King, Geo. H." TEIform="persName">Geo. H. King</persName>,
                                September 27, 1876, aged 81 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Locke, Florence" TEIform="index"/>Florence Locke
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Conn., <persName reg="Locke, Florence" TEIform="persName">Florence Locke</persName>, October
                                16,1876, aged 21 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perkins, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane PERKINS
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H., <persName reg="Perkins, Jane" TEIform="persName">Jane PERKINS</persName>, October 8,
                                1876, aged 31 years. Consumption.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Riley, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Riley
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At West Pittsfield, Mass., <persName reg="Riley, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy Riley</persName>, October
                                28,1876, aged 77 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thomas, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Thomas
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We copy from the Albany Express of Oct. 18,1876:<persName reg="Thomas, Charlotte" TEIform="persName">Charlotte Thomas</persName> died at Shaker Village, West Gloucester, Me., October
                                11, 1876, aged 80 years and 4 months. She was the daughter of Luther Sampson, one of the
                                founders of the Wesleyan Seminary at Bent's Hill, Redfield, Me. She, with her family,
                                joined the Shaker Church in 1813.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>