<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0901" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18790101" TEIform="date">January 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. IX. No. I. JANUARY, 1879. 60 Cents Per Annum MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editor. Published by
                        the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" '' Go preach the
                        Kingdom of God ! " ADDKESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879.</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p/></div2>
                        --><pb n="1" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="America in shame" TEIform="index"/>AMERICA IN SHAME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p">She was the earth's great refuge land, Designed to be a home indeed, Where noble souls erect
                            might stand, Beyond the reach of throne or creed. Does she maintain the world-wide cause For
                            which her fathers struggled long ? Or only mid her pleasures pause, To give to liberty a
                            song ? There is no time to sing nor dream— No moments for the banquet hall,— Behold, the
                            cloud whose lightning's beam Is like the writing on the wall! With childish pride, elate and
                            warm, She sees the past with ruddy sky; Unconscious of the brewing storm, That darkly,
                            wildly gathers nigh Her laborers, in their need for bread, Implore her for the right to
                            toil; She drops her hands, she drops her head, And whispers, this is freedom's soil! Above
                            her breath she dare not speak ; Her tyrants awe her with their might; She scarcely knows
                            that she is weak, Or that the right is right. Whence is this power, this conquest sore At
                            which her lips may not demur? Has the invader gained her shore, Or foreign despots conquered
                            her? Ah ! many masters calls she lord, And many kings she must obey,— Monopolists, a
                            soulless horde, Degrade America to-day. From valleys to the mountain's tops, Her heavy
                            golden harvests stand, Her soil is teeming with its crops, But want is seen on every hand.
                            The factory and the foundry still— Or, only making broken sound— The workshops, long
                            untrodden, will With rankest weeds and grass abound, And idlers, idlers, everywhere, And
                            tramps that no one could employ, Till Satan takes them in his care, And makes their reckless
                            hands destroy. The crimson flame is in the sky ; The crimson blood is on the ground; But
                            crimson of a deeper dye, Might on the nation's face be found ! For she who saw not the
                            distress, Nor heard the pleadings of her throngs, Could call her armies to suppress The
                            rage, that swelled against these wrongs. 0, had she heard them when they cried, And waked to
                            effort for their good, Prosperity would now be wide Where dissolution's terrors brood ; But
                            wealth above, and mines below, And commerce on the open sea, One clutching, grasping system
                            know, One law, and that monopoly / Can God o'erlook a crime so great; And human fiends his
                            projects foil! A few usurpers seal the fate That gives his children want and toil ? He made
                            all nations of one blood, And views them with parental eye ; He sends his blessing like a
                            flood, To all who dwell beneath the sky. The Golden Rule that Jesus gave, To each would make
                            a portion sure ; The Declaration of the brave, Would human rights secure. But hath the
                            nation power to say : " Ye shall not in my name oppress?" Or, can the Church in Truth's
                            array, Demand the work of righteousness ? 0,fair Columbia, captive now ! By thine own
                            household foes betrayed j Lift up thy voice, lift up thy brow, And let thy standard be
                            displayed. The craft of Church and State is there, Wherever poverty is found. Then be it
                            first thy urgent care, To know that conscience is unbound. Hear thou the prophecy that
                            thrills Through every heart that loves the right: " God is not dead, his spirit wills A work
                            of overwhelming might / And thou shalt not in bondage groan Nor be to tyrannies a prey ; For
                            he has claimed thee as his own To consecrate to Liberty." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="2" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steeple houses" TEIform="index"/>STEEPLE HOUSES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Forty church steeples were in ruin in the city of Brotherly Love — the city of Quaker origin
                            — acityfoundec by William Penn, who represents the Friends, the first of whom was George
                            Fox, a man of God, a Prophet, and more than a Prophet, more than a medium of others'
                            thoughts pertaining to the future, pertaining to that which God, by the agency of redeemed
                            human beings, in and out of the body, will yet effect. Was it chance, or is there an
                            intelligent, overruling Providence in such an event? Where much is given much is required.
                            Great light has shone in Philadelphia. The founders of Quakerism were men and women who did,
                            in Spiritual Babylon, what the signers of Independence Hall did in Governmental Babylon.
                            They began to right the wrongs of humanity. They laid down first principles as data for reai
                            soning and for action. The steeple, in church edifices, embodies an idea. A steeple, to the
                            rest of the building, is as an aristocracy to the body of the people, which has to be borne
                            and sustained by the strength of muscle and spirit of the mass of the population. Looks, not
                            utility, is the mission of a steeple, and of an aristocracy. George Fox bore as thundering a
                            testimony against a spiritual aristocracy that held high adulterous carnival in steeple
                            houses as Thomas Paine bore against the monarchy and aristocracy of palaces, that cost
                            millions of the people's money to build and support, literally grinding the faces of the
                            poor into abject, hopeless destitution—made them enlist in army and navy, to kill each other
                            in wars that had no moresense nor meaning to the nation than a steeple has to the rest of
                            the building. It is labor and money thrown away — the children's bread thrown to the dogs.
                            The poor erect the steeple houses, for the dole of breadr from their masters, to keep from
                            starvation, exactly as soldiers and marines kill each other, for the bare necessaries of
                            life from their rulers. God works by means. He is judging the world by man, whom he has
                            appointed to be his battle axe and weapon of war. We claim that Christ has come, as foretold
                            by genuine Quaker witnesses,. who said: "The great day of God Almighty is at hand." The
                            Kingdom of Heaven is on Earth. In it are no aristocracy, living upon the labor of others,
                            contrary to the law of Brotherly and Sisterly Love. Poverty and all sickness are being
                            removed by the removal of the causes that produce them. A man is a man and a woman is a
                            woman, "for a' that," who eats and drinks for use, not appetite. Light is sown for the
                            righteous. The human being who rises above his or her selfhood, above inherited and
                            educational proclivities ;o evil, above habit, into the realm of ight, is righteous. To such
                            light ontinually increases into perfect day. 'n food and drink, in labor, in dress, n
                            habitation, in public buildings, in jroperty, the good of the individual s the good of
                            society. To love God, ;ruth and goodness, supremely, is to ove our neighbor as we love
                            ourselve s 2<pb n="3" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Let all steeples be taken down, anc
                            churches be converted into halls oi science, as well as places of worship. Begin at the
                            bottom. Let a great company of the priesthood be converted to the faith that work is
                            worship, when directed to useful ends and purposes. Do not the Quakers in the Spirit world
                            suffer for the sins of Philadelphia? Have they any pleasure in the first, or second day of
                            the week, more than in the third, or fourth ? Are they not crying to God continually, day
                            and night, to come quickly and put an end to a figurative, shadowy Sabbath, that all the
                            people may have a Sabbath of the Lord — a rest from the evils, the corruptions in the world
                            through the legion of lusts of its inhabitants? The Lord was not in the whirlwind, nor in
                            the earthquake, nor yet in the fire — and that is the reason why they destroy that which God
                            hath not wrought — the steeple houses, and the system that steeples are but a sign of. But
                            God is in the still small voice of conscience, saying: Do not these abominable things which
                            I hate. Do not any thing contrary to Brotherly Love, in the city of Brotherly Love. ML
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War positively unchristian" TEIform="index"/>WAR POSITIVELY UNCHRISTIAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName">ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Whence come wars ? How do they originate, and who fans the flames ? These questions are broad
                            ; and to trace them from the embryo stages, through family broils, and the cragged paths of
                            society — in the higher and lower walks of life, Christian (?) and profane —would require
                            time and space to fully answer. It is evident that two powers or forces occupy the
                            unregenerate human heart; one earthly and animal, the other spiritual and heavenly. The
                            earthly, when perverted, is full of evil thinking, hatred and revenge, demonlike ; and these
                            bring forth war. The spiritual, by proper culture, symbolizes the angel condition, and
                            produces peace and good will to all. War is incompatible with Christianity. It is not only
                            un-christian, but is immoral, unscientific, and retards civilization. Its place, if
                            anywhere, should be among barbarous tribes ; yet, at the present time, it seems to be a
                            dominant power, rulingall the nations of our earth. Will it always be thus ? If truth is
                            stronger than error, and it be possible to overcome evil with good, will not Peace
                            principles — although "their vindicators are now in the minority — work their way against
                            opposing forces to final triumph ? Many who admit the supremacy of Peace, still vindicate
                            war, and plead its necessity as a means to defend and preserve the honor and peace of
                            nations. That even the Christian religion can jbnly be maintained by force of arms. Would
                            He, who so strongly advocated Peace, by precept and example, that He was called the Prince
                            of Peace, and who said " My kingdom is not of ;his world ; My servants will not fight,"
                            employ agents to fight for His kingdom, and to make a way for Him and His lowly followers,
                            through jloody battle-fields strewn with the 3<pb n="4" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. dead
                            and dying ? Or would He pass through the warriors' camps, and see thousands of demoralized
                            human beings, professedly figh ting in His name, and calling upon God, through their
                            chaplains, to aid them in their battles, and feel that His cause was strengthened and
                            honored by such conflicts ? Eeason and conscience answer, Nay. Sooner would He lead His
                            tender lambs to some lone mountain, or to some peaceful vale, where wild beasts of prey do
                            not rend and devour; and there, with strong cries and tears, supplicate the Father to remove
                            ignorance and folly from the minds of men, and show them how cause and effect are related ;
                            and that reason and a forgiving spirit are more potent than madness and revenge. Human
                            nature, unsubdued by the grace of God, is the same in all ages and nations ; fierce,
                            resentful, unforgiving, and culminates in war, which, when called by the right name, is
                            murder on a large scale ; and drape it, or crown it with laurels as best we may, it is the
                            same odious offender. Its best directed methods destroy the peace of nations, waste all
                            vital energies, empty public treasuries, and spread desolation far and wide. That great
                            wrongs exist in society, at home and abroad, none will deny. How to meet and remove those
                            wrongs is the great question to be solved. May we not yet hop6 to see just tribunals
                            established, where righteous and peace-loving judges will hold the sceptre of power and
                            influence ; when reason, and an enlightened conscience shall bear rule, and one nation shall
                            say to another nation, " Come now and let us reason together, as man with his brother man."
                            The war spirit arouses the vilest passions of the human heart; therefore, as intelligent,
                            accountable beings, we should learn to subdue the evil within our own breasts, and strive to
                            live in peace with all men, whether they be our friends or foes. When people are educated to
                            see that arbitration is better than the sword ; that to bless is wiser than to curse; and to
                            render good for evil, more dignified and noble than retaliation, then will the banner of the
                            Prince of Peace wave in triumph over the nations of the earth, and the shadows of great
                            armies upon the land, and fleets upon the sea grow less; and God's earth, by proper culti-
                            vation, be made to bring forth bountiful supplies for man and beast.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Millennium" TEIform="index"/>THE MILLENNIUM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">In conversation with one of the brethren lately, whose particular charge is in the temporal
                            sphere, I was deeply impressed by a remark of his that the strong of a Christian community
                            bless and support the weak in contradistinction to the common, worldly career, of grinding
                            their faces and preying upon their weakness. How beautiful is this, thought I; how like the
                            wisdom of God, to inaugurate a system on the earth, wherein the strong in mind and body
                            should ever delight to bear the infirmities of the weak ! How unworldly is that prac- tice,
                            where those blessed with more than ordinary powers of body or mind, not only experience it a
                            duty, but a privilege, to contribute these for the support, guidance and blessing of 4<pb n="5" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. their less gifted fellows, instead of making their
                            weakness a means of aggrandizement! Applying this idea to morals and spiritual conditions is
                            the work of a Shaker Community ; and with these prosecuted intact, what remains to complete
                            the coming of the long-desired Millennium ? There is sufficient talent among the worldly, to
                            create a system, under which all will be amply provided for in all the necessaries of this
                            life. What reason is there that this is not done ? Is it not the grasping selfishness of the
                            more talented few, who aggrandize to themselves such a monopoly, that all indulgence and
                            extravagance may be theirs, at the expense of poverty and sorrows of the less gifted and
                            weak ? What is the world waiting for ? What will it have ? Here are presented to it
                            principles that bring millennial blessings every day ; yet these are spurned, through
                            excessive selfishness and hatred of self-denials. Through the principles and practices of
                            "live, and help us to live as well," in all that pertains to a peaceful, godly life, Christ
                            has already come, nor need we look' for another. Under such gospel precepts, a complete
                            brotherhood is created — the Jew, the Infidel, the tribes of black, yellow and red skins,
                            with all denominations of professing and non-professing religionists — all would be as one,
                            each striving for the best good of all; all striving for the good, comfort and blessing of
                            each. Such is the millennium aimed at in Shaker families ; where "no one is set on high to
                            sway an earthly sceptre ; where tyrants cannot come to reign, nor despots to rule ; the sick
                            are ministered unto, and the decline of life, and those tottering with feeble knees,
                            supported by loving hands and kinder hearts." Such is pure Shakerism, removed from human
                            selfishness. In it, there can be no scrambling for place nor power ; no other emolument
                            sought nor expected but the blessing of those blessed ; no excessive exertion therein for
                            purposes of self-exaltation ; no godly wants but are filled ; no need of crime for what is
                            necessary ; no harbor for bloated wealth, nor corner for the poverty-stricken. Is the
                            millennium desired ? Let any live the life of Jesus, the Christ, and the above practices
                            will be put into practical operation. In Christ's life, and in the lives of those who
                            pattern Jesus, are not all the conditions given necessary for the constitution of the
                            millennium ? And does not the fact that such principles of life, as nearest represent Jesus
                            Christ, are in practical operation, evidence that Christ has come ? that the millennium is
                            here ? that selfishness, that " accuser of the brethren," is cast out, and that peace
                            reigns? jV". Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">Doubtless the time is coming when the Indian Territory, containing the "five nations" of
                            civilized Indians, viz.: Oherokees, GMckasaws, Choctaws, Creeks, and Seminoles, will be
                            admitted into the Union as a State, and will be as ably represented in Congress by educated
                            Indians, as any State in the Union ;" even as South Carolina is at the present time by an
                            educated African, Rainey, who is able to cope in argument with any white man in Congress.
                                5<pb n="6" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. The present degree of civilization to which
                            these Indians have attained, show conclusively that they are as capable of being led on to a
                            higher degree of civilization and development, when the time shall come to have a perfect
                            example set before them, as any nation on the earth, and more so, because they are more
                            susceptible of divine illuminations. They are now self-educating and self-supporting ; they
                            ask no favors of the white men but to fulfill their treaty obligations, and if they will not
                            do this, they only asked to be left alone, to " manage their own domestic concerns in their
                            own way." They wisely wish to postpone their admission into the Union as a State for the
                            present, and not without good reasons. It is said there are over 60,000, or thirty-five
                            nations and tribes now occupying the Indian Territory. The following are extracts of a
                            letter from a Ghickasaw Indian, one of the civilized nations, dated Tishomingo, G. N.,
                            Indian Territory, Nov. 4th, 1878 : We give place to the foregoing because it expresses the
                            sentiments of all the Indians on the subject of being transferred to the War Department.
                            They are a unit on this question, and are all opposed to it. And why should their united
                            voices not be heard in the councils of the nation, in the decision of so grave a question,
                            on which their future destiny and civilization depend, numbering as they do, in all, about
                            308,000 souls, according to the best and most reliable authority ? We are sure if the Hon.
                            Commissioners who are appointed to investigate this matter will listen to their cries and
                            entreaties, and allow them to have a voice in the deci sion of this question, that this
                            odious "transfer bill" will never ,'pass the Senate of the United States, so as to become a
                            law. Never! If it does, it will very soon have to be repealed, for something higher and
                            better, to save the Indian, if he is saved. In view of such injustice, no wonder Thomas
                            Jefferson exclaimed, " I tremble for my country when I remember that God is just." North
                            Union, Ohio. </p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="James S. Prescott—Dear Sir: I am in receipt of yours of the 25th ult...." TEIform="index"/>James S. Prescott—Dear Sir:...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">James S. Prescott—Dear Sir: I am in receipt of yours of the 25th ult., and am truly glad
                                to receive the Manifesto. I read both copies you sent me, and am more thaii pleased to
                                see the principles inculcated in its pages. You say you would hardly take me to be an
                                Indian from my picture sent you. Very few can detect any trace in me of my Indian
                                parentage, excepting by my actions ; in my every-day life I am perfectly sound, stand
                                over six feet in my stockings, and pull the scales at 185 pounds. I am 27 years of age
                                and considered a fair specimen of the Ghickasaw nation. I am of a wandering disposition
                                and have traveled over every State east of the Mississippi, and nearly all west of here.
                                I send you a sample copy of our Choctaw Indian spelling book, used in our schools. You
                                cannot find an Indian here, no matter how ignorant he may appear, who cannot read and
                                write positively well in our own language. We have spelling books, bibles, testaments,
                                hymn-books, catechisms, and various other works in our own tongue. You have the idea
                                just right in your article on the Indian. You say in The Shaker Manifesto he is not
                                benefited " by associating with bad white men ; but rather made worse." Could you go
                                with me and see the shame children (as we call them) at every military post, you could
                                then form an idea why we do not want the War Department over us, for it means
                                demoralization, and finally extermination. Give us the Peace policy and we can ere long
                                become an honor to the IT. S. But turn us over to the War Department, and you set us
                                back forty years on the road to civilization. PJead for us, my friend; cry to your God
                                that this great injustice may not be done us. We are all children of the great Gitchee
                                Manito — " Great Spirit " — and he will hold the white people responsible for the way
                                they treat us. Trusting his blessing may rest upon you, I have the pleasure to sign
                                myself, Respectfully yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guy, James H." TEIform="persName"/>James H. Guy</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More about Indians" TEIform="index"/>MORE ABOUT INDIANS</head><p TEIform="p">General Sheridan charges that mismanagement of Indian affairs by governmental officials has
                            caused all the troubles with the red men, and he believes kind treatment, administered with
                            steadiness and justice, would relieve our western frontier from all the appalling horrors
                            arising from Indian outbreaks. <pb n="7" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> Peace Policy.—Win. Penn was the first
                            and only man that ever solved the Indian problem. And how did he do it ? He did it by fair
                            dealing, and practically carrying out the Peace Policy ; and by this policy he conquered the
                            Indians and made them his friends. And we have never heard that a drop of Quaker blood was
                            ever shed by an Indian. Gen. Grant indorsed the Peace Policy when he said, " Let us have
                            Peace ;" and when he recommended to Congress the appointment of an Indian agency, from among
                            the Society of Friends, he did a good thing for the Indians, and an honor to the country. It
                            was taking a step in the right direction—approved by all Christian people A Beautiful Indian
                            Custom. — A few weeks since, a camp meeting was held in the Creek Nation lasting several
                            days. The meeting was attended by many Choctaws from our sister nation over the line, and
                            had been one of great solemnity and serious interest. At its close and before parting they
                            all placed themselves in two lines facing each other, and the Choctaws in their own language
                            sang some of their sweetest hymns. Then each passed down the opposite line and earnestly
                            shook the hands of the Creeks. Then the Creeks repeated the graceful ceremony, singing in
                            their beautiful Muskoke language, shaking the hands of the Choctaw worshipers, wished them
                            God speed, and then filed off to their respective Nations and homes. This was an
                            exemplification of the " peace on earth and good will" policy.— Indian paper.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker meeting" TEIform="index"/>A SHAKER MEETING</head><p TEIform="p">[In a most absurd and impossible story, running through a few numbers of The Atlantic, the
                            following facts are culled from among much dirty fiction It is a well-known fact that the
                            Jamestown Weed, or Stinlt Weed, contains much honey. As a bee seeking honey among most
                            nauseous surroundings, so we present the good and true, leaving the passion-awakening and
                            silly to die without good company. The following excerpts illustrate, pretty correctly, the
                            public, religious services of all Shakers.—Ed.] "As he drew near the village, he heard the
                            toll of a bell, and was surprised by the sight of a procession crossing the road from one of
                            the houses to the plain Meeting House opposite. He stopped in admiration. Two and two the
                            women walked, carrying music books in their hands, and dressed now in quiet-colored,
                            delicate gowns which hung in straight folds, but were rendered singu- larly beautiful by the
                            addition of the soft, silk kerchief about the neck; while the head was inclosed in a snug
                            cap, which could not be called lovely in itself, yet had an undeniable harmony with the rest
                            of the dress. The placid manner and quiet dignity of the little procession, moving under the
                            blue sky, brought a singular sense of quiet to him, and as they entered the Meeting House,
                            he suddenly resolved to follow them and see what their service was like. Some wagons and
                            carriages stood near by, and strangers—world's people—were moving into the little building.
                            He followed through the men's door and seated himself upon one of the benches set apart for
                            outsiders. The whole company of men and women were standing in opposite rows and singing, a
                            few holding music books, but most familiar with music and words. The hymn sung was
                            introductory to the service, which began with the reading of a chapter from the New
                            Testament by one of the elders. The chief part of the service, however, was in the combined
                            music and marching, or dancing, as it might sometimes be called. By some understanding, the
                            company quietly formed, eight young men and women occupying the center of the room in an
                            oval figure, the remainder disposed in two circles outside the smaller one; this small
                            circle was stationary, and seemed to form a choir ; the song was started by it, and the two
                            circles began moving round it, the inner in an opposite direction to that taken by the
                            outer. The choir members held their hands before them with uplifted palms, and gently let
                            them rise and fall to the cadences of the music. So, also, did the two circles of marchers,
                            and the singing was carried on not only by the choir, but by so many of the marchers as were
                            possessed of musical powers ; while those who could not sing moved their lips with the words
                            of the song and seemed to share in the singing. 7<pb n="8" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            When the song was ended, the double procession stopped, each member in place, and all, choir
                            and marchers, swept their hands downward and by a gesture appeared to arrest the music.
                            Then, after a pause, either new singing with a resumption of the marching would begin, or
                            some one would speak a few words of thanksgiving or exhortation. " It was the first time
                            that he had ever been within the Shaker meeting house, and lie was surprised into a spirit
                            of reverence. Whatever of the grotesque had been asso- ciated with the service in his mind,
                            from the descriptions he had heard, disappeared in the actual presence of these sincere men
                            and women. It is true that now and then he had to repress a smile, as some peculiar
                            earnestness of expression turned its odd side toward him, and he thought also that he
                            detected certain sleepy and perfunctory movements on the part of some, as if their minds
                            were on some remote occupation, perchance the gathering of roses for the distilled
                            rose-water to be made shortly, or some like innocent occupation in their unexciting life ;
                            but the congregation doubtless had its range of devotion, like other congregations. The main
                            effect was of a simple-minded and simple-hearted people, who threw into this service a
                            fervor which expressed the ideal of their life. To be neat and practical was not the whole
                            of their religion ; for them also were aspirations and anticipations ; and sometimes, as
                            they marched to the singing of a hymn which spoke of them as pilgrims on their way to a
                            heavenly home, their faces were turned up with an eager, joyous look, their feet seemed only
                            to touch the floor, and their hands pushed back the sordid world with an energetic gesture.
                            It was at such times that he was thrilled with a sympathetic emotion. The rude singing and
                            the quick movements of the marchers blended harmoniously, and his soul was fanned as it were
                            by a breath from some distant sea. There were, besides, other times where the gestures,
                            changing their meaning with the varying hymn, swept the world away and brought back heavenly
                            presences, and the refrain was repeated again and again, so that the meaning was driven in
                            upon one with renewed waves of feeling; and, finally, by a sudden movement,, the inner
                            circle of singers was itself transformed into a moving circle, making three rings of
                            worshipers, passing and repassing each other with rhythmic tread, and singing joyfully a
                            triumphant song. He half closed his eyes, and the moving bodies before him seemed almost
                            resolved into a cloud of witnesses, wavering under a divine power which swept it backward
                            and forward across the heavenly field. " There was doubtless in him a sensitiveness to
                            subtle influences which made him easily affected by the spectacle. It was the visible and
                            frank manifestation of emotions which he shared with others, but was rarely permitted to
                            witness, because in most cases one needs first to express like emotions, and he by his
                            constitutional shyness was prevented from soliciting or sharing in any exhibition of
                            feeling. Besides', the humorous was not strongly developed in him, and very simple sentiment
                            from his long brooding in solitude, had come to have an elemental force likely to be
                            overlooked by persons more familiar with the process of expression and repression. In the
                            scene before him he thought he was looking into depths of the human heart, just as in
                            hearing a few chords of music he might believe himself listening to spheral harmonies.
                            Perhaps it was because he was so sympathetic and responsive that the faces of the men and
                            women were hallowed by a light not ordinarily seen by him. * * * * There were all ages
                            present, from young, children to old men and women ; but the beauty of devotion never
                            appears so fair as when residing in those who are heirs to all that the world can give, yet
                            reach upward for more enduring delights. * * * * " The Elder came forward as usual, and
                            placing his hands together with a familiar gesture began what at first might more properly
                            be called a meditation than an address: "'Jesus Christ said that if any man would be great
                            among you he<pb n="9" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 9 should be your servant. The law of
                            service is the law of supremacy. If I use my neighbor for my personal ends, I degrade him,
                            but I degrade myself still more. I show that I am not free, that I am the slave of j my
                            ambition, my appetite, my propensities. He is free who has learned to govern his
                            propensities. The rich man has a propensity for property, and he gets it from the poor. The
                            more he gets, the more he wants, and as the poor man grows poorer, the rich man grows richer
                            and more and more unable to do without his riches. His wants are increased, and they
                            increase faster than he can supply them. He becomes a slave to his avaricious desires, and
                            sinks lower and lower. The politician ' has a propensity for power, and he gets it by using
                            men; he makes them serve him while he professes to serve them; he never gives any thing
                            except for a greater return. Every step he takes toward power brings him more under the
                            control of other men; he binds himself by obligations, and when he gets supreme authority he
                            finds that he has lost the right to call his soul his own, and he can do nothing without
                            reference to meaner men. The selfish man has a propensity to gratify himself, and he seeks
                            his end by shutting out everybody else from the participation of his pleasure. He will end
                            by being himself shut out from the kingdom of heaven, an outcast who, seeking to gratify
                            himself alone, finds that he has none of the things which he thought he had; that he has
                            become a paralytic, unable to vise the power that had been given him. The people called
                            Shakers have set themselves a higher law, the law' of service, and they have found that it
                            has made them great by lifting them above the meaner desires that lead men captive. Are you
                            rich ? Come to us and learn that no man is rich till he calls nothing his own, Are you a
                            politician? Come to us and learn that no man is exalted until he has made himself a servant
                            of all. Are you selfish? Do you look for your pleasure in those things that minister to your
                            ease, to your intellectual gratification; yea, to your love of family, of wife and of
                            children? Let me tell you that no man is worthy of the society of the head man of the race,
                            Jesus Christ, who does not leave father and mother and wife and children to live as Christ
                            lived, who called no man father and no man brother after the flesh; who did not marry, but
                            loved all women with the pure love of a brother for his sisters. Come out and be ye separate
                            from the world; crucify your lusts, conquer your propensities, and come into the higher
                            manhood, where all are equal, and every one loves his neighbor as himself, instead of loving
                            his neighbor for the sake of himself.' "</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, tenth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE. HER
                            WORK, HER PEOPLE, AND THEIR CRITICS. Tenth Paper.</head><p TEIform="p">William Lee, brother of Mother Ann, was born in Manchester, in 1740, being four years younger
                            than his honored sister. He followed in the line of business of his father, being a
                            blacksmith. He was married ; had one .son. Of the wife or son we have been unable to gain
                            but little information. He was at one time an officer of horse in the King's royal guard —
                            the Oxford Blues. In his personal appearance he was above medium height, thick set, large
                                limbs<pb n="10" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. and strong body. He commanded the
                            respect, or won the confidence of all with whom he came in contact. He knew not what fear
                            was ; and was notably ever placing himself in the van of the little Shaker company during
                            the scenes of their bloodshed and persecution. Before adopting as his own the peculiar faith
                            enunciated by his sister, he was a haughty, overbearing young man; fond of gay dress, and
                            sought distinction in worldly glory. While under the influences of such aspirations, he "
                            was met on the way " by a spirit of conviction that his was a very sinful life ; and after
                            battling these convictions unsuccessfully, he visited his sister Ann, in hopes of relief,
                            and found it, but not in the way he expected it! On meeting him, Ann rebuked him with
                            severity for his pride, and showed him his dan. ger of longer continuing in sin. From this
                            hour began a work with him which changed the whole tenor of his life, not only in an
                            external line, but in all his intentions and internal labors. From the proudest youngster,
                            he became the model of humility and self-abasement; from being unequally resentful, he
                            became the most peace-lovingnon-combatant, but not without severe struggles; for when
                            personally abused he, biting his lips, under self-control, was often heard to remark : "
                            Once upon a time you would not have dared to do that! " That time was past, however, and
                            instead of resisting, he became very harmless. We have record of an amusing scene occurring
                            in Albany, N. Y., which, as it culminated very peacefully, we are left to conjecture how
                            severely he was tried and how " it might have been." Being at work over his anvil, tUtere
                            came into the shop a low ruffian, noted for being a brutal fighter. Urged on by others, he
                            did every imaginable insult to William to provoke him to rage and a fight. William bore
                            every thing until personal violence was commenced upon him, when, turning to his assailant,
                            he said : " Hold on ; if we must fight, let's make room for it!" and seizing hold of the
                            large anvil with one hand he threw it in one corner, and then sotne heavy iron with the
                            other, which, when his bullying antagonist observed, he slunk quickly away, saying he was ''
                            not going to fight a man who could do that'' and was ever after jeered by his comrades. That
                            he was physically powerful was fully demonstrated by a neighbor giving him a barrel of cider
                            if he would carry it home ! Being assisted to shoulder it, he trudged nearly half a mile
                            home with the 350 pounds. But he was the opposite of being quarrelsome, contentious or
                            violent, excepting his extreme violence of labors and testimony against the powers of evil.
                            In his labors of self-control he would work hard all day, and restrain himself from any
                            remarks whatever. In all religious devotions he manifested a kind, fatherly spirit to those
                            who were erring and to the young. A most grateful man for the commonest blessings, as bread,
                            water, potatoes or meal, he would often eat every mouthful with tears and gratitude. He
                            became very gifted in visions, in teaching of the faith, and encouraging the growth of good
                            in others. He was a beautiful and powerful singer, and often ministered a revival power to a
                            whole assembly through the beauties and powers of song. Although young and powerful in body,
                            he was made to bear the brunt of ridicule and the personal violence of persecutors. And when
                            these were administered he never shrunk from the fullest share. As a consequence he became "
                            a man of suffering," carrying, as we have stated in a previous paper, the fracture of his
                            skull for many months, down to his grave ; and was reduced through physical sufferings to
                            the mere skeleton of a man, and from which condition he never rallied, but died, aged 44.
                            Mother Ann Lee had other and noble supporters while she lived, others who, in consequence of
                            their peculiar temperaments and education, became better known to the people, and very
                            highly appreciated by her; but it is difficult for us to know how she could have succeeded
                            in planting the seeds of her great testimony in America or elsewhere, without the assistance
                            of this noble brother, William Lee. His remains lie at Shakers, N. Y., beside those of his
                            sister, the spot being marked by a similar, plain slab, on which may be seen wf L.----ELDER
                            WILLIAM LEE.</p></div2><pb n="11" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lord make me what thou wilt" TEIform="index"/>LORD MAKE ME WHAT THOU WILT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">If on the rough, tempestuous sea of life, My lot be cast 'mid wild terrific strife ; If
                            lightning's flash and heavy thunders roar, And drenching torrents oft upon me pour; Or if my
                            feeble barque should often strand., Upon some rock-bound coast in stranger land; Exposed to
                            enemies of sin and guilt, My words shall be, Lord make me what Thou wilt. If on the
                            battle-field of strife and might, (Though Lord I know Thou would'st not have me fight)
                            Within its fated ranks I'll meekly stand, Proclaiming peace unto my fellow man;
                            Administering the healing balm of love, With the becoming meekness of a dove ; And though in
                            martyred form my blood be spilt, My heart shall say, Lord make me what Ihou wilt. If as a
                            missionary o'er the earth, Proclaiming gospel truths of priceless worth, Through trackless
                            wilds in weariness I plod, To teach the suffering millions, of that God Who reigns supremely
                            in the realms of light; And guides the planets in their rapid flight, On God's pure word my
                            solid fortress built, I'll still proclaim, Lord make me what Thou wilt. If in the cause of
                            temperance I move, To check the drunkard in his fated groove ; Protesting with that ardency
                            of soul, That would the dissipated course control; I will not count on life's affliction
                            sore, As far surpassing those my Saviour bore; But with a spirit free from stains and guilt
                            Again I'll say, Lord make me whatThou wilt' If, as a watchman on Mount Zion's walls, A
                            sentinel to give the watchword calls; To keep the lurking enemy at bay ; Throughout the
                            weary hours of night and day, I will not count my burdened care unjust, Nor traitor-like
                            betray my sacred trust; But ever true and free from shame and guilt, I fain would say, Lord
                            make me what Thou wilt. Or if within Mount Zion's courts I stand, A humble servant, laborer;
                            heart and hand Shall be devoted truly to the cause, Upholding and supporting Zion's laws,
                            Contented, happy, cheerful in my lot, To know and do God's will the part that's sought;
                            Devoted ever without sin or guilt, I'll ever say, Lord make me what Thou wilt. Enfield, N.
                            H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker view" TEIform="index"/>Shaker view
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Pennsylvania, New Garden, Octover 26, 1878" TEIform="index"/>New Garden, Chester
                                Co., Pa., Oct. 26, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">[From The American Socialist.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE SHAKER VIEW. Dear Socialist.—Our Shaker friends assume, or believe (as I
                                        understand them) that theirs is a higher life — that they are " upstairs " (as
                                        our friend Eads expresses it) because they are celibates. I cannot understand
                                        their position, and would feel obliged to them, and no doubt many of your
                                        readers would feel the same, if they would throw more light on this extremely
                                        important subject. Yours truly, Communist. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American socialist" TEIform="index"/>The American Socialist.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply by Elder Geo. Albert Lomas" TEIform="index"/>REPLY BY ELDER GEO. ALBERT LOMAS</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers, November 3, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y., Nov. 3,1878. </dateline><p TEIform="p">Editors American Socialist— My Friends—Yours, simply inclosing the letter of " Communist"
                                is at hand, and your meaning interpreted. After the lapse of so many centuries since the
                                dawn of the Christian era, which centuries have beheld so many brilliant examples, whose
                                testimonies championed virgin celibacy as a superior element, not only to work out the
                                Christian's salvation from sin, but as a steppingstone to conditions which are superior
                                to the best estates of earth-life without it, my pen can only poorly supplement their
                                illustrious arguments, leaving my life and that of my fellows, to attest the correctness
                                of the conclusions arrived at by them. We opine, " Communist" is sincere, in that the
                                life he is living is the best for him ; we are very unwilling to dispute his
                                convictions, and can only hope that he will give us as much credit for honest
                                convictions, and permit us undisturbed, " to pursue the even tenor of our way" in the
                                strictest, virgin celibacy ; which, while we are satisfied is best for us, may not be
                                best for him, nor for many others who are not yet ripe for such a harvest. But that he
                                and all will sometime ripen to such a conclusion we feel an assurance equal to our
                                expectations of the rotations of the seasons. Many who are now Shakers have been
                                married—adopted marriage as the very best for them; who after- ward became convinced of
                                the superior fa(OXX£SpOUtlUtZ.<pb n="12" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. cilities
                                which a celibate life would give them in the prosecution* of a Christian's duty. They
                                found upon the trial of both marriage and celibacy, that celibacy was not only a
                                necessity ofChristian life, but that there could be no complete Christianity without it.
                                This will be called a sweeping assertion, as it is ; for we have learned by long
                                experience that there can be no thorough Christianity practiced where marriage or
                                sexuality is engaged in. Very many of us are as ignorant and innocent of sexual
                                knowledge and contact as babes, and feel so well satisfied and justified by the absence
                                of such contact that thoughts, even, leaning- tow ard such knowledge are construed by us
                                as a tarnish to the garments of our spirits. Attribute, if you please, such feelings to
                                early education and bias; we will, in our jubilant justification, thank God for such an
                                education, and bless the hands that bent the twigs by which our riper years have been
                                inclined. We have never asserted that the engagement in sexual love was other than as
                                natural as eating, sleeping, breathing, etc., but we have laid greater stress upon such
                                an engagement as affecting the spiritual progress very much more for the worse than any
                                other natural occupation. Both experience in it before embracing Shakerism, and the
                                absence of experience demonstrate this to us. Sexual disobedience we hold -to have been
                                the seat of man's loss ; and yet it is not because of our inclination to sin sexually
                                that we have become total abstinents thereto. Had there been no disobedience — no fall
                                of humanity — the harvestman, Christ, would have been a necessity, to cut off from
                                earthly, primitive practices all who should ripen up to the Christian sickle. Surely, if
                                every man and woman were as perfect and sinless as untempted Adams and Eves—if each
                                could engage in the reproduction of the most perfect human species—the fact that
                                Christ's testimony was a call, to as many as " are able," to come up higher, above the
                                plane of animal reproductions, and into superior relations with God, by having our lives
                                taken from the earthly, with none to declare our generations (Acts 8:33), appears to be
                                only the sequence of a duty—a pleasurable duty. We aim at the greatest of heavenly
                                practice on earth ; and believe our enjoyment is here enhanced by patterning Jesus and
                                what we have learned to «be the practice of the angels of God in the spiritual world.
                                Jesus lived a self-denying, superior, heavenly life while on earth. If it might be
                                called unnatural, it may as reasonably be termed a beautiful sample of angel-life on the
                                earth; and all of our self-denials, as copyists of that life, are more than balanced by
                                the superior fruits of the spirit. " All men are not able/' said Jesus, " to live as I
                                do ; but whoso is able let him live the life." " The children of the world marry," and
                                engage in sexual pleasures ; but the children of the Resurrection—Christ's children—are
                                raised above such practices, and live as the angels do; and who supposes the angels to
                                so engage? Paul says: "Those who marry do well; but those who abstain do better." So
                                even the Shakers say : Those who, " unable to become eunuchs for the kingdom," do marry,
                                and regulate their sexual commerce for reproductions only—being as good in this as the
                                best practice of the beasts of ttie field—do well; but not as well as those " whose
                                lives are hid with Christ" in greater godliness of life. " Marriage peoples the earth,"
                                says St. Jerome ; " but celibacy increases the heavens." Said Henry C. Wright: " Jesus
                                and Paul practiced and taught celibacy. If Paul lived to-day he would undoubtedly be a
                                strict, thorough-going Shaker. I do not see how any believer in the New Testament can
                                come to any other conclusion than that at which the Shakers have arrived ; nevertheless,
                                Shakerism is a monstrosity to me !" The best modern treatise upon " Holy Matrimony " of
                                which we know is by Rev. J. A. Bolles, D. D., of Boston. Thirteen chapters embody the
                                most beautiful delinea^ tions of what marriage is for and what it should be. I doubt if
                                any have ever excelled his expatiations upon the bliss of the marital relations ; yet
                                his " after all,' in one chapter upon " Celibacy " sheds a blaze of glory upon it, that
                                reminds one of the sun,<pb n="13" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 13 when at its
                                meridian height, forbidding the glow of the stars, however beautiful. In closing, hear
                                him : " After all, is there not a higher life revealed in the Scriptures than even the
                                holy state of matrimony—a life by which an individual may voluntarily forego all the
                                blessings of the mystery of marriage, in order to become more and more absorbed in
                                devotion to the duties of the spiritual union of Christ and the Church—a life in which a
                                love for the antitype may be even so great as to banish from the mind all thought of the
                                type, concentrating all the affections of the soul upon the reality of the substance a
                                life so entirely free from the temporal, with all its joys and cares, and entanglements,
                                as to see nothing, to think of nothing, and to long for nothing but the Eternal—Christ
                                himself, and the fruition of his glorious Godhead? How can it be denied that the
                                Scriptures do reveal to us the possibility of such a life ; and that it is the life of
                                the celibate ' for the kingdom of heaven's sake'—not the life of the mere unmarried,
                                which in itself considered is one of the most selfish of all lives, and which is not
                                infrequently chosen for the sake of selfish and criminal indulgence; but the life of the
                                celibate 'for the kingdom of heaven's sake f ' Our blessed Lord said indeed, ' All men
                                cannot receive this saying, save they to whom it is given ; but he that is able to
                                receive it, let him receive it.' " Therefore, dear Socialist, our long experience of an
                                hundred years has proved to us, that not only " all men cannot" be Shakers, but that
                                only a few are able at present to meet its demands upon them. Until they are able and
                                willing, the words of Young apply to their duty right well: " He who does the best his
                                circumstance allows, does well, acts nobly, angels could no more;" while I remain the
                                friend of " Communist," and yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor of Manifesto : Thanks for the B. P. Journal sent me..." TEIform="index"/>Editor of Manifesto : Thanks for the B. P. Journal sent me...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, December 10, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., Dec. 10, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor of Manifesto : Thanks for the B. P. Journal sent me. I read your very excellent
                                address, delivered at the Watkins Convention, with much interest. It can but serve as an
                                eye and earopener to many. Enclosed, I send you " The Tombs of the Prophets" from the "
                                Common People." How differs this from the fate of our modern prophets, except in mode,
                                means, and missiles ? Horace Mann, alluding to this subject, said : " Public opinion and
                                the press were a forty satan-power engine." Add to these the espionage of the guardians
                                of public virtue—special agents of the post-office department, and should the
                                constitution of the United States be prostituted by the introduction of some sectarian
                                God, the record of the past would be but a prolusion of what would follow. The present
                                should learn wisdom, and guard against what is charged to the past; and to avoid another
                                fatal error—idolatry to those resurrected prophets. Hearers of their divinely inspired
                                words; standing in their footprints, saying, great and divine souls were they; instead
                                of carrying forward the progressive principles of truth they taught and lived. Those
                                great, heroic souls never claimed perfection—that "greater works" could not be done.
                                Such claims were the invention of devotees, who es- teemed a prophet or medium more than
                                principles. One of our modern prophets said, " Let no fondness for me blind your eyes to
                                my errors ;" and Jesus declared, " I am come to send fire on the earth, and what will I
                                (do) if it be already kindled ?" He queried if he could bear the consuming of natural
                                ties and affections so that his life should agree with the testimony he was delivering
                                to others. And he continues : " But I have a baptism to be baptized with, and how am I
                                straitened till it be accomplished ? " He evidently felt his inspiration in advance of
                                his travel —of his attainments ; hence his restraint till he was fully baptized into
                                that divine element of which he was a medium and subject. While we duly appreciate, and
                                justly honor those saints and martyrs who have gone before us, and no less those present
                                with us now, let our devotion be to truth and progress ; and our greatest concern be of
                                the footprints we make ; for the guidance<pb n="14" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                of those who follow, even as those before have served us. Let no one defraud themselves
                                by clinging to the garments of their ancestors, hoping to extract life therefrom; nor
                                think that because they are one in name, and living among God's peculiar people that
                                these will insure salvation or growth of their spiritual beings. Our praise to God,
                                Jesus and the martyrs, will never atone for deeds of charity and love left undone by us.
                                Yours</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tombs of the prophets" TEIform="index"/>THE TOMBS OF THE PROPHETS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The prophets are noted for having very respectable sepulchres. Men fling stones
                                    at them when they are alive, and heap stones over them when they are dead. As long
                                    as a prophet is alive and faithful, standing for God and rebuking iniquity, so long
                                    he will be despised, hated, persecuted and scorned by the Scribes and Pharisees who
                                    claim to be the custodians of divine blessings and guardians of religious truth. "
                                    Which of the prophets," said Stephen, "have not your fathers persecuted ? And they
                                    have slain them which had shown before of the coming of the Just One; of whom ye
                                    have been now the betrayers and murderers." They answered his question by a volley
                                    of stones—their most convenient and most convincing argument. When once a prophet
                                    has been stoned, and is fairly out of the way, and likely to make no more trouble,
                                    then there is no special objection to making him respectable and honorable. The sons
                                    of the men who stone the prophet pass a subscription paper and raise money to build
                                    him a monument, and send half way round the world for a marble white enough to bear
                                    the name that was " cast out as evil " when the man was alive, and would be again if
                                    he were not entirely out of sight and hearing. Many a man whose life has been filled
                                    with bitterness and weariness by the spite and envy of those whom he sought to help
                                    and save, when dead and in his coffin has been pronounced "an eminent saint" in the
                                    " customary resolutions " passed by the very men who had planted thorns in his
                                    pillow and briars in his path, and vexed his righteous soul from day to day with
                                    their unholy deeds. If we have any sympathy for the servants of God, it is better to
                                    put it into something warmer than grave-stones. Half the kind words that are spoken
                                    over men when dead, would add greatly to their comfort if uttered while they were
                                    alive; and the money squandered on the gorgeous tombs of the dead prophets might be
                                    more wisely spent in ministering to the comfort of their successors who yet live,
                                    and who are as little honored by the tomb-builders as their predecessors were by
                                    their fathers.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Common people" TEIform="index"/>The Common People</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto: the world's need of us" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. THE
                                WORLD'S NEED OF US</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Friends and Brethren : We greet you ! From a deep consciousness only, that there is yet a
                                work for us to do; that there is a niche in the temple of thought which we should fill;
                                that there is a more radically Christian testimony for us to deliver among many other
                                testimonies called Christian ; that there is a higher life than the ordinary for us to
                                illustrate to the world, and to elevate in the wilderness of sin a panacea for all
                                sins—even to present the principle of SELF-DENTAL as the WOELD'S SAVIOUE —from these,
                                and similar causes, or calls to duty, do we greet you again in the beginning of a new
                                volume. Were there a publication more radically Christian jn its tone than is ours, we
                                could better afford to retire from the field of journalism; and so soon as there shall
                                reach our conscious feelings the tidings of a testimony that will reflect the Christ
                                Spirit more fully than does ours, we will deem our labors in this line superfluous, and
                                    %CHtaxint<pb n="15" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 15 will unite with superior and
                                more perfect labors. Among hundreds of theologies, which excuse their adherents from
                                bearing their own crosses of self. denial ; which teach a reliance for salvation upon
                                the death of a man, rather than in the life of Christ, we raise our Standard ; and upon
                                this emblem there cannot be found any excuse for those who name Christ, or Christian,
                                from departing their sinful ways, and living as Jesus, the Christ, lived. Self-denial
                                was the saviour of Jesus ; and this made him Christ! Self-denial will be our saviour, if
                                we are ever saved from our sins. The call of the Spirit of Gk)d, through Christianity,
                                is : Let sin and the soul part company. Thus only can salvation be experienced. The
                                people of the world too generally look for a salvation from the punishment of their sins
                                ; but such will look in vain, until the causes are put away, that the effects, in
                                punishments, may cease. The Shaker Manifesto will prove itself a benefactor, if it
                                survives only to announce that there is no salvation, nor hopes of salvation, while
                                souls will live in sin ; that Christian salvation means living without sin, and unto a
                                resurrected life, " that is hidden with Christ's" in godliness. More than this : Our
                                testimony exceeds the boundaries of a testimony against a sinful life. It teaches a
                                better way than the good of a worldly life—of a progress unto a heavenly, Christ life,
                                where even the good of the worldly is relinquished for the unworldly. It treats of a
                                harvest of souls, of the which Christ is the harvestman, "and the angels are the
                                reapers;" and as fast as individuals are ripe for this harvest, they are enabled to rise
                                above the primal, animal plane of reproduction, into a life- pracfcice whose elements
                                contain none of the dust of a life in the flesh. "Freed from the law," because living
                                better than taught by the law. The Manifesto will announce Peace as better than the good
                                and best in War ; and while it will chastise the evils of private possessions, and
                                acknowledge the inferior good therein, it will urge as superior the communal life of the
                                heavens, from which the spirit of mine is banished. Under these colors, throw Ave our
                                flag to the breeze of the nations. Denouncing no good of the past—neither in Marriage,
                                Selfish Relations nor War—but rising above these, it bears on its folds the hopes and
                                possibility of a life on earth, of Virgin Celibacy, Nonresistance and Community of
                                G-oods. And is there not room for us, and need of our testimony ? And will not those
                                able to live Christ, receive it ? </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Present religious sensation" TEIform="index"/>THE PRESENT RELIGIOUS SENSATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Since the Prophetic Conference, lately held in New York city, the subject of Christ's
                                coming has been uppermost as a topic, riding on the religious waves of mind. Very many
                                believe in an early advent of the personal Jesus. If this is possible, why should any
                                object ? Many there are who believe that two advents have already been made; and are not
                                the additional appearances of so good an individual desirable, and the more the better ?
                                Among all the believers of Christ's coming, or of<pb n="16" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 16 THE SHAKES
                                MANIFESTO. his having come the second time, there is an unusual stir of anxiety upon the
                                subject. Yet amid the deep interest apparently manifested by many, we confess there is
                                only seen by us, a superficial position taken by the masses so believing, of the needs
                                and consequences of such a coming. The coming of Christ to Jesus, and by his testimony
                                the first time, the purpose was ft to save the people from their unchristian sins." He
                                came to some, delivered his testimony; lived, the pattern of a Christian; invited,
                                "follow me ;" and as the people followed him, so far they experienced the salvation he
                                came to bring, no further. Have the people learned and imitated the first edition of
                                Christianity so well, that a second is desired or demanded ? We trow not. Therefore,
                                many millions, who are clamoring for a second coming of the Lord, realize but little,
                                and practice less the purposes of the first advent. Do the people feel so desirous o$
                                being saved from their sinful and unchristian practices that they want Christ to come ?
                                Again, we avow not; else, why not accept of his self-denying testimony and life, and
                                gladly relinquish their abominable sins and worldly practices, which alone' hide Christ
                                from the soul, and prevent an oft appearance ? It is with sorrow that we testify that
                                the people love their sins ; do not wish to be parted from them ! When they shall hate
                                sin, and want to be saved from its practices, then we gladly testify Christ will come to
                                them ; hut never before ! The annunciation of Christianity has been made; the model for
                                Christians to pattern ; accepting the testimony, and living the life of Jesus, prepare
                                souls for further developments of the Christ; for many advents, and the more the better.
                                When people experience the purposes of Christ's first mission, they will reform their
                                lives, abstain from sin and practice that which Jesus' life presented. This will be the
                                evidence that the first appearance has been made; and until this evidence is given, let
                                none look with any hope for a second experience. How many millions have heard of
                                Christ's first appearance ! how very few know of that appearance by personally
                                experiencing the abiding of Christ's spirit! There cannot be a second until there, has
                                been a first. Who has experienced th.efirst? let such anticipate a second appearance of
                                Christ, and so on. True, Christ, that made its appearance to Jesus and disciples of auld
                                lang syne, will yet visit every soul, when prepared for the visitation. The evidence of
                                this visitation will be pro- claimed by conviction for sins, and a conversion into a
                                life that will resemble Christ in Jesus. True, a second advent will occur, " every eye
                                will see him" ; not simultaneously, but as soon as prepared by the testimony in life of
                                the first appearance. As the light gradually breaks upon the darkness ; as the warmth of
                                solar ray, progresses seasons and vegetation ; as the acquisition of learning and
                                experience, as the sickening tire of sinful life and earnest longings for power to live
                                as angels live; almost unconsciously, imperceptibly, but nevertheless certainly, will we
                                all yet find Christ "knocking" at the doors of our con-<pb n="17" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. sciences. " Then shall two men be in the field, two women grinding at the
                                mill," some here, others there, and many everywhere will receive a call—be taken from a
                                worldly life to see the Christian life they should live; while " one will be taken and
                                the other left"—while some will experience Christ, yet others will not, and remain yet
                                longer without a knowledge of the advent------such will be the phenomena of Christ's
                                comings. And if any would know what has become of those taken while others are yet left
                                to worldly practice------we suggest the idea that they have united themselves with the
                                Shakers, compared to eagles in Luke 17:37, and are "altogether " experiencing to-day in
                                truth, deed and life the much-looked for, Second Appeaeanoe of Cheist. </p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophetic convention" TEIform="index"/>THE PROPHETIC CONVENTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We promised a notice of our observations at the great gathering in New York on
                                    October 30, 31 and November 1. We had really hoped, until the last possible moment,
                                    to have met with several representatives of our Societies thereat; but we were
                                    reasonably mistaken, for every thing there having been pre-arranged, and the line of
                                    thought marked out for both speakers and hearers, there was no possible chance for
                                    any utterance differing from the demarcation, and therefore no necessity of sending
                                    representatives. The gathering was a notable one— several hundreds of ministers,
                                    repre- senting many denominations, being there and in sympathy—but as notable also
                                    by the absence of so many more prominent clergymen, and particularly those of New
                                    York city, who have no sympathy with premillennialism, being as we gladly and yet
                                    with astonishment learned, postmillennial in belief. The theories and dogmas which
                                    alone were permitted to be discussed at the Conference were the affirmative of 1.
                                    The personal coming of Jesus, again in the flesh ; 2. The resurrection of the
                                    physical body; 3. The final exaltation of believers, and condemnation of
                                    unbelievers. All of which, to those of us who believe that Christ has appeared again
                                    spiritually through others, is simply foolishness.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second or third?" TEIform="index"/>"SECOND OR THIRD?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Elihu Burritt has lately written a very sensible article in The Christian at Work in
                                    which he testifies that " I think we have a hundred fold stronger evidence of the
                                    second advent, than we have had of the first." Such utterances from such notables,
                                    are destined to awaken investigation, that may result in affixing the date of the
                                    second arrival in 1770 ! Let us all keep our eyes and ears open.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Will this be a happy year?" TEIform="index"/>WILL THIS BE A HAPPY YEAR?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In wishing all a happy year—the happiest of years—we would remind every one that the
                                    principal ingredi- ent in the composition of happiness is self-control, aye,
                                    self-denial. Even though this strikes chills through us, it is true. They are not
                                    happiest who do as they please, nor those who en17<pb n="18" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE
                                    SHAKER MANIFESTO. gage in the luxury of pleasures until surfeited by them. We are
                                    earnest in our interest for the greater, greatest happiness of the people ; and ass
                                    are all, who will give a few moments to the thoughts and practices of selfdenial to
                                    selfish indulgences, that their pleasures will be enhanced thereby. Christ Jesus was
                                    a good pattern ; as we picture the pattern on our minds, let us deny where he
                                    denied, and we will be happy like him.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chips" TEIform="index"/>CHIPS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Can it be that a little " wedge of gold," silver, copper or greenbacks is the
                                    splitting point between the circulation and non-circulation of the genuine gospel ?
                                    Be it known, that we have, and long have had, a noble, self-sacrificing friend in
                                    Melbourne, Australia, by name, W. H. Terry, publisher of The Harbinger of Light, 84
                                    Russell street. We hope all who read this will feel like sending him books, pam-
                                    phlets and subscriptions for his paper. We have sent him some " Plain Talks," and we
                                    wish some of our friends would send him fifty more. </p></div4><div4 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Rev. J. B. Gross..." TEIform="index"/>The Rev. J. B. Gross...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">The Albany Morning Express says : <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany morning press" TEIform="index"/></bibl><quote TEIform="quote">"The Rev. J. B. Gross, of Wilkesbarre, Pa., in a book upon ' The Parson
                                            on Dancing,' treats of it as an excellent means of praising God, as it
                                            enlists the feet in the service rendered by the tongue, hands and looks, and
                                            ought to be introduced into worship. Mr. Gross here stands on the Shaker
                                            platform.'' </quote></cit>The attempted agreement of Protestants and Roman Catholics again to introduce
                                    religious services into secular schools in New Haven, ought (as it has) to prove a
                                    failure. It is a Church and State wedge.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our patrons" TEIform="index"/>OUR PATRONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Please look over our advertising columns and see the array of respectable firms
                                    therein represented. We have been very choice in our selection of patrons to this
                                    department, and can vouch for their fair-dealing, generous qualities. The majority
                                    of them we have proved. Write them ; patronize them ; mention us.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Particular notice" TEIform="index"/>PARTICULAR NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The subscription price of The Manifesto is very low at sixty cents ; but we would be
                                    pleased to get two subscribers for One Dollar. When thinking of the good we would
                                    do, make a present of The Manifesto to some friend when you subscribe for yourself.
                                    In remitting we prefer money ; and in the absence of the very convenient "
                                    shinplaster," fractional currency, we advise sending six dimes for one subscription
                                    ; One Dollar bill for two subscriptions. </p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lying" TEIform="index"/>LYING</head><p TEIform="p">It is recorded in history that a certain philosopher of ancient times was one day asked,
                                " What does a man gain by telling a lie ?" " Not to be believed," said he, " even when
                                he speaks the truth." Young readers, bear in mind this answer of a wise man. A LITTLE
                                LOAF. Once, when there was a famine throughout the land, a rich man sent for the twenty
                                poorest children in the town to come to his house, and said to them : " In the basket
                                there is a little loaf for each of you. Take it, and come back to me every day at the
                                same hour till the good God sends us better times." Eagerly did the hungry children fall
                                upon the basket, and quarreled and struggled for the bread, because each wished to have
                                the best and largest; at last they went away without having even thanked the old
                                gentleman. But Gretchen, a poorly, but neatlydressed little maiden, remained standing
                                modestly in the distance; then she took the smallest loaf which alone was left in the
                                basket, gratefully kissed the rich gentleman's hand, and went quickly home. Next day the
                                children were just as ill-betiaved, and the poor, timid Gretchen received this time a
                                loaf which was scarcely half the "gixt €tyXxmf* (vatto.<pb n="19" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 19 size of the others. But when she came home and her sick mother cut the
                                loaf open many new silver pieces of money fell rattling and shining out of it. The
                                mother was not a little alarmed, and said : " Take the money at once back to the good
                                gentleman, for it certainly got into the dough by accident. Be quick, Grretchen ! be
                                quick ! " But when the little girl came to the rich man and gave him her mother's
                                message, he said, kindly: " No, no, my child, it was no mistake. I had the silver put
                                into the smallest loaf to reward you. Remain always as contented, peaceable,
                                self-denying and grateful. She who would rather take the smallest loaf than quarrel for
                                the larger ones, will obtain far richer blessings than even if money were baked into the
                                loaf. Go home now, and greet your good mother very kindly from me." LITTLE FOXES. One
                                little fox is " By-and-by." If you track him, you come to his hole—" Never." Another
                                little fox is " I can't." You had better set on him an active, plucky little thing, " I
                                can" byname. It does wonders. A third little fox is " No use in trying." He has spoiled
                                more vines, and hindered the growth of more fruit, than many a worse looking enemy. A
                                fourth little fox is " I forgot." He is very provoking. He is a great cheat. He slips
                                through your fingers like time. He is seldom caught up with. Fifth little fox is " Don't
                                care." Oh, what mischief he has done ! Sixth little fox is " No matter." It is matter
                                whether your life is spoiled by small faults. We must not deceive ourselves, for he that
                                overcometh not himself in little matters will not be able to do so in great things.
                                —Good News. THE HEAVENLY DEPOT. A boy of five years was " playing railroad " with his
                                sister of two and a half. Drawing her upon a footstool, he imagined himself both the
                                engine and the conductor. After imitating the puffing noise of the steam, he stopped and
                                called out " New York," and in a moment after " Paterson," and then " Philadelphia." His
                                knowledge of towns was now exhausted, and at the next place he cried " Heaven." His
                                little sister said eagerly, " Top, I des I'll det out here." THE THREE KULES. What is
                                the lowest rule of human conduct ? The Iron rule. What is the next higher rule ? The
                                Silver rule. What is the highest rule ? The Golden rule. What is the Iron rule 1 Evil
                                for evil. What is the Silver rule ? Good for good. What is the Golden rule ? Good for
                                evil. Why do you consider the Iron rule the lowest ? Because it is the expression of the
                                animal faculties of the mind, and the law of brutes and savages. Why is the Silver rule
                                better 1 Because it is the Golden rule one-half expressed. Why is the Golden rule the
                                highest and the best ? Because it is the essence of our spiritual perceptions of right;
                                and flowing from the highest faculties of our nature, must be the best guide in the
                                conduct of life. Hold on Boys.—Hold on to your tongue when you are just ready to swear,
                                lie or speak harshly, or use an improper word. Hold on to your hand when you are about
                                to punch, strike, scratch, or do any improper act. Hold on to your foot when you are on
                                the point of kicking, running off from study, or pursuing the path of error, shame or
                                crime. Hold on to your temper when you are angry, excited, or imposed upon, or others
                                are angry with you. Hold on to your heart when evil associations seek your company and
                                invite you to join in their mirth, games, or revels. Hold on to your good name in all
                                times, for it is of more value than gold, high Maces, or fashionable attire. Hold on to
                                the truth, for it will serve you well, and do you good throughout eternity.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="20" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society Record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Early manufacture of steel pens" TEIform="index"/>EARLY MANUFACTURE OF STEEL PENS</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of the Scientific American: I write to inquire if you can give me
                                information concerning the manufacture of metal pens in this country. I may be vain in
                                the supposition, but I am almost persuaded, that my people—the Shakers—were the
                                originators of metal pens. I write this to you with a silver pen,"one slit," that was
                                made in the year 1819 at this village by the Shakers. Two or three years previous to the
                                use of silver for pens, our people used brass plate for their manufacture, but soon
                                found silver preferable. Some of our people, now living, sold these pens in the year
                                1820 for 25 cents each, and disposed of all that could be made at that price. The
                                machinery for rolling the brass and silver plate was a home invention ; also the shears
                                for cutting the pens; these we still have in our possession. At the above date the
                                inventor writes : " I now have my new shears, with which I have cut 292 pens in 14
                                minutes ; this is doing it with dispatch ! " The metal used was melted silver coins ;
                                and at one time the worker says, " I melted up $55.00 or $60.00 of silver money." I find
                                the following in a late Boston paper: " English steel pens are almost entirely made by
                                women. In 1828-29 the first gross of ' three-slit' steel pens was sold wholesale at £7
                                4s. the gross. In 1830 they had fallen to 8s. and in 1832 to 6s, the gross. A better
                                article is now sold at 6d. per gross." I leave you to judge the merits of this pen from
                                the appearance of my chirography; and can assure you it has seen nearly sixty years'
                                service. The two I have in possession are equally good writers, and were presented to me
                                by my venerable friend, D. A. Bucking ham, who, 58 and more years ago, engaged in the
                                sale of pens. By giving me what information you are able I will be under many
                                obligations. I neglected to say that the handles to these pens were made of both wood
                                and tin ; the tin one I have is tubular and closes the pen telescopically.</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers" TEIform="index"/> Shakers,N. Y..</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>REPLY</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We find no record of the manufacture of metal pens in this country as early
                                        as 1820. At that time Gillott had begun to make steel pens in England. As early
                                        as 1803 barrel pens of steel were made by a Mr. Wise in England. Evidently Mr.
                                        Lomas writes with a good pen.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Scientific American" TEIform="index"/>Scientific American</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bates, Irene" TEIform="index"/>Irene Bates
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., Sept. 2, <persName reg="Bates, Irene" TEIform="persName">Irene Bates,</persName> aged
                                    54 years. (It is difficult to realize how the record of this peaceful sister's death
                                    has been delayed.)</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jacobs, Lucy" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Jacobs
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Nov. 14, <persName reg="Jacobs, Lucy" TEIform="persName">Lucy Jacobs</persName>,
                                    aged 78 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="King, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>Caroline King
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Mass., Nov. 18,1878, <persName reg="King, Caroline" TEIform="persName">Caroline
                                    King</persName>, aged 78 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lockwood, John" TEIform="index"/>John Lockwood
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Groveland, N. Y., Nov. 22, <persName reg="Lockwood, John" TEIform="persName">John
                                    Lockwood</persName>, aged 87 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Legrow, Erastus" TEIform="index"/>Erastus Legrow
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Poland Hill, Me., <persName reg="Legrow, Erastus" TEIform="persName">Erastus Legrow</persName>, aged
                                    43 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. The evidence of the superiority of spirit-power..." TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. The evidence of the superiority of spirit-power...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. The evidence of the superiority of spirit-power over earthly
                                impediments was simply, but prettily and satisfactorily illustrated at the recent
                                funeral of Lucy Jacobs, when one of the young sis- ters, an inveterate stammerer,
                                speaking under the influence of the deceased, addressed the assembly for half an hour,
                                without any impediment whatever. We will soon present a paper upon "Dried Corn " and its
                                introduction to the world as an article of merchandise by this society.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers,N. Y.. This society is known for its manufactures of brooms..." TEIform="index"/>Shakers,N. Y.. This society is known for its manufactures of brooms...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Shakers, N. Y. This society is known for its manufactures of brooms, brushes, dried and
                                hermetically sealed fruits and vegetables. Stock on hand equal to former years, both
                                quality and quantity. Hence proceed " Shaker Garden Seeds," which, according to the
                                analysis of Prof. Beal, of Michigan, stood best over all others tested —and there were
                                many tests. See Adv. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. This society is doing the handsome by Shakers, N. Y...." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. This society is doing the handsome by Shakers, N. Y....
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. This society is doing the handsome by Shakers, N. Y., and Mt.
                                Lebanon societies, in sparing from its number Marcia R. Hillsgrove, to teach music.
                                Vocal drills and organ practice as a j^jciettj Hjettfrtl<pb n="21" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/>
                                consequence are very lively in the latter societies. At Shaker Village, N. H., also
                                lives our ex-publisher, N. A Briggs—(than whom a nobler man does not exist ; and with
                                whom we have spent three years undisturbed by a ripple even)-who would be glad to
                                receive orders for power Shaker Washing Machines. It will be a great favor to us, for
                                any interested on the subject, to drop him a line requesting a descriptive pamphlet.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, O. In a previous number of The Manifesto we stated that a new barn ..." TEIform="index"/>North Union, O. In a previous number of The Manifesto we stated that a new barn...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">North Union, O. In a previous number of The Manifesto we stated that a new barn had been
                                erected at the " Middle Family ; " we should have written " Mill " Family, where a
                                beautiful structure for the Jower animals has been erected. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Restoring the drowned" TEIform="index"/>Restoring the drowned
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Restoring the drowned.—A New York physician says that any person who has not been in the
                                water more than two hours may be restored to life by thoroughly warming him. Wrap the
                                body in a blanket or quilt and pour hot water on it, and continue to do so until the
                                subject revives. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ribbons and silks" TEIform="index"/>Ribbons and silks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Ribbons and silks.—Ribbons and other silks should be put away for preservation in brown
                                paper; the chloride of lime used in manufacturing white paper frequently pro- duces
                                discoloration. A white satin dress should be pinned in blue paper, with brown paper
                                outside, sewn together at the edges. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A lady has found the following remedy..." TEIform="index"/>A lady has found the following remedy...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A lady has found the following remedy for the prevention of bed bugs : After cleaning the
                                bedstead thoroughly, rub it over with hog's lard. The lard should be rubbed on with a
                                woolen cloth. Bugs will not infest such a bedstead for a whole season. The reason for
                                this is the antipathy of insects for grease of any kind. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove putty from glass..." TEIform="index"/>To remove putty from glass...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To remove putty from glass, dip a small brush in nitric or muriatic acid, and with it
                                paint over the dry putty that adheres to the broken glasses and frames of the windows
                                After an hour's interval the putty will have become so soft as to be easily
                            removable.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winter reflections" TEIform="index"/>WINTER REFLECTIONS</head><p TEIform="p">It is difficult to make people understand that food in animals, as well as in plants, is
                                largely derived from the air, and that good pure air can only supply what nature demands
                                from the atmosphere. Muddy and filthy barns turn out lean cattle. Farmers should
                                remember that we keep cows for their milk particularly. The warmer they are kept, the
                                more milk they will give, and with much less feed. Keep them warm. Socrates wrote:
                                "Agriculture is an employment the most worthy the application of man, the most ancient
                                and the most suit- able to his nature. It is the common nurse of persons in every age
                                and condition in life ; it is the source of health, strength, plenty, and riches, and of
                                a thousand sober delights and honest pleasures. It is the mistress and school of
                                sobriety, temperance, justice, religion and, in short, of all virtues."</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing clover in winter" TEIform="index"/>SOWING CLOVER IN WINTER</head><p TEIform="p">Clover seed may be sown upon the snow, or when a frost has hardened the surface. One
                                great advantage of sowing upon the snow is that a very even spread can be made, as the
                                seed can readily be seen, and the foot marks remain as a guide for the next breadth
                                sowed. The most inexperienced need make no lapse or misses. A good quantity of seed for
                                each cast is as much as can be held between the first and second fingers and the thumb.
                                Walking at an easy gait, this will use up about eight quarts of seed per acre. If the
                                wind is blowing, walk so that it blows across the path ; the effect is then equal both
                                going and returning ; but it is not so if it blows first on the face and then on the
                                back. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="About 'Sunday corn'" TEIform="index"/>ABOUT "SUNDAY CORN."</head><p TEIform="p">A man out west recently boasted that his two acres of " Sunday corn," on which. all the
                                work had been done on Sunday and which yielded seventy bushels to the acre, upset the
                                Bible idea that Sunday work xxtultuxxl.<pb n="22" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                never prospers. To this the editor of an agricultural paper replied thus: " If th author
                                of this shallow nonsense had read the Bible half as much as he has the works of its
                                opponents, he would have known that the great Euler of the universe does not always
                                square up his accounts with mankind in the month of October." </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poems of the life beyond and within" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stebbins, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">POEMS OF THE LIFE BEYOND AND WITHIN. Beautifully tinted paper. Compiled by Giles B.
                                Stebbins. Such is the title of some very fine selections of poetry, extending back to
                                the days of Hindoo Veda, and embodying some of the finest sentiments of well-known
                                poets, dead and living. Great skill has been manifested by the compiler in securing the
                                best poetic thoughts of the most respectec poets. To very many such a book would be
                                esteemed one of the brightest gems that could grace the literary repository. In it we
                                find no mediocre sentiments ; and surely none of low degree. The aim of the editor can
                                clearly be seen—that it was to present a superior collection of emotions, rhythmically
                                expressed, to displace, if possible, the inferior line of poems. Colby &amp; Rich, 9
                                Montgomery Place, Boston, are the publishers. It can be obtained through this office for
                                $1.50. harper's school geographies. The firm of Harper &amp; Brothers have certainly
                                produced the most comprehensive series of geographies yet issued from any press in the
                                country. As a whole, the series are unequaled ; and their particular good feature of
                                representing the peculiar features and advantages of each State—the State in which the
                                book is used—is assuredly a preeminent one. "THE BRIEF EXPOSITION." This little work
                                upon our faith and principles has ever been acknowledged as standard. The last editions
                                having been exhausted, and in consideration of the great value of the work, the Society
                                of Canterbury has undertaken the issue of a large edition. We hope all friends will,
                                according to their interests, aid in the enterprise. Send five cents to this office for
                                specimen copy.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science" TEIform="index"/>Science and Mechanics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Softening files" TEIform="index"/>Softening files
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Softening Files.—Cover them with oil and hold them over the fire until the oil blazes; as
                                soon as the flame runs all over the file, plunge it into the water. Or put them. in*a
                                moderate hot oven for half an hour, if large files; but if small files the first plan is
                                the best. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following method is used in Germany..." TEIform="index"/>The following method is used in Germany...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The following method is used in Germany, for the preservation of wood; mix 40 parts
                                chalk, 50 resin, 4 linseed oil, melting them together in an iron pot ; then add 1 part
                                native oxide of copper, and afterward 1 part sulphuric acid.—Apply with a brush. When
                                dry thi3 varnish is as hard as stone. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement to withstand heat" TEIform="index"/>Cement to withstand heat
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cement to Withstand Heat.—The following is an iron cement which is unaffected by
                                red-heat; four parts, by weight, iron filings, two parts clay, one part fragments of a
                                Hessian crucible ; reduce to the size of rape seed and mix together, working the whole
                                into a stiff paste with a saturated solution of salt. A piece of fire-brick can be used
                                instead of the Hessian crucible. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hardening springs" TEIform="index"/>Hardening springs
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Hardening Springs. — Get a piece of spring steel about the size of spring wanted ; when
                                forged and filed to suit, make it warm red, immerse in spring water, dry the spring,
                                then tie a piece of wire fast to the spring in any form, so as to hold it; dip in clean
                                tallow or oil, put it on the fire until all the grease is burned off, and then swing it
                                round and round, as swift as you can, until cold.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Engineers' cement" TEIform="index"/>Engineers' cement
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Engineers' Cement.—Mix ground whiteead with as much finely powdered red lead is will make
                                it the consistency of soft putty. Another is to mix equal parts of white lead and red
                                lead, and add as much boiled lineed oil as is required to give it the required
                                consistency ; or boiled linseed oil and red ead mixed into putty. These cements are used
                                for making metallic points sound.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A clergyman asked some children, 'Why do we say in the Lord's prayer'..." TEIform="index"/>A clergyman asked some children, 'Why do we say in the Lord's prayer'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A clergyman asked some children, "Why o we say in the Lord's prayer, ' who art in leaven,'
                            since God is everywhere ? " A litle drummer boy answered, " Because it's headquarters."</p></div2><pb n="23" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loyalty" TEIform="index"/>LOYALTY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., M. R." TEIform="persName"/>M. R. H.</byline><p TEIform="p">Bellicozamente. Canterbury, N. H. 1. We're marching, marching, for we've heard the 2. We're
                            fearless, fearless, tho we've en e trumpet sound. We're hastening, mies to slay. No
                            weakness, hastening, eweakness, is quipped for the battle ground. We're loy bearing arms
                            today. We're work-<pb n="24" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. al, ins:, loyal to the banner
                            that we bear; working for the kingdom and the crown; the we We're trusting, trusting in
                            We're joyful, joyful as Father's promised lay our own lives care, down.</p></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements Deleted] </p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>