<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2507" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18950701" TEIform="date">July 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">147-169</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
JULY.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
" Cast thy brbad upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days.0
Eccl. XI : I.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
The Mission of Shakerism,         ...      147
Hannah Bronson,              .....   149
Address to Old Age,                     -      -      -      122
Letter,Nancy L. Rupe,         -       .       -       -   153
Adventure among the Uosicrucians No. 2'     154
Social Improvement Society,                -       -   15o
Aggressive Christianity,             -       -       -      158
Music,I look to Thee,                                    -   100
Notes about Home,         ...       -       -      161
Practical Self-denial                ....   165
Exchange,.......      166
In M( ni >ry of P. Van Houtou        -       -       -     "
Acrostic,            .......        "
What are the Wild Waves saying,       -      -   167
Snow-drops,              ......      168
Feeling in Religion,          -       -       -       -       -     "
The Right of Self-defence,          ...      169
Deaths,           -       -       -       .       -       -       -       -   170
Books & Papers,            .....        "
SKJRADEMARks
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTATN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN & CO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
Issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work In the
world.  S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, tiS cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New York, 361 Broadway.
AGENTS_wanteo
Salary or commission to good men.
Fast selling Imported Specialties.
Stock falling to lire replace! free,
Also Pure Seed. Potato Stock our
Specialty Leader.
Address   R. D. LUTCHFORD &  CO.,
jcvTTiEt sue: aEfsraaciE 3v.
(Letters promptly answered.)  ROCHESTER, N. Y.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
-i
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic    Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINE MFG. CO., Phila., Pa.
This it a good thimjEd.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per year, devoted to PHEEN0L0GY,
PHYSIOGNOMY.  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEF0EM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
WANTED
RELIABLE MEN to sell
our choice and complete
line of Nursery Stock.
Highest salary and commission paid weekly, paying permanent position
guaranteed and success assured to good men.
Special inducements to beginners, experience,
not necessary. Exclusive territory and your
own choice of same given.   Do not delay.
Apply to
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
WANTED!
Agent to sell our new book, Dictionary of
United States History, by Prof. J. Franklin Jameson. Needed by every1 teacher, pu.
pil, and family; indorsed. Agents selling fifty books per week. Successful agents will
be made general agents.   Big: pay.
PURITAN PUBLISHING CO., Boston. Mass.--><pb n="147" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mission of shakerism" TEIform="index"/>THE MISSION OF SHAKERISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">i4T I ^0 every one has been given a measure of the Spirit of God." Can -L we doubt that the
                            spiritual truths set forth in the Shaker system are a portion of that Spirit? Can we doubt
                            that it has a God appointed mission to humanity? We think not. We have been accused, and
                            perhaps truthfully so, of hiding our light under a bushel. We may be at fault for the
                            widespread ignorance concerning our faith; but being a spiritual people, is it not, as Paul
                            declared unto the Corinthians? "The natural man discerneth not the things of the Spirit." In
                            this day all things pertaining to human welfare are subject to the most unsparing test of
                            investigation ; let us search and see what panacea for the ills of suffering humanity we can
                            offer. The foundation stone upon which the structure of Shakerism rests, the primal
                            principle that has held the system intact, is Virgin Purity, or in other words, a life of
                            celibacy. This principle has been kept unsullied for over one hundred years of successful
                            communism. How often are we confronted with the cry, "If all should become Shakers the race
                            would become extinct." But we believe the great sin of the age is the destructive force of
                            sensualism, and~'only by a return to the law of God through chastity in the relationship of
                            men and women, can human beings be delivered from the curses of want and disease, and the
                            great train of evils that so afflict modern society. "An angel came out of the temple crying
                            with a great voice to him who sat on the white cloud : send forth thy sickle"and reap, for
                            the harvest of the world is over-ripe ; and he who sat on the white cloud (purity) cast his
                            sickle upon the earth and the earth was reaped." We hold that Virgin celibacy is the harvest
                            of the world, and celibate communities, the garners into which the JULY <pb n="148" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 148 THE MANIFESTO. "wheat shall be gathered. When at least a small portion of earth's
                            inhabitants realize, that a life of Virgin purity is the higher lifethe God-like
                            lifecertainly there must be a law and purpose in it. Another primal principle is communism,
                            patterned after the Pentecostal Church. A community is the outgrowth of the divine in man;
                            it cin not exist in the worldly order, because the emotions and affections of the natural
                            man are antagonistic to it; it can only be sustained by being built upon the "Rock,"Christa
                            divine life, "loving the neighbor at the expense of self." Does not this present an ideal
                            vision to the soul? men and women who have gaiiKd the mastery over selfishness; risen above
                            all sordid and grasping ambitions; so inspired with a sublime love for others, that they
                            consecrate all they possess to the good of all, thus inaugurating upon earth that Kingdom of
                            Hi aven for which souls in all ages have prayed. In the distressing conditions that are an
                            outgrowth of our present system of civilization, we discern the vast fruitage of
                            selfishness; it is the mainspring of our savage competition, running through all industrial
                            systems, and its direful results, poverty and crime, are yet to be confronted by the higher
                            law of love. Here we see little communities, like green oases, dotting the land in various
                            sections, which have not only been delivered from wrong effects, but are removing the causes
                            and environments that produced them. Surely, this alone holds the "prophecy of better
                            things" for struggling humanity. We can but present a birds-eye view upon a few minor
                            points. Never having had a written creed we are not bound by any theological dogma;
                            believing in a continual revelation from Grod as the Spirit prepares human hearts to receive
                            it. Our religion, therefore, not only contains a vital element of progress, but we are ready
                            to accept the broadest interpretation of life, in the light of the highest truth. We believe
                            in God as Father and Mother, Wisdom and Love. This is not a strange idea, when all through
                            nature we perceive two distinct forces, positive and negative; from the centripetal and
                            centrifugal forces that hold the stars in their orbits, to the lowest forms of animal life.
                            When the maternal principle of Deity is universally recognized, we shall have more of the
                            love of God in the soul. Some one has said, that the civilization of a nation is known by
                            the development of its women. In a Shaker home the Sisters stand on a perfect equality with
                            their Brethren in all the affairs of life, both temporal and spiritual. The ballot has not
                            procured them their rights, but it is the liberty of Christ that has made them free and
                            equal, no rich, no poor, no high, no low; it is the virginity of their souls that has
                            enfranchised them. Is humanity prepared to receive the philosophy of Shakerism ? It is
                            neither fanaticism nor asceticism, but stands a bulwark against the surging, engulfing
                            flood-tide of sensuality;stands for the broadest interpretation of life, and for the fullest
                            unfoldment of the soul in the light of the Divine. Shak- <pb n="149" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 149 erism has given to the world a spiritual impulse. None can measure the force
                            of that divine, esoteric power that has gone, and is still going out from silent
                            unostentatious lives. There have been those among us, who, clothed with the prophet's
                            mantle, have foretold of a time when a wave of Pentecostal baptism would descend upon
                            humanity; then souls would flock to our homes as "doves to the windows ;" and we have been
                            waiting, (but not with folded hands,) for the fulfillment of the prophecy, that "God would
                            pour out his spirit upon all flesh." God and the angel world are rolling away the rock of a
                            base sensuality from the sepulcher.of the sleeping spirit; and obedient to the voice of
                            Omnipotent Love, it is coming forth in the renewed power of a risen humanity." Surely "old
                            things are passing away and all things are becoming new." In the many inquiries coming from
                            near and from distant lands, concerning our faith, principles and order of life, we have an
                            evidence that there is to be a renewal of the Christ baptism in another form. Our hearts and
                            our homes stand ready and open to receive the sin-sick and Godward aspiring soul, and fain
                            would we reach out our hands to bemired and struggling humanity. The call is,Come and
                            partake of the spiritual treasures stored up in the Kingdom of God. Shaker Communities are
                            established for the redemption of the race, and whosoever will may come. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hannah Bronson" TEIform="index"/>
                            HANNAH BRONSON.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following article has been put in type agreeably to
                            the system of "The Spelling Reform Association," as found in "The Standard Dictionary." Ed.]
                            SUM one has been so interested in the "Address to Old Age," that was written by Sister Hannah
                            Bronson as to send it to us for publication. In memory of the dear Sister, who for many
                            years gave her life to God and to his people, we shal not only find a place for these few
                            lines but wil ad other interesting matter for the pleasure of many of the frends still
                            living who bear in fond remembrance the subject of this skech. Hannah Bronson was born in
                            the town of Norwich, Vt., Jan. 13, 1781. Fortunately for us we hav found sum autobiografical
                            notes which wil aid us very much in the illustration. "In my childhood I became frightend
                            when I lernd that everybody must die, and askt my mother if I should certainly die. My
                            mother very thoughtfully answerd, "Yes, my child, but if you ar a good girl and wil say the
                            Lord's prayer every night, you wil be happy after death and go to heaven." I carefully
                            regarded this advice for several weeks, but as I grew older I joind in the foolish
                            conversation of idle companions and became careless. In a dream I saw that the day of
                            judgment had alredy commenct, and <pb n="150" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 150 THE MANIFESTO. that I should
                            soon be calld to giv an account of how I had spent my time. I had red in the Bible that for
                            every idle word I must render a full account, and I knew I had spoken a great many, and that
                            for several years there was not much change. When I had reacht the age of seventeen years I
                            felt a conviction for wrong doing, and obtaind sum relief by again carefully reading the
                            Bible. At this time I made a resolv to forsake all my sinful ways. I attended the church as
                            often as 1 could, but its great distance from my home prevented my attendance only at long
                            intervals. Once while engage! in prayer and asking to know the wil of God, the spirit gav me
                            this answer, "Deny yourself, take up the cross and follow me." In 1798 I was baptized and
                            enterd the church with a full purpose of giving my heart to God, and in this I found a
                            measure of salvation. Subsequently I lernd of a revival that was being held but a few miles
                            distant from my home. I was anxious to attend, and to my surprize, found that sum of the
                            members of the Shaker Community had been present. On lerning that sum of the pepl had
                            accepted the faith as taught by the Shakers, I felt very sorry, as I had herd that the
                            Shakers were sadly deluded. Indeed, I was strongly prejudist against them, and yet was at
                            the same time quite anxious to hear them for myself. I now made arrangements with one of our
                            neighbors to inform me should the Shakers cum into that vicinity again. My father also
                            wanted to see and hear the Shakers, and in this he was like the Athenians, who were always
                            interested in new things. On the loth of January, 1799, several persons from the Communities
                            of Canterbury and Enfield were invited to our house, by my father. As they were engagd in
                            conversation I listend very attentivly. When opportunity offerd I also converst with the
                            Shakers and brought forward all the objections that occurcl to my mind, stil believing them
                            to be sadly in error in regard to a religious faith and life. The Shakers were very social
                            and plezant and wanted me to understand fully the object of their mission. On leaving us
                            they invited those present to visit them at their home in Enfield, and as sum of my frends
                            were expecting to make them a visit, I was invited to be one of the company. This visit
                            changd my mind, and I found myself among beutifully anticipated frends and became so wel
                            pleased in this new home that I had no wish to return to Norwich. However, I did return to
                            attend to sum bizness that was left unfinisht. Many of my frends and relativs were much
                            opposd to the course I had taken. My dres, my language and my religious observances were all
                            objectionabl. Two persons who had formerly livd with the Shakers, came to see me. One was
                            bitterly oppozd and made a great many unplezant remarks about my Shaker frends, while the
                            other spoke kindly of the pepl. A family living about one half mile from my father's had
                            joind the Shak- <pb n="151" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 151 ers, and were holding meetings in
                            their house. I visited them that I might attend the meetings. A storm detaind me from Sunday
                            til Tuesday, and when I reacht home my father and frends could hardly wait for each other,
                            in their anxiety to oppoz me. As I could find no place for an answer, I quietly busied
                            myself with sum work. A younger brother changd the subject by reading a few passages from
                            the Scriptures, and their reverence for the Book had, at this time, a good effect. In 1800
                            my brother and his family united with the Believers. I obtaind board with him and gave
                            instruction to his children and to those of another family. 1 subsequently movd into the
                            family of Bennett Libbey, in Strafford who livd at a distance of seven miles., Bennett was
                            very kind and his charity was unbounded. After the Believers had lernd that Bennett would
                            like to enter one of the Societies they made arrangements to cum to Strafford on the 3rd of
                            March, 1801 and assist us in the moving of our goods. We reacht Enfield quite late on
                            Saturday p. in. and remaind there til Monday, when we drove on to Canterbury. Bennett movd
                            into the house formerly owned by the Muffetts' and I reremaind as one of the family. After
                            being here a few weeks I movd into the family of Joshua Wright, at the "West Place," and was
                            appointed to teach the children of the Believers. As there was no scool-houz at this date I
                            was accommodated with a room in the blacksmith shop. As the opportunity for attending scool
                            was very limited thruout the town, the Believers were obligd to accommodate themselvs as
                            best they could for the benefit of their children. As a general thing they could spare but a
                            few hours in a day and but few weeks in a year for purposes of education. The pupils at the
                            Church family, were no better accommodated than were those in the smaller families, and it
                            was not til 1823 that the Community felt abl to bild a scool-houz and conduct the scool
                            agreeably to the town law. At the opening of the next term a much better place was provided,
                            and the scool was kept in one of the rooms of the family dweling. My next mov was into the
                            family of James Fisher to teach his children. As was the custom I movd from place to place
                            as occasion required. In 1805 I movd into the family of Jeremiah Garland. Here I kept the
                            scool on the driving floor of the barn. As the place was destitute of furniture, the
                            children were seated on the floor, except those who were fortunate enuf to find a box or a
                            block of wood. These children, in the summer scool did not weary themselvs with multiplid
                            studies, but had primers, Webster's speling book and the New Testament. Ink was too expensiv
                            to be bought, and what little was used was made from the berries found in the pasture. Very
                            little time, however, was given even by the oldest pupils to penmanship. <pb n="152" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 152 THE MANIFESTO. A short time, each day, was spent in the setting of card teeth, so
                            that the boys when tired of study were not left in idlness. The employment of children at
                            sum kind of work was not uncommon in the District scool, and the girls often biought their
                            sewing and knitting work. The time for play was generally during the intermission at noon.
                            This season I was taken sick and for several weeks was not expected to live. Thru the care
                            of a kind Providence and loving frends, however, I recivd a healing gift on the 16th of May,
                            and on the following Sunday attended religious service with the family. On receiving this
                            gift I refusd al medicin, and on the fiist day of June collected al the pils, powders,
                            drops, and lotions, and carried them to the physicians who had orderd them. Several persons
                            calld to see me, and were surprizd at my sudden recuvery. Dea. Zadock Wright said he was as
                            pleasd to see me, as he would be to see the President of the U. S.; it seemd so like a
                            miraculous recuvery. While living in the family of Brother Garland we attended religious
                            service at the West family, twice each week, and the walk up that steep hil to my home,
                            after a long evening meeting, seemd a great deal farther than it did going down. In 1806 I
                            taught scool in the West family and occupied a room in the laundry. I again became a member
                            of the family, and was appointed to care for the sick. My first patient was a daughter of
                            Bennett Libbey. She was fifteen years of age and wasting away with consumption. After
                            suffering for another month she past quietly to her rest. My care for the sick requird my
                            constant attention and much of the time, both day and night. On moving to the North Family
                            in 1818 I continued my labors at the Infirmary, and for several years, made this my only
                            buziness." Hannah Bronson was a beautiful sister in the Shaker Community. Her mind was of
                            the first quality. She possesst a fund of information, and took great plezure in extending
                            the same to others. She was gifted as a poetess and the Society has often shard the
                            blessings of her thoughts from her pen. In 1836 she was appointed Eldress of the Novitiate
                            order, which place she held with honor, til age and failing helth obligd her to find a place
                            of retirement from so many arduous dutes. Her life so peacefully wrought out, clozd
                            plezantly on the 23rd of Feb. 1870 at the age of 89 yrs. lmo. and 10 days.</p><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address to old age" TEIform="index"/>ADDRESS TO OLD AGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bronson, Hannah" TEIform="persName"/>By Hannah Bronson.</byline><p TEIform="p">(Age 74 Trs.) Age, what art thou doing? why art thou so bold, To rob us of reason and
                                sense, when we're old? Oh, spare us our senses, our ears and our eyz, And pray, let some
                                smaller privations suffice. <pb n="153" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 153 Is not this
                                sufficient to shackl the frame, And make us decrepit and feebl and lame? And cause all
                                our hairs to be frosted and white? Oh, spare us our sensez, our hearing and sight. But
                                if 'tis our lot to be lame, def or blind Pray have sum compassion at least on the mind;
                                And altho the system may lose all its tone, Pray don't touch the intellect,let that
                                alone. "Old Age" comes along with his stamping machine, And sets on his marks,
                                unperceivd and unseen, And altho unheeded we scarcely know how, Is stamping the wrinkls
                                of age on our brow. All this we can bear and feel fully resignd; But pray do not fetter
                                and hamper the mind! With many privations we'll cheerfully bear, But don't take our
                                sensezwe hav none to spare. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Greetings to our precious little craft, its kind Pilot, and crew..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Greetings to our precious little craft, its kind Pilot, and crew...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, Pleasant Hill, May 26, 1895" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky. May 26,
                                1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Greetings to our precious little craft, its kind Pilot, and crew. Recently through the
                                kindness of Elder A. G. Hollister, I was the recipient of a number of valuable tracts,
                                so clearly exemplifying the life teachings of Jesus, the Christ, that it is surprising
                                that people seeking truth and salvation from sin, can not see it. Of coarse it means a
                                daily sacrifice and constant prayer, yet thousands have lived it, and do now, I trust,
                                and are numbered with the hundred, forty and four thousand virgins, who are redeemed
                                from the earth. That virgin life ! so singular to the majority, even though it was lived
                                by our Savior and who even declared that except we forsake the relations of the flesh,
                                father, mother, wife and children, we can not become one of his disciples. Upon this
                                principle the church of Christ is founded. It is the communion of our Lord, where all of
                                our possessions belong to the Lord, in which we can have no selfish interest. In
                                obedience to this system, our Church has prospered in all temporal and spiritual
                                blessings. The Church was to be the home of those who were convicted of the sins of the
                                world. It was free for the rich and poor; children were to be cared for in the
                                admonition of the Lord. The selfish and ignorant wonder at the choice that the Believers
                                have made. Their sense is wholly absorbed in the duties of a husband, a wife <pb n="154" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 154 THE MANIFESTO. and children. We have the record that Jesus was
                                tempted in all points as were his brethren, and is it reasonable to suppose that his
                                disciples will escape, the same trials? "Be of good cheer," said he. "I have overcome
                                the world." And the overcoming of the world is to forsake the relations which form it.
                                Your Sister in Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy L. Rupe.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Adventure among the rosicrucians, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>
                            ADVENTURE AMONG THE ROSICRUCIANS, NO 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hartmann, Franz" TEIform="persName"/>By Franz Hartmann.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by William C. Ayer.]
                            BUT it is also true that ignorance and conceit are closely connected together, and that the
                            ignorant hate him who is wiser than they. If one man, knowing more about the requirements of
                            his nature, and desirous to employ all his energies for the attainment of a higher state,
                            were to dai*e to assert his manhood and to rebel against the chains of fashion, could he
                            continue to live unmolested in his community? and if he were to emigrate to another, would
                            he not be exposed there to the same troubles? He would still come in contact with men who
                            hated the light because they were educated in darkness, who would misunderstand him, suspect
                            his motives, and persecute him; and woe to him if he had any human failings upon which the
                            snake of slander could fasten its poison fangs. Wherever darkness exists, there exists
                            abhorrence of light. Where ignorant man enters, there enter his imperfections. Wherever
                            ignorance resides, there are her attending angels, suspicion, envy and fear. Would it not be
                            more within the scope of true science to enlighten man about his true nature, than to invent
                            theories regarding the causes of phenomena which she does not know and which she can not
                            prevent? "That which is almost impossible by the unaided efforts of a single individual, may
                            often easily be accomplished by the co-operation of many, and this law seems to prevail in
                            all departments of nature. If a sufficient number of people were determined to retire from
                            the harlequin stage of the world and to turn away from the tomfooleries of a fashionable
                            existence, they may if they can harmonize with each other, form a power sufficiently strong
                            to repel the attacks of the monster which would devour them all if they were all separated
                            and unaided by each other. ' 'There have been at previous times as there are now, numerous
                            people who became convinced that there was a higher and inner life, and who desired to
                            surround themselves with such conditions as were most favorable for its attainment. Such
                            people were not merely to be found in Christian countries, but also among the 'heathen;' and
                            thousands of years ago lamaseries <pb n="155" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 155 and lodges,
                            orders, monasteries, convents, and places of refuge have been established, where people
                            might strive to attain a higher life, unimpeded by the aggressions and annoyances of the
                            external world of illusions. Their original purpose was beyond a doubt very recoinmendable.
                            If in the course of time many such institutions have become degraded and lost their original
                            character; if instead of being places for the performance of the noblest and most difficult
                            kind of labor, they have become places of refuge for the indolent, idle and superstitious ;
                            it is not the fault of that principle which first caused such institutions to be organized,
                            but it is the consequence of the knowledge of the true nature of man and his powers and
                            destiny having been lost, and with the loss of that knowledge the means for the attainment,
                            the original aim was naturally lost and forgotten. "Such a degradation took place in Europe,
                            especially during and after the Middle Ages when, enriched by robberies and endowed by dying
                            thieves who wanted to buy salvation, they amassed great wealth and lived a luxurious life,
                            feasting on the fat of the land. They then knew nothing more of the conditions of a higher
                            existence; they became centers of attraction for the hypocrite and the idle. They passed
                            away their idle hours in pious amusements and in striving to gain material wealth. Instead
                            of being centers from which blessings should spread over the'country, they became a plague
                            to the land. They robbed the rich and vampire-like, they sucked the last drop of blood out
                            of the poor. They continued in this manner until the cup of their crimes was full, when the
                            great Reformation caused the downfall of many and the reform of the rest.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social improvement society" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>(Leading paper by Catherine Allen.)</byline><p TEIform="p">Question. HOW far is it the duty of Believers, and to what extent will it be profitable for
                            them to co-operate with and sustain the various reform movements of the outside world, and
                            through what means should they co-operate? Answer. As a people, we believe we have received
                            revelations of spiritual truth which in some lines are in advance of any other religious
                            body, and this truth gives us power to lay the ax at the root of evil, which enables us to
                            live that new life wherein are embodied, as a whole, most of the reforms now in progress
                            among mankind. If this be true, we can only maintain our rightful position by leading the
                            religious thought of the world, which is always progressive; for it is only the husk of
                            theology which grows old, while in the kernel of true religion inheres a vitality which will
                            eternally renew and expand itself in the life of humanity, ever evolving from the dogmatic
                            and <pb n="156" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 15 6 THE MANIFES TO. superstitious to the rational and
                            comprehensive. If we have received light, is it for ourselves alone? is it not our duty to
                            let it shine? Every evil is a form of bondage. If we have found emancipation from one or
                            from many evils, then in obedience to the command to k'love one another," should we not do
                            all in our power to disenthrall our brother man? As part of the great life of humanity it is
                            impossible for us to advance alone. No separate good can an}'where exist, we can only live
                            by loving, by serving one another; therefore is it not vitally necessary to our existence as
                            a people to interest ourselves in every movement which tends toward reform and the general
                            progress of the race? As to active co-operation therewith, some will say;"We are too few in
                            number; too limited in means and not sufficiently educated in the required measure for
                            public work, either to honor our cause or to be helpful to those whom we would gladly
                            assist. Others may remind us of our calling to "come out and be separate" from the world,
                            fearing lest sympathetic action, even in a good cause, would lead us to condescend to the
                            standards of the earthly order and so we would lose sight of our own especial work. These
                            objections we will separately consider. First :As to our being few in number. The strength
                            of principle is not measured by the number of those who sustain it. One on the side of truth
                            is always a majority. We believe that to us has been revealed a testimony in whose potency
                            is the hope of the world for salvation ; should we not therefore embrace every opportunity
                            to publish it? and through channels most favorable for reaching leading minds such as would
                            open to us through efforts to support the many worthy movements of our time ? Second:Are we
                            too limited in means ? Shall we cozily enjoy the accumulated comforts which have been
                            bequeathed us through the sacrifices of those who sought "first the kingdom of heaven," and
                            in our abundance allow material interests to absorb those of a higher nature? If so, the
                            earth will kindly give us a burial place, while another people, braver, truer and less
                            selfish will herald our testimony to the world. Third :It is true that, as a people long
                            accustomed to seclusion, we are not at present educated in those lines which are necessary
                            to give us a leading or even helpful influence, where we would be glad to add our strength.
                            This is because so few among us have recognized our relation and duty to the outside world,
                            or have kept sufficiently informed of the many living themes and organized efforts for human
                            advancement, to be in touch with the new thought, new modes of expression and of action,
                            which would be essential for successful co-operation with leading minds of to-day. We must
                            allow our customs and habits of thought and life to be remolded, not in conformity to the
                            spirit of the world, but by the progressive spirit of the age, while we renew the sources of
                            spiritual life within ourselves, by studying and applying more closely those divine truths
                            which alone are the vitality of our Order. <pb n="157" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANCFESTO. 157 The
                            longer we refrain from this and from active expressions of sympathy with such movements as
                            tend to raise the standard of life in any direction, the less capacity we will have for
                            united action in our Community, and the less opportunity to make our life and principles
                            known to that of people to whom we look for the perpetuation of our Societies, also the less
                            prepared we will be to receive such as members. Fourth :Of the objection to assimilation
                            with the world. We think that the love of truth and of humanity which gives impulse to the
                            reformer, and that self-denial which is the underlying principle of every true reform, are
                            not of the world, but of the Christ spirit. All good is from the great central Good, the
                            goal of every progressive movement. Shall we then receive harm by affiliated effort with
                            those who are thus prompted? Lastly :By what means shall we co-operate with or sustain the
                            various movements with which we are in sympathy ? We suggest, by writing articles for such
                            publications as give them voice ; when petitions are to be presented to the Legislature or
                            to Congress, to sign our own names and use our influence to get signers among outside
                            friends; by cultivating ourselves in a clear and concise expressions of opinions so that we
                            ma}T occasionally be acceptable speakers at conventions. Although in intellectual
                            attainments we can not at present approach many of the workers in the fields of reform,
                            nevertheless there are many well organized societies who would gladly enroll us as honorary
                            or contributing members. They would look to us as a stronghold of moral and spiritual
                            strength if we would but extend to them the hand of fellowship. Could we not thus increase
                            our power for good without in any degree participating in the worldly spirit of party strife
                            and division, or otherwise departing from our most pure and holy faith? Are we fulfilling
                            our calling, or can we consider our past existence successful, if by the efforts of more
                            than a century there has not been conserved enough individual strength and vitality to
                            enable us now to take this step in advance ? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Since the days of the Reformation..." TEIform="index"/>Since the days of the Reformation...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Since the days of the Reformation the forces of truth have operated powerfully as a
                            desintegrating element. To-day these are manifest in the rapid organization of centers for
                            mutual sympathetic action;the building process.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>G. Allen.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make appetite subservient..." TEIform="index"/>To make appetite subservient...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To make appetite subservient to judgment, we must not pamper our likes and dislikes; our
                            abnormal conditions make us slaves to physical demands.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="158" id="n14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aggressive christianity" TEIform="index"/>AGGRESSIVE CHRISTIANITY. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">TFjHAT the testimony of Jesus the Christ is that which the abuv titl JL would convey to the
                            mind of any interested Christian, and nothing less, is quite evident. That it is a work
                            which intensifies the whole being and thru its demanding sacrifices, promises exalted
                            privileges, is at once an incentiv to do and to dare for the Kingdom of heaven's sake. John
                            the Revelator, thru the spirit of inspiration saw the aggressiv work of the Christian so
                            clearly illustrated that he presents it as a conqueror riding upon a beutiful white horse.
                            The warrior is equippt with a bow and arrows, as he goes forth conquering and to conquer.
                            The representation, is indeed, like a warrior upon the earth, and on this account may impres
                            itself more forcibly upon the mind, as a vivid picture of a living Christian in his duty for
                            his God. Some, however, may look upon it as a work in the spirit of the Lord, and
                            contemplate the time when the Kingdoms of the whole world shal becum the Kingdoms of our
                            Lord. Possibly the profetic order of life may see more clearly just how this is to be
                            accomplisht, and writh that form of solution it must now rest. The good apostl who had
                            consecrated himself to the spirit of Christ, has also illustrated this interesting feature
                            of his life in language not to be misunderstood, as he makes this record. "I hav fought a
                            good fight, and hav kept the faith." In these few words the whole of a religious experience
                            is most beutifully concentrated. Thru this contest with weapons not carnal, he had obtaind a
                            victory over all the enemies of God, and equally as essential, he had kept his faith in God,
                            that he might be protected and prosperd. This contest against evil and the securing of a
                            victory over the foes of our own household was so like a warfare against the enemies of our
                            common country that the apostl represented it in the language that was best understood. When
                            he addresses the Christian in the fulness of his life duties, he instructs him to make as
                            careful a preparation against the enemies of his own soul, as the Roman soldiers would make
                            against the enemies of their country. Nothing short of an aggressiv contest against the
                            worldly element, either at home or abroad, wil ever accomplish any satisfactory result for a
                            religious person or for a religious Society. It makes but litl difference how we may wish to
                            hav this religious system accomplisht, if we fail to act in accordance with its general
                            plan, <pb n="159" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 154 while it makes all difference in the
                            ultimate by the course we are led to pursue in its development. No one disputes the point of
                            the continuance of God's laws in the heavens and in the earth, or in the hearts of the
                            children of men. The sun, moon and stars go unerringly on their way, regardless of all the
                            wars and rumors of wars that may agitate the Kingdoms of this world. Seedtime and harvest
                            are with us agreeably to the early promise, and we share in all the blessings which they may
                            develop. Over all these wonderful works of God, and over many others equal]}' as wonderful,
                            man very fortunately has no control. The sunshine and the rain belong to no privilegd class,
                            and the just and unjust are made welcuni recipients of all these good gifts from the hand of
                            an over-ruling Providence. Whatever course may be pursued by an individual or by a nation in
                            the cultivation of selfishness, the race of man must be moving upward toward higher and
                            better degrees of goodness, and thru this, up to the Kingdom of God. These laws whether
                            adapted to our understanding or not, wil evidently move on without molestation. The
                            Christian's life interest, however, has all these blessings, and then we hav an extended
                            blessing, the basis of which is the spirit of godliness. This great journey with its trials
                            and burdens, is in all clearness up toward God, to a better disciplind order that shal make
                            men more like the sons of God, and this earth more like a home that is ruld in
                            righteousness. Jesus brought this work of the Kingdom into the very homes of all his
                            followers. It was like the voice of a trumpet that gives no uncertain sound. "If any man wil
                            cum after me let him deny himself and take up his cross and follow me." This confirms the
                            testimony of the apostl who had receivd a disciplin in the life of Jesus the Christ. This,
                            said he, teaches us to deny ourselvs "of all ungodliness and every worldly lust." It
                            requires no studied effort to be abl to comprehend the full effect jf such a clear cut
                            declaration. No words ar wasted in the presentation, and no time need be wasted in the
                            transposing of a singl sentence. It is the unalloyd formula of the Christian religion, and
                            is the sure foundation of Christianity. It is the baptizm of the holy Spirit, and of fire,
                            which came with the Advent of Jesus the Christ. A neglect in securing this most important
                            treasure would be to any individual the falling away from a spiritual protection and equally
                            so, the wasting away of any society that has ever been blest with the revelation of light
                            and truth from God.</p></div2><pb n="160" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I look to thee" TEIform="index"/>I LOOK TO THEE.</head><p TEIform="p">"As the hart panteth after the waterbrooks, so panteth my soul after thee, O God."Psalms,
                            xlii., 1. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. My heart hath need of thee, O living Christ divine! Make 2.
                            The thorny crown I see, The pilgrim's brow must wear, The 3. I cannot walk alone, And bear
                            life's chastenings, But 4. Thou art life's light and joy, My soul looks up to thee, The
                            known thy will to me, And claim me ever thine. My cross of Calvary, I must with patience
                            bear. The thy sweet mercy shown, A constant solace brings. O rock so high and vast, That
                            ever shelters me. A wayward feet may turn, In shadowed paths of woe; But rugged mountain's
                            steep, Temptation's glowing height; The pure Evangel Guide, Blest hope in God and heaven! In
                            noint my blinded eyes, Until thro' faith I see, The when for thee I yearn, Thy saving pow'r
                            I know, stormy Jordan's deep, The valley's darkened light. thee I will confide, In ev'ry
                            promise giv'n. hills of glory rise; Beyond the stormswept sea.</p></div2><pb n="161" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JULY 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year,
                            postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. Our promised early spring was suddenly retarded by a fortnight of unusually
                                cold weather for the month of May. Notwithstanding this, the cherry, plum, pear and
                                early apple trees which were abundantly covered with blossoms, escaped without injury
                                although we had several successive frosts. Sr. Anna Dodgson said we had twelve nights of
                                frost; we presume that an anxiety for her flowers seemingly intensified the cold. But it
                                was a curious fact observed by her, that just before sunrise the frost would gather on
                                the flat roof of the gas house when perhaps none was seen elsewhere. We attended our
                                first Society meeting June 9th and were blessed with many inspirational gifts from both
                                Brethren and Sisters of different families, and from the beloved Ministry of Canterbury,
                                Eldress Joanna J. Kaime and Eldress Eliza A. Stratton. What a joy and blessing to meet
                                such loved ones. We always feel a special ministration of good on such occasions. Sr.
                                Mary Ella Briggs of Enfield, N. H. is also with us enjoying the beautiful mountain air,
                                and we hope that she may return home renewed in strength for dailj duties. Thanks to Sr.
                                Nancy llupe for her interest in our Florida enterprise, as expressed in the April
                                number. Being a native of tlie Western states we always read with interest what is
                                written from that locality. We have received letters from our Florida friends stating
                                all are well. They seem to have the interest necessary to pioneers. Sr. Anna Lane has
                                just sent us a sample grasshopper. Its body measures three inches and a half in length;
                                its hind legs are five inches long, which look like the walking beams of a steam engine;
                                it has feet half an inch in length, and beautiful pink wings. As he survived the journey
                                we shall be very careful that he does not escape confinement, for we would not like an
                                addition of such monsters to our over supply of voracious insects. Neva Martin. Center
                                Family. June, 1895. Since writing our last Home Notes the blossoms have come and gone.
                                Fruit trees of all kinds with the exception of plums gave evidence of bearing a full
                                crop the coming season. Cherries have already put on considerable size and if nothing
                                injures them we shall have a large yield. The weather just now is extremely warm and a
                                cool place at the White mountains would be very agreeable. At 9 p. m. Friday, May 31st,
                                the mercury stood at 84 deg. in our sitting room. Health of family fairly good. Timothy
                                Raysov. South Family. June, 1895. "Beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of those
                                who bring tidings to the house of Israel." And "beautiful for habitation is Mount Zion."
                                TERMS. <pb n="162" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 162 THE MANIFESTO. June in all its beauty, glory and
                                grandeur has smiled her most lovely smile upon the inhabitants of tins and other homes
                                dotted over our broad universe. The frosts of May have proved less destructive to
                                vegetation than was at first supposed. There is now a good outlook for fruit and labor
                                for busy hands will be the demand of the season. There continues a constant demand for
                                the famous "Shaker Chairs," sofas, footrests, and numerous other articles manufactured
                                by the family. We are quite positive that the South family at Mt. Lebanon is the
                                Champion Chair Maker of the world. The work is of the very best and it is well known
                                that They're useful,ornamental Two grand principles combined, You may search the wide
                                world over Xor better chairs you'll finci. Then their sofas, and their foot rests Are
                                the best this world can give; Do not try to find their equal For you can not while you
                                live. The past month was rendered delightful by a brief visit with Sr. Louisa Greene of
                                Harvard, Mass. May others of the sa'me Society come and do likewise. We are always
                                interested in reading The Manifesto; the Notes about Home, are a choice melody
                                completing a charming harmony. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">May, 1895. Eldeb Henry;I am interested to inform you that Eldress Betsey Spalding, Br. J.
                                Brown and the writer made a visit to Union Village. We left home one lovely morning and
                                had a most pleasant journey to the beautiful City of Cincinnati, thence to the village
                                of Lebanon, about four miles from the home of the Believers. Elder Joseph Slingerland,
                                and Eldress Elizabeth were waiting with horses and carriage to receive us. We shared
                                bountifully in the love and good will of all. Our own home in Kentucky is a beautiful
                                place, and doubly dear to all who hold it as a consecrated home for Believers. We are
                                having a nice crop of strawberries, and the farm and other business is in a prosperous
                                condition. With kind thoughts for all the readers of The Manifesto. Mary J. Settles.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. I keceivkd a letter recently from Texas purporting to be from a reader of our
                                paper, The Manifesto, showing appreciation of the various subjects discussed in the Home
                                Notes, also expressing the further idea that a knowledge of our life in the Communities
                                would be enlightening and very satisfactory. ISTot a difficult request to grant as to
                                the general routine of duty in a Shaker family, for it is quite similar to that of any
                                weil regulated home, but of the inward peace found by a conscience void of offence
                                toward God or man we can say but little in this small space, it must be found by each
                                one. The signal bell for rising peals forth at 5 a. m. and breakfast follows at 6
                                o'clock and then preparations for the work of the clay. Some of the Sisters are busy
                                with domestic duties which make home so comfortable; others are engaged in various kinds
                                of sale work in the line of sewing and knitting. The Brethren find employment in sawing
                                of lumber and shingles; some follow the Tailors' trade, and others work in the garden.
                                Our time is thus well rilled in performing the general work of a family of over seventy
                                members, of all ages. We aim to supply, not only the physical needs of the being, but
                                offer to the soul sin-sick and weary the true bread of life. May 16. We enjoy a concert
                                given by our young people. Here was exhibited musical ability and attention to lessons
                                pleasing to the many interested friends, such occasions greatly enhance the pleasure of
                                our lives. <pb n="163" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 163 May 17. James Moyer, of Toronto,
                                Ontario, Canada, gives us an excellent entertainment through a phonograph. It was given
                                by contract and was a rare treat and a marvel of wonderment. During the past month many
                                of our people have been vaccinated in compliance with state laws. Undoubtedly this
                                precaution will prevent certain physical diseases, but there arises the thought that if
                                the government were as ready to enforce the laws for temperance and education, how many
                                homes now darkened by vice would know of the cleansing power of a Christian life. George
                                H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. IN reviewing the obituaries in the June Manifesto, we find it recorded of one
                                of the saints that has journeyed on, that she was "faithful unto death." In the conflict
                                of life it is grand and glorious to be able to have it said when we enter into rest that
                                we were worthy to be counted with those who are faithful. The boy who, taken prisoner
                                was ordered to sound the retreat on his bugle under penalty of death, and sounded the
                                charge dying like a hero at his post with his face to the enemy was "faithful unto
                                death." Since our last we have had very changeable weather; the month of May giving us
                                some frosty nights, injuring gardens more or less according to the advanced condition of
                                the crops. We escaped with slight damage when compared with the loss of crops in some
                                sections. We have been favored with a visit from our beloved Sister Ann Cummings of
                                Enfield, N. H. and also we hear it reported that the Ministry Sisters from East
                                Canterbury are expecting to visit Watervliet. We enjoy these seasons of social and
                                spiritual communion with our gospel relation, they are our interest and our treasure. We
                                have had a delightful rain that has refreshed vegetation and made us realize how
                                dependent we are, and how grateful we should be for the care extended over us by the
                                hand cf divine Providence. The editorial in June Manifesto is timely, "Aggressive
                                evangelism" is absolutely necessary in the advancement of the truths of the Divine Life
                                with a strong emphasis placed on Aggressive. That spirit is far removed from the one
                                that seeks to breed contention. Only by a vigorous promulgation of the advocates of the
                                truth are the advocates of the higher life able to stand the assaults of the opposing
                                powers that seek to hold down to the lower stratum of thought and life the expanding
                                powers of the soul. Hamilton DeGraw,.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. It is even at this date too early to foresee what may be expected of the
                                several orders of fruit trees. The frosts and rains and continued cold wether ar al
                                unfrendly to the prosperity of fruit growing. A writer in the "People and Patriot"' says
                                that there ar no Blu birds in NewHampshire tills season, and he is at a loss, to solv
                                the problem. I am quite sure that I saw one, several weeks since and herd him sing. I
                                hav also observd that the English sparrows, driv the blu birds away from the places,
                                where they formerly made their nests. Last month we made extended reference to the
                                "Standard Dictionary." In this; number of The Manifesto several articls ar publisht in
                                which we hav attempted to follow the rules of the International Spelling Eeform
                                Association, as they ar set forth in this new work. The advantages of the reformd system
                                so essentially simplifid, especially in the suppression of so many silent letters, will
                                at once present themselvs to those who may hav occasion to write, Ji. C, Blinn,</p></div3><pb n="164" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. "Watch and pray that ye enter not into temptation," is wise counsel and if
                                heeded will save many wrong steps and much misery. Those who are ever watchful are
                                always strong. If we follow the spirit of truth it will lead us safely. Let us form this
                                link of communion with the angelic host and commit all our trials and burdens to One,
                                who has promised to protect and guide those who trust in Him, However zealous or earnest
                                we may be, if we cease to watch and pray we shall be overcome by the adversary of souls.
                                We should live so each day that God and our conscience can approve. Many persons tell
                                what a lovely place they picture heaven to be, but do nothing to make a present heaven.
                                The virtuous and true find heaven here. Let us be true to our trust and God will give
                                just compensation. Live but for ourselves and we live in vain, but live for Christ and
                                the human brotherhood and we shall reign with him. One half of the year is gone forever,
                                let us wisely improve the remaining months. There is nothing like pure air and clean
                                water for hens. Corn alone will not make good chickens it is most valuable for its
                                fattening qualities. Wheat one part, corn one part and oats one part will produce a fast
                                growing chicken. Daniel Orcutt. South. Family. June, 1885. "We are enjoying delightful
                                weather. June, with all its admirable scenery has thus far been cool and bracing, with
                                some showers which were much needed. The strawberries were not injured by the frosts and
                                are fast ripening. The vegetables are also coming forward rapidly and our daily supply
                                for the table will meet our expectations although the dry season was severe in this
                                locality, while in some places too much rain damaged the crops. Our mowing fields are
                                looking well and the prospects are encouraging. The many improvements which have been
                                going on around our home have resulted satisfactorily, the fruit trees have all lived
                                and are looking finely. A few years will give evidence of the industry and perseverance
                                which has not been sparingly laid out. The new method of raising chickens has also
                                proved successful as over a hundred are in good growing condition. For all the varied
                                blessings which are daily bestowed upon us, we render thanks and praise to the giver of
                                every good and perfect gift. Forgetting self, we are striving for the wealth that is not
                                of earth, and endeavoring to fill the moments with deeds of love and principles of
                                right, which will prove our discipleship. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. ISTow is the time to remember The Manifesto, and as we enjoy the
                                contributions of others to its support, we should be willing to give our mite, as far as
                                ability permits to the enjoyment of others. Through its pages we become acquainted with
                                distant Societies and an interchange of living thought is profitable to stir up our
                                minds by way of remembrance, not only of kindred spirits but perhaps of neglected duties
                                the performance of which is necessary for a further growth into the religion of Christ
                                which teaches us to love our neighbors as ourselves. The month of roses came with
                                mercury dancing among the nineties; but only for a few days and a cold wave from the
                                rock" ies ran it so low we feared a repetition of May's frost which ruined the prospect
                                of small fruits. Thus our lives are checkered with sunshine and shadow, hopes and
                                disappointments. Herein is manifest the patience of the saints,to meet life's varied
                                changes with Christian resignation. The present rains are seasonable to give the grass a
                                free growth that we may be able to replenish our barns and in a meas- <pb n="165" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 165 ure repair the loss of last year's fire. I fear it
                                will take several years to make the loss good. Seed time is past, and has been well
                                improved, and the laborers are busy making war on the noxious weeds, that like little
                                evils, will destroy the tender plants if not exterminated. Now that we have planted and
                                watered we look to nature's god to give an increase, and pray we need not look in vain.
                                Afarcia M. Dullard,.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. June comes with all her beauty; the most perfect month of the year! The birds
                                commence their songs of rapture early in the morning and sing throughout the long day.
                                We are having fine sunny weather; just what the vegetation needs. A few days since the
                                gardener came into the kitchen with a large basket of spinach saying "Who wants to goto
                                Florida?" It had grown from seed in twenty-eight days. We think that is doing well for
                                this state&gt; especially as the weather has not always been favorable. The Maine State
                                Building from the World's Fair, Chicago, is now erected at Poland Springs and will be
                                dedicated the 26 inst. Some ot the Officers and a great many people will be present. The
                                Proprietors have very kindly invited us to come with our fancy work; a privilege which
                                we shall gladly accept. Of this eventful day we will tell you in our next Notes. Ada S.
                                Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. The planting of the seeds is past and now comes the care of the growing
                                plants that the weeds and insects do not spoil them. How curious it is that the weeds
                                will grow and mature without aid from us, but the good plants require our greatest care.
                                So it is with the things of the Spirit. As natural creatures we are as prone to evil as
                                the sparks to fly upward. The path of progress is an uphill work, requiring eternal
                                vigilance, that we do not lose in jm hour what it has taken us days to gain. June has
                                given us a variety of weathers. One day is so cold that a fire is needed for comfort and
                                the next day is so warm, that had we wings, there would be quite a company in the region
                                of the North Pole. We often think of our Florida friends. Our prayers go out for their
                                prosperity, and as our little monthly paper is the only messenger to the distant lands,
                                we will send by it our kindest love to our gospel friends who are toiling for the cause
                                of right. Just now we are needing rain for the growing crops. Grass which has been doing
                                well requires rain soon, or we shall get a small hay crop. The Brethren have taken
                                advantage of the dry weather to shingle the meetinghouse which was built in 1794, and
                                the shingles have lasted until now. The boards of the roof were of excellent lumber,
                                evidently our early father's brought their best to build a temple to their Father and
                                Mother, God. May we pattern them in our offerings. Fannie Casey.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">PRACTICAL SELF-DENIAL. The Editor of "Times of Restitution" in making reference to himself,
                            says,"We spend no money for luxuries, we dress plain, chew no tobacco, take no medicine,
                            drink no tea or coffee, eat the plainest food, attend no theatres, take no pleasure trips,
                            and work from 5.30 in the morning till 9.30 at night. Kemember our work in your prayers." A
                            record of this order is certainly commendable, and many a Christian might read it with
                            profit to both soul and body.</p></div2><pb n="166" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ" TEIform="index"/>Christ
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Christ is edited and published by Marion B. Van Eps. The paper is devoted to the
                                scientific teaching of Jesus Christ. Lessons in Christ Science teaches one how to heal
                                himself or others. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temple of health" TEIform="index"/>The Temple of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Temple of Health is edited by Dr. J. M. Peebles and published at
                                San Diego, Cal. It is the only Journal in the world devoted exclusively to hygiene,
                                psychic healing, the demonstrations of the spirit, therapeutic medicines, the finer
                                forces and the laws to be observed to live a century. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Association herald" TEIform="index"/>Association Herald
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Association Herald, is conducted
                                in the interest of the Madison Avenue Baptist Church, Charles J. Townsend, Editor. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of glad tidings" TEIform="index"/>The
                                Herald of Glad Tidings
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Herald of Glad Tidings is edited by Ulyssus G. Morrow. It is said to be "strictly
                                unsectarian, and illustrates God's purpose of the ages, and objects, time and manner of
                                the second advent.". As this number of the paper seems to be wholly in the interest of
                                Roresbanity, we think it must belong to that order of Christians. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian" TEIform="index"/>Christian
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Christian, is edited
                                by Rev. T. J. Shelton. Little Rock, Ark. He writes,"My treatments for success in
                                business and money matters have been wonderfully successful."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our loved sister, Phebe Van Houten" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of our Loved
                            Sister, PHEBE VAN HOUTEN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cutler, Sarah E." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah E. Cutler.</byline><p TEIform="p">O! patient toiler thou hast reached the goal, Hast found the river, and hast crossed it o'er
                            Hast joined the loved ones in that better land From whence the traveler doth return no more.
                            Loved Sister, thou hast borne the cross for many years, Hast been a noble veteran in the
                            cause. Thy character so firm, would never swerve But bravely vindicate Mt. Zion's laws. A
                            braver soldier never scored the field; Heroic warrior 'gainst the powers of sin; For thou
                            hast turned the battle to the gate And fought most valiantly the foes within. Thy loyalty
                            and interest in the cause were ever true; Thou counted all as dross, if Christ to win, Thy
                            soul a willing sacrifice was made Thy heart's desire was,to gain the victory's over sin.
                            Devotion to the blessed gospel work Seemed truly all thy inner powers to claim, And sweet to
                            thee was sacred worship's hour Where thOu couldst praise thy heavenly Father's name. Thy
                            early youth wis given unto God ; The first ripe fruits were sacrifices free Those solemn
                            vows of consecration offered then Were landmarks on life's journey, unto thee. O! Sister
                            dear! thy life was spent in truly praising G )d; To serve thy gospel kindred was thy only jo
                            j ; To consecrate thy labors for the good of all Has been thy greatest treasure and thy
                            sweet employ. We'll miss the many favors from thy hands, . We'll miss thy pleasant spirit
                            from our home; We fain would hold thee here for it is hard to part But thou must go with
                            friends beyond to roam To meet thy sure reward so justly thine A recompense well merited in
                            time The promised blessing to the faithful soul A crown of glory and a robe divine, Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC. The Psalmist's prayer Alphabetically arranged.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Belden, Emoretta" TEIform="persName"/>By Emoretta Belden.</byline><p TEIform="p">As the hart panteth after the water-brooks so, panteth my soul after thee, O God. xlii., 1.
                            Be thou not far from me, O Lord, my strength.xxii., 19. Cause me to hear thy loving kindness
                            in the morning; for in thee do I trust. cxliii., 8. Deliver the poor and needy: defend the
                            afflicted and fatherless.lxxxii., 3, 4. Every day will I bless thee; I will praise thy name
                            forever and ever.cxlv., 2. For thou art my rock and my fortress; therefore for thy name's
                            sake lead me, and guide me.xxxi., 8. Give ear to my prayer, O God; and hide not thyself from
                            my supplication. lv., 1. Help us, 0 God of our salvation, for the glory of thy name.lxxix.,
                            9. I will praise thee, O Lord, with my whole heart; I will show forth thy marvelous
                            works.ix.,1. Judge me, O Lord, my God, according to thy righteousness.xxxv., 24. Keep me as
                            the apple of the eye; hide me <pb n="167" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 167 under the shadow of
                            thy wings. xvii., 8. Let the words of my mouth, and the meditation of my heart, be
                            acceptable in thy sight, O Lord, my strength and my redeemer.xix., 14. Make thy face to
                            shine upon thy servant: save me for thy mercies' sake.xxxi., 10. Nevertheless I am withthee:
                            thou hast holden me by my right hand.lxxiii., 23. O God, thou knowest my foolishness; and my
                            sins are not hid from thee lxix., 5. Purge me with hyssop, and I shall be clean.li., 7.
                            Quicken me, O Lord, for thy name's sake: for thy righteousness' sake bring my soul out of
                            trouble.cxliii., 11. Redeem Israel, O God, out of all his troubles.xxv., 22. Save thy
                            people, and bless thine inheritance: feed them, and lift them up forever.28., 9. Thou
                            ci'ownest the year with thy goodness.lxv., 11. Unto thee, O Lord, do we give thanks: for
                            that thy name is near thy wondrous works declare.lxxv., 1. Verily there is a reward for the
                            righteous. lviii., 11. We have thought of thy loving-kindness, O God, in the midst of thy
                            temple. xlviii., 9. Yea, let none that wait upon thee be ashamed.xxv.. 3. Zion heard, and
                            was glad; and the daughters of Judah rejoiced because of thy judgments, O Lord.xcvii., 8.
                            West Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What are the wild waves saying" TEIform="index"/>"WHAT ARE
                            THE WILD WAVES SAYING?"</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by S. A. Collins.] 
                                    What are the wild waves saying? Forever the whole day long! Just over, and over,
                                    and over! One grand, monotonous song! Who can their language utter? Or tell us the
                                    song they sing Who can explain their music, Or tell us the message they bring? I
                                    know what the waves are saying An angel told it to me : 'Tis the bass of the
                                    heavenly anthem, Struck on an earthly key! 'Tis a part of the grand old chorus They
                                    chant in the world above Over and over for ever, In the anthem "God is Love!"
                                    Forever reverberating Thro' all the invisible spheres, The echoes forever resounding
                                    Thro' all the eternal years; Forever rolling and swelling, In tonesall tones above
                                    The same glad story telling That Godour Godis Love! From the roar of the great
                                    Niagara, To the tiniest waterfall From the tides of the mighty ocean, To the
                                    smallest ripple of all . Mingling with unheard music, Sung in the heights above,
                                    That Godthe God we worship That Godour Godis Love! Go on, then, waves of the ocean,
                                    I never will doubt you more; You have brought me a heavenly melody I never had
                                    learned before! I could sit and listen forever To your grand monotonous song; I
                                    never should wea.y to hear it, Forever the whole day long. Some time, in the blessed
                                    future, I shall hear the other parts The tenor, alto and treble, From sainted human
                                    hearts: Nay, moreI shall join in the music, Here or in heights above, And sing with
                                    the glorified millions, That God, the Lord, is Love.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A minister, annoyed..." TEIform="index"/>A minister, annoyed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A minister, annoyed by tobacco chewing, thus spoke to his congregation: "Take
                                    your quid of tobacco out of your mouth on entering the house of God, and gently lay
                                    it on the outer edge of the <pb n="168" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 168 THE MANIFESTO. fence. It will
                                    posilively be there when you go out, for a rat won't take it, a cat won't take it, a
                                    dog w n't lake it, you are certain of your quid when you go after it.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dr. Foote's Health Monthly" TEIform="index"/>Dr. Footers Health Monthly.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">A cokeespondent to "The Altruist," J. F. Bean, of Mont, writes as follows: "I watch your
                            progress with a good deal of interest, but I want to urge you all the time t keep out of
                            debt. Regard debt as crime, and avoid it persistently." advice might prove profitable for
                            the Shakers as well as for the Altruists.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why should mankind be so dependent..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Why should mankind be so dependent...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Why should mankind be so dependent on the lower animals for so much of his food supply? They
                            are not his natural food. Animals do not form food. Animals are liable to disease the same
                            as man. It is a fact that iem of our domestic animals are really in health when slaughtered.
                            So with the aid of knowledge and science the human family will find out as they get the
                            truth, and have more information on the subject of dietetics, that it is a delusion and a
                            great error to think that animal foods of any and of all kinds are essential to his growth,
                            development and health.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stair, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. Stair, M. D.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Snow-drops" TEIform="index"/>SNOW-DROPS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Napoleon D. Brown.] Beneath the coverlet of snow, Two little flowers learn to grow,; Their cheeks are
                                    pale and white and fair, Their lips are sweet as summer air. At first they shiver in
                                    the cold, Then grow more fearless, calm and bold, To push aside the snowy sheet And
                                    lift their faces pure and sweet. One to the other gently speaks, As March winds
                                    blanch her tender cheeks: "Dear Sister, it is cold to-day, But yet I think we here
                                    may stay: The earth is bleak, and dark and chill, All other flowers are sleeping
                                    still, But we'll remain awhile to sing In token of the coining spring." The sister
                                    softly makes reply: "We'll bloom together, you and I And send our choicest perfume
                                    out To gladden mortals round about; I'm sure they must be weary now Of winter's
                                    dismal icy brow, And longing for the breath of flowers, So we will stay and offer
                                    ours. And so the dainty blossoms braved The snow and sleet, and only craved A tiny
                                    place to fill with bloom, And scatter forth their rich perfume; And many hearts that
                                    yearned for spring, And all the beauties she would bring, Gave blessing to the
                                    little flowers, As heralds of her fragrant hours.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feeling in religion" TEIform="index"/>FEELING IN RELIGION.</head><p TEIform="p">"Feeling is of just as much use in religion as steam is in an engine; if it drives the engine
                            it is good, but if it does not, it is not good for anything but to fizz and hiss and buzz.
                            There are some people who seem to be like yard-engines that never go anywhere, but keep
                            puffing, blowing and hissing, and running up and down side tracks doing nothing, going
                            nowhere. Feeling in religion is of no value at all if it does not propel us along the track
                            of duty toward our final destinationGod. Fine feelings, glorious feelings,we all have them
                            after our own measure; but fine feelings, quick responsive sensibilities do you know that
                            they have been the occasion of the ruin of some of the greatest geniuses that God ever gave
                            to the human race? Feeling is a miserable, cheap substitute for duty. It takes more than
                            being happy on Sunday in church to be religious. My friends, true religion never stops short
                            of holiness. It means that first and last. Religion does not stop at feeling; religion does
                            not stop at tradition, or at respectability, or to ecclesiasticism, or at eloquent
                            preaching, or delightful music. Religion means, always has meant, always must mean, the
                            actual communion of the human soul with God in righteousness and holiness. And that kind of
                            reThis <pb n="169" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Hi!) ligion costs; it takes the best there is
                            in a man to be religious in that way."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, J." TEIform="persName"/>Rev. J. Parker.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Right of self-defence" TEIform="index"/>THE RIGHT OF SELF-DEFENCE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Christianity is the only infallible or perfect standard by which the right or the
                                    wrong of any and all questions in morals may be determined. Hence consistency on the
                                    part of persons who profess belief in the Christian Scriptures requires the
                                    rejection of all other standards so far as they may differ from the teachings of the
                                    New Testament. 1. No man is his own. Having been bought with a price, the man
                                    belongs to Christ, who bought him with his own "precious blood." 2. A man thus
                                    bought is bound to do as his owner commands, be the commands what they mayactive or
                                    passive, to do or to suffer. In thus obeying, the man in his body and in his spirit,
                                    glorifies God "manifests the life of Jesus in his mortal flesh," which is a
                                    "reasonable service." 3. A man has no right to endanger or lose his life except it
                                    be for the sake of Christcovered by command to do or to suffer, and governed by the
                                    Spirit of Christ. "Love your enemies, bless them that curse you, do good to them
                                    that hate you, and pray for them which despite fully use you and persecute you."
                                    "Let this mind be in you which was also in Christ Jesus." "It any man have not the
                                    Spirit of Christ he is none of his"be what else he may. 4. A man has no right to
                                    give offense to any person. *'Be ye therefore wise as serpents, and harmless as
                                    doves." ''Give none offense, neither to the Jews, nor to the Church of God." 5. In
                                    associating with his fellows a man has no right to carry about his person deadly
                                    weapons. "The weapons of our warfare are not carnal." "Take unto you the whole armor
                                    of Godloins girt about with truthbreastplate of righteousnessfeet shod with the
                                    preparation of the gospel of peaceshield of faith helmet of salvationthe sword of
                                    the Spirit, which is the word of Godpraying always with all prayer and supplication
                                    in the Spirit." Thus armored "fight the good fight of faith""war a good warfare." In
                                    taking carnal weapons to defend himself a man thereby forfeits the protection of Him
                                    who said, "they that take the sword shall perish with the sword." Obedience to the
                                    Scriptures quoted will give to a Christian all the right of selfdefense which he can
                                    consistently claim, and no man in Christendom has any right not to be a Christian.
                                    "To him that knoweth to do good, and doeth it not, to him it is sin." While
                                    obedience to Christ does not ensure against violence and death by wicked hands, yet
                                    it does ensure a divinely ordered protection which would not otherwise be afforded.
                                    If faithfulness be "unto death," the chief end of manto glorify God, is attained,
                                    and to enjoy Gud forewr is made sure. The "'glory" with which men cover themselves
                                    on a battle-field is but a bloody bubblean abomination in the sight of God"but the
                                    man who loses his life for the sake of Ciirist shall find it, and shall have given
                                    him "a crown of life." Self-defense or self-exposure is with the Christian, a
                                    question of small import when compared with the controlling purpose of life which is
                                    well expressed by the faithful Paul: "Christ shall be magnified in my body, whether
                                    it be by life, or by death." If faithful to Christ does not secure against death by
                                    wicked hands, then is it better "to depart and be with Christ" than to deny Christ
                                    and live a while longer with a tormenting conscience.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian Neighbor" TEIform="index"/>Christian Neighbor.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessed are they who do not run to the wood shed..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Blessed are they who do not run to the wood shed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Blessed are they who do not run to the wood shed to fetch the ax to kill the small beetle
                            that they find in their path. Blessed also are they who often remember that gentle words are
                            more powerful than hasty threats.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Themis" TEIform="persName"/>Themis.</byline></div2><pb n="170" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE PHRENOLOGICAL JOURNAL AND SCIENCE of Health for .June will be especially interesting
                                to all tlie editors of the country, sis well as to general reader!*, us its special
                                feature is a phrenograph of the fim.ous journalist, Cluis. A. Dana, of the New York Sim.
                                Severn] portraits! illustrate his salient tiaitsof character and their agreement with
                                the principles of phrenology. The analysis is from a personal examination by the editor,
                                Dr. Bcall. Cheiro the palmist, well known in New York, contributes a fascinating article
                                on c heirosophy. Dr. II. S. Drayton writes learnedly of "The Scientific Relation, Past
                                and Present." Mrs. Charlotte Fowler Wells concludes her sketch of William Walton, and
                                introduces a most interesting study of Shakespeare, illustrated by a fine picture of the
                                celebrated Kesselstadt death mask of the master poet. "Contrasted Heads" is a conclusive
                                argument for phrenology, by the. editor, accompanied by fine drawings of Charles
                                Bradlaugh and Daniel Drew. Prof. Nelson Sizer continues his charming studies of
                                children. In the Science of Health Department there is the usual variety of excellent
                                hygienic advice, etc. Other well-known writers discuss "Human Nature" and "The
                                Temperaments," etc. There are editorials on the "Status of Phrenology," "Science of the
                                Hand," and other matters of current interest. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio Tiiekapv. May,
                                Contents. Phrenology; The Graduating Thesis; Ueply to a letter; Pure Vaccine points;
                                Plant Something; Disintegrating Theory; Dr. T. V. Gifford, Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladles' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A NEW ART
                                EDITOR. William Martin Johnson, who illustrated the "Garfield" edition of "Ben Hur" for
                                the Harpers, and also their editions of "The Cloister and the Hearth" and "Hypatia,"
                                becomes the art editor of The Ladles' Home Journal on June 1st, leaving New Y'ork to
                                reside permanently in Philadelphia. Mr. Barton Cheyney, a clever newspaper man who has
                                been attached to the press of Delaware and Pennsylvania is also added to the Journal's
                                editorial staff as one of Mr. Bolt's principle associates. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Separated nation" TEIform="index"/>The Separated Nation
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Separated Nation by H. L.
                                Hastings is a work of some 225 pages. This separated nation is a brief historical
                                account of the Jewish people and written largely from a religious standpoint, with the
                                leading thought that they were at one time a race especially favored of God. The object
                                of the writer is to prove that God was the direct counselor of this nation and that
                                under this inspiration, Moses and other anointed officers directed the people by divine
                                commandment, and that their history throughout the whole earth is the most wonderful, in
                                every respect, of any nation that ever has or that now exists. To all biblical students
                                this little work will prove to be very interesting and equally as instructive. Published
                                at 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Van Houten, Phebe" TEIform="index"/>Phebe Van Houten
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Phebe Van Houten, at Mt. Lebanon, K Y. April 20, 1895. Age 77 years and 4 mo. Sister
                                Phebe has by a long life of consecrated service won the sincere love and esteem of all
                                who knew her. E. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carpenter, Julia H." TEIform="index"/>Julia H. Carpenter
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Julia H. Carpenter, at Pleasant Hill. Ky. May 29, 1895. Age 15 yrs.
                                Sister Julia was received into the Community when she was two years of age, and has been
                                "faithful unto death." Her ever kind and courteous manners made for her many friends. J.
                                W. S. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Koch, William" TEIform="index"/>William Koch
                            </head><p TEIform="p">William Koch, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. June 8, 1895. Age 70 years, 9 mo. and 1-1
                                days. William was born in Brunswick, Germany. He studied in the university of
                                Heidelberg, and qualified himself for a lawyer. In 1848 he took part in the revolution
                                at Eome. When the Pope's rule was restored by French soldiers, William being proscribed
                                also in Germany, took refuge in Switzerland. He afterward emigrated to Brazil, became
                                naturalized and was made Judge of the only Court in the Colony of 10,000 inhabitants and
                                held this office for twenty years. He returned to Europe to visit his relations and then
                                came to the U. S. at the solicitation of his brother who desired his aid in publishing a
                                German paper. His belief in Communistic principles induced him to visit the Shakers of
                                Mt. Lebanon in the fall of 1884. In Dec. of that year he entered the Society with his
                                companion and has manifested himself a man of a clean spirit, and respect to the
                                discipline and regulations of the Community. He was gentle and peaceable and seemed
                                rather to submit to injustice, than engage in sharp contention. He was of the better
                                class of mankind, and we believe will be better prepared for his privilege here to
                                become a leader of that class to the higher truths of eternal salvation. A. G. H.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
This is an American   Stem-winder,  up to date.    It represents the  most important step taken in watch evolution in many years.    It  describes  a line beyond
which nothing radical will pass for years, not only in the matter of price, but quality.
Two styles.   Gilt and nickel,   Snap  back, Bevel crystal,
tern. Set.   Fully timed and regulated.
For $2.00 we will  send the Watch, and also a copy of The Manifesto for one
year, to any adress in the U. S.           Address
The   Manifesto,
EAST    CANTERBURY,    N.    H.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S.W
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Tillage of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY.
The religiousjbasis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OW   BELIEVBES.
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MA N1 FES TO.
 sqmpound concentrated
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar   baking   powder
H'gbest of   all in   leavening-strength.
Latest   United  States   Government
Food Report.
Royal Baking Powdei: Co.,
106 Wall St., N.  Y.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, paitly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a-year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
2 N. Fourth St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
= IU.USTBATED HOME JOT7BZTA =
SO ots. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
THOOCAS a. XnSWSHAS & SOS,
CHICAGO, ILL.
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA, 
With 1 oz. Hydriodate of Potassa to 12 Bottle
PREPARED AT
gbaker Tillage, Merrimacb @o., B.
This medicine has proved to be most
 valuable in the following diseases:
[     Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
  Organs; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Bheu. matism ; Salt Bheum  Secondary Syphilis 
  Functional Disorders of the Liver; Chronic
' Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous
. diseases and disorders arising from im purities of the blood.    It is also an exceltsmedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
', Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
I so apt to end in consumption.
> Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
; four or five times a day, with or without
[ a little water, which may be increased to
'. a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
i To guard against counterfeits, observe
[ the signature of the inventor on each
 label and on each wrapper.
Of course, everybody knows how to
"pour" for is not that merely to lift and
tip? But who enjoys doing it? Yet, this
act must be for the Mother or Hostess, or
Sweetheart and Hostess in one; but what
a strain in lifting and tipping. Who can
talk and smile and also pour? Who would
not be glad if a way were found to pour
the tea without pouring? The way is
found, and it is a way so simple, neat, effective and perfect that one can only wonder that it was not found long ago.
See "a^." on another page.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>