<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0811" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18781101" TEIform="date">November 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">262-287</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. VIII. NO. II NOVEMBER. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE
                        UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT WATERVLIET, N. Y. "GO PREACH THE KlNGDOM OF GOD." 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT
                        SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher.<pb n="262" id="p2"/> Meetings 263 Correspondence The Twelve Christian
                        Virtues 265 Ann Lee Advice to Youth 266 The Shakers Mistaken Souls 266 For the Children The Premium on Virginity 267
                        Selected The Ends have come 26-7 Home Topics Indians No. 9. 268 Farm and Gardei My views of Prayer 269 Book Table
                        Voice of Peace 270 Society Recdrd The Shaker Manifesto 27] Obituary Editorial Notes 272 Music _ TERMS OF
                        ADVERTISING. 273 275 277 278 28a 282 283 284 285 285 286 For one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 ' one half column, ' $
                        3. 00 one " " " $ 6. 00 page, " " $12.00 Continued insertion for three months, 20jper ct. discount. " six " 25 " " "
                        " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H.
                        Subscription will begin when order is received.—No back numbers. CONTENTS.</p>
                    --><pb n="263" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL.
                        VIII.—NOVEMBER, 1878.—No. XI. </p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meetings" TEIform="index"/>MEETINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">This is a subject seldom treated, except in the way of reports ! It does not require comment
                            to convince sensible people of the utility of meetings, even though they may, sometimes feel
                            aversion to them. They are appreciated as necessary to tone the public mind, awaken it,
                            energize it, harmonize it, and prepare it for all the important concerns of life. In the
                            educational departments, meetings called schools are instituted for the purpose of an
                            economical expenditure of time and talent in the administration of instruction, also to
                            train the pupils to a unity of understanding of the same sciences and arts, so as to enable
                            them to act in concert in the pursuit and application of knowledge to the varied duties of
                            life. It is harmony in language and science that gives power to a nation. In the various
                            pursuits of earth life, for like purposes, meetings are appro- priately instituted. Tillers
                            of the soil have meetings to canvass the subjects concerning the best systems of culture for
                            various crops; best plant foods; best kinds of grains, cereals and bulbs for profit and
                            health ; best tools for tillage ; and lands best adapted to specific crops. Mechanics have
                            meetings to discuss the utility of certain woods, metals, or chemicals in the arts ; their
                            best modes of use ; the most simple, useful, or novel applications of the mechanical powers
                            to overcome resistances, or remove obstacles to improvement, &amp;c. &amp;c. Artists
                            have meetings to stimulate ambitions to excellence, to circulate information relative to the
                            uses and applications of substances for the productions of handicraft, and beauty of forms
                            and styles, cheapness of manufacture, ingenuity of structure to economize the use of
                            material so as to combine utility, sim- plicity, cheapness and durability. Scientists have
                            meetings to exchange *—' CD and reciprocate the knowledge obtained by experiments and
                            philosophical research, and to encourage inquiry and investigation of the causes of manifest
                            products, and the action of unknown laws. Statesmen have meetings to canvass the science of
                            government, to report past experiences of the application of principles and their
                            experimental results as precedents by which to anticipate future good or ill, by similar
                            uses of principles of diplomacy, or of national, social, or personal pi-otection.<pb n="264" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> !C4 THE SHAKER ZMLAJSTIITIGSTO. sparsely attended, if free for all! Why?
                            because there is provided wherewith to satisfy physical hunger, and minister to appetite and
                            gustations. To provide such a feast numerous have been the contributions from interested and
                            sacrificing persons. It is both possible and practicable so to replenish our spiritual
                            tables with food for the soul, that a lack of interest in religious meetings, or a neglect
                            of attendance of them would be seldom known ! But, it is no more possible to supply
                            spiritual food without effort directed to it, thai) it is material. It may be safely
                            affirmed that no soul food was ever tasted which was not the fruit of spirit toil, on the
                            part of some interested intelligen- ces in this or spirit life, who are benefactors of our
                            race. This toil consisted in a discipline of soul that characterized the conduct and
                            condition of both the physical and spiritual man, keeping the tongue with all diligence that
                            naught hould be uttered offensive to souls hunering for righteousness, nought that vould mar
                            a heavenly union and loving jeace ; such a government of the feellgs tliat no emotions of
                            the soul should )e in exercise that would prompt offeucs. This spirit to.'l is a
                            consecration of the powers, mental and spiritual to the labor of putting the soul in concert
                            of lotive and action with the heavenly losts so as to draw power from the highr spheres. Is
                            there a lack of love in our religious ssemblies? May be the causes are eglect or abuse of
                            our brother or sister ; or it is worldly nature first to abuse person, and then to hate the
                            same,— lis abuse, perchance, may be evil speakReligionists have meetings for th great
                            purposes of Divine worship and devotion ; of commingling and uniting soul emotions : of
                            considering the best means of administering needs, comforts and blessings to humanity ; of
                            stimulating each other to needful and commendable exertion to the spiritual labor requisite
                            to the attainment of the necessary inspirations contributing to soul life, in the individual
                            and the church, to afford the opportunity for the reciprocal interchange of gifts graces and
                            inspirations, accompanied by revivals of religious fervor, and resolutions for the mainte-
                            nance of Christian principles, and for the exercise of brotherly and sisterly fellowship. A
                            prominent use of religious meetings is to unite and combine strength in supplicating the
                            powers above for the baptisms of those refreshing dews and showers of spirit life, love and
                            charity which form the soul's home of contentment, and energize it for the continuous labors
                            necessary for the cultivation of heavenly fruits, and the practice of the virtues of a godly
                            life. Yet, notwithstanding this manifest need of meetings, it is not an uncommon experience
                            among professors of religion, to weary of meetings for religious worship and culture ; and,
                            were the multitude of this class of society to respond to the question : "What is the cause
                            of aversion or reluctance to the attendance of religious meetings ?" the answer would
                            doubtless well up from every voice lA lack of soul life in the meeting!' An assembly at the
                            dining hall, where the tables are laden with delicious savory viands and fruits, is a
                            meeting; but, it is seldom that such meetings are wanting in interest, or that they are<pb n="265" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE 365 ing, slander, backbiting, or, unkindness,
                            uncliaritableness, unforgiving. Love lias not been sown, not been cultivated, of course
                            cannot be harvested ! Do blessings cease to flow? then blessings have not been bestowed,
                            for, blessed are those who can love and bless every effort that any soul makes to do good. O
                            what good might be wrought if ail would remember the homely, though true maxim that "curses
                            like chickens, come home to roost." But souls who so love humanity as to be willing to live
                            and die for its good, as did Jesus, will know the truth of the Psalmist: "He that goeth
                            forth and weepeth, bearing precious seed, shall ¦doubtless return again with rejoicing
                            bringing his sheaves with him." As the physical body would perish without food, so must the
                            soul die without its nourishment. And, meetings for religious purposes, if appropriately
                            attended by devoted worshipers, and consecrated workers for human weal, furnish soul food.
                            But, that religious society or family which neglects religions meetings, is sure to wane,
                            and gradually perish ; it is a covenant with death ! Mt. Lebanon., N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twelve christian virtues: faith, hope, virgin purity, honesty, innocence, simplicity, meekness,                                 humility, prudence, patience, thankfulness, charity." TEIform="index"/>The Twelve Christian Virtues. Faith, Hope, Virgin Purity, Honesty, Innocence, Simplicity,
                            Meekness, Humility, Prudence, Patience, Thankfulness, Charity.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Faith, is a well defined conception of a plan, which, when reduced to practice, will be an
                            embodiment of that conception. Hence, in receiving faith in our gospel, and working after
                            the methods of the great patterns—Father Jesus, and Mother Ann ; we can have well grounded
                            Hope, that the same results will be wrought in us, that was wrought in them. Jesus and Ann,
                            had the same nature in themselves that we have ; experienced the same emotions, and were
                            tempted by them, even as we in our day and time are tempted. In working according to their
                            method, bearing a cross against all the lusts of the flesh and of the mind ; we will at-
                            tain finally to a state of redemption and learn at once not only to keep the faith of Jesus,
                            but also the commandments of God. Keeping the commandments of God written and unwritten, is
                            the external evidence of keeping the faith now delivered tons. In fulfilling the desires of
                            the flesh and of the mind, we have the world with its physical and moral diseases, abhor-
                            lent in many of its aspects, and at times awfully cruel and destructive; which when rightly
                            seen, may well constrain us to exclaim, increase our faith in Virgin Purity. For in bearing
                            a cross against the emotions of our animal selfhoods, and animated with the creative
                            energies of the New Creation, we hold a divine relation to each other, and have an angelic
                            form of social life. Having Faith, and Hope in Purity, and appreciating the privilege of
                            consecrating ourselves to divine uses instead of selfish pursuits, we add Honesty of thought
                            and purpose, then we can easily grow in Innocence and Simplicity : and having a true sense
                            of what we are by nature, we may well clothe our spirits with Humility. And when stirred up
                            at any time, we will find Meekness and Patience powerful virtues. Having these in operation,
                            we will be Prudent in the use of the things of this world, MAISTIFKSTO.<pb n="266" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            366 THE SHAKER and saving of the crumbs of all divine ministrations. Then from off the altar
                            of our inner life, Thankfulness and Charity shall ascend, with the aspirations of those who
                            are redeemed from among men, who keep the commandments of God, and the faith of Jesus. Mi.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mistaken souls" TEIform="index"/>MISTAKEN SOULS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hooser, Hortency G." TEIform="persName"/>HORTENCY G. HOOSER</byline><p TEIform="p">Mistaken souls, are those who think to be saved from sin and sorrow, by the blood of Jesus,
                            Avithout their own endeavors, to work out their salvation with fear and trembling ; as
                            verified by the precepts and example of Jesus. Let no man say that he is a Christian, except
                            he can say in the language of Christ that his own arm, is bringing salvation to him. Again,
                            mistaken souls, are those who find their way into Societies of Communists with no higher
                            motives than to spend easy lives at the expense of the faithful seiwants of the vineyard ;
                            and expecting, ''the penny," as promised. That penny is salvation from sin and sorrow—this
                            they do not find ; but they do find an outward cleansing, with food, clothing and comforts
                            for the outer man. These things all enjoyed, constitute a great salvation. Thousands, have
                            the Shaker communists saved from cold, hunger and destitution ; but this is not being saved
                            from sin and sorrow ; for alas ! we soon find such ones, begin to sin against the
                            regulations of Society, and break the peace, by finding fault, wishing to direct, and to
                            correct the leaders in this, that and other things. These assumptions are not received ; and
                            soon they are offended, and thus the reward of their own sin brings sorrow, and their
                            absence. But let the honest seeker after l'ighteousness, live up to Shakerism ; and he will
                            find complete salvation and redemption from sin ; and be enabled to become pure and
                            peaceable, feeling a just relationship to the church of Christ on earth—in full communion
                            with the angels in heaven, and be accepted of God —the Father and Mother above. Pleasant
                            Hill, Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advice to youth" TEIform="index"/>ADVICE TO YOUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">Never be discouraged by trifles. "If a spider breaks his thread twenty times he will mend it
                            again." Firmly resolve to subdue wrong and you can do it. Be not disheartened at slow
                            progress ; work on ; little by little great things are accomplished ; "with truth for your
                            standard" success will be certain. Fear not when trials come ; though the day seem dark,
                            trust in God and all will be well. Mind what you run after. Never be content with bubbles
                            that burst and end in disappointment. Get that which you can keep, that is worth keeping.
                            Koot out the noxious passions from the heart, as you would hurtful plants from the garden.
                            Cherish the virtues, love, meekness, modesty, goodness, purity ; let them thrive and pro-
                            duce their natural fruit, real happiness and joy. Fight hard against sinful thotights.
                            Temptations will come; resist them firmly. Say to the tempter, "Get thee hence, Satan." The
                            indulgence of sinful thoughts produces sinful actions. "When lust hath conceived it bringeth
                                MANIFESTO.<pb n="267" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFB1STO. S67 forth sin ; sin, when it is
                            finished, bringeth forth death." Evil passions grow fast; they are hard masters ; destroy
                            them or they will destroy you! Evil passions are vile weeds of the heart, and every
                            indulgence of them is seed, from which will spring a new crop. If your thoughts are pure,
                            your souls will be lovely; if impure, they will be deformed and wretched. Keep your minds
                            filled with good thoughts that bad ones may find no room to enter. Look well to your
                            thoughts. You are sowing on the field of life. Be sure that the seed is good. "As you sow,
                            so shall you reap." If you sow "tares," you will reap a harvest of vices ! Suppose a farmer
                            should sow vile seed with his wheat, and say, "When the grain is ripe I will gather and
                            separate them ? " Would it not be better to sow clean wheat? Sow only pure seed, that when
                            you reap, you may find nothing but golden grain. Enfield, Gt. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Premium on virginity" TEIform="index"/>THE PREMIUM ON VIRGINITY</head><p TEIform="p"> "Marriage is a holy state, instituted by "God, and in the order of providence and nature the
                            general and most ordinary state of those who live in the world. Those, therefore, who upon
                            motives of virtue, engage in this state, do well. Those nevertheless, who for the sake of
                            practising more perfect virtue, by a divine call, prefer a state of perpetual virginity,
                            embrace that which is more perfect and more excellent. Dr. Wells, a learned protestant,
                            confesses that Christ declares voluntary chastity, for the kingdom of heaven's sake, to be
                            an excellency, and an excellent state of mind. This is also the manifest inspired doctrine
                            of St. Paul, and in the revelations of Saint John, spotless virgins are called in a
                            particular manner, the companions of the Lamb, and are said to enjoy the singular privilege
                            of following him wherever he goes. The tradition of the church has always been unanimous on
                            this point; and among the Romans, Greeks, Syrians and barbarians, many holy virgins joyfully
                            preferred torments and death to the violation of their integrity, which they bound
                            themselves by vow to preserve without defilement, in mind or body. The fathers, from the
                            very disciples of the apostles, are all profuse in extolling the excellency of holy
                            virginity, as a special fruit of the incarnation of Christ, his divine institution, and a
                            virtue which has peculiar charms in the eyes of God, who delights in chaste minds, and
                            chooses to dwell singularly in them. They often repeat, that -purity raises men, even in
                            this mortal life, to the dignity of angels; purifies the soul, fits it for a more perfect
                            love of God, and a closer application to heavenly things, and disengages the mind and heart
                            from worldly thoughts and affections. It produces in the soul the nearest resemblance to
                            God. Chastity is threefold, that of virgins, that of widows, and that of married persons ;
                            in each state it will receive its crown, as St. Ambrose observes, but in the first is most
                            perfect, so that St. Austin calls its fruit a hundred fold, and that of marriage sixty fold;
                            but the more excellent this virtue is, and the higher its glory and reward, the more heroic
                            and the more difficult is its victory ; nor is it perfect unless it be embellished with all
                            other virtues in an heroic degree, especially divine charity and the most profound hu-
                            mility."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Butler" TEIform="persName"/>Butler's lives of the Saints. Vol. 1. Page 202. </byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ends Have gone" TEIform="index"/>THE ENDS HAVE GONE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Napoleon" TEIform="persName"/>NAPOLEON BROWN</byline><p TEIform="p">The end of Gods has come. "For the Lord our God is one Lord, and we have no others before
                            Him." The end of Idolatry has come, for we worship the Lord our God and Him only do we
                                serve.<pb n="268" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 268 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. The end of Swearing has come, for
                            our "communication is Yea, Yea, and Nay, Nay." The end of Sabbaths has come ; for we have
                            come to the Lord of the Sabbath. The end of the Father and Mother has come, for we have
                            given them up to follow Christ. The end of Killing has come, for we have put up our Swords
                            into their sheaths. The end of Adultery has come, for we look not upon man nor woman to lust
                            after either. The end of Stealing has come, for we "covet not." The end of bearing false
                            witness has come, for we love our neighbors as ourselves. The end of Coveting has come, for
                            we have no wives nor do we want any, being in the resurrection where they neither marry nor
                            give in marriage ; but are as the Angels of God, having all property in common. The end of
                            Sin has come, for Christ has appeared to us the second time "without sin" unto "salvation."
                            The end of the Law has come, for the Kingdom is set up within us, therefore we are a law
                            unto ourselves. The end of our lives has come, for we have lost them for Christ's sake. The
                            end of time has come, lor we have been begotton of God and born into eternity. Therefore the
                            end of all things has surely come. Pleasant Hill, Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians no. 9" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 9</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">A Chicago clergyman startled his flock a few Sunday evenings ago, by telling them "hell is
                            not half so full of men and women as men and women are full of hell." "Where are we to go?"
                            Chickasaw. The tide of emigration from the Eastern States and emigrants from the old world
                            are fast filling up the Western States and Territories, especially, in the fertile fields of
                            Dakota, Kansas, and Nebraska. It is said officially, "that in Dakota alone the increased
                            number of acres taken over that of the previous, year was a million and a quarter." Once the
                            Indians claimed the whole of this country for their home, and there, were none that disputed
                            their right; but now they are limited to one Territory, called the Indian Territory. And
                            they hardly dare call this their home for fear it will be taken from them. This. is small
                            indeed compared with what they once possessed. Small as it is, the, whites are already
                            trying to get it away from them, because they say the land is too good for the Indians. They
                            want, to get the richest land for selfish ends, and rail-road purposes, but they should not
                            have it—not a single foot of it. I would sooner enlarge the Indian Territory—it ought to be
                            extended, and bounded as follows. Taking in the North West part of Texas, on a line, running
                            parallel with the Southern line of the Indian Territory, as it now is ; bounded on the east,
                            by Arkansas, and Missouri; on the south, by Texas, and Mexico; on the west, by California,
                            and Nevada; on the north, by Utah, Colorado, and Kansas; including the whole of New Mexico,
                            and Arizona— to make one grand ''•Indian Territory,'* secured by the U. S. government to the
                            Indians, exclusively, by laws made as. unalterable as the laws of the Medes<pb n="269" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THK SHAKER 269 and Persians. This would form a basis for future civilization
                            of the Indians. POPULATION. "The following is an estimate of the entire original population
                            of the Indians in 1650. Algonquins 90,000 ; Eastern Sioux, less than 3,000 ; Iroquois. in-
                            cluding their southern kindred about 17, 000; Catawbas, 3,000. Cherokees, (now more numerous
                            than ever) 12,000 ; Mobilian tribes, 50,000; lichees, 1, 000 ; Natches, 4,000 ; in all,
                            130,000. These were the only nations and tribes then known to the first settlers. Since that
                            time, with the expansion of our territory west, and south, we have embraced numerous Indian
                            nations, some of them quite populous, until their number is nearly doubled according to the
                            last census. The whole number of Indians within the limits of the United States, in 1867,
                            according to the official estimates, was a little more than 300,000. There are about 15,000,
                            in the States East of the Mississippi, principally in New York, Michigan, and Wisconsin ;
                            the remainder, consisting of Cherokees, Choctaws, and Seminoles, being in North Carolina,
                            Mississippi, and Florida. The number in Minnesota and along the frontiers, of the western
                            States, and Texas, is estimated at 30,000. Those on the Plains and among the Rocky
                            Mountains, not within any organized Territory, at 50,000 ; in Texas, at 25,000; in New
                            Mexico, at 30,000; in California, at 78,000 ; in Utah, at 10, 000 ; in Oregon and Washington
                            Territories, at 20,000; Total, 308,000." Ziossing, p. 38. "Where are we to go?" Is it any
                            wonder that this question should be asked by a civilized Chickasaw—one of the five nations
                            in the Indian Territory? when he sees they are surrounded on every hand by the whites, some
                            of whom are enemies in disguise, ready to take every advantage in their power, to block the
                            wheels of progress and stop the car of civilization, regardless of what may become of the
                            future home of the Indians. If he turns his eyes towards the setting sun, he sees the state
                            of California and all the lands bordering on the Pacific Ocean, fast filling up with the
                            whites^ and if he looks beyond these settlements,, the last ray of hope of the Indian is
                            gone—his sun is set forever, he sees nothing beyond but the end of the log, where the white
                            man crowded him off'— a literal fulfillment of a prophetic illustration, given by an Indian
                            long time ago, to represent the encroachment of the whites, in crowding the Indians off of
                            their lands. North Union, O. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My views of prayer" TEIform="index"/>MY VIEWS OF PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patrick, Isabell E." TEIform="persName"/>ISABELL E. PATRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">Prayer is the application of want to him who only can relieve it. The answer to prayer is a
                            confirmation to the mind of man, that there is a higher power which is able to devise ways
                            and means, that are not of our own choosing ; but which ultimately bring us to a point,
                            where we shall learn that man's ways are not as God's ways ; that God is all seeing and
                            knows the vanity of those desires which incline the frail heart, to grope in sin, until
                            seemingly there is no way for escape. But by serious meditation, and earnest prayer to God
                            who alone is able MANIFESTO.<pb n="270" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE 8HAKBE MANIFESTO. to bestow that
                            convicting power, we are redeemed to a virtuous life. Prayer is the soul's sincere
                            breathings to God, either with or without words. It is humiliating, but a soul refining
                            gift. Without a realization of its effects, and the duty which it enjoins upon us, our souls
                            would perish for the want of its support. Therefore, let us consider our dependent
                            condition, and renew our energies to pray unceasingly, that we may be preserved from evil;
                            never indulging in vain thoughts, and assuming to be what we are not. ¦Let us desire the
                            substance obtained by prayer and supplication to Him who knows our needs, and will bestow
                            that power which will save if we persevere in asking his favor to protect us to the end. Of
                            this we have the assurance, if we continue faithful, and submissive, to the will of Grod,
                            that we can stand justified and obtain the blessing which is promised to those who walk
                            uprightly. Prayer is the medium through which we are enabled to find access to God. It fills
                            the heart of the seeker after righteousness, with a satisfaction not to ~be expressed by
                            words, and affords pleasures far superior to those of a worldly nature. It will assuage the
                            deepest sorrow and awaken our sympathies for our fellow beings ; causing us to withdraw from
                            those elements which lead the youthful mind to wander in by and forbidden paths. By this we
                            can see what an effect prayer has wrought in our souls, if we falter not, in striving to
                            subdue every self pleasing desire, and vain imagination of the heart; these are not subject
                            to the law of God nor indeed can be. And if we would be advancing onward, we must be often
                            exercised in earnest, heart-felt prayer to God, for deliverance from the bondage of sin and
                            death. 3nfield, Gt. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>VOICE OF PEACE</head><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Louse indians offered to sell the Black Hills to the government for..." TEIform="index"/>The Louse indians offered to sell the Black Hills to the government for...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Louse Indians offered to sell the Black Hills to the government for 50, 000 Dollars.
                                It was refused, and a war ensued which cost 2,000,000 Dollars.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Love, A." TEIform="persName"/>Official Report, A. Love</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The old time idea has been that there could be but one head in a family..." TEIform="index"/>The old time idea has been that there could be but one head in a family...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The old time idea has been that there could be but one "head in a family, and that the
                                husband, whether right or wrong must rule. The women could only gain their ends by tact
                                and deceit. They trained children to deceive their fathers, and this is why so many
                                practiced embezzlement.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Deyo, Amanda" TEIform="persName"/>Amanda Deyo</byline></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Standing army" TEIform="index"/>STANDING ARMY</head><p TEIform="p">Out of the 19,000 that compose the United States Army, 2,286 are Officers, eight Men to
                                each Officer. The amount paid to Officers, is more than the combined pay of the enlisted
                                men. Voice of Peace. Most of our Indian wars have had their origin in broken promises
                                upon our part. Their advances in civilization have been slow because the treatment they
                                received did not permit it to be faster. We cannot expect them to fol- low our guidance
                                unless we keep faith with them and respect their rights. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hayes, Rutherford B." TEIform="persName"/>President Hayes' Message</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is becoming the public opinion of the civilized world that nations..." TEIform="index"/>It is becoming the public opinion of the civilized world that nations...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is becoming the public opinion of the civilized world that Nations cannot afford to
                                submit their differences to the costly arbitrament of the sword, that nothing is gained
                                by a war of classes to compensate the loss caused by the disturbance of all industrial
                                relations and free institutions. It is a shame to humanity to require men under certain
                                    27O<pb n="271" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> circumstances to fire their own houses, shoot their own
                                father or brother, to meet those whom they have never known or wronged to fight out the
                                quarrels which others have made. (Penn.)</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hartranft, Governor" TEIform="persName"/>Governor Hartranft's Message</byline></div3><div3 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="England has been at war with France 226 years out of 670..." TEIform="index"/>England has been at war with France 226 years out of 670...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">England has been at war with France 226 years out of 670. The declaration of war passes
                                sentence of death on thousands of our innocent fellow creatures. If the legislators who
                                provoke the battle were sent to fight there would be more peace. The battle field is a
                                theater of immense cost for the commission of crime on a grand scale. A concen- tration
                                of all human crimes. It turns man into a beast</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Channing" TEIform="persName"/>Channing</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A fixed idea is like a fixed star which shines brightest in..." TEIform="index"/>A fixed idea is like a fixed star which shines brightest in...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A fixed idea is like a fixed star which shines brightest in the darkest night. The fixed
                                idea of mine I want to say to you is peace from my youth up, the grandest dream of my
                                life has been, no more war, all people, everywhere, occupied in useful labor, in
                                benevolence, in progress, and enjoying prosperity. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hugo, Victor" TEIform="persName"/>Victor Hugo in Paris</byline></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In Italy the government has abolished the Death Penalty" TEIform="index"/>In Italy the government has abolished the Death Penalty
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In Italy the government has abolished the Death Penalty.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The just man says, 'Do not let me hurt'..." TEIform="index"/>The just man says, 'Do not let me hurt'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The just man says, "Do not let me hurt;" the good man says, "Let me bless." The just man
                            says, "Let me take nothing from my fellow men;" the good man says, "Let me bestow much upon
                            them." The just man says, "Let me be pure ;" the good man says, "Let me draw all men into
                            purity." One is equitable; the other is benevolent. One seeks his own perfectness; the other
                            seeks the welfare of those about him.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The minister was telling the story of Mary Magdalene to the children..." TEIform="index"/>The minister was telling the story of Mary Magdalene to the children...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The minister was telling the story of Mary Magdalene to the children, and when he had
                            finished, he wished to ascertain if they had been listening attentively; so he asked, "Now,
                            children, what did Mary have?" Billy Green yelled out, "Mary had a little lamb !"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto: no backward steps" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER MANIFESTO, NO BACKWARD STEPS</head><p TEIform="p">Just now, the spiritual barometer marks a low degree ; few applications of a desirable
                            character are made for membership in any of our Societies. The aged among us are leaving for
                            their homes in the better land, and our numbers are not large. Grand and noble principles
                            remain with us, to be sustained by us in all their regal splendor and unequaled purity; to
                            be transmitted by us, unchanged, unless magnified in excellence, to our successors, who will
                            come, so soon as the world, outside of our body, shall be sufficiently baptized with
                            genuine, Christly revivals, to produce those Worthy to be called "Children of the
                            Resurrection." Successors, of noble forms of mind, of full and fuller consecration we will
                            have. The earth is the Lord's ; and He has "set up His kingdom that shall never be
                            destroyed," nor come to an end. Our system is the needed savor in the world ; the world
                            "looks to us for a testimony ;" and bad will it be for the world should it look therefor and
                            find it not. While resting under the knowledge that it is not in our power to make con-
                            verts to our faith—that unless "the Lord keep the city, the watchman waketh in vain"—that
                            except God converts the heart, all the conviction we bring to bear on the intellect is
                            unprofitable ; nevertheless, under real or imaginary discouragements ; trials of our faith;
                            loneliness, and feelings like those of God bereft, to take any backward steps is a progress
                            unto death. MANIFESTO. 271<pb n="272" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 3 "-'3 THE SHAKKB Our founder, during
                            similar feelings, would shun the surrounding, pitying elements, because they "would pity as
                            God did not!" and against these same ungodly and worldly sympathies, we must pre- sent an
                            unmoved, unbroken front, that through these we may not become willing tools in worldly hands
                            to substitute anything for Christ. About these times the weak-kneed will have misgivings of
                            their power to stand ; and the half-way workers and inconfident will be giving testimonies
                            of uncertain sound. Such will listen to the syren voice of the worldly tempter: "Come down
                            from those crosses, and all men will be Shakers !" Ostensibly, to build up the churches made
                            less in numbers by those disloyal to Christ, some would come down a little ; and a little
                            would mean a little more ; and more, leads inevitably to more and more, until worldliness,
                            in all its corruption would reign supremely. Let no backward steps betaken ; nay, not even
                            to fill every house, and dot every yard of our domains with uncertain, unconsccrated
                            laborers—traitors to Christ and His Cause. The world "look to us for a testimony;" need our
                            influences born of long-continued and godly self-denials ; and if any in the world are saved
                            from the world, flesh and devil, it will be by those same influ- ences, and not at all by
                            our relinquishment of them—by our taking steps world-ward. Few we are ; fewer we may be ;
                            but few or many, let our resolves be to present to the woi'ld living testimonies through our
                            lives, that we have been with Christ and walk with Him daily. Paul pandered to the people in
                            his day, hoping thereby to gain some to the church, but gained none to Christ by so doing.
                            If we go half-way to meet the world, let us take our principles with us —put on the whole
                            armor—and make no compromises with tempting, worldly overtures. If we fail to do so, there
                            will beanother falling away of the church, and another era of dark ages inaugurated. Let us
                            go forward, brim full of denials to worldliness and selfishness ; then God will be with us,
                            and what need we care, who else may be against us ? *</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our mission" TEIform="index"/>OUR MISSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Now is the season, when people can give more thought to self-improvement and religious
                                necessities. TsTow begins the lecture season ; the revival meetings, prayer gatherings,
                                and sincere outpourings of the soul, variously rendered, for more light. "Let there be
                                light." We want to take part in the religious meetings of the people ; we want to be in
                                ten thousands of homes simultaneously, through our representative, The Manifesto. We
                                would willingly meet our friends, desirous of hearing verbal, Shaker testimony, in word,
                                in song and in life-evidences. W'rite us for lecturers ; for singers; and do not fail to
                                write us for a renewal of The Manifesto. Permit us to come to you through its
                                mediumship, if by no other avenue, and we will do you good, our brethren and sisters in
                                nature—all mankind. Send to us your personal subscriptions ; add one more to them this
                                year, and make some other person your everlasting friend.</p></div3><pb n="273" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's second appearing" TEIform="index"/>"Christ's Second Appearing"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Ere we come to our readers, in this our Nov. No. there will have been held in N. Y. city
                                a Convention of sincere souls, who are particularly interested in, and anxious for the
                                coming of Christ the Second time. Led by very prominent ministers of various
                                denominations, the Convention promises to be a very interesting occasion. We shall send
                                delegates thereto, prominent among whom will be . the Elders of the North, Mt. Lebanon.
                                To us, the Shakers, Christ has come already the second time, without sin unto salvation.
                                We are variously experiencing the degrees of this salvation, inasmuch as this spirit of
                                Christ manifests itself to and in our lives. We are anxious to experience more of this
                                Second Advent power ; and anxious that others should do so. We are an invited guest to
                                the Convention ; and if we can attend, will give to our readers in Dec. No. more
                                information thereof, and its probable consequences.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peculiar people" TEIform="index"/>"Peculiar People '</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Shakers, aiming to live superior to carnal, passionate impulses, and above the world,
                                become peculiar as a result; with no intention of being singular as a cause. There are
                                no people, who, as a class of religionists, bring equally to bear on all of its members
                                similarly, the restraints of Christianity that do the Shakers. Bishop Hughes, when
                                living, remarked this feature of our church— all were priests unto an exceeding puri-
                                ty—none marry, nor indulge the flesh ; none, are permitted to fight, wage war nor
                                quarrel; none hold private possessions ; and where but little of the gospel of Christ is
                                active, the name and spirit of mine is cast out, and all is ours. Thus is proved that
                                the wrong comes, not in working for our own comfort, but in not seeking the good of
                                others equally well and in excess of our own. It m. good to be thus peculiar.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>Notice</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We would kindly give notice, that with the issue of this number of The Manifesto and
                                hence, all communications and correspondence relating to ThbSiiaker Manifesto, should be
                                addressed : "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Most kind and affectionate Bro. Albert. I wish with you to ever keep the gospel..." TEIform="index"/>Most kind and affectionate Bro. Albert. I wish with you to ever keep the gospel...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, October 4, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Aver, Mass. Oct. 4, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">Most kind and affectionate Bro. Albert. I wish with you to ever keep the gospel
                                principles alive and growing. How can we hope to reap an easy harvest on the fields
                                where our ancestors felled the forests and drove the wild beasts away? Shall we not grow
                                good, and spend our strength in diffusing good under friendly and favorable condition*?
                                Or is the lash of persecution necessary to stimulate zeal and heroism? If permit- ted,
                                we might diffuse and influence, for good in the open fields near at hand. Clean, white
                                napkins are in order at a refreshment; but not in order to lay away our food in, that we
                                should eat, or give to the needy. Be assured that Eld. Frederick and yourself, and all
                                who attended the Liberal League Convention were inspired by those bold thinkers who have
                                advanced the world. "The demons of our lives become the saints* that we adore." Thanking
                                you for your kindness, pleases ever think of me as one with you in faith. and good,
                                works. Yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline></div3><pb n="274" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers vs Girlingites" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERS vs. GIRLINGITES</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of the Albany Morning Express : Having noticed an article in your paper on
                                "Shakers in England," and seeing that, apparently, the Express is misinformed con-
                                cerning the subject, for the correct information of your readers we would here state
                                that the Girlingites of England have never had any relation to, or connection with the
                                Shakers. As a class of professed Christians, they are entirely distinct, as is many of
                                their principles; and, if we are rightly informed concerning them, their social and
                                sexual relations are the extreme opposite to Shaker principles and practical life. There
                                have never been any "Shakers" in England, other than as visitors, since the demise of
                                the remnant of the little band which Ann Lee left in England when she embarked for
                                America in 1774, and their exit occurred but few years subsequent to that emigration of
                                Ann Lee and the few who accompanied her to this land. Our English, as well as our
                                American public should know that "Shakers," wherever located, are distinguished from all
                                other religious sects, in the fact of the sexes living together in the same dwelling,
                                but in separate rooms, dining in the same hall, at the same time, but at separate tables
                                ; meeting for worship in the same temple and at the same time, uniting in the same
                                worshipful exercises in prayer, praise, song, march and dance, but each sex maintaining
                                a separate collection and association together, not intermingling at all. Thus, in all
                                the relations of life maintaining the strictest virgin purity. If rightfully informed,
                                this is not the practice of the Girlingites of England; but we would not, by any means,
                                decry the Girlingites unjustly; we simply wish "Shakers" to be known as being strict
                                followers of Jesus Christ, whose mission on earth was to intro- duce upon it the kingdom
                                of Heaven, wherein all the relations of the sexes are pure and virginal.</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some one seeing two or three eminent lawyers gathered together..." TEIform="index"/>Some one seeing two or three eminent lawyers gathered together...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some one seeing two or three eminent lawyers gathered together on the side of the new law
                                courts said that they had met to view the ground where they must shortly lie.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Decay of Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>THE DECAY OF SHAKERISM: A Letter From Elder Lomas</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editors of the Albany Morning Express: Your able and sympathetic editorial of the
                                10th inst. upon "The Decay of Shakerism and Quakerism," and your equally well intended
                                but incongruous remarks upon the failure of Shakerism in England, seem to call for a
                                response. Very many in this intelligent age make but little, if any, distinction between
                                Shakers and Quakers, while there is just as wide a difference as between the best of
                                Jews in olden time and primitive Christians. Quakers are modern Jews, while Shakers are
                                a new, and we think improved edition of primitive Christianity, being an organized
                                church. Quakers have been very careful in all times past, until within a few years, to
                                keep their young people from much "worldly" contact, especially in their
                                marriages—rkeeping these so closely under restraint that no marriages could take place
                                between the members of their church and others ; and so long as they succeeded they were
                                able to regulate their passions to the furtherance of su- perior reproductions ; their
                                decline is the more apparent, having had the power to succeed in their own hands. Having
                                lost it, they must of necessity decrease. Quakerism's decay comes from inferior
                                reproductions, caused by its children conforming to the passions and fashions of those
                                much more worldly. Its sticcess is dependent on numbers. Not so with Shakerism. But has
                                Shakerism declined ? We think not. Neither does its success or failure depend on
                                numerical calculations. Depending solely on the waves of spiritual reforms among the
                                people, to wash to its shores, those who MANIFESTO.<pb n="275" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 275
                                would be resurrected from the world, the flesh and the devil, by gladly relinquishing
                                them, the Shakers, numerically, rise and fall according to the spiritual barometer
                                outside of their body. The power for numerical success is not in their hands. Hence, we
                                are fewer or more numerous, several times, both ways in a single decade of years. We are
                                few now ; we have been fewer, and yet several times more numerous. Perhaps this will be
                                the case for all time to come. We do not know why it should not be so. At least six
                                times within one hundred years has the rumor been very prevalent that uthe Shakers are
                                running out." We realize that Shaker influence has been and is felt in the world among
                                the people. In all genuine and superior reforms ; emancipation from bondage ; in church
                                reforms and liberality ; in women's rights movements and co-operative societies, and in
                                the maintenance of sep* aration of Church and State. Shaker testimony has acted like
                                salt among the morals of the people—these have been preserved and improved—the world is
                                better for Shakerism. Besides there are thousands who claim that they "are more than
                                half Shakers," who, Nicodemus-like, come to us through correspondence and privately ;
                                count these, in increasing numbers and give Shakerism credit therefor. We are not on the
                                decline, friend editors, unless forsaking our principles— and for aught that we know
                                these are yet taught and practiced intact—and •when you are tempted to deplore such an
                                event as possible, please take hold of another horn of the dilemma, and sorrow that more
                                of you worldly people are not yet ready for Shakerism. We are following you up, and will
                                continue to do so until we get you into the other world, when and where you all expect
                                to be Shakers, or like them. Concerning your editorial of the 12th, it is an entire
                                mistake to suppose that the Girling woman has anything in common with the Shakers of
                                America. Her principles are not the same, nor has there been anything but a slight
                                similarity in the worship of her followers. Elder Evans' visit to England, some years
                                ago, was in every way a success ;, planting seed that is now bearing valuable fruit, in
                                many who would form, very probably, into successful communities, and who stand waiting
                                and washing for delegations from here to go there to start them, which may soon become a
                                necessity. Yours, Shakers, </p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Albany County, September 20, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Albany Co., Sept. 20,
                                1878.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people and their critics, eigth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE: Her
                            work, her People, and their Critics, Eighth Paper</head><p TEIform="p">Where the Shaker Church at Mt. Lebanon now stands, there was once a building of comfortable
                            proportions possessed by George Darrow. To this house Mother Ann went for the purpose of
                            having a Shaker meeting on the morrow. Scarcely had the day dawned, when a mob began to
                            collect, surrounding the house, and commenced a terrible scene of persecution. The mob
                            consisted of two companies, having each a captain. Their first acts were to seize George
                            Darrow and David Meacham and hustled them off to a Squire Grant, under the false charge that
                            they had committed some grave offense. Then, the balance of the mob, forced their way into
                            the three doors of the house, and as the Chronicler says: "They seized the brethren one
                            after another, and dragged them out with the most savage violence. Richard Spier was thrown
                            out of a high back door three times. Some were drawn out by the MANIFESTO.<pb n="276" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER hair of their heads ; some were taken by four or five persons, one
                            at each arm and leg, and pitched head-foremost into a deep mud puddle ; while many had their
                            clothes badly torn." Mother Ann took refuge in a back, bed room; but the mob tearing away
                            the ceiling between her and them, they found her, and seizing her by the feet, dragged her
                            thus out of doors. They then took her in her own wagon before Grant, abusing her and
                            companions all along the road for a mile and a half, by beating and trying to n-:n over
                            their. James Whittaker was thrown down a precipice ; and though his life was saved, had
                            three of his ribs broken. After various mock trials, Grant ordered Mother Ann and others to
                            be placed under guard for the night; and for this purpose she was dragged along the road for
                            many rods, and up the stairs of an unfinished building in a manner similar to dealing with a
                            dead beast! As all knew, Grant could not hold them upon any of the trumped up charges—and
                            these were "disturbing the peace of the people by singing and shouting along the road at a
                            late hour of the night"—so he dismissed them; at the same time advising the mob to "lay
                            hands suddenly on no man"—emphasizing as printed. The mob took the hint, and there being a
                            woman in the case, they put Mother into a carriage , and drove towards Albany with her for
                            seven miles, choosing the roughest route over stones, stumps, while every little while her
                            persecutors would strike her across the breast causing her great pain. They drove on without
                            stopping for any refreshment; although Mother complained of having had nothing but a few
                            mouthfuls during the day. Passing by a tavern, near the town line, they were heard, by the
                            landlord, abusing the innocent woman ; and he became enraged and threatened them violence if
                            they -did not desist. The mob now having driven them out of the town left them at dark, to
                            seek their own shelter where they could. They received permission of a poor man to lie on
                            the tloors of his log house and barn; here they rested as best they could with their ¦wet,
                            torn and bloody clothes on, passing the night under great distress and suflerings. Eising
                            from their cold, hard berths, the first thing done was to prepare a place, by removing the
                            rubbish in the dooryard, for a meeting! They went forth with great zeal, singing, shouting
                            and dancing witli much joy. Many people assembled, some of whom were so afFected
                            sympathetically at seeing these worship in their uncomfortable plight, that they kneeled
                            down and wept with great sorrow. Soon after this meeting, certain believers arrived from New
                            Lebanon bringing provisions to eat; these were joyfully partaken of, as many had not eaten
                            anything the previous day. After breakfast Mother showed the sisters her bruises. She was
                            black and blue all over her body ! nor was this wondered at, seeing how much she had been
                            dragged and beaten. She wept bitterly, as she said : "So it has been with me nearly ever
                            since I left Niskayuna, day and night—night and day— and I have been like a dying creature!"
                            In the afternoon they returned to New Lebanon to the house of a believer, where they
                            prepared to take some rest; but a mob of some forty persons, called the "Indian Club," in
                            the roughest manner and basest language wanted "to see the old woman!" They threw stones and
                            clubs at the windows and doors, as if determined to break them all in. Nathan Farrington
                            went out stating he was thx owner of the house and forbid their violence and its
                            destruction. Said he : "I have lived as a neighbor with you for years in peace ; but now,
                            because I have joined this people of God, confessed my sins as you ought to do, you come
                            here to break into my house and to abuse my family." The mob became furious ; tore the
                            boards from the house and would have entered with violence; but being threatened with legal
                            proceedings they halted; and further being promised that they might see Mother Ann in the
                            morning the majority withdrew. The next morning eight men came to the house; and Mother Ann
                            went out of the doors and met them. "This is the woman whom you pressed so hard to see last
                            night,' said John Farrington. "What do you want of me?" said Mother Arm; "I am a poor, weak
                            woman; I would not hurt anybody." MANIFESTO. 276<pb n="277" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THP1 SHAKEE 277 The
                            guilty fellows hung their heads, and began to move off; they were invited to stay to
                            breakfast, but they were too much ashamed, and went away. Mother Ann now moved toward
                            Niskayuna, taking with her only a few Elders, advising her people not to follow her, as it
                            was not best thus to stir up the pass^ns of their enemies. Proceeding a short distance, and
                            stopping at a blacksmith's shop to have a shoe set on a horse, the smith began abusing them
                            in language, and threw his tongs at them with such violence that missing their mark. they
                            entered in the ground to the depth of six inches. They moved on. Thus we find that dread
                            persecution still followed them; yet their zeal for the cause never abated. Shocking as
                            these tales appear today, they were more numerous than we have implied. They now moved
                            toward the Hudson river. Arriving at the ferry, a company of Indians espied Mother, whom
                            they must have met before, and manifested their joy by crying out, "The good woman has come
                            !" And to the credit of the Indians, be it ever remembered, they always were friendly, and
                            invariably helped, the Shakers— never did anything to hurt them. Mother and the Elders
                            arrived at Niskayuna, (now Shakers, N. Y.,) on Sept. 4, 1783, having been absent two years
                            and four months; and having passed through multitudes of indescribable persecutions and
                            sufferings, found themselves at home again where they could rest. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers: their creed and other matters of interest" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS. Their Creed
                            and Other Matters of Interest</head><p TEIform="p">The following very kind notice is copied from the N. Y. Times, which declines our pleasant
                            invitation of last month to "perse. cute us just a little." The statements in the main, are
                            very concise and correct; but those figures! The correspondent must have become a convert to
                            materialization of spirits, or counted those "not of our fold as yet," when he made such an
                            estimate of our numbers. We think, for the good of America, we ought to number about so
                            many. We have not numbered our Israel of late and we hope the correspondent may be correct,
                            in the prospective at least. That very singular body of persons, commonly known as
                            Shakers—their proper name is the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing
                            —is said to have materially increased since 1870, and to number now nearly 12,000. This is
                            remarkable, inasmuch as, believing and rigidly adhering to celibacy, they can recruit their
                            ranks only by external accretion. They have 18 separate settlements (the sect is confined
                            entirely to the United States), of which there are two in Maine, two in New Hampshire, four
                            in Massachusetts, one in Connecticut, three in this state, four in Ohio and two in Kentucky.
                            They believe the kingdom of heaven has been established ; that Christ has come upon earth a
                            second time in the form of Mother Ann (Ann Lee, an English woman, born in Manchester, was
                            the founder of the sect, having emigrated thence with a small band of disciples shortly
                            before the revolutionary war), and that the personal reign of God has been restored. They
                            believe, also, that the new dispensation has begun, that Adam's sin has been atoned; that
                            man has been delivered from ali errors except his own ; that the earth and all it contains
                            shall be redeemed. This would seem to be a comfortable sort of creed, and they hold it most
                            sincerely. To their peculiar mind there is no death, what appears to be death being merely a
                            change of form, a transfiguration, which does not conceal them from the purified eyes of the
                            saints. They look for no resurrection ; nor have they any faith in heaven beyond what they
                            call ''living in union," which MANIFESTO.<pb n="278" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 378 THE SHAKER is their
                            present state of existence. Upon entering into union, they think they leave behind all
                            earthly relationships and interests, just as if they had been separated from these by death.
                            Those who have "passed out of sight,' as they phrase it, are still in union ; and the
                            Shakers have perfect faith that they dwell in daily communion with spirits of the departed.
                            Indeed, they profess to be more familiar with the dead than with the living. Labor is, in
                            their eyes, more than noble—it is sacred—a sacerdotal function, especially when employed
                            upon the soil in adding to its abundance and beauty. Consistently with their faith is the
                            second appearance of Christ in the form of a woman, they believe there is a feminine, as
                            well as a masculine essence in the Grod-head, a motherhood, not less than fatherhood, of
                            Deity, which would seem to be a sort of compromise with the Roman Catholic doctrine. The so-
                            ciety is mainly increased by girls and young men ; but married couples likewise join it,
                            becoming then as brothers and sisters. They are almost invariably noted for virtue,
                            conscientiousness, health, prosperity, and contentment. They are the sole people on this
                            continent, if not on 'the face of the globe, who for more than seventy years have lived
                            together harmoniously on the fundamental principle of community of property.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Connecticut man, whose death was falsely reported in a newspaper..." TEIform="index"/>A Connecticut man, whose death was falsely reported in a newspaper...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A Connecticut man, whose death was falsely reported in a newspaper, writes: "It's a mistake.
                            I've no thought of dying. I couldn't afford it, when funeral expenses are up higher than a
                            kite, and potatoes worth only fifty cents a bushel in Waterbury."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter X" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName">WILLIAM G. LIBBEY</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">My feelings were changed, as I stood in this high gap looking down upon the pleasant val-
                                leys that lie directly back of Parpatie. On my first visit, my good shipmate Francis Ly-
                                on was with me, and we breathed the air of uncertainty concerning the kind of welcome
                                awaiting us, when our ship should depart. Now I was quite at rest in mind about those
                                natives whom I had found very kind; forgiving, if not forgetting the hard knocks they
                                had received at our hands three years before. They really had no grudge against us. They
                                wanted the sixteen dollars for our seizure ; having obtained this they were satisfied.
                                Here was the very place where Francis and I had remained six days waiting for the de-
                                parture of our ship. Near by, on the steep mountain side, was a barren cocoa-nut tree
                                which I had climbed the first day we came. It was noon, and very hot, we were suffering
                                from thirst. No one who has not seen a tall cocoa-nut tree on a steep height, can form a
                                just idea of the nerve and agility it costs to reach the top. Yet hunger and thirst
                                helps ¦wonderfully sometimes, and did in this case. I had thrown down several nuts when
                                I heard Francis in a very subdued voice say : "Come down, the nuts are all blighted."
                                There was no nutrition in them, nothing but a dry shell! I have often thought of that-
                                barren tree, in comparison with the fig tree of old,—we were so nearly famished. But we
                                soon found a tree much easier to climb, and bearing good nuts. After having satisfied
                                our thirst with the water of the cocoa-nuts, we found some fugees, which was a real
                                treat. ^ This fruit is a species of the Plantain, shaped like the banana, more
                                nutritious, but not as pleasant MANIFESTO.<pb n="279" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                iMAJSTXEPJECST'O. 279 to the taste. It is a staple food with the natives, growing wild
                                through all the highlands of these islands When we finished our repast, it was quite
                                dark; having no time to build a shelter we ¦crawled under a very thick bush, making our
                                beds of tall grass that grew on this terrace in great abundance. Some time past
                                midnight, we were aroused by a terrific thunder showier that seemed to break directly
                                over us. The rain poured in torrents, but there was too much of the sailor in us to
                                wince at any amount of rain drops ; so as we sat crouched under that bush waiting for
                                daylight, a sense of our ridiculous appearance came over us, and we laughed heartily.
                                The morning was bright and clear. The tropical sun came out with just enoilgh warmth to
                                be delightfully pleasant. We built us a nice shelter hut of palm-leaves, and here we
                                remained during the week, watching for the departure of our old ship Phenix. We had
                                never been down on what was called the back side of Eimeo, from the mountains to the
                                sea-shore; yet we found the way without any difficulty although mostof the way lay
                                through a heavy growth of tropical forest trees. We passed many scattering orange tree*
                                growing wild. The fruit was delicious. It is said that these islands produce the finest
                                in the world. We reached Matear late in the afternoon— too late to go to Affraito. As
                                Edward was going there in the morning I gave him the money entrusted with me for the
                                purchase of the shoes. Our worthy countryman, James Martin, previous to our coming to
                                Eimeo had cleared up about an acre and a half of ground and planted two sweet potatoes.
                                These were now our staple article of food, yet, we generally managed to provide meat or
                                fish at our two daily meals. Our company now commenced clearing a piece of new land
                                which contained about two acres. It was covered with guava bushes, burow trees, and many
                                other varieties of tropical vegetation peculiar to these islands. All this tangled mass
                                was to be cleared off by hand labor, as we had no team of any kind to assist us. However
                                we worked away cheerfully with such tools as we could procure at AfFraito. These were
                                awkward enough. The axes were long-bitted, strange, unwielding things in our hands, who
                                had been accustomed to use the improved American ax. The mattocks were heavy enough for
                                the strength of a plantation negro ;—yet we soon cleared and dug up a large piece of
                                this black earth which was very good soil for sweet potatoes. Our labor yielded us a
                                fine crop. There is so little variation in the seasons here, that vegetables can be
                                grown any month in the year. Hearing that there were whale ships in the harbor of
                                Parpatie, we loaded the schooner boat with sweet potatoes, and started inside the reef
                                for the bay, where we expected to find a market for them. We had a tall, good tempered
                                native for a pilot, whose son, a fine lad of seven or eight years, sat on the forecastle
                                of the boat keeping a bright look out for the small coral reefs, through which we passed
                                in safety. As we were unable to reach Parpatie the first day, we camped late in the
                                afternoon on a nice sand beach, near a native house. Having made a tent of our boat
                                sails, the pilot in the meantime cooked our supper of sweet potatoes. After a
                                comfortable night's rest, we arose early and continued our voyage. We soon reached a
                                small island, covered with a kind of tree called by the natives Hoe. The leaves resemble
                                our pine very much. The ground was-covered with them, reminding us of a pine forest in
                                our Northern home. It was a very nice place to camp. There were no insect pests to
                                torment us. Our pilot soon made an oven and filled it with sweet potatoes. These with
                                meat and fish brought on shore formed a very refreshing repast. On our return to Matear,
                                we went by way of the Itoe island, crossing the mouth of Cook's bay. This bay was named
                                for Capt. Cook no doubt, for his ships anchored in the same harbor where we sold our
                                boat load of sweet potatoes. On the west side of this harbor is located the "Simpson
                                mission." Near this place, lived an aged native who had some very nice Pampam trees
                                growing around his little hut, the fruit of which was excellent and had often supplied
                                the wants of mvself and shinmates of t\:.eld Phcuii:.<pb n="280" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> S8O THE
                                SHAKBE MANIFESTO. This aged man, whose name was Bobo, stated that when Captain Cook's
                                ships anchored in Parpatie, he went alongside of one, in his canoe, and thumped on it
                                with his paddle, to see if it was hollow. He could not understand how such great vessels
                                or canoes, as he thought them to be could be built. After crossing Cook's bay, we kept
                                inside the reef until we reached Affraito, the home of our good triend Sanders. Having
                                housed the boat, covering it with leaves of the cocoa palm, we went home to Matear, a
                                distance of about two miles. Here we continued to work hard clearing land for a new
                                potato piece. Our food was bread fruit, sweet potatoes, and fars, the latter, a
                                vegetable shaped like a sugar beet, grown by the natives, in beds of mud, kept wet by
                                irrigation from a brook that ran past our house. The natives gave more attention to
                                raising this root, than to any other branch of farming, or in fact, to any other kind of
                                work. Nature having dealt . so kindly with them, that their simple wants were nearly all
                                supplied from her bountiful lap. We had fish every meal, and for drink, cold water from
                                the brook above mentioned, this we procured ia a piece of bamboo, eight or ten feet
                                long, precisely like a cane pole, such as we use for fishing rods, only larger in
                                diameter. By balancing our bamboo on the fence, and tipping it very gently with the
                                mouth, we could drink; but the skill required to do this successfully could very
                                properly be classed with the exact sciences. For if we tipped the bamboo a trifle too
                                much, the water would come with a rush wetting us from head to foot. But we soon learned
                                how to manage, and we had many a good drink from our long bamboo bucket. Our good
                                friends had an old flintlock musket, with which I managed to shoot several goat and wild
                                cattle which abounded on these mountains. I made a nice hammock of the skin of one
                                animal and suspended it in our house making a comfortable sleeping place, compared Avith
                                our lodgings on the ground which swarmed with insects. The very dirt seemed alive with
                                fleas, and the musquitoes were so troublesome that sometimes we were forced to go to the
                                beach and make our beds on the sand, as salt water is death to fleas, while the fresh
                                trade winds would blow the musquitoes back to the woods. My ram-hide hammock is noticed
                                in a book written by Hermann Melville who was at Tahiti when we were at Eimeo. From his
                                account of meeting us, I will quote the following : "I met two Yankee lads, twins, who
                                had left their ship on Fanning's island, and after wandering about among the islands,
                                hailed last from Eimeo, where they had been engaged farming." (to be continued.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good news for vegetarians" TEIform="index"/>Good news for Vegetarians</head><p TEIform="p">Jews have refrained from the eating of oysters because a verse of scripture forbids the
                                eating of creatures living in the water that "have not fins or scales ;" but an English
                                rabbi has released his "flock" from this aggravating deprivation by declaring the oyster
                                to be a plant.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daily striving" TEIform="index"/>Daily Striving</head><p TEIform="p">Wait not for some great cross to show How much with patience thou canst bear; Try now thy
                                strength in bending low To take the cross of daily care ; It may seem poor and small
                                instead, But it may yet more needful be To train thee, first of all, to tread The path
                                of true humility. Sunday at Home.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tell what you know" TEIform="index"/>Tell what you know&gt;</head><p TEIform="p">The world craves positive teachings, and not the dreariness of negations. Goethe ex-
                                pressed this idea when he said : "I will listen to any one's convictions ; but pray keep
                                your doubts to yourself. I have plenty of mine own." Direct teachings are like centres
                                of force and influence, but negations are like leaden weights, burdening the traveler,
                                and drowning the swimmer.</p></div3><pb n="281" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unreason and reason" TEIform="index"/>Unreason and Reason</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Paine, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Paine</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">This is the lesson that's taught us By those who the pulpits do fillThat for
                                        every wrong that's done by us Kind Jesus will settle the bill! But reason
                                        refuses the credit, And holds us, our contracts to fill— And I think, at the Day
                                        of the Judgment I'll find I must pay my own bill!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Common sense" TEIform="index"/>Common Sense</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beecherisms" TEIform="index"/>Beecherisms</head><p TEIform="p">There is an'ugly kind of forgiveness in this world,—a kind of hedgehog forgiveness, shot
                                out like quills. Men take one who has offended and set him down before the blowpipe of
                                their indignation and scorch him, anc burn his fault with him: and, when they have
                                kneaded him sufficiently with their fiery fists, then—they forgive him. There are many
                                persons who think they are Christians because they have had experience ; but they do not
                                feel it to be their Christian duty to use their tongues according to the laws of
                                kindness. Nor do they think, in the confession of their sins, to confess that day in and
                                day out, they are making somebody unhappy by the manner in which they use that
                            member.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why not forgive him?" TEIform="index"/>WHY NOT F0RGIVE HIM?</head><p TEIform="p">Why not forgive your brother, If he comes to you in sorrow? Why not your anger smother
                                Ere the dawning of to-morrow? You say he has reviled you Your dearest friends among; But
                                has error ne'er beguiled you? Have you ne'er committed wrong? Why not forgive him? He is
                                penitent and humble, He is weak and in your power— Who is not apt to stumble When
                                passion rules the hour? He wronged you in his blindness ; Now act the Christian's part,
                                And pour the balm of kindness On his sad, repentant heart. Why not fotgiva him? Can you
                                look for sweet contentment, Or can love your bosom fill, While you cherish fierce
                                resentment For the one who treats you ill? No ! spite of proud position, Of place, or
                                power, or pelf, Unblest is your condition Till you triumph o'er yourself. Why not
                                forgive him? With his grief his heart is riven, And can you with reason pray That your
                                sins may be forgiven When from him you turn away? Vaunt not your pure condition, Nor
                                back forgiveness keep— Think of Heaven's admonition, As ye sow so shall ye reap." Why
                                not forgive him?</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can you read?" TEIform="index"/>CAN YOU READ?</head><p TEIform="p">A student at the theological seminary at Andover, who had an excellent opinion of his own
                                talent, on one occasion asked the professor who taught elocution; "What do I specially
                                need to learn in this department?" "You ought just to learn to read," said the
                                professor. "Oh, I can read now," replied the student. The professor handed the young man
                                a testament, and pointing to Luke 24:24, he asked him to read that. The student read :
                                "Then he said unto them, 0 fools and slow of heart to believe all that the prophets have
                                spoken." "Ah," said the professor, "they were fools for believing the prophets, were
                                they?" Of course that was not right, and so the young man tried again. "0 fools, and
                                slow of heart to believe all ;hat the prophets have spoken." "The prophets, then, were
                                sometimes iars?" asked the professor. "No. 0 fools, and slow of heart to beieve all that
                                the prophets have spoken." "According to this reading," the professor iuggested, "the
                                prophets were notorious iars." This was not a, satisfactory conclusion, and : another
                                trial was made. "0 fools, and MANIFESTO.<pb n="282" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER slow of heart
                                to believe all that the prophets have spoken." "I see, now," said the professor, "the
                                prophets wrote the truth, but they spoke falsehoods." This last criticism discouraged
                                the student, and he acknowledged that he did not know how to read."</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lifeless preaching" TEIform="index"/>Lifeless Preaching</head><p TEIform="p">The following is from the N. Y. Herald: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A preacher who has often suspected himself of being one of the prosy ones
                                        desires to thank the Herald for its late protest against long and lifeless
                                        sermons. Such efforts are as tiresome to the preacher as they are to the people;
                                        but custom being what it is, it is very probable that if any minister were to
                                        change his pulpit manner, and say in plain, unadorned style whatever might seem
                                        to him appropriate to the needs of his congregation some worthy parishioners
                                        would find fault •with him for not doing as his predecessors have done from time
                                        immemorial. Public opinion alone can change the prevalent pulpit manner for one
                                        that has more life and Usefulness, and as public opinion cannot in any other way
                                        be so easily influenced as through the press, let the Herald and other papers
                                        agitate the subject until sermons become as pointed as editorials.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York herald" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To see ourselves" TEIform="index"/>'To See Ourselves."</head><p TEIform="p"> The intoxication of anger, like that of wine shows us to others, but hides us from
                                ourselves; and we injure our own cause in the opinion of the world, when we too pas-
                                sionately or eagerly defend it. Neither will men be disposed to view our quarrels in the
                                light that we do; and a man's blindness to his own defects, will ever increase in
                                proportion as he is angry with others, or pleased with himself. It is easier to pretend
                                to be what you are not, than to hide what you really are; he that can accomplish both
                                has little to learn in hypocrisy.—Laxon. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beware of evil thoughts..." TEIform="index"/>Beware of evil thoughts...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Beware of evil thoughts. They have done great mischief in the world. Bad words follow,
                                and bad deeds finish the progress. Watch against them, strive against them, pray against
                                them. They prepare the way for the enemy of souls. Is there, in truth, any blessing of
                                Heaven which is more beautiful, more worthy of our warmest gratitude, than the
                                possession of a home where goodness, kindness and joy are daily inmates ; where friends,
                                not merely by words but by actions, say to each other, ''Thy goodness, thy sorrow, thy
                                hope, thy prayer, are also mine?"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bremer, Frederika" TEIform="persName"/>—Frederika Breme". </byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The call for a new religion has been made..." TEIform="index"/>The call for a new religion has been made...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The call for a new religion has been made; but the bids are not all in. James Freeman
                                Clarke read this at the last Unitarian Convention held at Saratoga : "The New Theology
                                will be Christian—that is still the greatest force of the world—but it will not be in
                                the line of creeds ; it has outgrown them. The historic Christ is, however, not
                                outgrown. He will still be the central force and pnver, as he is the central figure in
                                human history. One life like that of Jesus lifts men forever to a higher plane. He
                                brought and brings God to men, and all attempts to discredit.his work will be
                            futile."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make cloth waterproof" TEIform="index"/>To make Cloth Water-proof</head><p TEIform="p"> —In a bucket of soft water, put one half pound sugar of lead, one half pound powdered
                                alum—stir at intervals until clean. Pour off into another bucket, put in the garment and
                                let it remain twenty-four hours, then hang up to dry without wringing. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chillblains" TEIform="index"/>Chilblains</head><p TEIform="p">—The best remedy for this disagreeable infirmity is fire. Hold the feet as near the fire,
                                and as long as can be borne. Let them cool, and do so again, and yet again. This
                                followed for three or four successive nights, accompanied by dry stockings in the
                                morning will cure the worst case. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement for joining glass" TEIform="index"/>Cement for joining Glass</head><p TEIform="p">—Dissolve fineMANIFESTO. 282<pb n="283" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> TH.E1 SHAKEE M^NTF'ICS'XO. SS3 ly
                                powdered Gum Copal in three times its weight of Sulphuric Ether: apply tothe edges of
                                the broken glass with a camels-hair pencil, put. the pieces together immediately, and
                                press closely till they adhere. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our diet" TEIform="index"/>Our Diet</head><p TEIform="p"> —Chemical analysis discloses the fact that among the many articles used as food there
                                are only two, wheat and milk, which contains all the elements of the human body, and in
                                the proper proportion. Other articles, such as butter, sugar, syrup, and fat of all
                                kinds, are wholly carbonaceous, or heat producing, so that if a human being were to
                                attempt to live on these articles alone his brain and muscles would starve. By actual
                                experiment it has been found that a man could not survive two months on such a diet.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brown bread" TEIform="index"/>Brown Bread&gt;</head><p TEIform="p">—2 qts. Indian meal. 1 qt. rye meal. 1 pt. canaille, mix with scaldinghot sweet milk,
                                stir with a pudding stick till quite a stiff batter. Bake in iron pans seven or eight
                                hours. A soap-stone oven is best; but if you bake in a stove oven keep a steady heat.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lemon custard" TEIform="index"/>Lemon Custard</head><p TEIform="p">—Two white potatoes grated, the rind and juice of two lemons, two eggs, one cup sugar.
                                Line the pie-plate with good crust, pour in the custard and bake. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hot water sponge cake" TEIform="index"/>Hot Water Sponge Cake</head><p TEIform="p">—Break two eggs into a dish, add a coffee cup of sugar, beat well, then pour into that
                                one half cup of boiling water stirring briskly. Add one and one half cups of sifted
                                flour and two teaspoonfuls baking powder. Bake three fourths of an hour.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Roughton, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>Annie Roughton, Phila.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Catarrh" TEIform="index"/>Catarrh
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Catarrh.—Water, made quite salt, is the best known remedy for nasal catarrh. Use as a
                                douche several times in a day ; it will remove largely the very unpleasant, effect in
                                company of one afflicted with it, and has cured in many eases. It is pretty generally
                                believed, that most catarrhal remedies are composed largely of salt water, with other
                                materials thrown in to hide the simple, but effective agency. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weak eyes" TEIform="index"/>Weak Eyes</head><p TEIform="p">—Bathe in soft water, that is sufficiently impregnated with spirits of camphor to be
                                discernible to the smell—teaspoonful of spirits of camphor to tumbler of water. For
                                inflamed eyes use milk and camphor, adding a little more ot the camphor than above' Let
                                the baths enter the eyes freely. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Composition tea" TEIform="index"/>Composition Tea</head><p TEIform="p">—This almost universal remedy of the Shakers, and which has been sought for by so many
                                thousands as a panacea for colds, coughs, lung irregularities and inflammations, is now
                                made public : Take two pounds of bayberry root bark, one pound of the inner bark of
                                hemlock, one pound of ginger, two ounces of Cayenne pepper, all reduced to a powder and
                                sifted through a fine sieve. Mix well together. Dose: One teaspoonful, in a
                                half-teacupful of hot water; add milk and sugar to please the taste, and drink, as warm
                                as consistent. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soaking potatoes" TEIform="index"/>Soaking Potatoes</head><p TEIform="p"> —The common practice of paring potatoes, and leaving them for hours, and sometimes for
                                days, reduces their value exceedingly as food. Solon Eobinsort in "How to live" tells us
                                that meat, fish, potatoes, and else, when left for twelve hours in water, impart to the
                                water half their value. If, then, they are left to soak longer than twelve hours, there
                                is more value in the water which is commonly thrown away, than in the article to be
                                cooked. So far as the cooking of potatoes is in question, those who soak them for hours,
                                are worthy of beingcalled very poor cooks ; as a comparison between the tubers soaked
                                and unsoaked will abundantly testify.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our opinions of vegetables and fruits" TEIform="index"/>Our Opinions of Vegetables
                                &amp; Fruits</head><p TEIform="p">We have heretofore been favorably impressed with the Trophy and Canada Victor tomatoes.
                                Acknowledging these to be good' I still, we have proved this season that the ! Acme is
                                superior to any other variety known<pb n="284" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 284 THE SHAKER "The Types of
                                Christ," which appeared a our August No, has been put in pamphlet to us. If there is a
                                better, we would be glad to know it. We have tested the New Melon, The Surprise—and were
                                disappointed at finding it inferior to the Sills' Hybrid. This latter, while not so
                                juicy as the Green-Fleshed * Nutmeg, is every way its superior; and as a universal
                                Musk-melon, we should deem it unequaled. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Greeley Mohawk grape has been the wonder of many this season..." TEIform="index"/>Our Greeley Mohawk grape has been the wonder of many this season...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Our Greeley Mohawk Grape has been the •wonder of many this season, in earliness and
                                quality. It was ripe fully two weeks ahead of the Concord; and though not so noble in
                                form of bunch as this latter, is valuable as a predecessor. The Monarch Strawberry
                                proved fully equal in siz^e to reports; but there was an unequal ripening about it, that
                                hurts its reputation somewhat. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Drilling in fall grain" TEIform="index"/>Drilling in Fall Grain</head><p TEIform="p">—It has been proven, beyond dispute, that enough more grain is harvested from fields that
                                are drilled in, in excess of those sown broadcast, so that in 150 acres the excess would
                                buy a drill. Can this be so!</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No two places can produce the same kind of wool..." TEIform="index"/>No two places can produce the same kind of wool...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">No two places can produce the same kind of wool. The United States cannot raise all the
                                wool it consumes, because it does not raise all kinds. This country can, however,
                                produce all the wool it needs when it ignores ¦ Paris as the headquarters of fashion.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="You can get a very good idea of 'natural selection'..." TEIform="index"/>You can get a very good idea of 'natural selection'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">You can get a very good idea of "natural selection" in its practical workings by viewing
                                a celery glass after it has been once around the table. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The day is certainly not far distant..." TEIform="index"/>The day is certainly not far distant...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Professor E. W. Stewart, of Lake View, N. Y. says: "The day is certainly not far distant
                                when all enterprising farmers will soil their stock to a great extent. The best way to
                                soil is to begin raising grain. Make a calculation as to how much corn and other grain
                                crops you will require, raise good crops and you will soon see the folly of using three
                                to five acres to pasture a cow when she can be soiled on a half acre.</p></div3><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advantages of a feed-cutter" TEIform="index"/>Advantages of a Feed-cutter</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., A." TEIform="persName"/>"A. D."</byline><p TEIform="p">Du Quoin, 111., writes, that in 1871, he had h MANIFESTO. 30 acres of land, 4 cows, and a
                                pair of mules, for which he found it difficult to provide fodder. For economy, he bought
                                a feed cutter, and then had plenty of feed and increased his stock. This increased his
                                manure, and that doubled the supply of feed. The stock was again added to, and at
                                present there are 22 head of cattle and horses on the 30 acres, and more feed than can
                                he used. He now has a steam engine attached to a large-sized cutter. His prosperity
                                dates from the day he used a fodder cutter. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the removal of stable stains..." TEIform="index"/>For the removal of stable stains...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For the removal of stable stains from a gray or white horse apply a thick paste of finely
                                powered charcoal and water; let it dry and rub off with brush or wisp of straw, and the
                                discoloration will be found to have entirely disappeared.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heaves" TEIform="index"/>Heaves</head><p TEIform="p">While other remedies may cure, the simple feeding of cornstalks, cut small and wet with
                                hot water, will dissipate the heaves in a short time. Yet a return to hay will reproduce
                                them. Let those with horses .so troubled, feed cornstalks, wetted, with coarse bran
                                added.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lice on poultry" TEIform="index"/>Lice on Poultry</head><p TEIform="p">The best as well as easiest remedy for getting rid of vermin on fowls, and keeping them
                                clear afterward, is first to clean and whitewash the roosts, adding a liberal supply of
                                salt to the wash. Then have the entrance to and from these roosts sufficiently small,
                                that a sponge saturated with kerosene oil, hung over the entrance would come in contact
                                with the back of each fowl every time it goes in or out. We know this to be a most
                                excellent remedy. Supply the sponge with oil once a week. Hens with chickens, not before
                                hatching, should be liberally smeared with a mixture of lard oil and kerosene,
                                immediately on leaving the nest. The chicks will show a rapid and lealthy growth, being
                                free from gapes and pip.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Types of Christ" TEIform="index"/>The Types of Christ</head><p TEIform="p">.<pb n="285" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE S85 form, beautifully covered, and is being sent from this
                                office, post paid, for seven cents. The Central Bishopric of our Church give this little
                                work the most encouraging approval, and wish that the limited number of copies may have
                                the widest circulation. We should be glad to receive orders for the same; and hope
                                wherever the pamphlet goes, great good will accrue. Brethren, Friends, Inquirers, shall
                                we hear from you? </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treatise on the horse and his diseases" TEIform="index"/>Treatise on the horse and his diseases
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kendall, R. J." TEIform="persName"/>R. J. Kendall, M. D</byline><p TEIform="p"> This is a .small, but comprehensive work upon what its title appertains. It is full of
                                information, giving numerous illustrations of the horse's appearance in various kinds of
                                sickness, lameness ; and showing by the teeth, an infallible rule in finding the age of
                                the animal; also giving twenty pages of valuable receipts for cures, 'and a complete
                                glossary describing the medicines recommended. We have the opinion of Chauncy Copley,
                                our best authority on the horse, that "the book is a valuable one, well worth the
                                money." Its price ^s within the reach of the poorest farmer, and is worth the
                                consideration and reference of those in better circumstances. Copies will be sent, in
                                paper, for Twenty Five Cents ; in cloth for Fifty Cents, by addressing The Shaker
                                Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wateseka wonder" TEIform="index"/>Wateseka wonder
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stevens, E. W." TEIform="persName"/>E. W. Stevens</byline><p TEIform="p">A startling, instructive, psychological study, and well authenticated instance of
                                spiritualistic visitation ; being a narrative of the leading phenomena occurring in the
                                case of Mary Lurancy Vennum, , price 15 cents, published by the Keligio-Philosophical
                                Publishing House, Chicago, 111. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ethics of spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>Ethics of spiritualism
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davis, Andrew Jackson" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Jackson Davis</byline><p TEIform="p">Religio-Philosophical Publishing House, Chicago, 111. " have just read your announcement
                                concerning the series of articles you will soon begin to publish from the ever-active
                                and thoroughly honest pen of Brother Hudson Tuttle. He is a farmer, and knows how to
                                plow and sow and reap; a grape-grower, and can discriminate between good and bad fruit.
                                He writes from the fullness of the sj.irit, and therefore he constantly rises above the
                                clouds of materialism. He is no sophist, no hairsplitting apologist for the loose
                                practices of mankind, and so you may look for the highst and most philosophical
                                statement of the morality from his faithful pen ; and the comfort is great when one
                                reflects and knows to a certainty that Hudson Tuttle is no hypocrite, and hence is
                                always personally as good as his written word."Price in Cloth 60 cts. paper, 40 cts</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel of common sense: or Jesus as a liberal" TEIform="index"/>The gospel of common
                                sense: or Jesus as a liberal."</head><p TEIform="p">The above is the title of our address delivered at the Watkins' Convention; and was
                                published in the Religo-Philosophical Journal, Chicago, 111. for Oct. 12. Those desirous
                                of reading it will do well if they can secure a copy of that paper, price eight cents.
                                It is "plain, radical, and should be read by everybody;" so says our companion
                                there—Elder F. W. Evans. It will not appear in The Manifesto—it is too lengthy. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society Record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Shakers, N. Y. Perhaps, no year has passed, when larger assemblages from strangers and
                                neighbors met with us at our Church on Sundays. With very many who come/Jit cannot be
                                mere curiosity that attracts them, for they are very regular attendants. We have
                                established a stand for the disposal of "Plain Talks," "Brief Exposition," and copies of
                                The Manifesto at cost. We urge other Societies to do so ; for by it we can circulate our
                                ideas, and thereby defray the cost of a number or two of The Manifesto. Alfred, Me.
                                Considerable moving of buildings, with other improvements at this place, will greet
                                visitors hereafter with pleasant surprise. The gospel lives here also.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Obituary</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Montgomery, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Montgomery
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At North Union, Ohio, Oct. 5, 1878, <persName reg="Montgomery, Joseph" TEIform="persName">Joseph
                                Montgomery</persName>, aged 68 years. </p></div3></div2><pb n="286" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peaceful victory" TEIform="index"/>PEACEFUL VICTORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Rise ye waves of joyful music! 2. Stay the work of desolation, Roll
                            to earth's remotest Still the pulse of fevered! bound, Bearing notes of peaceful victory To the jarring kingstrife, Where the marshaled hosts are treading, Crushing virtue,
                            hope doms round; Thrill the air with strains of gladness, Swell and life; Reason's rule a
                            loud proclaiming, Arthe blessed song of peace, Till the nations own its power,
                            bitratioa's peaceful sway Opens now the pearly portal<pb n="287" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 28? And all sound of discord cease. To the bright approaching day. Come ye
                            spirits brave and earnest, Work with purpose Haste O day of golden promise ! 4. Prophecy of
                            human weal; Swords shall be to ploughshares beaten, Spears to pruning hooks of steel; Then
                            as time with budding glory Brings the coming years' increase, Men shall march to fields of
                            labor, Learning there the arts of peace. Earth shall smile in youthful beauty, Ocean sing
                            from shore to shore To a brotherhood united, Peace, goodwill forevermore; Fruitful fields
                            and verdant valleys, Mountain, plain and flowing stream, Prospered homes and gladsome labor*
                            Will the praise of peace redeem. true and strong, God will bless your faithful labors,
                            Right shall triumph over wrong. </p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p28"/>
                        <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Editorials"/>Editorial Notes</head>
                        <div3 type="editorial">
                            <head>
                                <index level1="We are using a number of Tele Bickford knitting machines..."/>
                            </head>
                            <byline>
                                <persName reg="Editor"/>
                            </byline>
                            <p>We are using a number of Tele Bickfokd KnittingMachines; and they u.ve very satisfactory indeed, Being among
                                "the wonders in this age" of machinery. Their utility and expedition in business should be experienced by
                                all, ai so smull coat. Material for Fences of wood variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the
                                alternative of no fences, or rely on the metal ones offered us by Wash burn, Mokn Co. We are at a loss to
                                speak as yet, of the best Water Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the firms ol Leffel & Co.
                                and X. F. Buruham, who enter into friendly competition in our columns, are both moat honorable. We find
                                Stinson and Co. very honorable in their dealing. ' Try'them. We hope "everybody and his neighbor" will send
                                us six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for two copies post paid. It is a pretty book.
                                Please procure it and present it to your friend. We are able to speak of the various agricultural implements
                                of Wheeler & Melick Co., and of West- inghouse manufacture. We have tested their Threshers and
                                Powers for years, and found them unexcelled. We would call especial attention to the new advertisement of N.
                                F. Burnham. As enterprise is ever praiseworthy when applied as they apply it, let every one lend this firm a
                                token of praise. If any can do better for the furnishing of Dry Goods, etc. than can be done at Win. M.
                                Whitney & Co., we would be pleased to hear from such party. Take choice and choose soon from among
                                the most beautiful musical instruments advertised in our columns. Quite a number of families are the happier
                                to-day for taking our advice, and buying their Organs and Pianos of - well "read and you will know.' D.
                                H. Fonda, the most enterprising of Druggists, etc. can be relied upon by parties, nearby or distant, who are
                                in want of anything m his line, wholesale and retail. Try him, prove him. Any parties who would learn how we
                                make such good, "gilt-edged" butter, must read an article entitled "OUt-Edged Butter Maker" Gillott's Pens
                                are unequaled by any other steel pen, and we deem his No. 332 equal in every thing but wear, to the best
                                gold pen. Get Gillott's Pens. </p>
                        </div3>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>