<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0303" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18730301" TEIform="date">March 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. III. No. 3. F. W. EVANS, Editor. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y.. March, 1873
                        Fifty Cents per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="English spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>ENGLISH SPIRITUALISM "It does move."</head><p TEIform="p">The contest that is raging in England between Protestant skeptics and Spiritualists in
                            relation to supernatural events, is not generally known by Americans, both parties being
                            firm believers in the principles involved, and in the facts produced by them in the past.
                            The Church of England and its sectarists, are continually and persistingly teaching faith in
                            the "miracles" and spiritualistic phenomena of former ages, and in preceding dispensations.
                            Spiritualists, while adhering to that belief, add thereunto faith in the recurrence and
                            occurrence, in our own day and generation, of all the supernatural phenomena of former
                            times; as recorded in authentic writings or scriptures of the Jews and Christians; and not
                            excluding similar reliable records by other races and nations, whether so recorded in or
                            outside of their Bibles. The spiritualists are waging an aggressive war, and have made
                            repeated onslaughts against the established Church of England and her daughters, the
                            "dissenting" sects, as they lay intrenched behind the scientists, headed by Prof. Farraday,
                            and with somewhat a similar chance of success that Lord Cardigan possessed when he " rode
                            into the jaws of death" with his intrepid "six hundred." The British press, like the walls
                            of ancient Babylon, surrounding all other institutions, have pursued a system of
                            masterly-inactivity tactics — dogged silence. It has stood immovable in its towering
                            contempt, presenting to Spiritualists a front impregnable and unassailable with any hope of
                            success. Some two years ago, the u London Dialectical Society " was formed, composed of
                            about thirty-six distinguished, learnedly — scientific men, with the avowed purpose ot "
                            laying " all the spirits that had been " conjured up " by the Spiritualists. After attending
                            seances and critically examining the modern supernatural manifestations (a fair and rational
                            mode of procedure, and the very one the Church and its sects should have adopted), the
                            result is, itself, the most wonderful of all hitherto publicly known spiritual phenomena.
                            For these thirty-six scientists, under the lead of H. G-. Atkinson Esq., F. G. S., having
                            spent two years attending the seances of thirty-two of the most distinguished Spiritualists,
                            beginning with Emma Hardinge and ending with Home, the aristocratic medium, thus report: "
                            Tour committee, taking into consideration the high character and great intelligence of many
                            of the witnesses to the more extraordinary facts, the extent to which their testimony is
                            supported by the reports of the sub-committees, and the absence of any proof of imposture or
                            delusion as regards a large portion of the phenomena: and, further, having regard to the
                            exceptional character of the phenomena, the large number of persons in every grade of
                            society and over the whole civilized world, who are more or less influenced by a belief in
                            their supernatural origin, and to the fact that no philosophical explanation of them has yet
                            been arrived at, deem it incumbent upon them to state their conviction that the subject is
                            worthy of more serious attention and careful investigation than it has hitherto received."
                            The statements of witnesses are given at length, embracing an accurate description,
                            amplified by cross-examination, of some of the most remarkable phenomena which have been
                            witnessed. This important evidence may be thus summarized: 1. Thirteen witnesses state that
                            they have seen heavy bodies — in some instances men — rise slowly in the air, and remain
                            there for some time, without visible or tangible support. 2. Fourteen witnesses testify to
                            having seen hands or fingers, not appertaining to any human being, but life-like in
                            appearance and mobility, which they have sometimes touched, or even grasped, and which they
                            are therefore convinced were not the result of imposture or illusion. 3. Five witnesses
                            state that they have been touched by some invisible agency on various parts of the body, and
                            often, when requested, when the hands of all present were visible. 4. Thirteen witnesses
                            declare that they have heard musical pieces well played upon instruments not manipulated by
                            any visible agency. 5. Five witnesses state that they have seen red-hot coal applied to the
                            hands or heads of several persons without producing pain or scorching. 6. Eight witnesses
                            state that they have received precise information through rappings, writings, and in other
                            ways, the accuracy of which was unknown at the time to themselves or to any persons present,
                            and which, on subsequent inquiry, was found to be correct. 7. Three witnesses state that
                            they have been present when drawings, both in pencil and colors, were produced in so short a
                            time, and under such conditions as to render human agency impossible. 8. Six witnesses
                            declare that they have received information of future events, and that in some cases the
                            hour and minute of their occurrence have been accurately foretold days, and even weeks
                            before. The work also contains communications, letters and statements from many
                        persons."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As Cyrus, in his siege of Babylon, after finding that he..." TEIform="index"/>As Cyrus, in his siege of Babylon, after finding that he...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London times" TEIform="index"/>London Times</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">As Cyrus, in his siege of Babylon, after finding that he could neither breach the
                                    walls nor successfully storm the gates, simply turned the river Euphrates, and, with
                                    his whole army marched in on its dry bed; and from the inside, himself opened the
                                    gates, so have the spiritualists turned the river of feeling and public opinion in
                                    England, respecting Spiritualism, by the report of this dialectical committee. And
                                    now the great gates of the city, the London Times, are actually opened. The hitherto
                                    silent "Thunderer" did, last year, report a "Shaker" lecture, that included
                                    Spiritualism, delivered in St. George's Hall, while it would not lisp one word of a
                                    preceding lecture delivered by Emma Hardinge on Spiritualism itself, in the same
                                    hall. To-day, its mouth and columns are thrown wide open, in the cause of modern
                                    supernaturalism, and the whole English press are sure to follow in its wake. The "
                                    New Dispensation " opened by the cotemporary and "John Baptist" of Ann Lee — Emanuel
                                    Swedenborg — is progressing toward its destined ultimatum, a permanent and reliable
                                    means of communication between this earth and the spirit world, that will effect a
                                    radical revolution in all existing national and social systems, in Church and State,
                                    preparatory to the final unfoldment of two distinct orders. It was spiritualism that
                                    presaged the downfall of ancient external Babylon, in which a great assembly of her
                                    lords, her priesthood and savans, saw the supernatural hand, writing on the wall, at
                                    the time of their midnight revels, " weighed in the balance and found wanting! "
                                    Modern spiritualism is also perpetually prophesying the downfall of our mystical
                                    Babylon. Justice is holding the scales, and the disembodied souls of men and women
                                    in the spirit world, who, in their earth life, have suffered from, as they have
                                    partaken of, the evils and plagues of our modern Babylonish social system, are
                                    pronouncing and executing judgment. From the inner heavens the cry is heard, " Come
                                    out of her my people that ye be not partakers of her sins and that ye receive not of
                                    her plagues." In ancient Babylonia Cyrus found the then chosen people of God — the
                                    Jews — who had incorporated spiritualism as one of the elements of their system.
                                    Josephus records how the Jewish priesthood, issued from their temple and city in
                                    gorgeous religious procession, to meet the " conquering hero," who was marching upon
                                    them, they showed him his own name in their sacred writings, as a prophesy of the
                                    very events then transpiring of which himself was the principal — the chief actor.
                                    And he, having previously seen the procession in a vision, had been instructed how
                                    to treat them, as they had been supernaturally instructed how to receive Cyrus and
                                    his army.</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism and science" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUALISM AID SCIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">(Reprinted from the Times of December 26,1872.) It is now nearly twenty years since the late
                            Professor Farraday made public the result of his investigations into the then fashionable
                            mania of table-turning. With apparent conclusiveness, he proved that the mysterious
                            movements which were at that time the new nine-days' wonder of the world, arose from
                            unconscious muscular action ; but, such is the tenacity of a belief once received into the
                            mind, this solution of the pseudo-marvel seems to have satisfied few but those who were pre-
                            pared to accept it by previous disbelief. Spiritualism and its adherents never heeded it;
                            they went on their way rejoicing, and rose day MONTHLY <pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 18 SBCAKER
                            A-INTD by day*on stepping-stones of their former selves to mysteries wonderful and still
                            more wonderful. Our Australian correspondence of this morning shows that the spiritualist
                            epi- demic has reached the Antipodes, and that it has already attained the dignity there of
                            hav- ing its own Press, and, still more, its own schismatics and sectarians. That in a
                            generation which boasts itself to be one of exact science and plain matter-of-fact, a belief
                            should have been so long-lived, and should have grown even to such proportions that Mr.
                            William Howitt, one of its chief fanatics, can number its adherents at " twenty millions,"
                            and that it should have attained to such an age and vitality without its falsity having been
                            demonstrated to the satisfaction of all but the very ignorant, is strange indeed. It is
                            evident either that the subject is surrounded by unusual difficulties, or that in this
                            matter our scientific men have signally failed to do their duty by the public, which looks
                            to them for its facts. We believe the latter to be the case. It may be said, and is said by
                            some, that spiritualism was long ago investigated and proved to be a mass of imposture and
                            delusion ; but, as a matter of fact, this is not so, for there has never been undertaken an
                            inquiry of that impartial, authoritative, and thorough nature which alone can decide a
                            prejudiced controversy. Our savans, too much preferring to give themselves up to such
                            matters as the descent of men from monkeys or the fertilization of the world by means of
                            mossy stones falling through space, have forgotten that, however absurd the phenomena and
                            paraphernalia of spiritualism may be, the sifting and settling of the whole matter, once and
                            for all, would be a practical benefit, for which the age would thank them at least as much
                            as it thanks them for recondite theories and abstract speculations, half of which are only
                            laid up in print for the next generation to ridicule. Mr. Home himself attended at one of
                            the meetings, and gave evidence as to his " levitations "and." elongations," relating among
                            other marvels, the generally-known story of a seance at the Tuilleries. He tells us of a
                            lady who was in the habit of seeing " heads in her lap at night. They were quite luminous ;
                            there was quite a glow about them." The Master of Lindsay, now Lord Lindsay, and well known
                            for his various scientific knowledge and researches, deposes to have seen Mr. Home elongated
                            eleven inches, floating round a room in an arm-chair, " pushing the pictures out of their
                            places as he passed along the walls " of a room at Mr. Milner Gibson's house. Lord Lindsay
                            also testifies to Mr. Home having floated out of a window in Victoria street eighty-five
                            feet from the ground, and in at another on the same story. He has seen Mr. Home in full
                            light standing in the air seventeen inches from the ground. Mr. Gr. H. Lewes, in a letter,
                            full of sound maxims, cautioned the committee not to confound " the cause we do not know
                            with an unknown cause ;" and Professor Tyndall was willing to " pay due respect to the
                            invitation of such men as Mr. Wallace or Mr. Crookes, and to witness whatever new phenomena
                            they were in a position to show him." Mr. G. H. Lewes gave golden advice when he said, "
                            Distinguish between facts and inferences from facts." Mr. William Howitt asked whether the
                            Dialectical Society, after having determined the truth of spiritualism which had " now
                            received the assent of about twenty millions of people in all countries," would proceed to
                            investigate tho correctness of the theory of the Copernican system, of gravita- tion, or of
                            the circulation of the blood; for spiritualism, he considered, " stood fairly on the same
                            basis of fact." These extracts from its pages may serve better than any thing else to give
                            our non-spiritualistic readers some idea of the marvelous proportions to which the faith,
                            which at first was a mere turning of tables, has swollen in these latter days. Such was the
                            Report on Spiritualism, and our readers will probably agree that, if it proves nothing else,
                            it proves that it is high time competent hands undertook the unravel- ing of this Gordian
                            knot. It must be fairly and patiently unraveled, and not cut through. The slash of an
                            Alexandrian blade has been tried often enough, and has never sufficed. Scientific men forget
                            that in the matter of Spiritualism they must make themselves fools that they may become
                            wise. They must conform to the conditions imposed; even in con- juring one has to do as much
                            as this. They must meet the " mediums" on their own ground, and, if possible, cut that
                            ground from under their feet. To take an extreme case, Spiritualists assert that certain
                            phenomena are only manifested in a half light, or in the dark; scientific men refuse to meet
                            them under these conditions, and what is the result ? Causes are not ascertained, delusions
                            are not exposed, impositions are not detected, and the company of fools are confirmed in
                            their belief. Surely a scientific man is a match for a me- dium, even in the dark; and
                            surely the one can bring his science to bear wherever the other can bring his " mediumship,"
                            whatever that may be ! We will suppose that the man of science consents to sit at a dark
                            seance, and that something happens which he cannot explain. What then ? He is not
                            compromised or converted, and, without being in the least so, may go again and again, and it
                            will be strange if by dint of precautions and expedients he cannot sift the whole matter in
                            a very few sittings. It is owing to the stiffness of scientific men, and their refusal to
                            meet the Spiritualists on their own ground, that this matter has not been settled long ago."
                            Thus is the wisdom of the wise confounded and their worldly greatness humbled. Mother Ann
                            said, while in vision, "I see souls in the world of spirits who have lately set out to
                            embrace the gospel, and I see them under the beautiful operations of the power of God. I saw
                            Ezekiel Goodrich flying from one heaven to another." She spake of another soul who had
                            "risen from the dead and come into the first heavens, and was traveling on to the second and
                            third heavens." All of which goes to show that, while there may be chemistry, astronomy and
                            even spritualism, without Christianity, there can be no Christianity without spiritualism,
                            ancient and modern. " These signs shall follow." They shall lay hands on the sick and heal
                            them, as truly as did Jesus and his apostles, and do many wonderful and good works, under
                            the head of Christian Spiritualism. </p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul petrifactions" TEIform="index"/>SOUL PETRIFACTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline><p TEIform="p">Petrifaction and death seem almost synonymous. " The soul that sinneth shall die " is a truth
                            uttered from the mouth of God's prophets and witnessed to by the whole human fam- ily. Soul
                            life is the beatific benediction conferred on man by the redeeming Gospel of Christ. "A
                            crown of life" "Eternal life" is the bountiful reward of righteousness. Not long since we
                            were reading of the petrifying wells of England. According to the statements of our author
                            the waters of these wells are pure, clear and limpid in appearance, and pleasant to the
                            taste; but, so charged with silicate of lime, that, as their spray rests upon an object
                            exposed to the air, where the moisture becomes evaporated, they coat that object with stone;
                            or, if it be porous, they charge the pores with stone, so that, in a few months, its whole
                            substance becomes, as it were, changed to stone. The most delicate vegetables, as tiny
                            mosses and flowers, exposed to the spray of these waters, are turned to stone; even bird's
                            nests, and eggs — the germs of future life — become petrified! As on we read, and drink in
                            the full sense of this narrative, our spiritual senses were quickened. A thrill of inspiring
                            pleasure welled up in our heart, in the contemplation of our opportunities for the
                            attainment of " eternal life" flowing from the heavenly fountains of inspiration and love,
                            and fever its wells of salvation and joyous blessings. The beautiful plants of gospel
                            graces, cherished by these pure and living waters, appeared fresh and green, decked in
                            vernal bloom and gorgeous beauty transporting to the senses of the Gos- pel Traveler, and
                            filled us with raptures; and our spirit instinctively poured out praises to God that a soul
                            life, capacitated to appreciate and drink up this inspiration, was vouchsafed to the pure in
                            heart. Succeeding these transports of joy, a sadness indescribable seemed to pall our
                            spirits as peering into the spiritual conditions and haunts of men, we saw myriad millions
                            or our race whose souls were petrified with the stony waters from the wells of sinful
                            worldly pleasure entombed in spiritual death! Many of these waters, like unto those of the
                            petrifying wells of England, are pure to look upon, clear and limpid, pleasant to the taste,
                            and cheering to the senses, but, alas! charged with soluble stone — limpid death —piercing
                            every pore of the being and charging every fibre and sprig, yea, even the nowrets and germs
                            of future spirit life, with death, — stone! Slowly, imperceptibly, but surely, petrifying
                            the very soul itself, converting its lively sensibilities to stolid death. Changed to this
                            petrifaction human beings could be, for a time, in the angelic society of the pure and good,
                            who were quaffing inspiration from the overflowing wells of salvation — the fountains of
                            life, and love, and heaven — and yet be utterly insensible to their bliss! And, if this
                            insensibility to heaven be not hell, vainly is the spirit of man gifted with sensation. To
                            those thus petrified by sinful pleasure, the most gorgeous flowers and luscious fruits of
                            paradise were no better than the bitter apples on the slimy, murky beach of the sea of
                            Sodom; all, all are without delight; for the perceptive faculties are entombed in stone! —
                            stone so dense that repentant waters may not permeate the being. Hence, for such there is no
                            forgiveness, as forgiveness is predicated on repentance. But these can only be relieved from
                            their sarcophagus through sufferings of emptiness, hunger and solitude ; hence, though they
                            eventually have a resurrection, it is not of life, but of condemnation; and their revival
                            into spiritual life must be slow and painful, like the evolutions of soil from the granite
                            rock. This condition is the result of sinning against light, and the knowledge of the truth!
                            It is a warning to those that are at ease in Zion! — an admonition to those who sit in
                            heavenly places, and bask in the sunbeams of truth — not to partake of the pleasures of sin,
                            which petrify the powers of sensation. Soul life, — eternal life, — senses able to regale
                            upon the odors of the flowers of heaven, and taste the sweetness of the fruits of Paradise ;
                            to enjoy the melodies of the angel choirs, and drink up with gustation the wine <pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKERE88. 19 of consolation newly expressed from the clusters of the heavenly
                            vine, are alone the rewards of a virtuous Christian life of virgin purity! — Mount Lebanon.
                            " Infidelity " or skepticism to the warring theology of Babylon, is one mark of a true
                            Christian.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiries" TEIform="index"/>INQUIRIES</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Brown, Napoleon" TEIform="persName"/>Napoleon Brown</byline><p TEIform="p">To the Churches Universally — Let those Answer who will. Did Jesus do what he taught? Did he
                            love his enemies, and do good to those who hated him ? Did he bless them that cursed him,
                            and pray for them who despitefully used him? And when they smote him on the one cheek, did
                            he turn the other, also? Did he do unto others as he would have others do unto him ? Did he
                            loan to every one that asked him, hoping for nothing again ? When he taught to judge not!
                            did he judge? Condemn not! did he condemn? Forgive! did he forgive? Did he cast the beam (if
                            he had one) out of his own eye, that he might see clearly to pull the mote out of his
                            brother's eye ? Did he forsake father, mother, brothers, and sisters, and all worldly
                            relations with its goods and possessions? Did he crucify his carnal life? If so! Who are his
                            followers ? — Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time" TEIform="index"/>TIME</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline><p TEIform="p">" Time and tide wait for no man." We are constantly reminded of this truth, as we leave days,
                            weeks, months and years behind. And, are we becoming better, as golden opportunities come
                            and go? We are certainly growing better or worse. Writer, how stands the verdict regarding
                            yourself? You must know, if you are true to your own conscience. Having lately crossed the
                            line which separates 1872 from 1873, what is your ultimate aim for the present year? Your
                            aims may be good. But good desires, without corresponding efforts, will not benefit you. If
                            you make earthly pleasure your ultimate aim, you will certainly fail of finding real
                            happiness. " For what is earthly pleasure ? 'Tis like the snowflake on the river. One moment
                            there, then gone for ever." The desire to be like the meek and lowly Saviour, unless that
                            desire calls forth daily practical obedience, will not make you like him. If you would live
                            with Jesus in heaven, you must live to Christ on earth. The time allotted you for heavenly
                            discipline, and for holy living, like the current of a mighty river, is swiftly passing.
                            Therefore, give earnest heed to the injunction, ''Work while it is day." For "to-day is
                            gold, tomorrow is dust." Resolve to be so pure in heart that you can "see God" in yourself;
                            and act fully up to that purpose; "then the work of redemption will have commenced. Will you
                            make that resolve? The prudent mariner, when sailing in windy latitudes, sweeps the horizon
                            with his glass, to ascertain if there are signs of a storm. As night approaches, he shortens
                            sail, sets his watch, and keeps a good look-out. If prudence be necessary when applied to
                            things of time, how much more so when applied to our religious life here, and to the life
                            which is to come? For the soul is of more importance than the body; and time is of less
                            importance than eternity. "A prudent man foreseeth the evil, and hideth himself; but the
                            simple pass on, and are punished." — Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American slavery: the woman's suffrage question -- the case of Susan B. Anthony" TEIform="index"/>AMERICAN SLAVERY: THE WOMAN'S SUFFRAGE QUESTION — THE CASE OF SUSAN B. ANTHONY.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The case of Susan B. Anthony, who was arrested on charge of illegally voting at
                                    Rochester, at the late presidential election, was before the United States District
                                    Court, Judge Hall presiding, at the city hall, yesterday. The court room was crowded
                                    with spectators, among whom were Miss Lydia Mott, Mrs. Jane Hoxsie, Miss Phoebe
                                    Jones, and other ladies. Judge Henry E. Selden, of the counsel for Miss Anthony,
                                    briefly recited the facts that at the late presidential election, held in the 29th
                                    congressional district, Miss Anthony appeared before the registration board and was
                                    registered, and at the election she appeared and cast her ballot, and it was
                                    received and counted the same as the others, and the cause and the sole cause of her
                                    arrest is, that she was a woman. If this proceeding is sanctioned, she will be
                                    punished simply because she is a woman. He asked her discharge because she had a
                                    constitutional right to offer her ballot and express her choice as to whom she
                                    desired for her rulers. The right of woman to vote is not an appropriate matter for
                                    consideration here. It is not claimed that, under the State constitution, Miss
                                    Anthony is entitled to vote ; such authority can only be found in the laws of the
                                    United States. He cited the first constitution and the 13th, 14th and 15th
                                    amendments in support of his position. He held that the 14th amendment, although the
                                    fact might have been overlooked by its constructor, gave to all citizens, whether
                                    men or women, the right to vote and hold office, and that therefore Miss Anthony,
                                    being a citizen under the constitution, in being taxed, etc., possessed all the
                                    rights and privileges of a citizen, together with the political right to hold office
                                    and vote ; and the constitution of the United States did not give to any State the
                                    right to restrict the right of suffrage. Mr. Selden's argument was quite lengthy and
                                    exhaustive. Judge Hall said he was of the opinion that Miss Anthony had no right to
                                    vote, and decided to discharge the writ of habeas corpus, but denied the application
                                    for her discharge from custody, and allowed the case to go before the supreme court
                                    of the United States, where he understood, they desired carrying it.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany express" TEIform="index"/>Albany Express.</bibl></cit> Susan B. Anthony is, or she is not, a human being. If she is a human being, she may
                            do wrong, and may be punished for that wrong under laws which she had no part in forming,
                            and by executive officials of those laws, whom she had no voice, or choice, or vote, in
                            electing. Is that republicanism, or is it Church and State slavery not yet abolished ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Penalty vs. transgression" TEIform="index"/>PENALTY vs. TRANSGRESSION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Briggs, Nicholas" TEIform="persName"/>Nicholas Briggs</byline><p TEIform="p">Believing that God is just, and that strict justice will be impartially awarded to all his
                            creatures, we confidently anticipate reward for faithful obedience to his known behests, and
                            corresponding punishment for transgression. The law of penalty and the law of recompense are
                            co-existent; a comfort to the virtuous ; a terror to the vicious. They are inex- orable
                            laws, governing our moral and spiritual as they govern our physical being. They do not well
                            who ignore retribution for sin, or at least imply as much in their specious arguments ; and
                            while we may respect the sincerity of their motives, we must condemn the sophistry and
                            deplore its influence. Rogues and libertines find eminent satisfaction in the idea that
                            future punishment is a myth — an antiquated notion. We rejoice that ecclesiastical thunder
                            no more terrifies the masses ; that the dogmatism of fanatical religionists, and the
                            arbitrary creeds of pseudo-reformers, no longer fetter the minds of intelligent men and
                            women. We hail, with infinite pleasure, the era of free thought and speech ; but every
                            Christian, every true lover of mankind who desires to behold virtue as the acme of all
                            aspiration, would have philosophy and science co-operate with religion in ameliorating the
                            condition of our race. Inevitably we are social beings. Our destinies are as closely
                            interwoven as the twigs of the climbing vine. Being virtuous ourselves we breathe purity on
                            our brother and sister, who are therefore made better and happier for our existence. We
                            illuminate the little world in which we move with a holy light that pierces the dark places,
                            turning gloom and despair into beautiful hope and trust. Our conversation is elevating and
                            soul-inspiring, and our daily life gives tone and color and health to society. But when men
                            are low, and gross, and sensual, this influence is deadly poison, infectious and contagious
                            ; a moral Upas, near which no good thing can thrive. Bad men draw down society to their own
                            level, and fiendishly exult in defacing the image of God; but this exultation is succeeded
                            by remorse for the suffering and ruin they have caused, and despair at their own
                            degradation. They have condign punishment, a veritable hell, grim and terrible. " The
                            present is hell, and the coming tomorrow adds new torture to the curse of today." In further
                            elucidation of our subject, we will present a little parable. A poor man receives
                            notification from a distant country that, by appearing in person within a specified time, he
                            may become the possessor of sufficient wealth to render him comfortable for life. He
                            succeeds in obtaining money with which to prosecute his journey, and embarks with bright
                            anticipations for the future. On the way, through cruel robbery, his little all is lost, and
                            the delay thus occasioned is fatal to his bright hopes, for, by his non-appearance the
                            property passes into other hands. Formerly he had managed, by dint of industry and economy,
                            to eke out a comfortable subsistence; but now the disastrous disap- pointment proves too
                            great for him, and he turns to intoxicating drinks to forget his sorrow. The robber, the
                            author of all this trouble, is at last touched with remorse, and seeking his victim, tenders
                            in full the amount of which he had despoiled him, penitently expressing sorrow and asking
                            forgiveness. The injured man replies: " Restore me wealth, which through you I lost — honor
                            and position in society, which but for you I might now be enjoying. You are the cause of all
                            my misery ; restore me, therefore, to happiness, ere I forgive you." The application and
                            relevancy of this supposed case are apparent. If a man deviate from the straight road to
                            Heaven's Kingdom, he may, by carefully retracing every false step, regain the true path ;
                            and though he find himself behind his former comrades, and the loser of much valuable time,
                            still the misfortune is confined to himself, and he has done no injury to other souls. But
                            if he mislead a fellow-pilgrim, the case becomes more complex. He finds, after taking <pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 2O observation and ascertaining his position on the chart of life, that
                            he has not only himself to restore to rectitude, but his brother also. His victim may have
                            wandered into many bypaths — may have become entangled in bogs and morasses; he must be
                            sought, extricated, and toiled for until he is again restored to Heaven's road. The penitent
                            may have to work years, aye ages, to effect this; but justice demands that he shall retrieve
                            the results of his own conduct, dire as they may be. Is not our reasoning logical? Is not
                            our conclusion reasonable ? By simply tracing back effect to cause, and contrasting our
                            original error with its logical result, injury, per- haps irreparable, to ourselves and
                            other souls, have we not indeed a full penalty for trans- gression ? — Canterbury.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Press" TEIform="index"/>THE PRESS</head><p TEIform="p">[Evening Register, Hudson.} " The Shaker and Shakeress." This is the title of an exceedingly
                            neat quarto publication, issued monthly by the Shaker Society at Mount Lebanon, and ably
                            edited by Elder Frederick W. Evans. While it must be a powerful auxiliary to the Society in
                            whose interests it is conducted, from the high tone of its general contents and the literary
                            ability it displays, it cannot fail to be popular with a large class outside the Shaker
                            community. We welcome it to our table.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Methodist sermon" TEIform="index"/>METHODIST SERMON</head><p TEIform="p">"The Jlrst requisite with a little child is not to teach it the Lord's Prayer, or ask it,
                            What is God? — What is heaven, or hell? But teach it to take care of its health; teach it
                            physiology ; teach it, as it can understand, simple facts in science. " Just so with men and
                            women who tell me they are ready for heaven, and know exactly God's intentions about the
                            race. Why, they cannot tell you the difference between a cabbage and a goose ! They know
                            about God, and don't know one simple law of health! Ready for heaven, and so ignorant of
                            themselves, they bring children into the world with not enough physical stamina to live! And
                            why? Because, by debauchery and sin, they have entailed on their children their own
                            rottenness and weakness. " We must learn to raise children aright before we talk of
                            religion. Religion, I insist, is last, not first. We must learn all about this world before
                            we study the next world. Better learn to boil potatoes than study theology. " Why have we so
                            many skeptics in the church ? Why do not our young men attend church ? because they have
                            been taught authority—authority all their youth up, instead of being taught to rely on their
                            own strength — to stand on their own two feet. " First, that which is natural, said old
                            Paul. He was right. First, know the laws governing your own bodies—first, know of this world
                            : first, study science, and then build your religious faith on that science. "You cannot get
                            science f rom!the Bible. The fathers of the church tried to do that, and a flat world, with
                            angels above the molten heavens, to drag the sun out of a pit in the morning, was Bible
                            astronomy. This is all wrong. We have begun at the wrong end. The true law is science first,
                            and then religion."—Bann of Light. True science is Shaker theology.— Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Card" TEIform="index"/>CARD</head><p TEIform="p">Lebanon Springs, November 10. In the Banner of October 26th I regret to see the revival of an
                            error which went the rounds of the press some months ago, and which, at the time, I denied
                            by published cards. Please do me the justice to state — 1. As I regard the Shaker order as a
                            testimony against "the pollutions that are in the world through lust," I have never desired
                            their renunciation of celibacy. 2. As I consider the greater part of their disci- pline as
                            eminently protective of the celibate life, I have never desired the abrogation of any rule
                            that prohibits shaking hands and kissing. 3. As I view their societies as nuclei for some of
                            the purest and most refined of human souls, 1 deprecate their dissolution, unless that God
                            shall build up for poor humanity some equally as good or better " covert from the tempest."
                            Yours for truth, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Robe, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Robe</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blood" TEIform="index"/>[ From the Irish.] THE BLOOD</head><p TEIform="p">Sii thousand years after his era began, The astonishing fact was discovered by man, That the
                            blood in his body does not remain still, But rushes along like the race from a mill. Certain
                            vessels called arteries, hidden within The body, conduct from the heart to the skin, While
                            others called veins throughout every part Of the system conduct from the skin to the heart.
                            The heart every instant gets flll'd with new blood, Prepar'd as you'll see, from the air and
                            the food ; And this new blood is driven throughout the whole frame, As from a force-pump by
                            the force of the same. The blood in its passage leaves everywhere Some of what it has got
                            from the food and the air, Which is all taken up, ere a moment be gone, To replenish the
                            tissue, the fat and the bone. Throughout the whole structure—bone, muscle, orskin — Where
                            the arteries end the veins begin, And changing its colour from red blood to black, The blood
                            enters the veins and is so carried back. When the old blood arrives by the veins at the
                            heart, It is mixed and churned up in a chamber apart, With a thick milky fluid, nutritious
                            and good, Which the stomach and bowels have drawn from the food. It is then driven off by a
                            similar force To the lungs,where the air cells receive it, in course; Where at every breath
                            it takes up through the skin The material parts of the air within. Thus regenerate,
                            vigorous, lusty and red, And once more forced back on its fountain head, To the artery
                            chamber it rushes amain, And is ready to start upon service again. What we get from the air
                            is equal in weight To what we derive from the food which we eat; But what we breathe out, I
                            must tell you once more, Is of poisons the worst, as I told you before. In a much clearer
                            light you now may perceive What it's hoped you'll hold fast and devoutly believe, That for
                            health and enjoyment the very best fare Is the soundest of food and the purest of air. Then
                            show that you value your blood and your skin, Remove every nuisance without or within ; Obey
                            all the iaws that are made to that end, And regard the inspector of health as your friend.
                            If your house has a taint, employ in good time Either carbolic acid or chloride of lime ;
                            But of all disinfectants the earth is the best — Smells covered by earth are for ever at
                            rest. With all these precautions don't fear any harm, And yield to no panic or foolish alarm
                            ; When the enemy comes, be brave but prepared — Survey your defenses and stand on your
                            guard!</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is not what we eat, but what we digest, that makes us fat..." TEIform="index"/>It is not what we eat, but what we digest, that makes us fat...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"It is not what we eat, but what we digest, that makes us fat; it is not what we read, but
                            what we remember, that makes us learned ; it is not what we earn, but what we save, that
                            makes us rich." As the wild waves that fiercely contend in mid ocean touch gently the shore,
                            and speak in the low, soft music of broken ripples, so will the heart, once tumultuous with
                            passion, when brought under self-control, breathe holy love as it nears the promised land of
                            rest.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To love the unlovely, to sympathize with the contrary-minded..." TEIform="index"/>To love the unlovely, to sympathize with the contrary-minded...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To love the unlovely, to sympathize with the contrary-minded, to give to the uncharitable, to
                            forgive such as never pity, to be just to men who make iniquity a law, to pay their
                            ceaseless [hate with never-ceasing love, is one of the noblest attainments of man, and in
                            this he becomes most like G-od.</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Parker, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theodore Parker</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith is not a light thought that sweeps across the brain..." TEIform="index"/>Faith is not a light thought that sweeps across the brain...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Faith is not a light thought that sweeps across the brain to be condensed and fall in tears;
                            it is not a mere emotion like the wind that rises powerfully, then dies into the stillness
                            of the air; neither is it like the lightning's flash that gathers force to dissipate, and
                            return from whence it came; nor the fragrance of the flower borne away by the passing
                            breeze, but it is a life germ planted in the soul; and by cultivation and growth it gains
                            strength and lifts the heart to high and holy aims, and opens the vision to the beauties of
                            a new angelic life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Out with it" TEIform="index"/>OUT WITH IT</head><p TEIform="p">How many kind thoughts die unborn; how many kind words are stifled unspoken. Hearts hungry
                            for a word of appreciation and praise, would leap for gladness if they knew the kindness
                            that we feel toward them; but while they plod on in doubt and darkness, we stifle kindly
                            aspirations, and the cheering thought and sympathizing word dies within our hearts and makes
                            no sign. Why need we be so reticent concerning things thai are good? Most people are
                            outspoken enough when angry and discontented. They find fault boldly, with a relish ;-. but
                            words of praise are with them exceedingly few. It is true that he that flattereth his
                            neighbor spreadeth a net for his feet. We are to avoid flattery and fulsome praise. But yet,
                            when a glow of honest admiration or approval risea within our hearts, why not out with it,
                            and let it gladden others as it cheers us ? How happy families might be if every thought of
                            thankfulness manifested itself in speech and action from day to day. How many a home, now
                            dreary and uncomfortable, might be made joyous with light and sunshine, if we would not only
                            rebuke with fidelity, and reprove in love, but would also sho"w in words and deeds our sense
                            of gratitude and approval when we can honestly do so. — Exchange.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To subscribers" TEIform="index"/>TO SUBSCRIBERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Those wishing to subscribe for The Shaker and Shakeress will please enclose fifty cents, with
                            their address very plainly written. Full name, town, county and State. We intend that the
                            original music shall be worth the half dollar.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste basket" TEIform="index"/>THE WASTE BASKET!</head><p TEIform="p">That bug-bear of impecunious writers of newspaper articles, the receptacle of the effusions
                            of many ambitious aspirants for cheap notoriety, to you, poor suffering humanity, is much
                            indebted. Among newspaper and magazine writers of all descriptions and grades there is a
                            continuous striving to excel in making all of their articles agreeable and readable. It is a
                            positive necessity that their productions shall tickle the public taste. It is a matter of
                            bread and butter to them. No editor in the world would think for an instant of publishing an
                            ill-written article, no matter how great the truth advanced. Though he may treasure the
                            idea, and, at a future time, produce it in a more acceptable form, still the original is
                            flung ignominiously into the Waste Basket. Disagreeable matters of news, police items, etc.,
                            are worked into as pleasant a shape as possible. It is the righteous fear of the Waste
                            Basket, and the consequent diminution of the means of living, that brings matters of fact
                            and fancy to us in a piquant, pithy form. By this same benefactor of mankind are we saved
                            from the infliction of numberless wretched love stories with the inevitable conclusions. So
                            ought we not to recognize in the Waste Basket, an institution proper of every sanctum
                            editorial, the wholesome dread of which makes us brush up our memories for the almost
                            forgotten rules of punctuation and rhetoric ? Then long live the Waste Basket! and let us
                            unite in keeping this appendage of the " Shaker and Shakeress" full to repletion. We shall
                            find on trial, that the more we write, the better we write. Write an article for every
                            issue, for a year, and let them all be consigned to the Waste Basket; still, be not
                            discouraged ; for an idea in some one of them may suggest a train of thought to another
                            mind, the expression of which may be fraught with value to mankind. I close with a promise
                            and a wondering; a promise to do the share of one at least in this direction, and a
                            wondering as to the company amongst which this article will find itself, when consigned to
                            the " WasteBasket."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>E</byline></div2><pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: freedom of thought" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: FREEDOM OF THOUGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">In days of yore we had so much veneration for our sires and grandsires, and such entire
                            confidence in their opinions, that we felt safety in thinking and believing much as they
                            thought and believed. Occasionally an erratic individual would venture to strike out for him
                            or herself an independent course of action; but such were sure, while striving to get the
                            wheels of their car of progress out of the old ruts in which they had been accustomed to
                            run, to feel the strong pressure of conservative public opinion. This was grievous to bear.
                            But times are gradually changing, and conservatism is yielding to the progressive tendencies
                            of the age. All now claim the right to think and act freely for themselves, independent of
                            the past. Human ideality of to-day is raising a higher standard of truth and right to gather
                            around; for the present generation is reaping the benefit of the ripest experiences of the
                            most coherent thinkers and philosophers of former ages, which is of priceless worth; and may
                            be profitably used as auxiliaries to present superior attainments. The present is so closely
                            allied to the past that, as seen in vision by the prophet Ezekiel, " The wings of the living
                            creature," which rolled forward the wheels of progress in the past, touch the wings of the
                            living spirit which is at work in the same direction to-day. There is no break in the march
                            of progression. " The living creatures " of each dispensation move straight forward ; " they
                            turn not as they go." We live in an analytic age. By the accelerated action of the brain,
                            ideas are increased, minds are expanded and go deeper into cause and effect than at any
                            previous time; and reason, as a God-given power to humanity, asserts her right to the
                            throne, in matters relating to the theological views and religious sentiments, as really and
                            freely as in natural science. The civil polity protects all lawabiding citizens in the
                            exercise of perfect liberty of conscience, and guards the rights of all persons,
                            irrespective of nation or color, in their theology and religion. The American flag, wherever
                            seen, is an ensign of human freedom. As it floats in the breeze, it inspires hope and gives
                            promise to all people of a glorious emancipation from bondage, civil and ecclesiastical.
                            Under this banner have arisen the Shaker Societies, constituting the most unpopulai body of
                            professing Christians of the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Their radical testimony
                            against all sinful indulgences, teaches that those who do not deny all sensual pleasures —
                            all the lusts of the flesh and mine — must suffer in their own bodies and souls the penalty
                            of every violated law, irrespective of the meritorious vicarious sufferings o Jesus of
                            Nazareth. These Shakers, who, from deep religious conviction, subject themselves to stern
                            selfdiscipline, are now beginning to be heard. Thousands who do not feel prepared to walk
                            with them in full communion personally, who cannot say, "Not my will, but Thine 0 God be
                            done," and thus consecrate their all of person and property, do nevertheless rejoice in
                            those who throw themselves into the burning crucible of spiritual and religious truth, that
                            they may thereby become purified and reflect the image of the heavenly Refiner. They, too,
                            will help uplift humanity to a state of moral rectitude on the earth plane. In blessing they
                            will be blest by higher intelligences, and by progressive degrees will eventually be led by
                            the spirit of truth up to the plane of spiritual life, to unite with those who are forming
                            the angelic character. Many of this class look hopefully on, and anxiously await the coming
                            of our little " Monthly," to learn if it is well with us, and to see if the star of hope is
                            still brightly beaming over our pathway, which leads to the heavenly home, the " city which
                            hath foundations whose builder and maker is God." While in the present, as in the past, we
                            realize that "struggle is the condition of victory," and that only " through conflict can
                            deliverance come," we yet say, God be praised! Our " reward is with us," and we feel that
                            Heaven's blessing rests upon our labors, and that truly " the lines have fallen to us in
                            pleasant places."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest" TEIform="index"/>REST</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Sears, Florinda" TEIform="persName"/>Florinda Sears</byline><p TEIform="p">There is a rest for the people of God. In days gone by — those days of which we read in the
                            New Testament when Jesus and the Apostles received the Christ, and by the power of the
                            Father were commissioned to preach salvation — brother Paul, in his epistle to the Hebrews,
                            after wisely philosophizing on the subject, declared, " There remaineth a rest for the
                            people of God." Learned divines have used this text, calling upon their hearers to believe
                            on the man Jesus, and thus insure to themselves this promised rest. But, notwithstanding the
                            darkness, the true light has dawned upon us and a star of hope is arising. Who, from a
                            distance, or within the precincts of our home, will solve the problem, and divine how this
                            rest which still remaineth for the people of God is to be entered? Brother Paul further
                            says: " He that hath entered into that rest hath also ceased from his own works." Thus it
                            would appear we must become " new creatures, new brothers, new sisters, new fathers, and new
                            mothers; " that is, spiritual or heavenly beings, instead of continuing earthly and natural.
                            Again, our New Testament brother rejoices, inasmuch as " we have not a high priest who
                            cannot be touched with the feeling of our infirmities; but was in all points tempted like as
                            we are yet without sin." Why do we flatter ourselves that the promised rest can be obtained
                            in any other than a sinless condition ? Then let all enlightened spiritual Christians " come
                            boldly to the throne of grace, that they may obtain mercy and the remission of sin, by
                            confession, as did Jesus and Ann, by the confession of their faults, ere they received the
                            anointing, or the Christ, which constituted them the saviours of the world. Those who thus
                            enter the promised rest are God's people. To them the fires of hell are quenched, and they
                            fear no torment, no judgment to come; their lives being "hid in Christ" with Jesus and Ann.
                            They are the virgins who follow them whithersoever they go; for they are no longer of the
                            number who are " like the troubled sea, whose waters cannot rest." We may therefore conclude
                            that the people of God, in the highest sense, are those who really and practically live the
                            nearest to Him, by letting the Adamic life pass away that they may become " new creatures,"
                            actuated by the Spirit of Christ, as the life of God in their souls. Such will feel no more
                            sorrow nor sighing—the fruits of sin and wrong-doing. — Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pure in heart" TEIform="index"/>PURE IN HEART</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Deming, Josephine" TEIform="persName"/>Josephine Deming</byline><p TEIform="p">Jesus said " Blessed are the pure in heart; for they shall see God." See Him where and how?
                            We behold His handiwork in the outward visible creation. The sunbeam, and the tiny flower —
                            the grasses and fruits — the trees with their lofty waving branches — and the murmuring
                            rill, as well as the mighty surging ocean — all bespeak a great producing cause. We admire
                            the beauties of Nature, and through them adore the Wisdom that formed them, and the hand of
                            Love that gave them as gifts to humanity. But there is a consciousness in our hearts, that a
                            deeper sense of God is needed; that the outward senses, even if properly directed, cannot
                            supply the inward cravings of the soul. We must draw nigh unto Him in spirit, and so
                            thoroughly purify our hearts from all that is sinful and vain, that we can commune with
                            heavenly Messengers, who are sent unto us from spirit spheres to quicken into more life, and
                            produce in us more purity of heart, that we may have still clearer perceptions of God. This
                            alone can satisfy the unutterable longings in the human soul, for the Heavenly Father's
                            blessing, and the love and tender care of a Heavenly Mother. And when we receive this sweet
                            influence, our hearts go out in love to our brother and sister in Christ, in whom the image
                            of the Divine is found; and thus we see God in man and in woman, the crowning work of his
                            hands, in a higher and more spiritual sense, than in any mere external thing. Purity is the
                            basis of all true and enduring friendship. What is there in all of God's creation so noble
                            as Man, when he stands uprightly, showing forth the image in which he was created? And what
                            being so lovely as Woman, when really pure in heart"? Then why should we not see God in
                            them, and reverence Him there ? What can give greater happiness than to be loved and
                            cherished by them, and to dwell in their presence and partake of their heavenly influence ?
                            Blessed indeed are the pure in heart! They dispense light, love, and comfort to all around
                            them; and I would gather to such, and learn to be like them — beautiful in spirit — lowly in
                            heart —¦ and free from all contamination of a worldly, selfish life. — Whitewater, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Grey, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>Alice Grey</byline><p TEIform="p">Religion is the only true basis of happiness. "Pure and undefiled religion," outflowing from
                            Wisdom and Love, is soul-purifying and exalting. We may be intellectually wise, and may
                            possess great scientific knowledge and be morally correct in our habits of life ; but we
                            cannot form 'perfect characters without religion. A mere profession, or belief in some theo-
                            logical creed, will prove ineffectual, unless we live out the law of Love; and we shall be
                            left in the cold, barren region of selfishness, toiling for, and feeding the animal part of
                            our natures, instead of the higher spiritual faculties of our souls, which would lead us to
                            condemn error in our own lives, and to look charitably upon the faults of others. 21 <pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEE A.ISTD True religion will teach us to be tender and
                            compassionate ; to be as ministering angels of love and mercy to the fallen and lowly, and
                            to take them by the hand, and walk with them in the path of virtue. Thus shall we help to
                            lift them up to better conditions, by practically showing the power of love, and the worth
                            of that kind of religion, which will not allow us to stand with folded hands, and see a
                            brother or sister in need or distress, and coldly say, " Be ye warmed and clothed; " neither
                            in a Pharisaical manner boastingly say —" I thank God that my condition is otherwise ; " for
                            " He knoweth the proud afar off." Pride is incompatible with true Christian religion, which
                            fills its subjects with humility and love. —Whitewater, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the October, 1872, number of 'The Shaker'..." TEIform="index"/>In the October, 1872, number of 'The Shaker'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">In the October, 1872, number of " The Shaker," edited by Elder G. A. Loinas, was given a
                            succinct account of a meeting which he attended in a pine grove in Canaan, at the " Social
                            Gathering," of the three families of the novitiate order at Mt. Lebanon. He made mention of
                            a conversation that took place at the time between six young sisters, which he thought
                            worthy to appear in print. Some of our outside friends have since urged its publication ;
                            for they were anxious to see it. Though somewhat lengthy for our small paper, we have
                            concluded to publish it. It was prepared by the sisters expressly for the occasion, and was
                            repeated from memory.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>DIALOGUE THE GOSPEL WORK — ITS PRESENT AND FUTURE INCREASE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patterson, Margaret; Offordd, Ann; Anderson, Martha; Byrdsall, Charlotte; Soul, Melissa; and                                 Cleveland, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/> MARGARET PATTERCHARLOTTE BYRDSON. SALL. ANN OFFORDD. MELISSA SOUL and MARTHA ANDERSON.
                            MARGARET CLEVELAND</byline><p TEIform="p">Martha.— We hail this year, 1872, as the Twelfth Celebration of our Social Gathering, and as
                            the centenary of the opening of the Gospel. In reviewing the past, from the first stages of
                            the work to the present time, we find much that is interesting and instructive to the
                            thoughtful and observing mind, and encouraging and hopeful to those whose aspirations are
                            spiritually directed. I propose to trace the onward progress of a system which, though small
                            in its beginning, embodied the germs of scientific, moral and spiritual knowledge, which, by
                            culture and growth, would become widespread — a revelation of truth that was and is destined
                            to shake the foundations of the old heavens and earth, and bring to perfection a plan of
                            true harmonial development for humanity. We who are in the enjoyment of the good that has
                            been accumulated and conserved by the consecrated lives of those who were pio- neers in the
                            cause, with their faithful successors, can testify to the permanency and validity of those
                            principles which constitute a solid basis for a life in which the nobler faculties and
                            God-like attributes of mind and soul can be unfolded, and, through the influences of
                            increasing truth, rise to the altitudes of heavenly perfection which the Creator designed
                            all intelligent progressive beings should occupy. Margaret P.— Are you not mistak en in this
                            being the centennial year ? I thought it was not until eighteen hundred and seventyfour.
                            Martha.— I referred to the revelation in England, not to the actual occurrence in America.
                            Am I not right in the assertion ? ANN.— You are. Mother Ann (Lee) received a baptism from
                            the Christ sphere in seventeen hundred and seventy, when confined in prison, on account of
                            her advanced religious ideas. During her imprisonment she had a clear conception of the loss
                            of mankind, and of the only means that would resurrect them into a higher life. For the
                            space of two years, and amid great persecution, she openly bore her testimony against a
                            generative life for Christians ; then she received a revelation of the work in America; and
                            in seventeen hundred and seventy-four, by the aid of Divine power, she, with her little band
                            of eight souls, was enabled to leave the shores of the eastern continent, and through the
                            guidance of the spirit of truth, was led to this land of freedom where liberty of conscience
                            is enjoyed. " For liberty is the soul's right to breathe, and, where it cannot take a long
                            breath, laws are girdled too tight." Char.— What you have said is in accordance with our
                            record. While listening to Mar. tha's expressed thoughts a desire for the increase and
                            spread of this pure Gospel was stirred anew within my heart. With her I would turn and
                            return the pages of this celestial work, and bring to open reflective view the increased
                            outgrowth of Mother's pure Gospel. We should be immortal teachers to mortals, developing to
                            external and internal glory, that nature whereon is enstamped the seal of God. Mel.— We will
                            note the progress of this Church, and, as we traverse the recesses of truth, strive to let
                            the blinding scales fall from spirit eye-sight, that all who see and hear may be edified and
                            encouraged in the upbuilding and sustaining of a cause, noble in its purpose, refining in
                            its character, and angelic and eternal in its life. Mar. C.— What need was there of a Second
                            appearing of Christ, when Jesus brought forth and promulgated a systenji of truth which
                            alone was sufficient for human redemption'? Mar. P.— How could he, without the aid of the
                            Mother Spirit, bring forth a perfect system of truth that would redeem the race ? Ann.— He
                            could not. He did not commu- nicate all the truth that was revealed to him, and which
                            governed His own life ; surround- ing conditions would not admit of it. He said to even his
                            nearest companions, " 1 have many things to tell you, but ye are not able to bear them now ;
                            when I am gone hence I will send the Comforter," etc., whjch was undoubtedly the Mother
                            Spirit, the esse of love. Mel.— Do we understand that the Christ is a direct unction from
                            the Supreme, or from the highest order of spirits, who stand as mediatorial agents for the
                            revelation of those exalted truths which will uplift souls from the generative life into the
                            angelic and divine ? Char.— The Christ baptism came from the highest order of spirits, who
                            are as Saviours, lights to other worlds, sons and daughters of the seventh sphere, or
                            Heaven; the only redemptive agents and mediators between supreme goodness and souls in this
                            and in other worlds. Mar. C.— By other worlds, do you mean planets? It is true that
                            scientific discovery lias led to the conclusion that they are composed of material
                            substances similar to this earth, and are inhabited by mortal beings who are adapted to
                            their varied climates. Sir William Herschel said, " It would be no more foolish for a man to
                            build twenty houses and only have one inhabited, than it would have been for the Creator to
                            frame myriads of worlds similar to this (and in many respects excelling it), and then have
                            only this one little dusty ball peopled with rational, intelligent beings V But, do you
                            suppose they are fallen and need redemption's work, as we all admit the inhabitants of this
                            world do ? Char.— By other worlds, I mean the six successive spheres or worlds, preceding
                            the seventh, and also the planets, the inhabitants of which, whether fallen or unfallen,
                            need the influence of the same spiritual agencies to unfold in them (as natural beings), the
                            seed buds of eternal life. As was once remarked with inspired power, " Mankind, whether
                            fallen or unfallen, need the mighty power of God to resurrect them from the natural into the
                            spiritual." Martha.— It is a broad and liberal system of theology that admits such universal
                            dissemination. A grand and lofty thought, the acme of which is the converging of all souls
                            to one harmonious Center — Eternal Wisdom and love, the Creative Source of the universe of
                            mind and matter. Mar. P.— Christ signifies anointing. It was this Anointing Spirit that
                            inspired the Witnesses of former days when they prophesied of the millennium, and uttered
                            many truths in advance of the knowledge and life of the people. The divine unction has also
                            rested upon the successors of Mother Ann, spiritually qualifying them (in the order of
                            leadership), to administer the Gospel in its power, and increase to other souls. Ann. —
                            Ancient philosophy taught that there was but " one God, the Father of all;" and its numerous
                            deities were intermediate spirits employed as agents, for God was too pure to be approached
                            by mortals. This ancient religion or theology is identical with ours, and we may consider
                            all religions as merely progressive steps, by which the human understanding has developed
                            itself in every time and place, and will continue to develop itself in the future. Mel.— May
                            we not conclude that the evident design of the " second appearing" was to reveal the female
                            in Christ ? Its intent also was progress, as prophesied by Isaiah : " To the order and
                            beauty of Christ's king- dom, in the latter day, there would be no end." Mar. C. — Eternal
                            progress ! beautiful thought. No popish or protestant creed, or thwarting priestly power
                            could check its cousee; but pure and simple in its unfoldings, it guided Mother and her
                            little band to this land of freedom, to establish a Church that was too universal in its
                            religious sentiments to find continued existence under the combined Church-and-State
                            government of England. Martha.— Then we believe that the Shaker Order holds a closer union
                            to, and more abiding relations with, the American government, than does any other organized
                            church to its government ? Char.— We do. The effect of the American revolution was the
                            institution of a republican form of government, which entitled all to an equal right in
                            political and religious belief. Thus America became the land of free thought and free
                            speech, as J. M. Peebles 22 <pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEES8. writes: "A land where the
                            people, conscious of their God-given rights, and cringing before no cowled priests, feel
                            themselves ' sovereigns.'" This prepared the way for the organization of the Shalcer Church
                            (in America) where the unadulterated principles of Christianity were recognized and wrought
                            out in the daily lives of its members. Hence the product of this Republican Government was
                            the estab- lishment of a spiritual government, moving in a corresponding line with the
                            regulations of the civil polity, yet exceeding it in purity and holiness, although the
                            interior order will be dependent for its increase of members upon the outward order. The
                            progressive advance of religious ideas, the rising wave of spiritual thought, and the wide
                            diffusion of the holy teachings, and principles evolved by wisdom in the civil government,
                            are the fruits of this union. And, as far as republican principles are diffused and
                            acknowledged, so far will the abstract principles of true Christianity be extended, until
                            all shall see and own their truth and validity. The growth of freedom and progressive rights
                            which belong to humanity are embodied in both. No sectarian creed, or fearful priestly
                            symbol harass the soul, or make it a subject of terror by arbitrary laws ; but true liberty
                            is ensured to all who nobly and uprightly maintain the just principles upon which these two
                            institutions are founded. Thus we see the civil and religious governments advancing toward a
                            genuine union; and the Christian Church, established upon a true foundation, will be blessed
                            and protected by the civil government, and they will co-operate and work harmoniously
                            together, while the superior law in the spiritual order will be as a guide to the earthly
                            order; and both standing in relation to true principles, will toil in harmony with God's
                            creation, in the cultivation of the soil, and the hills and dales will unite with those who
                            work the work of God. Mar. P.—You have clearly portrayed the relation that will exist in the
                            future between the civil and religious governments, when woman shall not be excluded from
                            her right to aid in purifying and sustaining the constitution and laws of the natural order
                            (which right is fully awarded her in the spiritual order). As this should precede and be as
                            a light outside, we know the day will yet dawn when woman's voice and influence will be
                            blest by the Republic, even as it is in the Temple of Christ's second appearing. Ann.— That
                            will be a glorious day, Margaret; but you are rather fast; you are foretelling the joys of
                            the future. Let us go back to the past, and from that rise to the present, then to the
                            future, as was our intention in this conversation. Mar. C.— Was Mother's testimony a new
                            revelation, or was it a revival of the principles of the Primitive Church, with an increase
                            of spiritual life and power ? Mel.— The principles of truth vary in power and strength,
                            according to the growth of mind, and Mother's testimony, with increased revelation, was a
                            revival of the same principles. Thus, the standard of truth was raised higher, with an
                            increase of self-denial. Martha.— Great and truthful principles have outlived generations,
                            traditions and corruptions, and have descended to us in the trans- cendent light of their
                            heavenly origin. " All good cometh from God, the source of light and perfection." Important
                            and elevating truths, manifested through chosen mediums and wit- nesses (and designed for
                            humanity's good) through past periods, have often been miscon- strued, and seemingly
                            perverted, by coming in contact with those corrupt influences which result from man's lost
                            condition, and, through his inability to perceive, or unwillingness to accept and apply them
                            practically, they have, for a time, been turned from a free and effective course. "But
                            truth,although crushed to earth shall rise again ;" and, however deeply it may be buried in
                            the debris of error, it shall be brought forth by the agency of that Almighty power, which
                            overrules all things, to shine untarnished in the lustre of its divine light. Mar. P.— We
                            must not overlook the fact, that in the formation and regulation of the Church, much
                            suffering was endured. Souls consecrated to truth freely gave their lives for those who
                            should succeed them in future generations. We who are now in a greater fullness of gospel
                            blessings do not comprehend or realize the depths of sorrow which often overwhelmed their
                            spirits. Mar. C.—And in this our day, many, not appreciating that fullness of blessing,
                            would conceive the idea of great personal disadvantages and trial. This feeling arises from
                            a lack of consecration and devotion to gospel communistic interests. We possess much greater
                            strength with which to bear life's needful burdens, and carry forward a noble and glorious
                            spiritual work, than when, in Mother's time, only eight souls were with her to sustain and
                            minister the truth. We are surrounded with gospel relations, and number eighteen established
                            societies (and bright spots they form in this broad free land of America), and, if there
                            were in each society but one individual, true and faithful to gospel principles, would there
                            not be more mediums for imparting the strength of virtue and the worth of goodness, than in
                            Mother's time? (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the editress" TEIform="index"/>TO THE EDITRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Neal, Emma Jane" TEIform="persName"/>Emma Jane Neal</byline><p TEIform="p">There is a line of demarcation between those who live a worldly life, and the practical
                            believer in Christ. One of the apostles said, " If ye be risen with Christ, set your
                            affections on things above, for ye are dead (to the world), and your life is hid with Christ
                            in God." It seems difficult for persons outside of a Shaker community to see and comprehend
                            the source of our supplies ; therefore they cannot believe that within the precincts of our
                            home there is aught but monotony, a dull round of duties ; and they do not see how the great
                            and growing desire for change, and what is called pleasure, can be satisfied, especially in
                            those who are full of young life. „, We are two-fold beings—have outward senses of hearing,
                            seeing, etc., with which we hear and see external things, which, if not abused, are a
                            blessing to us in our earth life. We also have spiritual organs corresponding to the
                            natural. If we use the external to the exclusion of the internal, then all our enjoyment
                            must be derived from the sensuous ; but if the spiritual senses are developed, and we learn
                            to commune with angels, and with them climb the immortal hills of truth, and roam in the
                            ever-verdant fields where we can cull flowers that will not fade, and gather heavenly fruit
                            that is sweet to the taste, then we feel joy of enduring worth, and pleasure that will never
                            die. If we fill the Christian character, we shall neither joy nor sorrow as do those who
                            live a worldly life ; but I am an admirer of the beautiful in nature, from which we may take
                            useful lessons ; and I think an occasional change of air and scenery is conducive to
                            physical health; yet we do not find comforts or pleasures abroad that equal those of our own
                            home and its surroundings. I recently took a trip into a north-western county of New York
                            State, and I send to you a few lines which I penned on that occasion. Do with them as you
                            think proper. Our journey was performed partly by rail and coach, and partly by boat down
                            the winding stream known as the Sacandaga. The scenery was wild, but varied and beautiful.
                            Our little bark lay tethered to the shore, Which soon would bear us down the winding stream,
                            Mid scenes beyond the skill of man to paint. Earth's verdant carpet now we tread with care
                            Unto the water's brink. All things arranged, the signal given, we move. A thrill of mingled
                            joy and fear pervades The mind, as o'er the laughing stream we glide But soon our trusting
                            hearts the nerve relieves As in our worthy pilot we confide, And, giving up our minds to
                            nature's gaze, Sweet inspiration fills the quickened tho't With themes sublime from her vast
                            book of lore. 0 erring man, puff'd up with vain conceit Of thy superior worth, take lessons
                            From the wild-wood's beauty ; rare, sublime, it Breathes perpetual praise, an offering free,
                            A grateful recompense for gifts bestowed, Outvying all thy feeble skill can give. The
                            massive heights o'er which the wild deer bounds, Stand forth as monuments of silent praise,
                            Save when the huntsman's gun doth echo there, Or cry of wild beasts rend the nightly air;
                            These, these alone thy sacred precincts mar. O nature fair ! enchanted with thy views, Thy
                            broad expanse where meekly thou dost weave, In solemn stillness, rarest patterns pure, Of
                            taste exquisite, wrought by skillful art, Without a boast of thy achievements great. The
                            Author of thy gifts my soul adores. And, like the wild bird in thy temple pure, On freedom's
                            pinions let my soul take flight, Far from the haunts of man's ambition vain, There my small
                            tribute offer at thy shrine — Unsoiled by vice which often treads the aisles Of sacred
                            temples rear'd by human art, And from thy teachings learn henceforth to act In life's great
                            drama with untiring zeal, Not for ambition's weak and worthless prize, But, like Thee,
                            offering simple, pure and free, God-given powers to bless humanity. Thus, while we're wafted
                            on thy bosom calm, Thou placid stream, winding 'mid verdure fair Through smiling fields and
                            circling lofty mounts, Let these sweet hours their hallowed impress make Upon my life when
                            cares and toils surround. In true reflection may I oft recall, And drink from memory's
                            spring the same sweet bliss Which fills my soul with tranquil thoughts of Heaven. — Mt.
                            Lebanon.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gentle deeds" TEIform="index"/>GENTLE DEEDS</head><p TEIform="p">Andante. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Gentle deeds are 2. It is ours to 3. O, it is a ever forming
                            Verdant spots within each heart; Whence shall spring the plants of virtue, Flow'rs that
                            incense sweet impart; be progressing, And to toil with ardent thought, That our lives may
                            mer it blessing, And with hoIiness be fraught, blessed haven. Where no blighted pow'rs
                            remain; Where unholy strife is banish'd, And pure love our souls enchain. Such shall wa ken
                            thoughts most holy; Bring to life some germ of love; Cause as pir ings true and lasting, For
                            the powers that lift above. Morn shall ope with new desires; Evening shall their strength
                            increase; While the angels find our spirits Eesting in the realms of peace. Here in union we
                            are leaving All the glit'ring dust of earth; Seeking only the immortal, Which will give us
                            angel birth.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit I covet" TEIform="index"/>THE SPIRIT I COVET</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Calver, Amelia" TEIform="persName"/>Amelia Calver</byline><p TEIform="p">Praying spirit of my Savior, In my heart O, find a place ; Help me, when the night is
                            darkest, When upon the desert waste. When the day seems drear and cloudy, And sweet hope her
                            powers resign, Blessed Savior, be thou near me ; Prayerful spirit, be thou mine. Peaceful
                            spirit of my Savior, Canst thou find a place with me ? Give me power to calm the tempest,
                            While upon Time's billowy sea. I would have my words and actions Bend subservient to thy
                            will; That, should wrath my bosom enter, I can whisper " Peace, be still." Steadfast spirit
                            of my Savior, Let me feel thy scepter's sway, Then like thee, I'll tread with firmness
                            Duty's path, in trial's day. Like thee, I will stand unyielding To the lurking charms of
                            ease ; Over self will reign triumphant, Seeking God alone to please. Forgiving spirit of my
                            Savior, Take possession of my heart; When offenses grieve my spirit, Wilt thou then thy balm
                            impart ? Aid me to recall thy sorrows On the crucifixion day, When in sweet and tender
                            accents, " Forgive them Father," thou did'st pray. Loving spirit of my Savior, Let me in thy
                            fountains bathe, Ready to renounce all pleasure Which a selfish heart would crave. With thy
                            influence for my guardian, I can for all others care ; Joy with them when joy aboundeth,
                            Likewise of their sorrows share. Healing spirit of my Savior, O could I possess thy power,
                            Gladly every pain I'd banish, Frail humanity restore. Tho' I fail to heal the body, May I
                            not the spirit soothe ? Touch the wounded broken spirit, Healing with the tones of love ?
                            Blessed Savior, thy example E 'er shall be my " Polar star," Guiding, though 'mid trackless
                            waters, Pointing on to realms afar. Prayerful, Peaceful, Steadfast, Healing, Loving and
                            Forgiving ever, Blessed spirit of my Savior, O, I pray thee, leave me never. Mt.
                        Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines addressed to Elder Daniel Hawkins, a short time before his demise" TEIform="index"/>LINES ADDRESSED TO ELDER DANIEL HAWKINS, A SHORT TIME BEFORE HIS DEMISE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Agnew, Hannah R." TEIform="persName"/>Hannah R. Agnew</byline><p TEIform="p">Thou worthy disciple, time's journey is ended, Repair to thy treasure above; Bright angels
                            are waiting in triumph to meet you, With songs of rejoicing and love. With patience and
                            zeal, you toiled in the vineyard Of Him, who will justly reward; In health and in sickness,
                            in joy and in sorrow, Devoted your all to the Lord. The rising and falling of many in
                            Israel, You witnessed, and firmly you stood; 'Mid rough, beating surge, like a rock in the
                            ocean, You braved the tempestuous flood. In times of affliction,the Lord has been mindful,
                            His angels to guard you he sent; His hand was not shortened, his ear was not heavy, When
                            humbly in prayer you have bent. Now hear the glad sound of " Well done faithful servant,"
                            Rejoice with your Savior and Lord ; His cross you have borne, and His yoke you have taken;
                            Receive your most glorious reward. Go meet the dear friends, who have toiled for the gospel,
                            And suffered on earth with you here; Go rest where the wicked shall never more trouble, Nor
                            sorrow's dark shadow appear. Your crown is prepared, and your mansion is ready, Bright
                            angels invite you along; Go join in the choir, and sing the sweet chorus Rejoice with the
                            purified throng. O, grant a free blessing to those you are leaving. Give love that will
                            banish their tears ; Exhort all to trust in the Lord, and remember The prayer of the
                            righteous He hears. And now, fare you well, loving father and brother, With full length of
                            days you are blest; Like a well-ripened sheaf that's prepared for the garner, So you are
                            prepared for your rest. Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Susan B. Anthony before the Constitutional Convention" TEIform="index"/>SUSAN B. ANTHONY
                            BEFORE THE CONSTITUTIONAL CONVENTION</head><p TEIform="p">By permission of the Constitutional Convention, Susan B. Anthony appeared before that body,
                            and delivered a forcible and earnest plea in behalf of female suffrage, in which she
                            requested the Convention, in making their report, to suggest that the objectionable word
                            male be stricken out of the State laws, so that women may enjoy that liberty which is their
                            right, for, said Susan Anthony, it is just as certain that ultimately the franchise will be
                            accorded women as that it has been granted to the negro; and by your honorable body
                            assisting us now you will be simply performing a duty that, in the event of your failing,
                            will be granted by your successors, and to them will be given the honor.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What you can never catch" TEIform="index"/>What You Can Never Catch</head><p TEIform="p">— Boys and girls, what is it that you can never catch, though you chase after it on the wings
                            of the wind? You can never catch the word that has once gone out of your lips. Once spoken
                            it is out of your reach; do your best, you can never recall it. Therefore take care of what
                            you say. Never speak an unkind word, an impure word, a lying word, a profane word.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>