<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1208" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18820801" TEIform="date">August 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> VOL. XII. AUGUST. NO. 8. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. our home at
                        shirley, mass. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it.'' SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1882. </p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb n="2"/>
                            <pb n="3"/>
                            <pb n="4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="169" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                        <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Beauty, God's Agents, Hannah Goodrich, un attained, A Dialogue, Kind Words, Early Impressions,
                            Thoroughness, Elijah Wilds, Judge Not, Abolition of Slavery, Orville Dyeh, A Great Evil, Concert of Action, E.
                            Page. 169 Temperance, 183 171 Life, ..... 183 173 Notes, .... 184 174 Correspondence, - , 186 175 Deaths, .....
                            187 176 My Little Bed, 187 176 Not if it was my Boy, 187 177 Books and Papers, 188 178 To prepare Straw for
                            making Bonnets, 188 179 Value of Borax, 189 180 Shaker Brown Bread, - 189 181 Glycerine for Burns, 189 182
                            Music,—Exaltation of Zion, 190 183 How to Milk, 192 Vol. XII. AUGUST, 1882. ]STo. VIII. </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>CALVIN G. REED</byline><p TEIform="p">Beauty is the reflex of the inner Life. Within the rough, unsightly stone, the Sculptor's
                            penetrating, cultured eye, views All the graceful figure of the noble Statue, and witli
                            careful, patient strokes on Skillfully directed chisel, forms for The admiring world, the
                            Beau-ideal Of his mental, beautiful conception. The artist, sketches on his sensitive,
                            Receptive canvass, bright creations which Adorn the decorated chambers of His roseate,
                            illuminated soul; And fascinated throngs, admire the grace And imagery, displayed by
                            beauteous Art. The skilled musician, sweeps with magic hand The cords of harp or violin, or
                            tunes The soul with touching melody, and strains Of richest music, ears enchanted greet,
                            Enraptured hearts with deep emotions swell, And every sense of all our being thrill. We
                            breathe ecstatic air! We feel the soul Of beauties sweet, controlling power, emersed In holy
                            inspiration and delight. The poet tunes his lyre, and measures move In harmony with finest
                            shades of thought, Ard marshalled metaphors and figures, wake The world of loving
                            symphonies, arrayed In all the beauties of celestial life. All glorious is the universal
                            plan ! Here symmetry and beauty wisely blend. But what of grace, hath rich and gaudy
                            flowers? What beauty hath the vernal landscape's robe Of green, bedecked with blooming trees
                            and plants, And purling streams meandering thro' the meads, And crystal lake, upon whose
                            glassy face, Is mirrored all the grandeur of the earth And sky, within its clear and pure
                            confines? What charms have the arborean slopes ; the Graceful, undulating hills' embowered
                            Dells ; rich fertile fields ; grand lofty mountains, With their vast, umbrageous forests
                            crowned; Or pleasant groves, the balmy zephyrs kiss,— That, with adoring grace, bow their
                            proud heads, And with extended, waving arms, slim, Emerald, silken fingers play aeolian
                            harps, While tuneful songsters, warble joyful praise And hallelujahs mid their sylvan
                            bowers? What beauty hath the canopy of heaven, With twinkling stars and brilliant orbs
                            adorned, <pb n="170" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 170 SHAKER MANIFESTO. That nightly smile, with mellow light,
                            upon Us from their spacious dwelling place on high? What beauty, charm, or symmetry,
                            havethese For those, whose inner life feels r.ot the thrill Of the inspiring tints and
                            tones, displayed In the grand realm of Beauty's ceaseless Spring? The melancholy,
                            superstitious soul, Enshrouded in thick mists of ignorance, Views Earth and her
                            environments, with all The multitudes that feed upon her life, In deep disorder and
                            confusion sunk. Beholds the Great Creator, angry with his Intermeddling children, who in
                            their Fancied bliss, by Curiosity led on, Pried open Queen Pandora's box of Private
                            treasures, when out sprang all Earth's woes, With our afflicting sins and ills, and all The
                            black, portentious forms of chilling death ! Sees all the mighty depths of space, alive With
                            specters and commissioned spirits, sent To visit earth and erring sinful man, With plagues
                            and retributive chastenings, For broken laws and unrepentant heart. The cloudless skies, and
                            ambient stilly air, Are but precursors of impending storms. The lonely Indian, simple soul,
                            could see No beauty in the sweet Magnolia's ricli And fragrant bloom, nor in the splendor of
                            The golden sunset sky, inlaid with lines Of silver, and the rainbow's matchless hues, To
                            him, creation was a joyless waste, The cheerful sun, lent him no cheering ray, His springs
                            of pleasure all had ceased to flow, And all the fountains of his hopes were dry. E'en life
                            was but a gilded mockery ! His kindred slept in silent graves, within The cold damp earth,
                            or bleaching lay, stretched on The sanguinary fields of strife. Nought left To charm him to
                            the love of mundane life. What multitudes seek only glittering joys ! Chase phantoms that
                            elude the eager grasp, Which, while they lure, spread disappointment's thorns Along the
                            pathway of their votaries, To pierce the wayward feet and grasping hands, And sting with
                            bitterness the heart's bright hopes, Because they seek through Alchemy for gold, Instead of
                            veins, where, hidden, lies the rich, Productive ore that pays the miner's toil. God fills
                            the world with beauty ! Radiant rays Of light, imprint his living glories on His noble
                            works. On man, He sheds the powers Of His Great Soul, mid happy tho'ts to dwell, In pleasant
                            paths of halcyon peace to tread, To be unto himself the treasurer Of the refulgent
                            brightness of His love. Then why not choose the beautiful! Why not, With faculties of mind,
                            of soul, attuned To all the grand sublimities of life, Have every heart pulse beat with
                            Wisdom's Laws, Unfolding in us beatific grace, True goodness, and eternal love divine. When
                            the deep fountains of the soul, well up With jetting spraj's of liquid blissfulness, And all
                            is brilliancy and joy within, The bloom and fruitage of our daily lives, Then will the whole
                            creation, smiling, shed The lustre of its beauteous spirit On our pure, receptive minds, in
                            halos Of inspiring power, and symphonies Refulgent with the glory of the Blest. Then will
                            the buds, the leaves, the opening flowers, Meet kindly welcome in our loving hearts, And
                            open volumes of philosophy, And heaven born truths for our improvement given. How marvelous
                            are all thy works ! Supreme Omniscient Architect of worlds unnumbered, Swarming with their
                            myriad hosts of living Ranks, in just gradation ranged, from man To brute, from brute to
                            insect tribes, and thence To floral fields, of diverse kinds, instinct With life and beauty.
                            Th' workmanship, divine! Eternal Father, Great Preserver, Guide, And kind Protector of the
                            soul immortal, Undying spark of thy Eternal Brightness, Formed to shine Mrith heavenly
                            light, and dwell mid Glories of bright spheres, delectable and pure, Thou art the soul and
                            source of harmony. Thy beauties blend most gracefully to full Perfection brought, Thou
                            fillest every heart, <pb n="171" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 171 With constant cheerfulness
                            and lasting peace, Who make the inner life all beautiful Thro' education and celestial
                            grace. Such see the beautiful in everything; And feel that happy angels, on their snow White
                            pinions, bear them blessings from the spheres Of purest joys aud lasting happiness. Give,
                            then, the mind to understanding! Rule The soul by inspirations found alone In Wisdom's model
                            school,—The Beautiful. All wise Creator of the realms of Light, Whose every thought is full
                            of blooming grace, Whose breath is fragrant with supreme delight, Whose works, unnumbered,
                            full of harmony, The effluence of eternal, sacred truth;— Let me, now, offer at thy hallowed
                            shrine, Sweet incense of adoring gratitude ; And worship, with unfolded, graceful soul, The
                            God of Beauty, who created all. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's agents" TEIform="index"/> GOD'S AGENTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">God works through human, and superhuman agencies to perfect His plans, and accomplish His
                            work. Mediums, or ruling spirits from age to age, have been employed to roll forward the
                            wheels of progress, and prepare the race for higher, and still higher planes of thought, and
                            action. Thus we reason, and decide, according to the evidence produced to our minds. We read
                            that "God is Love" that "He is'Light." We judge that no one who believes that God is, will
                            question the premises, that He is the Author and Giver of all that is good, true and just.
                            But the mode and manner of administration to sentient beings, has been a subject of debate ;
                            whether by direct communication with mortals, or through one Mediator Christ Jesus, or
                            through many Mediators, who are appointed agencies to watch over and^ guard the welfare and
                            protect the interest of all who are in rapport with them. There have been marked periods of
                            time, doAvn through the rolling ages, when the spirit of war, hatred and revenge, ruled in
                            the hearts, and controlled the actions of the children of men, and caused them to devour one
                            another, in so much, that thousands upon thousands have fallen in battle in a short period
                            of time. Could we open our eyes upon the vast multitudes of beings who are now dwellers in
                            spirit spheres, who have been slain in battle, tortured upon the rack, consumed by wild
                            beasts, and perished by faggots and flames ; what would be o'-ir sensations? Let us pass
                            that by ! The claim that the Lord not only sanctioned their cause, but commanded them thus
                            to do, and even went with them and took an active part, and helped them fight their battles,
                            we cannot admit. If any God was with them, it was not the good God whom we address, in a
                            dual capacity, as the God of Love ! The god, or gods of the warring Israelites, must have
                            been on the same plane, and in rapport with the kings of that ancient people, whose
                            vengeance through ambition, and love of rule, could be easily stirred, and were so blood
                            thirsty that themselves and the steeds which they rode "smelled the battle afar off." They
                            believed in war, it was the god of that age and dispensation. How far a large majority at
                            the present time is removed from those conditions, they who are able, and clear sighted must
                            decide. We claim to live in an age of civilization, of free thought and Christian culture ;
                            but in the recent conflict between the North and South, the professed followers of thelowy
                            Prince of Peace, had an^ opportunity <pb n="172" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 172 SHAKER MANIFESTO. to show
                            their faith by their words, and works. How did they do it? The priests stood in their
                            pulpits, and with uplifted hands before assembled multitudes, prayed that God would confound
                            their opponents, and give them the victory over those whom they called their enemies,
                            although, in a large degree, they were professedly their Christian brethren, who had
                            frequently met with them in what they called "holy communion" at the Lord's table. We are
                            free to say, that we do not admit that the projectors, nor the participators in that war,
                            were influenced by the God of Love, as manifest through the Christ spirit, sent from the
                            high heavens on a mission of peace to this sin darkened earth. If any god was in it, it was
                            the god who rules over the affairs of men on the generative plane of life, where war,
                            marriage and private property bear sway ; but can have no abiding place in Christ's kingdom
                            on the resurrection plane. If those elements, or principles, seek to find entrance there, He
                            will make his angels ministers of spiritual fire that will burn as an oven, until it
                            consumes them, as a flame devours the stubble. But those who stand steadfast in all that is
                            true and good, will feel that "Christ has risen with healing in his wings ;" and will be
                            comforted as a loving mother would embrace, caress, and comfort a good obedient child. As we
                            trace the history of the past, let us read, understand, and learn wisdom. The spirit of
                            anti-christhas been, is and will be in the future, opposed to the true Christ. In the first
                            Christian era, even before Jesus, the first prepared medium received the holy unction, the
                            heavenly baptism which clothed him with spiritual power to inaugurate a new dispensation,
                            and lay the foundation of a spiritual edifice, anti-christ began to work against; and
                            mediums inspired by Jewish law givers, and law worshipers in the spirit world, instituted a
                            system of espionage and persecution; and sought to destroy the life of the child, who was to
                            wax strong, and bring forth a system of New ideas, and teach a higher law than "an eye for
                            an eye" as Moses had done. His, was the law of Love, not of revenge and retaliation ! "Love
                            your enemies ; bless and curse not." After he was imbued with the Christ spirit from the
                            interior heavens, so strong and powerful was the love of the Father that dwelt in him, and
                            pervaded his whole being, that the whole power and combined influence of the priesthood
                            could not overcome nor prevail against him, until he had performed his mission, and finished
                            the work his Father had given him to do. He transmitted his powei to his disciples, and the
                            Jews killed his physical body ; but his testimony did not die ! The spirit of persecution
                            followed his disciples; and the strong adherents of the law, not even its most learned
                            devotees could prevail against the testimony of the new Law-giver. The strong spirited Paul
                            fell prostrate before the power that attended the ministry of the new dispensation,
                            convicted him of his persecuting spirit, and converted him to the Christian faith. The
                            principles upon which the Father Church was founded eighteen centuries ago through the
                            medium of the Son-ship, are as true today as they were then. A virgin life ; Non-resistance
                            and Community of temporal interest, formed the basis of that noble structure. The history of
                            the first Christian Church, although <pb n="173" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 173 it has
                            passed through many revisions, and by change may have been weakened, yet is filled with
                            useful lessons, in many respects is our teacher and corrector today. How came that glorious
                            church to decline and lose its spiritual power ? Internal division opened the door for the
                            entrance of the war spirit through Constantine, a man of blood, who found his way into the
                            temple of God, dethroned the real Christ, usurped the power, and conquered by the sword.
                            What followed in succeeding ages, they who run may read ! What spirit threatens to destroy
                            the foundations of the second Christian Church of today ? It is the sensual spirit; it has
                            an oily tongue and already stands at our doors knocking, and singing the siren song ! Let
                            Zion's sons and daughters awake from their lethargy and take warning! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hannah Goodrich" TEIform="index"/> HANNAH GOODRICH</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">(Continued from last number.) She was also eminently endowed with great spiritual discernment
                            and at the same time gifted in the spirit of prophecy. During the first years of Mother
                            Hannah's ministry, she was quite able to bear the fatigue of the long and severe journeys to
                            New Lebanon, as well as to the other societies, but as these journeys were generally made in
                            the saddle, she discontinued them as soon as carriages were introduced, and the roads made
                            suitable for travel.* *The saddle which Mother Hannah Goodrich used on her first journey
                            from Hancock to Canterbury is still preserved at the last named place. It formerly belonged
                            to MothMother Hannah Goodrich was also a woman of excellent executive abilities, and her
                            general management of the affairs of the Societies, at Canterbury and Enfield, met with
                            universal favor and approval. During the twenty eight years of her administration, she very
                            carefully and conscientiously followed the instructions of the Ministry of New Lebanon and
                            taught her people, that in order to insure prosperity and the blessing of God to his people,
                            they must never lose sight of their religious obligations. At the early date of which we are
                            writing, it was considered quite an attainment to be able to present an article of
                            manufacture that would reflect an honor upon the makers. The Believers at New Lebanon stood
                            first in this as well as in many other things, and Mother Hannah took pleasure in the
                            cultivation of so worthy an object. While on her visits to New Lebanon, she would obtain
                            some article to take home as a model of religious care as exercised by the Brethren and
                            Sisters of the Parent Society. In the journal of the Church of Canterbury, it says,—"We
                            often received specimens of the various kinds of manufacture as samples, made in the most
                            substantial and perfect manner, such as leather, seives, clothing, boots and shoes, pails,
                            small oval boxes, hoes, nails and other articles." "The Trustees were not permitted to sell
                            any article whatever, at any price, unless it was free from blemish. We er Lucy Wright, who
                            presented it to Mother Hannah. The acceptance of the gilt was under a very severe cross as
                            it separated Hannah from all her former friends as well as her gospel relation with whom she
                            had so long and so earnestly prayed and suffered for the truths's sake. <pb n="174" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 174 SHAKER MANIFESTO. were to be an example of righteousness in all our temporal
                            management and workmanship." At the time of Mother Hannah's initiation into the order of the
                            Ministry, in 1792, it was found necessary to establish an equality of government for the
                            sexes, that the sisters should have the same rights and privileges in things pertaining to
                            the temporal and spiritual economy of the order as was vested in the Brethren. Father Job
                            Bishop and Elder Edmund Lougee of New Lebanon N. Y. had already been appointed to the office
                            of Ministers, and were engaged in the establishment of the Societies of Canterbury and
                            Enfield in N. PL On the arrival of Mother Hannah Goodrich and Eldress Anna Burdick of
                            Hancock, Mass, the leading authority was perfected. Under the direction of this order, and
                            by the union of the adult members, all of the offices in the Society were established, and
                            the management of the departments was conducted by their respective directors. In the early
                            part of the year of 1819 Mother Hannah was prostrated by severe sickness, while at the
                            (Society in Enfield. She was obliged to remain in that place some five months, from Feb.
                            10th to July 13th. During this protracted term of ill health she was kindly and tenderly
                            cared for by Sister Esther Ferrin who was, at that time, an associate with Mother Hannah.
                            The Brethren made their regular trips to the Societies, during this time, although
                            unaccompanied by any sisters. On the 13th of July Mother Hannah returned to Canterbury,
                            accompanied by two sisters and Br. Benjamin Warren, the physician of the Society at Enfield.
                            From this severe prostration Mother Hannah never recovered sufficiently to be able to attend
                            to her official duties. Her decease occurred on the 9th of Feb. 1820, to the great sorrow of
                            all her Brethren and Sisters in the Societies of Canterbury and Enfield. Her age was 56
                            years, 9mo. and 13 days. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unattained" TEIform="index"/>UNATTAINED
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> [From Scribner's Monthly.]</p><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Tired, tired and spent, the day is almost run, And oh, so little done
                                    ! Above, and far beyond, far out, of sight, Ilight over hight, I know the distant
                                    hills I should have trod— The hills of GodLift up their airy peaks, crest over
                                    crest, Where I had prest My faltering, weary feet, had strength been given, And
                                    found my Heaven. Yet once, ah, once, the place where I now stand, The promised land
                                    Seemed to my young, rapt vision, from afar, The morning star Shone for my guidance,
                                    beckoned me along, At break of day light, The path looked strewn with flowers; in
                                    that white Each distant hight Smiled at me like a friend—a faithful friend— Sure
                                    that the end Would soon, ah, soon repay with sweet redress All weariness, But when
                                    the time wore on, and in the bright And searching light Of high noonday, I lifted up
                                    my eyes, The purple dyes Through which I had descried my mountain hight, Had
                                    vanished quite. Then, suddenly I knew that I did stand Within the promised land Of
                                    youth's fair dreams and hopes; but with a thrill, I saw that still Above and far
                                    beyond far out of sight Ilight over hight, Lifted the fairer hills I should have
                                    trod— The hills of God!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Scribner's monthly" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perry, Nora" TEIform="persName"/> Nora Perry</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest" TEIform="index"/>REST</head><p TEIform="p">Go and rest, it is the best Of all life's panaceas To give new strength, And may at length
                            Give even new ideas.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><pb n="175" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue between a Shaker and a clergyman" TEIform="index"/>A DIALOGUE Between a Shaker and a
                            Clergyman</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">(Continued fkom last number.) C. What! Having begun in the spirit dt you expect to be made
                            perfect by the flesh? Do you count the blood of the covenant wherewith Jesus was sanctified
                            an unholj thing? 0 ! may God have mercy on you, and save you from your awful delusion. What!
                            Have you discarded the righteousness of Jesus Christ as the ground of your hope for
                            justification before God? And do you expect to obtain heaven on the ground of your own
                            righteousness? May God have mercy on you. and pluck you as a brand from the eternal burning.
                            Is it then in vain that God has declared that He, Jesus, who knew no sin was made sin, or a
                            sin offering for us, that we might be made the righteousness of God in him? If our sins are
                            not reckoned to the account of Jesus, and if his righteousness is not reckoned to our
                            account, to us there is no hope, but the blackness of darkness forever. S. In relation to
                            imputed righteousness, I was led to believe that it would not be a safe foundation for me to
                            stand upon, when I saw so much positive testimony in the scriptures of truth to the
                            contrary, showing that a man must become righteous himself, personally, by doing right.
                            Christ taught his disciples that they must have an exceeding righteousness of their own, by
                            a daily cross, by following his example, and living his life. See Matt, v : 10, 20, "For I
                            say unto you except your righteousness shall exceed etc." If a dependence on the
                            righteousness of Christ was sufficient for salvation, why did he not tell his disciples?
                            John testified thus, "Little children, let no man deceive you, he that doeth righteousness,
                            is righteous, even as he is righteous." I John ii: 29, and iii: 7. If the single testimony
                            of John be true, what more do we need, than to become righteous, as Christ is righteous, by
                            doing right as he did? What need is there for imputation? And what must be the situation of
                            those who profess the Christian name, and live in sin? "He that comrnitteth sin is of the
                            devil." I John iii: 7, 8, 9. But time would fail to quote all the testimony in favor of a
                            righteous life, and being saved by the cross of Jesus. C Read, dear brother, the epistle to
                            the Galatians if indeed you have not discarded the precious, holy Bible. Read, I entreat of
                            you the Holy Bible, search the New Testament, and pray much to your injured but merciful
                            Redeemer, and may God give you a spiritual imderstanding of his truth.—Come and see me again
                            soon. S- It was by reading and prayer to God that made me a Shaker. In answer to my prayers
                            I have received that peace which heretofore I was a stranger, and did not know that it was
                            on the earth until I found it for myself, and in obeying the light and truth of God as fast
                            as it was made manifest to me, I have found peace and happiness. On reading the Testimony of
                            Christ's Second Appearing, I found it so full of the precious holy Bible, and ecclesiastical
                            history, that I could not possibly, discard one without discarding the other, they were
                            indissolubly connected. Both were designed to make us wise unto salvation. • Before closing
                            this discussion allow me to say, that "marrying and giving in marriage" was one of the
                            charges brought against the ante-diluvians—not so much against marriage, as it was the
                            unbounded licentiousness cloaked under it. And as it was in the days of Noah, so it is now
                            in this day. Crimes are increasing all over the world. It is said on good authority that
                            houses of ill fame in all our large cities, are supported largely by the married, some of
                            whom are clergymen, of the orthodox persuasion, church members, not a few, members of our
                            Legislature, Lawyers, Judges, members of Congress, and other high officials, too numerous to
                            mention. If this be true, is it any wonder that "caamities," of which we have been
                            fore-warned, are increasing, and growing more serious every year? When the Judgments of God
                            are abroad in the earth, will men learn righteousness?" Will they learn to do right? If
                            udgments begin at the house of God, what will be the end of those who obey not the gosjel of
                            Christ's second coming? <pb n="176" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 176 SHAKER MANIFESTO. C. Having laid your
                            views before the Church, and they consider them contrary to sound doctrine, and under a
                            sense of their duty to God, and covenant obligations, have with drawn from you the hand of
                            fellowship. Done by order and in behalf of the Church. A. D. Clerk. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tiffany, Amanda" TEIform="persName"/>AMANDA TIFFANY</byline><p TEIform="p">O the power of kindly spoken words ! Who can tell their priceless worth ; who,' but those who
                            have been soothed and cheered by their sweet influence ! When the care-worn heart, oppressed
                            by the toils and burdens of life, receives a kindly, sympathetic word, how quickly the
                            drooping spirit will revive, and show its appreciation by that glow of pleasure which lights
                            up the countenance, and brightens the whole being, manifesting its tranquilizing influence
                            over the soul. When naught else with the erring avails, let us try the kind loving word of
                            unfeigned interest, and see the effect. How often has the most hardened and unrelenting
                            heart been led to feel sorrow and contrition for its wrongs through the influence of the
                            timely, kind word. Be kind to the aged, those who have borne the burdens of life in the heat
                            of the day, who have endured privations and hardships, that the rising generations might
                            enjoy a quiet and peaceful home, and the many luxuries of life, which to them were unknown.
                            We are enjoying the fruits of their labors, in peace and plenty. Do we realize how much we
                            are indebted to them ? Dear young friends, let us be more thoughtful on this subject, and
                            give to them the kind word, the pleasant smile and the helping hand, thus fill their few
                            remaining days with the sunshine of kindness and the peace of loving, grateful hearts. Mb.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Early impressions" TEIform="index"/> EARLY IMPRESSIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha A." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA A. BURGER</byline><p TEIform="p">''As the twig is bent, the tree inclines." This is an axiom that should be borne in mind by
                            those who are the guardians and instructors of children and youth. True principles may be so
                            simplified and brought down to the comprehension of children at an early age as to form a
                            basis of future action, and to help mold their characters for noble and useful lives.
                            Speaking and acting the truth in all places and at all times, should be constantly kept
                            before the minds of children and youth ; and they should be taught it is far more noble to
                            acknowledge a fault, either great or small—than to seek to conceal it; and that by so doing,
                            they will form a bond of love and confidence between themselves and their guardians that
                            will not be easily broken. Also the necessity of yielding obedience to elders and teachers,
                            and those who watch over their welfare, and to pay deference to superiors of larger
                            experience than they, should be one of the first lessons taught. As a general rule, we find
                            that children at the present time are precocious, and stiff-willed ; that at an early age
                            they ^incline to be haughty, and independent of the counsel of those who are older, and
                            should be wiser ; but whose example, we regret to say, is many times far from being worthy
                            to be copied. Parents need moralizing ; and to feel the necessity of regarding natural laws
                                <pb n="177" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 177 on the procreative plane of life, that
                            children may have a better start, and be better born ; and not be conceived in sin of the
                            most sensual kind—as. many are, and cradled in iniquity by partaking diseased food from
                            diseased parents. If children were brought into existence properly, under right influences
                            and right impressions were stamped upon their minds while they were young and tender, we
                            would have better children, better men and women, and a better condition of society. As it
                            is now, tens of thousands are stranded on the shores of the great ocean of time, like
                            strangers in some foreign land, without home and friends, and are left to be lashed by the
                            wild waves of passion, or to be guided by fate's strong decree, and take their chance for
                            weal or for woe. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoroughness" TEIform="index"/> THOROUGHNESS</head><p TEIform="p">If you only do one thing during the day, do if—don't half do it. The want of thoroughness is
                            the cause of more than half the small miseries we endure, and which, altogether, make life
                            almost uneudurable. Try to find out the best way of doing the smallest thing, and when you
                            have learned that way, do it, even if it takes a little more time. Time ! people are always
                            complaining that they haven't time for anything, and the principal reason is, that
                            everything is so poorly done, that three-fourths of j our time is spent in doing it over, or
                            in trying to remedy the mischief caused by inaccuracy and want of thoroughness. The evil is
                            not confined to domestic and social life ; it does not stop at smearing instead of washing
                            dishes, and pots, and kettles ; it is not content with destroying all chance of peace and
                            comfort by the destruction and waste it causes ; it is sapping the moral character and
                            integrity of the people. Men and women are as careless of what they say, as whatthey do.
                            Without any intention of really falsifying, allow themselves to convey false impressions,
                            and seem to have almost lost the power of making a simple, plain, and truthful statement.
                            They deal in gross exaggerations, in high-sounding words, which convey either a wrong idea
                            or none at all. No one is content to be themselves ; every one wants to be, or appear to be,
                            something else ; and so, instead of a pleasing variety of individualities, in which every
                            one is content to be his own best, we have a Babel of shams and make-believes, in which each
                            one tries to lose his own identity and take txp that of his neighbor. Pretense is the
                            natural out-growth of want of thoroughness. Persons who are thorough are generally honest,
                            simple, truthful. Try to be this. If you are careless or have acquired the habit of
                            exaggeration, stop it! try to control it as you would a disease. If you have only a button
                            to sew on, sew it on well. One of the most-tedious and important tasks which the mother of a
                            family has to perform, is sewing the buttons on shoes and garments which have been purchased
                            ready made, and which she knows, by experience, the first strain will pull from their
                            places. A shoe store or furnishing store would make a fortune by advertising *¦'buttons well
                            sewed on." How gratefully we remember one who <pb n="178" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 178 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            has worked for us thoroughly and conscientiously ! His work lives after him, while the
                            careless person does untold mischief, not only by carelessness, but by recklessness ; for
                            "Fools rush in where angels fear to tread." Young men and young women, the future is in your
                            hands ; make it an improvement on the present in this respect, at least: Don't be a sham,
                            and don't do things by halves. If your duty lies in digging potatoes, or peeling them, do it
                            so well that it will be a pleasure to yourself and others to contemplate your work. The
                            quality of thoroughness, or the absence of it, shows as plainly in one position as another,
                            and is as valuable in the king as in the one who serves him. Be your own best !—Exchange</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elijah Wilds [part 1]" TEIform="index"/>ELIJAH WILDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilds, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">[We publish the following auto-biographic sketch, at the suggestion of Elder John Whiteley.]
                            I was born in the year 1746 at Groton, in Massachusetts. My parents were very careful to
                            instill the principles of morality into the minds of their children, and took much pains,
                            according to the light they had, to show us our state by nature, and the necessity of being
                            regenerated and born of God, in order to obtain the Kingdom of Heaven. These instructions
                            made a serious impression upon my mind, in early youth, and increased as I advanced in
                            years. I was taught to search the scriptures, and became well acquainted with the written
                            word, but was ignorant of the spirit by which it was dictated. Having an anxiety about a
                            future state, and desinng to find some way of salvation, I went from place to place to hear
                            preachers of different denominations, but found none who could administer relief to my soul.
                            This anxiety of mind continued, till I was twenty one years of age. At this time I purchased
                            a farm in the town of Shirley, and was much prospered in my efforts to improve it. My mind
                            continued anxious to find the way of God, and so intense was my thought of God's work in the
                            days of the apostles, that I often wept, hoping and praying that I might live to see the
                            glorious day of Christ's Second Coming. Improvements were made upon my farm, and buildings
                            were erected for the accommodation of my family, which was now increased by the addition of
                            four children. In the summer of 1781 I heard of a new sect of people who were at the Square
                            House, so called, in Harvard. I went to see them, and they taught that the gospel of Christ
                            required us to confess and forsake all sin, and to bear a daily cross. They testified that
                            in order to obtain salvation from sin, God required the self-denial of every impure act,
                            word and thought. They also testified that Christ had commenced his second appearance,
                            without sin, u. to salvation, to all who were willing to believe and obey. And truly,
                            salvation was the object of my desires. The power of their testimony, and the spirit of
                            godliness, which I felt from them convinced me that Mother Ann was a person sent to
                            administer eternal life, to the children of this world. On my second visit they presented a
                            farther degree of light, to my mind, than before. The trumpet gave a certain sound, and I
                            felt it my duty to prepare <pb n="179" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> for battle. They said, we must .overcome
                            sin before we could sit down with the Lamb of God in the Kingdom of Heaven. That we must
                            overcome, even as Jesus overcame. The evidences of the testimony, and the manifestations of
                            the power of God, were so powerful and convincing, that I could not resist them. I therefore
                            confessed my sins, to God, in the presence of his witnesses and found that assurance and
                            releasement which I had never found before. They taught me the necessity of righting all my
                            wrongs, by making restitution where I had done injury to any one, and of living a pure and
                            holy life. They also taught me that the only repentance that was acceptable to God, was to
                            cease from sin : and that there could be no real repentance of sin without forsaking it.
                            This was now the work before me, and in faithfulness I should certainly find the blessing of
                            God. I soon began to see clearly the difference between traveling into sin, and traveling
                            out of it: as the one was directly contrary to the other. My wife also received 'the same
                            faith, to follow Christ in the regeneration. By the blessing of Divine Providence we were
                            favored with the best accommodations of any family which had embraced the gospel in the
                            neighborhood, to entertain our beloved Mother and the Elders, while they were visiting the
                            people in this vicinity. They accordingly came to our house several times, and tarried with
                            us, and received visitors. During this time they commenced their labors very eai-ly in the
                            morning, and often continued them till late in the evening. Many of those who accepted the
                            testimony were heard groaning under powerful convictions of sin, some speaking in an unknown
                            tongue, while others were filled with raptures of joy and thanksgiving to God for the great
                            manifestation of his love to them. I often visited Mother and the Elders, at New Lebanon and
                            Watervliet, in the state of New York, and in many other places. I always found them engaged
                            in the same kind of labors, pulling down the strong holds of sin, and building up Zion. They
                            were a prudent, temperate and charitable people : wise, chaste and discreet in their
                            language and deportment. I have not only seen the blessed fruits of righteousness which were
                            in their own lives, but I have received the same from them, into my own soul. In the
                            uprightness and sincerity of my heart, and in obedience to the testimony of the gospel which
                            I received from them, I have been saved from the power of sin, and loosed from the bands of
                            death, and have found a daily increasing victory over a sinful nature, which has afforded me
                            peace and justification and given full releasement and freedom to my soul, from the time of
                            my confessing my sins to this day. It is not, therefore, a mere profession which I have
                            found, but a substantial and permanent salvation. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge not" TEIform="index"/>JUDGE NOT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Theobald, Arthur" TEIform="persName"/>ARTHUR THEOBALD</byline><p TEIform="p">Judge not; the heart thou canst not see; And 'neath a stern outside may flow A crystal fount
                            of purity; Or there may lie, unknown to thee, A gem, with purest love aglow. The heart,
                            perchance to thee unknown, May have a fertile teeming soil, Wherein the seed of love, there
                            sown, 179 <pb n="180" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 180 SHAKER MANIFESTO. May live, and flourish, and when
                            grown, Repay the sower's care and toil. Judge not; the mind—the inner man, Cannot by fr^il
                            mortality Be seen. One Eye alone can scan That temple, and unfold that plan Which lasts
                            through all eternity. The thoughts which thrill that mystic chain Thou canstnot read. They
                            may be r,uYe As are the skies—as free from stain, Or aught that would this sacred fame
                            Defile, as are the heavens secure. Judge not; this life is but a span ; But let that
                            blessing from above O'ertiow the banks of creed and clan, And love, whilst thou hast time,
                            and can, Humanity; "for God is love." Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abolition of slavery" TEIform="index"/> [A LETTER FROM ELDER F. W. EVANS.] ABOLITION OF
                            SLAVERY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F.W." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Sir: Was it premature? So far as the South is concerned, are not they, in heart, as really
                            slave-holders to-day as they ever were ? The Israelitish law, under which, at each seventh
                            or Sabbatical year, all debts were cancelled and all slaves released, the masters and
                            mistresses were enjoined not to send them away empty, but to remember that they had been
                            worth more to their ownerthan hired servants. Therefore, they were to give them liberally of
                            the vat, the herd and the flock, the things that money alone represented, thus to part with
                            them in friendship, as some of the Cuban slaveholders are doing by releasing three hundred
                            and seven hundred at a time, and as England did with the West Indies and Russia with her
                            millions, a free will offering of enlightened conscience, quickened by convictions of the
                            wrong they have done to their own flesh and blood, to their own Hebrew brethren. For be it
                            remembered that the Jewish brotherhood did not extend beyond their own nationality. Gentiles
                            might be held as slaves, and usury be taken of them. Something of this distinction may be
                            observed at the South. The slave must be black. Then it must be proved logically to the
                            southern intellect, that black people are not human beings, members of the southern-
                            nationality, or of the universal brotherhood of man, or born with the inalienable lights of
                            life, land and liberty. To condemn by organic law national or society wrong, is a great
                            gain, but after thus doing the will of God, we have need of patience to endure the time of
                            healing, when . the cause of the moral wounds, bruises and sores have been removed. The
                            North must be patient with the South. It had not progressed up to abolition ; hence the war,
                            and hence the antagonism to the North, and the persistent effort to continue slavery, in
                            substance, after the institution has ceased to have legal existence. When it was legal, the
                            moralists contended against it. Now that it is illegal the immoralists contend for it. When
                            nations are born in a day, the accouchment must be with prolonged national pain and agony.
                            The young life must be protected into manhood and womanhood by parental and filial
                            affection, care and solicitude on the part of nursing fathers and nursing mothers. To Aveave
                            a web of governmental union out of thirty-seven States is a work so great and grand that few
                            appreciate its significance, or measure its magnitude. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All religion is at a discount..." TEIform="index"/>All religion is at a discount...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">All religion is at a discount in the Spirit world that does not overcome selfishness.</p></div2><pb n="181" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Orville Dyer" TEIform="index"/>ORVILLE DYER</head><p TEIform="p">The subject of this sketch Avas a prominent member of the Society of Shakers at Enfield N. H.
                            His parents united with that religious order in 1813, bringing to the community their whole
                            family, five sons and one daughter. Orville was the fourth child and was then nine years
                            old. With this people lie was nurtured, and as he grew to an understanding and knowledge of
                            their religious principles he embraced them and with the society ever remained, becoming one
                            of its firmest pillars, occupying several responsible positions, and at the time of his
                            death was a member of the board of Trustees of that institution, having occupied the office
                            for nine years. For thirteen years he was associated with the Presiding Elder as an
                            assistant, and twenty eight years officiated as Presiding Elder of the Church Family. He was
                            a noble specimen of God's handiwork; possessed of strong mental powers, moderate in
                            judgment, but when formed, it was established as the hills ; no influence or bribe of friend
                            or foe could change him; when convinced of a truth he accepted it, and from it there was no
                            shadow of turning. He was perfectly honest in all the transactions of life. Every manifest
                            worthy principle he revered and no power could weaken or destroy his confidence in the
                            integrity of those who gave him the evidence of honesty. In giving judgment, you had his
                            genuine opinion; as he viewed a subject, so was that view expressed. No person could accuse
                            him of hypocrisy or duplicity in any shade; as was his profession, so was his life, an
                            honest, upright Christian, true to the name oi Shaker, from the days of his childhood, and
                            an honor to his sect. Although not favored with the advantages of education and culture as
                            is more universally bestowed today, it did not detract from his manliness or deprive him of
                            the attributes and graces of the gospel. He was therefore a plain "matter of fact" man, with
                            a spirit akin to angels. Though human and subject to human frailties, few men had less
                            faults. His life and character were eminently noble and exalted, which gave him power over
                            the arch enemy. To him death had no sting, neither has the grave a victory. Enfield, N. H.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines read at the funeral of Orville Dyer" TEIform="index"/>LINES READ AT THE FUNERAL OF
                            0RVILLE DYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Asenath" TEIform="persName"/> ASENATH RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> A sheaf well ripened now is gathered home, Into the heavenly garners of our God ; We dare
                            not say, the Reaper came too soon, Our loss we know, is his eternal good. For while we
                            sorrow at the stern decree, We realize this change is sure to all; And that there comes a
                            day when earthly things, Each one must leave, and heed the Angel's call. Our brother's life,
                            "well spent in all its years, Worn out with care^ serenely passed away ; Surely for such,
                            death has no gloomy fears, They find their treasure rich in endless day. That sweet
                            contentment only known to those, Who've been resigned the yoke of Christ to wear. , This was
                            his strife, from dawn of day till close. Though oft times heavy burdens were his share. To
                            the convictions of his early days, Thro' every phase of life he has been true; O ! be to
                            those kind guardians, glory, praise, Who lent a hand, to help him safely thro'. The conflict
                            o'er, life's battle bravely fought, He now receives the laurels he has won, And hears the
                            benedictions of our Lord, Well done beloved, to thy mansion come. Time, strength, and
                            talent, unto God he gave, When life was all before him fresh and fair; Though others
                            faltered, he was true and brave, Courage his watchword. Still to do and dare. With trust
                            unflinching in that arm of power, Whose love encompasses both sea and land, He was enabled
                            in the darkest hour The powers of evil firmly to withstand. A faithful Servant in the "House
                            of God," A Father kind and true has ever been, Who chose to walk the path that Jesus trod,
                            Renouncing self, the higher life to win. <pb n="182" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> Long will his memory live
                            within our hearts, As we go forth to duty, day by day, Nor from his precepts would we e'er
                            depart, However stern the conflict by the way. An active worker never found at ease, Filling
                            his life with consecrated toil; With doubts nor fears he made no compromise, Whatever
                            station he was called to fill, For many years a "Shepherd of the flock," Devoting all the
                            powers of his soul, To plant their feet upon the solid rock, Which will endure when ages
                            cease to roll. Not only those within our Zion home, Can testify to his parental care; But
                            many whom we fain would call our own In his aflection have a loving share. A tower of
                            strength, and blessing to the young, The anguish of his spirit who can tell, When those tor
                            whom he toiled and suffered long, In hours of trial by the wayside fell. His bright example
                            evermore shall be A light in darkness, on our homeward way; And tho' no more his earthly
                            form we see, We ask his blessing for us here today. Dear Father, may we feel that thou art
                            near, To bless and strengthen every striving soul, E'en as a guardian angel wilt thou be,
                            When earthly wisdom would our thoughts control. Ah! we shall miss thee, in the walks of
                            life, And miss thee, when we meet for prayer, and praise; For thou was't ever constant in
                            the strife, Of doing good in kindly, loving ways. And though the voice which vre've so often
                            heard, Speak words of cheer, is silenced now in death, We'll strive to follow Christ, the
                            Living Word, Like thee be true, unto the latent breath. We know kind heaven hath reserved
                            for thee, In realms of bliss, thy crown,—Eternal Life ! That "over there" thrice welcome
                            thou wilt be, To meet this treasure, gained thro' earthly strife. 0 blest abode ! The port
                            of heavenly rest, Where troubles vanish, and where joys increase; No longer by the cares of
                            earth oppressed, Lie still, brave heart, safe in the arms of peace. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great evil" TEIform="index"/>A GREAT EVIL</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">There is one great evil in this country which we think the pulpit and the press
                                    ought to denounce more frequently than they do—that is the habit of getting into
                                    debt and making no effort to pay. Can a man be a consistent Christian and not strive
                                    to pay all his debts ? Can a man be a Christian and not be honest ? Is a man who
                                    does not try to live within his means and pay his debts an honest man? If so, we do
                                    not understand the Bible. Should men who habitually disregard their financial
                                    obligations be allowed to remain in the church ? We think not, and think that a
                                    man's being a member of the church ought to be a letter of credit in any part of the
                                    globe where the Christian religion prevails. But it is not the case. Far from it;
                                    and there are even some ministers whose sermons do no good because they are preached
                                    by men who are not considered honest even by the men of the world. Whisky is
                                    pronounced the great evil of this country, and it is a great curse ; but we doubt
                                    whether it does more harm to the cause of the church than the lying and dishonesty
                                    of sober church-mem ¦ bers, whose promise to pay is not worth the paper it is
                                    written on. The church is not the place for fraud and dishonesty.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="183" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Concert of action" TEIform="index"/>CONCERT OF ACTION
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davis, D. Ambrose" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">BY D. AMBROSE DAVIS. Why stand we apart with our work in the
                                    vineyard, Since God's every child has its mission to fill? Oh, why not go forward
                                    like brothers and sisters, Forever united, in earnest good will? Are we not all in
                                    the hands of Jehovah, All the recipients of his divine care? Then why so ungrateful
                                    as not to be willing To let every soul have its God-given share ? Oh, if we look
                                    upward for wisdom and guidance, How quickly the angels respond to our call, Using
                                    forever, their utmost endeavor, To make us evangels of kindness to all. The trees of
                                    the forest have no altercation, But stand in their order as if they were one; Their
                                    roots and their branches make progress together, Until their great work of the
                                    temple is done. The sunshine, the rain, and the dew drops of morning, Are ever the
                                    same to the high and the low; For nature, we find, in her blessed bestowal, Is
                                    always impartial, wherever we go. The star gems that sparkle in beauty above us, So
                                    many and varied, all acting their part, Are seeming to ask us to be more fraternal,
                                    With shoulder to shoulder, and heart pulse to heart. For tho' in God's wisdom our
                                    missions are varied, Our hearts best emotions should still be the same; And favors,
                                    the kindest, from one to another, Should always be known as our purpose, our aim.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temperance: tobacco and strong drink" TEIform="index"/> TEMPERANCE, Tobacco and Strong Drink</head><p TEIform="p">Many persons use tobacco who do not u«e strong drink ; few use strong drink who do not use
                            tobacco first. These two poisons are peculiarly fitted for close companionship. Alcohol is a
                            stimulant, exciting and irritating; tobacco is a narcotic, benumbing, stupefying, and
                            depressing ; hence either of them, if used, prepares the way for the other. When a man is
                            wearied and exhausted, a glass of liquor excites and exhilarates him ; when he is excited
                            and worried, a few whiffs from a pipe may make him calm as a summer evening. When he has
                            stupefied himself day after day with the benumbing narcotic, he then excites himself with
                            the irritating stimulant. The poisons work together like the halves of a pair of
                            shears—alcohol exciting, tobacco soothing, and both killing! When a man is dull and heavy
                            from the use of tobacco he drinks until he is excited and stimulated, then he smokes his
                            pipe until he is calm and quiet, and then drinks again to wake himself up. So the two
                            poisons work together, like the upper and nether millstones ; and between them both the man
                            gets ground up. Every time he uses tobacco he feels the need of a stimulant; every time he
                            drinks strong drink he cultivates the desire for a narcotic. Such habits, like hounds, hunt
                            in pairs. When one vulture has fastened his claws in a victim others are always at hand to
                            assist in destroying him. So wherever one of these vices may beset a thoughtless mortal the
                            other one is usually not far away to assist in dragging him down to the pit.—Christian</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life" TEIform="index"/> LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">I would not be a blithsome leaf, While I have feet and hands ; By wind and wave so tossed
                            adrift That life hath no commands. I would not be an idle spell, And know no journey home,
                            To do, to be, for good or well By which I could be known. Life, what is life? what doth it
                            mean But action, work and thought? Not merely breath, or life to seem, With no attendance
                            wrought. Then up, my heart, my loins agirt With valor, kin to steel, To do the little in thy
                            work Which doth thy life reveal. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="184" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publication" TEIform="index"/>Office of Publication
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Office of Publication. The "Shaker Manifesto" is published at Shaker Village, Mm*. Co., N. H.
                            Ail business matters connected with the financial department of the paper will be directed
                            to the Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. All other communications may be
                            addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid, .(50
                            six months, " .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copyTo avoid mistakes, those who
                            send money, should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. TO One inch, one
                            insertion " " three " " il six " " " twelve " " column ------: ----- each 1.00 .75, .65 .50
                            fi.00 Larger spaces, rates in same proportion. </p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is really refreshing to learn that even in this worldly-wise-christian age, a body of
                            moral teachers have arisen who can kindly and fearlessly publish God's laws in regard to the
                            body. There lias been no end to the sermonizing about the soul; to the advancement of a
                            speculative theology which has resulted in analmost entire neglect of that sacred duty which
                            takes cognizance of the physical life. The Mosaic code, notwithstanding the mistakes of the
                            author, taught men that God cared for the body, for its food, its clothing, aud for the
                            rules of chastity by which it should be governed. An infliction of severe penalties followed
                            every deviation from the letter of this law. It seems unfortunate that siich excellent, God
                            given regulations should not have been more abiding but on the introduction of asceticism
                            among the early Christians they very singularly held that the body was the great obstacle in
                            the way of spiritual progress. It must be starved into subjection, flaggellated as a
                            mortification for its sins, and then subjected to all the uncleanness of their surroundings.
                            This slight estimation of the body still clings more or less tenaciously, in its varied
                            degrees, to the Christian as well as unchristian races. A. great many benevolent societies
                            have been formed, with able and earnest workers, looking to the care and protection of the
                            feeble and fallen, but a society for the advancement of a moral education which calls in
                            question the deflections of adults as well as of children, is one of the new things under
                            the sun. To become better acquainted with this interesting subject, consult the pages of
                            "The Alpha," Edited by Dr. Caroline B. Winslow, Washington, D.C. We shall watch with
                            interest every phase of progress in this new order, believing that the spirit of God will
                            abundantly reward them in all their labors. At Mount Lebanon we observed that the pupils
                            used for readers, some papers that were published in the interest of the schools. We thought
                            it to be an excellent plan as it serves to awaken an enquiry on subjects that are fresh, and
                            to create an intelligence that the old system A.:E&gt; VE! lEtT I S:E5 3EVS - <pb n="185" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 185 has failed to do. A knowledge of the general
                            affairs of life, as pertaining to the house, or farm or workshop is far more preferable than
                            a class of old stories, even though they may be bound in a large and expensive book. </p><p TEIform="p"> Alfred, Me. From the Annual report of the Sup. Sch. Com. of the town of Alfred Me., for the
                            year ending March 1882, we take the following:— District No. 6. John B. Vance, Agent. The
                            closing examination of the winter term of '81 which took place after the annual report of
                            last year was made, maintained the excellent reputation of this school. The recitation of
                            the younger scholars in the multiplication table was remarkably good, and some matters of
                            oral instruction were highly creditable. We wish all our schools could reach the high rank
                            taken by this in mental arithmetic. The class in history made sound and commendable progress
                            and we are glad that this useful branch has now its place as a fixed study for this school. </p><p TEIform="p"> Summer Term.—Fannie C. Casey,— Teacher. Commenced May '61, closed July 8. Length of school,
                            6 weeks, five days. Whole number of scholars, 14. Average attendance, 14. Wages of teacher,
                            including board, $4.50. Though the term taught by Fannie Casey was short, we are only doing
                            justice to the school a:~d teacher in giving it a very favorable report. The reading was
                            very good, the Arithmetic both written and mental, was remarkably well done, and the
                            examination in Geography was thorough and admirably sustained,—comparing the number of
                            questions well answered with the whole number asked, this was one of the smoothest and most
                            successful examinations of the year. The modest teacher certainly has made a good beginning
                            in the school room work. </p><p TEIform="p"> Winter Term,—John B. Vance, teacher. Commenced Nov. 15, 1881, closed Feb. 17, 1882. Length
                            of school 13 weeks. Number of scholars, 20. Average, 20. Wages of teacher, including board,
                            $42.00 per, month. This term was taught by the same teacher as the winter previous, and with
                            like success. </p><p TEIform="p"> West Gloucester, Me. Report of School in District No. 9, for the year ending March 1, 1882.
                            Summer Term taughtJbyAda S. Cummings. Number of weeks 12. Number of pupils 15. Average
                            attendance 14. Wages of teacher per week exclusive of board $5.00. Average cost of pupils
                            per term, $4.28. The School was reported a success in every point of view. </p><p TEIform="p"> Winter Term. taught by Ada S. Cummings. Number of weeks 14. Number of pupils 17. Average
                            attendance 16. Wages per week exclusive of board $4.00. Average cost of pupil per term,
                            $5.25. This School was uncommonly successful. The ability of the Teacher was manifest in the
                            good order maintained. The evident love of her work and desire to benefit the children, who
                            were apt in learning and made good progress in their <pb n="186" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/></p><p TEIform="p"> School in District No. 12 in Poland was taught by Sophia F. Mace. Length of School in both
                            Summer and Winter terms 20 weeks. Number of pupils 7 in constant attendance. The
                            S.S.Committee say, "as is the Teacher so is the School." Of the ability and qualification of
                            the teacher it is only necessary to say that she has taught nearly forty terms and in places
                            where she has lived, has been the Principal in High Schools where there were sixty pupils,
                            and always with eminent success. District No. 12 is legally annexed to District No. 9 in New
                            Gloucester, but the distance is so great for small pupils to travel, it is deemed judicious,
                            to have an extra school. Otis Sawyer, Agent.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To be a man's own fool is bad enough..." TEIform="index"/>To be a man's own fool is bad enough...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To be a man's own fool is bad enough, but the vain man is everybody's.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Penn, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Penn</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Briggs, Dear Sir;—I am still inclined to..." TEIform="index"/>Mr. Briggs, Dear Sir;—I am still inclined to...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Boston, May 20, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Boston, May, 20. 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">Mr. Briggs, Dear Sir;—I am still inclined to believe I would like to join your Society. I
                                suppose by this time you begin to think that I am somewhat of a trifler. But then I
                                don't believe in jumping into anything regardless of thought. Now what I want to know is
                                if you desire to have me come among you, and if you do will you allow three hours a day
                                for practice on the Violin? And another thing if I were to have my own way in selecting
                                work I would rather teach the Violin than anything else, because I could.become more
                                profitable to you for that purpose. So I will close hoping to hear from you again,— I
                                remain, Yours truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="G." TEIform="persName"/>G.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Young Friend;—Your letter of the 20th, inst is..." TEIform="index"/>My Dear Young Friend;—Your letter of the 20th, inst is...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Shaker Village, June 1882" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, June, 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Young Friend;—Your letter of the 20th, inst is received. You ask if we desire
                                you to come and live with us. We do not desire you to live with us unless you consider
                                it to he for your best interest to do so. To be frank with you—we are not particularly
                                pleased with your letter, nor with your aast trifling. If you really wish to live a pure
                                and noble ife, and have the ability to steady yourself down to business habits, we are
                                still willing ;o give you a fair trial upon the conditions named in our past
                                correspondence. You can visit us, and after becoming acquainted, nake your own decision.
                                You must divest yourself of the erroneous dea that we are so anxious for your presence
                                hat our customs will be modified to suit your ^articular taste. Nor can you be too nice
                                about your employment, as we all work for a iving, and whoever is too good to work is
                                unsuited for our Society. We do not object o your violin if it does not interfere with
                                duies assigned you,—but as mere teacher of he Violin we have no use for you. You will
                                find us to be really kind friends, and it shall je our pleasure to use every reasonable
                                effort ,o make your home with us agreeable and lappy; but you will find very little
                                sentimenstudies. Their success in compositioi was highly commended considering the age
                                of the pupils. The S.S.Committee reported it a model school for promptnes in reciting
                                their lessons, and responding to the requirements of the teacher. Something may be said
                                of the Schoo building which is one of the best ii town, built in 1879. Two years
                                previous, the town abolished the old Schoo District System, purchased of the Districts
                                all the school houses and schoo property, and gave the entire control o' the schools
                                into the hands of the S. Schoo Committee or Supervisors, and in a very liberal manner
                                commenced repairs oi School Houses or built new ones. Ours is well adapted to the
                                purpose, well ventilated by the most approved method and furnished with adjustable
                                single desks, Black-boards, Maps, etc. <pb n="187" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 187 tal
                                nonsense here, and we shall not hesitate to tell you just what we think. Your
                                employment, this Summer, will most probably be some light out of door work, perhaps
                                gardening. As ours is a family relation on a liberal plan in which every member is
                                interested to do whatever he can be most useful in for the time being, our occupation is
                                necessarily varied, and none of us can tell what our employment may be a month or a year
                                hence. If you are sincerely in earnest, and have a definite idea of what you want, you
                                had better come and see us. Considerately discuss this matter with yourself, and visit
                                us or decisively reply at once, as we wish no more trifling. Your friend, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="index"/>N. A. Briggs</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dyer, Orville" TEIform="index"/>Orville Dyer</head><p TEIform="p">, at Enfield, N. H. June 16. Age, 78 years. (See page 181.)</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whitcher, Tryphena C." TEIform="index"/>Tryphena C. Whitcher,</head><p TEIform="p">at Canterbury, N. H. June 30. Age, 75 years, 3 months and 3 days. </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brackett, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Elder Joseph Brackett</head><p TEIform="p"> at New Gloucester, July i. Age, 85 yrs. 1 mo. and 28 days.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My little bed: written with, and for the little girls" TEIform="index"/>MY LITTLE BED.
                                Written with, and for the, little girls</head><p TEIform="p">Written with, and for the, little girls. LUCY S. BOWK US. (Continued from last number.)
                                My blankets come from the meadows green. Where the blue-eyed grasses blow, And daises
                                bloom, and hedges shade, And the dancing waters flow. It may seem strange but 'tis even
                                true, As the lambs might all declare ; They live on the verdant sod, and thrive By the
                                shepherd's kindly care. And the fleece of wool that covers them, Protects when the sky
                                is cold; When the winds and show of the frosty days, Blow over the gentle fold. But as
                                soon as the ices melt away, And the balmy June appears ; With submissive will it is
                                sacrificed, To the workman's clipping shears. Then with spindles and loom, and warp and
                                woof, The blankets are quickly made. What would we do, but for sheep and lambs, Through
                                the chill of the mighty shade ! My pillow is made of the softest down, Though not from
                                the icy shores, Where the Eider-duck builds her distant nest, But from poultry round our
                                doors. The feathers feel good to the aching head; Or when sleep the eyelids close : And
                                my coverlet is as fresh and clean, As the whitest thing that grows. What a goodly thing
                                is my little bed; What a place for blessed dreams Of the far away hills, and meadow
                                lands, Where the sun in its brightness beams. My mind is filled with the thought each
                                day, Of the many who have no bed; Of how even the Saviour had naught on earth, Where
                                upon to lay his head. And at even-tide when I go to rest, I will offer this humble
                                prayer, That a thankful heart may be ever mine, For the blessings I daily share. Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A very smart boy returning from school..." TEIform="index"/> A very smart boy returning
                                from school</head><p TEIform="p"> attempted'to prove that two were equal to three. Pointing to a roasted chicken on the
                                table, he said. Is not that, one? Then pointing to another,— Is not that two,—and do not
                                one and two make three? Whereupon the father said, I will take one ; your mother may
                                take one and our boy can have the third for his dinner. </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not if it was my boy" TEIform="index"/> "NOT IF IT WAS MY EOT"</head><p TEIform="p"> Some years ago, the late Horace Mann, the eminent educator, delivered an address at the
                                opening Of some reformatory institute for boys, during which he remarked that if only
                                one boy was saved from ruin, it would pay for all the cost and labor of establishing
                                such an institution as that. After the exercises had 3D IE-A. T tl SSS. <pb n="188" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> ceased, in private conversation a gentlema rallied Mr. Mann on his
                                statement anc said to him,— "Did you not color that a little, when you said that all the
                                expense and labor would be repaid if it only saved one boy?" "Not if it was my boy," was
                                the solemn and convincing reply. Ah, there is a wonderful value about "my boy." ' Other
                                boys may be rude and rough; other boys may be reckless and wild; other boys may seem to
                                require more pains and labor than they will ever repay; other boys may be left to drift
                                uncared for to the ruin which is near at hand; but "my boy"—it were worth the toil of a
                                lifetime, and the lavish wealth of a world to save him from temporal and eternal ruin.
                                We would go the world round to save him from peril, and would bless every hand that was
                                stretched out to give help and welcome. And yet every poor, wandering outcast, homeless
                                man, is one whom some fond mother called "my boy." Shall we shrink from labor, shall we
                                hesitate at cost, when the work before us is the salvation of a soul? Not if it is "my
                                boy," nor if we have the love of Him who gave his life to save the lost.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Ex." TEIform="index"/>Ex.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="books" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Phrenological Journal; July; Pub. by Fowler &amp; Wells, 753 Broadway, N. Y.
                                Contents; Robert Browning, the eminent English Poet,—with Portrait. The
                                Transcendentalists of Brook Farm. PheniasL. Buell, Phrenologist and Editor, with
                                portrait. Scottish Shepherd Dogs. Illustrated, A Moral Mix. The work of Culture in the
                                face. Self Culture. Warm, vs Cold Bathing. Kitchen Leaflets. Notes in Science and
                                Agriculture. Editorial. Poetry, etc. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</head><p TEIform="p"> July; Pub. by M. L. Holbkook, 13 &amp; 15 Laight St., N. Y. Contents. How women may
                                become strong. A Vegetarian danger. Know Thyself. Objections to milk. Spread of
                                Consumption. Tobacco at West Point. Shop girls and their health. Foul Cisterns. House
                                Flies. Hair Brushes, etc. Terms, $1.00 per. year. Single copy, 10 cts. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="City and country" TEIform="index"/>City and Country</head><p TEIform="p"> The July number of this most excellent of Agricultural publications—having also as
                                salient features its literary department and its illustrations, has been received. It
                                con tains four fine illustrations this issue : "A California Threshing Outfit," "Falls
                                of the Yosemite," "Ornamental Flower Basket" and "Scene on Eondout Creek, State of New
                                York." In this number an interesting serial "Honor's Debt," is begun, written by the
                                talented Abbie C. M'Keever. Editorially, among other trite matter, it gives an able
                                article on "Strikes and Trades Unions" and an excellent eulogy of the patriot Garibaldi.
                                Subscription price, $1.00 per yearwith premium. WillC. Turner, Editor. A. W. Lincoln,
                                Associate. City and Country Co., Publisiiers, Columbus, Ohio. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly</head><p TEIform="p"> July. Contents; The crude cake, by R. S. McArthur, D.D. The Criminality of Neutrality by
                                J. H. Rylance, D.D. Resurrection of Christ, by Rev. J. W. (Joodlin; Total Abstinence by
                                Rev. J. Cook; Cloaks of sin, by Rev. W. F. Crafts; The Minister sent by Rev. John McRay;
                                Power of atonement by Rev. John Hemphill; Joy of Easter by Canon Liddon; The Singing
                                Pilgrim, by Rev. C. II. Spurgeon; Biblical Inspiration by Rev. James Hunter; Character
                                by R.S. Storrs, D.D. Prayers before Sermon; Prayer Meeting Service; Homiletic Studies in
                                the book of Hebrews; Light on important texts; Eminent Preachers; Misquoted Scriptures;
                                SermonicCriticism; Queries and Answers, etc. Price $2.50 per year. Single number 25
                                cents. Funk &amp; Wacjnalls, 10 &amp; 12 Dey St.N. Y.. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To prepare straw for making bonnets and other articles" TEIform="index"/>To Prepare Straw
                                for making Bonnets and other Articles</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/> E. A. S.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The time for gathering the straw is when the grain commences to ripen or turn yellow.
                                Gather in the field, the grain standing; as the best straws, those freest from mildew,
                                can be more easily selected. Cut just above the upper joint on the stalk for bonnets,
                                the next two are shorter and may be used for table mats and small fancy articles. It is
                                preferable to gather the straw a little too young, than too old. Have ready, water
                                boiling hot in which to scald the straw. When scalded sufficiently, the joints will make
                                a snapping sound. The next process is to whiten it in the sun ; three days are usually a
                                sufficient length of time. Do not leave it out over night after the first. Unsheathe it
                                the second day. Bleach it in the same manner that woolens are bleached, repeating- the
                                burning of the brimstone two or three times. Rye and oats produce the best straw of any
                                f the grains. Rye straw is the strongest; at straw the whitest. Brimstone causes steel
                                to rust; palm-leaf nd straw being bleached with this, should not <pb n="189" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/>be cut with scissors or knives that are good, as it ruins them. It is a good idea to
                                varnish wire that is used in making bonnets, to prevent rusting. E A.S.</p><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value of borax" TEIform="index"/>Value of Borax.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Value of Borax. It is better than soap in cleansing the hands ; and it
                                        softens the skin. For washing the hair, cleansing brushes and combs, in
                                        extracting dirt from clothes without rubbing, in driving away ants and roaches,
                                        it is the housekeeper's friend.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Filling for woodwork" TEIform="index"/>Filling for Woodwork.</head><p TEIform="p"> Two thirds bolted whiting, one third plaster paris, mixed with one fourth boiled linseed
                                oil, one fourth colorless japan, two fourths turpentine.—Enfield, Ct. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker brown bread" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Brown Bread.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mix together 2 qts. Indian meal, 1 qt. rye meal, and 1 pt. canaille (coarse flour.) Take
                                1 pt. of this mixed meal, add water and scald it thoroughly, and when cool, add a
                                teaspoonful of stock yeast and let stand to rise. To the remainder of the meal, add 3
                                qts. sweet milk, scalding hot. Mix thoroughly with pudding stick, and when cooled to
                                lukewarm, add the yeasted portion. Put in the oven immediately, and bake with a steady
                                heat for seven or eight hours. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glycerine for burns" TEIform="index"/>Glycerine for Burns.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Glycerine for Burns. Glycerine as an application to burns is recommended by
                                        a writer. Through the explosion of a spirit lamp the greater part of his face
                                        had been covered with rather deep burns, which healed in a week by the immediate
                                        and oft-repeated application of glycerine, without producing blisters or
                                        festering, or leaving any scar. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To keep lemons" TEIform="index"/>To Keep Lemons.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To Keep Lemons. Take good lemons, put them into an earthen vessel and pour on
                                        new butter-milk, covering well; set in a cool place, changing the buttermilk
                                        occasionally. We have found this a very excellent way for keeping them fresh. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato catchup" TEIform="index"/>Tomato Catchup.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Tomato Catchup. Cut tomatoes in pieces, and between every layer sprinkle a
                                        thin layer of salt; let them stand a few hours, then add a little horseradish,
                                        garlic, pepper, and mace. Boil well and strain; then bottle, cork, and seal for
                                        use. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When any person gets a piece or pieces of glass in the foot..." TEIform="index"/>
                                When any person gets a piece or pieces of glass in the foot...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> When any person gets a piece or pieces of glass in the foot, hand or any part of the
                                flesh, extract it at once by excision; then hold the part in water as warm as can be
                                borne, five or six days, night and day consecutively. This will so far soften all the
                                muscular fibres that they will easily part with every atom of the glass, and all the
                                virus also, leaving the wound perfectly clean and healthy.— Union Village, Ohio. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value of ammonia" TEIform="index"/>Value of Ammonia.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Value of Ammonia—Ammonia will remove finger-marks from paint, where there
                                        would otherwise have to be a good deal of scrubbing with soap, which takes the
                                        paint off too. Ammonia is useful to wash all the brushes that are used in a
                                        household Nothing will cleanse greasy sinks, pans, or scrubbing-brushes so well.
                                        A tea-spoonful in aba* sin of water will make hair-brushes beautifully white.
                                        Take care not to let the back of brushes dip below the surface—rinse them with
                                        clear, warm water, and put them in a sunny window to dry. A small bottle of
                                        ammonia is also useful for the wardrobe. Wet a little sponge with it, and you
                                        can take out most any spot. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Domestic receipts" TEIform="index"/>Domestic Receipts.</head><p TEIform="p"> If your coal fire is low, throw on a tablespoonful of salt and it will help it very
                                much. In icing cakes, dip the knife frequently into cold water. In boiling meat for
                                soup, use cold water to extract the juices. If the meat is wanted for itself alone,
                                plunge in boiling water at once. You can get a bottle or barrel of oil off any carpet or
                                woolen stuff by applying dry buckwheat plentifully and faithfully. Never put water to
                                such a grease spot, or liquid of any kind__End </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best duster with which to clean carved furniture is..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The best duster with which to clean carved furniture is...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The best duster with which to clean carved furniture is a new paint brush; you can
                                remove absolutely all the dust with it. Try it. <pb n="190" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></p></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exaltation of Zion" TEIform="index"/>EXALTATION OF ZION.</head><p TEIform="p">Thou art exalted above all the hills That surround thee, O Zion; Blessed be thy name, thy
                            name forever; Blessed be thy name, thy name forever; Blessed, blessed, blessed be thy name,
                            thy name forever. For in thee is established the kingdom of Christ, Wherein dwelleth<pb n="191" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> righteousness and peace. The wanderer here may find a home, The
                            sin-sick soul a healing balm. Nothing can destroy or harm In all God's holy mountain.
                            Beautiful for habitation is mount Zion. Beautiful, beautiful for habitation, for habitation
                            is mount Zion, is mount Zion. Beautiful for habitation is mount Zion. </p></div2><pb n="192" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden </head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hens" TEIform="index"/>Hens.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Hens. If you have to shut your hens up to keep them out of the newly made
                                        garden do not forget to throw them an occasional sod so that they may scratch
                                        and peck it. They will ever tear out the young grass The exercise does them
                                        good. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boiled potatoes are said to be a cure for diarrhoea..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Boiled potatoes are said to be a cure for diarrhoea...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Boiled potatoes are said to be a cure for diarrhoea in cattle. Feed warm and
                                        give as much as the cattle will eat. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experiments of a famous Swedish chemist..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The experiments of a famous Swedish chemist...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The experiments of a famous Swedish chemist, prolonged over two years,
                                        making it definitely certain that separating cream by the centrifugal secures 10
                                        per cent, more of it than any other process, while if the cream is at once
                                        churned what chemists and other experimenters pronounce the best lasting and
                                        best keeping butter is obtained ; the refuse— the skimmed milk and buttermilk,
                                        are sweet, that is, in their most valuable condition—and the milk has been in
                                        the course of a few hours turned into money. This appears to be the ultimate
                                        perfection of scientific butter-making. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forest leaves should be collected and used as bedding in the stables" TEIform="index"/>
                                Forest leaves should be collected and used as bedding in the stables
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Forest leaves should be collected and used as bedding in the stables. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Decayed grain of any kind is highly injurious to stock..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Decayed grain of any kind is highly injurious to stock...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Decayed grain of any kind is highly injurious to stock, often producing
                                        paralysis and death. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value of refuse" TEIform="index"/>Value of Refuse.</head><p TEIform="p"> The value of the refuse of the starch and glucose factories for feeding cows is about
                                half that of corn-meal when it is dry; but as it contains a large portion of water—90
                                per cent.—the estimated value is only 15 cents per 100 pounds. When it has been partly
                                dried its value is proportionately increased. The starch has been nearly nil taken out
                                of the corn-meal and the gluten left. It is an excellent food for producing milk on
                                account of the albumen it contains, and which is similar in composition to the casein of
                                milk, or rather that one is changeable into the other in the animal system. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grape-vines ought, as a rule, to be pruned in the fall..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Grape-vines ought, as a rule, to be pruned in the fall...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Grape-vines ought, as a rule, to be pruned in the fall. If the work is
                                        deferred until spring, the hurry of the work may cause it to be put off too
                                        late. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to milk" TEIform="index"/>How to Milk.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> In milking, do not seize the teat between the thumb and forefinger, and drag
                                        down until the end slips from the grasp of the digits. Do not grasp with the
                                        hand, pressing the nails into the teat, with a squeeze and a pull. Grasp the
                                        teat with the thumb partly upward, and the fingers in their natural position
                                        when closed, next the udder, and closing the fingers in succession, force the
                                        milk downward, with a gentle pull on the udder. So proceed alternately with each
                                        hand, going further and further up into the udder as the flow ceases, until you
                                        have all the milk drawn. Thus you may milk easily for yourself and the cow. In
                                        fact, the cow soon comes to like the manipulation. If a few simple rules founded
                                        upon common sense were observed in milking, instead of kicking cows and holding
                                        up the milk, we should find our cows gentle to handle, and much vexation would
                                        be spared to the milkers. It should however, be remembered that, in milking
                                        cows, gentleness is a cardinal virtue. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Exchange" TEIform="index"/>Ex. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sheep are becoming popular..." TEIform="index"/>Sheep are becoming popular...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Sheep are becoming popular with the masses of Western Farmers, who seek to
                                        increase their profits by stock raising and at the same time improve their soil,
                                        raise more grass, have less labor, and make more money. A pound of mutton can be
                                        raised as cheap as a pound of beef or pork, and is worth equally as much in
                                        market, and the wool is extra profit. Use thoroughbred males of any of the
                                        popular breeds, and in a few years your sheep will be a source of pride as well
                                        as of profit.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Farming world" TEIform="index"/>Farming World. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seeding a swamp meadow" TEIform="index"/>Seeding a Swamp Meadow
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Seeding a Swamp Meadow. J.K., Carmel N. Y. : Corn is an excellent preparatory
                                        crop to seeding a newly reclaimed swamp meadow to grass. The cultivation of the
                                        corn will clean the ground and rot the sod. When the corn is cultivated the last
                                        time the grass seed may be sown on the fresh mellow soil and will soon sink into
                                        it and be covered. But the corn should be planted flat and cultivated without
                                        any hilling up. The seed to be chosen should be six pounds of red top, twelve
                                        pounds of fowl meadow grass, and six pounds of yellow or tall oat grass.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune and farmer" TEIform="index"/> Tribune Farmer.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>