<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1103" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18810301" TEIform="date">March 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49- 72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>MARCH, 1881. MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, H. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        CANTERBURY, N. H. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:'1 "Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XI. No. 3. 60 Cents Per
                        Annum. The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="49" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revelation" TEIform="index"/>REVELATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Tie but the morning twilight now, The ancient shadows fainter grow, The light that rims yon
                            summit's brow Will flood the soundless depths below. The dawn, advancing in its might,
                            Reflects the work of which we dream ; We watch the sun's advancing light, Along the mountain
                            flash and gleam, Where lightning writes upon the cloud, And thunder tones proclaim its doom.
                            Though still doth ignorance enshroud And rob the earth of joy and bloom, We see the
                            hilltop's gilded crown, While cliffs and woods are veiled in mists The fertile plain, the
                            busy town, Give little sign that they exist. We see the gushing fountain rise, While sweeps
                            the rayless tide along ; We hear the lark that thrills the skies, 'Ere other warblers wake
                            to song. The glory falling from above, Upo,n the noble of our rdce ; The gift of God's
                            o'erflowing love, The inspiration of His grace ; These are the source of each Reform That
                            comes to dissipate the night; That comes to vivify and warm, To bring the truth and spread
                            the light. Then speak, O worker, speak aloud! Let thunder-bolts of thought be hurled, And
                            they will break the night-mare cloud That long has settled on the world. Flow out, O
                            fountain heart, and bring A blessing to the low and poor ; Thou soul of inspiration, sing
                            The gladness of the just and pure, Till every outpost, wall and dome, That sheltered wrong
                            shall sink from sight And earth is one vast happy home, Where God has spread His perfect
                            light. 0 then will Revelation glow Upon our hearts, without a shade, And, by the things
                            external, show The things that are eternal made. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Means and ends" TEIform="index"/>MEANS AND ENDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> The ends proposed as " the uitimates of a believer's life are : Salvation, contentment,
                            eternal peace. But what is salvation ? For, since the bottom of what has been the
                            theological hell for ages has been knocked out, in these latter times, and since the popular
                            theological heaven depended so very much for its existence on the exploded hell, they are in
                            danger of going over the dam together ; so also the mythical salvation predicated upon those
                            misapprehensions of Heaven and Hell vanishes with them, being relegated to the limbo of the
                            worn-out theological machinery of the past. What believers in Christ's second as well as his
                            first appearing understand by salvation is a perfect, practical triumph over all lower
                            lusts, appetites and proclivities, and a consequent immunity and relief from the ruin and
                            sorrow of their <pb n="50" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. indulgence. Invulnerable peace
                            is the necessary result of such triumph ; and complete at-onement with God is to be
                            possessed by sincere confession and repentance of all known sin and an after-perseverance in
                            righteousness in thought, word and deed. 0, if persons struggling amid the " burning glooms
                            " and deadly sorrows of an incipient experience of a Shaker life, while the lower^ baser
                            instincts of rudimental man are clamoring for gratification, could only see the bright
                            glory, the calm serenity, the sublime exultation, the tempered but permanent joy and
                            tranquil contentment, silently evolving from these holy, solemn experiences, what immense
                            energy and courage would be imparted by the beatific vision ! But, alas, this seems
                            generally to be incompatible with those conditions, or excluded therefrom, from some
                            inscrutable element in the Divine scheme of evolution and elevation to higher and holier
                            planes of existence ; and we must, for some cause, learn to bear these scenes patiently and
                            with what cheerfulness we can. It is a consoling truth, however, that although no chastening
                            for " the present'seemeth to be joyous but grievous, nevertheless, afterward it yieldeth the
                            peacea. ble fruit of righteousness unto them which are exercised thereby." Heb, 12 ch., 11
                            v. It is, furthermore, comforting to remember that this was written for our encouragement by
                            one who had passed through the purifying^cenes of spiritual evolution and had come into
                            permanent possession of their blessed fruitions. So calm, comfortable and self-poised are
                            those who have "patiently traveled quite through this low ground " of self-sacrifice, that
                            there is constantly eman. ating from them a spiritual aura which many times is sufficient to
                            raise others who are wading in deep sorrows completely above them all, and, for the time
                            being, surround them with a safe, holy joy and releasement, even a foretaste of the eternal
                            peace-victory and triumph which awaits them. This is One of the purest joys of the spiritual
                            harvest ; this blessed power and privilege of relieving and even chasing away at times the
                            deadly sorrows and fierce temptations of our dear companions who are " lashing through their
                            scenes of trouble." An individual instance of this occurs to my memory at this time. A
                            person for whom I felt a deep spiritual interest sent for me to visit him. I went, and being
                            one whom I had in spiritual charge, he " communed with me of all that was in his heart."
                            When he finished I said to him : '' You will not fail; you will triumph ; you are too
                            sincere to fail ; and now, you can, for the present; feel entirely released from these
                            severe struggles." Being called elsewhere, I did not see him for three or four days. Upon
                            inquiring of him at the end of that time how he was getting along, he said: " After you came
                            at my request, and talked with me a little, I was entirely and completely released and have
                            not felt the least bit of those terrible buffetings since." Now, I am some ashamed and
                            mortified to be obliged to introduce the objectionable pronoun into this little episode, but
                            if it will do any person any good, I can stand it ; for what I like to read is not so much
                            theological speculations and logically wire-drawn theories, as little interesting details of
                            actual experience, and I suppose many of the readers of the invaluable S. M. are of the same
                            taste and way of thinking. When one is pretty well along in gospel experience and most of
                            his or her hardest battles and severest sacrifices have been so thoroughly gone through with
                            that they will stay gone through with, then " the day-spring from on high" begins to
                            permanently pervade and abide with that soul, and " the well of water springing up into
                            everlasting life" is no longer a sweet anticipation of hope to be earnestly longed after, "
                            as the poor, weary servant desireth the shadow," but is thenceforward a sublime and
                            unspeakably glorious reality. The sun of perpetual peace and serenity beams from his
                            spiritual sky, and the illuminations and inspirations from his dear companions and still
                            more liis illustrious predecessors, reflect their bright love and consolation upon him
                            forever. He needs not wait for another world to enter upon these eternal joys and fruitions,
                            for this happy estate is attainable here. In fact, this is "the world to come" which Jesus
                            spoke of, and the " eternal life " he referred to. If a man is able to take pleasure in his
                                <pb n="51" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 51 duties of whatever character, with the
                            music of heaven in his soul, and surrounded by good and faithful companions between whom and
                            himself the love of God is always flowing ; if he sits down by his fireside in the evening
                            and engages in conversation, reading, singing, or silent meditation, with no painful memory
                            of sin troubling his conscience, and no degrading impulse goading him into desperation and
                            guilt and ruin ; if he can and does feel the love of God toward all humanity, whether saints
                            or sinners, and a tender and Divine sympathy for all who are suffering, and a willingness
                            and a joy in relieving them so far as he can ; we say in earnest : " If this will not
                            Heaven's true happiness bring, It must be because there is no such thing." These, then, are
                            the ends proposed to be reached by believers, through the instrumentality of self-sacrifice
                            ; for, first, our own purity and elevation ; and, second, for the good and similar elevation
                            of our fellowbeings ; and even these sublime beatitudes are but the beginning of an eternal
                            scene and process of evolution, whose glory and goodness and happiness no mortal has ever
                            conceived. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monopoly" TEIform="index"/>MONOPOLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> The nineteenth century in which we live is marked for its scientific culture, brilliant
                            ideas, and intellectual attainments; but unless such, knowledge be utilized and f*educed to
                            practice, so as to benefit and bless humanity at large, it will be used as an engine of
                            power to oppress the poorer and less educated, and to bind heavy burdens upon them unjustly.
                            America, the land in which our lot is cast, is a broad, beautiful and goodly land ; and with
                            proper cultivation will yield a fullness of all that is needful to sustain life. Her rich
                            mines of gold, silver, iron and precious stone, under the direction of skilled labor, if
                            rightly used and not abused, may be made a great blessing ; but it is quite possible to turn
                            great blessings into dire curses. As we trace the planets in their courses, and note the
                            precision with which they move, and mark the seasons as they come and go, with so much
                            regularity, bringing their seed time and harvest, reason as best we may, we can arrive at
                            only one conclusion ; i. e., there is one source of knowledge and power ; a prescience and a
                            guiding, directing hand seen and felt in the vast universe. That all pervading Mind or
                            Being, we call God ! The Originator, Producer and Sustainer of all created things. And when
                            we contemplate the love, wisdom and goodness of G©d toward His creatures, we ask : What more
                            could have been done for His vineyard that He has not done ? He indeed planted noble vines,
                            and sowed goo.d seeds ; but an enemy through various instrumentalities has sown tares ; and
                            we find strange vines producing wild and sour grapes ; and degenerate plants in almost
                            endless variety and forms—which are as thorns and briers. If the earth and its products were
                            blighted because of man's disobedience to established law; why not by a return to those
                            broken laws find restoration from penalty inflicted, and call down especial blessing,
                            instead of continuing in sinful practices that " grace may abound "? In other words,
                            continue in wrong doing, in far reaching, and speculation that profit may abound, and
                            interest accrue to a few at the expense of the many who are rendered destitute, and are
                            realy enslaved thereby. Does a good and righteous God show particular favor to a few,
                            because of intellectual endowment, or accumulated wealth? "The earth is the Lord's and the
                            fullness thereof." His love for His creatures is without partiality ; in Him there is not a
                            shadow of turning from justice and equity! Man with perverted desires and appetites is
                            unjust and and unequal, and is ruled by the spirit of monopoly, which manifests itself in
                            individual claims to thousands of acres of land more than is needful to supply his real
                            wants—and gold and silver in proportion. If the present age is marked for its scientific
                            research, and analytic investigation— <pb n="52" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. resulting
                            in skilled improvement in laborsaving machinery, in nearly every department of life—it is
                            also marked for its ingenious machinations in amalgamating, and mixing deleterious
                            substances with almost every thing that pertains to food or clothing ; and in preparing
                            articles for market in the most artistic and guileful manner, and then stamping them "
                            warranted.'' If honesty instead of craft and cunning device ruled, the word spurious would
                            in many cases be placed under the word " warranted." Thus we are forced to the conclusion,
                            that greed and monopoly form a ground work of untold evils in society. The selfish
                            monopolizing spirit of the present age is the parent of many other existing evils, which may
                            legitimately be traced to it, as the producing cause. Capitalists have power to grind the
                            faces of the poor ; and as a general rule, they do not fail to exercise that power. Too
                            often men are measured by their wealth, instead of moral worth and integrity; and money is
                            the charger upon which they ride into office, professedly to fill important positions in
                            National Councils, for which they are not fitted, nor capacitated. Will this state of things
                            always exist ? That is a question for the future to decide. We look forward with inspired
                            hope, that truth in its onward march will banish error, and that increasing light, through
                            the medium of reason and conscience united, will banish ignorance and darkness, so that
                            inequality and injustice will flee the land, which should afford shelter and clothing, not
                            only to the home born, but to the oppressed of all nations. May it be the prayer of all
                            lovers of humanity, that the hills of aristocracy and pride may be laid low, and the valleys
                            be lifted up, so that all may meet, the rich and the poor, on one common plane of
                            brotherhood, and that justice and equal rights may be the inheritance of all. A man cannot
                            live upon material bread alone—however bountiful his supplies, without spiritual food to
                            supply the soul cravings—neither can he live upon acquired knowledge, and dwell in the realm
                            of ideality, without the real and practical, pertaining to the present life, and that which
                            is to come. As well undertake to live upon flowers, which please the senses and fill the air
                            with rich perfume for a moment. Spring and blossom time are always welcome in their season,
                            after a cold and ice bound winter ; but doubly welcome, because it presages what we hope
                            will be a bountiful harvest. One season foreshadows another. What is the shadow to the
                            substance ? All things in their season. Honest labor should be exalted. Monopoly, however
                            skillfully we may weave a garment to cover its deformity, is not worthy to be tolerated by a
                            free Republic or an honest, j ust, and God-fearing people.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discord—concord: no. 1" TEIform="index"/>DISCORD-CONCORD: No. I</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> These two words, placed in contrast with each other, fitly represent the primitive condition
                            of mankind, as proved by its history, and that which is yet to be, as indicated by
                            aspiration and the spirit of prophecy. "First, the sensual, afterward, the spiritual." All
                            beings act in accordance with their several natures; the tiger must act out the tiger; even
                            when tamed by man and apparently gentle as the lamb, he cannot always be trusted ; " blood
                            will tell " Human beings, originally, are mere wild beasts in disposition. Thus the poet: "
                            Into a world of ruffians sent, I tread on hostile ground ; Wild human bears, on mischief
                            bent, And ravening wolves surround." It is not too much to say that, in ferocity and cruelty
                            they have far surpassed the most destructive wild beasts. In the earliest times they seemed
                            to have no object in view, in their contests with each other, but to gratify their passion
                            for rapine and slaughter. The greatest warrior ruled over the most widely extended realms.
                            His throne was surrounded by warriors like himself, and his power sustained by vast armies.
                            It has been so quite up to the present age. Those called pagan nations have not alone been
                            involved in wars; those professing to have a revelation from 52 <pb n="53" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 53 Heaven urging them on to better things have been equally at fault. By
                            conquest and slaughter ancient Rome enlarged her dominions. Since her fall, those who were
                            instrumental in her overthrow have been just as busy in warring upon each othor. Where,
                            then, it may be asked, are the evidences of the concord that is to be, if such has been the
                            condition of mankind all along ? Progress in the best and most enduring things is slow.
                            Ephemeral things are of rapid growth and of equally rapid decay. To truth and right and
                            goodness belong the eternal years of God. As far back as the records of history carry us the
                            manifestations of Divine Love have been apparent to some minds, at least. As the ages have
                            passed along, these have become more and more apparent, and to a greater number of minds. In
                            the days of Jesus and his early followers there seemed to be an outburst, a gushing from the
                            very fountain of love. Then again the waters seemed to cease flowing, and the ministers of
                            peace and love to have changed to messengers of discord. Advancement has not always been
                            continuous in a right line. To some minds there has, at times, been an apparent retrograde,
                            though others discern the forward movement even in such cases, just as the astronomer sees
                            the continuous movement of planets and systems in the vast universe. To one looking back
                            from the present over the whole field of the past, or as far as his discernment can reach,
                            the change from worse to better, or from lower to higher things, has been great indeed.
                            Within the last century the change for the better, both in material and moral improvement,
                            has been so great that our historians have made it one of the especial themes on which they
                            have loved to dwell. Looking through this glass, the celebrated French poet, Victor Hugo,
                            has declared it his belief that in the course of the next century wars will not be resorted
                            to by the nations to settle difficulties that may arise among them, but peaceful measures
                            alone will be used. The golden era may not arrive so soon as that, yet that it will come
                            before many centuries more shall have passed away seems clear, not to the eye of faith
                            merely, but to the reason that views Infinite Power and Love forever employed, and knows how
                            much has already been effected. Improvement in material conditions helps to bring about
                            better moral conditions. That is a lesson clearly taught by the experience of the past
                            century ; and then, better moral conditions aid in effecting still better material
                            improvements. Remove the mental distractions caused by wars, and the power of thought will
                            be multiplied a hundred fold ; and, once directed in the right course, its victories over
                            mere material obstacles will be great, being aided both by intellectual and inspirational
                            force. Sonyea, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's sermon on the mount" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST'S SERMON ON THE MOUNT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sutton, Elizaette" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZAETTE SUTTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> I have been reading Christ's Sermon on the Mount, and I find so much that is beautiful in it
                            that I cannot forbear expressing my own thoughts upon it. In the first place our Saviour was
                            a governed man, led by the " Holy Spirit." He nerved Himself for the conflict of heaven and
                            earth within Him. He served the living principles infused in His being and became a
                            Regenerator, winning a renown that no other one had attained unto. He sought the power of
                            salvation as no other one had done, and could, therefore, teach as no other one had taught.
                            The sermon so true, so free and expressive, I will read again. Blessed are the poor in
                            spirit, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven : Deep toned, pure and unremitting are the pure
                            in spirits' claims. Blest are they, blest in creating a heavenly kingdom worth the name.
                            They are of a broken and contrite heart, easily entreated, deeply imbued with the spirit of
                            love they have broken up the fallow ground of the heart, and are removed from the sterile
                            rocks of selfhood, and have based their dwelling place on the fertile soil of humility that
                            is always so productive of good and wholesome fruit. Blessed are they that mourn, for they
                            shall be comforted: A mourner, worthy the name, is one who <pb n="54" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 54 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. mourns for dead works, shedding tears of repentance for iniquity ; in this
                            they cannot fail to find the balm of comfort promised. A true spirit of mourning implies
                            forsaking, for effect follows cause. The moment we sorrow for wrong-doing we begin to make
                            amends, and to such the comforter is nigh. Blessed are the meek, for they sliall inherit the
                            earth : Although Jesus himself had not where to lay His head, I think He had a sight, in
                            futurity, that took Him beyond the age in which He lived, and He saw an earthly inheritance
                            for a people who would make themselves particularly worthy. A home of earth that would not
                            be taken from them so long- as they maintained a meek and humble spirit. I believe a
                            thorough gospel baptism will meet the wants of physical and spiritual existence. Blessed are
                            they which do hunger and thirst after righteousness for they shall be filled : God says : My
                            son and my daughter give me thy whole heart; the first sacrifice must be a worldly life—in
                            making this sacrifice avenues of immortal good are opened to the soul, and we cannot cease
                            to hunger and thirst after righteousness. Let the powers of an endless life and the joys
                            thereof fill the entire being, we most gladly deny opposite influences upon us ; we lose a
                            relish for the lesser joys of nature, for more and truer encouraging things that lead to a
                            peaceful rest and a happy hereafter. We are filled in proportion as we hunger and thirst.
                            Blessed are the merciful for they shall obtain mercy: Here the golden rule is brought to
                            mind; Do unto others as we would have them do to us. Who does not love the spirit of mercy?
                            all forgiving, open to conviction, feeling and doing in accordance with just principles ;
                            not enlarging seeming faults, but considerate in a merciful spirit; bringing love to bear on
                            discordant elements. Thus we win confidence and earn the mercy of others in return. Blessed
                            are the pure in heart for they shall see Ood: This is heaven's best gift, clothing us
                            brightly as are the angels in heaven. On this depends our success in Christianity. God's
                            love may flow to us, but if we are not pure in spirit we cannot feel it. His light may beam
                            around our pathway, but we are liable to stumble if we are not pure in heart. The richest
                            treasures flow unimpeded to the heavenly mind. It sees God in smallest points that tend
                            upward. As a magnet draws an object and clings to it tenaciously, so the pure in heart draw
                            like influences around them. They sparkle in the firmament of the spiritual heavens as the
                            stars glitter in earth's horizon. God is eminently beautiful and altogether lovely in the
                            eyes of the pure in heart. Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called the
                            children of Ood : The character of a peacemaker is a joy in the house, lighting it in every
                            department. How bland is the atmosphere surrounding a peacemaker whose heart spreads its
                            dovelike wings and overshadows the erring. It soothes the afflicted when passion rises to
                            disturb and offend, and gently warns the tempest tossed, causing a fevered pulse to beat
                            quietly ; a loving word to drop from lips all sealed to kindly expression, and to say with
                            the poet : " The heart depends less for its joys and its beauties, On the flight of the
                            Eagle than the coo of the Dove." Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beatitudes and rewards" TEIform="index"/>BEATITUDES AND REWARDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Variety is universal law. Variety in harmony is the desideratum. The nine Beatitudes are all
                            well — their Rewards well — well for such as seek rewards. One of the nine — the sixth —
                            fills my eye. I'd take it for my portion, minus rewards. Among the seraphim and cherubim —
                            feminine and masculine angels — of the more advanced heavens, the pure in heart oeatitude is
                            transparently pre-eminent. We ask no more.</p></div2><pb n="55" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines sacred to the memory of our dearly beloved sister, Martha Curtis" TEIform="index"/>LINES SACRED TO THE MEMORY Of our Dearly Beloved Sister, Martha Curtis</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Gillespie</byline><p TEIform="p">1. As we read Life's daily record, And its rugged paths we tread, We are visited by Angels,
                            And by Angel hands are led. Sometimes thro' the vale of sorrow, Upwards to the mount of joy,
                            Where we feed and feast our spirits, And sweet praise is our employ. 2. Now, to-day, as we
                            are reading, One familiar name we miss ; One who long hath walked Life's pathway, Walks the
                            golden streets of bliss. Here her life-work is accomplished ; There the new life is begun ;
                            She has taken those bright laurels, Which thro' faithfulness she won. 3. Blessed, patient,
                            toiling Sister — One whose faith was tried and true ; On the earth and in the Heavens, Blest
                            thou art, and honored too. E'en the little children loved thee, Gospel mother, while thy
                            care For each sister and each brother Will be missed ; but constant prayer Will unite us in
                            the spirit, Soul with soul will often blend, As we drink from crystal fountains, And our
                            prayers to Heaven ascend. Father, Mother, God be with us,4 Grant us love, and may we feel
                            Thy protecting hand still o'er us ; All our sorrows thou canst heal. 5. Thou art Light, amid
                            the darkness]; Peace when angry storms arise ; Joy when ills of life betide us, Star of Hope
                            — our glorious prize ! Thou art rest when life grows restless, Thou art strength when we
                            feel weak ; Lord be with us thro' all dangers, And the trials here we meet. 6. 0 be with us
                            in temptation ; Lead us in the narrow way : Let us ne'er be God forsaken, Unto TJiiMi, 0
                            Lord, we pray. And when life-scenes close around us, And our sun of life goes down, Like our
                            Heaven-born Angel Sister May we win and wear the Crown. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eternal beauties" TEIform="index"/>ETERNAL BEAUTIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHERINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> The orb of day is rising in its glorious light; It sends its golden shafts o'er mountain top
                            and dale. And nature's beauties, bathed in crystal dews of night, Inhale the breath of life
                            from morning's gentle gale. I gaze upon the towering trees and verdant meads ; Upon the many
                            ripening fruits and blossoming flowers, And think how God brings forth this wealth from
                            little seeds, Beneath the sunbeam's rays and summer's genial showers. And then I think of
                            treasures found within the earth ; Of diamonds bright, and gems, and glittering mineral ore
                            ; And wealth the ocean bears—her shining pearls of worth— That slumber while they grow
                            beneath the billows' roar. While calmly contemplating all these beauteous things, I feel my
                            being thrilled with wonderment and joy ; But, suddenly, a hand, a shadowy darkness brings—
                            It is the hand of death that surely will destroy. And must their beauty fade? "All fade," a
                            voice returnsA cloud of disappointment o'er me now doth lower ; A moment's pause, and then
                            my longing spirit turns To seek the Fountain Source of all-creative power : On aspiration's
                            wings my soul is upward borne, Beyond the shades of earth and elements that blight ; Rich
                            beauties I behold in light of endless morn ; For now the veil is drawn that dimmed my inner
                            sight. I see the treasures there that earnest souls may gain, Who seek their wealth and joy
                            in the immortal life; And I feel my soul inspired, their substance to attain, Which shall be
                            the sweet reward of all my toil and strife. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A beautiful answer was given by a little Scotch girl..." TEIform="index"/>A beautiful answer was given by a little Scotch girl...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A beautiful answer was given by a little Scotch girl. When her class was examined, she
                            replied to the question, " What is patience ? " " Wait a wee, and dinna weary."</p></div2><pb n="56" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of the millenium" TEIform="index"/>SIGNS OF THE MILLENNIUM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Rev. Dr. Talmadge, on his return from, a western tour September, 1880, said in the Brooklyn
                            Tabernacle, recurring to his text [Romans, iiii, 13]. " The day for the Church is at hand."
                            Extending his vision to the outer world he saw there the day at hand. He saw it in the trend
                            of the age towards arbitration with the pen, instead of the clash of arms ; in the Geneva
                            award, and in the settlement of the Fisheries' dispute without bloodshed, in the outcome of
                            the Franco-Prussian war, and in England's mortification over her warfare with Zululand. " I
                            may be mistaken," he continued, " but I think there'll be no more wars between Christian
                            nations, and I hope, that ere long, there will be no more fighting Indians, no more brave
                            Ousters lost. But we must stop encroaching upon the red men. A general of high repute, who
                            has seen much of the Indian warfare, told me only a few days ago that all the wars between
                            the Indians and the whites have been provoked by our race. Now, while we are arbitrating
                            with the civilized world, let us deal in a spirit of fairness with the Indians." The speaker
                            drew a vivid picture of the wrongs against which the red men have recalcitrated, and then
                            continued: "Behold the government of the United States and the North American Indians. The
                            Indian has borne more than either you or I would bear. What is right in New York, is right
                            on the lands that were inherited by the aborigines." The speaker hoped that reparation might
                            be made for the wrongs done the Indians by our forefathers. " I'd rather be a red handed
                            Modoc, than one of the thieving agents who have robbed the Indians! " Here the vigorous
                            rapping of canes indicated a desire to break out in hearty cheering. Not more than two weeks
                            after this, the Doctor, perhaps lost in the effects of the pure mountain air of the west,
                            and we hear him relapsing into another tone, calling on the general government to destroy
                            Mormonism by arbitration, if possible, if not, then by howitzers, bomshells, bullets, cannon
                            balls etc. We regret that a man of so large sympathy and brilliant talents should, through a
                            spirit of religious intolerance, counsel war, especially after proclaiming that the time of
                            Universal Peace is at hand. He should remember that the true antidote of an evil is not to
                            commit another and greater evil. Persecution has helped Mormonism and it would again. The
                            Christian method is to inspire the people of Utah with a better and purer spirit. Does
                            Christianity, as it is practiced outside of Mormonism, afford this pure inspiration ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright lights!" TEIform="index"/>BRIGHT LIGHTS!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> In traveling the numerous and oft-times dreary thoroughfares of this busy world, after the
                            sable curtains of night-fall have been lowered, to screen earth from the sun's illumination,
                            how pleasant to meet the "bright lights" all along the way, which time and invention have
                            brought to such perfection. Just as cheering it is to meet with " bright Lights" in human
                            hearts, that have been kept trimmed and burning, perfected by progression of thought, and
                            obedience to truth, shining with steady glow in cloud or sunshine. Counting all workers for
                            the good of humanity, these may be numbered b}r the hundreds and thousands, extending so far
                            back that the dim glimmer of those which brightened the early ages (long since extinguished
                            to mortal eyes though to-day lighting the streets of heaven) is scarcely discernible. It is
                            with regret that while gazing at the stars of the nineteenth century, so bright, beautiful
                            and alive with inspirations, we behold them swiftly and suddenly dart into regions unknown,
                            or become lost to sight in the deep blue haze of eternity. One by one they pass from the
                            intellectual, moral and spiritual firmaments, and we watch with interest the gradual rise
                            and increasing magnitude of others, God sends to fill their places in the orbits of human
                            existence. Among the many gone who will be missed <pb n="57" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 57 more than others, those two noble workers for general good, Lucretia Mott and
                            Lydia M. Child, whose broad sentiments, unbounded by sea or land and ministrations of peace,
                            have gone forth like an aura of healing to thousands of aching hearts, some of whom ^ave
                            felt its blessing though unconscious of the source. Those who were the immediate sharers of
                            their social intercourse in life, und who tread the byways and highways in which their feet
                            have wended on missions of love, no doubt, know the value of such true friends, while all
                            lovers of truth who have read, heard or seen the jewels and diamonds, that have fallen from
                            the pen and lips of these brave thinkers, are ever ready to respond in a soul-felt amen ! As
                            friends to the oppressed of every grade and color, strong workers for the uplifting of women
                            from slavery to nobility of character, they have woven Immortelles in their garlands, which
                            will increase in beauty as the true Order of Heaven is established in this now chaotic
                            world, where man rules as " monarch of all he surveys." We know there are many in the land
                            whose hearts beat to the same measure and who will continue the great work of reform, that
                            has its grand ultimate in the equality of the sexes, all nations and races of people on the
                            earth, when land will be as free as air and water. " I may not be a prophet yet the fabled
                            time's at hand, In which the nations shall combine as one united band ; That day will see
                            one God, one Church, one government on earth, The long expected golden age, the truer second
                            birth." To all who have pulled out a stone from the foundation of the old creation, or added
                            one to the new (though their bodies lie in the grave), will be rendered the thanks and
                            praise of those who follow on to complete the structure. Every one has power to make the
                            world a little better for having lived in it, if they so will it. We may all be a " bright
                            light " to some one, two, three or more if we fan into life the little spark God has created
                            on the altar of each soul, which He designed should benefit not only ourselves but each
                            other. By thus doing we may send a gleam to cheer some struggling one, whether our journey
                            lie through the valley of shadows or over the rolling main. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Airing the beds and room" TEIform="index"/>AIRING THE BEDS AND ROOM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> The air of a sleeping-room should be constantly renewed from without, yet it should not be
                            icy cold. It is quite amazing to see in otherwise well-informed people the lingering
                            prejudice against night air, which makes them willing to breathe vitiated air all night
                            long. Attention to the airing of beds and bedding cannot be too great, and it ought to be
                            insisted upon in every house. The hurry to have rooms in order early causes beds to be made
                            up before they have been thoroughly permeated by air and sunlight, and gives them that
                            close, stuffy smell which is a sure index of deficient cleanliness. During the night the
                            body throws off, through the invisible pores of the skin, much impurity, and to make up a
                            bed while mattress, sheets and blankets are still sweltering with animal heat is a thing no
                            neat, intelligent housekeeper should ever do under any pressure of hurry. The rest of the
                            room can be dusted and set to rights, and the bedclothing left spread over chairs, with
                            windows open, until a late hour, and nobody will be hurt. Where the bedroom is the common
                            sitting or sewing apartment of a family, it should be thoroughly aired for a half-hour
                            before dark, everybody vacating it for the purpose, and again before its occupants retire.
                            In our societies it is an evil under the sun that beds and bedding, with some excep. tions,
                            are not aired, agreeable to the above directions. In the Canterbury Bishopric the whole
                            matter is systematized. Loops are ingeniously attached to mattresses and bedclothing, so
                            that it is hung up and the rooms are thus left until the afterpart of the day. Where this
                            practice does not prevail infirmities and weaknesses result, that cost <pb n="58" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>
                            58 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. the sisterhood more labor than is saved by the short-cut, unclean
                            plan of making1 up a bed. before it is air-washed. As to " looks," they are like tastes ;
                            there is no accounting for them. What people did not reason into, they cannot be reasoned
                            out of. It is as the difference between white and brown bread ; the decision will depend
                            upon the condition of the person who " looks."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Titusville, Penn., Feb. 5, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Titusville, Penn., Feb. 5, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Aikin, L. T. R., (Mrs.)" TEIform="persName"/>Mrs. L. T. R. Aikin</byline><p TEIform="p">Titusville, Penn., Feb. 5, 1881. G. A. Lomas — Dear Friend and Brother : I am reminded by
                                the return of the New Year that I must send you a few stamps in order to enjoy the
                                monthly visits of that most welcome visitor, the Shaker MantFESTO." For four years it
                                has come to me in due time, laden with messages of love and wisdom ; and each time I
                                have (as our Methodist friends express it in their conference meetings) " felt my
                                spiritual strength renewed," feeling as I do that every word is the utterance of a true,
                                honest and upright heart, that the words which they preach they practice also —
                                something which we do not often see down in the" outside world. This is the year 1881, a
                                year which has been designated by seers of the past ages (among whom are Mother Shipton,
                                of England, and Mrs. Abby Marsh, of Canada) as fraught with great, with glorious events,
                                insomuch that it has even been called the "end of the world." And methinks it may be
                                so—in the sense in which Shakers believe that their Society is the end of the Earthly
                                Order and. the beginning of the Heavenly, I tray God it may be so. I think I see in the
                                principles of the " Irish Land League " more of the teaching o£ the Christ-spirit than
                                has ever been expressed by any other organization (except the Shakers) of which we have
                                any account in past history. And how it is spreading ! Wonder of wonders to see the
                                people flocking together and proclaiming, to the world the great truth : " God is the
                                Father of all, and we are brethren." "The worlds are His, for He made them, and gave
                                them to His children for a home; not to a few but to each and every one." " He who
                                taketh from his brother the home that belongs to him, and his means of subsistence, is a
                                thief and a murderer." Is it not glorious to hear these great truths proclaimed in the
                                ears of the " Scribes and Pharisees " as in the days of Jesus of Nazareth ? May the time
                                have come when these teachings will be received by the people in a more literal sense
                                than they have ever yet done ! I am making my letter too long, perhaps, but my soul is
                                so filled with enthusiasm to see this great uprising of the people in the cause of
                                equality and justice that I cannot help expressing it to my dear friends the Shakers,
                                who I know have long been working for the same cause. With love and kind wishes for you
                                all, I remain, respectfully,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of the eyes" TEIform="index"/>CARE OF THE EYES</head><p TEIform="p">1. Rest the eyes for a few minutes when the sight becomes in the least painful, blurred or
                            indistinct. 2. Have sufficient light; never sit facing it; let it come from behind or from
                            one side. The writer considers too much light almost as bad as too little. He strongly
                            recommends a moderate light, so that surrounding objects may not be too much illuminated and
                            the wearing of a black shade, so large that front and side light may not enter the eyes.
                            With this protection the light may be safely in front—if reading, it is better that it be to
                            one side. 3. Never read in horse or steam cars. 4. Never read when lying down. 5. Do not
                            read much during convalescence from illness. G. The general health should be maintained by a
                            good diet, air, exercise, amusement and a proper restriction of the hours of hard work. 7.
                            Take plenty of sleep. Retire early and avoid the painful evening lights.— Ten hours sleep
                            for delicate eyes is better than eight. If any thing more is needed, use The Shaker Eye and
                            Ear Balsam.</p></div2><pb n="59" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mosaic reminders" TEIform="index"/>MOSAIC REMINDERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We have long contended that no nation, since the days of Mosaical discipline, has been
                                governed by so just and consistent code of laws. That no more rational and effectual
                                physiological science has ever since been taught, practiced, nor better fruits thereof
                                been experienced. That no more, nor as much, justice has since been familiar in the
                                dealings of the people, nor any greater nor more extended philanthropy anywhere since
                                been exercised. On the contrary, we can look to the failure of the observance of
                                Levitical arrangements for nearly all " the ills that flesh is heir to," and also for
                                nearly all of man's inhumanity to his brethren. In the tremendous agitations now
                                occurring in Ireland, we are forcibly reminded how very rigid were the laws of Moses in
                                the restriction of the then aristocracy, limiting the same to a few years at most, when
                                all would begin again upon a level, with equal facilities, so far as real estate
                                concerned the people, to rise again to aristocratic pre-eminence. When we think that the
                                lands of England, Ireland and Scotland are owned by a few thousands of inhuman and
                                unfeeling tyrants, and that this ownership is perpetual in their individual families ;
                                and that the parties who work the land get only a small pittance of what they grow, and
                                are unreasonably evicted at the caprices of said tyrants, we may well recall the fact
                                that such a state of things could not have existed under Moses, nor occasions given for
                                such violent, but only reasonable demonstrations, under the pressure of circumstances. A
                                parallel, if not an exceeding injustice is being perpetrated upon the Indians of the
                                United States. Their lands are being robbed from them by the government, and sold by the
                                government to others, not Indians, in perpetuity. Not so under Moses' rule. The purchase
                                and possession of the lands by the purchasers were limited. The service of individuals
                                to others was limited; and not as in Ireland and elsewhere, perpetual, and without hope
                                of a better condition for the servers. What a happy and vastly superior plan was that of
                                olden time, to have the people rest from their labors and speculations, not only one day
                                in seven, but one year in seven ; while the spontaneous grains, vegetables and fruits of
                                the year belonged to no one in particular, but to all equally. Would there be these
                                violent but righteous uprisings by the oppressed the world over; would we have our
                                perpetual Indian wars; would we then have the terrible contrasts of rich and poor,
                                masters and slaves, if such an arrangement should be made and executed ? And
                                particularly would not the great troubles of the world be banished, if the lands were
                                returned, as of old, every fifty years to their original owners ? Then would we hear the
                                songs of peace and plenty the world over, instead of these, only to be expected
                                remonstrances and bloodshed. Many of the slaves of Ireland — and Ireland<pb n="60" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 60 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. is no exception—-would come into just possession
                                of the lands upon which they are so horribly taxed, and brutally evicted. Then would we
                                see our Indians and their descendants rising up, once in a generation, to the renewed
                                assumption of their rights, instead of being annihilated by bloodthirsty, socalled,
                                Christian people. The present agitations of tlie Land Leaguers, and the constant battles
                                upon the plains, cause us to think now and to dwell particularly upon the limited
                                possession and re-distributions of the crops and real estate.. But we might dwell just
                                as reasonably and perhaps with mightier and more truthful effects, upon the systems of
                                diet, of the various habits in the lives of the Children of Israel, as reminders of the
                                present almost universal cry of disease, and of systems and habits which foster disease
                                ; and that a return to Mosaical instructions presents the shortest, safest, if not the
                                only refuge from sickness and disease. And perhaps, very reasonably so, this
                                physiological return is of the first necessity ; which condition being attained unto,
                                would be all powerful in correcting all other lusts which are giving the various
                                governments so much trouble, because of the unjust and ungodly contrasts between the
                                conditions of the rich and the poor, the masters and the slaves. Let us, while praying
                                for the millennium, bear in mind that its coming will convulse the gross injustice that
                                prevails among men who should fare as brethren, equally well, and that it may find more
                                or less to condemn and revolutionize, in us as individuals. *£?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communism and communists" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNISM AND COMMUNISTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It must be apparent to every student of Christianity, that the early disciples of Christ
                                were genuine communists ; those who were willing to, and did share every thing within
                                the reach of all, one with another. This is communism in genuine. It is not of the
                                invasive spirit ; that which would demand of and force those who had possessions to fall
                                down and share all they possess with them ; but who are able to work and wait in
                                patience, for the good spirit to turn the hearts of selfish possessors to a union with
                                the Commune. We believe there is no one feature more fully representing Christianity,
                                than the ability to commune, truly, with the brethren, the household of faith, " having
                                all things in common ; and no one possessed aught he called his own." Let governments or
                                churches decry communism if they will ; but they could with equal or greater propriety
                                decry purity of heart as being unchristian. Of the two—communism truly, purity of
                                heart—true, unselfish communism demands the greater nobility of the man and woman, and
                                the same is proved, where we see those who may, can and do boast of their purity of
                                hearts, who are as selfish as the smallness of their souls permits them ¦ to be, and
                                just as unchristian as ignoble. Let us have' more and more of true communism in the
                                churches ; let the same be accompanied by purity of heart and every other virtue ; but
                                do not let us hear so much of the possession of this peculiar virtue or that, with
                                genuine communism—true <pb n="61" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 61 brotherly
                                love—left out ; or we will decry the whole self-proclamation as a piece of deception
                                worthy only of the devil. Bear in mind there are neither rich nor poor in the assembly
                                of Christ "Ye are brethren* ; and " one is, your Lord, even Christ," the original
                                Christian Communist, ft</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unnatural or heavenly?" TEIform="index"/>Unnatural or Heavenly ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. Every attempt at a fac simile representation of Jesus Christ's life, is
                                met by two classes of individuals: Of one class we will hear that the attempt is in
                                contradiction to the behests of nature—unnatural. Of the other class we will hear : "
                                This is not of earth ; this is of heaven." Which is the true definition of the attempt ?
                                We claim both are. To do heavenly deeds is an unnatural proceeding, according to the
                                interpretation of what nature is understood to be. That Earth and Heaven can be
                                opposites and yet both right, good, each in its place, is a lesson to be learned by many
                                good folk. The chemist finds in his laboratory, oils and alkalies ; and everywhere we
                                find opposites which are equally good to all appearances. The earthly tends to the
                                grosser or lesser good; while the heavenly has enduring and eternal value. " The first,
                                was of the earth, earthy (good but transient and of the lesser good) ; the second, is
                                the Lord from heaven, a quickening spirit." Let the attempt of copying Christ represent
                                eternal features, and these will be opposites to those of temporary consideration,
                                however good they may be considered. The Shakers sing: '' Oil and Water cannot blend, N
                                either flesh with spirit ; Purity of heart alone, Can heaven's gifts inherit." And let
                                it be understood that the Uesh is inferior to the spirit; and while one is natural, the
                                other is heavenly.. The decision classes the individual.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is right" TEIform="index"/>What is Right</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">If any thing could convince people of the absolute puerility of most of the discussions
                                about religious forms and symbolism, it would be the fact that the Dunkards of Johnson
                                County, Missouri, have split on the question as to whether in celebrating religious
                                feetwasliing both feet should be washed or only one. Will the era of common sense never
                                commence in religious matters ?— Christian Union. Our brave and illustrious
                                contemporary, The Christian Union, hits hard, both right and left. The feet-washings,
                                the communism, the nearly hundred, or more, of arranged performances, may be essentials
                                of salvations, and we will not say they are not; but we will say as our contemporary
                                almost observes, that in this age, it is below the dignity of matured religious
                                enlightenment, to consider such inferiorities Christianity ; let us have Christ Himself
                                represented, and all these inferiorities will be unostentatiously, imperceptibly, but
                                inevitably involved and represented. Essentials are good ; but the essentials are in
                                doing good things in the right spirit; and the right spirit is the good essential thing,
                                regardless of what any may consider essential.</p></div3><pb n="62" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conversion" TEIform="index"/>Conversion</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We believe that the tendency of the race of humanity is upward. Larger comprehension of
                                what good is; keener apprehension, with charity, of what wrong intends, noble feelings
                                of what human nature is capable of, are features to be observed more than occasionally.
                                To be converted, means to he changed, changed from something to something else.
                                Conviction of what is wrong is inevitably accompanied by the conviction of "the better
                                way." Conviction is not conversion. It is an easy matter to be convicted; but to become
                                converted to the better way, changed from what we were, to what we ought to he, like
                                Christ, the pattern, is a conversion worth having, and one seldom heard of in the
                                bubbling effervescence of modern revivalism.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not forgotten" TEIform="index"/>Not Forgotten</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A few days ago we received a Five Dollar note from our kind Bro. Watson Andrews, who
                                seems to believe, that the unsalaried position of the editor of The Manifesto needs now
                                and then a kindly deed. The following accompanied the happy present : I'm too busy to
                                sing, so instead of a song, I send you a sum, my dear ; If you must have a song, make a
                                song of the sum, And wont that be the sum of a song ?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acceptable substitution" TEIform="index"/>Acceptable Substitution</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The children will gladly accept the beautiful articles of Elders Sproat and Orcutt. In
                                the story of Mindahminah, kindness is taught by a case of extreme selfdenial ; while in
                                the Best Capital we have as good things, and better, than we could say to the
                            children.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wears the bell" TEIform="index"/>Wears the Bell</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, Conn., has been outdoing herself and everybody lately by member's subscriptions
                                to The Manifesto. We give it the assurance of gratitude in behalf of the Publisher, with
                                his hopes that many would "go and do likewise."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Take notice" TEIform="index"/>Take Notice</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We purpose supplying all subscribers for The Manifesto, so long as we can, from January
                                number. Publisher Manifesto.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wash for wood work" TEIform="index"/>WASH FOR WOOD WORK</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Betsy" TEIform="persName"/>Betsy Johnson</byline><p TEIform="p">Kind Editor ; As it is now about the time for the cleanly sisterhood to begin their
                                annual " scrubbing " and putting on better appearances, I thought to send for
                                publication a recipe for making a solution to wash woodwork. We have used it and find it
                                a good and " helpful friend " in times of need : To one pint of soft soap add two
                                tablespoonfuls of spirits turpentine; stir these together thoroughly and put sufficient
                                of it into two quarts of warm water and one pint of skimmed milk to make a weak suds;
                                wash the wood-work with it without any rinsing. It leaves a glossy appearance, and a
                                wholesome flavor which every one will appreciate. West Pittsfield, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Chinese have a time-honored custom that..." TEIform="index"/>The Chinese have a time-honored custom that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Chinese have a time-honored custom that they shall pay all debts before their New
                                Year's Day, and those who are unable to do this will almost always commit suicide on
                                account of the disgrace. We don't want the suicides, but our people would be better off
                                with the other part of the custom.</p></div3></div2><pb n="63" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mindahminah: an Indian legend" TEIform="index"/>MINDAHMIMH: An Indian Legend</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p"> How the first corn grew —from whom it received its name — origin of the green-corn
                                dance. Mindahminah, the aged, sat in his solitary wigwam on the shores of the Keche
                                Qa'hme (Great Lake). The night was dark and stormy ; the old oaks, on the shores of the
                                lake, creaked and groaned in the blast ; for Keche Nodin, the Spirit of Wind, was very
                                angry, and threatened to tear them up by the roots, and scatter them on the rocks below.
                                Mindahminah had been a great hunter ; but he was old, and nearly blind, and his feet
                                failed him in the chase ; and he lay in his wigwam faint and exhausted, for this was the
                                ninth day he had been without food. Then he heard a sound like that of the wings of a
                                bird fluttering among the poles at the top of his wigwam. Mindahminah reached forth his
                                hand, and, lo ! a quail was confined among the poles, and could not find its way out.
                                Mindahminah took the quail in his hand. Then he said to himself, " Now has Keche Manito,
                                the Great and Good Spirit, sent me this quail for food, who am alone, and perishing with
                                hunger." Then he raked together a few embers, that lay on the bottom of his wigwam, and
                                kindled a fire, and proceeded to dress the quail, for food. Soon, amid the pauses of the
                                storm, he heard cries of distress, as of some one perishing for want of shelter. He
                                hastened to the door of his wigwam, and groped his way to a rock in the forest. Beside
                                it lay a woman, faint and exhausted, who had missed her way in the midnight darkness. He
                                took her by the hand, and led her to his wigwam ; rekindled his fire ; chafed her hands
                                and her feet; and laid her on his own buffalo robe to rest. Then he took the quail,
                                which he had caught and prepared for his own nourishment, and gave it to her, saying: "
                                My sister, all that I have for food in my wigwam is thine. Take it ; I give it to thee
                                freely. There is not enough for thee and for me. One of us must perish. I shall die;
                                thou wilt survive. Hereafter, when thou seest the poor and perishing, feed them as I
                                have done to thee. Then will this last act of my life not be lost to thee, or to those
                                who shall be blessed by thee. Farewell ! We meet not again till we meet in the Land of
                                Souls !" Mindahminah said no more. He" laid himself down on the bare earth, for his bed;
                                and that night the Great Spirit called him home to the Land of Souls. In the morning,
                                the woman arose, warm and refreshed from her sleep, and raised the curtain of the wigwam
                                ; and, lo ! Mindahminah lay cold and dead on the ground, in his wigwam ! Then she went
                                and told the chief of the tribe; and they came and buried him on the spot where the
                                wigwam had stood, and in which Mindahminah died. Then, the next morning, the men who had
                                buried him arose, and went to the place and looked; and, behold, there were green shoots
                                springing up above the grave,and the ground around it was covered. Then they wondered
                                what it was that had grown up so green and beautiful in a single night. And a voice
                                answered them from a cloud that lay, white and floating, over their heads : " My
                                children, listen to the voice of the Great Spirit ! This, that you see, shall be food
                                for you and your children to eat, for many generations. It is called Mindahminah (corn).
                                The good spirits planted it, and called it by his name, as a reward for his kindness to
                                the poor and perishing one, whom he took to his wigwam, one coli, stormy night, and
                                warmed, and nourished, and gave her of his own food to eat, while he, himself, perished
                                with hunger. And this tale shall be told by the Story Tellers,* through all your tribes
                                ; and they shall write on rolls of bark, for others to read, in the picture-writing of
                                the tribe, these words: "' Blessed is he that giveth to the poor ! Keche Manito, the
                                Great Spirit, shall reward him from his home in the southern heavens; and send him rain,
                                and Kesis, the sun, shall smile on him, and cause his corn to grow ; and his children
                                shall worship before me in the green corn time.f Blessed are the mer <pb n="64" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 64 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. ciful and loving ones; for great shall be their reward of
                                love !' " *The Story Tellers of the Indians are a class chosen by the tribe to
                                perpetuate its history to the rising generation among them. They assemble in the wigwam
                                of the Story Teller, during the long winter evenings, and he relates to them the tales
                                and traditions of the tribe. To assist his memory, lie holds in his hands long rolls of
                                birch bark — some of them very ancient — covered with picture-writing, on which the most
                                prominent events are delineated. The young men copy them from his hands, and repeat
                                together the lessons of the deeds of their fathers he has given them. They include all
                                their most daring exploits in hunting and fishing, and their successful raids upon the
                                enemy in time of war. Many of them are chanted in a low monotonous key, in which they
                                keep time with a drum, and rattle made of gourd shells. The Story Tellers are called the
                                Ke-ke-no-ah-mah-gade ; and they are the real historians of the tribe. + The Green Corn
                                Dance is a dance of thanksgiving, and is performed in the season of the early corn. It
                                is generally performed on tbe open plain in the center of the Indian camp by the young
                                men of the tribe It is the most laborious of all the sacred dances of the Indians, hence
                                the old men and women seldom join, only as spectators. They come to the place of worship
                                decorated with leaves and ears of corn; corn dangling from their heads, arms, and legs;
                                and holding a sheaf of it in each hand. They sing and chant songs of praise to the Great
                                Spirit, for the beautiful gift of corn ; whirling and leaping, as they feel inspired by
                                the Great Spirit to worship before him. The ceremony ends with a feast of corn, prepared
                                and laid before them, of which they all partake, sitting on the ground in circles.
                                During the feast they chant and sing a song of praise to the Great Spirit. The following
                                is a portion of the Nahgomin, or Song of the Indian Green Corn Worshipers : " The green
                                corn that waves o'er the valleys and hills The Great Spirit planted and causes to grow ;
                                From behind a cloud curtain his pipe smoke ascends, And he looks down, in love, on his
                                children below. Raise high your Nahgomin, with hearts brave and strong, And worship him
                                now with the dance and the song. Raise high your Nahgomin," etc.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best capital" TEIform="index"/>THE BEST CAPITAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> The best capital to begin life with is a good character. Make and keep good resolutions
                                ; let them call forth daily self-denying effort. Build up virtue by precept and example.
                                One clock that goes wrong may be the means of misleading a whole community ; and the
                                same may be said of the example that some persons set before their companions, Place a
                                pure life above all things. A clear conscience and a pure record are of untold value;
                                thousands disregard their worth. Never feel above an honorable calling, nor be afraid of
                                the coarse frock and the apron. Put your hands to work in the line of duty ; dust on
                                your garments and moisture on your brows bring neither shame nor disgrace. Better soil
                                your hands than your characters. Nothing can essentially injure your characters but your
                                own deeds. Work is no hardship, for it brings its satisfactions and its victories. Where
                                hard work kills one person, idleness .kills ten. The founders of this great Republic
                                were earnest toilers, and the noblest characters of our day are constant workers. You
                                miss it fearfully when you feel shame or embarrassment at being seen in the laboring
                                garb, rather thank God, who has enabled you to perform needful labor, and be grateful
                                that you have learned to work. Never surrender your good name, and however poor you may
                                be.in worldly goods, you are heirs to an inheritance that riches cannot buy — the
                                heavenly treasures. When a person has lost his good name, who.will trust him? Who wants
                                his society ? He may have been many years in building up a reputation ; it goes down.
                                His friends "shy off;" a noble ancestry cannot save him. Why'? it is whispered. . He is
                                dishonest ! he has lost his good name! That blasts him. Now, look out, that there is no
                                question regarding your character ; do not create any suspicions. You cannot afford to
                                do it, for your good name is your only reliable capital, and when that is blasted by
                                dishonesty, your character is ruined. Eternal vigilance is the price of safety.
                                "Watch,thou,in all things." Warners are all along life's pathway, warning the
                                inexperienced of dangers. The self-conceited may say, " Oh ! how foolish and weak are
                                those who have fallen ! I am strong ! I cannot fall." But sooner or later, if they
                                persist in wrong-doing, they <pb n="65" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 65 will fall.
                                It is inevitable; and the longer they walk the " broad road," the greater will be the
                                shock, and the more complete the destruction. Observe how sharply the Bible puts it, "
                                Let him that thinketh he standeth, take heed lest he fall." Enfield, Conn.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little boy was tempted..." TEIform="index"/>A little boy was tempted...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little boy was tempted to pluck some cherries from a tree which his father had
                                forbidden him to touch. " You need not be afraid," said his evil companion ; '' for if
                                your father should find out that you have taken them, he is too kind to hurt you." "
                                Ah," said the brave little fellow, " that is the very reason why I would not touch them,
                                for though my father would not hurt me, yet I should hurt him by my disobedience."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jenkins, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Jenkins</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dunlavy, B. B." TEIform="persName"/>B. B. DUNLAVY</byline><p TEIform="p">Pleasant Hill,Ky., Feb. 27, 1881. Beloved Elder, Giles B. Avery : I fear that the demise
                                of our very worthy beloved Eldress , which •occurred June 12, 1880, has never been
                                reported, by reason of the temporary suspension of correspondence. It was well
                                understood that she was one of the choicest jewels of the Shaker-fold, having spent a
                                long and useful life in the holy cause without a single drawback to record. She was
                                truly a Mother in Israel, and as peaceable as a lamb, even to the day of her departure
                                for the better land, in the 90th year of her age.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jones, Stephen" TEIform="index"/>Stephen Jones</head><p TEIform="p">At Watervliet, O., Jan. 10, 1881, , aged 78 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sneden, Joseph" TEIform="index"/>Joseph Sneden</head><p TEIform="p">At Hancock, Mass., Feb. 1, , aged 88 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rose, Wellington R." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Wellington R. Rose</head><p TEIform="p"> Also, Feb. 8, , aged 87 years.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received of" TEIform="index"/>Received of</head><p TEIform="p">H. S. Kellogg.................... $25 00 Abraham Perkins................. 29 60 R. M.
                                Wagan..................... 20 00 Galen Richmond................. 15 00 Amelia
                                Lyman.................... 21 43 Charles Clapp.................... 7 20 Benjamin
                                Yates................... G8 50</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silo" TEIform="index"/>THE SILO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> By consulting Webster's latest edition, we find that a Silo is " a pit, or subterraneous
                                store for keeping grain." The name is now applied to a partial or entire subterraneous
                                apartment for curing and keeping green forage for cattle, called, by the French, "
                                Ensilage," when it is cured in the Silo, a process which is effected by fermentation, as
                                nearly excluded from atmospheric air as possible. On the 7th of January, 1881, the
                                writer, accompanied by Elder Isaac Augur, of Hancock, and Geo. H. Cantrell, of Mt
                                Lebanon, went to Lee, Berkshire Co., Mass., to see a Silo, which was possessed by E. M.
                                Washburn, a scientific and flourishing agriculturist, importer and breeder of Holstein
                                cattle of that town. We found a well-informed and genial gentlemen, who was the
                                economical originator and manager of a model farm, and superb herds of cattle. In the
                                summer of 1880, he built a Silo, thirty-five feet long by seventeen feet wide and
                                seventeen feet deep. The walls were one foot in thickness, built of cobble stones and
                                grout of Rosendale cement. The Silo contained about 200 tons of ensilage, consisting of
                                alternate layers of sweet fodder corn and millet, all put in green, simply having the
                                water dried off before cutting. Before putting it into the Silo, it was cut up by power
                                about from one to two inches in length. (Should have been still fiuer, for the stalks.)
                                This, when put into the Silo, was packed as solid as practicable, by treading and
                                pounding down and covering nights with weights of stone upon plank coverings on top. The
                                mass cures in about five or six weeks, then retains its characteristic qualities,
                                whether fresh from the mass in Silo or left loose to dry. Friend Washburne is now
                                feeding this ensilage to a herd of fifteen two-year old heifers (coming spring), some
                                ten or twelve cows, two bulls and twelve yearlings, or rather last spring's calves, or
                                about thirty <pb n="66" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 66 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. eight or forty head, at the
                                rate of 2,000 pounds per day, to the entire herd, adding eight pounds of hay per day, at
                                noon. All the stock, old and young, eat the ensilage greedily, and prefer the millet to
                                fodder corn. They were all healthy, free from lice, their coats sleek and smooth, and
                                the cows giving good messes of milk, and the proprietor informed us that his stock were
                                doingbetter on this fare, thus far this winter, than they did last year on plenty of
                                good hay and one peck each of shorts per day. He further stated that the enterprise
                                would more than pay for itself in forage the present season. The Silo was built by
                                himself and his own hired men, using for its construction about seventy-five dollars'
                                worth of Rosendale cement, and some lumber, and the entire structure costing about $200,
                                labor and materials included. To speak of the flavor of the ensilage, the millet smelled
                                and tasted sweet, the fodder corn was slightly acid, about as much as weak acetic acid,
                                unfit for table use ; but each and all was eaten by the cattle with as much avidity and
                                apparent relish as the same weight of apples, and the entire waste of a week's foddering
                                would not exceed from one to two bushels of short butts of fodder corn stalks, which,
                                had they been cut one-half inch long instead of two inches, would have all been friable
                                and eatable. So remarked our gentlemanly friend Washburn e, to whom we felt much
                                indebted for his kindly attention, information and friendly entertainment. We found him
                                economically husbanding all his resources for fertilization of lands. His stable floors,
                                whereon cattle stood, were cement, and, behind, a space of three and one-half feet,
                                consisted of a pit three feet deep, and filled solidly as it could bo well tread down
                                with dry muck of peat-like consistency ; this is to absorb the liquids of the stables.
                                It was filled even with the stable floors, then covered with loose planks, a plank one
                                foot wide next the stable flooring being depressed about four inches lower than the main
                                flooring, so as to keep the stall floors dry, also the walks behind, and to admit free
                                ingress of liquids to the muck beds. When this filling is thoroughly charged with
                                liquids, it is removed and more dry muck added. The droppings of hen roosts were also
                                saved with dry muck and plaster, frequently and carefully gathered up and stored in
                                barrels for use on corn, etc.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread question" TEIform="index"/>THE BREAD QUESTION</head><p TEIform="p">•-----------?----------[From House and Home, London, Bng.] In another column we report
                                the proceedings at a public meeting upon the bread question, held at Kensington last
                                Saturday. Our readers have been kept pretty well informed upon the subject which we
                                regard as being one of the first importance in die tetics. We have over and over again
                                pointed out the irrationality of the present system of bread-making. Its pernicious
                                effects upon the national health, wealth and wellbeing cannot be over-estimated. We have
                                reached such a pitch of refinement that custom demands the use of bread of the whitest
                                color and lightest texture. To produce this, the baker uses flour from which the most
                                nutritive parts have been abstracted, and which, in reality, is little else than starch.
                                This is especially the case in what is known as Vienna and French breads. Eaten alone,
                                such a compound would not support human life, and it can by no pretence claim to be
                                called " the staff of life." It has become such a hollow mockery, and its nutritive
                                properties are so attenuated, that scarcely any amount of misdirected ingenuity can
                                further refine away its pabulum ; so that we have the advantage of having reached the
                                extreme limit in the manufacture of an article which is neither more nor less than sham
                                bread. We are an ingenious race, and prone to adopt a circuitous route when a direct
                                course is open before us. There are few things which we do in which this is better
                                illustrated than in our bread-making. As the grain grows it contains all the elements
                                and properties necessary to build up the human frame and maintain it in the brightest
                                state of health. But that is too good— or not good enough—for us. We immediately set
                                about to improve upon nature, and by our acts we claim a wisdom superior to that of the
                                Infinite. The color of the <pb n="67" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> . THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 67 grain is not
                                to our liking, so we set up a costly machinery for the separation of the darker and what
                                we call the coarser parts of it from its whiter and finer portions ; and in the case of
                                very fine flour we retain but little beyond the starch of the grain. The resulting bread
                                is deficient in essential structure, building and life-sustaining elements ; and, not
                                being nourished, we become uncomfortable and diseased. Deficient in the bony pillars of
                                our bodies, with our muscles in a half-starved condition, and with brain exhausted for
                                want of its appropriate material for renewal, we are ready to fall victims to any
                                unnatural method of stimulating the system, or of silencing those unpleasant nervous
                                sensations which, as our true protectors, ever warn us to yield obedience to nature's
                                laws. Hence, it is because our bread—so-called—is not bread, that so much flesh meat is
                                required, and that animal food is in such good repute. It also favors luxury in food in
                                other respects, and it induces a condition of body in which alcohol is taken with so
                                much apparent benefit, while the narcotic tobacco is in requisition, to calm ar.d soothe
                                the nerves of the victim of the baker. Fashion and' custom lead to this result;
                                sham-like, as our bread is made, it is for the sake of appearance. We instruct our baker
                                to supply us with white bread, and the whiteness of the article is our general test of
                                its quality. The miller is required by the baker to furnish him with white flour, and,
                                accordingly, he grinds the wheat to a great degree of fineness, and removes from the
                                powdered grain all but its whitest parts. By doing this he abstracts altogether the
                                salts and phosphates — those elements capable of supplying material to bone, teeth,
                                nails, etc., and much of that required to nourish the brain and support the muscular
                                system. And having done this, we fall back on the butcher, the brewer, and even the
                                distiller and tobacconist to make up the deficiency! But instead of getting relief, we
                                pile up and accumulate woes unutterable, and dub them " the ills flesh is heir to." It
                                has come to our knowledge that several of our readers, adopting our advice, and eating
                                only whole, meal bread, have lost all desire for the use of alcohol and tobacco ; a fact
                                which temperance reformers should not lose sight of. The question is, as Dr. Richardson
                                said at the meeting above referred to, " one of the greatest possible national
                                importance.' It, perhaps, more than any other in dietetics, affects the physique of the
                                race. Of importance to every individual in so far as it interferes with his own health
                                and capacity for work, it is of supreme importance for the same reason to the nation,
                                whose truest wealth is the health of its citizens. We trust the promine nee now given to
                                the subject, and the social rank and scientific attainments of its advocates, will
                                induce a general and speedy return to the use of nature's grand provision for the
                                sustenance of the human frame; unmutilated wheaten bread.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our want of faith" TEIform="index"/>OUR WANT OF FAITH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morrison, John L." TEIform="persName"/>JOHN L. MORRISON</byline><p TEIform="p"> When skies are clear and winds are fair, And flowers bloom, and fields declare The
                                bounties of a fruitful year; Tis then without one doubt or fear, We trust in God.. But
                                let the clouds in anger frown, Torrents of rain come pouring down, . That harvest fruits
                                may be despoiled, For which we've watched and cared and toiled, And then we faint. We
                                cannot penetrate the gloom, Our faith all dies, and there's no room For hope ; so in
                                despondency We sit and brood, and fail to see The hand of God. 'Tis often thus along
                                life's road, If we're compelled to bear a load, Forget the blessings of the past,
                                Because they will not always last, And fret for more. If we could but remove the veil,
                                When sorrow doth our hearts assail, And see how near the Master stands, Still guiding
                                with his loving hands, We'd never doubt, But sing amidst the deepest grief. His hand
                                will bring us sweet relief From all our sad, distressing woes, Deceitful friends and
                                deadly foes, And guide us home.</p></div3></div2><pb n="68" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Giver and the taker" TEIform="index"/>THE GIVER AND THE TAKER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier, John O." TEIform="persName"/>John O. Whittier</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following is an attempt to versify a literal translation of a poem by the Hindoo writer,
                            , who lived, it is supposed, in the third century of our era. He was remarkable for his
                            hatred of idolatry and caste, and for his almost Christian conception of God and human
                            duty.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Who gives what others may not see, Nor counts on favor, fame or p.raise, Shall
                                    find his smallest gift outweighs The burden of the mighty sea. Who gives to whom
                                    hath naught been given, His gift in need, though small indeed As is the
                                    grass-blade's wind-blown seed Is large as earth and rich as heaven ! Forget thou
                                    not, 0 man ! to whom A gift shall fall, while yet on earth, Yea, even to thy
                                    seven-fold birth, Revive it in the lives to come! Who, brooding, keeps a wrong in
                                    thought, Sins much, but greater sin is his Who, fed and clothed with kindnesses,
                                    Shall count the holy aims as naught. For he who breaks all laws may still In Sivam's
                                    mercy be forgiven ; But none can save in earth or heaven The wretch who answers good
                                    with ill!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in the <index level1="Waif" TEIform="index"/>Waif.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Atonement" TEIform="index"/>ATONEMENT</head><p TEIform="p">While professed Christians depend on the blood of Christ to atone for the consequences of
                            sin, the reputed (Christian) infidels, physiologists, reformers, saviours, are working at
                            the cause by striving to introduce pure blood into the reputed Christians. The former rely
                            on the blood of a dead man, the latter depend on the blood of active, healthy, living men.
                            The blood of Christ must have run low when the church instituted a fee paid in advance to
                            atone for sins in anticipation, against which invention Martin Luther's honest soul
                            protested, as did Jesus against the practices of the Jewish priesthood. As did Voltaire
                            against the inquisition, and the exercise of unwarranted authority. And George Fox and Ann
                            Lee against moral and physical sins, and spiritual blindness. And Thomas Paine against
                            Church and State despotism. The great army which have ever confronted progress; the foe of
                            human advancement and happiness, with " cross over their heads, the gospel in their mouths,
                            and fire and sword in their hands, have not all passed yet." But other lingering relics have
                            more the appearance of a retreating than a victorious army, well described in the 18th
                            chapter of Revelations : " Babylon shall be (is being) burned with fire " of scientific
                            truth, which preceedeth out of the mouths of Ingersoll, Bradlaugh and their compeers, who
                            give more quantity and quality for thought than is found elsewhere. The Jews " God's
                            peculiar people," and Christians who would evangelize the whole world, must correct their
                            bloody record by atonement, confession and repentance, before they cry " infidel ! " " He
                            hath a devil,'* etc. ; and stone and imprison the modern prophets whose record has ever
                            been, " Peace on earth and unto men good will." By their icorks shall ye know them. Atone,
                            repent and be baptised into the spirit and practice of the golden rule, and God, angels and
                            men will accept the atonement. " O! make thou us, through centuries long In peace secure, in
                            justice strong ; Around our gift of freedom draw The safeguards of Thy righteous law; And
                            cast in some diviuer mould. Let the new cycle shame the old."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-forgetfulness" TEIform="index"/>SELF-FORGETFULNESS</head><p TEIform="p">The Sunday School Times thus editorially hits hard all of us who are wanting of It is utter
                            forgetfulness of self that gives truest power and truest attractiveness in character.
                            Self-consciousness does not always show itself with equal offensiveness ; sometimes it
                            appears in undisguised vanity: sometimes in overbearing assumption; again it is chiefly
                            manifest in extreme embarrassment of manner ; but it is always a loss of power and a loss of
                            winsomeness. Self-consciousness is not inconsistent with sincerity, but it is inconsistent
                            with simplicity, and the truest grace and the greatest force are always found in simplicity.
                            Many who pride themselves on their sincerity are ut- <pb n="69" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 69 terly lacking in simplicity, and they suffer before others accordingly. " We
                            see many people," says Fenelon, "who are sincere without being simple. They do not wish to
                            be taken for other than what they are ; but they are always fearing lest they should be
                            taken for what they are not. A simple man neither affects virtue nor truth ; he is never
                            busy thinking about himself ; and seems to have lost that ego about which we are so
                            jealous." Simplicity is a sure cure of that morbid sensitiveness which causes one to think
                            that he is always under prominent observation one way or the other, or which would bring him
                            to confess if he really spoke out sincerely : " I fancy all the world engrossed with judging
                            My merit or my blame." Simplicity goes straight at its work everywhere and always, and
                            without a thought of any thing but that work. That is always a power — always a source of
                            attractiveness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Witty and true" TEIform="index"/>WITTY AND TRUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hill, Rowland" TEIform="persName"/>Rowland Hill</byline><p TEIform="p">Some of the sayings of that pious but witty clergyman, Rev. were remarkable for hitting the
                            nail on the head. Not another blow was needed to drive it home. Being very much grieved at
                            the conduct of some of his congregation, who were frequently unpunctual, he once offered the
                            following prayer : '•' O Lord, bless those who are in their places, have mercy on those who
                            are on the road, and save those who are getting ready to come." He once said of a man who
                            knew the truth, but seemed afraid to preach it in its fullness: " He preaches the truth as a
                            donkey mumbles a thistle — very cautiously." On a wet day a number of persons took shelter
                            in his chapel, during a heavy shower, while he was preaching; he remarked: "Many people are
                            blamed for making their religion a cloak, but I do not think those are much better who make
                            it an umbrella." Entering the house of one of his congregation, he saw a child on a rocking
                            horse : " Dear me," exclaimed the aged minister, " how wondrously like some Christians ;
                            there is motion, but no progress." A professed Christian, who was addicted to drinking,
                            asked him impertinently," Now, do you think, Mr. Hill, that a glass of spirits would drive
                            religion out of my heart ? " " No," he answered, " for there is none in it." A lady who
                            professed religion, but whose daily practice was not in harmony with it, once said to him, "
                            I am afraid lest after all I shall not be saved." " I am glad to hear you say so," replied
                            Mr. Hill, " for I have been long afraid for you, I assure you.''</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not lost" TEIform="index"/>NOT LOST</head><p TEIform="p">The look of sympathy, ihe gentle word, Spoken so low that only angels heard ; The secret art
                            of pure self-sacrifice, Unseen by men, but marked by angels eyes— These are not lost. The
                            sacred music of a tender strain, Wrung from a poet's heart by grief and pain, And chanted
                            timidly, with doubt and fear, To busy crowds who scarcely pause to hear— These are not lost.
                            The silent tears that fall at dead of night Over soiled robes, that once were pure and white
                            ; The prayers that rise like incense from the soul, Longing for Christ to make it clean and
                            whole — These are not lost. The happy dreams that gladdened all our youth, When dreams had
                            less of self and more of truth ; The childhood's faith, so tranquil and so sweet, Which sat
                            like Mary at the Master's feet — These are not lost. The kindly plans devised for other's
                            good, So seldom guessed, so little understood; The quiet, steadfast love that strove to win
                            Some wanderer from the ways of sin — These are not lost. Not lost, O Lord, in Thy city
                            bright Our eyes shall see the past by clearer light. And things long hidden from our gaze
                            below Thou wilt reveal, and we shall surely know These are not lost.</p></div2><pb n="70" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual home" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL HOME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Emily Offord</byline><p TEIform="p"> Canaan, N. Y. 1. There's a beautiful home on the mountain of God, Where flowers in purity
                            bloom, 2. There is joy and delight in that beautiful home, And sweet is the peace reigning
                            there, 3. We will sing of that home thro' the journey of life, While crosses we faithfully
                            bear, 4. And we joy in the conflict rejoice in the strife That we may inheritance gain, And
                            the fair beams of glory in radiance bright, The heavenly mansions illume. And a rest happy
                            rest for the weary and worn, A glorious freedom to share. For a blessed fruition of eternal
                            bliss These trials our spirits prepare. Even now to our vision the shadow's revealed, The
                            substance e're long we'll obtain. Home, home, O, beautiful home! Heavenly graces are there,
                            Where pxire love each heart controls, We long of its glories to share.</p></div2><pb n="71" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kerosene" TEIform="index"/>KEROSENE</head><p TEIform="p">Before any of our readers shall so foolishly tamper, and with carelessness, to the probable
                            endangering and destruction of their own lives, property, and the same of others —" Halt! "
                            Read and reflect upon the wisdom enunciated by the Evening Times. Albany, N. Y.: "An idea
                            seems to be prevalent that kerosene is useful not only as an illuminating agent, but also in
                            starting kitchen fires. It matters not that the papers almost daily record cases of painful
                            death from its being put to the latter use. When a fire is to be started to cook the morning
                            meal, it would be far better that nitro-glycerine, dynamite or gunpowder should be used,
                            than that the kerosene-can should be called into requisition. The substances named only
                            explode, but the kerosene oil takes fire and spreads itself on every object in its
                            neighborhood. Would that every woman who tries to start a fire with kerosene would stop a
                            moment to consider that the soldier under fire, in the midst of a hot battle, has many more
                            chances to escape with life than she. Kerosene is a dangerous compound to be kept in a
                            house, even if used prudently. It should be kept in some portion of the house where neither
                            sunlight, nor any fire nor artificial heat can come. Lamps should be filled in the day-time,
                            and under no circumstances should be filled at night with another light near. The oil itself
                            is not explosive ; it is the gas engendered by the oil that occasions the explosions that
                            daily occur. A half-empty lamp, although standing on a table, and without being touched, is
                            liable at any moment to explode. Such accidents we have been called upon to record time and
                            time again. In order to prevent explosions, lamps should be filled with the oil and filled
                            in the day-time. So far as lighting fires by pouring oil from a can is concerned, it is to
                            be hoped that no reader of this paper would ever even think of doing any thing so reckless
                            and dangerous. Housewives should not only conform strictly to the rules here laid down, but
                            should instruct their servants to do the same, and see to it, personally, that their
                            instructions are obeyed. The picture of a woman with blazing garments, rushing through the
                            streets, has become altogether too familiar. To be burned is the most fearful of all deaths,
                            and yet, how often does it happen, because the most ordinary rules of prudence are
                            disregarded?</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fear of disease" TEIform="index"/>FEAR OF DISEASE</head><p TEIform="p">It is said that while the plague was raging in Buenos Ayres, the grave-diggers bore charmed
                            lives. Of the three hundred men so employed, not one died of the disease. It has often been
                            noticed that during the prevalence of pestilential diseases, physicians, undertakers,
                            nurses, and grave-diggers, whose business compelled constant liability to infection, have
                            usually escaped in a far greater ratio than their numbers would warrant. The "charm" of this
                            immunity from the prevailing scourge is very simple. They are not scared. They are positive
                            to the disease, and repel its attacks. Fear is a great ally of death. Whoever is afraid of
                            disease is in a negative condition and really invites its approach. And thus it is the world
                            over. The brave die but once, while cowards die many times. Much unnecessary alarm exists in
                            every community in regard to many diseases. We are, it is true, all liable to sickness and
                            death. But if we are all sober, cleanly, and brave of heart, we need have no fear of disease
                            of body or mind.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purified church needed" TEIform="index"/>A PURIFIED CHURCH NEEDED</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">At the Northfield Conference Mr. Moody is reported as saying : "I am a thousand
                                    times more anxious for the purification of the church than for the conversion of
                                    sinners. There will be no trouble in securing the conviction of sinners when the
                                    church can show a clean record." These are true words, as all revival efforts prove.
                                    To pass over the church, already enfeebled by worldliness, and seek the con version
                                    of sinners, is a great mistake. Converts, under such circumstances, if they be
                                    converts at all, will be feeble and useless. The child will partake of the feeble-
                                        <pb n="72" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 72 THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. ness of the mother, and both
                                    together will soon find a common grave. But let the church become pure, and filled
                                    with the Holy Ghost, and converts not only become numerous, but " mighty through God
                                    to the pulling down of strongholds." The conversion of the three thousand at the
                                    Pentecost was preceded by the baptism of the Holy Ghost, with which they were all
                                    filled. How can the churches be made to see and feel this? Purity is commanded by
                                    God, and demanded by the state of the church.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Advocate of holiness" TEIform="index"/>Advocate of Holiness.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extracts voice of peace" TEIform="index"/>EXTRACTS VOICE OF PEACE</head><p TEIform="p">Nations impoverish each other by standing armies and armaments which in peace are useless and
                            in war destructive. Ironclads are useless national luxuries. They cannot stand against
                            torpedoes, and are only fit to be sold as old iron. Monster guns are another folly.
                            Fortresses are not safe against dynamite, which can be thrown upon them from balloons. But,
                            say some, if it were not for war, what would we do with all the people ; the world would be
                            overpopulated ? This is another great error. The Valley of the Mississippi can maintain two
                            hundred millions of people, and the Province of Guyana, In Venezuela, which is as large as
                            Prance, has only thirtyfive thousand inhabitants and some of the richest soil on the face of
                            the earth. The United States alone could produce food and shelter for the present human
                            race. Oneseventh part of the globe is still covered with swamps and deserts awaiting the
                            labor of men, whilst nations destroy each other in wars for the benefit of a few politicians
                            and reigning families, and still we hope and believe that peace and good-will among men
                            shall one day reign upon earth. May that day not be far off; and may the labors of free and
                            law-loving men hasten its advent.</p></div2><div2 type="instructions" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every girl should have the power to earn her own livelihood..." TEIform="index"/>Every girl should have the power to earn her own livelihood...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Every girl should have the power to earn her own livelihood. Tt is a false
                                    position taken by many mothers to train up their daughters to be merely ornamental.
                                    Labor is honorable, and every person should do his or her share. Frugal husbandry
                                    and household prudence are the foundations of peace in the land. I advise all to be
                                    born of healthy mothers if they can. Health is essential to peace, and healthy
                                    mothers are essential to healthy children, and healthy children are essential to the
                                    training up of the world to peace and righteousness. Bring this influence into the
                                    Sabbath schools and churches. We want something better than dogmas and creeds. A few
                                    years ago it was thought a woman could not manage a winter school in this country
                                    because it was supposed necessary to thrash the boys. Now women are preferred, even
                                    in country schools, in winter, because that the mild power rules most effectually.
                                    This principle is growing in the community, and it will be carried out all through
                                    the management of our public prisons.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Peace advocate" TEIform="index"/>Peace Advocate</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing and reaping" TEIform="index"/>SOWING AND REAPING</head><p TEIform="p">Sow with a generous hand, Pause not for toil or pain ; Weary not through the heat of summer,
                            Weary not through the cold spring rain; But wait till the autumn comes For the sheaves of
                            golden grain. Scatter the seed, and fear not, A table will be spread; What matter if you are
                            too weary To eat your hard earned bread ! Sow, while the earth is broken, For the hungry
                            must be fed. Sow,—while the seeds are lying In the warm earth's bosom deep, And your warm
                            tears fall upon it,— They will stir in their quiet sleep; And the green blades rise the
                            quicker Perchance for the tears you weep. Then sow,—for the hours are fleeting, And the seed
                            must fall, to-day ; And care not what hands shall reap it, Or if you have passed away Before
                            the waving cornfields Shall gladden the sunny day. Sow; and look onward, upward, Where the
                            starry light appears,— Where, in spite of the cowards doubting, Or your own heart's doubts
                            and fears, You shall reap in joy the harvest You have sown, to-day, in tears. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Proctor, Adelaide" TEIform="index"/>Adelaide Proctor.</byline></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>