<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0208" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18720801" TEIform="date">August 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">SHAKER. I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DBSIRE OP ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORY,
                        SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. vol. II. G. A. Lomas,
                        Editor. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., AUGUST, 1872. No. 8. Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Daniel and John" TEIform="index"/>Daniel and John</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">" The superior will govern," were words spoken by Ann Lee. He whose right it is to reign, will reign in the end.
                            God is above all. The spiritual is "superior" to the natural, even as cause exists before effects. And, as a "
                            little leaven leaveneth the whole lump," in process of time, so will the Christ Spirit, ultimately, leaven the
                            whole mass of humanity. It goeth forth conquering, and to conquer. The highest class of spiritual religious
                            people, in any day in the past, were as Moses expressed it to his Israel: " The Lord did not set his love upon
                            you, nor choose you because ye were more in number than any people; for ye were the fewest of all people." As a
                            priesthood to mankind, and as a prophetical order, how could it otherwise be ? The Jews were a royal priesthood,
                            commissioned to teach the nations of earth important radical principles. In Israel, as in every other nation, an
                            order of Prophets and Prophetesses existed, as ministers of the Christ heavens, few in number, and a far more
                            numerous order of Prophets and Prophetesses were inspired by the gods of their people, tutelary divinities. As a
                            priesthood, Israel performed the office of instructor of babes to the Gentiles in the most efficient manner.
                            When its national organization was entirely broken up, its national priesthood disrupted, their religious
                            ministrations abolished, the daily sacrifice taken away, the feasts and solemn assemblies suspended, the temple
                            destroyed, and the people themselves transported into foreign lands, their missionary work to mankind was only
                            the more decidedly successful, and powerfully triumphant. But the glory thereof redounded almost exclusively to
                            the honor and glory of the Hebrew God. Moses, the greatest of the early Hebrew prophets, accomplished the
                            national organization of his people ; created the Levitical priesthood, and established it upon the foundation
                            of the national existence. Consequently, it stood in its original integrity ; it became corrupted, it rose or
                            fell, was pure or impure, as the body, of which it was the head, was holy or unholy: it was always "like priest,
                            like people." The Prophet was the fountain, the priesthood the cup, from whence the people drank; and sometimes
                            the people filled that cup from their own fountains. Thus, when Moses, the Prophet, was up in the mount,
                            communing with the God of Israel, receiving from the highest spiritual source to which they had access, the ten
                            commandments, written by spirits on tables of stone, as the basis of all succeeding laws and statutes to Israel,
                            and having left the whole nation in charge of the Levitical priesthood, and under their legitimate ministration;
                            "when the people saw that the Prophet delayed to come down from the mount, to inspire and guide the priesthood,
                            the people gathered themselves together unto Aaron, their priest, and said unto him, " Up, make us gods which
                            shall go before us; for as for this Moses, the man, or Prophet, which brought us up out of the land of Egypt, we
                            know not what has become of him." " Now Aaron had made a molten calf of the offerings of the people, and said,
                            These be thy gods, 0 Israel; and they sat down to eat and drink, after the manner of the people of the land,
                            and, like them, when the feast was over, they rose up to commit fornication." Moses knew nothing of the
                            defection of his people; but "God said to him: Up, get thee down; for the people which thou broughtest up out of
                            Egypt have corrupted themselves. Let me alone, that my wrath may wax hot against them, that I may consume them
                            as in a moment; and I will make of thee a great nation." When acting as a Christ Prophet, and under its
                            inspiration, Moses was not only above the Jewish king and priesthood; but was superior in governmental dignity
                            and official supremacy to the God of Israel, who was himself but a subordinate or tutelary divinity. Yet was
                            Moses, at that time, the meekest man that there was upon earth ; and therefore did he not only resist this
                            appeal to his ambition, but became a minister of the Christ Spirit to the Hebrew divinity, by which he pacified
                            his anger, and allayed in him the spirit of revenge. Thus it is recorded: "Moses besought the Lord his God, and
                            said, Lord, why doth thy wrath wax hot against thy people which thou hast brought forth out of the land of Egypt
                            with great spiritual power and mighty physical manifestations? Wherefore should the Egyptians speak and say, For
                            mischief did he bring them out to slay them in the mountains, and to consume them from the face of the earth.
                            Turn from thy fierce wrath, and repent of this evil which thou hast devised against thy people;" for they are
                            still better mediums than any other nation to work through—better material to build with. Should you take my
                            posterity, they also would come to the same state, and develop similar conditions. For the attainment of your
                            object, the final redemption of the race of man, you can do no better than keep hold of this people. "And the
                            Lord repented of the evil which he had thought to do unto his people." And when Moses went down from the mount,
                            "he saw the calf and the dancing; and Moses' own anger waxed hot; for he was only a medium of the Christ Spirit,
                            which was not incarnated in him, nor incorporated in his own personal character. Moses had not thus attained; he
                            partook of the spirit of his God ; and in his wrath— the wrath of man—he threw down the precious tablets "
                            written with the finger of God, and break them beneath the mount." Then he took the calf which they had made,
                            and burnt it in the fire and ground it to powder, strewed it upon the water, and made the children of Israel
                            drink up their own God. And the Levites went in and out from gate to gate through-, out the camp, slaying every
                            man his neighbor, and every man his brother and companion, until three thousand men were slain. The remainder
                            were plagued all their days because of the calf which they had made; for the Lord had said, Whose ever hath
                            sinned against me, him will I blot out of my book. And all the people saw a cloudy pillar stand at the
                            tabernacle door when Moses entered in, and God talked with him face to face as a man talketh with his friend.
                            This caused Moses' face so to shine, that he put a vail over his face when he appeared before the <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE SHAKER. people. And the cloud of the Lord was upon the tabernacle by day, and fire was on
                            it by night, in the sight of all the house of Israel, throughout all their journeyings. The practical result of
                            all this was, that Israel took possession, by means of a spiritualistic warfare, of all the land of Canaan. And
                            it was only when the nation sinned after the manner of the people of the land, that the heathen were able to
                            carry them away into captivity. And even then, under the law that tie superior will govern, they became a power
                            in the midst of their enemies. As Joseph was raised up in Egypt to be its chief ruler, under Pharaoh, so in
                            Babylon we find the captive Daniel, by the same agency, raised to power in the civil government. His spiritual
                            gifts were superior to any which the magi, soothsayers, astrologers, or wise, scientific men of the nation, who
                            held him in bondage, were equal unto. Thus Daniel and his fellows attained to almost supreme authority in
                            Babylonia, the most mighty nation then upon the face of the earth. Being chosen to stand before the king, he and
                            his companions carefully observed the Mosaic law of diet, subsisting on pulse, with water for their only drink.
                            With this fare, the Jewish captives proved to be "in matters of wisdom and understanding, ten times better than
                            all the magicians and astrologers that were in all the realm of Babylon; and Daniel continued unto the first
                            year of Cyrus, king of Persia, who conquered the kingdom of Babylon." The means by which this influence was
                            attained and maintained for so long a period is worthy of critical examination. Principles are eternal. And the
                            Millennium, of which Daniel so plainly prophesied, is a possibility of the race illustrated in his own history,
                            to be ultimately effected by the same spiritual agencies that were employed by David to secure his ascendency
                            over all the opposing influences in Babylon. His foundational principle was vegetable diet—conscientious
                            religious observance of the laws of physiology. He was also strictly obedient to his spiritual guide—the Christ
                            Spirit. He feared and obeyed God rather than man, as a Prophet, and assumed the consequences. It was the rulers
                            of a great national organization, with its legal enactments and penal laws, versus the enslaved Prophet. The
                            king dreamed, and required the magi to interpret the dream. " Tell thy servants the dream, and we will show the
                            interpretation," they said. But the king replied: "The thing is gone from me; and if he will not make known unto
                            me the dream, with the interpretation thereof, ye shall be cut in pieces, and your houses shall be made a
                            dunghill. Tell me the dream, and I shall know that ye can interpret it aright." Pleading for life, they
                            declared, ' There is not a man upon earth that can show the king's matter. And no king, .ord, or ruler, asketh
                            such things at any magician, or astrologer, or Chaldean. STone other can show it, except the gods whose dwelling
                            is not with flesh." This only made the king angry and very furious; and he commanded to destroy all the wise men
                            of Babylon," the captives of Judah included. But, when Daniel and his fellows prayed, the secret was revealed
                            unto them by their ministering Christ Spirit. Then Arioch took Daniel into the king in haste, saying, I have
                            found a man of the captives of Judah who will interpret thy dream and vision, and show what shall be in the
                            latter days. Daniel saw the march of empires succeeding each other, and their varying characteristics, under the
                            figure of a great image, made of gold, silver, brass, iron, and clay. The last of these, the toes of the feet,
                            repre- senting many kingdoms and republics, instead of one mighty empire like Babylon the Great. And Daniel
                            prophesied, that, in the days of these numerous kings and many republics, shall the God of heaven set up a
                            kingdom which shall never be destroyed, but shall stand for ever, having broken to pieces and displaced all
                            other kingdoms and governments. This power was represented by a little stone cut out of the mountain without
                            hands, by spirit agency, like the tablets of Moses ; spiritual, not natural agency. It smote the image, as David
                            did Goliath, and destroyed it. This dream is certain, and the interpretation sure. Thus the Jewish captives
                            became great men, and rulers over all the provinces of Babylon, by means of Spiritualism, the mother of the
                            sciences, and Daniel was constituted " chief of the governors over the wise men of Babylon." Is not this
                            significant of the final triumph of the Christ Order, when the " knowledge of the Lord shall cover the earth as
                            the waters cover the sea? " Thus ends one of the cycles, by which the great external Babylon, of which Daniel
                            was contemporary, melted away, and was so subdued that Government issued a decree recognizing and acknowledging
                            the Hebrew God as superior to any of the gods of the nations, being Lord of their lords, and God of their gods.
                            The king, Darius, wrote unto all peoples, nations, and languages, that dwell in all the earth, Peace be
                            multiplied unto you. I make a decree, that, in every dominion of my kingdom, men tremble and fear before the God
                            of Daniel; for he is the living God, steadfast forever: his kingdom shall not be destroyed ; his dominion shall
                            be even unto the end; for he delivered Daniel from the power of the lions. Of all the Christ Prophets, none had
                            found that spiritual soul-travel, and incarnated the Christ Spirit into their individual personal character,
                            ascended to the heaven of heavens, penetrated the Holy of holies—the Christ sphere—as John the Revelator of it.
                            He stood in the gift and power of Divine causation. Daniel, like Moses, was on the external providential wheel.
                            His vision related to the history of kings—a succession of empires on the outward plane, the earth— until the
                            final consummation; when all were subjugated by the little stone; and the kingdom and the dominion, under the
                            whole heavens, were given to the people of the saints of the Most High. Daniel begins with the external, and
                            moves towards the spiritual. John begins with the Christ Spirit, and moves outward. He gives the history of the
                            little stone taken from the spiritual mountain without human hands, from the time when it went forth conquering
                            and to conquer, till the kingdoms of this world became the kingdoms of our Lord, and of his Christ. Daniel was a
                            Jew, holding civil office in the literal kingdom of Babylon, attaining and maintaining his position by
                            natural-spiritual power like Moses, and applied to the outer, material elements of earth—its earth and water,
                            its air and fire ; and over the animal creation. John was first a Jew, like Daniel, then a Christian— not of
                            this world, its kingdoms or offices. The visions of John were of the physical, moral, spiritual, and religious
                            history of man as a whole, from the beginning to the end; as such, they included Daniel's prophecies, as the
                            whole includes the parts. Their visions dovetail into one another like body and soul; they duplicate and sustain
                            each other in their minutest details, and in the most wonderful manner. The spiritual manifestations of Moses,
                            although upon a grand scale, and affecting the destiny of thousands of people, infesting a whole nation with
                            lice, and flies, and frogs; killing the fish, by turning the waters into blood; destroying man and beast by fire
                            and hail; or enveloping the Egyptians in darkness that could be felt, were yet secondary to the manifestations
                            through Noah, by which a whole world of humanity was at once destroyed. The spiritual manifestations of the
                            present day reach down to the material elements more as in the days of Daniel, or as in the days of Jesus, who
                            operated so largely upon human bodies as combinations of the elements of earth. While the spiritual manifestions
                            which <pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SKLA.KEH. 59 obtain among the Shakers, are first upon the spirit, affecting the
                            conscience, then upon the soul, removing the causes of physical diseases in the mortal body, inculcating the law
                            of " Go, and sin no more," by correcting all bad habits, and teaching to use all the elements of this present
                            world as not abusing them.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baptism of consecration" TEIform="index"/>Baptism of Consecration</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Sweet inspiration's gilded, wings Are hovering near the earth, And in her tuneful voice there rings The song of a
                            new birth— A birth to higher, holier life, The burden of her song; A birth from rudimental strife, And every
                            groveling wrong. My spirit feels her quickening power In every quivering nerve, Forever, from this burning hour,
                            Humanity to serve; To move in God's eternal peace, In ministries of love; To cause the tears of grief to cease
                            Below me, and above ; To make the how of hope serene; To span the mourner's sky; To rid earth of the monster
                            sin, And every tear to dry. My inner temple first to cleanse, And live a sinless life, Forgiving foes as well as
                            friends, With patience ever rife. Thus peals sweet inspiration's hymn Across the slumbering years, As on our
                            planet's glittering run, Her angel form appears. She calls to you, she calls to me, To let our light so shine,
                            That men shall be compelled to see, And own a power divine. The records of the fading years May leave no history
                            bright, Of all our labors, pains and tears, Or arduous upward flight. What matter, so we work in love. The work
                            God gives us all, We walk serenely, far above Fame's best or basest call. What though our pilgrimage be lone,
                            And little rest we find, Still they are angels of the throne, Who love and bless mankind. A preacher of reform
                            I'll be, And practice what I preach, And purpose of my destiny Sin shall not overreach. So shall I walk heaven's
                            heights sublime, And bless my fellow man, While I remain in rolling time, And in my weakness, can. To leave for
                            aye the fogs of sense, The rudimental plane, And take my final journey hence, Far holier heights to gain. Keed
                            we in starry realms to peer, To find heaven's blest abode ? We walk the heights of heaven here, If loving, pure,
                            and good. Ye saints above, ye saints below, Help me my vows to keep; Henceforward in this path to go, Rich gems
                            for heaven to reap— Rich harvests of the souls of men,' Ripe for the realms above; Rich spoils to take from
                            earth's domain, By works of peace and love.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is religion?" TEIform="index"/>"What is Religion?"</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Bowie, Samantha" TEIform="persName"/>SAMANTHA BOWIE</byline><p TEIform="p">It is an awakening of truth in the soul; a love for God; giving a just sense of one's duty, by opening the eyes
                            of the soul to the great end and purpose of life—redemption. It does not consist of words, thoughts nor actions;
                            but these are governed by the living principle of religion. How admirable is that religious belief, which, while
                            it seems to have in view, not alone the soul's felicity in another world, but effectually secures its happiness
                            in this life ! Religion is being good; and this is being like God. The various names given to religion are
                            subject to much odium; but all admire the fruits of religion in a pure life. Morality is one step towards pure
                            religion. Spirituality is in its advance. All things of real beauty and worth have their origin in pure
                            religion; and nothing will satisfy the soul's demands but practical religion Under the influence of true
                            religion the soul is mild, humane, and only spiritually inclined, working untiringly for humanity. It teaches
                            souls to serve God through the love of a pure life, and not from the fear of his displeasure. There are many
                            creeds, but there is one only religion, and this will make of all humanity, one relationship in spirit, by
                            bringing all into a life that is alone found in Christ—pure, vir- ginal, pentecostal.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who wonders?" TEIform="index"/>"Who Wonders?"</head><p TEIform="p">Hie Springfield (Mass.) Republican does not wonder that some former members and the Shakers parted company; for,
                            from the utterances of the departed, it is of the opinion that they would not grace any moral company, but be a
                            disgrace to an}^ respectable community. " Why go they out from among us ? Because they are not of us; " they
                            want the world, the fleah, and the excitement of perverted sense. These we deny to all, holding union with us.
                            No honorable Shaker has ever failed to merit and receive the respect of those who differed with him in matters
                            of faith ; while a suspicion follows and distrust rests upon those who depart their principles, and practice the
                            world. It is no honor to anj^ sect, to have a seceding Shaker become one of their number, for they leave us for
                            nothing purer, better. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Avesta—fire-worship—baptism" TEIform="index"/>The Avesta—Fire-Worship— Baptism</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. PEEBLES</byline><p TEIform="p">Man, made in the Divine image, is naturally a religious being. In all ages and under all skies, have been found
                            symbols of man's faith and worship. The soul's better aspirations, ever tend heavenward. The most graceful and
                            dignified people that we saw while traveling in the East were the Persians. They do not, as Christians have
                            represented, worship fire, but consider fire a symbol of the sacred fire—the infinite light of the universe.
                            Some of the religious books of the Parsees are exceedingly clear in statement, and spiritual in tendency. To
                            thinkers, the "Avesta " especially is a most valuable work; enabling the student to compare its divine truths
                            with those of the Vedas, the Koran, and the Jewish and Christian scriptures. . The Parsee religion is much older
                            than Judaism, and has been considered by distinguised religionists, a purer faith. Their sacred books, aflame
                            with inspiration, taught the immortality of the soul, the certainty of compensation, and the importance of
                            purity of heart (rather than the sacrificing of animals for sin-offerings) centuries before these doctrines were
                            prevalent among the Jews. At a time when the ancestors of the French and English nations were accustomed to
                            sacrifice human victims to their sanguinary deities, the Parsees taught that heaven was attained only through
                            repentance and purity of life. Though teaching the negative and relative eternity of evil, they also taught the
                            final restoration of all souls, during the progressive period of the resurrection. There have been different
                            opinions as to the age of Zoroaster. The earliest and best authorities upon this subject are the Greek writers.
                            It is a suggestive and remarkable circumstance that all the Greek authors who wrote upon the Magi and the Parsee
                            religion previous to the Christian era, put Zoroaster back to a period 6,000 years B. C. Xanthos, of Lydia, one
                            of the first writers upon the subject, living about 450 B. C, was a younger cotemporary of Darius and Xerxes. He
                            reckons, according to the statement of Diogenes of Laerte in the prooemium to his " Lives and Sayings of Eminent
                            Philosophers," from Zoroaster to the time of Xerxes' expedition to Greece—about 480 B. C—6,000 years. Therefore
                            Zoroaster would have been living at a period about 6,500 B. C. The philosopher Aristotle, and teacher of
                            Alexander the Great, is very positive in his statement. He affirms, according to Pliny (Natural History, xxx, 2)
                            that Zoroaster lived about 6,000 years before the death of Plato, 348 B. C, which would carry us to about 6,350
                            B. C. A similar calculation and statement was made by Eudoxus, distinguished for historic accuracy. Hermippus,
                            of Smyrna, one of the most ancient authorities among the Greeks upon the religion of the Magi, lived about 250
                            B. C, making the Zoroastrian books the study of his life. This Hermippus, according to Pliny, was informed by
                            his teacher, Agonakes, a Magian priest, that Zoroaster lived about 5,000 years before the Trojan war — occurring
                            1,180 B. C. This would take Zoroaster back to 6,180 B. C. The historian, Hermodorus, and other Grecian writers,
                            confirm the above statements. The ancient Greeks all believed that Moses, living several thousand years later
                            than Zoroaster, taught the Jews the magic he had learned in Egypt. It is quite evident that the Egyptians
                            obtained their knowledge of psychology and magic from India and Persia. That there was a Zoroaster living in the
                            time of Hystaspes, Darius' father, is not dis- puted. As Jesus was a common name in <pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 60 THE
                            S H _A. K E H . Syria, so was Zarathustra, Zoroaster, in Persian countries. There were certainly three
                            distinguished persons called Zoroaster, the last living nearly a thousand years before the Christian era. Before
                            us lies a volume rich in the sayings and dogmas of Zoroaster. Listen : '' Come from far and near and hearken to
                            what I shall proclaim. * * * The wise have discovered that this universe is a duality. The maternal cause is
                            double, having received from the Father matter and spirit. * * * Praise the creator Ahura-Mazda, the shining the
                            very shining ! " " I will proclaim as the greatest of all things that one should be good and pure, praising only
                            truth. Ahura-Mazda delights to hear those who speak for and further the good." " All that have been living, and
                            will be living subsist upon the divine bounty. The souls of the pure attain at once to immortality; but the
                            wicked have to undergo age-lasting discipline. Such is the rule of the wise AhuraMazda." " All Hail, to the
                            divine Intelligence, which holds in itself the Word of excellence. All pure beings who were, are and have been,
                            existed through it. The world is of male and female nature. Oh, let us put down our gifts of praise in the
                            dwelling-place of the heavenly singers." " The heavens are a point from the pen of God's Perfection, the world
                            is a bud from the flower of His Beauty, the sun is a spark from the light of His Wisdom, and the sky is a bubble
                            on the sea of His Power. He made lmrrors of the atoms of the world, and threw the reflection of His own face on
                            every atom." The Mendai Ijahi of Persia, were by their countrymen, called Sabians, and considered descendants of
                            Zabii, a pre-historic race. It is very evident that Jews and Greeks derived the principles of their ascetic
                            philosophy from India, through Egypt and Persia. After the Jews had mingled with the .ancient Chaldeans, and the
                            Persian "fire-worshipers," we find traces of the effects of it in the ceremonials of Jewish service, and also in
                            such phrases as these : The "camp of fire" in the appearing to Abraham—the "flame of fire" in the Lord's
                            appearance to Moses—the descent "in fire" to give the law—the devouring of the Sons of Aaron "with fire from the
                            Lord," because they offered in their censers, strange fire—the " pillar of fire " that went before the
                            Israelites through the wilderness—"the fire" that the Prophet Elijah proposed to convert the Prophets of the god
                            Baal; and, " the sacred fire of the Lord," that was ever "burning in Zion." In the apostolic period of
                            Christianity—" our God is a consuming fire"—was a common term, symbolizing the destruction of earthly dross and
                            the necessity of spiritual purification. Fire and water were used typically by all the ancient religionists of
                            the Orient. The East was long the land of sign and symbol. No historian will deny that the old Brahmins of
                            India, baptized at certain seasons in the Ganges for the remission of sins, supposing the waters contained a
                            sanctifying quality. Hence, people flocked to the banks of this divine stream, even from remote Tartary, to be
                            therein baptized. The Egyptians practiced immersion as a religious rite; they also bathed immediately after
                            having touched a swine, considering themselves morally defiled by the contact. For a somewhat different purpose,
                            they were baptized in the Nile as an act of reverence towards its sacred waters. (Herodot. in Euterpe, 47.) The
                            learned Spencer, in his work on the "Rites and Institutions of the Hebrews," says: "Not only was baptism
                            practiced among the Jews, prior to the time of John," but, he assures us, * that they borrowed it as they did
                            circumcision from Pagan nations— for he adds—' among the Egyptians, Persians, Greeks and Romans, baptism by
                            plunging the whole body in water, was customary to purify those who Avere to be initiated into the mysteries of
                            the sacred orders.' " The Christian father, Justin Martyr, not well versed in ancient history, yet seeing, or
                            rather knowing that "baptism was prevalent among the heathens," accounted for the fact, by supposing that the "
                            demons invented it in imita- tion of the Christians." This church father, and others also of that period,
                            claimed in their ignorance, that the Hebrew was the original language of mankind. Max Muller and other noted
                            philologists have completely exploded this idea. The Sanskrit of India, was a lan- guage much older than the
                            Hebrew, as well as more rich and elegant in structure. No thorough scholar will dispute that baptism by
                            immersion, was a very ancient rite— implying in different countries physical and moral cleansing—change of
                            religious faith and practice—" a washing away of sin"—a "putting off of the old man with his deeds," etc. But
                            for a pure, perfect, and sinless individual to have presented himself by the banks of the Ganges, Nile, or
                            flowing Jordan as a candidate for baptism, would have been considered a joke bordering on blasphemy. On\y filthy
                            bodies require outward washings—and only imperfect, sinful men need inner baptismal purifications—the descent
                            and abiding power of the Christ Spirit. This, in the Evangelists, is called the " baptism of the Holy Ghost," or
                            rather Holy Spirit, for Spirit is a much better translation of the Greek pneuma, than " Ghost." The Essenes,
                            sometimes denominated Coenobite Ascetics, true to the principle of "all things in common," practiced the rite of
                            baptism, clothing themselves in white robes after coming " up out of the water." This ceremony, considered by
                            them a symbol of the washing away of a sinful nature, was preceded by a full confession of sin. This
                            cross-bearing people, ever a center of moral force in the East, regarded purity as the only passport to
                            Paradise. And, in harmony with the same inspiration, Jesus taught that "the pure in heart shall see God." It was
                            the custom for Saviours in the Orient, to submit to the ceremony of baptism. India, Egypt, Persia, Phoenicia,
                            Greece, Judea—all ancient nations had their Paradises lost and gained—their Millenniums— their Crosses—and their
                            Saviours too, baptized with the Christ Spirit. The prophel Obadiah, with vision unsealed and soul all aflame
                            with inspiration, said : " Saviours shall come up on Mount Zion." God is no " respecter of persons,
                            nationalities or periods of time." There were many Saviours in the past. The good and the pure, are Saviours
                            to-day. The influence of angel ministry is to elevate humanity. The tendency of the spirtually minded in all
                            ages has been from grossness to refinement—from promiscuity to chas;ity—from chastity to holiness—from holiness
                            ,o divinity. This is "growing in grace," traveling from Adam to Christ.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal obedience" TEIform="index"/>Universal Obedience</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">" He that keepeth the whole law, and yet offendeth in one point, is guilty of all." This doctrine at first view
                            appears unjust, but close examination will show it to be strictly correct. God requires universal and perfect
                            obedience— the whole heart. Now the intentional breach of one of his commandments, as fully proves the want of
                            this is the neglect of all of them. God will, undoubtedly, be merciful to our frailties; but a deliberate and
                            willful act of disobedience cannot pass for lrailty ; it sufficiently shows the state of l.he mind, and proves
                            that the whole spirit of obedience is wanting. A servant being commanded by his master to do ten things all
                            equally just and right, may do nine of them with great exact- ness ; but if he obstinately refuses to do the
                            tenth, he cannot be considered an obedient servant, but a rebel. Indeed, he is just as willful and disobedient
                            as if he had refused to obey all the commandments of his master. His spirit is a spirit of rebellion and not of
                            obedience. There is no good reason to believe that he has done one of the commandments of his master from a pure
                            spirit of love, and simple desire to do his will, since such a motive, would lead him to perform the tenth
                            requirement as faithfully as any or all the rest. Hence, we may be assured that some selfish end, and not purely
                            the love of his master— not a true spirit of obedience—prompted him to do what he did; and that, therefore, he
                            had no true obedience, because he was destitute of true love.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How do we do it?" TEIform="index"/>How do We do It ?</head><p TEIform="p">The New YorJc Tribune lately reported that some seceding Shaker was lecturing against the protective measures
                            instituted among the Shakers, upon shaking hands, kissing, etc., at the same time dilating upon the beauty and
                            necessity of celibacy. It is refreshing to us to have The Tribune " give it as our opinion, that when our
                            friends, the Shakers, yield the point of kissing, celibacy will naturally go next." When those, inimical to us,
                            complain of our celibacy, we are led to remember how much we have suffered upon the charge of secret corruption,
                            and since it is not a question, but a charge, how we live, we force the question, " How do we do it ?" When any
                            attempt Christian celibacy and succeed, without many simple abstainences and effective crosses, then we will
                            admit being over scrupulous, and extravagant crossbearers. *</p></div2><pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Past, present and future" TEIform="index"/>Past, Present and Future</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">The longevity of some of the ancients, who attained to the great age of five, six and nine hundred years, seems a
                            long period of time; especially, if we look upon the race of men, as more perfect then, than at the present
                            time. We speak of the blissful Eden state; of man's innocence when he came from the hands of the Creator. This
                            is well, if rightly understood. The innocence of childhood is beautiful; but it cannot be trusted like the
                            positive innocence of mature years, gained by trial, and battling against temptation in its multifarious forms.
                            There are persons with us to-day, who recollect distinctly when sailing vessels, or stage coaches were the
                            swiftest modes of transit from continent to continent and over kingdoms and countries. Future generations will
                            look upon those modes of traveling, somewhat as we look upon historic records of the long past. And since
                            science has developed the power of steam, and the intelligence of man has systematized, tamed and made it
                            subservient to his use, the desires of people to travel and visit foreign lands, have become so intensified,
                            that we should need some hundreds of years to accomplish our designs if required to return to the modes of
                            travel which our grandsires possessed. If we look upon the early history of our race, as in a childhood state,
                            undeveloped, but possessing all the germs of perfect men and women, who, by progressive degrees, under proper
                            guidance and instruction, would attain under the full stature of manhood, progressing in natural law pertaining
                            to the rudimental sphere in which we live, and also learning more of the higher spiritual laws which relate to
                            the soul's welfare that must guide and control it in the life beyond, then we can understand why the ancients
                            needed so much longer time than the present generation to accumulate knowledge which, in a large degree, was
                            bounded by their own personal experience; while we have the benefit of the accumulated experience of past ages
                            added to our own. The progressive degrees of development have been under the control of teachers adapted to the
                            condition of the people, and their powers of receptivity. Hence, the word of the Lord at one time, was not the
                            same as at another; not that God, or truth changed, but lessons were given, as the people were able to receive.
                            Wise parents in nature do not force a knowledge of the arts and sciences upon their children whose minds are
                            weak and tender; but they give them such mental food as they can digest. Thus has it been with the Universal
                            Father and Mother of all intelligences. How clearly we see this law in operation in the first epoch of bible
                            history concerning man ; whether that history be correct, or not, the rule and deductions to be drawn therefrom,
                            are equally true. Their first necessity was to learn to provide sustenance for the physical part; how to cul-
                            tivate the soil, and gain an honest living ; anc in obedience to natural law and physical truth they received
                            great blessings. The natural srecedes the spiritual—that is the law. When ;hey were sufficiently developed,
                            lessons were 2;iven by degrees, relating to the immortality of the soul. Their condition was not the effect of
                            violated law, but they were immature, [t would have been an impossibility for them to have received direct
                            communication from Deity, as much so as for an infant to understand the science of astronomy. Tutelary deities
                            were appointed to preside over them, who were not of the highest order of spirits, yet, so far progressed, that
                            they were capable of imparting all the knowledge and truth necessary for the time being. The Angels Avho first
                            began to minister to the people, were so near to earth, that it was difficult to decide whether they were
                            veritable men or disembodied spirits. But, as the people grew and waxed strong, the ministrations to them were
                            more spiritual and interior; and occasionally a ray of light from the inner spheres, which we call the
                            Christ-heavens, where spirits dwell who are clothed with power to baptize souls with resurrection life, shone
                            upon them. Only Prophets of the highest order were capable of communing with spirits from the inner heavens ;
                            but they were sought unto by Kings and Princes. The King of Israel at one time, called four hundred Prophets
                            together, that he might enquire of the Lord through them. The god of the Jews was a warring god; and he
                            purposely put a lie in the mouths of those Prophets to deceive the blood-thirsty King; and only one was found
                            who prophesied truly, for which he was hated and consigned to prison. The more truth the Prophets possessed, the
                            higher their Mediumship, the more they were feared, hated and persecuted. Thus has it ever been. Truth, and its
                            defenders, have had to battle against error, as the prison, rack, and flame would attest. At length, under the
                            law of progress, Prophets of the higher Order, were multiplied in the land. The Christ Spirit,—" the Rock,"
                            which followed them in the wilderness, visited them and touched their hearts with the fire of inspiration and
                            stirred the deep feelings of their souls ; and in a vision they saw the beauties of a coming day, and prophesied
                            of a coming Messiah, who would be anointed King of Saints; and his throne be established in their midst, and he
                            would dwell and walk with them. Thus, from age to age, the generations of men were prepared for higher degrees
                            of spiritual truth; and in due time, Jesus the Nazarene, according to prophecy, was anointed from the
                            Christ-heavens; and through the Medium of the Sonship, the Everlasting Father was revealed. And as Jesus became
                            a Son of God, to as many as received him in his Father's name, he also baptized them with the same spirit and
                            they became sons of God; all brethren of one spiritual famity. He gave to his disciples divine gifts, and
                            empowered them to transmit the same to others. To Peter, he gave the keys of the Kingdom (the gift of divine
                            revelation) ; that was a new epoch in the history of our race, when the Bridegroom came forth from his secret
                            chamber. As it took centuries to fill the former epoch and prepare the way for the advent of the male Messiah,
                            so also centuries passed before a way was opened for the Bride, the female Messiah to come forth from her closet
                            where she had been concealed from mortal view. In the first Christian era, a church was founded upon a true
                            basis, i. e., a Virgin Life, community of Goods, and Non-resistance. But there was so little love to just
                            principles, and the love of earthly idols so strong, that the people " gave their power unto the beast," and
                            Anti-Christ dethroned the true Christ, and himself sat in the temple of God for ages persecuting the saints.
                            Civil and ecclesiastic powers combined to make war with the followers of the lowly Jesus, and a bloody reign
                            ensued. While we bestow honor and praise upon those who embraced the Christian faith, for their firm adherence
                            thereto, and willingness to endure torture, imprisonment and death, rather than violate -their highest
                            convictions of right, may we not give some mitigating con- siderations to their persecutors ! They were
                            defending the religion of their fathers, which justified war, and taught the law of retaliation, " an eye for an
                            eye." The traditions which had been handed down to them were as sacred to them as the Christian religion was to
                            its new converts. Viewed from our standpoint, in the light of the nineteenth century, they are not only
                            reprehensible, but nearly allied to demons, deserving the tortures of the Calvinistic hells ! But there is a
                            tribunal higher than man, where all things will be weighed and duly balanced. Would not the same intolerant
                            spirit, even in this age of progress, again lift its head and stretch forth its persecuting hand, if there was
                            not a controlling and balancing power? Let the religious Pharisees—the learned Rabbins of our time, who so
                            devoutly desire to see the name of God and Christ placed in the National Constitution, succeed in the attempt,
                            and they would show us how the Sabbath breaker should be punished ! It would require the strength of many
                            Washingtons, Paines and Jeffersons combined, to stay the hand of persecution, and set things right. Would it not
                            be well to have an amendment to that proposition, and let woman's name be inserted instead ? Let her voice be
                            heard, and her influence felt in the councils of the nation ; and let God and Christ be enthroned in the human
                            heart, quickening the conscience and guiding it in all the practical duties of life. When woman finds her proper
                            place, she will help to frame the laws to which she is amenable and by which she is bound, and plead the cause
                            of the down-trodden of her own sex. She will help to inaugurate her own rulers, and cease to be the slave of
                            man's passions. Then, may we not hope when the law of chastity is broken, guilt and shame will rest where it
                            justly belongs ? Now man assumes the right to allure woman into vicious paths, there to leave her despoiled,
                            helpless and hopeless, while he walks defiantly away to his companions, wTho receive him into their fashionable
                            circles without a rebuke ! The .woman is an outcast from respectable society, left to drag out a miserable
                            existence, while he <pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 62 THE SHAKER. is honored ! Shall this state of things always continue
                            ? Nay ! as God is just, an end will come. The powers of the heavens are moving, and justice will arise and shake
                            terribly the earth in this respect! A light is dawning upon our earth which gives promise of a day of freedom
                            for woman. The strong influence of the Dove Messenger sent from the bosom of the Eternal Mother in Deity, who a
                            century ago called upon a few prepared souls to enter into the secret tabernacle of the Most High, and hide in
                            that Pavilion which has been guarded by the Cherubims, called the most Holy Place, because it is the house of
                            the virgin character, is felt far and near to-day. That spirit has been working like leaven to open a way for
                            woman to escape from her physical, moral and spiritual servitude. And at the present time a voice is heard: "
                            Woman shall be free as man is free ! Let him or her who violates the law of chastity, bear their own
                        iniquity."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>Faith</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">" Believe in the Lord your God individually; so shall ye be established in your organiza- tion." Believe his
                            Prophets, in and as an organization ; so shall ye prosper and grow, " increasing with the increase of God,"—of
                            Truth Divine,—in your collective capacity, as a living body of Christ, ministered unto by Christ Spirits, those
                            of the Resurrection Order, who never touched the generative life in human beings in the past, except to prophesy
                            of its future death ; and who never touch it in the present, except to kill it, and to elevate the powers and
                            faculties involved therein to higher uses, on a spiritual plane—the Resurrection Order. After Jesus passed
                            beyond John, who, as a Jewish priest, had been his Elder under the Jewish Law, and was baptized with the Christ
                            elements, he " trod the wine-press alone," like Adam or Noah, or Abraham, or Moses had done in his day and
                            Dispensation; and as all godly Reformers have ever done in the degrees of the Dispensation in which they stood
                            and labored. Principles are eternal, and Prophecy is of no private interpretation, but is of universal
                            application to humanity. Thenceforth Jesus had no Elder on the earth, unless he came short of the glory of God
                            in any one of the planes of progress in the natural order; then he would have been amenable to the Elders of
                            that plane or order. As " the Resurrection," he was ministered unto by the Angels of the Order of God that is
                            eternal in the heaven of heavens.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker in state prisons" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker in State Prisons</head><p TEIform="p">Friend David Sargent has been visiting the Shirley Shakers, and writes us his impressions. He is a man of keen
                            sensibility, deep convictions of the right, and appreciates the life-labors of the Shakers to be " the oest
                            illustration of Christianity on the face of the earth.1' Friend Sargent superintends Massachusetts' State prison
                            at Charlestown, and it must have been a genuine relief to his care-worn soul and overtaxed body, to visit a
                            people who are not only physically and spiritually free, but are daily crucifying that which would make them
                            otherwise. May the Shakers, that monthly go to State prisons, work out a reformatory influence .with their in'
                            mates; and we would not object, nor be surprised, if many of these preceded in the heavenly race the multitudes
                            of bigoted pharisees. *</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian's sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>The Christian's Sacrifice</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Dodson, John" TEIform="persName"/>JOHN DODSON,—THE AQUILLA</byline><p TEIform="p">The gospel light began to dawn Upon Columbia's happy land, And many gladly hailed the morn, "While more aloof did
                            boldly stand. Aquilla and Priscilla's cot Stood near the ocean's surges wild; Peace and contentment was their
                            lot, They had but one, one only child. The gospel trumpet reached their ears, And wakened up a sense of sin,
                            Producing doubts, producing fears, They found all was not right within. They found they were from God estranged—
                            That they'd been traveling into loss; From sin's broad path they now must change, To follow Christ, and bear his
                            cross. The testimony, clear and plain, Which unto them was ushered in, Was, Christ has now appeared again, To
                            save his people from all sin. The sanctuary to make clean, Immersed in Jordan's rolling main, Made fit to drink
                            salvation's streams For sin, no more to thirst again. Confess, repent, the dross remove, Before the soul can
                            entrance flnd To Zion's ark of peace and love, Or swreet contentment clothe the mind. All sin the soul must now
                            forsake; All carnal ties must now break down; This sacrifice it now must make, Or fail to win salvation's crown.
                            From sin, from sorrow now released, Walking in truth's straight narrow way, Aquilla and Priscilla's peace, No
                            pen nor tongue can now portray. By love's pure river, trees of life Stand spreading free, and fair to view;
                            Their leaves heal envy, hatred, strife, Their lovely fruits the strength renew. But, walking in this narrow way,
                            A goal is reached ; they must be tried, The voice of God they must obey, And ofler up their only child. At this
                            the mother shed a tear, The father's heart athwart recoiled; " Can God of love be so severe, To part from us our
                            only child ? '' " O mother, dry those fruitless tears, Father, stand firm," the daughter cries, " The God of
                            mercy 's not severe, This only breaks the carnal ties. The gospel day no more requires The blood of bulls, nor
                            goats, nor men, But selfish animal desires Upon the cross must now be slain. " Like Jephtha's daughter, I will
                            not Lament for my virginity; But be contented with my lot, And live a life of purity. In heavenly joys I will
                            increase, All vile affections prompt repel; I'll live in love, and joy, and peace, •So parents dear, farewell,
                            farewell.'' Kow when this parting scene was o'er The parents found all worked for good ; Their sun grew brighter
                            than before, On higher, holier ground they stood; No selfish passions filled their breasts, But universal love
                            did reign. They felt for all who were oppressed With sin and sorrow, grief and pain. With faith in Christ, their
                            lead, before, They press along their path with joy; They to the world look back no more, But prayer and praise
                            their thoughts employ. They're verging to the heavenly land, Ready the summons to obey; Upon its borders joyous
                            stand, While angels beckon them away.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans frequently has an attack of admiration for The Golden Age. In a recent letter to this office,
                            he tried to excite our jealousy, we suppose, by enclosing the following paragraphs, but he failed : The Golden
                            Age Is pure, free from love stories, which corrupt the young. Its columns are open to all representative
                            writers, who can condense their thoughts. It concentrates the living ideas or issues of the Age, being the organ
                            of Progress for the day or time. Is independent, possesses strong convictions; impartial in criticism; not
                            fearing even its best friends, but ' 'hears before it strikes." If all who read The Shaker subscribe for The
                            Golden Age, they will, thereby, assist in actualizing it.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker?" TEIform="index"/>What Shall I do to be a Shaker ?</head><p TEIform="p">At present, this is not a very popular question, but is nearly as much so as its syn- onym—" What shall I do to
                            be saved ?" In answering either, we answer both; for if we are saved from doing wrong, we are in the enjoyment
                            of Shakerism—if we are genuine Shakers, then are we saved. Shakerism purposes an end of sinful works : nor this
                            only, for much that is good on the earthly plane, it rejects as useless to Angelic life. Not only does it save
                            individuals from the commission of sin, but resurrects them to an exceeding godliness, than is possible while
                            living on the earthly animal plane. It asks none to forsake any earthly good, until it presents somethingbetter
                            of a heavenly nature, and thus it teaches souls to rise/row earth to heaven. We claim that it is radical
                            Christianity. That it takes hold of our lives, moulds them anew, just as it reformed the Jewish nature of Jesus
                            into a model for all Christians. The most radical Shakerism is simple, unadorned Christianity. The first is a
                            monstrous system to "worldly appreciation; but so is the last in its genuineness. What is popularly called
                            Christianity does not resemble Shakerism at all; but what is called Shakerism, is a fae simile of thorough
                            Christianity. Radical means root; and that which is Christian at its root, will inevitably produce Shakerism in
                            its every branch. Let any Church remodel its creed in accordance with the Christ life—the pattern—and who will
                            deny that its believing congregation would become a genuine Shaker Society ? And wherein would this congregation
                            materially differ from the hosts of heaven with whom it hopes soon to consolidate ? Is the prayer— " Thy will be
                            done on earth, as it is done in heaven," impossible of realization ? We know it is not. Let any individual
                            attempt to live as nearly angel-like as he conceives an Angel's life to be, would he not resemble a Shaker in
                            his daily practice ? Let him conscientiously investigate Angelhood ; compare or contrast it with his desires,
                            inclinations, passions; and what is the result? Do the Angels eat, drink and are clothed ? Certainly. But they
                            are <pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. 63 very unlike this animal—murdering, bibulous, and fashion-loving race.
                            Contrast what we know of the Angel diet with the same of the gluttonous worldling, or even of the commonplace
                            Christian ! What an opportunity for improvement. Do the Angels use tobacco, imbibe the ardent, and dress a la
                            Eugenie 1 Some may, but they are not Christian Angels; nor will good imitations of, present such features. Let
                            us pursue. Arriving at mature years, those "of the world3' marry; and who in the world will object to this ! Our
                            question is, how will this compare with heav- enly practice ? How will the auditors of Ward Beecher and of most
                            Revs, compare with the characters, as seen by the Revelator standing " with the Lamb on Mount Zion ?" How would
                            a Shaker practice compare ? How will the paraphernalia and fashionable gew-gaws of Chapin's, Cuyler's, St.
                            Paul's or Trinity's congregations compare with the uniform of " those who have come up out of great tribulation
                            ? Let us be reasonable. Some believe, and teach sin to be a necessity. Is there sin in heaven ? In heaven or
                            earth will there be any iniquity ? If heaven is ever realized here, which must change, the Angel life or the
                            worldly life ? Is not their difference sin ? Christianity was the introduction of " thy will be done on earth;"
                            and Jesus, in obedience to Christ principles was the pattern of the new life. Whoso lives as he did, will bear
                            the cross; will not sin, will not pervert, corrupt, nor be aught but heavenly. The same causes that made Jesus
                            what he became, will regenerate us into the same results. These causes or principles will be like waves of
                            progressive life, each advancing the individual adopting it, into an increased, heavenly altitude, or like the
                            reappearing of the Christ Spirit in various cycles, making demands of us of further renunciation of the worldly
                            and a deeper adoption of, and consecration to the heavenly. Do you ask : " What you must do to be a Shaker ? "
                            In the usual, simple manner, I will answer: 1. Seek for a Christian conviction of, and sorrow for sin. Confess
                            every wrong action, and renounce every evil consideration. Repent—solemnly promise to do so no more, and
                            faithfully fulfill the obligation. Settle all indebtedness; if you have at any time wronged an individual, seek
                            to repair the injury and accomplish reconciliation. 2. You are now a candidate for the acceptance of the Christ
                            Spirit, and adoption of the Christ Life. Be as a Virgin henceforth; abstain from fleshly lusts and from
                            lascivious thoughts. Had you a wife ? Now use her as a sister. Is she unwilling ? The Spirit never concedes to
                            the flesh—stand firm. Are you persecuted? retaliate not, bear and forbear. Have you property ? Use this for the
                            care of your unbelieving family. If your family is one in faith with you, consecrate your earthly goods where
                            you and they have consecrated your physical lives, and from which cause you are enjoying a foretaste of an
                            eternal pentecost. Yours is now an hundred fold, and in the life that now is, you are experiencing the entrance
                            upon a new and eternal existence. Yours is an exceeding peace. " The world " will seem and really be beneath
                            you; your companions of yore will not interest you, and the life of the " old creation," you will verily hate.
                            You are becoming a "new creature." The life of the flesh renounced; a virgin character pronounced and adopted.
                            All vicious habits rejected ; cleanly, temperate and healthful substitutes accepted—you are a Shaker in the
                            first degree of Angelhood—be faithful, be patient, the next cycle will open upon you. Here is where all true
                            Shakers should aim to arrive in this life—and many do. Others arrive where, in accordance with their
                            renunciation of the worldly, and agreeable to their consecration to the cross of the Spirit—if these aie much,
                            so is their gain; if not much, they are trifling with their gospel call, and tampering with inferior desires—and
                            the consequences too often are, the backslider's career! Have we advised anything that Jesus did not, or would
                            not, were he here ? Is there any unchristian performance recommended or the neglect of any Christian duty
                            advised ? Have we proposed the abandonment of any relation that can continue in the heavens, or of any practice
                            but " perishes with the using ?" For wars of nations and of households, do we not give in exchange, peace ? For
                            the generative life of the world do we not offer an Angelic resurrection ? In the extinction of the sexual works
                            of the flesh, do we not present the fraternal relations of the sexes as found in Christ ? What becomes of the
                            selfishness that was concentrated in self or found recognition under the title of Mine ? It is diversified over
                            a very large household and is mine no longer, but ours. What takes its place ? An ambition to be an unreserved
                            worker for the good of souls ; for their salvation, even as we have been and are saved from the commission of
                            sin. No more reliance upon the physical death of Jesus, but upon the beautiful practice of his life—a life to
                            God, and a death unto the world of sin. This is Shakerism. This is Christianity. This is the way we become
                            Shakers, experience salvation, and enjoy a life eternal. Thus we are seeking and learning more truth ; and thus
                            we measurably enjoy here, the Angel life—Christ's life. " And let him that heareth say, Come! and partake of the
                            bread and waters of life freely," in our heavenly Father's and Mother's home. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth, faith, and reason, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Truth, Faith and Reason.—No. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">t is a fixed and immutable law of the generative order, to multiply and divide—to keep up a continued series of
                            successive separations and separate interests. The fixed and immutable law of the Christ Order, is aggregation,
                            " gathering together, uniting in one all in heaven and earth in Christ." (Eph. i, 10.) "To be carnally minded is
                            death, to be spiritualty minded is life." In this aphorism, Paul again sets forth the eternal antagonism of the
                            flesh and spirit; it is but the utterance of a fixed, immutable and eternal truth; a truth which every one who
                            has been made alive in Christ, knows just as well as Paul. The antagonism between the flesh and spirit does not
                            take place in the air, but in the human soul, and every spiritually minded man knows that this conflict is
                            irreconcilable—knows that his carnal, lustful, generative nature, is not subject to the laws of God in Christ,
                            or in the regenerative order, neither, indeed, can be— knows he must keep up an unceasing warfare against it, at
                            the peril of his spiritual life, until it is subdued. "If ye be risen with Christ, seek those things which are
                            above, where Christ dwells." Those who are subjects to this resurrection— those who have risen with Christ and
                            lived in his sphere which is "above" the flesh, " neither marry nor are given in marriage." They are " children
                            of the resurrection " order, exalted with Christ above the generative work. Be cautious of forming or adopting
                            systems. When men become wedded to a system, either of their own or another's, their minds are liable to be so
                            biased, that they will desire to bend everything into conformity to it; and in their eagerness to support the
                            system, they lose sight of truth. Truth is a unit. No one truth can be opposed to another truth. And one truth
                            harmonizes with every other truth, therefore, any system or part of a system opposed to one single truth, is
                            opposed to all truth, and utterly foundationless and false. As light is pleasant to the eye, so is truth to the
                            understanding. The Catholic Church requires her members to believe in Transubstantiation, contrary to the
                            evidence of their senses, and to renounce opinions as heretical without any proof of their error; but all such
                            requirements are as unwise as they are tyrannical and unjust, because it is impossible to comply with them. If a
                            man is required to sacrifice his rational faculty in order to salvation, what will he have left worth saving ?
                            He will be no better than a maniac or ourang-outang. He that requires a man to believe mere assertion against
                            the clear convictions of his own understanding, demands the surrender of his rationality, and would rob him of
                            the chief attribute of man. Nothing fears investigation but mistrustful bigotry or determined ignorance. He who
                            feels confident of the rectitude of his opinions and actions, fears not investigation. The fear of
                            investigation, or of being investigated, are certain marks of bigotry or dishonesty. Faith founded in ignorance,
                            is always exposed to the assails of light and truth, and therefore constantly in danger. The better one
                            understands the why and the wherefore of a theory, the less liable he is to have his faith shaken. He who
                            through bigotry and ignorance builds on falsehood, is under continual necessity of guarding against the
                            approaches of light and truth. The most effectual way to shake off unbelief is to demonstrate truth to the
                            understanding. He who goes about to divest himself of unbelief by violently shaking his body, will be about as
                            successful, as he who should try to satiate his hunger by running a foot race. <pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 64= THE
                            SPI^LKER. He can swallow incredible things whose interest prompts the resolve not to be choked by any thing. He
                            that is most positive in his opinions may nevertheless be positively mistaken. I am tired of systems and system
                            mongers; I desire to know nothing—to feel nothing but gospel simplicity—to believe nothing but pure truth. He
                            that loves truth for its own sake, likes it best in its pure unadorned simplicity. Great names, high sanctions,
                            or even mighty miracles, if they do not indeed detract from its merits, can add nothing to its value.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical death versus future life" TEIform="index"/>Physical Death versus Future Life</head><p TEIform="p">The World's Crisis very sharply and unchristianly criticises Otis Sawj^er's " Shaker Cemeteries" in June Shaker;
                            also Bro. Peebles' remarks in same number. It very plainly asserts that Spiritualism and Shakerism are not of
                            God, but of him who fathers all the iniquities of the world since first he whispered in Eve's ear what she
                            should never have known. The Crisis is stirred to this because we believe and know of a future exist-
                            ence—immortality. It knows only of the grave and its dead ; the resurrection has not occurred to its Editor and
                            numerous readers. But as a dead tree compares with a living and fruitful one—as a dead man and a dead God
                            contrast with men of life and a God eternal— so do the teachings and philosophy of the physical resurrection of
                            dead, and twice dead bodies compete with the religion of life which comforts us that our loved ones are not, and
                            never were dead; but that "their spirits are living, in beauty they are blooming" on the eternal shore. Were
                            there any truthful philosophy in "an irresistible force striking an immovable object," then might the "
                            irresistibility " of The Crisis, affect the " immovableness " of The Shaker, upon the truth of immortality. A
                            few days will decide this point to any who now live and have doubts. But it is a curious fact that Second
                            Advents do die; for in all the spirit peregrinations we ever heard of, not one of them has been found in the
                            spirit world ! We will not say The Crisis is of the devil; but we do infer it is blinded by the flesh, is
                            leading souls in the dark, and needs the enlightenment and resurrection of the Spirit which we have been favored
                            with. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Disappointed" TEIform="index"/>Disappointed</head><p TEIform="p">Elder J. B. Vance, in an address at Troy, stated that many of the requirements of Shaker Communism appeared like
                            the lions in the way of Bunyan's Pilgrim; and which exist more in the imagirtation than in anything else, being
                            dissolved by attack, into thin air. Just so ; much that we dreaded, becomes our delight to engage in. Some fear
                            the Confessional—yet the relief obtained therefrom compensates the soul so much, that it is never relinquished
                            by the faithful nor its absence desired. Some dread the Dance: One individual said, " he would like to unite,
                            but he could not agree to dance, particularly on the Sabbath." This being his only objection, he was excused,
                            with the proviso that we should not be compelled to keep out from the dance. He having no fears of this, "set
                            out" to be a Shaker. But a short time elapsed, before he broke into the circle, and was the most zealous dancer
                            in the room ! It is difficult for us to get individuals to wear their own apparel; whereas ours presented an
                            appearance too plain, before they united. Just so are individuals disappointed in their fears of what they must
                            need do to become members of Shaker Societies. We say, if you will live the life, we care little what your
                            theology is, what your fears are, desires have been, or hopes may be. The spirit of oneness will prevail, where
                            all are united in the purpose to maintain a pure, virginal relation, as is found only in Christ. Only let an
                            individual con- fess all their sins on the start in the race, and keep a conscience undefiled, and we predict
                            all their fears will be turned into pleasurable disappointments. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paradox of Jesus" TEIform="index"/>The Paradox of Jesus</head><p TEIform="p">Calvin Green, of Mt. Lebanon, once said that " Jesus was the Sarcastus of his day ! " Reference in this was had
                            to " Go tell that fox, etc." But where can a greater, apparent inconsistency be found, than "He that saves his
                            life shall lose it; but he that loses his life shall find it ? The pronoun it, apparently refers to the same
                            life; and only as the two lives of humanity are understood—the natural or earthly life, and the spiritual or
                            Christ life—this paradox is not and cannot be comprehended. Would you gain the Christ life, you must lose the
                            carnal, Adamic, generative practice that is opposed to Christ. Would you save this, then be not disappointed if
                            you find that you have not found Christ. Though paradoxical, this is one of the most beautiful sayings of Jesus,
                            and is worthy of a whole life's study. Probably no passage in scripture is generally less understood, and at the
                            same time of greater value when comprehended. As in this saying so much is enclosed, so let our lives " be hid
                            in Christ." *</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is a beautiful piece of music attached to 'Spirit Prophecy'..." TEIform="index"/>There is a beautiful piece of music attached to 'Spirit Prophecy'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is a beautiful piece of music attached to "Spirit Prophecy.'' Believers desirous of obtaining the same, may
                            address our young and noble Prophet Elder, Thomas Smith. Canaan Corners, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker communism" TEIform="index"/>Shaker communism
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Shaker Communism" has not yet arrived from England. When it does we will notify. All orders for the same, may
                            be addressed to this Office, or to Elder F. W. Evans. See list of Publications. </p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are in receipt of several letters from individuals who ask..." TEIform="index"/>We are in receipt of several letters from individuals who ask...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We are in receipt of several letters from individuals who ask, among other questions, concerning our position on
                            the wearing or non-wearing of the beard. We answer, that for uniformity, we shave smoothly twice or thrice a
                            week. This is our present custom. We attach no religious importance to it, other than union of action. That we
                            are physiologically wrong, many of us have no doubt; and that we shall eventually change present habit, we doubt
                            still less ; but until there can be a unanimous voice in the change, we shall abide present usage. It is a
                            nonessential to the salvation of the soul from present sins, only as it affects the body seriously by shaving;
                            and when individuals remove greater difficulties in their path to righteousness, the shaving or not shaving the
                            beard will assume less proportions. Let us be alive to whatever is progress in the right direction only.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit prophecy" TEIform="index"/>Spirit Prophecy</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>THOMAS SMITH</byline><p TEIform="p">Rivers of waters shall open in Zion ; And thousands shall seek 10 be cleansed therein— '¦ Save us, oh, save us !
                            " I hear them crying, "From the curses of Babylon, from darkness and sin!' Away with yovtr doubting, ye feeble
                            and fainting! Away with your fears for the Zion of God! The Lord in his infinite wisdom is guiding The feet of
                            the wanderer to Zion's blest fold.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A religious journal tells its readers, spitefully, that..." TEIform="index"/>A religious journal tells its readers, spitefully, that...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A religious journal tells its readers, spitefully, that it costs the heathen Chinese #400,000,000 annually to run
                            their religion, " whatever it is." That, the Chinaman might reply, is the strange part of this religious
                            interest. The Christians, before settling among themselves what Christianity is, hasten over to conrert China
                            whatever it is ; whereas, if they knew Christianity and Bhuddism as well as the Chinese know Bhuddism, they
                            might perhaps admire the wisdom (politically at least) which liberally spends so much money on a system of
                            religion that can keep three or four hundred millions of people whole centuries as a unit, without rebellion or
                            schism, giving out of itself an educational system which faithfully reaches one hundred per centum of the
                            population, and to which, to our sorrow be it said, the best Christian school system is but a feeble and as yet
                            rather ineffective copy. It ought to be a good religion, which is worth $400,000,000 a year to keep up, and, no
                            doubt, the Chinese are proud that no where but in China can a religion be found which is valued even half that
                            high.—American Land and Law Advisor. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dnnlavy's Manifesto .... Millennial Church .... Compendium of Shakerism Three
                            Discourses on United Interests Shaker Communism—Evans Tracts free, where postage is paid. m 25 1 25 1 0* 0 50 0
                            50 0 50</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Columbia
                            Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee,
                            West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham,
                            Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " Jonas Kutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass.
                            " B. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co.. N. H. " John B.
                            Vance, Alfred, Shakers. York Co., Me. " Joseph Brackett, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas.
                            Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen
                            Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co.,
                            Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>