<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2301" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">23</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18930101" TEIform="date">January 1893</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="23" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>JANUARY. MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. VOL. XXIII. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                        whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. Canterbury,
                        N. H. 1893. THE <pb id="p2"/> THE MANIFESTO. CONTENTS. Li^ht on Our Destiny, Page. 3 Mercy Seat. . 4 The Old Year,
                        (i Economy, . " Ltter,—I). Orcutt. it Without Fault, Passing Moments, 10 Planting Seed, 11 Gently, ... " Kilitorial,
                        .... 1-2 The Best we Can, 14 Notes About Home, I.") Cheerfulness, ¦ ¦20 Tempering Process, ¦21 (irowing Right, 22
                        Deaths, j» Kind Words, >> Music,—Life Eternal, ¦2:5 Books & Papers, 24</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="none"
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. VOL. XXIII. "Cast thy bread upon the waters; for thou shalt
                            find it after many days."—Eccl. XL, 1. East Canterbury, N. H. 1893.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
                    --><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light on our destiny" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT ON OUR DESTINY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">I am greatly interested in an article in the August Number of the Manifesto over the
                            signature of A. J. C. The writer puts the following query (viz.) "Blest as we are with a
                            three-fold life (or a three-fold manifestation of the same life) physical, mental and
                            spiritual, who is able to solve the problem of its equal growth?" And again "Do we not use
                            so much time and strength in the maintenance of the body that the mind is crippled and the
                            soul undeveloped?" Momentous questions indeed! But is there no remedy ? For we must confess
                            that we do just as is intimated in the queries. I believe there is an all-potent remedy for
                            the difficulty therein named. A part of this remedy may be indicated in two words (viz.)
                            Systematic Arrangement. In further elaboration of this subject, I may say it is hardly
                            possible to conceive how much time can be saved by a systematic allotment of time and
                            duties. Suppose we should resolve that as twenty-four is divisible by three (the departments
                            of our being, assigned by the interesting writer) we will labor with our hands for eight
                            hours faithfully each day—to procure our physical necessities—eight hours for mental and
                            spiritual improvement and recreation—and eight hours for sleep. This is quite possible to
                            bring about by scientific and systematic allotment of our duties and several avocations. But
                            first of all, can a luxurious, or (even voluptuous) method of living, consisting of flesh of
                            animals, fish, eggs and butter be made by working eight hours a day ? Nay, it cannot.
                            Because the expense of feeding and rearing a cow a pig or horse in the way of food, shelter
                            and attention has been estimated to be about eight times that of a human being fed on
                            vegetables, farina and fruits. The corn necessary to raise a pig will go several hundred
                            per. ct. farther in sustaining the life of a man, than the pork, after it is ready for use,
                            but thank God the pig is no longer allowed to be eaten among Believers. This pig estimate
                            will answer for an aggregate for most four-footed beasts. Now if we wish for less toil to
                            get a mere livelihood let us not forget that "we can't have the cake and eat it both."
                            Neither can we afford to be foolishly overstocked with clothing. I recollect a <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. long time ago, I was appointed to take a schedule of the pairs
                            of shoes each member owned. I was more than astonished ! I was utterly confounded. Some had
                            as high as sixteen pairs. What they wanted of so many I could not conceive. I have known
                            persons possessed of one and even two large chests full of clothes and yet never allow any
                            opportunity to get more, pass unimproved. An equal development of the triune phase of our
                            existence is utterly impossible under this extravagant and inconsistent regime. Again, how
                            many things go to waste from inexcusable carelessness! Without a vigorous retrenchment in
                            all these things by which the expenses of physical life might be prodigiously curtailed, the
                            fond hope of a life more in accordance with the laws our triune existence will, I fear have
                            to be abandoned for the present, and until we have traveled through another decade of sorrow
                            and unrest. A word or two about the systematic economy of time. I have known school teachers
                            to complain that they could not find time in a single day to teach spelling, reading and
                            arithmetic and possibly geography. Now I have taught school for a great many years but I
                            never had any difficulty in finding time to teach spelling, reading, writing, grammar,
                            arithmetic, algebra, physiology, chemistry, and one year added geometry and German. Perhaps
                            you will say I must have crowded out recess entirely—Not so, but instead of allowing recess
                            for fifteen minutes only, I allowed it for half an hour twice each day. It was all done
                            merely by systematic ordering of time, and I have not the least doubt but the same time
                            saving policy would work the same good results in regard to all our duties and various
                            avocations. But I do not wish to further trespass upon the space of the Manifesto or the
                            patience of the reader and so I will stop. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mercy seat" TEIform="index"/>THE MERCY SEAT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo G. Hollister</byline><p TEIform="p">"In this is love; not that we loved God, but that He loved us, and sent forth his son, a
                            propitiation concerning our sins. And he is a propitiation not only concerning ours, but
                            also concerning the whole world.'1''—1 John, ii., 2. The human memory is a marvelous
                            instrument for recording conduct and everything that engages attention, beyond possibility
                            of destruction by fire, or catastrophe, or time's flight, or wear, or by death and
                            dissolution of that delicate chemical vesture, within which its sensitive texture is
                            wrought. Though creatures forget the act, its record remains to testify in a season of
                            judgment, beyond the power even of its owner to erase. Only the Divine Wisdom that ordained
                            its laws, Could devise means to infuse an antidote, to correct, to cover or efface from the
                            life undesirable memories that testify against the actors, or neutralize their ill effects
                            and bury evil conduct and its consequences in perpetual oblivion. Hence we look to Divine
                            revelation for the true method of atoning for sin, and casting it out of heart and memory.
                            Jesus testified, "The Father judges no man, but has committed all 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. judgment to the Son, that all men may honor the Son, even as they honor the
                            Father." The Father is honored by honoring his messengers. "He has given him authority also
                            to execute judgment, because he is the Son of man." This teaches that the Father has
                            committed to man, the judgment of things pertaining to man. God in the conscience, is but
                            one's individual portion of God, and if it be unable to preserve one from sinning, how can
                            it perform the greater office of taking away sin and restoring lost liberty without external
                            aid, by confession before a witness. Partial judgments do indeed, arise at times in the
                            conscience and understanding, sufficient to turn their subject from an evil course, but they
                            do not erase past sins, nor purge corruption from the heart. The Son of man alluded to, is
                            not a particular person, but a character, which includes many in one spirit. For it is
                            written, "The saints shall judge the world." Hence, this Son of man is the regenerated, new
                            man, and heir of all precious things promised to man. He does not become such without
                            passing through the ordeal which takes away sin and purifies the soul. To be qualified
                            judges, they must be tested by the same standard that is to be applied to others in their
                            presence. Hence we are told "The sins of some men are manifest, going before to judgment,
                            but some, they follow after. Likewise the good works of some are manifest, and they that are
                            otherwise can not be hid." Under the law which was a shadow of good things to come, it is
                            written, God will bring every work into judgment, with every secret thing, whether it be
                            good, or whether it be evil. Jesus testified, "For every idle word that men shall speak,
                            they shall give account thereof in the day of judgment." To whom is this account to be
                            rendered? To God in his saints, through and by whom He judges the world. Daniel tells us of
                            a time when judgment was given to the saints of the Most High, and the time came that the
                            saints possessed the kingdom." The Apostle confirms the same : ' 'know ye not, the saints
                            shall judge the world?" Jesus said to his disciples, "When the Son of man shall sit on the
                            throne of his glory, ye also shall sit on twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of
                            Israel." John saw twice twelve thrones, on which sat twice twelve Elders around the central
                            throne, showing an equal participation in this judgment, by the feminine half of humanity,
                            as our Prophets reveal to us. Else, why has woman reason, judgment, conscience and
                            understanding to sift and weigh evidence. In describing the judgment of the first
                            resurrection and Millennial reign, the Seer says, "I saw thrones, and they sat upon them,"
                            but he does not denote their number. Daniel also, is indefinite as to number, saying, "The
                            thrones were placed." There may be twelve thousand or twelve times twelve thousand according
                            to the number sealed out of the tribes of Israel, for aught that appears to the contrary. Be
                            they few or many, they evidently signify judgment and dominion given to those who sit on
                            them. These Judges having been tempted 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. like ourselves,
                            and having been purged even if they have not yielded to the same extent, can be touched with
                            a feeling of our infirmities, and wherein themselves have suffered, are able to aid those
                            who are alike tempted. Here then, is the tribunal before which, in due season we must all be
                            made manifest, and here is found the mercy seat from which is dispensed the healing and
                            covering power of a true atonement. For Jesus testifies through his servant John, "He that
                            overcometh, shall sit down with me in my throne, even as I overcame and have set down with
                            my Father in his throne." Having been anointed with the same Holy Spirit, and baptized
                            thereby into death of the carnal life, as Jesus was, and having overcome death, and him
                            having the power of death, as Jesus overcame, they are one with Christ, and execute that
                            same judgment and rule in his commands. The prayer offered by Jesus, that his disciples
                            might be one with him, as he was one with the Father, signifies as much as this, to those in
                            whom it is fulfilled and fulfilling. So testifies one who has experienced the cleansing
                            effects and overcoming power dispensed in this judgment. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old year" TEIform="index"/>THE OLD YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davis, Margarette" TEIform="persName"/>Margarette Davis</byline><p TEIform="p">Now the dear Old Year is ended, Joy and sorrow both have blended In its passing days. And
                            'twas best so, both were given By our Father wise in heaven, Render we sweet praise.
                            Backward as the leaves we're turning, Precious lessons we are learning, Ne'er to be forgot.
                            Here are words unkindly spoken, There are obligations broken, All for want of thought. Sad
                            the hours we thus have squandered, As from duty we have wandered, In forbidden ways, Yet the
                            heavens bear us witness, How we've yearned for angel fitness, 'Mid these trying days.
                            Yearned for faith that is abiding, For a trust always confiding, In our God above, Who will
                            give when earth shall fail us, And when inward foes assail us, His protecting love. Gracious
                            Father, we surrender All to Thee, our sure defender, Whatsoe'er betide. Where Thou leadest
                            we will follow, Each to-day and each to-morrow, And thy wisdom bide. Cover in thy
                            loving-kindness, Missteps taken in our blindness, Often do we stray. Yet we seek thy kingdom
                            holy, Though we make the journey slowly, Lengthen out our day. Counting up our gains and
                            losses, Merged in love are all the crosses, Of the good Old Year. Cancelling all claims and
                            debts, As friends we part without regrets, Faithful, good Old Year. East Canterbury, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Economy" TEIform="index"/>ECONOMY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p">Economy was one of the first lessons taught and practiced by the founders of our communistic
                            home. Though actual want prompted its exercise in a great measure, yet it was undoubtedly a
                            well grounded principle, born of a 6 <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. faith that includes
                            every virtue which ennobles the life of the individual, and binds together in social compact
                            a self-sustaining community. Necessity is the goad that urges to industry, and poverty in
                            one aspect is better than riches, as it brings out sterling worth of character, especially
                            if persons are prompted by noble impulses and a philanthropic desire to toil for others
                            equally with themselves. This is as the good poet says, "A toil that gains with what it
                            yields, And scatters to its own increase, And hears while sowing outward fields The harvest
                            song of inward peace." Three years in the wilderness, with a hard struggle for material
                            subsistence, gave Mother Ann Lee and her devoted co-laborers, ample scope for the exercise
                            of all their faculties in saving and accumulating the necessaries of life, that they might
                            have enough and to spare for those who should embrace the truth as was manifested in the New
                            Dispensation, and practically exemplified in the revival of the Pentecostal spirit, when
                            souls were baptized into an element of unselfishness, and "they had all things in common."
                            By close economy, hard labor and an exceeding self-denial, some property was accumulated,
                            and in a few years they were able to build houses suitable for associative purposes. Land
                            was from time to time added to their possessions, some of which was dedicated by those that
                            believed. How earnestly the little band of zealous souls toiled to gain their desired ends,
                            and so devoted were they to each other's interests,—"in honor preferring one another"—that
                            when it was agreed to gather the Church of the Believers into order at New Lebanon, it was a
                            carefully considered question just where they should locate. The leading Brethren were so
                            anxious to maintain a spirit of love and fellowship, that each waived his choice for
                            another's decision, until at last, a quantity of fine lumber was procured by one of them,
                            and unloaded on the present site of the present Church Family. "There," said he, most em-
                            phatically, "that is for the Meeting house." On that spot it was reared by their own hands,
                            and "where the body was, thither the eagles were gathered together;" for the people came
                            from all the little hamlets of the country round about, where the word of the new life had
                            been preached, and the good seed had fallen in sincere and honest hearts, and in joyfulness
                            they dedicated their all to one united interest. How happy were they in their simple
                            occupations, ministering to each other's needs, "Not slothful in business, but fervent in
                            spirit, serving the Lord." Sustained through adversity, trial and persecution by a strong
                            uplifting faith, they went forth clad in its panoply; not with swords to slay, but with
                            implements of husbandry to clear the forests, turn the virgin soil, and dig wells, that
                            their bread and water might be sure. Many simple devices and industries procured their
                            clothing and the needful comforts of home. All this noble effort served to bind them in
                            close social and spiritual relation, and after each day's labor was 7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. done, they forgot not the assembling of themselves together to praise and
                            worship God, and build one another up in their most holy faith. In going from place to
                            place, on her heaven sent mission to spread the glad tidings of salvation ; Mother Ann Lee
                            never failed to inculcate simple and appropriate lessons in regard to the everyday duties of
                            life ; in these, order, cleanliness and economy were paramount, and essential to godliness
                            of character. She would often say, "Be prudent and saving of the blessings God has so
                            graciously given ; for you can not make one spear of grass to spring up, nor a kernel of
                            grain to grow, neither can you create aught that supplies your physical needs. Be careful,
                            be thankful, and ever realize your dependence upon the Giver of every good." She exhorted
                            the people to gather up the fragments, and as a practical example against extravagant
                            customs, would make her meal of the leavings on the plates, remarking, "If you have anything
                            to spare give it to the poor." Hence came the practice among Believers, never to take any
                            more on the plate than could be eaten ; which remains a good testimony against the senseless
                            and wasteful manners of the world. Thoughtfulness and care was impressed on all their goings
                            forth. Attention to small things, preserved neatness, order and thrift about house and farm.
                            Gates were kept closed; no tools were left broken or exposed to the weather to rust; barns,
                            sheds and shops were kept tidy, each member was expected to pick up and save, and no
                            spiritual blessing was ensured except in strict obedience to order and duty. How carefully
                            the young people were disciplined in regard to not marring furniture, windows or walls; they
                            were instruted to walk lightly, to open and close doors softty : to speak gently and
                            respectfully ; to have a care for their clothing, especially their shoes, which require
                            frequent attention to keep them in good repair. There was much salutary instruction and
                            godly example that tended to curb the rough animal nature that is manifest in the
                            unprogressed and unrestrained natural human being. A fulness of unearned blessing is a
                            doubtful inheritance of good; for he only knows the worth of wealth, who has first realized
                            want and privation in acquiring it. And how often we behold a painful lack of appreciation
                            on the part of those, who, though bred to penury, are thankless when an abundance is
                            bestowed upon them. Lifted above their real estate, they murmur at God's manna sent, and
                            long for the flesh pots and gross habits of the low life in Egyptian bondage, which they
                            first thought they loathed. Are we not too generous in the distribution of communal goods to
                            those who have no claim and have not proved themselves willing and obedient? If every
                            garment given should be the equivalent of a certain amount of work performed on the part of
                            the novitiate, there would perhaps be greater appreciation of its worth. But, in our homes
                            where consecrated labor of the few supplies the wants of many, especially of those who are
                            incapacitated to earn their own living—there 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. is often
                            a sad lack of the virtue of economy, and a tendency to discard clothing before it is
                            sufficiently worn ; and in other ways to be careless and thoughtless. Prudence garners
                            greater treasures than money can buy. The wealth of her store-house is the eternal riches
                            won by diligent toil and a careful spirit; for he who holds every blessing sacred, and
                            becomes a faithful steward of God's good gifts, will never suffer poverty of spirit. Let us
                            build on the firm foundation of enduring principles that support the temple of Truth ; not
                            removing a stone here and there, thus weakening the structure, but, by adding virtue to
                            virtue, rear an asylum for those who, "Seek first the kingdom of God and its righteousness."
                            Then will the addition of temporal things—the outcome of united and unselfish service, prove
                            an equal blessing to all who share the interest of our beautiful communal homes. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut, January 1893" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct., Jan. 1893</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children ;—Another year of life is forever gone. Have you wisely improved it? Not an
                            hour nor a moment can now be recalled whether they were spent in doing good or ill. Begin
                            the New Year right. If you would save hours do not waste moments. The days are fast speeding
                            away. Take each one as a gift to be used in God's service. Improve your talents and you will
                            receive the reward. Let no moments run to waste, years have come and gone in haste. Fight
                            against sin and subdue it. Forsake wrong doing to-day. Delays are dangerous and often prove
                            fatal and time is none too long for repentance. Every victory strengthens the victor. The
                            suffering which sin brings is the inevitable consequence of that sin. "Pleasures in a sinful
                            way, while they flatter you ever betray." Keep good vows better this year than you did last.
                            Each day make your heaven. Duties even in small things are duties still. The duty of the
                            hour is to live right now. There is no pleasure like duty well done. Struggle for a clean
                            heart. Base your actions on principle. "A lack of principle is often the principal lack."
                            Never evade the question, Is it right? "The pure in heart shall see God," therefore be so
                            pure that you can see godliness in each other. A conscience unspotted is heaven within. Your
                            Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Obcutt</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Without fault" TEIform="index"/>WITHOUT FAULT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy G. Danforth</byline><p TEIform="p">How pleasant the thought that we may stand with the redeemed on Mount Zion! How the heart
                            swells with rapture as we anticipate the glorious prospect! But what must be our attainments
                            to entitle us to this claim? We read that "in their mouth was found no guile." This, then,
                            is their condition, and for this perfection we must strive. The Apostle says, "If any man
                            offend not in word, the same is a perfect man and able also to bridle the whole body;" thus
                            bring the life in accordance with the Divine will which is unbounded love and charity for
                            all. This heavenly love extends to all; even the most sinful and erring are objects of
                            Divine love and pity. As "out of the abundance of the heart the mouth speaketh," it is
                            evident that the heart and mind must be cleansed from all evil thoughts and hard feelings,
                            by the truth and fire of the gospel testimony, until in truth, we can in honor prefer one
                            another. 9 <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. When the love of God reigns supreme in
                            our hearts and we can lend a helping hand to those in need, without judging their
                            worthiness, or despising their infirmities, then we have begun to control our whole being,
                            so that "in our mouths will be found no guile," and we can "stand without fault before the
                            throne of God" today and each day as time rolls on. God grant that we may all strive for
                            this glorious attainment. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Passing moments" TEIform="index"/>PASSING MOMENTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tiffany, Amanda" TEIform="persName"/>Amanda Tiffany</byline><p TEIform="p">How precious the moments so swiftly passing, like pearly dewdrops at early dawn in the sun's
                            bright rays, they quickly vanish ; are gone forever past recall. How careful we should be
                            well to improve each one, that in the future we may look back on a well-spent life without
                            regret; happy in the thought that the seed we sowed in the springtime of life, has yielded a
                            rich harvest of golden grain; that the journey of life has been a success, though fraught
                            with many dangers, trials and disappointments. Our path may not have been strewn with
                            flowers and the sun may not always have shone brightly to illumine our way; but it is
                            consoling to know we have been led and guided by Omnipotent power; that blessings,
                            innumerable, have been ours to share, while heavenly peace like a mantle enshrouded our
                            souls when we kept the strait path of duty. Then let us open our hearts to the glorious rays
                            of gospel light, and carefully cull the roses, as we journey, avoiding the thorns,
                            contention, envy and strife, the bane of all happiness, and cultivate only love and gospel
                            fellow-ship. We are called of God for a purpose. Let us be sure we are of the chosen number
                            who will choose to do his work with singleness of heart. Now, why have we, in particular
                            been thus noticed? Because we are more worthy than others ? Ah, nay ! But God will always
                            have a chosen few for a beacon light to the world, a pavilion wherein the sin-sick and weary
                            may find shelter and rest. We have been gathered from a world of strife, into the vineyard
                            of the Lord, not for a selfish purpose, or merely to gain peace and salvation for our own
                            souls, but as co-laborers with the spirit of good, to sow, water and nourish faith in other
                            souls, and by right living ourselves, be able to lead them home to God. I think the wisest
                            and surest way to improve the passing moments, is to perform all life's duties well; ever to
                            keep in view the golden rule. This will insure happiness and make life's labor a success and
                            faith and works will combine in a practical Christian life. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1,200,000 of little birds are destroyed..." TEIform="index"/>
                            1,200,000 of little birds are destroyed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">1,200,000 of little birds are destroyed every year in the department of Moselle
                                    in order to minister to the love of ornament. All the world over a like destruction
                                    is carried on, and we say that the clergy are responsible for this inhuman freak of
                                    fashion.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Our Animal Friends" TEIform="index"/>—Our Animal Friends.</bibl></p></div2><pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by <persName reg="Stratton, E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. Stratton.]</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Planting seed too deep" TEIform="index"/>PLANTING SEED TOO DEEP</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In the teacher's chair, in the Bible-class room, in the superintendent's desk,
                                    and in the pulpit, there is always danger of overheaping soil on the seed of truth.
                                    Too much comment may kill out the life of the text. To begin with, he who sows must
                                    have clearly in mind the distinction between the seed and the soil. "The seed is the
                                    Word"—God's Word, not man's thought about that Word. That Word needs to be handled
                                    as seed. It should be planted with judicious care, and not overheaped with soil of
                                    any sort. Soil is necessary. Planting below the surface, by a stimulating question
                                    or a suggestive remark or a helpful illustration, is better than broadcast sowing on
                                    the bare and hard earth. But, after all, the seed is the chief thing, not the soil.
                                    Yet there are teachers and superintendents and preachers who take one or two grains
                                    of good truth-seed, and then devote themselves to shoveling earth upon it until the
                                    seed is buried out of sight and hope forever. The seed was good enough, but it was
                                    killed in the planting. In all attempts at planting the seed of God's Word, in class
                                    or school or congregation, there is good reason for the old rule, "not to plant
                                    seeds more than five times their diameter in depth." Heaping soil on the seed is the
                                    great barrier to seed-growing in every field of human effort. Mistaking this
                                    soil-heaping for seed-planting, is one of the commonest errors of those who long for
                                    mental and moral harvests and fail of them. Many a housekeeper would have better
                                    servants if she planted more seeds and piled up less soil over those she did plant
                                    in her talks with her servants. Many a merchant or manufacturer or banker or
                                    overseer of laborers kills nine-tenths of the seeds of instruction he uses by the
                                    useless words of fault-finding or of reproach which he heaps over his counsels to
                                    those who are under him. Many a man fails of permanently interesting a neighbor in
                                    his personal affairs, because when he has planted the seeds of information about his
                                    case he buries those seeds beyond hope of life by his endless explanations and
                                    reasons for desiring help and sympathy. Many a person who recognizes his fault in a
                                    former interview with an acquaintance, and desires to make confession of it buries
                                    the seed of apology and regret under such a mass of soil in his new words about the
                                    original cause of misunderstanding that the seed itself fails to germinate, while
                                    the soil-heap above it is a new barrier to free intercourse between the
                                    acquaintances. In all our sowing for a harvest in the hearts of any of our fellows
                                    there is good reason for the old rule, "not to plant seeds more than five times
                                    their diameter in depth." Not the covering soil but the lightly covered seed gives
                                    hope of a harvest in planting. If we are to reap where we have sown we must choose
                                    our seed, must plant it wisely, and must resolutely refrain from crushing out its
                                    life by what we heap above it merely because soil is abundant and we enjoy
                                    shoveling. This truth would admit of many more specific applications, but here is
                                    soil enough for this seed. Now let it germinate.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gently" TEIform="index"/>GENTLY
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Arehart, J. Frank" TEIform="persName"/>J. Frank Arehart
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Gently speak in accents tender Of those friends ye
                                    loved of yore, Though perchance they may not render All the joys they gave before.
                                    There are few whose lives are blameless Who have nothing to regret; Then let others
                                    faults be nameless Or forgive them and forget. 'Tis no trifle that we cherish, When
                                    we find and prove a friend; One whose homage will not perish, Growing stronger to
                                    the end. But should dark clouds over shade thee And old friends grow cold, yet Think
                                    how happy once they made thee, Then forgive, but ne'er forget.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto. January, 1893. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY,
                            1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month,
                            and is the only work issued regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and
                            simple statement of the religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of
                            righteousness. All communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample
                            copy, free. Entered at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class
                        matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It must have been a pleasant season for St Paul..." TEIform="index"/>
                                It must have been a pleasant season for St Paul...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It must have been a pleasant season for St Paul, when the illumination of his mind was so
                                clear that he could enter into an element which foreshadowed the heavenly state, and
                                could see God's glory becoming the center of attraction, when all the things of this
                                life would become secondary or fall entirely into insignificance. Caught up into the
                                heavens and divested of the selfishness of earthly surroundings, he became anxiously
                                interested in aiding those who fortunately came within the sphere of his action. So
                                absorbed was he in the spirit of the testimony of Jesus, that he declared himself
                                thoroughly separated from all worldly relation, and from henceforth, said he, "We will
                                know no man after the flesh." All the long list of selfish relations that had come down
                                to him from the days of Adam and Eve, including the cousins and uncles and aunts, were
                                from this date, to be cancelled from the note book of remembrance, and a clean page
                                opened, on which to place the record of his new calling. "Therefore," said he, "if any
                                man be in Christ, he is a new creature, old things are passed away ; behold, all things
                                are become new." What subject could embody more depth of interest than that which
                                assures us that all things will become new : and that this renewal will not cease till
                                every follower of Christ Jesus is included. The testimony of living truth, even from the
                                day of the Baptist had been to repent, to change the mind, to make the crooked paths
                                straight, and to be baptized into the Holy Spirit; and not only this, but it was
                                imperatively taught that all who accepted the name or gospel of Christ, should depart
                                from iniquity. All through this incisive testimony was to be found the life of the word
                                of God, and the ministration which would enable the recipient to make strait paths, and
                                then to deny himself of all ungodliness and every worldly lust. TERMS. <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 The old things were to be done away and all things
                                become new; and then to make the state more in harmony with the life of Christ, all
                                these new things were to be of God. What a wonderful work it must be, that will baptize
                                a man into a new element so thoroughly that it will wash from him all remembrance of his
                                selfish inheritance. That will give him a place in the brotherhood of Christ, and so
                                cleanse his memory that he will not know even his nearest relatives after the flesh, as
                                these may, by the grace of God become transformed into the likeness of Christ. Buried in
                                baptism with the son of God he comes forth a new creature, with a new name and in
                                unspotted garments, to find himself a member of the new creation, and breathing the
                                "breath of life." The good apostle, at this time, was so deeply absorbed in his subject
                                that he saw clearly, the work of spiritual resurrection. He had lived as a selfish man,
                                in the order of nature, and he had coveted the relations of that order which made him
                                not only narrow in his work among men, but aroused his worst passions, and made him the
                                cruel persecutor of an innocent people. He now saw that Christ and the spiritual
                                resurrection was on an elevation above this sensual sphere in which he had, himself,
                                walked. At this time, he says, "It pleased God to call me, and to reveal his "son in me;
                                and immediately I conferred not with flesh and blood." Mark the difference in this
                                decided mind, to the call of God, from that of those undecided characters who wanted to
                                be disciples of Jesus, but hedged their own way with many foolish excuses, and then
                                thought to hold a close relation to the world. It is no wonder that they went away
                                sorrowfully. One says ;—"Let me first go and bid them farewell, which are at home, at my
                                house." We have known just such instances. With Christ on one side and a selfish
                                relation on the other, he stands like the "doubtful hesitator," fearing to decide. The
                                poor creature says, "My relatives will think so strange of me." Indeed, they will, but
                                if your call is from God, your return visit may cost you your spiritual life. "Suffer me
                                to go and bury my father," said another undecided would-be-disciple. Of course this must
                                touch the sympathetic heart of the loving Jesus. Funerals in that day were quite like
                                those of the present, a place where one can be seen of men, to display every shade of
                                mourning. In the cities, at the present date, they put on an air of fashion, and in the
                                country it is a good place to transact business. Jesus knew perfectly well that these
                                excuses were of the thinnest quality, and to the last speaker he said,—"Let the dead
                                bury their dead, go thou and preach the kingdom of God." This command was <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. more imperative than attending a funeral or the bidding
                                farewell to some selfish relative. This building of a Christian home is the forming of
                                new relations, and demands of those who enter it, to become new creatures, and to grow
                                into a new and spiritual resurrection. When all things become new then that beautiful
                                prophecy of the day of restoration will be fulfilled, as recorded by the prophet
                                Zephaniah ;—"Then will I return to the people a pure language, that they may call upon
                                the name of the Lord." How much we need, and how very anxiously we may anticipate the
                                coming of that day of the Lord when this pure language will be numbered among the new
                                and choice blessings vouchsafed to God's people. No doubt there will be a growing
                                appreciation of the study of English grammar, in that day, for even now that teaches us
                                to use the English language with propriety, and the inference to be drawn is, that those
                                who use unclean and profane words have not been taught in English grammar, nor studied
                                the rules of propriety. No one would believe, for a moment, that Jesus in his
                                disciplined state of mind used other than the most correct language, as he emphatically
                                urged it upon others to let their yea, be yea and their nay, be nay, in order to
                                establish a concise and correct use of speech. A Christian people should be Christ-like,
                                and if we believe that he was careful of his language, in conversation, among men, we
                                hold ourselves at a great disadvantage if we grow indifferent on this essential subject.
                                We had intended to publish in this number, all the articles received in memory of Elder
                                Daniel Boler, but were prevented by unforeseen circumstances. They will now appear in
                                the Manifesto for February.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best we can" TEIform="index"/>THE BEST WE CAN
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When things don't go to suit us, Why should we fold our hands
                                    And say, "No use in trying, Fate baffles all our plans." Let not your courage
                                    falter, Keep faith in God and man, And to this thought be steadfast— "I'll do the
                                    best I can." If clouds blot out the sunshine Along the way you tread, Don't grieve
                                    in hopeless fashion And sigh for brightness fled. Beyond the clouds the sunlight
                                    Shines in the Eternal Plan; Trust that the way will brighten, And do the best you
                                    can. Away with vain repinings; Sing songs of hope and cheer, Till many a weary
                                    comrade Grows strong of heart to hear. He who sings over trouble Is aye the wisest
                                    man. He can't help what has happened, But—does the best he can. So, if things won't
                                    go to suit us, Let's never fume and fret, For finding fault with fortune Ne'er
                                    mended matters yet. Make the best of whate'er happens; Bear failure like a man; And
                                    in good or evil fortune Do just the best you can.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York ledger" TEIform="index"/>New York Ledger</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. November. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1891. 35.98 2,% in.
                                1 in. 1892. 36.45 SU in. A% in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 64. Lowest " " " " 14.
                                Number of rainy days " " 6. " " snowy " " " 6. " " clear " " " 8. " " cloudy " C. 22. G.
                                .R Dec. 11, 1892. With this number of our welcomed little periodical, we wish our dear
                                friends, "A Happy New Year." This to us is not an idle pass-word, but from our hearts we
                                send a greeting to all, trusting that happiness the result of faithfulness, may rest as
                                a benediction in every home which the Manifesto visits. Our harvest months seem to have
                                been a reaping time for more than the sowing of men; for the Angel Reaper has garnered
                                four sheaves from our field, so fully ripened, that it was indeed a well-timed harvest.
                                The last of these, Sister Betsey Crosman was gathered just in time to be in at the
                                angels' Thanksgiving. As these noble veterans of our cause pass on, does it not behoove
                                us to look well to the position we hold in the ranks, to know that not only shall our
                                names be upon the roll-call, but that our lives shall be an entire consecration. Let no
                                one allow himself to be mustered in, only for the daily rations. We have a steady,
                                upward march to make, and it needs the single-hearted, valiant, earnest soldiers, brave
                                to conquer the foe within, and courageous to contend with prevailing errors, which
                                inevitably creep into every organization, by the way of unregenerated human nature. On
                                the occasion of the funeral of our worthy father, Elder Daniel Boler, we were happy to
                                meet even though for a short time, so many loved and honored representatives of the
                                Eastern Societies. Need we wait for funerals for the much needed conferences of leading
                                members? Will not our second century, begin a new era?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 12, 1892. "O how swiftly time is passing; And 'tis precious to me : The moments are
                                rolling As the waves of the sea. They are solemn and weighty As they roll one hy one,
                                And exclaim with a meaning, Ever gone! ever gone!" This I feel, and in a degree realize.
                                We have in the last eight weeks passed through various changes that have opened the way
                                by which can be brought about among ourselves that long denied spiritual revival, with
                                its wave of "New Life," that will start the new growth, and develop, or reveal, or bring
                                to fruition another degree of pure gospel truth embodied in the gospel of Christ and our
                                ever blessed Mother Ann. The chief change that we have met with, that will, in my
                                understanding help to bring the long desired spiritual wave, was the holding of a
                                Convention, or Meeting on the 13th. of November last. Which Meeting was composed of
                                delegates from ten Societies. These were brought together, accidentally, incidentally,
                                or providentially just as any one chooses to take it. ' It was on the occasion of the
                                funeral of our beloved father Elder Daniel Boler. To Elder Henry C. Blinn next to Provi-
                                dence is due the credit of holding one of the most profitable meetings ever held by
                                Believers in the past thirty-six years at least. Such a meeting has been talked, and
                                written about for some time but has never been held before. After the war of 1860 and 65
                                or during that period the currency of the country passed through several phases. At last
                                it reached the stage that the promise of the government in the form of paper notes were
                                not worthmore than half their face value: after the war, there were long talks and much
                                written about the return to specie payment; to resume as they called <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 16 THE MANIFESTO. it. Well, how to bring that about was the subject of long and warm
                                discussions; Lincoln the then wise head and leader, said, "Well, the only way if we are
                                going to resume is simply to resume." The people through their representatives had the
                                power and all they had to do was to exercise it. Is it not just so with ourselves? We
                                see many desired changes which we wish and desire, should be made for the better
                                understanding of our gospel, and for the further development of our pure and holy faith.
                                Is there any other way to bring it about than by just going to work and doing it? And
                                can anything be done except by somebody doing it? If it can, then it might be profitable
                                for us to understand the how and the where and the who. We have had very open weather,
                                no snow or ice of any account, so we have got pretty well tided up and are preparing to
                                do a little in the broom business. We have not done much for several years so we shall
                                have to move slowly and be sure that our religion goes into every broom we make; that it
                                may be a gospel testimony in every house or home, where it may be called upon to do
                                duty.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O., D." TEIform="persName"/>D. O.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Center family" TEIform="index"/>Center Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec, 1892. The Christmas season is fast approaching, that great season of joy and
                                gladness to all. The great day of all days in the year, when all the world can rejoice
                                and be glad that one was born who has made the world better and happier. The family send
                                their Christmas greeting to their friends who read the Manifesto and wish them a Merry
                                Christmas and a happy New Year. Time flies and the seasons come and go, a reminder that
                                we will all soon be in another world and our places filled by others. The winter has
                                been pleasant and very little snow at Mt. Lebanon, and the hills are brown and bare. The
                                family have all been well this winter except a few colds. Thanksgiving day found the
                                family very thankful for the good crops of the last season The Family had the Church
                                Family with us at the morning meeting, a very pleas-: ant season enjoyed by all that
                                were present. On Sunday afternoon, Dec. 11th.,we went over to the North Family to hear.
                                M. M. Pomeroy of New York speak on the religious movements of the day, especially the
                                Salvation Army. He gave a very interesting account of the work in which they are engaged
                                and the good they are doing. With his broad and liberal mind he takes in the whole
                                world, he also freely acknowledges that Believers are a power for good and thinks they
                                should imitate the Salvation Army, in preaching our faith that others may become
                                partakers of our gospel.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="O., G." TEIform="persName"/>G. O.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Second Eamily. Dec. 1892. Theee is nothing eventful at this season of the year. We are
                                busy gathering our usual supply of fire-wood. Our gospel friends from Groveland are now
                                all with us; the last, but not least, was Elder Alexander who arrived Friday the 9th. We
                                are glad that they have been able to get moved before the extreme cold weath- er. We
                                also feel that they have not only added numbers to Watervliet, but much spiritual
                                strength. They are as comfortably situated bodily as the short space of time could make
                                them. It will take some time, no doubt, to make it seem just like home. But they are
                                cheerful and feel the additional spiritual union and strength will more than compensate
                                for the cross, if so it be, of the removal. Elder Andrew Barrett of Harvard made us a
                                short visit; we are always pleased to see such consecrated souls as we know our good
                                Brother to be. Let us all resolve with the coming year to live closer to our gospel
                                call, not only hearers of the good word but doers of the needful work, that will bring
                                joy and peace. <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. North Family. When the Revelator saw
                                in vision a mighty host that were virgin souls, the goodly company that we found on
                                arriving here, were part of that band. O those blessed Fathers and Mothers, dear
                                Brethren and Sisters that constitute the household of faith, and that blessed communion
                                we are privileged to enjoy with them. Nay, the world cannot give, neither can it take it
                                away. We have been welcomed with open hearts and hands, and for the kindness extended to
                                us, we bow in humble gratitude. We are trying to bring concord out of the temporary
                                confusion incident to moving so far. Blessing has attended our efforts and may those who
                                bear the burden in our communal homes be sustained in their efforts to promote and
                                advance this glorious cause. We are all here at Watervliet, the home of our beloved
                                Mother while in earth life. May her spirit ever hover over thee and shield thee from the
                                tempest, that there liiay be a home, a house of refuge for the weary, and sin-sick souls
                                when tired of the contentions of worldly conditions and willing to renounce them, all
                                can find a haven of rest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="G., H. D." TEIform="persName"/>H. D. G.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1892. The winter term of school commenced Nov. 22, with sixteen scholars. An Otto
                                Gasoline Engine has been put into the Dairy to take the place of the hot air engine
                                formerly used for separating the milk and churning the butter. We hope it may prove as
                                satisfactory as anticipated. The old year is nearly at a close and the New Year about to
                                dawn. As we look back through the past, can we count as many victories as .we hoped for
                                when the year began? if so, it is well with us, if not, let us pray for more courage,
                                strength and Christian fortitude that the coming year may bring to our souls that growth
                                of the Spirit we all sincerely desire. We extend to every one in our Zion Homes, our
                                purest and earnest prayers, that the coming year may be a happy and prosperous New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., F." TEIform="persName"/>F. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1892. Jesus said, "I have meat to eat that ye know not of." If the meat that perish-
                                eth is good and desirable, the meat that endureth unto everlasting life is much more
                                needful. There is no hunger like the hunger of the soul for spiritual food. Many persons
                                desire peace and rest in a worldly life but find continual unrest. True rest is found
                                only in a godly life a sinless condition. ^'Godliness is profitable unto all things " It
                                is as blessed as it is profitable. Choice literature is sometimes chosen for New Year's
                                gifts, often very appropriately. It is natural to make use of what interests us, as an
                                expression of our interest in others. A gift of the Manifesto for one year to our
                                friends, who are not now blest with its monthly messages of purity and truth, might be
                                productive of much good. Let us try it. Special grain for fowls at this season of the
                                year, such as buckwheat, ilax-seed, wheat and oats, make excellent changes used in small
                                quantities in connection with the regular diet. A good supply of coarse food is very
                                essential to the health of the flock. Loose or poor heads of cabbage stored by
                                themselves are the best and most easily obtained green food for poultry during winter.
                                Two or three heads hung so that the fowls can easily reach them, and renewed when
                                necessary will well repay the trouble. Onions are very good to mix with the salt food.
                                Poultry keepers must exercise judgment in the selection and changes of food in cold
                                weather. A change of rations two or three times every week will give strength, tone and
                                appetite to chickens.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1892. In union with our precious kindred elsewhere who are doubtless preparing their
                                contributions for the coming Manifesto, we likewise hasten to sign our final Notes for
                                the departing of the grand old year so soon to be numbered with the past; but before we
                                bid our friends adieu 17 <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFESTO. would send in advance
                                to one and all, our best wishes for a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year. Since we
                                find that there is nothing more worthy our strife than the cultivation of kindly
                                thoughts and deeds toward our gospel relations, we pledge anew to grow these ennobling
                                graces by toil and care until we become "the Angels in the way," to our dear Brethren
                                and Sisters who with us are on the pilgrim journey toward a purer, higher life. We are
                                at present date enjoying a very pleasant visit with our good Brother, Thomas Evans of
                                East Canterbury, N. H. He seems earnest and hearty in the strife to become a true heir
                                of the kingdom. May the powers of good above and around sustain and strengthen him, is
                                our earnest prayer. To-day we are again called upon to consign to its kindred dust the
                                mortal re- mains of our loving Sister Tirzah Whittaker of the South Family. How rapidly
                                the aged in our Society are passing on; soon the few now remaining will all be in
                                brighter mansions with kindred souls who have been their loved companions in earth life.
                                We have enjoyed many bright days since the frost king first nipped our fingers, but
                                winter must have its full reign. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. R.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North family" TEIform="index"/>North Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1892. Esteemed Editor:—No doubt other pens have chronicled the death of our worthy
                                Sister, Hannah Taylor, who passed to spirit life, Dec. 3rd. As her life was ebbing away,
                                she asked those in attendance if the Dec. number of the Manifesto had come, and added,
                                that one of the hardest things for her to leave in exchanging worlds, was the Manifesto,
                                stating she had not failed of reading every issue of the paper since its first
                                publication. A grand tribute of appreciation; denoting a strong love for our herald of
                                truth. As one after another the aged throughout Zion enter the realms of immortality,
                                reflective minds can but experience a thrill of sadness, as less of this class means
                                less moral and intellectual strength, yet the rich legacy which the translated ones
                                leave, a treasure of Christ-like examples, are potent factors to stimulate and encourage
                                us to work the works of righteousness, thus fulfilling our God given mission; a life
                                service fraught with due reverence to our fellow-beings, and activity of those qualities
                                which cheer, bless, and forgive as we would be forgiven. From the lives of our departed,
                                loved ones we learn the lesson that works, not personal theories, are the polishing
                                forces of life. In that domain where we shall be known as we are, true worth is
                                recognized at its full value, and spiritual affinity seeks its class. Here our noble,
                                tried kindred are going, and imitating their worthy examples, we are joining this band
                                of spiritualized characters. May the New Year unfold to us all re- newed blesings, and
                                record to our lives greater victories over the selfishness of the human heart. We
                                express our thanks to the Editor, and all who aid in publishing our Manifesto. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., G. H." TEIform="persName"/>G. H. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1892. A proud, , irritable, discontented or quarrelsome disposition can never be
                                happy. He has thrown a tempestuous atmosphere around himself and must forever move in
                                the region of storms. He has employed sure means to embitter life, whatever may be his
                                external circumstances. He has been the architect of his temper and misery must be the
                                result of his labors. Such elements in Society seem to mar the peace which rightly
                                belongs to the cheerful, contented workers. Like a foul disease it impregnates the
                                surrounding atmosphere. Such persons are ever finding fault with present conditions.
                                Their part of the work is always the hardest. Heaven is full of sunshine and happiness,
                                made so by the cheerful spirits that have left the earth, crowned with a blessing.
                                Better let the spirit of discontent go <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 10 to the
                                land of forgetfulness, among the shadows. The fruits of this spirit are an- gry
                                feelings, selfishness, jealousy, envy and despondency. All are discouraging and very
                                injurious to the mind. Ten cloudy days may pass over a garden without winning a flower,
                                but no sooner does the sun shine, than hundreds of roses open upon the air. Good cheer
                                divides our burdens and carries many of them: so farewell to all discouragement.
                                December finds us busy looking after the stock and hauling wood. The great strife among
                                the farmers, just now, is more milk. Twenty-eight cents for eight quarts of milk is
                                quite a stimulus to milk producers; and it would do you good to see the milk cans that
                                go to Boston, daily, over the Fitchburg R. R. We have had quite a fall of snow and this
                                makes traveling a little more expeditious.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., A. D." TEIform="persName"/>A. D. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield" TEIform="index"/>WestPittsfieldd</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 12, 1892. Ix contemplating the approaching close of the year ninety two, which was
                                ushered in seemingly but a few days since, we are led to exclaim, Oh! time, thou art
                                fleeting and mutable. Whither goest thou, and what are the records thou hast chronicled?
                                Will the Omniscient Father read them with satisfaction or displeasure? Are noble deeds,
                                kind acts, loving words and charitable feelings registered there? May we so adjust and
                                order our conduct each hour that passes, that our record may entitle us to an
                                inheritance with the good and the true. Winter is fully enthroned, as evidenced by an
                                occasional shower of pure white snow-flakes, by the piercing winds, cold rains, and
                                biting frosts. We deeply regret our unfortunate absence from home, where so many
                                precious gospel friends centered, when on their way to Mt. Lebanon to pay the last
                                tribute of respect to the sainted Father; the late Elder Daniel Boler who for so long a
                                period of time has so efficiently and judiciously, acted as Leader and Counselor in the
                                Shaker Church. In him is verified the beautiful Scriptural passage,—"An honest man is
                                the noblest work of God." Redeemed from earth and all things of an earthly character, he
                                has ascended to the celestial regions, there to mingle with the glorified throng,
                                bearing the palm of the victor, and wearing the crown of the conqueror. On Thanksgiving
                                day we enjoyed not only a feast of good things for the physical part of our beings, but
                                the mental and social parts were supplied as well. It being the Centennial year of the
                                founding of our Society, a royal celebration was beautifully planned and very creditably
                                executed by the younger portion of the Community. Songs prepared for the occasion were
                                sung, recitations and dialogues spoken, appropriate selections read, and altogether it
                                was an interesting entertainment. In our humble opinion the Oct. No. of the Maxifesto
                                was most excellent. May the New Year that is soon to dawn upon us be as rich in
                                blessings as the past year has been, with an addition of all that the great and good
                                Father may deem it wise to bestow. May peace, health and happiness abound.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1892. Christmas Time, the "gladdest time of all the year" some one has called it, is
                                almost here, but we doubt if the victims of the coughing, wheezing, and sneezing
                                distemper which is so prevalent just now, can feel in a very cheerful frame of mind. Our
                                changeable New England climate may be a very good thing, but like all the good things of
                                this world, it has its drawbacks. Our Society are once more all at home. The two Sisters
                                who have been in Boston for the last two months, engaged in selling fancy articles at
                                the Mechanics' Fair, have now returned; as have others who have been away from home,
                                more or less, during the year. Winter term of school opened the 5th. inst. with ten
                                pupils. A small number, but they represent so many little minds <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20
                                THE MANIFESTO. and souls to be trained and educated, not merely for this present world,
                                but for an immortal existence. Wise, indeed, must the training be, that both the life
                                that is, and the life that is to be, may be to them a blessing and not a blighted life.
                                E. Weather Kecord for November, 1892. Highest Tern, during the month, 59. Lowest " " " "
                                11. Mean " " " " 24.7 Total precipitation 5.43 in. Number of days on which----.01 in. or
                                more of rain fell, 9.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. Briggs.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Select thought" TEIform="index"/>A SELECT THOUGHT</head><p TEIform="p">If Believers know by their personal and social experience that the Christ-life and doctrines
                            "be of God," being effectual in freeing them from sensual slavery, working radical change in
                            thought and habit from the old self-caring, rudimental, animal life, to the new, universal
                            love and care, the angel spheres, what need they more?</p><byline TEIform="byline">From <persName reg="Andrews, W. W." TEIform="persName"/>W. W. Andrews, of Union Village, Ohio.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ambition may lead to fame, but self-sacrifice leads to immortal glory" TEIform="index"/>
                            Ambition may lead to fame, but self-sacrifice leads to immortal glory
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ambition may lead to fame, but self-sacrifice leads to immortal glory.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cheerfulness" TEIform="index"/>CHEERFULNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy S. Bowers</byline><p TEIform="p">"Good temper is the philosophy of the heart—a gem in the treasury within, whose rays are
                            reflected on all outward objects—a perpetual sunshine, imparting warmth, light and life."
                            Says Montaigne, "The most manifest sign of wisdom is continued cheerfulness. A spirit
                            governed and beautified by the power of Christ, chastened and humiliated in and through the
                            pure love of God will possess that grace of heart, that gentleness of demeanor, that
                            loveliness of character that is commendable in every sphere of life. No hearth-fire circle
                            could have a brighter link; no home a better ornament, and no place a worthier occupant than
                            one who, conquering the passions and powers of a contrary disposition, can manifest the
                            beauty of goodness in continued cheerfulness, it is the effect of goodness. St. Jerome said
                            : "He that hath no bridle on his tongue, hath no grace in his heart;" he that hath no
                            sunshine radiating from his countenance, likewise shows a sad want of virtue. A companion
                            who is cheerful, always seeing the bright side of things and free from unkind discourse, is
                            worth gold, such a soul perpetually overflows with benevolence and sympathy, their good
                            worthy deeds, uniformly joyous and graceful, inspire gladness and distil the sweet
                            influences of love and peace. High-toned humor, wit mirth and happy frolic are the real
                            leavening powers of life, and probably the best physical and mental tonics in the world. It
                            is debilitating and shows the lack of real stamina to sink despondingly under crosses and
                            trouble. "The gloomy soul aggravates misfortune while a cheerful smile often dispels those
                            mists which portend a storm." Former anxieties should be remembered no more; every uneasy
                            apprehension should vanish ; soothing hopes and delightful expectations will then succeed;
                            the countenance will drop its dejected mein ; the eyes brighten with a lively cheerfulness,
                            while the <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 lips express the heart-felt satisfaction
                            in the language of thanksgiving and the voice of melody. The practice of the Golden Rule
                            will cement the bonds of union, but the habit of fault-finding will prove a great disturber,
                            the indulgence of which requires no talent, no self-denial, no brains, no character, but
                            those who are moved by a Christian spirit and a genuine desire to do good have little time
                            for murmuring or complaining. There is a beautiful precept, which he who has received an
                            injury, or thinks he has, would for his own sake do well to follow, "Excuse half and forgive
                            the rest." Use charity toward all; be ever generous in thought and deed ; help others along
                            in life's thorny path ; we all walk the way of cross s, b^ our in- heritance, conditions and
                            environments what they may, then as far as wo arcapable of controlling our own inclinations
                            and surmounting all difficulties, let us do so. He who saul: "I glory not save in the cross
                            of Christ," assures us in these very words that he did not seek happiness in carnal
                            enjoyment but rather in honest self-denial in which he manifested real pleasure. Wherever
                            there is a soul on earth led by the spirit of God, and fill'd by the spirit of God, with
                            good, beautiful and true graces and inspirations, there is a soul which, as St. Paul says,
                            is sitting with Jesus Christ—a soul, already in heaven, though still on earth. Let us have
                            peace, love, joy and inward spiritual light, that it may be said of us as Cervantes said of
                            one, "He had a face like a benediction." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by <persName reg="Stickney, A. C." TEIform="persName"/>A. C. Stickney.]</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tempering process" TEIform="index"/>TEMPERING PROCESS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The best steel is subject to the alternatives of extreme heat and extreme cold.
                                    Were you ever in a cutlery? If you were, you noticed that the knife-blades were
                                    heated and beaten, and then heated again, and plunged into the coldest water, in
                                    order to give them the right shape and temper. And perhaps you have noticed that
                                    there were a large heap of rejected blades, rejected because they would not bear the
                                    tempering process. They cracked and warped; when put upon the grindstone little
                                    flaws appeared in some that up to that point had seemed fair and perfect. Hence they
                                    were thrown aside as unfit for market. So souls, in order to insure the right
                                    temper, are heated in the furnace of affliction, plunged into the cold waters of
                                    tribulation, and ground between the upper and nether stones of adversity and
                                    disaster. Some come out of the trial pure, clastic and bright, ready for the highest
                                    service; others come out brittle with ill-temper, full of flaws and spots of rust,
                                    and are tarown into the rubbish-room as unfit for any but the lowest uses. Now if
                                    you would be of any account among the lorces that are working out the salvation of
                                    this world, be quiet in the hands of God until he tempers you. Listen to that
                                    knife-blade in the hands of the cutler. "Stop now! I have been in the fire often
                                    enough. Would you burn the life out of me?" But in it goes again into the glowing
                                    furnace, and is heated to a white heat. "Stop hammering me! I have been pounded
                                    enough now." But down comes the sledge. "Keep me out of this cold water! One moment
                                    in the fiery furnace and the next in ice-cold water. It is enough to kill one!" But
                                    in it goes. "Keep me off the grindstone! You'll chafe the life out of me." <pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. But it is made to kiss the stone until the
                                    cutler is satisiied. Yet now see! When all the heating and cooling and pounding and
                                    grinding is done, you may bend it double, and yet it springs back straight as an
                                    arrow; it is as bright as polished silver, hard as a diamond, and will cut like a
                                    Damascus blade. It has been shaped, tempered, and polished, and is worth something.
                                    Be still now and let God temper and polish you, and you will be worth something too.
                                    Allow yourself to be prepared for usefulness. If you are so ill-tempered that your
                                    character is marred by the flaws of impatience, petulance, and anger, you will be
                                    thrown into the room assigned for the useless. Lie still in faith in the hands of
                                    God, and let him make something out of you. He will give you a post of holy renown,
                                    if you will let him fit you for it. He will cover you with glory immortal, if you
                                    will be still in the furnace fire while the Holy Ghost moulds and polishes your
                                    soul.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Growing right" TEIform="index"/>GROWING RIGHT
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Marsh, S. D." TEIform="persName"/>By S. D. Marsh. 
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We are growing out, or growing in, We're growing
                                    in goodness, or in sin. We're growing upward, or growing down, Whiche'er we will to
                                    shame or renown! We are growing right, or growing wrong, We stand not idle often, or
                                    long! The way's before; the right or the left, 'Tis ours to choose the worst, or the
                                    best, ' Tis easy to choose when days are all bright The hills all clothed with
                                    verdure and light It needs the furnace, to temper the blade, In conflict with wrong
                                    are heroes made, Growing in goodness is growing in peace, As life grows short, will
                                    triumphs increase. With face to the right, scorning the wrong, Let's be doing while
                                    active and strong, "Gird on the armor—eyes to the right!" "Charge!" See, evil has
                                    vanished from sight!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Usefulness increases happiness" TEIform="index"/>
                            Usefulness increases happiness
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Usefulness increases happiness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor:—I read the Manifesto with much pleasure every month and greatly desire for
                                it long life, with abundant prosperity. The same to Editor and managers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy G. Danforth</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stewart, Peter" TEIform="index"/>Peter Stewart, at 
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Stewart, Peter" TEIform="persName">Peter Stewart</persName>, at East Family, South Union,
                                Ky. Sept. 24, 1892. Age, 81 yrs. He has lived in our Society eleven years and was
                                faithful in every duty. A quiet man, true to principle, and of exemplary deportment. He
                                bore his afflictions with patience, and died the peaceful death of the righteous. J. W.
                                P.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crosman, Betsey" TEIform="index"/>Betsey Crosman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Crosman, Betsey" TEIform="persName">Betsey Crosman</persName>, at Church Family, Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. Nov. 24, 1892. Age, 88 years and 9 mo. Sister Betsey is the last of that
                                noble family whose names have for so long been synonyms of consecration, virtue and
                                trust-worthiness, in the several homes of our Society. They need no monument to
                                perpetuate their memory, for they will live in the hearts of the people so long as the
                                sun rises over the hills of Mt. Lebanon. A. J. C. We'll not mourn when the beaxitiful
                                spirit Is freed from its casket of clay; For the unseen life, is the real life, The dawn
                                of an Eternal day. A. E. N.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Hannah" TEIform="index"/>Hannah Taylor
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Taylor, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah Taylor</persName>, at Enfield, N. H. Dec. 3, 1892.
                                Age 84 yrs. and 6 mo.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whittaker, Tirzah" TEIform="index"/>Tirzah Whittaker
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Whittaker, Tirzah" TEIform="persName">Tirzah Whittaker</persName>, at Enfield, N. H. Dec.
                                10, 1892. Age 88 yrs. 7 mo. and 4 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rubles, Samuel" TEIform="index"/>Samuel Rubles
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rubles, Samuel" TEIform="persName">Samuel Rubles</persName>, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Dec 15,
                                1892. Age 77 yrs. Br. Samuel came to the Society in 1808, and was an industrious member
                                so long as his health permitted. J. W. S.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Libbey, Olive M." TEIform="index"/>Olive M. Libbey
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Libbey, Olive M." TEIform="persName">Olive M. Libbey</persName>, at East Canterbury, N. H.
                                Dec. 20, 1892. Age 70 yrs. 11 mo and 20 days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life eternal" TEIform="index"/>LIFE ETERNAL</head><p TEIform="p">"For neither height, nor depth, nor life, nor death, shall separate us from the love of
                            God."—Rom. viii., 39. Enfield, N. H. 1. O Lord, I've sought Thy helping hand, Its friendly
                            grasp have felt, And 2. Then to my vision, life and death Be setting ly appeared; And 3.
                            'Tis heaven's gift, and paramount To all the gifts of earth; Though 4. O blessed gift, consoling hope, It brings a joy divine To realized the strength and power Its to my soul in
                            trumpet sounds A pleasure come or pain abound, It souls prepared by Christian life; I
                            ministrations dealt. I've voice I plainly heard Reis of untold worth. May covet it as
                            mine. The sought it in the light of clay, And in the shades of night; vealing truths from
                            worlds above, With love and beauty rife, pow'rs above direct my feet, And ministrations bring, bitter cup that passed my lips, The spear that pierced my side, When Which
                            EnHave clouds of sorrow o'er me rolled, And when the sun was bright, gives a crown of glory bright, Boon of eternal life. a bling me, exultingly, A life long triumph sing,
                            oped to me a blissful rest, A peace that does a bide.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Beecher's unprinted words" TEIform="index"/>
                                MR. BEECHER'S UNPRINTED WORDS
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beecher, Henry Ward" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">MR. BEECHER'S UNPRINTED WORDS. The first of the unpublished intiterial by Henry Ward
                                Beecher, recently purchased by The Ladies' Home Journal, will appear in the January
                                issue of that magazine, and presents among other things, the great preacher's hitherto
                                imprinted opinion on "Wine' Drinking on New Year's Day." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We doubt not that the readers
                                of the old Phrenological Journal and Science of Health will be pleased with the December
                                issue, as its contents are replete with thought most pertinent to tlie day. A fine
                                portrait of Tennyson is followed by a rich summary or' the great poet considered as a
                                teacher. Appropriately a very thoughtful sketch of Mrs. Harrison succeeds, entitled,
                                "The White House Grief." "Further Views of the Columbian Exposition" adds to the already
                                longlist of illus- trations of the great structures going up in Jackson Park. "The
                                Measurement of Skulls or Heads" is practical. So is "Bicycle Record Making," with its
                                characteristic drawings. Several good things fill up the department of Practical
                                Phrenology; and allied to that is the excellent report of the Institute Alumni Dinner,
                                with its many really fine speeches by well-known citizens of New York, who thus show
                                their interest in a noble cause. "Phren- ology in the Schools" deserves universal
                                reading. And do the articles one and all in Child Culture. "The Therapeutic uses of the
                                Rectal Injection" gives a trustworthy account of a valuable mode of applying water. And
                                "Some Differences Between Men and Women" will open the eyes, we think, of certain people
                                who seem determined to ignore physiological facts and nature. The editor furnishes an
                                important addition to his series on Systematic Moral Culture that should be copied in
                                all the school publications, and given the widest currency, because of its direct
                                application to the most urgent need of society. This number closes the ninety-third
                                volume and now is a good time to subscribe. The Journal is only 15 cents a number, $1.50
                                a year, with a bust or chart premium. Address, Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East
                                Twenty-first street, New York. Arthur May Mowry contributes a very suggestive paper on
                                "How Civil Government is Taught in a New England High School" to the December Xew
                                England Magazine. It will interest teachers, and all those interested in the furtherance
                                of true ideas on good government. A WONDERFUL WORK. The Good Citizen. \ "The Birds of
                                North America." A magnificent imperial quarto volume. Contains ONE HUNDRED AND NINETEEN
                                engraved plates, representing all our birds, colored from nature, including a reliable
                                and interesting account of their habits and characteristics. Edition limited to 1,000.
                                Subscribe early and secure a copy for the holidays. The work is sold to subscribers,
                                bound hand- somely and substantially, at following net prices; line Russia Seal, or
                                Turkey Morocco half bindings, gold gilt edges $40.00; full bindings, same material.:,
                                $45.00 ENCOMIUMS PROM TflE PEESS. "A superb Work."—Publisher's Weekly. "A great
                                work."—National Teacher. "A magnificent Ornithological Work."— TurfField and Farm. "It
                                is one of the most ambitious publications ever attempted in this country or abroad."—
                                Cleveland Leader. "It is a marvel of beauty and excellence."— Ohio State Journal. "No
                                work evincing such perfect care and fin- ish, at such a reasonable rate, has ever been
                                published either in this country or abroad." —Inter-Ocean, Chicago. COMMENDED BY THE
                                HIGHEST AUTHORITY. From Ex-President Hayes: "It is a valuable work. I have subscribed
                                for two copies." Dr. Elliott Coues, author of "Birds of the North-West," says: "It is a
                                really notable work." Prof. C. J. Maynard, author of the "Birds of'Eastern North
                                America," says; "Contains the best pictures of the species which I have ever seen." Dr.
                                J. S. Newberry, President Academy of Sciences, says: "The work is accurately and
                                tastefully prepared, and I take pleasure in recommending it as the most at- tractive
                                popular exposition of our ornithology yet given to the public." From Prof. Wm. D.
                                Hornaday, Taxidermist, N. S. National Museum: "I have carefully compared the figures in
                                "The Birds of North America,' with those in Audubon's great work, and am free to say
                                that they are more accurate in outline as well as more faithfully colored to nature." "A
                                careful examination of this beautiful work has given me much pleasure. Indeed, it is a
                                great gift to those who love the study of Ornithology." Editor, Manifesto. Samples of
                                plates and text sent to any address on receipt of twenty-five cents in postage stamps.
                                Good active representatives can have steady employment and earn fair compensation by
                                receiving orders for this work with a specimen book furnished on receipt of one dollar
                                by the NATURAL SCIENCE ASSOCIATION, 114 Fifth Ave., New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>