<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0207" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18720701" TEIform="date">July 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL PILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric. Vol. n. G. A. Lomas, Editor. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., JULY, 1872. No. 7. Fifty
                        Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is truth?" TEIform="index"/>"What is Truth?"</head><p TEIform="p">" When Pilate had said this, he said to the Jews, I find in him no fault.'1'' The multitudes
                            of theories seeking to answer this question, find expositions, such as they are, in the
                            various theologies of the day. These theologies form the most monstrous Babylon ever
                            existing. The majority are professedly Christian; but instead of converging toward each
                            other into the Christ life, which is " the way and the truth," " no fault," a diverging from
                            the principles of truth are continually consummating. We propose the burning of all the
                            so-called Christian theologies, and substituting the simple, faultless life of Christ as a
                            guide— this is all the theology needed; relieving us from the necessity of clerical leger-
                            demain, pulpit wrangling, and the vast expense of that branch of colleges and academies used
                            for theological purposes. The popular, pettifogging education of the priest never yet made
                            truth more apparent. The agility acquired to twist the scriptures in this or that direction,
                            never yet had a savory influence. It has been used, rather, to interpret to the masses what
                            the original does not mea,n; to quiet the conscience of the people, thus preventing a revolt
                            against sectarian errors. Truth has a living expression. Christ is that expression. Whoso
                            lives as Christ Jesus did, will be a living representation of truth. Is there any doubt how
                            Jesus lived ? None. But no sooner did or does the cross appear, than its unpleasant
                            application is excused by the introduction of a theology that teaches an evasion of the
                            truth; and the exemption of every carnal taste from the cross, rather than its application,
                            is popular Christianity to-day. Every step made in this direction will be repented. What did
                            Jesus answer to Pilate, that so suddenly convinced him of Christ's life being the embodiment
                            of truth, and caused him to exclaim, " I find in him no fault?" We believe Jesus implied in
                            his answer to the question: " What is truth ? " that it is " the eternal relinquishment of
                            error." Are we seekers of truth ? We learn it in Christ's life— " seek " it there, " and you
                            shall find it." Had we no theologies, excepting the life of Christ, represented through the
                            medium Jesus, where would this affect us first ? "If any man would be a disciple of truth,
                            let him do as I have done— follow me." To the rich man he said: " If thou wouldst be
                            perfect—truth, without fault—make others to share in all that you possess." How this truth
                            would cross the multitudes! But they have theologies that excuse them. What next ? " Be
                            virgins ! " "I am the Resurrection ; my children do not marry! the children of this world do
                            marry, but as I am not of the world, so as my followers you must not be of the world." (John
                            xvii. 16.) " The angels do not marry, neither will those who live like the angels." (Luke
                            xx. 85, 36). How simple the testimony, yet how unplatable the cross ! Back fly the apolo-
                            gists, to a command given to the first man Adam and his followers; and refusing to see the
                            two orders—the flesh, generative, and the Spirit, resurrection above the flesh —fears for
                            the extinction of the world's inhabitants, conjoined to an ardent desire to prevent such
                            catastrophe, soon form a theological excuse from becoming angels just yet, and again, the
                            senses preponderate truth, the life of Christ; and the more effectually to blind the eyes of
                            the truthseeking, the once Church of Christ, which began its career by making brothers and
                            sisters of husbands and wives, is prostituted to the reversal of this rule, and glories in
                            making " children of this world" of those who should be the " Children of the Resurrection
                            "—Christ—Truth. We believe Christ actuated Jesus to an entire relinquishment of unchaste,
                            lustful manipulations, either individually or sexually. Some ignore the marriage bond, who
                            do not truth in their lascivious practices. Just so, some, in their illuminations of truth,
                            discard the "private property" error, while they indulge every other. Some see truth in
                            freedom from war— peace—yet enter a disclaimer if asked to put away the lusts that are the
                            cause of war! Do such seek truth ? The desires for fleshly lusts, for private property, for
                            martial glory, banish truth, and when these are banished, then will truth appear. Were
                            Jesus, under the influence of Christ, to enter the various places of worship, witness the
                            fashions, the rich and poor; the libertine, the military heroes ; husbands and wives,
                            representatives of millions of private property, together with a theology concocted for the
                            purpose of their continuance, we believe he would feel a holy indignation, that, though it
                            might not call for a scourge of small cords, yet would he rouse the congregations to the
                            truth, that sooner or later they must face the testimony : " Whoso would be my disciple, let
                            him follow me; I am the way, the truth and the life." *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Constitution and bible: doctrinal finality" TEIform="index"/>Constitution and Bible DOCTRINAL
                            FINALITY</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">" There is a spirit in man, and the inspiration of the Almighty giveth him understanding."
                            There is also in man a desire for doctrinal finality—a completed and perfected system ; like
                            the village that was finished fifty years ago. In esse, this is right, as indicative of a
                            time when there shall be "no darkness at all" in the human soul, even as there is none in
                            Deity. Perverted, it is forever concluded that the end of the journey, in pursuit of truth,
                            is already reached. A man or woman who resists the tendency to a fixity which organization
                            engenders, moving as the Spirit moves, increasing with the increase of God, creating the
                            letter of the future, rather than being bound by the letter of the past, produces trouble to
                            themselves and their organization. War—controversy, hatred, and persecution—follows in due
                            course of time. Authority requires an inquisition to keep its subjects on the basis of creed
                            and dogma, lest they substitute therefor the rock of Revelation. " Woe unto those who are at
                            ease in Zion," who seek to escape the disquiet of continual investigations, occasioned by
                            the influx of new truths. The Constitution! the Constitution! was the war-cry of the South.
                            To it, the Spirit of Truth on the political plane daringly responded, " What is the
                            Constitution ? Who made the Constitution ? and the answer came back from the L <pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 5O THE SHAKER. "sovereign people:" We uttered the declaration of principles,
                            and of independence of all Constitutional Governments then in existence; when the
                            Conservatives replied, we will have and wage endless war, unless you let us have a
                            Constitution that shall be a compromise—a covenant— between your Radicalism and our Con-
                            servatisim, in which our " Peculiar Institution," and a few other peculiar things, shall be
                            incorporated and protected; which covenant shall not be revoked, nor the Constitution
                            amended, except by mutual consent; and that consent we will never give. Thus your
                            declaration of rights and abstract principles shall never be practically attained, except by
                            and through another bloody Revolution. That bloody Revolution came in due time, and the "
                            Peculiar Institution " found no place in the now amended Constitution. Will the other
                            peculiar things ever be removed withotit another, and another, bloody Revolution ? Or, will
                            the Civil Government become, to the Church, as the moon to the sun ? and will the Church
                            become as the sun, shining on and on forever ? The Bible ! the Bible! is the cry raised
                            against Progress in the Church. But its living members undauntingly ask, What is the Bible?
                            Who made the Bible? How many Bibles are there ? Did not God and Christ, and "all truth,"
                            exist before the Bible ? Again: Who translated these Bibles after they were made ? And
                            history answers: As was the Constitution to the Declaration of first principles by the
                            nation's fathers and founders, so is the Bible—so are all Bibles—to the sermon on the mount,
                            and to the Pentecostal fathers of Christianity—to the simple declarations and statements of
                            first principles by Jesus and his immediate followers, who finally gathered together in the
                            Christ Spirit, and upon the foundation of those abstract, simple principles, in a
                            Pentecostal Church, practicing celibacy, and holding in common all temporal property. It is
                            well known that the Catholic Bible was formed by the Council of Nice 300 years after the
                            events it purports to record had transpired. While the Protestant Bible, by king James, was
                            a thousand years later coming into existence. The men who translated these Bibles (for no
                            women have yet translated any Bible) were, as compared with men of our own time, ignorant of
                            science. They believed in the Trinity, the Atonement, the vicarious sacrifice of Jesus for
                            our race, provided they became orthodox ; the resurrection of the body, and that the earth
                            was only 6,000 years from its creation out of nothing, and that by the mere fiat of will of
                            a Being. To them God and the devil existed somewhere in the natural universe. One had a city
                            made of all precious things that were grand and good; the other was in a pit, with no bottom
                            to it, filled with brimstone in a state of ignition, like the crater of Vesuvius that never
                            goes out. Would, or could, these translators fail to find, or to put into their Bibles, the
                            irrational and absurd theological ideas of which they were possessed? That they did this,
                            each affirms and demonstrates of the other. Jerusalem did ever stone her Prophets; and the
                            Zion of the day was ever indignant whenever a new Zion was born. The struggle between
                            organization and revelation is continuous unto the " end of the world ; " until all worldly
                            elements are worked out of the organization, and God rules supreme therein. As Gideon said
                            to the people, "I will not rule over you; neither shall my son rule over you. God shall rule
                            over you." As the Christ Spirit passed from Elijah to Elias, so did the Christ Spirit pass
                            from John the Baptist to Jesus. As a Jewish reformer and master, John had baptized Jesus
                            with water, after his confession. But he had previously been inspired to know that, amongst
                            those who came to him to be baptized, the Messiah would be made known to him by a certain
                            sign; and, when he saw the Spirit of Christ as a dove, resting upon and abiding with him, he
                            knew that the Christ had passed from himself to Jesus, and that he was to become the
                            Messiah, i. e., to incarnate the Christ in his character; and then, as he was decreasing and
                            Jesus increasing, he said to him, Comest thou to me to be baptized ? thou didst well; and I
                            did well in baptizing thee. But now I have still more need to come to thee, and be baptized
                            "with fire and the Holy Ghost," than you had to come to me confessing your Jewish sins, and
                            being baptized with water, for I must confess all that the Christ Spirit has come to burn
                            up. As the natural creation was progressive, so was the spiritual. The moral, spiritual, and
                            religious nature of man was of gradual development in Noah, Abraham, Moses, and in Jesus.
                            Their histories evidence that they learned as long as they lived. The Spirit in Noah created
                            Bible, or record, for Abraham; perhaps only in the form of tradition. The Spirit in Abraham
                            did the same for Moses; and Moses made Bible for the Prophets, down to Jesus; and Jesus made
                            Bible for Ann Lee—" the Scriptures of truth." Ann could read ; but she could not read the
                            Catholic or the Protestant Bibles, nor any outward record. What a blessing! seeing that it
                            made her the more dependent upon the Spirit—upon Revelation. And thus may each true
                            Christian throw himself upon the rock of Revelation, and have all traditions, records, and
                            Bibles broken to pieces. Because the first class of reformers do so much, shall the next
                            class do nothing but ape and worship them ? The Christ Spirit in Jesus, declared that his
                            successors should not only do the same works that he himself had done; but that they should
                            exceed him in that respect. "All truth " must exist, before any could progress into it. In
                            Noah's time, the millions of earth were sensualists; while he was perfect in his generations
                            for 600 years. Abram, came into spiritual truth beyond all Mesopotamia ; being the father of
                            a new people, who practiced self-restraint in generation, as Noah had done before him. Moses
                            stood opposed to and by all Egypt in relation to the substance of the whole of the Mosaic
                            laws and institutes. Jesus " trod the winepress alone ; " and Ann Lee was one of a company
                            of eight only, to found the Gospel in America.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us seek health!" TEIform="index"/>Let us Seek Health!</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Amery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AMERY</byline><p TEIform="p">In this day of light and knowledge, any attempt made to attribute bodily ailments, such as
                            headaches, disorders of the stomach, and nervous debility, to some unknown cause, is justly
                            regarded as unfair; and if, as some claim, that in their special case it is not to be
                            avoided, do they not judge that the Lord is dealing very partially with them ? Has the Lord
                            intended that we should be sick ? Has he, by a fixed and unalterable decree, determined that
                            we shall have the headache, be sick unto death with dyspepsia, or has he decreed that, in
                            obedience to his laws, we shall enjoy health ? Let us not evade the issue. Our profession is
                            to do God's will. If it is not his will that we should be sick, let us either ascertain for
                            ourselves or from others what law we are transgressing, and sin no more. Has any one ever
                            traveled out of the lusts of the flesh without experiencing at the commencement of their
                            travel an awakening of the low and sensual desires of that " serpentine nature?" We think
                            not. Those who desired deliverance from it, being tormented with it, readily embraced the
                            testimony against it, and accepted the means placed at their disposal to overcome it. Count
                            it not strange that they who are not convicted should be indifferent, but the testimony
                            against the lusts of the flesh convicted many of its sinfulness and impurity, who at first
                            were thoughtless. " The whole need not a physician," said Jesus. Those who through improper
                            eating or drinking were made sick, and who earnestly desired health at any sacrifice, would
                            eagerly accept any course of diet which would give it; and such, upon their restoration to
                            health, would, of course, have an experience and testimony <pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER.
                            51 to give to others, and doing as " they would others should do to them," whenever they
                            meet one afflicted as they had been, would naturally proffer their advice, whether it was
                            accepted or not. If one who has been dyspeptic sees a brother or sister eating or drinking
                            that which caused nauseating sensations in their experience, is it wrong for them to state
                            to the sufferer that abstinence from that article of diet removed the feeling ? Having been
                            a confirmed dyspeptic, miserably sick day and night, and through abstinence from certain
                            articles of diet, and fasting at times, measurably diminished the inordinate desire for
                            food, and rid myself of the sickness—enjoying reasonable health as I do, is it strange that
                            I should firmly believe that others afflicted in the same manner that I Avas, may be cured
                            by the adoption of the same means ? Many, when approached upon the subject) say they don't
                            believe they could do without this or that article. Believing where we can know, is
                            weakness. And feeling that we cannot do without, what science and the experience of others
                            prove to be hurtful to our health, is only an evidence of our abject servitude to a depraved
                            and unnatural taste. To put the matter plainly, it is letting our appetites (lusts) tell our
                            minds what they intend to do, instead of our rational faculties deciding what is lawful and
                            for the best. No one will get out of the flesh without suffering, nor need they expect to
                            get out of any evil without tribulation. Any one so bound to any article of diet, as to be
                            unwilling to sacrifice it, if economy and health demand it, is certainly (according to the
                            degree of their opposition) a slave to appetite. Christ's gift of healing was thought to be
                            a great one; but as the ability to live without sin is superior to all the " carnal
                            washings," so is the gift to keep icell superior and more to be desired than any gift of
                            healing, which, if sickness be a " transgression of law," could onby be temporary in its
                            effect. As lovers of truth, and desirous of progression, let us have a keen testimony
                            against lusts of every kind, being assured that " truth alone prevails." Whitewater, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-government" TEIform="index"/>Self-Government</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">To wisely speak and rightly act, In no case deviating, Require deep thought, much caution,
                            care. Perhaps some hesitating. For he who ventures out to Sea, Tho' in a course well beaten,
                            Keed oft observe the Polar Star, The point of compass taken. It is a work of nicest skill To
                            rule one's self completely, Bay after day, year after year— In all, perform discreetly. He
                            who his tongue would govern well, Must first control his passions; For most assured, the
                            latter are The " stepstone *' to expressions. Talk not too much—speak not in vain— Beware of
                            little errors; Like Jesus, overcome the world, Yea, face the •' King of Terrors!" What tho'
                            our natures plead for ease, And for indulgence prattle, The Cross of Christ will limit
                            these, And hold us to the battle. Jesus, our guide and pattern too, Sought not his own will
                            merely; He lived for higher purposes, And wrought redemption dearly. He gave his life of
                            carnal birth For Life that is eternal, Inviting all to follow him, And with him reign
                            supernal. ;Tis not the noisy winds nor waves, Tornadoes, avalanches— That make our hearts
                            harmonious blend, With inward, heavenly dances. The sturdy oak may stubborn stand And face
                            the storm and thunder; But the willow bows most gracefully, And lets the winds pass over.
                            Soft words do more to quell the foe Than volleys of vexation; Speak kindly then, and thereby
                            show We abound in good sensations. For, from the heart the mouth doth speak, The tongue doth
                            utter phrases, Some little spark of strife, when lit— Oh ! what a flame it raises ! The
                            still small voice—the voice of love— Kind looks, and speeches pleasant, Will heal the wounds
                            misfortune gives, And happily the present. 'Twill rend from social life distrust, Discord,
                            and cold embraces. Make desolation teem with life, With joy and smiling faces. Then Heaven
                            will not yonder be, Above the clouds, and hidden, But here on Earth, the Kingdom's come, In
                            which all souls are bidden; The lame and blind, the deaf and dumb, Xo sex nor color
                            slighted, A glorious Jubilee to all— And Heaven and Earth united.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Continence and community" TEIform="index"/>Continence and Community</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">There are moral and spiritual truths, either discovered or revealed, which are as fixed and
                            eternal as mathematical ones, and equally demonstrable. "Ye cannot serve God and Mammon."
                            This aphorism, first uttered by Jesus over 1800 years ago, did not then begin to be a truth;
                            it is a fixed and eternal verity. Beings in the condition of the human race cannot serve God
                            with all their mind and might, as He requires, and at the same time give up their hearts and
                            lives to the acquisition of riches. This is a truth that exists eternally and unchangeably
                            in all worlds. This same truth has been again uttered in other words near the beginning of
                            the 19th century by a modern poet: " Within the human breast Two master passions cannot
                            co-exist." Mammon means riches, wealth; sometimes personified as the God or Demon of riches.
                            The two conditions of mind, devotion to God and devotion to Mammon can no more co-exist in
                            the human breast, than two parallel lines can cross each other. This repugnance of these two
                            conditions, this impossibility with regard to man in his intellectual constitution and
                            present moral condition, and the requirements of Christ's gospel, or the Christian
                            institution upon him, is as certain, unchangeable, eternal and ubiquitous as any mathe-
                            matical truth. Therefore, in order to be a Christian, a man must divest himself of per-
                            sonal wealth. The brotherly love and perfect equality which eternal truth enjoins on
                            Christians, forever debar them from personal wealth, and require them to support a joint
                            interest, and to have their goods in common. The possession of personal wealth and equality
                            of enjoyment are conditions forever repugnant to one another and to eternal truth. Therefore
                            Jesus required the young man to sell all his personal possessions in order to gain an
                            inheritance and treasure in the heavenly kingdom which he was about to set up. He required
                            all others who would be his disciples. " Whosoever he be of you that forsake not all that he
                            hath, can not be my disciple." The rule of Jesus in regard to property is, individual
                            poverty and social abundance. The marriage relation is forever repugnant to equality of
                            possession ; and this repugnance is founded in "the eternal nature of things. If the young
                            man had obeyed Jesus and made himself a pauper, he would have been utterly unqualified for
                            entering the generative order and raising a family. And it was impossible for him to obey
                            that other command of Jesus, " Come follow me," and at the same time perform the work of
                            procreation. Jesus cannot be followed where Jesus did not go. The generative order
                            necessarity requires separate interests, and the possession of personal property; and this,
                            too, has its foundation in the very nature of things. Consequently, the generative is
                            forever repugnant to the Christ order, which requires the relinquishment of all personal
                            property. " The flesh lusteth against the spirit, and the spirit against the flesh, and
                            these two are contrary the one to the other." The truth of this irrepressible conflict of
                            flesh and spirit did not then begin to be, when it was first announced by Paul, but is
                            eternal and unchangeable, and exists everywhere in God's universe when they come in contact.
                            The order of the flesh existed from Adam to Moses, and from Moses to Jesus: Un- ceasing
                            diligence was exerted to bring it into order and subject it to law. "Divers wash- ings and
                            carnal ordinances," with many other restraints, were imposed by divine sanction, but all
                            without success, as testified by the martyr Stephen: "Ye do always resist the Holy Spirit,
                            as your father did so do ye." Thus, an experiment extended through 4000 years develops an
                            unbroken testimony to the existence of an eternal truth—a fixed law— that the flesh alivays
                            resists the spirit—that " the carnal mind is not subject to the law oi God, neither indeed
                            can be." A fixed and immutable law of the generative order is to multiply and divide. Thus a
                            series of successive divisions and separations of interest is continued. The fixed and
                            immutable law of the regenerative order is aggregation—gathering together uniting in one
                            till it reaches the whole brotherhood of man. The fleshly dispensation or procreative order,
                            is that in which a man and wife become " one flesh " for the purpose of procreat- ing a,
                            fleshly offspring. " That which is born of the flesh is flesh." The spiritual dispensation
                            inaugurated by Jesus, is that in which a man " forsakes the <pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 52 THE
                            SHA.KEK. wife," and all fleshly relations, to become one with Christ in being spiritual
                            offspring. " He that is joined to the Lord is one in spirit with him," and " that which is
                            born of the spirit is spirit." " To be carnally minded is death, to be spiritually minded is
                            life." In this aphorism of Paul, he again sets forth the eternal antagonism of the flesh and
                            spirit. It is but the utterance, of a fixed, immutable and eternal truth—a truth which every
                            one who has been made alive in the spirit, knows just as well as Paul. The antagonism
                            between the flesh and spirit does not take place in the air, but in the human breast, and
                            every spiritually minded man knows that this connict is irreconcilable—knows that his
                            carnal, lustful, generative nature is not subject to the law of God in the Christ order,
                            neither indeed can be—knows that he must keep up an unceasing warfare against it, at the
                            peril of his spiritual life, until it is subdued. "If ye be risen with Christ, seek those
                            things that are above,'1'' where Christ dwells. Those counted worthy of this resurrection—
                            those who have risen with Christ and live in his sphere "above " the flesh, neither marry
                            nor are given in marriage. " They are children of the resurrection order, who follow Jesus
                            in the regeneration, and are exalted with him above the generative work.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Temple which hath foundations" TEIform="index"/>A Temple which Hath Foundations."</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Matt. vii. 24, and Hogged ii. 6, 7, 8. Tempered with sadness is onrjoy, And'prayers our
                            thoughts employ, For avarice which walked on high, Whose temples almost touched the sky,
                            Knows not, alas ! its doom is nigh, But vainly strives to build anew The temples oi" the
                            past, And makes of earthly clay and dew A temple that will last. The glory of the latter
                            day, Whose strength shall bear truth's keenest ray, Must be with broad foundations laid,
                            With justice and with virtue stayed, And righteousness so long delayed; All else will surely
                            sweep away, All refuges of lies, All shaken in that burning day, When grim oppression
                        dies.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O, tempora, o, mores!" TEIform="index"/>O, Tempora, O, Mores!</head><p TEIform="p">We are in receipt of very many letters that bewail the conditions of the sectarian world— of
                            its high professions, yet poor practices ; of its advanced call to higher life, and from un-
                            christian loves and lusts, with so small reply. The following, from a Rev. Dr., near Spring-
                            field, Mass., puts the case, not just as we should ; but, we believe, fully as strong as his
                            congregations will bear with him ; and we have no doubt, if he continues thus to preach, he
                            will have to flee to the rocks and caves of Shaker homes for protection. His name is free to
                            those interested. "who are the infidels?" * * * " The essential features of the testimony of
                            Jesus are: That his followers must be of ' one soul and mind, and have all things in
                            common;' and, ' that it is good for a man not to touch a woman." " The first will prevent
                            temptations to stealing, cheating, prostitution, etc., lessen labor, do away with armies^
                            castles, war, police; so that there can be better education, better living, and more comfort
                            for all. " In the second, we find a prohibition to marriage, free love, fornication, and
                            lust generally, as now found inside and outside of the marriage order; all must live as
                            sisters and brothers. He that is already married, must " lead about his wife as a sister." "
                            The original says, not that marriage is honorable; but let marriage be (made) honorable ;
                            that is, abstain from carnal intercourse even in marriage. The Catholics say : " That the
                            irrational, insane stupidity of carnal intercourse cannot be pointed out too clearly, nor
                            condemned too severely." Those who preach much of an all-good, all-wise Creator, must know
                            he cannot love to see such miserable children as they produce; that they interfere with his
                            right to produce the best. " Even though I say it, so-called Christians who fail to live up
                            to these two foundational doctrines, are infidels to Christianity ; hypocrites to the cause;
                            liars in profession; sailing under false colors, and unworthy the confidence of the true
                            believers in Christ. "There are very many Eevs., who believe these assertions as truly as I
                            do; yet none of us dare preach but a part of the truth for most obvious reasons. The Shaker
                            is doing a silent, but terrible work to old theologies; and is the only medium I know of,
                            that dares make known the whole truth, without the loss of its bread and butter, together
                            with inquisitorial persecution."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., D. J." TEIform="persName"/>D. J. M.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Act from principle" TEIform="index"/>Act from Principle</head><p TEIform="p">How few persons there are whose lives are governed entirely by principle, rather than in-
                            clination. Even those of us who may be endeavoring to live for high purposes, come far short
                            of our aspirations; alas, how very far short ! How often Ave find ourselves debating with
                            our convictions of right and duty, questioning if it might not be as well for us to yield to
                            inclination just for this time, promising our disturbed consciences that we will make up for
                            the present indulgence by more rigorous self-denial, and strict attention to duty.— Vain,
                            fallacious reasoning of a weak nature ! We can never make up for a neglected opportunity,
                            one misspent hour, one wrong, selfish act. Once past, the opportunity unimproved, the hour
                            wasted, the act committed, and it is beyond our reach—beyond recall, except in thoughts of
                            regret. We may atone for it, but we can never change the past. Alas ! how painfully are we
                            aware of this fact. Then should we all endeavor the more earnestly to make our lives
                            ornaments of principle ; for we all know that after all, the path of duty, though sometimes
                            rugged, is not without sweet pleasures; and let us never follow our inclinations, if they
                            would lead us away from the right. Then shall we be permitted at the last to look back upon
                            our lives with satisfaction, feeling that we have " done what we could," and that our Father
                            regardeth us with smiles of approbation.—ZelVs Casket.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Answers to correspondents" TEIform="index"/>Answers to Correspondents</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">" Is marriage, as generally practiced, wrong in all cases?" We answer in the negative. Where
                            there is no law manifested to the individual higher than marriage, let him practice it,
                            Jesus answered this question very properly, see Matt. 19, 11. Some want and will have no
                            higher law, until they are forced to do so; others, like the Shakers, seek to know God's
                            will, and to do it. " How does marriage affect the spirit ?" By bringing it under bondage to
                            the generative order—the dominion of the first man— earthy; and by preventing its entrance
                            into the Christian ranks, its whole being is consecrated, not in the service of the God of
                            the Christians, but of the Jews, where marriage, war, private property and their
                            consequences were and are popular. If you are a professor of Christianity, and adore
                            marriage, compare your profession with 1 Cor., 7 chap. 32, 33, 34, and either repent, or
                            join the Jews, and strictly keep the marriage laws. " Is it wrong to work for an
                            independence in riches?" No man has any right to be rich. The gospel teaches Christians to
                            share alike. Whoever is rich, should know, one or many are consequently correspondingly
                            poor. The gospel says to the mountainous rich, come down, and to those in the valley of
                            poverty, rise up. The rich are still comfortable, while the poor are made equally so. Now
                            take conscience and an eternity of reflection into the council, and our word for it, present
                            and future heaven would demand a liberal division. '"' Do you require individuals to give up
                            their money or other property upon joining ?&gt;J We do not, never have. Your
                            information is incorrect. Individuals are welcome to retain property in their own right; but
                            Society does claim, that while said individuals are enjoying its benefits, that the use or
                            interest of their property shall be for the upbuilding of the Cause. No individual would
                            desire to remain long in a society who had so little consecration that he meant to get what
                            he could and keep it. This is world-like, not Christian. Send for a copy of our "Brief
                            Exposition"—Six cents. " Why is it, that those who leave your Society are seldom or never
                            successful after they leave it ?" Shakerism spoils individuals for worldly enjoyment,
                            worldly ambition, etc. The fact is a notably true one, and admits of a larger illustration
                            than we can now give. He who would be a Shaker should seriously count its cost. There is
                            nothing terrible nor compulsory in the system. To its subjects it is all lovely. But he is a
                            fool who, having been on the firm basis of truthful life, could expect to succeed with God's
                            blessing, after forsaking the counsel of God. We know of no more pitiable case than a
                            seceding Shaker— and they share our pity. * Subscriptions for The Shaker may begin with July
                            Number, or with the beginning of the Volume, at the option of the subscriber.</p></div2><pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian home missions" TEIform="index"/>Christian Home Missions</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">While reading in the Golden Age of March 23, the account given by Marie Ladreyt of the child
                            labor in England, I had no doubt of the correctness of her statements. Every feeling heart
                            must be grieved at the bare recital of such deep degradation and misery on the one side, and
                            the utter depravity and brutality on the other. We have just rid ourselves of chattel
                            slavery—that incubus which was fast sinking the nation into ruin, and which was enough to
                            make everj* true American blush for the honor of his country. But American slavery is
                            civilization and refinement compared with the condition of many thousands of children in the
                            factory districts of England. But we need not go to England to find sufferings and objects
                            of charity ; to find work for philanthropists and reformers; for though we have done much
                            there is still much that remains to be done. There yet are untold sufferings in this
                            counrry. Who, that having lived in our cities, but has been pained to see the extravagance
                            and luxury of the rich, and the abject poverty and degraded condition of the poor ? It is
                            true that many philanthropic individuals have done nobly; having given largely of their
                            abundance for bettering the condition of the needy. But does this reach the root of the
                            matter ? Is it not like lopping off a branch here and there, while the tree still grows and
                            bears its bitter fruit? Our friend Marie, after having faithfully delineated the vast amount
                            of misery it costs to earn wealth and procure luxuries for a small minority, more than hints
                            at the remedy. She asks, "Is it strange that Communism finds so many advocates, and that it
                            gains ground so rapidly in all countries ?" I suppose, of course, she means the rapid spread
                            of the doctrine—the idea; for it is no where practically carried into effect except in the
                            United States. In the regular progress of mind, we must first have ideas and then practice ;
                            and it is an encouraging fact that the idea of Communism is so extensively being embraced.
                            But can Europe, and England in particular, do nothing in the mean time to ameliorate the
                            condition of her poor outraged and suffering children ? England ! who sends missions to
                            christianize China, Hindostan, the Isles of the Ocean, and to the ends of the earth, while
                            there are millions in her own domains, more degraded and worse abused, than in any heathen
                            nation on the globe. Yet she claims to stand at the head of the civilized nations— boasts
                            that she is the bulwark of the Protestant religion ! It is well to call it protestant, for
                            certainly it is a protest to Christianity. Out upon such Christianity—such Christians ! "
                            Why call ye me Lord, Lord ? " Shall we advise her to send missionaries to humanize her
                            suffering children ? Of what use to preach, or try to instruct them in their present
                            condition ? If they had a passport to the Kingdom, they would barter it for a loaf of bread,
                            or a bottle of whiskey. But are these really the heathen ? Are not those who oppress the
                            poor ; who rob the hireling of his wages to fill their own coffers, that they may live in
                            splendor and revel in luxury—-are not these the heathen ? And I had almost said paupers too;
                            for they are a non-producing class, living on the earnings of others without a just
                            remuneration. But what use of knowing these things—of having our sympathies awakened, unless
                            we can do something for their relief—unless we can apply a remedy ? If every thing has
                            failed heretofore to reach the case, suppose we try something new? At least new on the other
                            side of the water. It has already been tried on this side to a limited extent, and, as far
                            as it has been practiced, it has proved effectual. There can be nothing valuable gained
                            without self-denial and the cross, and these are what mankind do not naturally love. The
                            times call for self-sacrificing souls, that are willing to suffer and bear and do for the
                            advancement of the race. The remedy for this vast and growing evil cannot be reached in any
                            other way. Are not the devout every where praying: " Thy kingdom como, thy will be done on
                            earth as it is done in heaven ?" Is there heaven on earth ? Is not hell there too ? As one
                            advances, the other must give way. We need a pentecostal baptism to relax our grasp on our
                            earthly possessions ! There is land enough, and wealth enough, were it equalized, for every
                            individual to have a competence, and every child property educated. Shaker Communism, we
                            believe is a sure remedy. No member of the Community ever suffers for food, clothing or
                            shelter; but mankind seem unprepared for so much self-denial. Let those over the waters, or
                            on this side, who embrace the theory of Communism, organize and enter into the practical
                            life which their theory calls for. If they cannot yet bear a full cross or deny themselves
                            as far, or as much as Shafcerism calls for, let them come as near as they can, and thus test
                            the truth of their theory, and the Shakers will bid them Godspeed. Let every one who has a
                            heart to feel for down-trodden humanity, consider the subject and act upon it. Union
                            Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">The two articles following are from some of our Shaker correspondents. We feel ashamed to say
                            they were sent anonymously. As they have kept so long and so well in the " pigeon hole,'' we
                            have concluded to depart our usual rule, and print them, as valuable additions to our
                            literature and testimony, whose authors we wish to know, and to chastise. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's rights" TEIform="index"/>Woman's Rights</head><p TEIform="p">"WOULDST -THOU RULE? RULE THYSELF." Genesis, in, 16. Evidently in this text is the voice of
                            nature; even those must admit who deny its being the voice of nature's God; and fearfully
                            has the prediction been fulfilled, as physiological researches abundantly prove. "And thy
                            desire shall be to thy husband, and he shall rule over thce." This sentence shows, that "in
                            the beginning" man did not rule, at least, in whatever it is herein declared he shall; and
                            farther, that the transfer of rule was the consequence of woman's desire. Fortunately for
                            the skeptical, experience as well as science comes to the aid of revelation in proof of
                            this. The maiden still rules; the wife must serve. The transfer of rule continues with the
                            continuance of the curse. Now, since the necessity for man's reproducing his kind upon the
                            earth, could alone necessitate the difference in sex, and that difference alone, makes it
                            necessary or even possible for either to rule in any general sense, it follows, that the
                            rule spoken of in the text must have reference to the procreative function. And since the
                            duties of maternity must necessarily restrict the action of the female; and those of
                            paternity as necessarily leave the male unrestricted; it follows, that whatever should
                            subject the female, in any department of the animal kingdom, to male rule, must be
                            productive of disorder. And if, with the logically admitted power in the ruler to govern the
                            ruled, we admit a desire in the ruled to be governed, we shall begin to comprehend the force
                            of the text. Shall we admit this, and thus easily account for the disorders of society; thus
                            easily solve the "m3Tstery of iniquity "—" take away the vail from the face of all nations
                            ?" Shall we accept the scriptural account, in so far, at least, as to admit that depraved
                            denizens of the spirit world found means to poison the mind of our first mother with the
                            virus of illicit desire, thus corrupting the streams of human life at their fountainhead,
                            and greatly multiplying the sorrows of earth as a natural consequence? We of the Shaker
                            order do admit this ; do believe it to be the only logical clue to the unraveling of the "
                            mystery of godliness." We believe that the human race, in common with the animal, were
                            indued in their creation with instincts, laws, powers, adequate to their preservation in
                            health and happiness; that the fact that mankind have not been so preserved while the animal
                            has is incontestable proof that these instincts have been followed—these laws obeyed—these
                            powers employed by the latter, according to the design of the Creator, while by the other,
                            they have not; and that to the difference in their habits alone, is to be ascribed the dif-
                            ference in their conditions. And since the principal difference in their habits relates to
                            the procreative right, we can but conclude, that herein is seen the principal cause of the
                            physical degeneracy and moral depravity of the human race to-day. That herein is seen "the
                            root of the trees which the Father hath not planted; " and what woman complains of, low
                            wages; monopoly of business pursuits; injustice of the laws ; being deprived of the
                            franchise, etc., are but legitimate branches; and only by applying the axe at the root of
                            the evil trees, can she reasonably expect the branches to wither. And thus believing, we
                            easily see the necessity for the second appearance of Christ, or rather, the manifestation
                            of the Second Christ, " the Comfortor," in her own order, to restore to woman, not only her
                            long lost rule (of herself), but a power in addition, enabling her to preserve and employ
                            her charms in a far more noble cause than that of generation (noble as that is when con-
                            ducted in an orderly manner), to wit, in that THE SHAKER. <pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> of
                            regeneration. And here she has no cause to complain of the usurpation of her rights by the
                            man; for the life of purity which, following Christ in the regeneration necessitates, places
                            them precisely in the relation of brother and sister, where they are alike mutually
                            dependent and mutually independent. Doing away with the " trouble in the flesh," and
                            bringing, oh, how abundantly, the blessings of the Spirit! And all who will, may come and
                            partake of the waters (blessings of this kind) of life freely. But, plead not for your
                            rights, 0 woman ! so long as you voluntarily surrender them. Dream not of liberty, so long
                            as you desire to be a slave. " Wouldst rule? Rule thyself." North Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exhort one another to good works" TEIform="index"/>"Exhort one another to good Works."</head><p TEIform="p">Many, styling themselves, no doubt, Christian youths, are spending much valuable time in
                            devouring the poisonous literature which is floating unrestrainedly through the land. Beware
                            ! their word will eat as doth a canker, as many, made weak by it, can testify ; • their
                            word,' whose highest aim is wealth; which aim they pursue regardless of the evil influence
                            they exert, in obtaining their hold upon the innocent mind. Who was it that said not long
                            since to a bright youth absorbed in reading a corrupting novel, "I hate, abhor, those
                            sickly, sentimental stories ? " It was, I think, Pure Mind ! She also exhorted youth to more
                            faithfulness in cultivating the better part of their nature, by reading such books as
                            contain instruction for mental and physical improvement; she told them to study, and to
                            meditate upon the thoughts and actions of the good and great, and to strive to emulate their
                            example ; and that in so doing they would increase their internal beauty. Reflection and
                            experience prove that more, of real value, is learned outside of books than inside of them.
                            The bulk of mankind have to procure a physical and spiritual livelihood ; and it is obvious
                            that those things are of the most value which tend to increase facilities to this end. Books
                            are of value for two purposes : to train the mind of youth, so that they may be prepared to
                            receive, with ease, ideas when presented to them; and that their minds may, by exercise, be
                            rendered flexible, and capable of pursuing sustained trains of thought, and to increase in
                            their powers of observation both of external and of spiritual things; secondly, to enable
                            the mind as it comes to maturity, to receive with advantage the thoughts of others; that is,
                            as an assistance to thought, not to give them a mastery over the mind. It should, however,
                            be constantly borne in mind that reading should never be made the chief aim of life. It is
                            necessary for the enlightenment of the understanding ; but the progress of individuals is
                            the chief aim of life, or rather the only design of our existence. It being true, then, of
                            those books, the matter of which is, in itself, good, that they should be used as a means
                            and not as an end, it is clearly of the greatest importance for youth—a time of life when
                            things which affect the imagination are generally deeply impressed on the mind—to carefully
                            avoid everything which does not conduce to solid improvement. The mind is like the stomach :
                            those who live sparingly on plain nourishing food, and take plenty of exercise, are
                            invariably healthy; while those who diet is luxurious, stimulating and excessive, suffer
                            from diseases of all kinds. Thus it is with the mind : reading that trains the mind, or
                            brings to our aid the thoughts of others, as above stated, and thus nourishes thought in
                            ourselves, is good J but that reading which merely excites the feeling, and increases or
                            generates morbid fancies, a light and unsettled state of the mind, is bad to the last
                            degree. Those minds which progress are always more occupied in thinking than in reading; and
                            the healthier the tone of thought the more rapid the progress. Use books to sourish a
                            progressive state of the mind, not to clog the brain with mental rubbish. Again: Reading of
                            particular kinds, though proper for some persons, is not proper for others. Thus, those who
                            have found out that their spiritual welfare is of more importance to them than their
                            temporal, inasmuch as the former is for Eternity, the latter for time, will find that
                            reading sufficient which assists the spirit to free itself from temporal influences, and to
                            discover spiritual truths; but those who have not been fortunate enough to strike on this
                            path, are occupied mainly with their own temporal welfare, or in the discovery of physical
                            and intellectual truth. But those, whose time and talents are occupied in the discovery of
                            means to rouse and stimulate unhealthy cravings for excitement of feeling in the young, are
                            most viciously employed; a-*d the mind that admits their influence will certainly be
                            injured. My youthful friends, there are abundant means within our reach for cultivating our
                            being's highest good. Let us thus exercise the spirit of watchfulness over our minds, aad
                            let us remember that the reading of exciting, vicious stories forms no part of the vocation
                            of a Christian.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust in God" TEIform="index"/>Trust in God</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">When clouds obscure the land, Should we in darkness roam; Oh ! Lord extend thy hand, And
                            kindly lead us home. We give our liearts to thee ; We would be wholly thine, Thy grace will
                            make us free, Thy love will make divine. Whate'er is needful here, We know that thou wilt
                            give; And be thou ever near, For only then we live. The only wealth we have, Is treasured up
                            above; The only wealth we crave, Is thy approving love. Earth has on us no claim; We've
                            severed every tie; Home, fortune, friends and fame, We've bid them all good-bye. Thou art,
                            Oh God, our all; WTe ask for nothing more, Let good or ill befall, Thy name we'll still
                            adore. Be thon our Father, Friend, As we thy children arc; AVhen weak, thy blessing send',
                            When wrong, in mercy spare. Though ill then oft betide, And friendship still betray, Well in
                            thy faith abide, And keep thy Living way.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Middle Granville, November 15, 1871" TEIform="index"/>Middle Granville, Nov. 15th, 1871</head><p TEIform="p">To the Dear Brethren and Sisters: Yours of the 29th ult. is duly received. I freely
                                acknowledge my thankfulness for the good expressions therein contained; I am fully
                                convinced that the standard of Right, Truth, and Divine Light among your people, is
                                towering far above all emblems of Light, given under the seal of Church Policy,
                                ignorantly sustained, through faith in sacrificial offerings of materialism and the shed
                                blood of one body, with other machinations of Priestcraft, all under the sanction of a
                                fighting Church. How aptly are they styled "blind leaders of the blind ! " how low, at
                                the veiy base, of all knowledge of a God of Love and Truth; and how ignorant of the true
                                resurrection of Christ, in the soul! His divine attributes are love, not hate, truth
                                without error, light which expels all darkness, and charity without selfishness. I truly
                                did enjoy that spirit of love and harmony which I realized among your people; it is a
                                baptism I crave, for every moment of my life, but my surroundings are not always
                                favorable for such enjoyment. While on my visit to the dear Shakers, in Enfield Conn.,
                                one }rear ago, I felt the spirit and power of God around and in me, realiz"ing the glory
                                revealed through the baptism of Love. Recently, I was influenced to visit your Society,
                                where I enjoyed, mingling in spirit with you, in the harmony and peace of your beloved
                                circle, receiving new impulses to be good and true, to learn more perfectly the laws of
                                myT being; and " the way " which is Christ, which leads me up the highways Oi
                                progression, through green pastures and by still waters; unfolding to my spiritual
                                vision new truths, and new beauties in the philosophy of life. I believe, however, that
                                your position has not been comprehended generally, by the world. But in this
                                dispensation, a new light has dawned upon the earth, that is revealing your true faith
                                and practice. Its soundness is being tested by others, their eyes being opened to behold
                                the light as revealed through the Spirit, I have not only a knowledge of it as given
                                through signs, but, in a visit to you, where blending our spirits, the light is still
                                more appreciated. I must confess I think the Shakers a little ahead of this
                                dispensation, which has shone out upon us all, for profit. The marriage question and
                                human rights in general, are having a fair and thorough appeal to common sense. God
                                speed the time, when all the ingonsistencies of dark Theology shall have a renovation of
                                character. Then we, Shakers and Spiritualists, with the Angels of God, can cry as of
                                old, Away with such abominations; and let the earth rejoice that a better covenant is
                                observed ; and humanity are being resurrected from darkness to light, through the second
                                coming of Christ. THE SHAKER. 54 <pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 55 His footsteps are
                                traceable back to the opening up of the dispensation, when the Shakers took a bold stand
                                against all iniquity; and now through the different phases of spiritual developement
                                among Spiritualists, the car is still moving on in which all, in time, are to be brought
                                to a knowledge of the Truth, and its resurrecting power. I find the operations of the
                                Spirit with me, are nearly allied to the exercises of the Shakers; not that I am free
                                from sin and ignorance, but am striving for the higher life; and believe that unborn
                                generations will grow more perfectly into this " way," and Shakers will be multiplied
                                without number. I speak boldly and honestly my idea.s; and I declare, I am not ashamed
                                of the gospel of Christ; it is the power of God unto salvation* Sincere love to all,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blossom, Eliza" TEIform="persName"/>Eliza Blossom</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Have the shakers made a mistake?" TEIform="index"/>"Have the Shakers made a Mistake?"</head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal for June, contained an article entitled " Have the Shakers made a
                            mistake?" and followed this question by an argument seeking to prove that Ann Lee never
                            taught celibacy, but merely chastity in marriage; and the following remark is what led to
                            our answer, appended hereto: " We have not found, we cannot find, anything in history to
                            warrant the inference that Ann Lee taught or practiced celibacy !" My Dear Wells : We have
                            been so familiar in the past, who shall say our spirits may not consult matters of history,
                            to-day ? You are in possession of the archives of mental and psychic forces. I may be
                            supposed to know more of Ann Lee's history—and this renews the query, " Have the Shakers
                            made a mistake ?" I will not perpetrate a wearisome rejoinder; but let me ask if it is
                            common for a class of individuals to become more radical than the founder of that class,
                            particularly upon a point so adverse to natural inclination, yet so conjoined to angel
                            nature as an entire abnegation of sexual coition ? Ann Lee was the leader of Shaker
                            Societies in her day, but is not now. Yet, having improved upon some of the themes and
                            practices of her day, we are only as strong on this, as she was. You give her large credit
                            as a sensible woman ; too much so, you think, to inaugurate a system so unnatural as ex-
                            isting Shakerism. Ann Lee never condemned marriage, but considered it the most honorable
                            relation outside of Christianity! Her testimony was not only against coition, but her
                            followers, upon uniting, enjoyed separate beds for the sexes. The Shakers admit the large
                            good in marriage, when properly conducted— but claim that there is no " kingdon of heaven "
                            on earth, in marriage. When the married die, they expect to enter into the ranks of angels,
                            who are living just as the Shakers do here, being Shakers. We believe, they then will wish
                            that they had learned angelic practices while here. Now, as to matters of history and fact,
                            let us quote Ann Lee's own words. Daniel Wood and others testify hearing her say: " Sometime
                            after I had set out to live up to the light of God, manifested through James and Jane
                            Wardly, I fell under heavy trials and tribulations on account of lodging with my husband;
                            and as I looked to them for counsel, I opened my mind to Jane. She said: James and I lodge
                            together, but we do not touch each other any more than two babes; you may go and do
                            likewise. " In obedience, I did so ; but could not sleep, seemingly, any more than if I had
                            been on a bed of embers. I quitted the bed in tribulation, and continued crying to God in
                            deep labors of soul, for the space of twelve days and nights, to know his will, and how the
                            restoration of the fall should take place. While in this labor, I saw Jesus, in vision. He
                            revealed to me the depth of man's loss, how it was accomplished, and how to regain lost
                            virtue. Then it was I was made able to bear an open testimony against coition, from which
                            the root of evil springs. Then I felt the power of God flow into my soul like a fountain of
                            living waters. From that day to the present, I have taken up a full cross, not only against
                            coition, but all the doleful works of the flesh! " We live as Brethren and Sisters together,
                            without any physical contact of the sexes, and keep a flaming testimony against individual
                            lusts, and thus shun " the very appearance of evil." Present to us an individual, who, being
                            married, and living under the most favorable circumstances of the reproductive sphere, who
                            is happier or more heavenly than a thorough-going, full crossbearing Shaker, and I will
                            reconsider the assertions, that Shakerism is the rudiments of the Kingdom of heaven on Earth
                            ; and that Marriage never was, and never can be a Christian institution ! Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This is for your health" TEIform="index"/>"This is for your Health."</head><p TEIform="p">The most popular and consistent Health journals of to-day are those which teach prevention of
                            disease; and where this has been contracted, direct applications of water or magnetic
                            baptisims. Of this class of journalism, we cannot speak too highly. It begins a reformation
                            of the physical race in the most proper direction—diet. And until this is accomplished, we
                            shall, from the unnatural concomitants of blood, continue to bewail the multiplication of
                            so-called human beings, of whom God cannot make Shakers. We have need of more good material
                            for Christ baptisms; and we hail every effort made on the earthly plane, to regulate the
                            diet of the race, through this its reproductions, and through both of these, teach man of
                            the two orders of existence, first the earthly, then the heavenly; and that properly
                            directed, expedites this. We call attention to The Herald of Health: is a good and re-
                            liable journal of its class. It has, in some late articles, dealt out to its readers some
                            xery unpalatable truths; but whoever has swallowed them, have been convinced of their
                            efficacy. Price, $1.25 per year, Wood &amp; Holbrook, New York. Home and Health, is also
                            deserving of much success. $1.50 a year. De Puy, Holmes &amp; Co., New York. The Laws of
                            Life, Danville, N. Y., comes from " Our home on the hillside"; and no journal tells more
                            truth about dress for females, and diet for dyspeptics. Austin, Jackson &amp; Co.,
                            Publishers. Send for sample copy. The Science of Health threatens to surpass all else in
                            counsels to the well and in its truth-telling to the sick. Whoever subscribes for this, may
                            " throw all medicine to the dogs"—who heretofore have been too sensible for the doctors. Its
                            appearance is strikingly beautiful. Price, $2.00 a year. S. K. Wells, New York.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True shaker discipline" TEIform="index"/>True Shaker Discipline</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>HARRIET BULLABD</byline><p TEIform="p">To be without fault should be the object of every professedly Christian soul. This is at-
                            tained only by severe discipline. To be a full Christian requires a complete subjection of
                            self unto the law of Christ. In the absence of Jesus, the apostles, ancient, holy men and
                            women, we must covenant to accept as our leaders and directors those of our own day who are
                            striving to faithfully represent Christ principles. Having so covenanted, willful dis-
                            obedience on our part is as really rebellion against Christ as though we had said "I will"
                            or "I won't" to the person of Jesus. It costs much self-denial always to yield self and
                            selfishness to known and accepted authority, but a cheerful and continued submission there
                            will prove a safeguard from other evils; while to rebel against this is worse than the
                            practice of gross evils, and will even sooner prove the downfall of any unwilling mind. Let
                            those who think they stand uprightly in all else but obedience to their present lead, take
                            heed, or soon they " Fall like stars to rise no more! "</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wanted" TEIform="index"/>Wanted
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Wanted:—A few hundred thousands or millions to investigate and " expose" Shakerism. We have
                            been so interested in those attempted, pro and con, that we hail with delight these various
                            attempts to illustrate and ventilate what we so love. If, in these varied illuminations, any
                            fraud, deceit or unrighteousness should appear, none will be happier to learn it than
                            ourselves, or more ready to condemn and eradicate it. Wanted : More " Expositions." *</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deceased</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bryant, J. Rufus" TEIform="index"/>J. Rufus Bryant
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bryant, J. Rufus" TEIform="persName">J. Rufus Bryant</persName>, Pleasant Hill, Ky., went to
                                rest on May 6th. He was a bright light in Zion's upbuilding. As a Trustee, he had few
                                equals in all that pertains to consecrated temporal aid and endeavor. We give Elder
                                Harvey Eades' announcement : " J. B. Bryant went to Heaven on the 6th.''</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hastings, Betsy" TEIform="index"/>Betsy Hastings
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Hastings, Betsy" TEIform="persName">Betsy Hastings</persName>, aged 67, May 25. at
                                Alfred, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baxter, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>Caroline Baxter
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In Shirley, Mass., 7th inst., <persName reg="Baxter, Caroline" TEIform="persName">Caroline
                                Baxter</persName>, 30 yrs. Also, several deaths at South Union, Ky., no names given.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Among many suggestions, in answer to our question in March, Elder J. S. Prescott urges an
                            assemblage of delegates at Watervliet or Mt. Lebanon, on Aug. 6, 1874, from every Society of
                            Believers ; and to invite the most advanced Spiritualists to attend the same.</p></div2><pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith's vision" TEIform="index"/>FAITH'S VISION</head><p TEIform="p">Affetuoso. North, Mt. L. it 1 To the spirit land we're hastening, Golden moments flit before, While each sunset brings us nearer To its seeming, distant shore. 2 Oft its pearly
                            gates are opened, Hoods of glory thro'them come; And we catch a glimpse of beauty, Juat a
                            foresight of our home. 3 Yet we ask their ministration While we tarry here below, And that
                            ever round our pathway Light in creasing still may glow. Yet up on her snowy pinions, Faith
                            will lift oar hearts to see, In the life that is before us, Blessed immortality. O it is
                            by holy living That we gain an entrance there; For communion with the Angels, Spotless
                            robes we must pie pare. If our lives are fraught with goodness, And the seeds of love we
                            sow, We shall reap a bundant blessing, And the joy of Angels know.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Items of interest" TEIform="index"/>Items of Interest</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are in receipt of glowing accounts of Shaker meetings, held at Portland, Me., Farm-
                            ington, O., and Albany, N. Y., with the Spiritualists and others. While we are thus giv- ing
                            the multitudes thousands of invitations to investigate our principles and examine our lives,
                            such vituperative articles as are occasionalty seen, entitled " Shakerism Exposed," must
                            fail of deceiving many, and do us much more good than harm. Nothing could please us better
                            than to have thousands inquiring, " Are these things so ?" and then come among us, sift us
                            to the foundation, and realize as we do how truly God does cause "the wrath of man to praise
                            him !" From our " Outlook "—whence we seek to read " the signs of the times"—we behold true
                            spiritualists in a very advanced condition of theology, which demands of them an advance in
                            purity of life that appears very much like Shakerism ! Whether this is an optical illusion
                            or not, remains to be seen. We anticipate on the part of these a congregation in cities and
                            villages, where they can yield each other consolations under the cross. We are aware of some
                            who testify to us their entire abstinence from fleshly lusts; and soon these are destined to
                            "flow together," inform each other, and experience, measurably, the eternal, celibate, angel
                            life, which will fit them here for the companionship of angels there. If we are mistaken,
                            then we are prepared to witness the phenomenon of very bright " stars falling from heaven "
                            into the corroding practices of earth—spiritualists (?) fulfilling fleshly inclinations, and
                            failing to walk according to the call of the Spirit. * Elder F. W. Evans and a noted
                            lecturer and reformer have been writing each other letters upon some living issues of the
                            day. We have put these in tract form, and are ready to send them, post paid, per doz. 25
                            cents. The worldly principle of mateship finds no sympathy in Shaker testimony; we believing
                            that brethren and sisters in Christ are without distinction or preference in each other's
                            estimation. A circular, lately issued from this Office, has the names of the leading
                            officers, male and female, of the Novitiate Orders at Watervliet, N. Y., and Mt. Lebanon.
                            "To the pure all things are pure;" but in our absence of knowing who alone are pure, we
                            acknowledge an over-sight on our part in departing the counsel of "shunning the very
                            appearance of evil," thus giving the impure a desired opportunity of expressing themselves,
                            whose pardon we now beg ; for we should have been in better business. * Excerpts fkom
                            Letters.—"Please change my P. O. address from-----to-----; my husband don't like The Shaker,
                            while I do, and will have it.'' s. b. "My son is greatly interested in the Shakers. As I
                            cannot let him go to them, it will be a pacification for him to have The Shakes." ** jdobbs'
                            FEEBY. "The greatest thing the Shakers have ever done for the world is the publication of
                            The Shaker.' j. M. p. "Not peace on the earthly plane, but a sword, is the effect of The
                            Shaker in my family !" k. Elder II. L. E. writes : I sought to have a neighbor subscribe. He
                            replied: "Do you think I am fool enough to create a disturbance in my family by subscribing
                            for The Shakes?" "1 have read The Shaker attentively and noticed it in The Era, and I must
                            say if there were not so much cross and self-denial in its instructions I should be almost
                            persuaded to become a Shaker !'' COL. J. T------N. '' I had thought that when 1 departed
                            this life I should part with the world j but The Shaker has convinced me that unless I get
                            rid of the. world before I die I shall be burdened with more of it there than I have here.
                            What is the world ? Let as reflect."' S. R. W. "Let The Shaker unfurl its whole self. Either
                            you must come down to us, or we must come up to you. Amen." b. 8. Troy, ST. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>Publications
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto .... Millennial Church Compendium of
                            Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Tests of Divine Inspiration—Evans Tracts
                            free, where postage is paid. 51 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 0 50 MEMBERS OF SOCIETY Appointed to
                            answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon,
                            Columbia Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Heed, Mt. Morris,
                            Livingston Co.,N. Y.. " Simon Mabee, WestPittsfieldd. Ma.ss. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. 11 Wm.
                            Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. " B.
                            H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co., N.
                            II. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers. York Co., Me. " Joseph Brackett, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. E. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland. Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>