<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0504" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18750401" TEIform="date">April 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="25" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 4. F. W. EVANS, Editoii. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N.
                        Y. April, 1875 Sixty Cents pek annum</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fire! Fire!!" TEIform="index"/>FIRE ! FIRE ! !</head><p TEIform="p">Still another fire at the Church Family. Mount Lebanon. About 11 o'clock, Saturday, February
                            27, the alarm was given —the Herb House was on tire. It proved to be in the Press room __was
                            supposed to have caught from a lamp, used to seal papers, and left burning. The fire was
                            extinguished in about half an hour, with slight damage. Two hours later, the alarm sounded
                            again. The same building was found on fire, in three different places, in an upper room. No
                            exertions could save the building. All efforts were directed to keep the barn and shed — but
                            a few rods distant — from taking fire. The shed was connected with the Herb House, by
                            gangway. This was cut away. Henry A. Tilden, who, before, was so efficient in saving the
                            Meeting House, was soon on the ground, with a large fire engine, on wheels. By the most
                            heroic and determined effort of himself and men, this building was kept from the flames.
                            Brother Daniel Offord, with another company and small water engine, was equally successful
                            in protecting the big barn. In both cases, the heat was so intense, and the danerer so
                            imminent, that the actors had to be covered with carpets and kept wet, to prevent them from
                            taking fire, with the buildings. To the stillness of the day, the well arranged, orderly
                            operations of the managers and their co-workers, we attribute the preservation of
                            surrounding property. As it is, the loss cannot be less than $50,000. We feel under the
                            deepest obligations of gratitude, to all our neighbors, who, as was well said, could not
                            have shown more interest, had the property been their own. Especially is this true of H. A.
                            Tilden, his sons and workmen. Pittsfield was telegraphed, and their fire brigade again
                            crossed the mountain. Had either of the buildings, which so narrowly escaped, caught fire,
                            the Pittsfield company would have been in the nick of time to do service, to the full extent
                            of their capacity. To say we appreciate the Pittsfield sacrifice, on our behalf, in this
                            emergency, would be but a feeble expression of our feelings of relief — knowing that sucli
                            help was so near at hand — when, without it, so many buildings would have inevitably burned,
                            had the fire taken at either of the three threatened points.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conservatism" TEIform="index"/>CONSERVATISM</head><p TEIform="p">Conservatism — the desire and effort to preserve what is established — and Radicalism—•
                            progress toward abstract ideas — are considered antipodes. Yet they balance reason on the
                            line of truth. Instead of considering their relationship as brotherly and sisterly, the
                            majority of those who think at all, take sides with one, as opposed to the other; and as a
                            consequence, reason is unbalanced, and loss is the result. To conservatives, radicalism is
                            the evil sprite of humanity; to radicals,there is no worse enemy to the race than
                            conservatives. Properly considered, these are unjust conclusions. There is nothing strange,
                            in the fact, that " New Lights," in all eras of the religious world, have considered the
                            systems discovered by them, to be the truth, the whole truth, and nothing but the truth.
                            Yet, these same individuals, who are thus, and now most radical, are destined to become, in
                            their turn, the rankest conservatives of the coming era. Evolution laughs and says, "To the
                            better hold fast." This is ever the song of reason. The comparative degree of good, is
                            better; and when this is attained, we leave the good of the past, and cling tenaciously to
                            the superlative as soon as it appears. By this, I am persuaded, how we may " leave the first
                            principles, and go on to perfection ;" condemning no good of the past, neither rejecting any
                            superior injunction for the future. If we. say we have all truth now, how can it be, that "
                            of the increase of the gospel there shall be no end ?" By assuming this position, we become
                            bigots, and the good of conservatism is neglected. We should then argue, that any amendment
                            suggested, was an invitation for the visitation of added plagues; while any proposed
                            subtraction, was worthy of the judgment of blotting out one's inheritance in God forever! No
                            one desires these. But is this the position of reason ? This idea of sufficiency, carried
                            out, would turn back the wheels of time and progress for two thousand years, and teach a
                            savage life. Under its rod of iron, we would not dare to say what we know to be true. We
                            would not dare to do what we know to be right; because of selfadulated conservatism.
                            Evolution is the keyword of progress — the forerunner of " the good time coming." Her
                            legitimate children, are, additions to genuine revelation. When we investigate the matter
                            closely, we see that God has so beautifully organized creation, that no two shall be, nor
                            act, nor think, identically, yet none need swerve from the harmonious law, which is all
                            truth. If I think a truth that is new, and each, of many, does the same, we have many truths
                            all new; and though differing in their aspects, each and all belong to the heavenly law of
                            spiritual progress. There are, to-day, no more staunch subjects of radicalism, than the
                            whole body of Believers called Shakers. In their testimony against all fleshly lusts ; in
                            their resurrected life, above, even the good and best of generative men and women, they
                            stand as reformers before the world to-day, even as Jesus did before his nation—the Jews.
                            Let us hold fast to this — let "no surrender" to any departures from virgin lives, for a
                            moment, be considered. But is not the best of the land yet before us ? Let not our testimony
                            and life against fleshly lusts, begin and conclude our whole mission ; for is not the
                            gospel, the power of God unto an increasing salvation, for soul and body, and for the body
                            first 1 Every Shaker is praiseworthy for rebutting the least " shadow of turning," by any,
                            from the spirit to the flesh. Such instances there have been among us, and may yet be ; and
                            such will be anathema, without our cursing them. But let us not stop here. Believers are now
                            far in advance of their predecessors, in their physiological habits ; and are, in that same
                            degree, advanced in spirituality. If we would be more spiritual, let us aim to be more
                            rational and perfect, physically ; and think not, that the gospel is to work our salvation
                            in one part of our systems and not in another. Israel stoned her prophets. We may have done,
                            and may still be doing the same thing and conscientiously too, thinking our conservatism
                            godly! While we are contending for first principles, we are rejecting weightier matters of
                            our spiritual law. Neither is our theology perfect. Let not the jealous guard we put over
                            it, cause us to close the doors to as perfect revelations as have ever been delivered. That
                            the world made a god of Jesus, and for a purpose, is well known by us, as is the object of
                            this elevation. The worship of Jesus as a god savors of self-worship and indulgence ; not of
                            an unreserved consecration of self to God. To worship Jesus, for living a life of godliness,
                            and ridicule others, for living the same life, shows a want of sincerity. The time has been
                            when conservatism would hardly permit us to think that Jesus was ever a Jew; and even now,
                            there is sufficient antichristianity left, to chasten us, if we presume that Jesus acted
                            like a Jew before he became a Christian 1 This is irrational conservatism— it does not
                            conserve. Our inclinations would lead us to stereotype our theology, even as ia done by the
                            worshipers of Jesus and Mary. We would incline to disbelief in present revelations; to an
                            insufficiency of painstaking, to prove the truthfulness of these revelations before
                            condemning them. Let us reflect. Our mission on Mount Zion is to be " exalted above all the
                            hills that surround;" and yet, by a <pb n="26" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 26 SHAKER A.ND false conservatism
                            we are losing golden opportunities, and permitting the hills, around us, to excel us in many
                            physiological, and in some spiritual adornments! Children of Mount Zion, let no one take
                            your crown; let none possess our birthright! Why should trouble rise, when men seek truth?
                            It does not rise when truth is sought aright. But error rules, where trouble is, and has,
                            from trouble's earliest birth. With the All-Wise there is no trouble; all trouble springs
                            from ignorance ; and ignorance of ourselves brings greatest trouble. It is apparent to all,
                            my dear relation, that by our devotion to the better life of virgin purity—peace, union of
                            interests, and unspottedness from the world, there has been no interruption of improvements
                            since first the cause began. Since our earliest day, we have made some noble departures from
                            the regime of our spiritual ancestry ; yet, we have conserved the vital principles. Let us
                            still conserve these, while we make all necessary departures. From that old house, made up
                            of logs, and roof all thatched with straw, we have happily departed. The same, of certain
                            meats and drinks, with large benefits accruing; nor is the end of improvement yet arrived
                            at. Tobacco, once an article of pastime for our united congregations, is under a ban — none
                            so honorable as if they used it not. We have built schools ; and we are thoroughly
                            ventilating our dwellings; we encourage esthetics in music, manners and literature; and we
                            publish the Shaker and Shakeeess! To be sure, the stubborn and willful thought they saw the
                            gospel standard lowering through these changes; but the true conservatives kissed the
                            radicals, and exercised a healthy influence in the balances of truth. Why, then, stumble at
                            testimonies, that are aimed for the eradication, not merely of nonessential idols, but for
                            the real aggressors of salvation ? And why, think, by our opposition to such testimonies,
                            that we are the conservators of everlasting principles ? I would not animadvert upon any
                            particular habits or customs of my friends; but I do urge a more liberal comprehension of
                            what conservatism should do for us — that we be not deceived, and remain in statu quo to our
                            condemnation and extinction! Let us be more radically conservative; and we will be more true
                            to ourselves, and to God; and there will be a cessation of all ignoble opposition, miscalled
                            conservatism. There will be more of putting on the new man and woman in Christ; and the
                            initiation of radical reforms, from customs which we well know are not only detrimental, but
                            actually sapping the life from the foundations of our Christianity. We would uphold the
                            hands of our prophets — not accepting their prophecies without testing them — but to be open
                            to truth and conviction, though they hew to the line, and take from us the idols of years.
                            May ours be a " Midnight Cry," and the bearer to all gospel kindred, that " the morning
                            dawns."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An eminent Hindoo skeptic once told what he believed to be true in Exeter Hall, London..." TEIform="index"/>An eminent Hindoo skeptic once told what he believed to be true in Exeter Hall, London...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">An eminent Hindoo skeptic once told what he believed to be true in Exeter Hall, London, when
                            he said that the part of India where Christianity had never entered was a precinct happy in
                            domestic relations and every thing that can make heathenism home, while another portion was
                            a blighted, un happy region, because Christianity and whisky were there. There are few
                            things in this world so utterly contemptible as contempt. It is the vice of vanity, and is a
                            sensation unknown to true greatness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conservatism and progress" TEIform="index"/>CONSERVATISM AND PROGRESS</head><p TEIform="p">Conservatism — the preservation of the good of the past — is the Mother. Progress — the
                            reaching up for increasing good—is the Child of that Mother. As sensible would it be, for
                            the Mother to manacle the Child, to prevent its learning to walk, as for those who received
                            the latest — the greatest manifestation of Divine Light and Life, to endeavor to scotch the
                            wheels of the car of progress — and as sensible, as for the child to call its mamma naughty
                            names, for holding it by the waistband, to prevent its tumbling down and bumping its little
                            nose, as for such as get hold of a new idea, to speak naughtily of every idea, not hammered
                            out on their anvil. Alas for poor, unprogressed humanity! In all ages of the past, they, to
                            whom Heaven has vouchsafed its latest favors, seem inclined to drive a stake and say:'' Wo
                            to the infidel, who has the presumption to say, This is not the center of the Universe." And
                            they, who have the presumption to make the sublime discovery that there is no top to the
                            ladder of progress, are much disposed to underrate or repudiate the equally important, for
                            the day, sublime discoveries of their predecessors. Will it always be so ? We trow not. What
                            the ground of our hope ? Looking through the long, prophetic glass, we behold, in the vastly
                            remote future, a time, when Religion will begin at the right end — when humanity will make
                            the important discovery, that what enters in at the mouth defiles the man, not much less
                            than that which cometh out. If the Soul be the Tabernacle of the Living God, and the Body be
                            the earthly house of this Tabernacle, why should not that which goeth in at the mouth of the
                            earthly house, with the assent of the Tabernacle, produce its effect on the Tabernacle ? If
                            what enters the mouth be unphysiological — deleterious, or stimulating to the animal
                            appetites and passions, beyond the soul's highest perception of right — there will be no
                            necessity for God to perform the drudgery of destroying the defiler of that Temple. Less
                            than a hundred years ago, souls might preserve their form erect, before high heaven, by
                            bearing tbe cross against the flesh, which then meant abstaining from the abuse, and use of
                            the powers of generation — the first principle of the doctrine of Christ — the first round
                            in the ladder of progress — the Resurrection. Now, an increase is called for — an advance
                            movement. The call is, Come up higher. Whether you eat, drink, act, think or feel, let all
                            be to the honor and glory of God and the good of humanity. Be pure — in all things be pure.
                            If you would be pure in heart, be pure all through and through. Let there not be a dark spot
                            about you. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winooski, Vermont, January 25, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Winooski, Vermont, Jan. 25, '75</head><p TEIform="p">Editors and Editresses of Shaker and Shakeress — Esteemed Brothers and Sisters: I come to you
                            for counsel and efficient action. I am at liberty to negotiate with an efficient party. I
                            want to see a community, as I have told you, based on the Christ-spirit, under the banner of
                            peace and harmonial science, having, for its corner-stone, practical goodness, with love to
                            God and love to. man. For this I look to you. WTill you come to our rescue ? Will you take
                            hold and build or help build a community to advance to a higher plane of life, on the
                            following basis ? — 1st. We will go with you, in self-denial, confessing and forsaking sins,
                            with honesty and purity of effort. 2d. For official station, celibates, with ability, shall
                            have preference, by the law of right. 3d. Scientific reproduction, of our species,
                            commensurate with wisdom, divested of the baser passions, under guidance of purity, culture
                            and refinement, by such as are esteemed worthy, for this life-demand. 4th. Celibates to take
                            rank as senior order. I beseech you to not let this hope of humanity perish from the earth.
                            Truly, yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shipman, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/>Orrin Shipman</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, February 1, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Feb. 1, '75</head><p TEIform="p">Orrin Shipman — Esteemed Friend: Your letter, of January 25, is before me. In a former
                            letter, July 14, I believe I answered the queries contained in your last. Should you again
                            cast your eye over that, I think you will perceive what my present answer must be. As I
                            understand the subject, our difference is not of opinion merely, but radical. The
                            Christ-spirit, as manifested in Jesus, exhibited Shakerism. Jesus and company constituted a
                            community, which was, to pentecostal organization, like the tabernacle of the wilderness to
                            the first temple built by Solomon. In that temple, Jews alone resided. In the court of that
                            temple, Gentiles could bring their offerings, and worship the God of the temple, through his
                            own priesthood, the Jews. Thus was it with the Gentile Christians, the seven churches of
                            Asia and their descendants, the marrying, fighting, private property-holding religionists of
                            the whole world, whether called Christians, Mahometans, or heathens ; principles being
                            universal as are characters formed by principles. The seven women, who desired to eat their
                            own kind of food, wear their own kind of clothes and do as they had been accustomed to do,
                            but be called by a certain name, were the religionists — children of this world — who marry
                            and give in marriage. This Gentile order, joined to the monastic, or temple order, who lived
                            Shaker lives of celibacy, constituted the first Christian church that is now occupying the
                            ground in Christendom, practicing generation, while holding celibacy to be the higher life —
                            the purer Christianity -— practicing war, while recognizing " return good for evil," as a
                            Christian requirement. Buying and selling, for personal acquisitiveness, the rule, community
                            the law. We claim that Christ, having reappeared in humanity — this time in a woman —
                            established a Christian church, in practice, as well as profession — a Shaker community. Not
                            a tabernacle that is movable, because in persons not yet organized; nor yet a temple with a
                            court to it; but a second temple, more perfect than the first; a house of prayer for all
                            nations, tongues and peoples, where the spiritualminded can be gathered together, in the
                            true Christ order, in the kingdom of Heaven that is not of this world, nor does it allow
                            such as serve the tabernacle, or the temple with a court to it, to have part or lot in the
                            matter. This leaves the children of this world to form civil governments, entirely unmixed
                            with theology, or any form of religious profession, as religion is commonly understood.
                            These two orders are being evolved out of existing elements. Henceforth there will be no
                            peace in the Shaker order, except so far as it shakes itself from worldly elements and
                            practices; and there will be no peace in the civil governments, except so far as they deal
                            justly, love, mercy and obey the laws of property, propagation and physiology, as contained
                            in the original abstract law of God, in nature pertaining to the life that now is, not
                            interfering with the faith and duties of the resurrection order — the true church — temple
                            of humanity — Shakerdom.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second thunder, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>SECOND THUNDER No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder John: Your reply of September 20th, to my article, is conceived in a spirit which
                            I think is wellnigh perfect. That Believers " love one another," is an imperative command ;
                            that they all see the same things, in the same light, at the same time, without regard to
                            age, condition or travel, is undesirable, unattainable, impossible. The path of the
                            right-doer is to become brighter and brighter, unto the perfect day. Being perfect in spirit
                            will bring us, individually, to perfection in truth. As we should have no physical habits,
                            in meats nor drinks, in gait nor dress, that we would not change for better, so neither
                            should we have any theory, sentiment, nor doctrine&gt; which we hold as not subject to
                            criticism, analysis, test. We can have no personal interest in error. Having this confidence
                            in truth, we shall be as unconcerned in the fires of the most sacredly religious zeal, while
                            it is inveighing <pb n="27" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKERESS. 27 against and investigating any of our
                            theological theorems, as we would be were they purely mathematical problems. Figures will
                            not lie nor flatter ; and the logical result is the best result, though the old heavens fall
                            as the result. Two extreme classes existed in Babylon — Christendom:—1st. The Orthodox, who
                            held Jesus to be God, and God to be a Trinity, of the masculine gender, upon which ideas the
                            divine right of kings rested, as a basis and pattern of all church and state governments ;
                            the physical resurrection ; a second coming of the person of Jesus; and salvation, or more
                            properly, acceptance with God, by believing certain or uncertain dogmas, without evidence or
                            logical reason for so believing. The merit of so believing was in inverse ratio with the
                            credibility or rationality of the thing to be believed. 2d. The Materialist, who begins life
                            by accepting facts, sustained by evidence, utterly regardless of consequences to any system
                            of ideas in existence. The founders of our order, in its first degree, were largely from the
                            Orthodox classes in Babylon. It is my opinion that the founders of the second degree will be
                            largely from the Tyndall school — the scientific, rationalistic, or materialistic classes,
                            who constitute a horn, or power, which turns logical telescopes upon the kingdom of
                            Antichrist—the Greek, Catholic and Protestant world, " For God hath put it into their hearts
                            to do his will." They are, therefore, as much the servants of God to-day, as were Fathers
                            William, James and Joseph, in their day. I am pleased, not a little, that you, as
                            representative of Orthodox views, see so clearly the work of God in this new aspect; '„'
                            Surely the Materialists were inspired to see the false foundation upon which the Dam was
                            built." You ask, " Is it not possible, while stripping from the mythical Jesus the robes
                            wherewith the Priests have clothed him, to take away what, of right, belongs to the real
                            Jesus ? " Not if we do no more than to reduce him to a level with his very best exponent,
                            his glory, his other half — Mother Ann Lee. If the Father of Jesus was greater than Jesus,
                            and his successors exceed him in good works, doing greater works than he performed, wherein
                            is the robbery in true Believers being equal with Jesus, or in being " perfect, even as God
                            is perfect ? " Jesus could not go beyond that, except by precedence. When Jesus was tempted
                            of the devil, forty days, in the wilderness, it was like John's vision. It was not the real
                            history of facts, as they have been transpiring from that day to this, 1874 years, but as
                            the plan of a campaign not yet accomplished. It was as the forty years' vision of Israel in
                            the wilderness, as compared with their historic record in Canaan. We must look to the actual
                            succession of events, in the life and travel of Jesus, for the real temptations — the
                            workings of Jesus' worldly nature, in its struggles and contentions with the Christspirit. I
                            am free to affirm that he came up, step by step, through every element and principle of the
                            generative, fighting Jews, and that in each battle fought with that old ser pent, that old
                            dragon, the devil, while Jesus bruised the head, himself was wounded in the heel. Under the
                            influence of religious zeal, for the honor of God and the glory of his temple, inspired by
                            Jewish spirits, who acted upon his Jewish proclivities, he fought the Temple profaners with
                            imchristian weapons. Wnen he rode into Jerusalem upon an ass, receiving the ovations of the
                            people, it was held as a religious insurrection against the civil government of Rome. That
                            caused his violent death, as " King of the Jews," by the Roman government. Successfully he
                            cleared the temple of Jewish transgressors, and the Romans did not interfere. But when he
                            arrayed the whole Jewish population of Jerusalem against the Romans, expecting to conquer by
                            spiritual aid, he failed. Having taken the spiritualistic sword, with a view of ruling over
                            all nations subject to Rome, he perished with the physical sword. He was not perfected in
                            Christianity until after his ascension. " Jesus was not yet perfected," or risen in the
                            Christ Resurrection. He was tempted to become a judge, or divider, just as we are; he was
                            tempted to marry, and did actually attend a wedding.which no true Believer would now do. As
                            Jesus was first—trod the wine-press alone — had each principle of Christianity to define and
                            locate, is it not glory enough that he succeeded as well as he did. From a sincere, zealous,
                            God-fearing Jew, with the substratum of a natural man, he became, by travel — learning by
                            his own mistakes — a Christian, the last we hear of him. From a sincere, zealous,
                            God-fearing Gentile Anti-christian, from the Orthodox extreme of Babylon, Mother Ann became,
                            before she died, a pretty good Christian, a Shaker, to be perfected, like Jesus, in the
                            eternal world. In how few points we differ, and in how many we agree. In admitting that the
                            Apostles did believe the physical resurrection, and in the physical resurrection of Jesus,
                            just as I do, one point of agreement is gained. In admitting that Elijah and Jesus had
                            brought back the departed soul into the body, is not the principle I advance recognized ? It
                            makes the return of Jesus possible and natural. " The spirit of truth searcheth all things :
                            yea, even the deep things of God." All who returned to the body, like Lazarus and Jesus,
                            died again. This physical resurrection was a sign to the natural people who witnessed it.
                            These signs shall follow them that believe. " They shall heal the sick, raise the dead." But
                            the healed will again be sick, and the resurrected will die once more. The evidence is the
                            same, that physical bodies have really passed through matter, as it is that spirits have
                            been materialized.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berlin, New Jersey, February 15, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Berlin, N. J., February 15, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederick and all the Household of Faith that are with you : I feel drawn to pen
                            you a few lines in love and sympathy. Would to Heaven I had a surplus of the almighty
                            dollar, that I might send you material aid, in this your sore affliction. But you must
                            accept the will for the deed. I am poor, as ever, not from idleness, nor extravagance, but
                            on accountof the drouth and the low price of fruit. Gold and silver, I have not. Such as I
                            have— sympathy and kind wishes — I give, in good measure, heaped up, shaken down and running
                            over. I have spoken of the almighty dollar, for that is the greatest almighty, most people
                            worship, to-day. They have many lesser almighties— selfishness, fleshly lusts, artificial
                            appetites and so forth. In the midst of my poverty, I have much to be thankful for, with the
                            Little Great Shaker and Shakeress to read. My little farm and cottage were under mortgage.
                            Friend Joseph S. Tillinghast, of New Bedford, sent me $100. I lifted the mortgage, and now
                            breathe easier. In the cities, are thousands, and hundreds of thousands, out of employ, and
                            on the borders of starvation. In one of your letters to me you said," Woe to him that
                            standeth alone." I do not know that I understand your meaning, but I have a meaning of my
                            own. By standing alone, and proclaiming the truth, against the Churches, I have had their
                            curses. I could not join them, because I could not be a hypocrite. I could not join the
                            Shakers, whom, for forty years, I have loved, more than any other people, because I belonged
                            to the world—my work was with the world — outside of Shakerdom— one, alone in the moutains,
                            blasting rocks and felling tall cedars, for the House of God, that the Shakers will yet
                            build, provided the material be not too rotten. That noble man—Elder Richard Bushnell— in
                            his last letter to me, called H. W. Beecher a Babel-builder. That was before the great
                            Beecher scandal was heard of ; but truer words were never written. What a Babel, Beecher,
                            Plymouth Church and Brooklyn court are building! Jesus and Mother Ann have no hand in that
                            Babel. When the Katie King manifestation commenced in Philadelphia, I was sure it was an
                            imposition. I am as certain that the Eddys are impostors. But here, I am wearying your
                            patience and wasting your precious time. Love, to you all,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hacker, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Hacker</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, February 18, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, February 18, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend Jeremiah : Your kind, sympathizing letter, of the 15th inst., is received. I
                            thank you for the love and blessing. Your gift is none the less real because you cannot make
                            an outward expression of it in the form of the almighty dollar. Neither is mine any the more
                            real because I express it in the form of a $5 check. Please receive it as a token of love
                            and remembrance of your North Family friends—Daniel Offord, Eldress Antoinette Doolittle and
                            Sister Anna White, who have deep affection for you. I have ever considered you a Prophet, to
                            this generation and nation — more especially to the people of Portland and Maine. With many
                            discomforts and trials, you are still mindful of the good that remains, and encourage us to
                            be like-minded. That is right. Am glad to learn your mortgage has been lifted. Friend Joseph
                            will be none the poorer for what he does for you. Any time that you are liable to suffer for
                            food or clothing, write me freely, and we will do you a little good, if we cannot do all you
                            so richly deserve. You are mistaken about the materialization business. There is a.
                            principle involved in it. That principle is as old as time. There have been periods when
                            materializations were frequent— will be so again. Spiritualism is an agency, for use, in the
                            Divine economy. There is meaning to it. Be patient, and fret not thyself because of evil
                            doers, who seek to get a living by it. Have they not done the same by the Gospel? While so
                            many preach for hire, why should not mediums divine for money ? Your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Human sacrifices!" TEIform="index"/>HUMAN SACRIFICES!</head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Editor—The ancient Israelites in 1,000 years sacrificed to their war-God fifty millions
                            of human beings! The creed of Christians in 1,600 years sacrificed to tjieir trinity God one
                            billion three hundred millions of human beings! Or, twelve millions more than the present
                            population of the globe For shedding human blood the Christians beat the Jews, the Pagans,
                            the Mahometans, the Mormons, the world ! The Israelites ceased to slaughter when swallowed
                            up by Pagan Rome! The Christians stayed their bloody hands when they lost the power of the
                            State! The orthodox churches in the North are making desperate efforts to amend the United
                            States Constitution so as to include fundamental dogmas of their creeds — an incipient and
                            covert attempt to unite Church and State ! These churches cost the people of the United
                            States two hundred millions of dollars per annum ! These corporations hold real and personal
                            property, exempt from taxation by the State or General Government, three hundred millions of
                            dollars ! Is it right to take money out of the pockets of the millions of heretics and
                            non-professors to support priests, parsons, and powerful ecclesiastical monopolies? They
                            tell us that salvation is free! Free? Tt takes a California gold mine every year to pay
                            expenses! Let us organize an anti-Orthodox Church Grange!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peterson, R." TEIform="persName"/>R. Peterson</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Danbury, Connecticut, January 12, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Danbury, Ct., Jan. 12, '75</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Evans — Dear sir : Inclosed, find sixty cents, the subscription price of your excellent
                            monthly," The Shaker and Shakeress." I have taken it the past year, and can hardly get along
                            without it. Its voice against sin, in its many forms, has no uncertain sound. Its
                            representations of the Gentile Christian church, are in almost perfect harmony with my
                            theory of Christianity. Whether I shall ever come any nearer to <pb n="28" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 28 your
                            order than a general acceptance of your theory, I am unable to say, at present. In many
                            respects, we are the creatures of circumstances. As far as in me lies, with my surroundings,
                            I am denying all ungodliness and worldly lusts. I am crucified with Christ. Perhaps you
                            think no one ought to say so much and, at the same time, consent to remain in Babylon. Are
                            these not times when we must choose between two evils ? At least, ought we not to wait for
                            the time remedy ? The Christ-spirit has certainly been leading me onward. I have been in
                            Egypt — have come forth and wandered in the wilderness. Have been content to go down into
                            Babylon, not knowing any better way. But I pee the new Jerusalem. Its light cheers my soul.
                            Still I am traveling. I hear the voice, " Fear not, for it is your Father's good pleasure to
                            give you the Kingdom." Would be pleased to hear from you. Yours, truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peck, J. L." TEIform="persName"/>J. L. Peck</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Balance-wheel of shakerism" TEIform="index"/>THE BALANCE-WHEEL OF SHAKERISM</head><p TEIform="p">As machinery cannot run with safety without a regulator, in like manner religion of whatever
                            class, kind, or character, cannot retain a uniform progress without some governing power.
                            Well may " the children of this world" (the natural order) wonder that the Shakers are
                            enabled to investigate the realities and nature of the " manifestations " now being produced
                            under the name of " Spiritualism," without being " led astray" by their ease-attracting
                            doctrines. And they have good reasons to wonder, for daily they perceive the more
                            considerate and liberal minds, among their adherents, leaving the fear of God which the fear
                            of hell prompts, and cleaving to the love of God, as advocated by this philosophy or science
                            of spirit-life. Our warning, to all souls, not established on any particular basis, is, look
                            at the balancewheel whieh governs the Shaker's faith — examine its stability — see if the
                            rock purity is not firm enough to sustain the Christian church. Those fire-tried souls have
                            passed through the refining furnace — soul travail — which removes every dross. Inviolate
                            purity is the basis of true Christianity. Upon this basis Jesus established the Pentecostal
                            Church, Hence, all organizations, not on this foundation, whether bearing the name
                            Christian, or not, are " founded upon the sand "— the perishable and ever-changing elements
                            of the mundane sphere — subject to "fallings off" identical with the Jewish nation and
                            religion, as illustrated by their biblical records. After the fall of the first Adam we see
                            that mankind were governed by warlike gods (or controlling spirits), and that a miserable
                            state of things existed, until holy angels, from the Christ, or inner heavens, found One fit
                            to receive their ministrations, and resurrected Him into that " pure and undefiled" state,
                            peculiar to their sphere, thus making Him a new creature in Christ, and a Saviour of lost
                            and deluded souls — not like the first, or natural Adam, the increase being, this time, to "
                            multiply and replenish" Heaven, instead of the earth, with souls " refined and purified by
                            the blood of the lamb"—the life-blood element of virgin purity—by which souls are washed "
                            whiter than snow." Jesus aspired to the conditions which find favor with God and the holy
                            angels. Single-handed (physically), for a season, he fought the prince of the power of
                            darkness — Lust. Afterward, he gathered unto himself, with the aid of his spirit attendants,
                            a few companions, lovers of pure and high-aspiring lives, like himself. With the
                            Christ-principle of Celibacy, for their balance-wheel, nothing earthly changed their
                            sentiments, or retarded their spiritual progress. What sin-sick soul can reject that
                            governing power which " saves" from the destructive elements of a "fast running out world 1
                            " A Thomas Paine may expound upon the sectarian's Bible and gods, showing the absurdity of
                            their claiming, for them, Divine origin. A Katie King may be exposed, Spiritualism
                            considered a delusion and Christianity a farce. It will not affect, in the least, the
                            eternal balance wheel of purity. The machinery of a mill might, if it had reasoning powers,
                            believe its motive power had a balance-wheel; yet, if it did not choose to become subject to
                            its regulating power, by being geared to it, of what use would a mere belief in its
                            existence be ? The Philadelphia expose illustrates how great and intellestual minds may be "
                            run away with," however good or honest the motives. Simply believing in the Christ
                            principle, and pure spirits, will not save one soul from the destructive elements of
                            impurity. Nay, if souls desire to become free from deluding spirits, let them " gear on" to
                            this great balance-wheel of eternal safety, for they cannot in this, or other worlds, find
                            or substitute any other power to save them from the " wiles of the adversary." If purity
                            appear to be a dangerous element, " gear on " cautiously at first, and try for a season,
                            loving the good that is in your neighbor, like that you perceive in your own self. Regard
                            all mankind as belonging to the human species. By this experiment, it lies within the power
                            of all, rich and poor, " without money and without price," to examine the regulator which
                            keeps Shakers within the bounds of their own belief, and prove the " Infallibility" of the
                            Balance-wheel of Shakerism.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Howard, E. C." TEIform="persName"/>E. C. Howard, South Hadley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love of God" TEIform="index"/>THE LOVE OF GOD</head><p TEIform="p">The love of God, like their universe is boundless. The most depraved being as well as the
                            brightest seraph that dazzles around their throne are alike the subjects of their warm
                            paternal and maternal embrace. The greatest exhibitions of God's love, of which we have any
                            knowledge, can give but a very faint idea of its exceeding riches and power. We may feel it,
                            like repeated shocks of electricity, passing through our physical frames, shaking out a
                            selfish, carnal nature, thereby laying a broad and solid foundation for a new life, a new
                            creation. God waits to fill and purify our hearts with his love. Men, and angels, are led to
                            behold, and admire. The highest order of angels will ever desire to look into the deep and
                            hidden mysteries of the love of God. Their universal testimony will be to all eternity. "
                            This love is better felt than told." The love of God should be the mainspring of all
                            Christian effort. Our happiness and our usefulness here, and hereafter, will be in
                            proportion to the amount of true Gospel-love which we possess and maintain. The love of God
                            is wonderful in its origin, mighty in its effects, mysterious, and incomprehensible in all
                            its tendencies. By its power this world must be conquered, and its kingdoms become the
                            kingdoms of our God and his Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hubbell, Gilbert" TEIform="persName"/>Gilbert Hubbell, Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union" TEIform="index"/>UNION</head><p TEIform="p">" Behold how good and how pleasant it is, for Brethren (and Sisters) to dwell together in
                            unity." Psalms, 133d, 1st. "A man, wishing to show his children the necessity of union among
                            themselves, prepared a bundle of sticks with a strong cord. Commencing with the youngest, he
                            requested him to break them ; he could not. The next was called, and so on up to the oldest;
                            all failed ; upon which the father cut the cord and they were easily broken, one by one."
                            Union is the cord that binds, consolidates and nourishes the various members of the body of
                            Christ, " for we are all members one of another." If this cord be broken, the army of the
                            cross will be divided, scattered and destroyed, by the wicked one. Disunion is the rock on
                            which many barks have been wrecked; but obedience to those principles which promote the ''
                            union of the spirit in the bond of peace," is a safe guide to the port of eternal rest.
                            Union is not only good and pleasant, but essential to success in spiritual prosperity. The
                            followers of Christ have a great work to do, and union is strength in spiritual warfare, as
                            well as in military tactics. " United, we stand ; divided, we fall." It is a part of the
                            plans of military officers to divide the forces of the enemy, both in the council and in the
                            field. It is also the plan of Satan, the adversary of souls, to divide and destroy
                            professing Christians. He has his officers out upon the watch, such as Lust, Pride,
                            Selfishness, Love of Worldly Pleasure, and many other petty officers; and O! how many
                            weak-minded soldiers they are capturing. I apprehend the reason why so many faint-hearted
                            soldiers are taken prisoners is, because they have failed to gird on the whole, armor and
                            obey all the orders of Christ, the good Commander. The true cross-bearer's life is compared
                            to a soldier's, and they are called to war a good warfare, " fight the good fight of faith,"
                            and it is their privilege to rejoice in victory, every day. They have a good Captain, who
                            was victorious in every battle, and He provides His soldiers with the beautiful armor of
                            righteousness. (Eph., 6, 11; 13.) They who put on this armor will overcome in every
                            encounter, and '' he that overcometh shall inherit all things."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield., Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A traveler in Sweden contributes to one of the newspapers..." TEIform="index"/>A traveler in Sweden contributes to one of the newspapers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A traveler in Sweden contributes to one of the newspapers an account of the very economical
                            mode of house-warming adopted in that country. The kakelung, or Swedish stove, is a great
                            oven of masonry covered with porcelain plates, having usually five flues, through which the
                            gases of combustion must pass up and down, a distance of thirty to sixty feet, before
                            escaping into the air. The general principle of their operation is to provide enough
                            material to absorb all the heat from the fire; to conduct the gases through these long flues
                            till their temperature has fallen to a point that no longer gives off heat. The quantity of
                            the material in the kakelung is so great that the temperature of any part is such that the
                            hand cannot be held upon the outside. Two hours after a fire is made, and after the wood
                            fuel has burned up, and the flue been closed, the kakelung begins to get warm on the
                            outside, the light porcelain plates give off their moderate warmth to the atmosphere la the
                            room, and ten hours later there will be much difference in the temperature of the stove or
                            of the room. A kakelung instead of being an unsightly obstruction, is an ornamental piece of
                            furniture. A door opens into it in front, where, in a kind of closet with iron shelves, food
                            can be kept warm or warmed. Baking can be done in the furnace for hours after the fire has
                            been burned out.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A writer in the 'London Magazine' says that men like Tyndall and Huxley..." TEIform="index"/>A writer in the 'London Magazine' says that men like Tyndall and Huxley...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A writer in the "London Magazine" says that men like Tyndall and Huxley, Spencer and Darwin,
                            with the terrible weapons of their materialism do but break down an old and much battered
                            idol which has long been the cause of dreadful doubts, even to its devotees, and has set
                            religion and science at bitter variance. But in breaking down the idol they are doing us the
                            greatest service. They are letting in the light; they are leaving us face to face with a
                            conception of God before hidden from us by our idol, but which presents him to us not only
                            in a form which science will allow, before which, indeed, science and religion become one,
                            but in a form which is immeasurably grander, more beautiful, and every way worthier of God
                            than that which has been broken down. Let us clearly recognize that when TyndaH claims for
                            matter that it is sufficient for every thing, he is not thinking of matter as that dead,
                            brute thing which the mass of men suppose it. To him as to Herbert Spencer, matter is but
                            the manifestation of a Great Entity in itself unknown and unknowable. It is but the garment
                            of what Tyndall calls the great cosmical life — the great life of the cosmos— the universe.
                            What is this Great Entity, what is this Great Cosmical Life but the Eternal God Himself, of
                            whom, and through whom, and to whom are all things, who " besets us behind and before" and "
                            in whom we live and move and have our being? " The Sons of Rechab were blessed of God, be
                            cause they carried out certain principles, enjoined by their father. The blessing was not
                            upon the thing done or not done, but upon the integrity of intention and the fixity of
                            purpose — invaluable elements in the work of redemption from wrong habits and evil purposes.
                            Among the Editoks.—As a scholar among school-masters, or a child with adults, so do I learn
                            from the Editors whom I visit. Editors of leading papers occupy responsible positions,
                            requiring nerve and wisdom, a discriminating liberality toward the representatives of the
                            people, as a whole, not omiting any integral element, party or sect. The real editor rises
                            above his individuality into the realm of causation, where he educates and guides the public
                            conscience.</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: what is man?" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: WHAT IS MAN?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">In view of the atomic structure of human beings when compared with the vaatness of God's
                            Universe, David of old said, " What is man, that Thou art mindful of him ? " Many Davids at
                            the present time are asking, Who, and what is man ? Whence came he — whither is he tending —
                            what his final destiny, and what relation does he sustain to Nature's wondrous realms of
                            mind and matter? How far is he dependent upon circumstances approximate or remote, in fixing
                            his choice and forming his character ? Of his own volition, is he free to choose between
                            good and evil: and what degree of responsibility, merit, or demerit, justly belongs to him?
                            The rudimental, or earth life, is a disciplinary school; and the most wakeful students of
                            Nature and her laws, who have chosen her as their chief mentor, have many times become lost,
                            as it were, in traversing the almost illimitable fields of scientific research, so varied
                            and intricate to finite comprehension. No human mind however expansive is adequate to grasp
                            the whole. People differ in their organisms; and each, if their faculties were unimpaired by
                            false uses, would occupy his or her proper place in the scale of being, and form a link in
                            the great chain of human progress. Man and woman, the microcosm of the Universal mind that
                            spake all things into existence, would, by individual and combined effort, search out the
                            essential parts, and scientifically connect the inner world of causation with the world of
                            matter, and perceive that all created things bear proper relations to their Creator, and
                            form one indivisible whole. That Nature cannot act independently of the creative power which
                            upholds and balances each part to the minutest atom. Else, all would be hurled into chaos.
                            Every true theory must have a basic foundation — a starting point. In the progress of the
                            world's history there have been different epochs. Each new cycle has evolved, from the old,
                            at an exact period of time, so that the date could be fixed, and yet, there was no break in
                            the chain of events. As the old year dies — goes out — and the new commences — steps in to
                            fill its place—so has it been with the successive cycles. But people reason differently
                            concerning those eventful periods. Some urge, that this world, at the beginning, was in a
                            crude, chaotic condition ; and that it has taken ages of growth and change to progress and
                            mature it thus far. Man has not been an exception to the general rule. All have progressed
                            together. He was not created all at once in the perfection of beauty and uprightness ; but
                            resembled other animals, to whom he was closely allied strong in physique — but weak in
                            intellect. And, although in his immature infant state he possessed a negative innocence, it,
                            like many other things, had to be subjected to trial before it could be trusted. They who
                            reason from that stand-point, begin at the lowest round in the ladder of progression, and
                            trace the lines upward, and claim for men and women, at the present time, superiority of
                            intellect and knowledge, over what were possessed by those who were placed in fair Eden.
                            Others take a different view, and begin with man as a perfect being, who, instead of his
                            being the product of Nature through growth and development, from the lower to the higher,
                            was an independent creation — fashioned directly by God, Himself ^ and of course was very
                            perfect and beautiful as he came from God's hands—resembling Angels, but a little lower. By
                            disobedience man was marred and lost his rectitude. Leaving all such theories, let us look
                            at stern facts and realities, as we find them existing to-day. It is said that " a stream
                            cannot rise above its source." In our own country and cities we see thousands of
                            individuals, who bear the distinctive marks of their progenitors, in form, feature and
                            habit. Education in a wrong direction, fortune, and circumstances, over which they had no
                            control, have, in a large degree, made them what they are. The question arises, " How far
                            will they be held responsible for acts performed while thus conditioned ? What the penalty —
                            and how administered? Does God inflict punishment upon any human being ? Or, being
                            themselves debtors to violated law, which reacts upon the transgressor, does He leave them
                            to balance accounts in that way ? " When the ignorant sin against their own souls and
                            bodies, they cannot escape the effects. Fire will burn, whether intentionally or
                            accidentally applied — the effect, physically, is the same. Poverty often induces crime.
                            Again, thirst for intoxicating drink, and desire for sensual indulgence, are often impressed
                            upon infants while in a germinal state ; they are really made drunkards and harlots, before
                            they see the light of day. Who in justice should bear the responsibility ? We might have to
                            go back upon ancestral history many generations to answer that question correctly. The
                            sinned against, in such cases, cannot avoid suffering; but inflictions thus imposed are far
                            more tolerable to bear, than the keen remorse which those must feel, who have had superior
                            advantages, by birth, and education, in a physical and moral point of view, also of rising
                            in the scale of angelic life, by having their spiritual understanding opened and quickened
                            to perceive the beautiful, the true and good. If such abuse their privilege and fall from
                            their rectitude, how will they be acquitted by their own reason and conscience, which is, in
                            reality, the soul's tribunal ? Paul said, "If such fall away, it is impossible to renew them
                            again to repentance." We would not use so strong language as Paul did ; but rather say it is
                            difficult for such to find repentance unto life ; and if they feel sorrow and repentance
                            they cannot occupy the same degree as before. We can have some faint conception how the laws
                            of progress, and change of events, may blot out from the soul's memory, sins of ignorance,
                            and sorrows caused by the wrongs of others ; and how joy may even be enhanced, by
                            contrasting the good attained, with the sad picture of the past; but we fail to comprehend
                            how a star of magnitude, that has once filled a place and shone in the horizon of the
                            spiritual heavens, and fallen therefrom, can ever regain its position. They do not need fire
                            to descend from heaven upon them, or that God should use direct agencies of any kind, to
                            punish them; their own consciences will arraign them to answer the demands of violated law ;
                            and show them the worm that dieth not, and the fire that is not easily quenched.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-cognition" TEIform="index"/>SELF-COGNITION</head><p TEIform="p">' Knowledge occupies its place in the mind j and a force, even to the moving of mountains, is
                            therein, forthwith generated." In the above quotation, let us suppose the noted author, A.
                            J. Davis, referred directly to a knowledge of individual selfhood—the body and the soul and
                            their proper relations, the one to the other -— calling one the house, the other the inmate.
                            Correct knowledge of material things, teaches the architect to plan and build his house with
                            reference to the protection, comfort and convenience of the person, who is to inhabit it. He
                            is careful to see that it is well constructed, that it may afford a pleasant retreat from
                            the scorching rays of the summer's sun, and be a safe refuge from the bitter blasts of the
                            winter's storm. He gives particular attention to ventilation, knowing that the house must
                            breathe, if the inmate would live. The individual, who inhabits the dwelling, should possess
                            sterling worth, moral, intellectual, and spiritual, so as to be able to cooperate with every
                            true principle, that the house may be kept in order and not become foul; and at an early
                            period begin to show signs of decay, creating unharmonious relations between it and its
                            occupant — and the once beautiful tenement be deserted and left, either for a habitation of
                            wild beasts, or to crumble and fall—while the tenant becomes a wanderer— disappointed —
                            homeless and despondent. Is not this analogous to the house we live in 1 If the body, which
                            is the dwelling of the soul, while in the earth sphere, be well constructed, and constantly
                            guarded by hygienic laws, resisting every thing that would tend to defile, or bring
                            premature decay upon the soul's temple, how strong, healthy and vigorous might man and woman
                            be ! Governed by the law of use, there would be a continuous expansion of the internal
                            forces, and the mind, ever actuated by true principles, would be a receptacle, and
                            reservatory of natural and spiritual truth, relating to body and soul. The tabernacle would
                            have a good foundation, and the superstructure would be grand and beautiful — an honor to
                            the builder. Would not angels love to knock at the door of such a temple ? and would not the
                            holy spirit delight to dwell therein, and keep alive the fires of Divine inspiration ?
                            Without knowledge, we cannot work successfully, either on the earthly, or heavenly plane of
                            life. Knowledge of cause and effect is essential in all the relations of life. To understand
                            the uses of the elements of subsistence, also how they may be abused — and blessings be
                            turned into curses — is of vital importance. The earthly man and woman should so understand
                            the procreative laws, that they may generate healthy offspring, containing the life germs of
                            immortal beings. And they who dwell in earthly mansions —human bodies — should study how
                            best to preserve those bodies from blight, disease and premature decay. Therefore, " Know
                            thyself," should be inscribed in letters of gold upon the tablet of the heart, and be
                            engrafted into every fiber of the being. The present generation have entered largely into
                            the study of self; not, however, with a view of self-discipline and culture, in the true and
                            real -, but for the purpose of obtaining more ease, and more indulgence in those things
                            which demoralize soul and body. 29 <pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 3O SHA.KER The power of discernment
                            — of penetration — is requisite, that we may comprehend the motives which prompt to action.
                            A stern^ fixed purpose, to condemn the wrong and false, and to adhere tenaciously to the
                            right and true, is an endowment worthy the most sanguine efforts of rational intelligence.
                            Such a controlling power is capable of " moving mountains " of error from the human soul,
                            and " casting down lofty imaginations of the heart." By the possession of this knowledge and
                            power, have the flood-gates of iniquity been opened to the youth of our land ! They have
                            sought out many inventions to please and exalt themselves, and through vain imaginations
                            have drawn pictures which are unreal — built air castles which they never reach. And some
                            there are, who seek to evade truth; they have not the moral courage to meet it, nor honesty
                            of purpose to obey it, even when convinced of its verity. Thus they are often slain by their
                            own hands ; or by launching out upon uncertain seas, without fixed principles to guide them,
                            they are driven by the strong winds of passion, until forced upon some lone and desolate
                            island — wrecked — and left to the merciless, wild waves, to be dashed in pieces. Therefore,
                            to know, judge and control ones self, is the most useful knowledge to possess, and the most
                            important lesson to be learned. If we do not violate any physical law, thereby producing
                            disease of body, nor transgress spiritual laws, which pertain to the soul's welfare, there
                            will be no inharmony ; and we shall progress from one stage to another, in natural and
                            spiritual things. As we ascend the ladder of truth, which reaches from earth to heaven,
                            there will be a continual unfolding of the life germ within, until we attain unto a
                            condition of perpetual joy, where the sun, which lights up the spiritual horizon, will shine
                            eternally, with no dark cloud to obscure its rays. That condition will be Heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity" TEIform="index"/>CHARITY</head><p TEIform="p">CHARITY is the most beautiful attribute of the soul. Not that kind of charity which displays
                            itself in munificent gifts, without distinction or discrimination, or that censures and
                            condemns while it gives. They, who go forth in the spirit of love, seeking to understand
                            conditions, human frailties, and human needs, and are guided by the lamp of reason, are able
                            to comprehend the causes which lead to error and misfortune, and will charitably aid and
                            instruct, instead of condemning. The faculties, proclivities, and conditions of individuals,
                            on entering this world, are not of their own choosing. They have neither choice of
                            parentage, nationality, nor the age in which they shall live; nor even whether they shall
                            live at all. The influences, by which they are surrounded in early life, are beyond their
                            control, and conditions which they are forced to accept, help to mould their characters in
                            after life. Hence, society, in a great degree, is responsible for individual action. If an
                            individual be wanting in intellectual and moral power to resist crime, and through malice,
                            or selfishness, commit a wrong against friend, neighbor, or stranger, is it possible to
                            remedy that wrong by retaliation ? Is it not better to " overcome evil with good ? " I think
                            we are safe in saying, that vindictive measures, for the punishment of crime, have totally
                            failed to prevent it. " Like, begets its like." If we would oppose evil successfully, it
                            must be by its opposite — the spirit and power of good. Expel darkness by the introduction
                            of light. A prison, as a place of punishment for offenders against civil law, where they are
                            shut in from the influence of superior minds — deprived of human sympathy — associated
                            exclusively with evil doers, who have been schooled in vice, appears, to my mind, a disgrace
                            to an enlightened age, and unworthy a Christian people, professing to be governed by "
                            Charity which suffereth long." Would not Christian charity be vindicated and made more
                            apparent by removing the incentives to selfish and dishonest acts — abolishing all forms of
                            monopoly — making nature's gifts equally free to all her children ? Would it not be more
                            effectual to convert jails and penitentiaries into reform schools — moral hospitals—where
                            those, who need it, could have sanitary treatment, and all could feel a wholesome restraint,
                            dictated only by wisdom and love ? The human family is inseparably bound together, each
                            class receiving aid and instruction from those above it. Heaven's blessings pass, from
                            sphere to sphere, through the links of the chain of gradation. And they who can extend a
                            helping hand to those who are the farthest below them, and still maintain their own
                            integrity, will be blest and receive strength from spheres correspondingly above them. Let
                            light shine, and sympathy flow to all; then the sweet spirit of charity will ally us closely
                            to the Angels whose crowning attribute is Love, "The noblest virtue of the soul — The
                            brightest star that gilds our skies— The fairest flower among the whole, Which blossoms in
                            their paradise."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Broadway, Emeline" TEIform="persName"/>Emeline Broadway, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC</head><p TEIform="p">There is music—harmony — in all of God's creation. Through all of nature's vast realm— the
                            great, deep, the dense forest, the wild winds — in the ripened fields of grain and flowers,
                            in the running streamlet and birdsong, there is melody. If man and woman, who were created
                            in honor to be the crowning, concentric work of God's hands, had abode in that honor, they
                            would have been pre-eminent instruments of music, to whom all other forms of music would
                            have converged and been adjuncts. No instrument of music invented by man can equal the human
                            voice, which God created. The souls of men and women, are living organs, and may drink in
                            inspiration, from the Almighty ; and the human voice, by the power of that inspiration, can
                            utter music, full of life, that is saving, healing and exhilarating. That is the music which
                            brings souls into contiguity with the angel-world. Every gift and faculty, of body and mind,
                            if properly used, tends to harmony. Music, in Nature, is God's gift to humanity ; but it is
                            designed to subserve the spiritual. When they are linked together, in harmonious relations,
                            then is God honored, and humanity happified. Hearts, oppressed with sin, have often found
                            relief, by the uplifting song of prayer and praise. When wearied with care and serving, the
                            ever-varying musical sounds in nature's voices, soothe and give rest; and when physically
                            diseased, or mentally depressed, music is a great restorative. We have all felt its power,
                            more or less, and are indebted to the Giver, from whom flow all good gifts to earth's
                            children. Soul music elevates, refines and purifies. Some persons have been heard to say, "
                            they were never affected to tears, but by the power of music." Music often touches the
                            divine feelings in the soul, and causes it to bow in humble contrition before God, the
                            author of its existence ; and to awaken slumbering energies, stir up latent powers, call
                            forth better thoughts and feelings, and form the basis of a purer, and more consecrated
                            life. There is a natural connection between delightful sounds, and beautiful thoughts; but
                            the noblest and richest of God's gifts to mankind, may be, and are, oftentimes, abused. Wre
                            see the military hero, by the sound of martial music, inspiring his army to go forth to
                            battle, like the infuriated demons, to wound and slay their fellows, who have never injured
                            them. Music, both vocal and instrumental, is often used to play upon the baser passions — to
                            allure to sin — and awaken sensual desires. Hence the vocal, musical organs, like the
                            tongue—the power of speech — are used both to bless God, and to dishonor Him — to cultivate
                            the religious and irreligious nature in man, and woman. We cannot be justified in rejecting,
                            or neglecting, any gift or faculty, because at times applied to false uses. Every gift and
                            talent may be exercised in honor of the Giver, and to the benefit of humanity, if we so will
                            it. And the best means should be accepted to accomplish that end. To promote harmony, and
                            exalt goodness and truth, should be our chief delight and purpose. The science of music
                            should be studied, and the human voice cultivated, under the direction and inspiration of
                            angelic teachers ; and whatever agencies can be applied, whether vocal or instrumental, that
                            will lead from low loves and desires, progress humanity God-ward, and tend to sanctify their
                            spirits — should be accepted. A deep appreciation, and enjoyment of fine appropriate music,
                            widens our sphere of thought, quickens the emotional feelings, increases inspiration, and
                            imparts heavenly joy. A recent writer on the subject of music says : " We have reached a
                            state of chaos in which music, as an embodiment of religious feeling, threatens to be
                            entirely lost." This ought not so to be. Science and Religion should be as nearly connected,
                            as a healthy soul and body. It is our privilege to grow and increase in all that is good and
                            true, and to be intelligent subjects of infinite grace. Let every heart be open to receive
                            good from any source, and closed to all discordant sounds. Then harmony and true love will
                            be ours, to enjoy in time, and we shall be fitted to join in those melodious strains of
                            praise divine, which roll through the heavenly arches in the life beyond.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Semantha" TEIform="persName"/>Semantha White, Son Yea, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food" TEIform="index"/>FOOD</head><p TEIform="p">Written for the Shakeress by a sister eightyfour years of age. Been a member of the Society
                            sixty-five years. Dearly Beloved : I prize the privilege of addressing a few lines
                            expressive of my feelings. The Shaker and Shakeress is a medium through which food is
                            conveyed to the lambs of Christ's flock who are daily striving against evil in themselves.
                            They need spiritual food; and I know you are inspired by the Christ-spirit to prepare such
                            food as is needed to encourage, strengthen, and bear souls through all trials and
                            temptations, which every one must meet while journeying, from the wilderness of sin, to the
                            heavenly land. The work of the Gospel is designed to purify and prepare souls for higher
                            enjoyments than nature can give — even the treasures of immortal life. The many strong,
                            clear testimonies of truth, coming from progressed minds, and those of long experience, shed
                            a benign influence, and give new vigor and life. 0, may it encourage others who are yet
                            bound in darkness—the servants of sinful passions — to come forth, " lay hold on eternal
                            life ;" and to rise above all carnal, selfish enjoyments, which are transient and worthless
                            ! That work can only be effected by an honest confession of all sin, and daily self-denial
                            of every thing that would corrupt and attach the feelings to inferior objects. Those who
                            have been the subjects of the Gospel of Christ and Mother, and have yielded obedience to its
                            injunctions, can testify of its power and efficacy. From my heart, I thank God that I was
                            called in .early life, to leave the paths of sin and sorrow, and take the cross of
                            self-denial which leads to purity of life, and gives an approved conscience. Again, I say, "
                            I love the Shaker and Shakeress. I receive strength and encouragement from every number. May
                            it live long — travel far and wide — and do much good to honest inquirers ! I ask God to
                            bless your labors. My treasure — my life — my all is in the work. And that good ministering
                            angels may guide us all in safety to mansions of peace, is the prayer of your sisA.ND <pb n="31" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEESS. 31 ter in the Church of Christ." And I ask for myself 0
                            blessed overruling Power; My every thought and act control! And in each dark and trying
                            hour, Be thou an anchor to my soul! Let me feel thy sweet embrace — Hold me with thy mighty
                            hand — Fill my soul with heavenly grace — Lead me to the promised land, Where the righteous
                            dwell together, Bound by cords of love divine ; Strife and discord never enter Those pure
                            mansions so sublime.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carnahan, Prudence" TEIform="persName"/>Prudence Carnahan, Pleasant HiU, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Death of the pharisee" TEIform="index"/>DEATH OF THE PHARISEE</head><p TEIform="p">Pastor, and deacons, and members were there, The church tower was just in sight. And the
                            pharisee gave them his last proud prayer From lips that were deadly white. He spoke of the
                            good that the blood had done That was spilt upon Calvary's tree, Of the godly race which his
                            feet had run — Of his deeds of charity. And he thanked the Lord again and again, With a
                            pious befitting look. That he was not like unto other men, But was led by the Holy Book. And
                            pastor, and members, and deacons groaned, To God let the praise be given ! The Crucified
                            also for us atoned, And we shall be with him in heaven. But the pharisee saw through the
                            veil of death An angel of truth draw near, And he wildly struggled and gasped for breath,
                            For his soul was struck with fear. And the angel said with a startling voice, Do you think
                            that your shams will win ? Can your spirit in light of life rejoice, When yours is a burden
                            of sin? But they tenderly bolstered the pharisee up To give him the holy bread, And they
                            brought him with care the communion And then stood amazed at his dread. [cup. O,why do you
                            bring me the wine? he said, For drunkards my eyes can see, That unto its treacherous tide
                            have fled Prom a woe that was wrought by me. They were the hopeful, trustful men, Who
                            thought my profession true, But just by the turn of my crafty pen Black ruin their fortunes
                            knew. O, take from my sight the children's food That I stole from the widow's hand, Their
                            father had call'd me his kinsman good, And left me his helpless band. Now I must meet with
                            that humbled face, Distorted by want and crime, Their mis'ry their deep hidden anguish
                            trace, As I pass from the shores of time. And look! do you see in your crowded street The
                            outcasts that wander there ? Do you know their young hearts, once pure and Were wreathed
                            with parental care ? Lsweet, But I gathered them into my lustful arms, By wiles that a fiend
                            might hate. And I robbed them of more than youthful charms, But repentance has come too
                            late. And the angel said with uplifted hand, Let all be warned who hear, For that is the
                            guilt that gives the brand Which will hardly disappear. Then the pharisee raised his dying
                            head, And said in a bitter tone, To those who were shrinking around his bed, Can any one
                            cast a stone ? We are alike in our worldly pride—¦ Alike in the angel's eye — Alike in the
                            sins which I strove to hide, And alike we all must die. Then give to the flames my pompous
                            will, And know you are dispossessed, For gain that was gotten by means so ill, Belongs to
                            the sore oppressed. And the parson, and deacons, and members said, With many a knowing
                            shrug, Our brother is fevered —out of his head — Physician, where is thy drug ? Or, where
                            thy balsam of acid and gall That was a last drink of old ? But, ere he could answer their
                            urgent call, The Pharisee's heart was cold. And they gave the pharisee burial grand, As
                            griefless as ever was given, And published his righteousness over the land, Yet knew he was
                            far from heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Even the white mantle of religion is too frequently dragged through the bloody pool of war..." TEIform="index"/>Even the white mantle of religion is too frequently dragged through the bloody pool of war...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Even the white mantle of religion is too frequently dragged through the bloody pool of war.
                            Spain waged war with England in the seventeenth century because the latter founded colonies
                            in America. The former, in behalf of the Pope of Rome, claimed that all heathen countries
                            belonged to him as the Vicegerent of God upon earth. The thirty years' war, 1618-1648,
                            between Germany and France, was a contest between Roman Catholicism and Protestantism. The
                            Greek and Latin monks of Jerusalem disputed about who should keep the key of the Holy
                            Sepulchre, whereupon Russia suspended diplomatic relations with Turkey and war subsequently
                            ensued. Hence Edward Everett remarked with a smile that Russia and Turkey went to war, spent
                            millions of treasure and destroyed thousands of lives to decide who should keep thekey to
                            thetomb of the Prince of Peace.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Personal experience" TEIform="index"/>PERSONAL EXPERIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Thirty years ago, while under a religious awakening, my mind was stirred to consider the
                            subject of Christ's second appearing, and to investigate the manner of his coming. I was
                            convinced that the prophetic periods, concerning that event, were fulfilled, and I accepted
                            the views of Miller for a time, and looked for the literal fulfillment of the scriptures in
                            regard to it. At length, I learned, through a paper then published by the Shakers, called "
                            The Day Star," that the second appearing of the Christspirit would be spiritual; and would
                            be spiritually discerned by those who were looking in faith for his coming; that instead of
                            a 'personal being, appearing in the literal clouds, in all the pomp and splendor of an
                            earthly prince, He would appear in a cloud of witnessing saints. And, as the apostolic band
                            was led by an ''Elder Brother, the first-born among brethren," who were left to establish
                            the first Christian church, after his ascension, so the cloud of witnesses that received the
                            returning Christ, that was promised, would be led and guided by an Elder Sister, the
                            first-born among many sisters. Thus the duality Deity — Father — Mother — God, would be
                            represented on earth, and it would be the commencement of a kingdom of righteousness and
                            peace that, like the " little stone cut out of the mountain without hands, would gradually
                            grow until it should fill the whole earth." I found that a watching, praying band, who had
                            looked in faith for the fulfillment of prophecy, had received according to their faith, were
                            already in the fruition of the prophetic promises, and were living in a united body,
                            carrying out the principles of the first pentecostal Church, bearing the insignia, Virgin
                            Purity, Non-resistance and Community of Goods. My understanding was opened to the excellency
                            of the work, my conscience approved, and I resolved to become a member of that body. I
                            dissolved my connection with the church to which I had belonged, and forsook my natural
                            kindred, for a superior heavenly relationship founded in truth and in justice. Thus, for
                            conscience sake, I forsook all, that I might rightfully inherit the kingdom of God. I have
                            not been disappointed. My anticipations have been realized. I found a new key to unlock
                            bible records, and never had the scriptures appeared half so precious, clear and
                            inspirational to me before. The Psalms of David filled me with a spirit of praise ! My mind
                            was particularly directed to the 21st chapter of Revelations. I realized, in a measure, what
                            it was " to eat of the hidden manna, and to receive the white stone with a sew name
                            (character) written therein, which no one can know save those who receive it." I felt that I
                            had found a people, who, by the purity of their lives, represented the number who were " to
                            stand upon Mt. Zion with palms of victory in their hands ; " and by consecrating all to God,
                            made it possible to live as do the angels, while here on earth, in human form. And while yet
                            young in years, I gave my heart, my life to God. And I have experienced the fulfillment of
                            that beautiful promise by the prophet Jeremiah, " Their souls shall be as a watered garden,
                            and they shall not sorrow any more at all;" the cause of sorrow being removed. Thus
                            perfectly agreeing with the revelator John, " God shall wipe away all tears from their eyes,
                            and there shall be no more death (spiritual death being produced by sin), neither sorrow nor
                            crying." To be placed in a condition to practically live according to Christ's teachings, to
                            be surrounded by brothers and sisters who are striving in all tilings to fulfill the
                            Saviour's inj unction, " Whatsoever ye would that others should do unto you, do ye even the
                            same unto them," is the greatest immunity mortals can possess. Self-discipline and
                            self-improvement are pre-eminently our work. Thirty years of my life have been given to
                            self-culture and reformation. I find it a noble work, and the most effectual way of helping
                            to reform others, and I do not grow weary in well doing.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Middleton, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Middleton, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crossing life's tide" TEIform="index"/>CROSSING LIFE'S TIDE</head><p TEIform="p">The loved, and the dear ones, are passing from me, One by one they are crossing life's tide ;
                            They're borne from my vision like ships on the sea, To the shore on eternity's side. The
                            spring time of childhood, and bright years of youth, Were blest by their kindness and caxe;
                            Their spotless example, of virtue and truth, Gave strength every conflict to bear. 0
                            precious the memories, twining my heart, Like tendrils of summer's fair vine! A new thrill
                            of life to my soul they impart, For sweet recollections are mine. The faces that beamed with
                            the sunshine of love— The hands that with mine were employed — The feet that were wont in my
                            pathway to move, And hearts that life's pleasures enjoyed. Though now in the immortal
                            regions beyond, And toiling in new fields above, Yet sacred and precious I hold the pure
                            bond, That links me to kindred, in love. For heavenly communion, my spirit oft yearns, I'll
                            draw from an angelic sphere; 1 know there's a land whence the trav'ler returns, To gladden
                            our pilgrimage here. Then come,O ye dear ones, who love as of yore, Add strength to the
                            faith that we hold ; Bring gifts that are new from the evergreen shore And treasures that
                            will not grow old.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Emily Offord, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solicitation" TEIform="index"/>SOLICITATION</head><p TEIform="p">The joys of earth I would not seek, That transient pleasures give; I ask a spirit low and
                            meek, That in the truth would live. I crave not worldly honor, fame, Or glittering golden
                            store ; But I would win the Christian name The cross our Saviour bore. Nor do I ask to be
                            adorn'd With laurels, won by strife; But only seek to be enroll'd, Within the book of life.
                            I ask, that pure angelic love May find in me a place, The spirit of the heavenly dove, The
                            power of quick'ning grace. That I may be a vessel pure, Fit for the Master's use ; The
                            burning fire of truth endure, Its radiance diffuse. And ever seek to bear aloft, The banner
                            of sweet peace ; That hung'ring souls may gather oft, To share its rich increase.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda R. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother or Criminals" TEIform="index"/>A MOTHER OF CRIMINALS</head><p TEIform="p">Some of the most curious and remarkable criminal statistics ever obtained have just been
                            given to the public by Dr. Harris of New York. His attention was called, some time since, to
                            a county on the upper Hudson which showed a remarkable proportion of crime and poverty to
                            the whole population—480 of its 40,000 inhabitants being in the alms-house — and, upon
                            looking into the records a little, he found certain names continually appearing. Becoming
                            interested in the subject, he concluded to search the genealogies of these families, and
                            after a thorough investigation he discovered that from a young girl named "Margaret"—who was
                            left adrift, nobody remembers how, in a village of the county, 70years ago, and, in the
                            absence of an alms-house, was left to grow up as best she could —have descended two hundred
                            criminals. As an illustration of this remarkable record, in one single generation of her
                            unhappy line there were twenty children ; of these, three died in infancy, and seventeen
                            survived to maturity. Of the seventeen, nine served in the State prisons for high crimes an
                            aggregate term of fifty years, while the others were frequent inmates of jails and
                            penitentiaries and alms-houses. The whole number of this girl's descendants, through six
                            generations, is nine hundred, and besides the two hundred who are on record as criminals, a
                            large number have been idiots, imbeciles, drunkards, lunatics, prostitutes and paupers. A
                            stronger argument for careful treatment of pauper children than these figures could hardly
                            be found.</p></div2><pb n="32" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning's dawn" TEIform="index"/>MORNING DAWN</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Zion shall arise and blossom like the rose, Her glorious light shine forth
                            to the islands afar, As when the star of Bethlehem arose. The wilderness shall bloom, hills
                            and valleys rejoice. Woodlands sing for joy, and the barren desert smiles To hear the
                            Saviour's voice. Thus saith the Lord, it shall yet come to pass, Many people and strong
                            nations shall come to Jerusalem to seek and to pray before the Lord. Chorus to be sung at
                            the end, of each repeat. Hail! all hail, the coming day I Hail! all hail, the coming
                        day.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Renouncing the world" TEIform="index"/>RENOUNCING THE WORLD</head><p TEIform="p">For three score years I've lived and toiled, Where selfishness has reigned supreme ; Where
                            sordid hands have grasped and soiled All that was worthy of esteem. Like soldiers in their
                            horrid strife To maim and slaughter all their foes, So men have struggled through this life,
                            To gain its lucre crimes and woes. To heal the wounds of such a curse, Many have read,
                            thought, preached and prayed, While still the world's been growing worse, Its downward
                            course by nothing staid. After much study, now, the case To me seems like the Gospel way,
                            Too plain for one of weakest race— Who loves the truth — to go astray. Can any live for self
                            and others? Serve mammon, and his God as true ? Exalt himself, lift up his brothers ? Keep
                            all he has — give to the poor? By aiming low, can we rise high ? Pursuing wrong, can we end
                            right? Perceive the truth with double eye? Truly preach peace, and really tight? Such
                            monstrous wrongs make fools and knaves, Crowding the road to endless strife, While simple
                            views make moral Braves, Who lead the narrow way to life. As Bunyan writes, destruction
                            lowers O'er all this silly reckless world; Why not then flee to the sweet bowers Where
                            Christ is gathering all his fold ? Gladly I go to that sweet place, To that household of
                            purest love, Renouncing all the world to embrace, And live and reign with Christ above.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. Perkins, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persons, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Persons
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Persons, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName">Elizabeth Persons</persName>, September 9, 1874, aged
                                72.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manard, Betsey F." TEIform="index"/>Betsey F. Manard
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Manard, Betsey F." TEIform="persName">Betsey F. Manard</persName>, February 6, 1875, aged
                                67, Enfield, Conn.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rope, Polly M." TEIform="index"/>Polly M. Rope
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rope, Polly M." TEIform="persName">Polly M. Rope</persName>, January 27, 1875, aged 49.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sprague, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Sprague
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sprague, Charlotte" TEIform="persName">Charlotte Sprague</persName>, February 3, 1875, aged
                                49, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buchanan, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane Buchanan
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Buchanan, Jane" TEIform="persName">Jane Buchanan</persName>, January 31, 1875, aged 86.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Redman, William" TEIform="index"/>William Redman
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Redman, William" TEIform="persName">William Redman</persName>, February 1, 1875, aged 76,
                                Union Village, O.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brown, John" TEIform="index"/>John Brown
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Brown, John" TEIform="persName">John Brown</persName>, February 13, 1875, aged 51.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stewart, Philemon" TEIform="index"/>Philemon Stewart
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Stewart, Philemon" TEIform="persName">Philemon Stewart</persName>, February 20, 1875, aged
                                75, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunny side" TEIform="index"/>SUNNY SIDE</head><p TEIform="p">Look on the sunny-side—dense clouds may gather, And silently overspread life's fairest sky;
                            Look on the sunny-side — next to your sorrow, And soon the dark shadows of gloom will pass
                            by. Look on the sunny-side, weary, worn sisters, Ye who are treading the world's thorny maze
                            ; You tread not alone, if your faith reaches heaven, You toil not alone,—God will brighten
                            your days. Look on the sunny-side, true struggling brothers, Ye, who are battling with
                            hardships of life ; Fight on, your weapons heaven will prosper; And vict'ry determine your
                            zeal in the strife. Look on the sunny-side, ye who are hopeless, And constantly mourn over
                            life's many ills ; Keep up good courage, for glorious sun-light Is gilding the tops of
                            faith's beautiful hills ! Look on the sunny-side, O ye who are drooping, Like flowers that
                            perish for want of good care ! Come, gather new strength — Truth's morning is breaking, Lift
                            up your frail heads, and breathe in its sweet air. Look on the sunny-side, ye who are
                            burdened, Cast off your cares, for this life is so brief, It must not be wasted, nor robbed
                            of enjoyment, Nor given to toil without rest or relief. Look on the sunny-side ye who are
                            youthful, Gather the light that will ever abide ; The way to be hopeful and healthful and
                            happy Is to keep right before you — the bright sunnyside.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shultz, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Shultz, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual cabinet" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL CABINET</head><p TEIform="p">Captious investigators of Spiritual phenomena have made great outcries about the "dark
                            circles," and serious objections to the '' medium's cabinet," I think unwisely so. Jesus
                            touched the law, when he said, '' When thou prayest, enter into thy closet, shut the door,
                            and thy Father, who seeth in secret, better than in outward light, shall respond to thee
                            openly — externally." The Soul — the real man or woman — has but one set of senses. If these
                            are acting through the bodily organs, upon things of external nature, they are turned away
                            from the objective realities of the inner Spirit world. Stillness — Quaker retirement —
                            waiting upon God — is as necessary to those who would become Spiritual-minded, as that a
                            person wishing to go east, should turn his or her face from the west. In the early stages
                            and phases of spiritual development, this retirement is indispensable. As communications
                            become established, faith increased, and the power of mediumship multiplied, the currents
                            from the inner world, more readily overbalance the earth currents of thought, motive and
                            self-interest. Some self-possessed persons can, like Horace Greeley, carry on conversation,
                            and write editorials, at the same time. That is not the rule. Secrecy has its proper
                            function, as in giving alms, in Spirit communion, and in many of the most important
                            functions of animal economy. The heart is a somewhat important organ, but the less sunlight
                            shines upon it, the better for the rest of the members. Among the Jews, the Ark was a hiding
                            place for sacred things. It was kept in the Holy of Holy places '' There will I meet with
                            thee and there will I commune with thee, from between the cherubim," — was the arrangement
                            of the Jewish God — and that was the most private — secret — sacred place, in the whole
                            nation. It was where the outward and inward worlds touched each other. There may be
                            condescension by materialization, but the Law remains — that a Cabinet is congenial to the
                            feelings, and useful, as a meeting house, both to Mediums and Spirits. A Shaker Society is a
                            Spiritual Cabinet, to the outside world. We go out, and retire back again, to renew our
                            strength. There are Thomases who need external manifestations to convince and satisfy them.
                            They believe from that kind of evidence. They need it. Another class believe, from a higher
                            and more spiritual kind of evidence. More blessed are such. They are on a higher
                            plane—further progressed. SEC^lKER A.JSTD SH^KERESS.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>