<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1102" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18810201" TEIform="date">February 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25- 48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> FEBRUARY, 1881. .{ 60 Cents Per Annum MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United
                        Societies. OUR HOME AT CANTERBURY, N. H. And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" "Go preach the Kingdom of
                        God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNiCATIONS TO "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.G." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XL No.
                        2. The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="25" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Shaker Manifesto, tho' in appearance small, Has this goodly motto : Go preach the
                            Kingdom" to all,— Embarrassed by none, it obeyeth the call. Sailing out in the deep waters
                            where danger assails, Heavy surges are breaking, and darkness prevails, Adding trials and
                            conflicts the Truth to maintain, Keeping boldly at work for humanity's gain; Ever prayerful
                            and humble, while trusting in God, Reviving new courage, by proclaiming His word: Making
                            paths of sweet sunshine, yea, happier days, All along thro' life's strange and mysterious
                            ways; Ne'er flinching in purpose, but upholding the right, In the many or few, who are
                            seeking true light,— Forgiving, forgetting all injuries past, Espousing no baneful emotions
                            that blast, Sincerely inviting all souls who aspire To rise, and keep rising, still higher
                            and higher Out of worldly dissensions— unholy desire.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England witchcraft and spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>NEW ENGLAND WITCHCRAFT AND
                            SPIRITUALISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">Abstract ideas are, to individual and national conduct, as the primitive rocks in earth's
                            structure are to the soils we cultivate which are the product of those rocks. Social customs
                            and national laws are resultants of theological creeds, abstract principles and ideas that
                            at the time are generally accepted and acted upon. From the Jewish axiom of justice—"An eye
                            for an eye and a tooth for a tooth"—come personal, family and national wars—and this, too,
                            even among Christians who also have an axiom—"return good for evil." The New England
                            Puritans held the abstract theological idea that God was an Athanasian God who could create
                            something out of nothing, and, because he was Almighty, had a right to do wrong. The
                            ecclesiastical and civil rulers united to act upon the same abstract principles. Their axiom
                            was: "A King or Priest can do no wrong"—their will being the standard of religious and
                            secular right and truth. To them, the Bible was the word of God—when it was finished by the
                            Council of Nice, Divine Revelation, from God to man, was also finished forever and ever.
                            Consequently every thing supernatural— all spiritual manifestations — were THK <pb n="26" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 26 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. necessarily from the devil and his angels, so that it
                            only had to be proved that a person was a spiritual medium—not a fraud—to put it beyond a
                            doubt that he, or she was a wizard, or witch, and as such, liable to be legally and
                            religiously executed. Upon this basis rested all the trials for witchcraft in New England.
                            The trials were conducted by torture so that the accused had no means of escaping punishment
                            except by confessing themselves guilty. In Essex Co., Ct., twenty persons were put to death
                            between June 9th and September 23d, 1692, by direct action of the civil magistrates—just one
                            hundred years before the Church of Christ's second appearing was founded. Some two hundred
                            persons were tried and condemned to death, and many of those, who were not publicly
                            executed, perished under the hardships of prison life and the gnawings of mental anxieties.
                            Others had health, spirits, domestic ties broken, worldly possessions shattered by
                            confiscation, and their subsequent lives made forlorn and miserable. Their social sufferings
                            and personal mental horrors can never be adequately portrayed. What constituted, legally, a
                            wizard or witch ? First, an undoubting belief in a great personal devil, almost equal in
                            power and omniscience to Deity itself. Second, a covenant with the devil, voluntarily
                            entered into, in which persons signed their names in the devil's book, with a pen dipped in
                            their own blood. The covenant consisted in an agreement, between the parties, to each do the
                            other's will when called upon. The mortal, in consideration of certain favors to be granted
                            by the devil—as riches, honors, sensual pleasures to be enjoyed for a speci. fled
                            time—agreed to be the devil's servant here on earth, and after death go to a hell of
                            unlimited duration and torment. It was believed that the devil was powerless for evil in a
                            community, unless some man, woman or child did thus covenant with, and sell their souls to
                            him. From this conviction it follows that the civil rulers, who cared for the interests of
                            the commonwealth, felt conscientiously bound to co-operate with the priests who were seeking
                            to save the souls, committed to their care, from a literal hell of fire and brimstone, by
                            hunting up, trying, convicting and killing the witches. The kingdom and dominion of the
                            devil consisted of the infernal regions, in the spirit world, and of all Jewish, Mahomedan
                            and heathen nations and their inhabitants on the earth. The American Continent— New
                            World—with its Indian population, was his special inheritance. He was therefore designated
                            as a " great land holder." From these premises, anti-Christians conceived it to be their
                            civil right and Christian duty to exterminate the Indians, as did the Spaniards, in South
                            America, and as the Jews exterminated the inhabitants of the land of Canaan. To the
                            Puritans,the Bible was a law-book^ in any court of justice. Hence, " Thou shalt not suffer a
                            witch to live," was New England common law. If the accused confessed being a witch and
                            having signed his or her name,in blood,in the devil's book, death was not inflicted.
                            Therefore the position of the greatest safety to any individual was that of an accuser of
                            other persons as being witches. Why the confession of being a witch—pleading guilty —when
                            accused, ensured safety, I am unable to decipher. As things were, for a time, no person,
                            high or low, in the community, was safe. The whole population were living in the greatest
                            degree of uncertainty and in a state of continual terror, beyond the power of modern secular
                            republicans to comprehend or conceive. As was to be expected, many became informers, both
                            for the pecuniary reward thut went with conviction, and also to insure their own personal
                            safety. Just before her own execution, the clearheaded Mary Estus said to her executioners,
                            "Try the confessing witches, I being confident several have belied themselves and others."
                            Any genuine spiritual manifestation, such as those at Dr. Phelps' in Stamford, Ct., that
                            I,myself witnessed" was demonstration strong as proof from holy writ," of a case of
                            witchcraft. Some whole families, like the Eddies, were mediumistic. Abigail Faulkner,
                            daughter of the Rev. Francis Dane, of Andover, was condemned <pb n="27" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 27 to death. Her two daughters, only eight and ten years of age, testifying that
                            their mother had made witches of them, they having signed their names in the devil's book
                            with pen dipped in their own blood. She was tortured to make her confess, but died without
                            confessing. Giles Corey, an old man eighty-one years of age, was accused and tried. Refusing
                            to confess, the court ordered him to be put to the torture. They laid him prostrate and
                            piled heavy weights upon him to break his stubborn will. He called upon them to "pile on
                            more weight! more weight!" till he died. Cotton Mather, Gov. Endicot and their coadjutors
                            were, no doubt, sincere, humane, God fearing people, who reasoned logically from false
                            premises—absurd theological dogmas and erroneous abstract ethical ideas —which at that time
                            were generally recognized by the compound government of Church and State as it then existed
                            in the British Empire, both at home and abroad, as a safe and infallible rule of action.
                            Some rationalists assume that there was nothing spiritual, or supernatural about New England
                            witchcraft—that the witches, or mediums, were frauds, and the accusers, informers, judges,
                            lawyers and juries were all superstitiously deluded—that given the power, all religious
                            people who are working for the union of Ecclesiastical and Civil government, whether
                            Catholic or Protestant, would be conscientiously bound to re-enact, with the modern
                            Spiritualists, Shakers and Quakers (on a far larger scale), all the bloody cruelty of New
                            England witchcraft. With Cotton Mather, Gov. Endicot and many magistrates,their hearts would
                            bleed, while their wrong-headed theology and the possession of Ecclesiastical and Civil
                            power, which should never ha^e been conceded by the people, impelled them to perpetrate
                            judicial murder. In her—Babylon Church and State—was found all the blood shed upon the
                            earth. The Duke of Alva, the Crusaders, Torquemada, Endicot, were just what any other human
                            being would be under their circumstances. The place for wild beasts is within iron bars,
                            with a keeper. And the place for ecclesiastics who believe in war, and for civil rulers who
                            believe in such ecclesiastics, is without the pale of pulpit or forum. That the supernatural
                            was enacted in the Salem witchcraft delusion is as certain as human testimony can make any
                            thing. It was this general popular belief that upheld the government in their legal
                            persecutions and public executions. To us, in the light of our American secular government,
                            republicanism and modern spiritualism, it is clearly a case of gross religious ignorance,
                            political heresy, "doctrine of devils "—of madness and folly on the part of priests,
                            magistrates and people, who all reasoned from false premises,—untrue abstract ideas of both
                            Church and State, with a logic that was almost as terrible to the judges, juries, witnesses
                            and spectators, as it was to the trembling victims themselves. , The form and manner of the
                            arraignment was one of the worst and most astonishing phases of the delusion. A person,
                            perhaps a mere child, affirmed that at such a time and place, the apparition, or ghost of
                            such and such a living man, or woman appeared to witness, and bewitched them—caused witness
                            to do so and so, and sign his, or herself away, and that the devil's book contained the
                            record. Then the man or woman was arrested, when the accused might not have been within ten
                            miles of the informer, tried, tortured to confess, goods confiscated, family broken up, good
                            name blasted, all ending in confusion and wretchedness. I heard Dr. Phelps say he would
                            rather his house had been burned, than to have his children become spiritual mediums. A
                            pious, blameless, religious life was no shield nor protection against an irresponsible
                            accusative informer. None were safe. In 1692, the spirit world came down upon, and entered
                            into the natural world—just as it is now doing in 1881. In 1842, the Beechers, in New York,
                            declared that spiritualism was real—but that it was of the devil. It only required the same
                            union of the Ecclesiastical and Civil powers that existed in 1692 to have reproduced the
                            scenes of New England witchcraft. Let all be thankful for the separation of Church and State
                            in a government that respects the inalienable rights of <pb n="28" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 28 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. the Jews, In (idels, Pagans, Atheists, Materialist, as it does those of the
                            marrying and fighting Christians who are working foi such a government as existed in the
                            times of New England witchcraft and spiritualism. In the above article I have drawn
                            literally from Allen Putnam's New England Witchcraft, a book I can highly recommend to the
                            students of Scientific Spiritualism. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exorcising spirits" TEIform="index"/>Exorcising Spirits</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>f. w. e.</byline><p TEIform="p">[NOTE.] . I had the following statement from the lips of Dr. Phelps of Stamford, Conn., which
                            is a village of retired Gospel ministers: When, beyond a doubt, his two children became
                            Spiritual mediums — the wonder of the whole country —• a meeting of the clergy and their
                            deacons was convened to exorcise Spirits, as they had no legal power to kill the mediums.
                            Each one came armed with the sacred Word of God — a holy Bible. Whilst sitting all around
                            the room, with the Bibles in their laps, the books began, of their own accord, to fly from
                            one's lap at the head of one of the ministers across the room. This process being continued
                            until the meeting was broken up in the utmost terror and confusion, </p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mending a back" TEIform="index"/>MENDING A BACK</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> There is a bright side in a sick room, as one of our brothers lately proved while patiently
                            enduring a painful tho' not serious " spell." To while away the hours of his almost willing
                            imprisonment among sympa. thizing friends, who had been generally only common brothers and
                            sisters, this cheerful patient wrote down the advice given him as freely as it was well
                            intended. Orders for a common attack of lumbago complicated with hypo and sciatica : Take a
                            wet sheet pack, a good dose of castor oil. Take blue pills ; also senna and salta. Try
                            Belladonna Plaster. You need a good dose of rhubarb and jalap. You need a good clearing out
                            with pills, a capcine plaster, and a good rubbing with Pain King. Do please put on some
                            Thompson's genuine Opodeldoc. If you would take some Buchu you would be all right in a few
                            days. All you need is one dose of black cohosh and nux vomica. Well, you might try that,
                            and, if no better, Kennedy's Kidney Cure will fetch you around all right in two days. Why,
                            did they not tell you to take Gum Guiac? It would bring you up soon. Pshaw ! There's nothing
                            you need more than electricity ; cure you in one day ; you need a good portion of Mandrake,
                            followed by Wine of Colchicum. You don't live high enough, man ! Take some old Stout and
                            rare steak, with Dover's powders at night. Too much sugar in your blood ; avoid all sweets,
                            and drink hard cider freely. Why don't you send for Poland water? Lie down on the floor and
                            let me walk on your back, and you will get up well. A good dose of gin and lemon will give
                            you great relief if not a positive cure. You ought to blister the back of your neck. A good
                            ginger and hop poultice would put a new back in you, or else use mustard drafts. Why don't
                            you give up and be doctored and not act so silly ? Just as brother Benj. Gates was about to
                            decide which school of advice and kind theories to be patient under, his own good
                            constitution brought the " crik" out of his back and the usual "spring" in again. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grumblers" TEIform="index"/>GRUMBLERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bulkley, Ella L." TEIform="persName"/>ELLA L. BULKLEY</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Some murmur when their sky is clear, And wholly bright to view; If one small speck of dark
                            appear In their great heaven of blue." How like a museum with its ever-varying :rowd of
                            humanity is a Shaker community! <pb n="29" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 29 Every race has
                            there its type ; every class its representative. Some have a glorious everdwelling sunshine;
                            others nothing but darkness and clouds. These are the ones that require of others great
                            patience and tact, to manipulate him into the paths of Christian respectability. It is a
                            wonder even that we sometimes succeed. It is no wonder we frequently fail. Our doors
                            standing wide open to receive such as the world sends, and trusting to Providence to glean
                            from the chaff the occasional grain of wheat. We are often deceived by this human drift ;
                            but never by the class known in natural history as " Grumblers." They are not generally
                            depraved, some of them never break the ten commandments; many are of the strictest sect; but
                            nevertheless they are always grumbling. They don't seem really to wish you any real awful
                            trouble ; neither do they wish you to be unhappy ; but it's a constant growl about somebody
                            or something. Their eyesight is always keen—so keen that straight things to them become
                            crooked. You might do a thousand good things and they would never find it out; but just make
                            one false step, and they spring upon you without mercy. They seem to think it an absolute
                            necessity, in order to fit you for Heaven, to make you perfectly miserable on earth. They
                            have a peculiar dislike to sunshine. Their aim is to keep every one, but themselves,
                            constantly on the stool of repentance. If one is light-hearted, they taunt them with
                            frivolity ; if reflective, and a little quiet, they laugh and say you are "getting good." If
                            ever, by a miracle, one succeeds in pleasing them, they are sure, as soon as they recover
                            their equilibrium, to make you regret such trifling with their feelings. It is a sin in
                            their sight to show contentment, and awful to show a feeling of being happy with present
                            surroundings. In fact to professional grumblers nothing is ever right. A person that blows
                            up once in a while and gives vent in strong language to their ailments can be borne with • a
                            good, smart storm clears the atmosphere, but this perpetual, cold drizzle brings with it no
                            compensation. The fact is, some people prefer to have something to grumble about. If there
                            is a snag in the stream they see it. Sometimes present troubles will not suffice. Their
                            imagination soars far oft into the future, and they fret about what may possibly happen, If
                            they have something to growl about, all right; if not, they invent it ; and the trouble is,
                            those about them are always as uncomfortable as themselves. What a blessing a retreat for
                            grumblers would be! but oh, how doleful such an institution ! After all though, "like cures
                            like," and certainly it would be either "kill or cure," for they could not stand long under
                            each other's temperaments, and in the course of time, perhaps, they would see that sunshine
                            is far more desirable than clouds ; that cheerfulness is a duty we owe to God,our companions
                            and ourselves, to make life endurable. We were not created to bring darkness with us and
                            throw it around wherever we happen to be. It is our duty to make life a pleasure, take what
                            enjoyment we find, and give all the pleasure we can. There are those whose veiy presence is
                            sunshine. "Some who, with thankful hearts are filled, If but one streak of light — One ray
                            of God's good mercy gild — The darkness of their night." Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work as a mode of worship" TEIform="index"/>WORK AS A MODE OF WORSHIP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bostwick, C. B." TEIform="persName"/>C. B. BOSTWICK</byline><p TEIform="p"> The quaint simplicity of our songs must often strike the mind of strangers with a sense of
                            freshness and beauty, as refreshing as it is pleasant; some of the ideas expressed have a
                            tendency to recur again and again, until the mind is perforce obliged to take up the train
                            of thought suggested. In one of our songs occurs the phrase: " The Lord will require His own
                            with usury." This sentence has caused, by the process above hinted at, the following stray
                            thoughts on work as a mode of worship. How can we best show our respect, or in other words,
                            worship, to the Giver of all good ? reasoning by analogy I would say, by increasing our
                            endeavors to make the best use of the gifts God has bestowed on\ <pb n="30" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 30
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. us whether bodily or mental. We all have a gift either small or great;
                            it matters not how small, be earnest in trying to make the best of it. If it lies in
                            mechanism, science, agriculture, &amp;c, &amp;c, all these require improvement. Get
                            all the available knowledge in the direction your gift leads and go ahead; but don't get
                            discouraged that you can't lift the world, tunnel the Rocky mountains, or some other large
                            feat, when perhaps there is a bad place in the road at your very door that you could mend
                            well, and make of use to all; or if a farmer, whose class is to my mind the noblest on
                            earth, learn your business thoroughly from every source, it does not matter where, men,
                            books or nature, but don't be content to do a thing because " it has been done so for the
                            last generation or two and will do for you," it won't do for you, be sure of that. " The
                            Lord requires his own with usury," and the usury can be best attained by improving your gift
                            and making your land produce more than your predecessor by the skill you bring to bear on
                            it. By doing this you have three causes of satisfaction: you are doing the will of God by
                            improving your talents, you have increased the yield of your land, and have also the
                            satisfaction of being a direct encourager, (by example, which is better than precept), of
                            others in the same path, and lastly, all the time you have been working, you have been
                            worshiping God by doing his will. This will be found to be the case throughout all the gifts
                            of God; if the gift be small make it of use by constant practice of it ; if it be large,
                            then, my friend, a greater responsibility rests upon you, " the greater the gift, the
                            greater the burden." An earnest worker is one of God's true nobility; he is trying to do all
                            he knows, and by respecting the gift, he respects the giver. If Vanderbilt, Jay Cooke, or
                            any such were to give you any thing and wish you to use and improve it, would not you try?
                            Then why not try much more to improve that which a greater than they has given you. Our
                            Foundress said: "Hands to work, hearts to God," and also '' do your work as though you had
                            to die to-morrow, and as if you had to live a thousand years," thus proving that work had a
                            higher value than the one commonly set on it. There is as much worship in good workmanship
                            done in the right spirit, as in any other act; the spirit of the thing done and not the act
                            itself is the key to tell whether anything done be worship or not, but God, the master
                            workman, who has made the minutest insect with as much care as the mammoth elephant, sets us
                            the example of good work. Imitation is the sincerest praise. Mount Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Means and ends" TEIform="index"/>MEANS AND ENDS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> The several phases of Shakers' destiny as individuals, and also as a community, may be
                            conveniently divided into two distinct departments, viz.: means and ends. These considered
                            distinctly may give rise to suggestions enabling us to meet the every-day experiences of a
                            religious life with more serenity and resignation than we otherwise would. The means by
                            which we are gradually elevated to higher and higher degrees of holiness and happiness,
                            being nearly all in direct antagonism with our lower instincts and are necessarily painful.
                            Consequently to take hold of these means and put them into active and successful practice is
                            something like proposing to one's self to dwell in "perpetual burnings." I have, to be sure,
                            met with individuals who affected to be almost insulted to be told that there could be any
                            pain or suffering in doing good and practicing righteousness and holiness—-that after they
                            were once convinced of truth in any direction, it was only a pleasure to practice it —
                            ignoring entirely the universally recognized doctrine of " no cross, no crown." But I never
                            found one of that class in my life, who abounded in works of self-sacrifice for the good of
                            others, or even very instant in season and out of season in governing their own disagreeable
                            idiosyncracies and lower proclivities to sensuality and selfishness. If you wish to measure
                            the forbearance, modesty, tolerant spirit such a one is in possession of, enter into a
                            discussion as moderately as you may with him or her, <pb n="31" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 31 and on a subject in which you do not see quite alike, and though the point may
                            be of no importance whatever, still, if you do not accept without parley every thing they
                            have to say (and such generally wish to say about all there is to be said thereupon) you
                            will soon find that their patience is not as long as a drawing-knife handle. Such therefore
                            cannot consistently be considered practical exponents of a gospel which openly professes "
                            that through much tribulation we shall enter the kingdom of Heaven." But once more to the
                            means. These are as various as the circumstances, temptations, trials, different degrees of
                            amiability or otherwise, obtain in society, or in the experience of individual life. The
                            means of final salvation and triumph over evil, though in many respects the same with all
                            individuals and communities, yet in many minor respects according to divers idiosyncracies
                            of physiological, mental and spiritual character are necessarily very greatly modified. And
                            now if some bright, intelligent man, angel, or redeemed spirit would step in and impart to
                            me two great mysteries of godliness, how soon might I draw this subject to a close. 1. How
                            so to manipulate the condition of all Zion, temporally, spiritually, individually, and
                            socially, with the least possible amount of friction consistent with the safety of the
                            institution, and how to clothe each individual of our earthly Zion with such heavenly wisdom
                            as to enable every one to meet the trials, self-abnegation and searching self-discipline
                            necessary to refinement and purity with the least amount of friction possible. But alas ! It
                            seems that nothing but the slow grinding mills of experience, and the still slower
                            evolutions of universal progress, can furnish this precious knowledge or open the
                            innumerable combination locks of these great mysteries. But how often the prophetic gleams
                            of future triumph and heavenly peace suddenly break through the clouds of sorrow, scattering
                            all darkness and sadness and blessing us for hours and even sometimes whole days and weeks,
                            cheering and recuperating hope, and calm consolation, as though we had already entered upon
                            the full fruition of our final Heaven. Sometimes this is done by means of instrumentalities
                            we little suspected of possessing such power. I remember years and years ago of going to my
                            spiritual adviser for comfort or at least ability to stand, under almost unendurable
                            tribulation. He said " I propose to spend the afternoon in calling to mind one by one in
                            mere mechanical succession, all the regulations governing our family. You need not dwell
                            upon them, or make any application of them," said he, " but merely call them over." Now I
                            could not see the remotest relation between my suffering and the remedy; for the stringency
                            of these very regulations were a very weighty coefficient of the unknown quantity thereof.
                            However, as a drowning man in this sea of perdition, I caught at the straw reached out to me
                            and went into thorough compliance with the counsel of my good old spiritual adviser. The
                            cloud went up from about my habitation and was succeeded by one of the most serene periods
                            of sunshine and consolation, I ever experienced. I don't think a dispensation of exactly
                            that kind, of such length and severity and from precisely similar causes, ever visited me
                            any more from that day to this. I would infer from this that one at least of the methods of
                            releasement and abatement of friction and severe trials, must be sought from the
                            inspirational side of our nature, rather than that of the philosophical. To be sure the
                            aftermath of experience yields us wisdom, patience, courage, etc., but for the deadly
                            struggles of the days of inexperience, give me- the rich inspirations of well traveled
                            saints, all the nonsense of " be your own Saviour," " individual sovereignty," etc., etc.,
                            to the contrary notwithstanding. Thus much of means; of ends in relation thereto, anon.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shall standing armies be abolished?" TEIform="index"/>SHALL STANDING ARMIES BE ABOLISHED?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser</byline><p TEIform="p">An Open Letter to John Ruskin, England. " Inasmuch as you have done good, you have done it
                            unto me." Emotions of thankfulness for the standard f righteousness you have unjvultd in the
                                <pb n="32" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. British empire, is my apology for this
                            intrusion. I have read your work on " Political Economy," having for its central idea " Unto
                            this last, even as unto thee, will I give a penny." The central idea of the political
                            economy of modern civilization is " men are commodities." It has been truthfully said " that
                            to make men commodities is the sum of all villanies." Therefore modern civilization is that
                            sum. From that central idea, we have pauperism, crime, standing armies, a vast network of
                            debts, and a system of usury, in itself a sum of huge villanies, corrupting public morals
                            with the presence of luxurious idlers, and with hungry multitudes offering themselves in the
                            marts of labor. It is poor economy " to make men commodities," dangerous to the public
                            peace, enormously expensive, and as wicked as it is costly. In the armies and navies of
                            Europe the assumption is, that more than nine millions are directly, or indirectly employed
                            fulfilling the demands of war. In the forests, getting timber and charcoal, in the mines,
                            getting iron, lead, and other metals. Getting brimstone, saltpetre; preparing fulminates. In
                            the fields raising hemp, flax and cotton ; in spinning, weaving, and making swords, guns,
                            and gunpowder, and other destructive things. In ship-yards, docks, warehouses, and in the
                            actual service of war. The business of all these millions is to consume and to destroy.
                            Suppose these costly ships of war, and all property connected with war are convertible and
                            sold at cost; would not the incredible amount furnish materials for all the farmhouses and
                            barns these millions might want ? Again suppose, that these millions ramain paid and
                            officered for two years, and that these able-bodied men build these houses and barns, and
                            that the cavalry horses be detailed to assist. The men not engaged in building, to be
                            employed to clear and drain the land, planting fruit trees, plowing, and in putting in as
                            great a breadth of winter grain as can be well done. In war, great efforts are made; in this
                            case, make efforts to stock these farms with animals. In the spring all hands will be free
                            to put in grain, roots, beans, peas, and fodder plants. The winter grain will be ready to
                            harvest soon ; the beans, peas, and roots will then be available. When the pay is
                            discontinued, a heavy burden will be removed from the shoulders of the people, and Europe
                            delivered from war and its expenses. Instead of the war-cry, "give us men and money," the
                            professional destructives will be transformed into useful men having stores of something to
                            eat, to dispose of, and to enrich the fields for future crops. Near the end of the third
                            year, these nine millions of able-bodied men will be self-supporting, and able to furnish
                            bread stuffs (or their equivalents) enough to feed about half the population of Europe. Many
                            may say, that the idea is not practical ; is it not practical to beat a sword into a
                            pruning-hook? Is peace not cheaper than war ? Practicability and cheapness, are they not
                            twin cousins ? Have we come to that, that folly and wickedness are more practical, than
                            their opposites ? Your system of education " training youth hygienically and morally,"
                            teaching them to be healthy and strong, " and to be just and kind to one another," rests on
                            the physical nature of man, and on his moral relationships. The system now in vogue, from
                            the A B C to the end of the chapter, rests on no such foundation. It does not deal with the
                            forced of life, the emotions ; but with the intellect, the servant of these forces. On this
                            system of education modern civilization rests ; and the underlying morality of it is, "
                            Unless you rob somebody, you will never be rich." It almost ignores human emotions* and goes
                            a great way toward arresting physical development, and self-reliant usefulness. Gives a
                            knowledge of words and figures, but not of the nature of the emotions. Cultivates the memory
                            but not the conscience, and throws a materialistic crust over the human spirit. A hygienic
                            and moral education brings joung people into the open air and gives useftrt exercise therein
                            : shows them how to provide for themselves, and for the demands of social life, and
                            introduces them to a knowledge of the spirituality of their being. No opposition can upset
                            your positions ; the more you are assailed, the clearer will the principles, and the facts
                            you have presented be. <pb n="33" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 33 I have had some
                            opportunity of testing a degree of hygiene applied to a few boys. Their diet consisted
                            mainly of breadstuff's, milk and fruit; flesh-meats, tea, coffee, etc., were not used. There
                            is a touch of instinct about us that recoils from taking the life of a chicken or a lamb;
                            not so with fruits, our hands are adapted to taking, and our mouths to eating them. Our legs
                            and feet are made but for moderate locomotion —not made to run after animals, nor our hands
                            to tear them to pieces. Before breakfast every boy had something to care for that involved
                            labor, and served as an introduction to the duties of the day, on the farm or in the garden.
                            The strength and tenacity of muscle these beys acquired surprised me; also did the
                            endurance, power of recuperation and buoyancy of spirits they possessed. No listlessness;
                            all that was ne cessary, was to direct their action, and that their leader should fare and
                            work as they did. If any thing occurred to mar the peace or affect the rights of any boy, it
                            had a good effect to turn the school into a court of justice, and make the boys jurors, and
                            justly and kindly settle the little difficulties. They felt better after the trial and a
                            wholesome moral tone was created. In such cases, the feelings of the boy tried should be
                            considered, that the sentiment of the court is not to punish, but to do justice. I was
                            pleased that the bishop of Manches. ter was led to write to you on the subject of " taking
                            interest on money lent," and sorry that a person of his standing should for an instant
                            entertain favorable sentiments in regard to the " giant sin of the age," and seek to support
                            the monstrous iniquity by referring to one of the parables of the Savior. First, He ought to
                            know that no authority can make wrong right; second, that the parables were drawn from the
                            common actions of men, and that for ages in the money marts of Palestine, the Jews treated
                            the heathens as they treat one another — take usury ; third, the bishop knows, that it is
                            contrary to Jewish law, to take any increase on any thing lent to a brother Jew. If wrong
                            for Jews, can it be right for Christians to take interest on money lent ? The direct
                            teachings of the Father of the New Creation on this point are " From him that would borrow
                            of thee, turn not thou away. Lend, hoping for nothing again." Desiring that the governments
                            of this world that operate by force and fraud, may be so changed, as to operate justly and
                            beneficially, is the prayer of Very respectfully, Your Friend,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ingersoll's creed" TEIform="index"/>INGERSOLL'S CREED</head><p TEIform="p">[From one lecture of Ingersoll we cull the following thoughtful assertions. Ingersoll is an
                            infidel to the Christ of the popular churches; but for the real Christ he has the largest
                            respect. So long as Ingersoll, or any other infidel, has an ardent love for the " Sermon on
                            the Mount," and has the greatest respect for honest men, with a hatred of jhypocrisy,
                            injustice, and impurity, he is our friend and we his. Barring the. fact, that Ingersoll
                            hurts our educated feelings, by his sometimes apparently sacrilegious remarks, few men who
                            say so much, savor more of wisdom.—Ed.] Honest industry is as good as pious idleness. Every
                            demonstrated fact is a verse in my Bible. Every school-house is a cathedral in my religion.
                            Real charity is to help the poor to help themselves. The Presbyterian God damns people to
                            glorify himself. No devil has ever been so bad as the Presbyterian God. Christ believed the
                            temple of God to be the heart of man. There was never a Presbyterian half so bad as his
                            creed. I have no ambition to be a winged pauper of the skies. If ever I go to heaven I want
                            to take my reason with me. If I owe Smith $10 and God forgives me, that don't pay Smith. If
                            we can't have a heaven without a hell then abolish both. <pb n="34" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. God will not damn a good citizen, a gooc father, nor a good friend. If there is a
                            God in the universe he wil' not damn an honest man. There is only one true worship, and that
                            is the practice of justice. Whenever a man can climb, help him climb, and make him climb.
                            Fear is a kind of dagger with which hypocrisy assassinates the soul. I will never ask God to
                            treat me any fairer than I do my fellow-men. Make the best of this world ; do the same of
                            the next when you get there. Let any church get control of power and you have the end of
                            political liberty. If I go to heaven and see even one of those I love in hell, I'll want to
                            emigrate. There is not a word in the gospel about keeping Sunday and going to church. The
                            most sacred edifice ever reared is home; the most sacred altar the fireside. As if an
                            infinite God would stand angry forever and ever at the insect called man ! Dignity is a mask
                            some people wear to keep you from finding out how little they know. John Calvin and John
                            Knox fitted each other like the upper and lower jaws of a wild beast. Presbyterianism looks
                            upon a baby as a lump of total depravity ; I, as a bud of humanity. I want to satisfy every
                            mother rocking her baby that she is not raising kindling wood for hell. I would rather be
                            annihilated than sit at God's right hand and know that a man was damned. If you go to hell
                            it will be for not practicing the virtues which the Sermon on the Mount proclaims. If you
                            forgive others God will forgive you. That's a fair bargain. You get nothing more than you
                            earn. Reason is the light of the soul, and if you haven't the right to follow it, what have
                            you the right to follow ? The churches for hundreds of years have always been willing to
                            trade off treasures in heaven for cash down. The Episcopal church is very fond of dignity.
                            Let every thing be done decently and in order, no matter who goes to the devil. If Christ
                            were to come again and the churches were t© try to crucify him, as they did before, I would
                            do my best to prevent it. The church of England exists by law and a man is saved by act of
                            Parliament. I suppose thousands of souls have been damned on demurrer. Whittield believed in
                            slavery because the negro stolen from Africa would be benefited by the Christian example of
                            the gentlemen who stole him. If preachers would turn their attention to cooking for the next
                            three months they would do more good than they have done by preaching in the last 300 years.
                            " They shall lay hands on the sick and they shall recover." This was foretold of the
                            preachers. But when they get sick themselves they fly to the doctor. A little miracle now,
                            right here—just a little one—• would do more toward the advancement of Christianity than all
                            the preaching of the last thirty years. Study the religion of the body in preference to the
                            religion of the soul. A healthy body will give a healthy mind, and a healthy mind will
                            destroy superstition. Jesus Christ was a Nazarene peasant, a great, good, and serene man,
                            and I pay him the tribute of my love and my tears. But for the theological Christ I have no
                            respect, The best man ever God made deserved damning, according to the Presbyterians, the
                            moment he was done, and then think that we must go back to the same shop for repairs. If I
                            meet in heaven some man whom I gouged on earth out of $300, and which God forgave me, he'll
                            be likely to make it uncomfortable for me and make me wish I'd settled in another star. It
                            is easier for a camel to pass through the eye of a needle than for a rich man to enter the
                            kingdom of heaven. But when did you see a rich church member unload because of this text ?
                            An infallible pope is no more absurd than an infallible book, and a good deal better in some
                            ways, for you can change the pope but you can't the book, unless you keep revising t all the
                            time.</p></div2><pb n="35" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leaves for the healing of the nations" TEIform="index"/>LEAVES FOR THE HEALING OF THE NATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hare, Gratia H." TEIform="persName"/>GRATIA H. HARE</byline><p TEIform="p"> [The following was sent us for publication. Out of respect for the parties so sending, we
                            comply, hoping great good may come from the same.—Ed.] Shall I, a child born but to love,
                            And through its sweets to find above The wisdom that from love evolves And it to its own law
                            resolves; In whom affections, like the spring From which the cooling draught you bring,
                            Gushes in constant pearly flow With gifts for all where it shall go ? Shall I be brought
                            subjective to Rough passion's sway in all I do, And feel its waves, all steeped in earth,
                            And, deeply dyed from fleshly birth, Rush madly o'er my world and me, All beauty through its
                            coloring see ? Must all affection's waters be Lost in such tumultuous sea, Diluted from its
                            purity ? ****** He, whom his manhood hath conserved, And hath his passion's force reserved,
                            Walks the earth, to-day a Lord, His garments, e'en, with life are stored; The very hem of
                            which would heal The saddest pain that hearts can feel. Oh, man ! my brother, through this
                            trust That life evolves e'en from the dust, Though crucifixion be the cost, The gain is
                            life, death only's lost. And if thy sister tempt thee, " eat The fruit," as to the taste
                            most sweet, Tell her of life ; its forces will, Through broken branch, in waste distill ;
                            And that the tree that beauteous waves Its branches clothed with glossy leaves All fragrant
                            in life's nectared breath, Through waste would fill the air with death To her thou'lt be a
                            Savior ; then A Jesus be 'midst other men. Glass eyes for horses are now made with such
                            perfection that the animals themselves cannot see through the deception.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pearls of great price" TEIform="index"/>PEARLS OF GREAT PRICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mills, Annie E." TEIform="persName"/>Annie E. Mills</byline><p TEIform="p"> I speak not of the wealth of the great deep sea; of the gems so eagerly sought for which lie
                            embedded in the sands of the ocean, and for which men risk their lives by diving to the
                            bottom shut up in diving bells, which must, if they but stop to think, appear like living
                            tombs. I would not speak of such pearls which are but trifles when compared with the rich
                            gems found in the great sea of humanity. Consider for a moment the bright and illustrious
                            minds in ages past, who have been called from time to eternity, but who have left on record
                            their lives of truth and honor, which are worth far more than rubies; of the sainted ones
                            who have passed^away who were so untiring, pleading with and teaching, not only by precept,
                            but by daily example, the way to worth and highest standard of life. But we are not obliged
                            to look back and call from the grave, to have it give up its dead, in order to prove that
                            the possession of truth and noble honor is far superior to that beauty which can be paid for
                            with the paltry dollar, for the love of truth, and a desire to shun every appearance of evil
                            is the greatest gift God ever gave to man. But what are these "pearls ? Are they not of the
                            mind? the intellect? in short, the whole souls of men? "And what will it profit a man if he
                            gain the whole world and lose his soul, or what will he give in exchange for his soul?" And
                            further, are our talents and time given to us for use or abuse ? Are we not responsible for
                            the gems intrusted to our care, even if they may be small or illustrious? But would the
                            valuable pearl's or precious stones, if left in the bottom of the sea, be more than the
                            pebble by the roadside if left for all time in oblivion? Do they not have to pass through
                            the hands of the refiner to be polished until rays gleam forth in dazzling brightness? How
                            thankful we should be for the gift of conscience, endeavoring to have it show up for each
                            day's work a clear record, being <pb n="36" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. careful else
                            it be contaminated with evil literature, evil associations, idleness, untruthfulness,
                            dishonesty, envy, jealousy and strife, until it becomes so seared and blackened with sin
                            that we deprive ourselves of the lofty enjoyments God designed for us in the beginning. It
                            matters not how long we may live, our time here is but short, if ^-pent in doing good ; if
                            our every-day life tends to promote the good of others, and in all things we have an eye
                            single to the honor and glory of God. We will, at the end of the race, obtain the pearl of
                            great price — the salvation of the soul — which will shine more and more bright through all
                            eternity. Watervliet, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self culture" TEIform="index"/>SELF CULTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Elkins, Odilon" TEIform="persName"/>ODILON ELKINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> We honor the day which, in all the ages of the Christian era, has been annually celebrated
                            and honored, in all Christian lands, with a universal sentiment of tender regard paid to no
                            other event on record. It is in our fraternity, as abroad, looked upon as the time to mend
                            old differences, to cement anew the fractures which our intercourse as brothers and sisters,
                            or as friends, may have sustained during the year ; and to renew those feelings of love,
                            good-will and kind wishes, without which life is indeed a dreary experience. If this is an
                            appropriate time to make amends for violated feelings, to seek reconciliation with our
                            injured or injuring companion, it would seem, also, a fit time to consider upon those habits
                            of conduct which serve to make life pleasant or unpleasant ; — to reflect upon those words
                            which sting, and looks which wound the sensibilities of those about us ; and above all, to
                            dwell upon the inner life — the thoughts — the feelings, whence issue these powerful agents
                            of evil. Some one has said: "For one occasion where we are liable to offend by deed, there
                            are a hundred where we are liable to do so by our words; and for one time when we may profit
                            another by any deed, 'there are a hundred when we may do this by our words." While we are
                            seeking self-improvement in these important matters, minor points should not be overlooked;
                            — while we studiously avoid saying that which will wound, and try to say those things which
                            will cheer and encourage, we should seek to avoid incorrectness, and improprieties of
                            speech. Whatever is worth doing at all, is worth doing well, is a maxim of which we are
                            making practical application in reference to singing and reading, and it should also be
                            applied to our conversation. We should talk by rule, as well as read or sing by rule. Two
                            extremes are frequently to be found in our conversation : one is an extreme carelessness in
                            the choice of our words, and the pronunciation of them ; the other is the introduction of
                            farfetched, pompous words, when simpler words are more agreeable to good taste. Common words
                            for common things is an acknowledged rule. Also, if we would have our language agreeable to
                            cultured ears, we should exclude all slang, or cant words. Of course we would not swear ;
                            that would not do for us; but there are many expressions current with us, which are, to my
                            mind simply substitutes for profanity. Every one of these, however harmless it may seem, is
                            a blemish in our intercourse ;— is gross, and far beneath our high profession. In proof that
                            I do not alone hold this view, I could name many bright examples in our midst from whom I
                            have never heard a syllable of this description. The purity and holiness of our cause is so
                            great, that anything not chaste and refined is out of proportion in our home. In regard to
                            speaking by rule, some will say there is not time to attend to such trifles now — there is
                            so much work in hand — the next life may be a more convenient place to take up these
                            secondary matters. I have never learned that to exercise all the care needful to speak as
                            correctly as one knows, requires extra time, or infringes upon other duties. Indeed it seems
                            more evident, that in consequence of this self-discipline, we should bring to the discharge
                            of our duties a greater thoroughness and fullness of pur- <pb n="37" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                            MANIFESTO. 37 pose, with a feeling that all the needed improvements are moving along hand in
                            hand, and that each of these is to adorn our Zion. However this may be, we shall surely take
                            our habits along, and that indifference which we manifest in this life will still be a
                            controlling force with us. While we are ordinarily too thoughtless of how we speak, in
                            meeting perhaps we are too careful, and take too much thought lest we violate some custom or
                            rule of propriety. We find too much restraint in meeting, and too little elsewhere. Where we
                            ought to exercise great spiritual freedom, we grip the reins tightly, and where we need the
                            reins we relax. Whenever we meet for devotional or social exercises, we are conscious of a
                            power within which restrains us from speaking our plain feelings, and doing it with
                            plainness. It is a painful self-consciousness, producing fears that what we may say, while
                            favorably received by some, may not be by others. Possibly we may not be so precise as
                            others, or we may overstep the customary formalities, and say something uncommon ; in a
                            word, we may be original. Whoever can be original has an enviable gift — one which should
                            not be hidden in a napkin. We should put aside all thought of how others may be impressed by
                            our remarks. The honesty of our motives will manifest itself and be sure of a response.
                            Besides, there may not be outside of self any occasion for distrust. While we are imagining
                            that others may feel to treat our offerings with a scornful dissent, there may not exist
                            such an inclination. If there does, it is a shame ©nly to those who entertain it. They only
                            are the legitimate objects of contempt. While I think we should endeavor to speak properly
                            everywhere, I also know that the mortification that results from a failure to be as euphonic
                            as we might desire is of greater benefit to us than success in the highest degree. Nothing
                            so damages this self pride which looms up within so mountain-like. Still we dread it more
                            than a cold bath. This has been called Shaker pride, and although common to the whole human
                            family, among us it seems to have attained a peculiar development. But it has no place in
                            the character of a thorough Shaker. There it is superseded by an oblivion of self—-by a
                            devotion to what is true and right, blended with an unassuming simplicity, and with all
                            dignity of demeanor. I am sensible that there is nothing merry in all this; yet I know that
                            your toleration is only equaled by a desire that all gifts be made public. Enfield, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let him tell a dream" TEIform="index"/>"LET HIM TELL A DREAM"-Jer.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">Fifty-nine years ago, I had a dream. Journeying from east to west, like the cars of
                            progress, I found many hills to climb and descend. After each hill a swamp — here, I had to
                            hop from bog to bog, occasionally slipping between—a long and toilsome journey. Having
                            ascended and descended all the little hills, and passed all the swamps, I was on terra
                            firma, gradually ascending a mighty big hill. The way was rough, rocky and thorny—growing
                            steeper all the way. After a long, laborious climb, an apparently insurmountable precipice,
                            not much unlike the wall, on the Canada side, at the foot of Niagara Falls, Table Rock and
                            all, seemed to effectually block my further progress. Did I give it up ? By efforts
                            Herculean I climbed, getting both arms on the Table Rock, and resting from my labors a
                            moment, one more effort carried me clear from the penitentiary. On the border of a gently
                            ascending plane, a land of calm sunshine and gentle breezes, perpetual verdure and perpetual
                            bloom, what do I now care for the trying scenes of the past ? I bless my saints for those
                            heart-searching ordeals, enabling me to decide the question —am I a vertebrate—viz., only a
                            reptile ? For a brief period, after reaching the plane, the rugged path I had trodden was in
                            full view. Passing cozily on, the gently ascending, ever-increasing in beauty plane, the <pb n="38" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. rugged ordeals vanished from sight—from
                            recollection. I told the dream to Elder Calvin Wells. He said, " It is a gift to you—an
                            epitome of your life's journey." I'm not disposed now to question his interpretation. In
                            this, or in some of the worlds without end, amen, all souls must have penitentiary
                            graduation, either voluntary or by compulsion. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Genuine Christian's testimony" TEIform="index"/>GENUINE CHRISTIAN'S TESTIMONY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Amos" TEIform="persName"/>Amos Stewart</byline><p TEIform="p">A . Mount Lebanon, January 1, 1881. Beloved Brother Albert,—I. wish to add my testimony in
                            support of the present work of God on earth; I feel a great interest in the Gospel of Christ
                            and of Mother Ann. It will slay the " man of sin," and give life to the souls of all who
                            obey it. To my gospel companions I would say, be faithful and true to your trust; God has
                            called you to a great and glorious work ; and every soul that has been called into the
                            gospel work will be accountable for what use they make of their day and privilege. The work
                            of God will never fail. It is built on a sure and unfailing foundation. Christ has made a
                            second manifestation through the female order, and the work is complete; the male and female
                            communicants of the Christian faith can now stand equals. These are the latter days spoken
                            of in Scripture, when God would set up his everlasting kingdom never more to have an end.
                            Beloved gospel companions, we are now enjoying a very great blessing which God has bestowed
                            upon us, and all who have been faithful to live out the true principles of the gospel of
                            Christ know it to be the power of God unto salvation from sin. This salvation is gained by
                            an honest confession and repentance of every thing that does not center to Christ's kingdom.
                            In the first opening of our gospel testimony in this land, souls that went to see Mother Ann
                            and the first elders, were instructed plainly and kindly in a manner they could understand.
                            They were told, the first step that any soul could take toward the kingdom of heaven was to
                            honestly confess their sins one by one as they were committed as nearly as possible; and the
                            witnesses boldly testified their calling. Their testimony was sharp, and powerful as a
                            two-edged sword against every kind of sin. I wish the same testimony could go forth to the
                            world now, to awaken consciences to know what sin is, and prepare souls for the gospel. I
                            fully believe that many who come in among us in this day never enter into the
                            heart-searching work which the gospel requires. Therefore they cannot abide. They seem
                            willing to own that some things they have done were wrong—things that they did not feel much
                            ashamed of, and pass over in silence sins of greater magnitude, and never delve to the
                            bottom of their secret lives to expose their filthy works of darkness which they feel so
                            ashamed to have known. Let all remember there is nothing done in the dark but what must come
                            to the light, before any soul can enter the kingdom of heaven. Souls may try to deceive for
                            a while, but they will sooner or later fall out by the way. They cannot endure the gospel
                            fire. No half-way work will ever do. God requires a full sacrifice of all that is sinful and
                            unclean. It is the pure in heart alone that can commune with God. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Of the Shaker grange" TEIform="index"/>OF THE SHAKER GRANGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Denhurst, William H. H." TEIform="persName"/>Wm, H. H. Denhurst</byline><p TEIform="p"> Amesbury, Mass., Dec. 17, 1880. Friend Polly Reed, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. : It is only a few
                            days since the Shaker Manifesto came into my possession. It is the first Shaker publication
                            apart from a little pamphlet of belief I have ever seen or read. The glorious principle of
                            unselfishness and holiness is the pervading Spirit. By its perusal my interest is at once
                            enlisted. What has hitherto been the unsightly phantom of blind prejudice is awakened by a
                            better comprehension into warm regard and sympathy, and a desire to become identified with
                            such commendable activities. An item in the Manifesto states that any one can become a
                            Granger after the Shaker style by remitting ten cents to Polly Reed. I avail myself of the
                            privilege, trusting that the membership from such small beginnings <pb n="39" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 39 will prove fraternal and worthy of additional membership by one and the
                            same person. With my best wishes for your health and happiness ; and the prosperity of the
                            muchmisunderstood " Institution " that you are identified with, I am yours inquiringly,
                        .</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My skein of yarn" TEIform="index"/>MY SKEIN OF YARN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lent, Emma A." TEIform="persName"/>EMMA A. LENT</byline><p TEIform="p">[Written for The Manifesto.] . BY Long years ago the skein was wound, And careless hands had
                            tucked away The ball, so hard, and smooth, and round, On which my thoughts have chanced to
                            stray And I have taken out to-day. The threads are finer now, than when The knots and
                            tangles vexed me so, I wonder if life's errors then, Recorded in the long ago Will ever any
                            fainter grow. This ball brings back an anxious night, When silently I watched alone, Beside
                            the bed, and shaded light, Till startled by the sleeper's moan, I solaced her with touch or
                            tone. And yet my thoughts were far from sad. As busily I wound this skein, A glad, sweet
                            hope, all fear forbade, I knew she would be well again, Because His prayers would conquer
                            pain. His potent prayer, for me and mine Were such support, I could not faint, I did not
                            lean on love divine, He had become my patron saint, Through Him, the Lord would hear my
                            plaint. Fierce furnace flames, my heart have tried, And sorely smitten from the heat, My
                            soul in sack-cloth feign would hide, 'Till I all broken at His feet Can cry, dear Lord, "
                            Thy will is sweet." While in the fire, I could not make An out cry, for I knew God's hand
                            The bruised reed would never break, The smoking flax His love hath fanned, Until I see my
                            fatherland. The sick one lived, the strong one fell, In one short week the crown was won ;
                            And now I know that it is well, Though all are taken one by one, Dear Father let " Thy will
                            be done." Bexford Flats, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True missionary spirit" TEIform="index"/>THE TRUE MISSIONARY SPIRIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">. We are afraid, not only sometimes, but often, lest the true missionary spirit will be
                                lost sight of, and Christians be left to the enjoyment of themselves and their financial
                                accumulations, while those whom they seem to know are not Christians, will be left
                                without the knowledge of what the professors know to be " the one true and only way." We
                                are sorry, not only for our Church, but for all other Churches in the land which profess
                                Christianity, where members thereof feel a contentedness in enjoying every good which
                                the gospel, according to their interpretation thereof will give them, unless they feel
                                such an ardent desire — such a loving, human, Christian feeling — that they are willing,
                                yea anxious to share everything they have, even to the last crust, that others may know
                                and feel to enjoy the blessings of the gospel of Christ as they are enjoying the same.
                                The principality of selfishness is of the devil in and to the gospel of Christ. We
                                therefore proclaim and maintain that the selfishness of self is destructive to the best
                                interests of what any individual, professing to be in possession of the gospel of
                                Christianity, claims to be the duty of a Christian missionary. The development of true
                                Christianity will make a new creature of any man or woman. Not only does this
                                development cause an individual to leave self and selfishness so far as to love their
                                neighbor equal to self, but insists that the neighbor shall share at self's expense
                                better than self. " Who is <pb n="40" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 40 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. our neighbor?"
                                Let it be remembered that Jesus thus enforced the lesson: That an individual went out of
                                his way to find a subject upon which to exercise something superior to Judaical
                                teachings. Too many self-constituted Christians are acting the part of the Levite, and
                                are saving their precious selves, and their more precious funds for the same precious
                                care of self. Too few of those professing Christianity are acting the part of the good
                                Samaritan, by giving both funds and self for the good of others. " Let your lights so
                                shine" — not for the simple enjoyment of all self can enjoy, but — for the benefit of
                                those you and we believe to be in error and danger. Let us recall the fact, that Jesus,
                                in enforcing this missionary spirit took pains to select as an exampler of merciful
                                missions, one who was not in accord with those of his own immediate race. It is to be
                                hoped, that in this late day of enlightened Christianity, those who are really (or who
                                think they are) in possession of the most discreet elements of the true Christian faith,
                                will leave it for those outside of their immediate body to transcend them in one of the
                                most advanced Christian duties — the missionary duty, — and excel them in the denial of
                                themselves, to administer gospel comforts to those whom they should supply, and thus get
                                the terrible rebuke of ancient days — " even as ye did it not unto the least of
                                these,"ye are not my disciples! We are dying of selfishness, unless we are very alive to
                                the call of Christ, to ''go preach the gospel." If we have the gospel in excess of our
                                fellows, let us so love them that we will preach the gospel with our means and by our
                                example. Let us begin by the true criterion of so loving our fellows at home — our
                                nearest neighbors — that we are willing and anxious to fare and share, even more than we
                                have, thab they may feel the goodness of the gospel equal to ourselves. The gospel
                                missionary must be one of the most unselfish of individuals; and ere such can be an
                                exact imitator of the unselfish Christ, there is nothing they possess that will be too
                                precious to part with to preach the gospel.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leave us not in temptation" TEIform="index"/>LEAVE US NOT IN TEMPTATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> EDITORIAL NOTES. ""." We strongly object to the "old line" of policy in teaching "The
                                Lord's Prayer." The implication of the expression "Lead us not into temptation"— is a
                                fear lest the good spirit would lead us thither unless petitioned to the contrary. The
                                true spirit of the prayer would and does indicate a way out of human depravity,
                                inclination and difficulty. The same, and fully as necessary, desirable condition of the
                                child, as the man or woman, is that neither should be left in a state of temptation. We
                                are not sufficiently learned to assert the fact of genuine interpretation of the
                                original, but we deliver the common sense interpretation, taught us by our Shaker
                                preceptors, to pray "Leave us not iist temptation."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West point appointee" TEIform="index"/>THE WEST POINT APPOINTEE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We wonder at the inordinate compliments that are being bestowed upon General Howard, who
                                lately displaced General Schofield at the military <pb n="41" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 41 academy at West Point, N. Y.! We have long been aware of the eulogiums
                                conferred upon 0. 0. Howard as a very Christian gentleman. Our religious contemporaries
                                have been very liberal in their compliments of his Christian character. We ask all such,
                                and the General himself, to consider for a few moments how Christian he or any man can
                                be, who believes in war. and the instruction of war to the as yet uninitiated? We ask
                                them to recall the testimony of General Schofield on the Whittaker trial, wherein he
                                asserted that " The Bible may teach such foolishness as turning the other cheek when one
                                is assaulted, but we teach no such foolishness here ! " We simply would assert, in
                                repetition of the first best Christian, " My servants will not fight! " and we would
                                simply add that Ave opine General Howard is either no Christian, or that the U. S.
                                Government has made a mistake in the appointment, or perhaps better, Howard has gone
                                there in the interest of the Lord to convert that devilish institution into a peaceable
                                array for the Lord—than which the U. 8. Government could expend its funds for no better
                                'purpose.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy omen" TEIform="index"/>THE HAPPY OMEN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">" The present age perceives that there are bonds of union far more important than
                                doctrinal divisions." The above we clip from the editorial note of The Christian Union
                                which commented upon that nature's nobleman, deceased, E. H. Chapin. We hope all our
                                dear friends will read, and ponder upon the noble, tmsectarian sentiments of the above
                                paragraph. Thirty years ago, Dr. Chapin suffered the ignominy of the direst persecutions
                                of pen, press and pulpit. At his funeral, as if to make amends for the iniquities of
                                their early educators, there gathered, to pay the sincerest of respects, clergymen of
                                all the denominations which a quarter of a century ago so detested him and his love for
                                humanity, which so loved God as to believe God hated no one. " The world does move;" and
                                with it its theological, biased prejudices grow less. Thirty years from now, who knows
                                how much more men will love each other and how fewer creeds there will be, and what
                                there are, how much nearer like Christ, who was positively non-sectarian !</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To our children" TEIform="index"/>TO OUR CHILDREN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We purpose in the future, a few simple talks with the children upon subjects that will
                                interest and instruct them. While we have tried that the " Grotto " should not be
                                neglected, we mean to do better still, and digest the wisdom of the wise, and bring it
                                to the comprehension of our juveniles. Let our boy and girl readers trust us, and we
                                will tell them some things in the future they will be glad to hear.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This number of the manifesto" TEIform="index"/>THIS NUMBER OF THE MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We ask kindly criticism of this number of The Manifesto, believing we present to our
                                readers a valuable issue. The leading article would grace any Magazine in our land, and
                                is full of facts, which should lead us who live to-day to be, very grateful for the
                                improved state of civil and religious conditions which have arisen from the separation
                                of Church and State, un- <pb n="42" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. holy coalitions;
                                and should put us more on our guard, to ever make the breach wider and wider. None will
                                read Bro. Fraser's letter to John Ruskin, without yielding the fact that it is full of
                                consistency, and one of the grand hopes of the millennium on earth. We hope and believe
                                both of the above articles will be ex.. tensively copied. We readily yield to the reason
                                of Bro. Bostwick, though there may be some who think singing psalms eternally is more
                                reasonable worship than doing good works. Bro. B. is correct. Whoever has read H. W.
                                Beecher, on " The Cynic" will find that lecture equaled, if not excelled by our talented
                                sister on "Grumblers." We hope for more of such truthful, spicy pictures from her pen;
                                and who knows of the breaking down of the " Iron Will" of Dunstan Kirke, in Steele
                                McKaye's drama, will agree that Bro. El kins has given us a similar lesson — to the
                                breaking down or up of some of our idiosyncracies. Thanks to Elder Buckingham for his
                                poem, at nearly eighty years of age. The sweet verses of Emma A. Lent, originally
                                published by us, sing of sweet trust and hopeful content, than whom none need such
                                consolations more than she, who, though blind, is one of the most ingenious and
                                industrious of goody goodies. " Mending a Back" is good, and is intended as a death blow
                                to " quacks." Others must excuse creditable comments, though worthy. Barring the simple
                                editorials, we know we present a good number—and if we failed in all else, the beautiful
                                music form the North Family, Mt. Lebanon N. Y., will make ample amends.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>MORE KIND WORDS</head><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Bedford, Mass., Dec. 31,1880" TEIform="index"/>New Bedford, Mass., Dec. 31,1880</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peckham, Caleb C." TEIform="persName"/>Caleb C. Peckham</byline><p TEIform="p"> . Mr. Gt. B. Avery : Dear Sir— My subscription ends with this twelve-month number,
                                    and I wish to renew it for the coming year. Inclosed you will find twenty three-cent
                                    stamps to pay for the same. I will say that no religious publication I have seen
                                    that I lik e better than I do the Shaker Manifesto, and I wish I could do more to
                                    spread the truths which it contains. A Shaker friend during the year has sent me a
                                    few extra copies for distribution, which I wish to return my sincere thanks for the
                                    same. Wishing you great success in the publication of the Shaker Manifesto, I remain
                                    truly your friend in the cause in which you are en.</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="December 20, 1880" TEIform="index"/>December 20, 1880</head><p TEIform="p">December 20, 1880. * * * Continue sending The Manifesto. The November number
                                    contained more true religion than I have heard elsewhere in a year.</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brooklyn, N. Y., January 3,1881" TEIform="index"/>Brooklyn, N. Y., January 3,1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Seery, Hannah B." TEIform="persName"/>Hannah B. Seery</byline><p TEIform="p"> Brooklyn, N. Y., January 3,1881. To The Manifesto : The first Manifesto I ever read
                                    was kindly sent to me from Mt. Lebanon. It interested me so much that I subscribed
                                    for it. Every number seems to say something special to me; let it continue its
                                    visits. Find subscription inclosed. Yours truly, .</p></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Erratum" TEIform="index"/>ERRATUM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Manifesto—Your types know nothing. They make me say one thing when I wrote
                                    another ! In my letter to Geo. Shaw, in January number, they say "by all means,
                                    friend Shaw, join the Shakers." I said join the Quakers — quite a difference.
                                Yours,</p></div4></div3></div2><pb n="43" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden ladder" TEIform="index"/>THE GOLDEN LADDER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Butler, M. R." TEIform="persName"/>M. R. BUTLER</byline><p TEIform="p"> The children watched the sun go down, And in its gleaming changes, The west seemed first
                                a sea of fire, Then golden mountain ranges. And Fannie asked, " what are the clouds ?
                                They look like hills of glory," " The steps of Heaven " Prank replied, " It is a sweet
                                old story. " A guardian angel, every day, To each of us is given ; And every night they
                                climb to Heaven, Up o'er that Golden Ladder. " And then the gates of pearl swing back
                                Upon their gleaming hinges, And all the sky seems melted gold, With red and purple
                                fringes. '' But when the doors are closed again, The guardian angels gather In solemn
                                silence, with their books, Around our Heavenly Father. " And when I close my eyes and
                                think How, in that sinless dwelling, Will sound the story of the life My angel must be
                                telling. " Some days, I know, my angel takes The record of my sinning ; But then I
                                always try to make The next a new beginning. " So, when at night our Father calls, My
                                angel may be bladder, And he the first to climb to Heaven, Up o'er the Golden
                            Ladder."</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep away from temptation" TEIform="index"/>KEEP AWAY FROM TEMPTATION</head><p TEIform="p">The only safe course for a young man, who would retain his virtue and his correct
                                principles, is to keep away from temptation. How many have fallen who merely ventured to
                                look at vice in her gaudy colors! Her temptation was too strong for them to resist. They
                                partook of the fatal glass — snatched the gilded treasure, or gave themselves up to
                                uncleanness. None are secure who run in the way of sin — who see how near they can
                                venture on the threshold of vice without entangling their feet in the net of the
                                adversary. Have you ever heard the story of the gen. tleman who advertised for a
                                coachman? If not, we will repeat it. Three applicants were admitted to the room. He
                                pointed out to them a precipice, remarking : " How near the edge of this can you drive
                                me without any danger of an upset? " The first applicant replied -. " Within a hair's
                                breadth." " How near can you drive me?" asked the gentleman of the second applicant. "
                                Within a hair's breadth," he replied. As the third was about leaving the room, supposing
                                he had no chance of competing with the other two, the gentleman stopped him. " Let us
                                hear what you have to say," said he. "Why, sir, I cannot compete with either of these ;
                                if I were to drive you, I would keep as far off as I possibly could." " You are the man
                                for me," said the gentleman, and he engaged him immediately. In regard to vice, he is
                                only safe who keeps away from temptation. Those who venture near are often upset and
                                destroyed. We can all point to individuals who are lost to virtue, who, when they took
                                the first wrong step, resolved never to take another. It was the voice of a pretended
                                friend, it may be, that urged them on, only for once, but it proved their destruction.
                                Ye who are now safe, whose hearts are not contaminated, listen to the voice of wisdom
                                and go not near the strong allurements to vice. Keep away from the gaming table, the
                                grog shop and the midnight party. Keep away as far as possible, and a life of integrity
                                and virtue will assuredly be yours.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Here are some lines for the little girls to read..." TEIform="index"/>Here are some lines for the little girls to read...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Here are some lines for the little girls to read. If they would really be pretty, and
                                grow up as handsome women, let them remember that it is " Not costly dress nor queenly
                                air, Not jeweled hand, complexion fair ; Not pearly teeth nor sparkling eyes, Not voice
                                that nightingale outvies. Not one, nor all of these combined Can make one woman true,
                                refined. 'Tis not the casket that we prize, But that which in the casket lies. These
                                outward charms that please the sight Are naught unless the heart be right. She to
                                fulfill her destined end Must with her beauty goodness blend."</p></div3><pb n="44" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hold your head up like a man" TEIform="index"/>HOLD UP YOUR HEAD LIKE A MAN</head><p TEIform="p">If the stormy winds should rustle While you tread the world's highway Still against them
                                bravely tussle, Hope and labor day by day. Falter not, no matter whether There is
                                sunshine, storm or calm, And in every kind of weather, Hold your head up like a man. If
                                a brother should deceive you, And should act a traitor's part, Never let. his treason
                                grieve you Jog along with lightsome heart ! Fortune seldom follows fawning, Boldness is
                                the only plan, Hoping for a better dawning, Hold your head up like a man. Earth, though
                                e'er so rich and mellow, Fields not for the worthless drone, But the bold and honest
                                fellow, He can shift and stand alone ; Spurn the knave of every nation, Always do the
                                best you can, And no matter what your station, Hold your head up like a man.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not only are the children inclined to use dreadful expressions.." TEIform="index"/>Not only are the children inclined to use dreadful expressions..
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Not only are the children inclined to use dreadful expressions, and words which signify
                                great exaggerations; but some of the children of larger growth can learn some good
                                lessons by reading</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How our Seth talks" TEIform="index"/>HOW OUR SETH TALKS</head><p TEIform="p">A boy I know who, if telling The truth, daily dies some new death: No martyr — religion
                                compelling — Has suffered so much as our Seth ! He " roasts " all the summer, and "
                                freezes " As soon as autumnal winds blow ; He has his " death-cold," if he sneezes ; Is
                                "buried " in one foot of snow. He's " starving " before he has dinner, He's '' stuffed "
                                like a turkey when through; He's " tickled to death " when he's winner, And "ready to
                                die" when 'tis you. He's "just tired to death " when he only Has run a short race with
                                his mates ; If kept in by the rain, he grows lonely,— He " can't live till night,"— so
                                he states. He's " dying to know " what comes after, In tales that he reads with delight;
                                Or " thought he would die" of much laughter, Or " nearly expired " with affright. Thus
                                over and over we hear it,— This dismal death-song that he sings; Yet body and soul is
                                still joined to spirit, And Seth has developed no wings!</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Analytical Concordance" TEIform="index"/>Analytical Concordance
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Young" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In justice to those honorable publishers, I. K. Funk &amp; Co., 10 &amp; 13
                                Barclay street, NewYork, we would state that they now have for sale Dr. Young's
                                "Analytical Concordance," printed under the Doctor's own supervision by government
                                presses in Edinburgh. That there is extant a " miserably executed reprint," we are
                                officially informed* and we would warn all who wish to be in possession of this most
                                valuable work of its kind, to shun the spurious edition and buy from the above firm. We
                                have not yet seen the famous work, but that it is immeasurably superior to Cruden's or
                                any other extant, we have been thoroughly assured.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New book of European travel" TEIform="index"/>A New Book of European Travel</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bennett, D. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Our indefatigable friend, D. M. Bennett is out with a new book containing a compilation
                                of his letters from Europe. As a letter writer he has but few equals in condensing much
                                in little space—and yet the letters are interestingly lengthy. His style is not of the
                                Chesterfield school ; neither do his thoughts savor at all of Jonathan Edwards'
                                philosophy, while telling us about the sacred places of the old world. Bennett has made
                                for himself a unique niche in modern history; and that he is doing- a great deal of good
                                in his peculiar field as an iconoclast, we have no doubts. Those wishing to know how an
                                honest man can differ from " orthodox" visions, while viewing the same historical
                                subjects, let them send for the book, inclosing $1.25 to D. M. Bennett, 141 Eighth
                                street, New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indications of character as manifested in the general shape of the head and the form of the face" TEIform="index"/>The Indications of Character As manifested in the general shape of the head and the
                                form of the face. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Drayton, H. S." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Illustrated. By H. S. Drayton, author "Light in Dark Places, "Brain and Mind," etc. 12mo.
                                Price in paper, 15 cents. Fowler &amp; Wells, Publishers, 753 Broadway, New York.
                                This compact and neatly printed pamphlet treats in a clear and popular style of an old
                                subject, but discusses it in a manner quite different from what we are accustomed to. As
                                an introduction to the study of the<pb n="45" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 45
                                physiology of the mind, it is a valuable treatise, and to those who have not the time
                                nor opportunity to pursue the subject in detail, it will be found both interesting and
                                useful. To teachers and all who have much to do with others, old or young, it will be
                                especially serviceable.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>ADIEU</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shepard, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Shepard</head><p TEIform="p">Deceased: At Shaker Village, N. H., Dec. 12, 1880, , aged 67 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wright, Eleanor" TEIform="index"/>Eleanor Wright</head><p TEIform="p">At Shaker Village, N. H., , aged 73 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patten, Harriet" TEIform="index"/>Harriet Patten</head><p TEIform="p">At West Pittsfield, Mass., January 6, 18S1, , aged 79 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hammon, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Hammond</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p">Ayer, Mass., Dec. 21, 1880. Brother G. A. Lomas— Please report in Manifesto the
                                    departure of our venerable and esteemed brother, Elder , to the next phase of human
                                    experience, at Harvard, Mass., Dec. 21, 1880, aged 89 years. Yours, truly,</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stickney, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Stickney</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. Briggs</byline><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H., Dec. 21, 1880. Dear Editor — Deceased: At North Family this
                                    morning, , aged 84 years. Yours, .</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Johnson, Ithamar" TEIform="index"/>Ithamar Johnson</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Reynolds</byline><p TEIform="p"> Union Village, Ohio, Dec. 23, 1880. Deceased, to-day at Centre Family, this village,
                                    Brother , in the eighty-second year of his age. He was an active, energetic man in
                                    business and for many years one of the leadingtrustees of this Society, having been
                                    first appointed to that office with Brother D. Boyd in 1830. . </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brannan, Emily" TEIform="index"/>Emily Brannan</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H., January 1st, , aged 76. She was the daughter of Lord Dun Raven of
                                    Ireland. She was possessed of great conscientiousness and strong-will power; was a
                                    noble specimen of Christianity, highly honoring her faith and Christian profession
                                    from early life. .</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Receipts" TEIform="index"/>Receipts</head><p TEIform="p">F. W. Evans...................... $54 00 John Sauerborn................... 19 20 Charles
                                Clapp..................... 66 00 John B. Vance.................... 30 00 E.
                                Myrick....................... 40 00 Ezra Sherman.................. 30 00 Augustus Blase
                                (for 1880)........... 18 00 J. R. Lawson...................... 20 00 Jas. S.
                                Kaime..................... 88 30 Henry Cummings.................. 15 75 John
                                Whiteley.................... 42 30 Hewitt Chandler, ) OK r.rt N. Trull,
                                f'•¦••;........... d5 UU D. C. Brainard.................. 25 00 A. W.
                                Williams................... 10 00 Omar Pease....................... 18 00 Amos
                                Babbitt..................... 20 50 Philip Smith (for 1880)............. 20 00</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ancient witness" TEIform="index"/>AN ANCIENT WITNESS</head><p TEIform="p">We, the undersigned, having for sometime past felt a concern, lest there should come loss
                                upon the joint interest, and dishonor upon the gospel, by purchasing seeds of the world,
                                and mixing them with ours for sale . and having duly considered the matter, we are
                                confident that it is best to leave off the practice, and we do hereby covenant and agree
                                that we will not, hereafter, put up, or sell, any seeds to the world which are not
                                raised among believers (excepting melon seeds). New Lebanon, April 13, 1819. Deacons.
                                Richard Spier. Stephen Munson. Israel Hammond. Jonathan Wood. Daniel Goodrich, John
                                Wright, Hancock, N. H. Hancock, N. H. Gardeners. Richard Treat. Samuel Johnson. Morrel
                                Baker, Thomas McKew, Watervliet, N. Y. Watervliet, N. Y Peter Dodge, Trustees. Abijah
                                Wood.</p></div3></div2><pb n="46" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Triumph of truth" TEIform="index"/>TRIUMPH OF TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon,N. Y. Spiritoso Giusto. 1. The ages have voiced thro' the myriad throng Of souls
                            who have battled 'gainst 2. The prophets were stoned, and the martyrs have bled, The dungeon
                            and fire by its 3. In scarlet and purple, the church in its pride, The rights of the people
                            has 4. Thro' civil upheaval, thro' discord and war, Destruction has threatened time honored
                            wrong, That unto the truth praise and glory belong, As it heroes were fed, Their bodies were
                            torn but their souls are not dead, And the ever denied, But the vail of false doctrine no
                            longer can hide The truth from near and far, But lo! in its triumph as life's guiding star,
                            The truth Ritard. marches triumphantly on, on! truth marches gloriously on, on! that moves
                            gloriously on, on! moves so gloriously on, on! As it marches triumphantly on! And the truth
                            marches gloriously on! The truth that moves gloriously on! The truth moves so gloriously
                        on!</p></div2><pb n="47" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the public:" TEIform="index"/>To the Public :</head><p TEIform="p">Always interested in whatever is calculated to improve the conditions of human society,
                                or the lands, vegetables and fruits they cultivate, and having heard much of the value
                                of a composition for preventing the ravages of the borer and the yellows in peach trees,
                                manufactured by Richard Van Deusen, of Enfield, Ct., post office address " Shaker
                                Station, Hartford Co., Ct.," on the 28th day of September, 1880, we visited his orchards
                                of pear and peach trees, to see, for ourselves, the result of the same upon them. The
                                peach trees numbered some hundreds of five years' growth ; there was not one of them
                                affected with the peach borer nor the yellows; not a single worm, nor the sign of one
                                having ever been upon the trees was to be found ; the trees were in full and very
                                vigorous leaf, wood well ripened, growth large, and all of a wonderfully uniform size
                                and thrift ; the land was clear of grass and mostly so of weeds. Other adjacent trees of
                                same orchard, on a hillside, were on sward land, some were younger, but all were healthy
                                and very vigorous, and no signs of yellows or the worm among them. Some extensive
                                orchards in the same vicinity, on same roll of land and set at same time, and not a
                                quarter of a mile distant, are now almost literally extinct, having been bored to powder
                                by the worm, and decimated by the yellows. The trees of a pear orchard in same vicinity,
                                consisting of some hundreds, were also all healthy, no blight, although some others near
                                by, not treated with the composition, were ruined. All these peach and pear trees had
                                been washed, twice a year, with the aforesaid composition, thus manifesting, to every
                                candid witness, the good effects of the same, and its safety from any injurious issue
                                upon the trees, while it effectually prevents the operations of the destructive borer,
                                and, probably, of the pear blight, though of this we should not yet feel so confident,
                                but still hope it may prove an effectual preventive . The said composition is also a
                                preventive from the gnawing of young trees by vermin, or by sheep, calves, etc., when
                                exposed to their depredations, thus avoiding the necessity of curbing such trees except
                                to prevent their branches being broken, etc. Yours truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Giles B. Avery</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers, Albany Co., January 26, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, Albany
                                Co., N. Y. Jan. 26th, 1880.</dateline></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farm notes" TEIform="index"/>FARM NOTES.</head><div4 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ticks and lice" TEIform="index"/>Ticks and lice</head><p TEIform="p">— Add sulphur to the salt fed to the sheep, and two ounces of saltpetre, pulverized,
                                    to every pound of salt fed to horned cattle troubled with vermin.</p></div4><div4 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crib-biting" TEIform="index"/>Crib-biting</head><p TEIform="p"> is often a habit, but may be caused by a disease. Indigestion occasions a constant
                                    irritation and uneasiness which may impel the horse to take hold with the teeth and
                                    stretch the neck as a means of relief. From this grows the habit of cribbiting and
                                    wind-sucking, which ceases when the cause is removed. As a remedy, feed him upon cut
                                    feed, with crushed or ground grain, and an ounce of salt in each feed.</p></div4><div4 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Make cows pay" TEIform="index"/>Make Cows Pay</head><p TEIform="p">.— We keep cows for their milk, mainly ; and while provender is so valuable, we
                                    should make the most of it. Let every farmer who is able buy a feed cutter, and soak
                                    the cut feed in hot water, unless he can do better, and steam it. Throw a little
                                    extra nourishment, like brewer's grain or buckwheat bran, upon the warmed cut feed,
                                    and thus we will find we will make cows and other stock pay.</p></div4><div4 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An old teamster of fifty years' experience..." TEIform="index"/>An old teamster of fifty years' experience...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">An old teamster of fifty years' experience says he has never had a case of the galls
                                    upon his animals where the following preventive was adopted, which was simply to rub
                                    the collars inside every few days with a little neatsf oot oil, and the moment any
                                    dirt was found sticking like wax to wash it off with warm soapsuds, and then oil. A
                                    yoke from oxen, or collar from a horse should not be removed when brought into the
                                    stable from work until the sweat is entirely dry, and all chafed spots should be
                                    oiled.</p></div4></div3></div2><pb n="48" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A waterproof whitewash..." TEIform="index"/>A waterproof whitewash...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A waterproof whitewash may be made as follows: " Take half a bushel of lime, slack it
                                with boiling water, and cover to keep in the steam-, strain and add seven pounds of salt
                                dissolved in hot water; three pounds of ground rice, boiled to a paste, and added hot;
                                half pound Spanish whiting, and one pound clean glue, previously dissolved to a thin
                                paste; add five gallons hot water, and stir the whole; cover it, and keep it a few days.
                                It must be used hot. One pint covers a square yard."</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oyster pie" TEIform="index"/>Oyster Pie</head><p TEIform="p">The Religious Telescope asks us: "Will you have some oysters ? " and treats us to the
                                following : .—Line a dish with puff-paste or a rich biscuit-paste, and dredge well with
                                flour; drain one quart of oysters, season with pepper, salt, and butter, and pour into
                                the dish ; add some of the liquor ; dredge with flower, and cover with a top crust,
                                leaving a small opening in the center.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fried oysters" TEIform="index"/>Fried Oysters</head><p TEIform="p">. — Select the largest, dip them in beat egg, and then in bread or cracker crumbs ; fry
                                in equal parts of butter and lard until they are brown. They are very good dipped in
                                corn-meal instead of crumbs.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pickled oysters" TEIform="index"/>Pickled Oysters</head><p TEIform="p">.—One quart of vinegar, one ounce of allspice, one-half ounce of cinnamon, one ounce of
                                cloves, one ounce of mace; scald all these together; when cold, put in the oysters; next
                                day scald together.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oyster soup" TEIform="index"/>Oyster Soup</head><p TEIform="p">.—Drain one quart of oysters and to the liquor add one quart of boiling water; let it
                                boil ; skim carefully; season with a little Cayenne pepper, and butter the size of an
                                egg; add the oysters; let it boil up once; season with salt; serve in a hot
                            soup-tureen</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oyster stew" TEIform="index"/>Oyster Stew</head><p TEIform="p">.—Put two quarts of oysters in a sauce-pan with the liquor, and when they begin to boil
                                skim them out and add a pint of cream or rich milk and seasoning; skim well; add to the
                                oysters butter to taste, and pour the hot liquor over them, and serve.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Recipe for curing meat" TEIform="index"/>Recipe for Curing Meat</head><p TEIform="p">.—In his last issue, Maj. Freas, the long-time editor of the Germantown Telegraph, says:
                                "As the season has arrived when curing meat is in order, we republish as of old our
                                famous recipe for curing beef, pork, mutton, hams, etc., as follows: To one gallon of
                                water take 1 1-2 lbs. of salt, 1-2 lb. of sugar, 1-2 oz. of saltpetre, 1-2 oz. of
                                potash. (Omit the potash unless you can get the pure article. Druggists usually keep
                                it.) In this ratio the pickle can be increased to any quantity desired. Let these be
                                boiled together until all the dirt from the sugar rises to the top and is skimmed off.
                                Then throw it into a tub to cool, and when cold, pour it over your beef or pork. The
                                meat must be well covered with pickle, and should not be put down for at least two days
                                after killing, during which time it should be slightly sprinkled with powdered
                                saltpeter, which removes all the surface-blood, etc., leaving the meat fresh and clean.
                                Some omit boiling the pickle, and find it to answer well, though the operation of
                                boiling purifies the pickle by throwing off the dirt always to be found in salt and
                                sugar. If this recipe is strictly followed it will require only a single trial to prove
                                its superiority over the common way, or most ways of putting down meat, and will not
                                soon be abondoned for any other. The meat is unsurpassed for sweetness, delicacy, and
                                freshness of color.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Amende honorable and notice" TEIform="index"/>AMENDE HONORABLE AND NOTICE</head><p TEIform="p"> Our excellent friend, Eld. John Whiteley, of Shirley Village, Mass., reminds us that he
                            renewed his offer to send a copy of " The Divine Afflatus " — an excellent little book — to
                            every one sending him sixty cents for a year's subscription to The Manifesto. In calling
                            attention to this beautiful offer, we beg pardon for neglecting the same in our January
                            issue. — Ed. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paul did not stop preaching..." TEIform="index"/>Paul did not stop preaching...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Paul did not stop preaching because all his converts did not hold out. Many of the converts,
                            even of Jesus, went back, " and went no more with him." If a man tumbles into the river, are
                            we to refuse to rescue him because he may fall in again.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>