<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2203" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">03</biblScope><date value="18920301" TEIform="date">March 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="03" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
 MARCH.
MANIFESTO,
Published by the United Societies.
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
THE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
49
-   52
55
Kentucky Revival, No. 15,
Farewell Sermon, H. L. Eads,
Closing the World's Fair,
Testimony,.......  57
Diary of Eldress Nancy Moore,       -       -     58
In Memory of Eldress Mary Vance,          -   59
Editorial,.......     60
Notes about Home,          .....   62
Discourses,Dr. Cyrus Teed,                    66
In Memory of Elder Charles Clapp,          -   68
Reports of Alfred Shakers         .
To the Memory of Marietta Brainard,     -   69
Letter,J. G. Toepper,        ....      70
"     ,D. Orcutt,           .....    "
Spectacles,.......       "
Music,Bright Day,.....   71
Deaths,      -       -......      72
Books & Papers,......     "
We are in receipt of a copy of The Exposition Graphic, a new quarterly issued by the Graphic Company of Chicago,
devoted to the World's Columbian Exposition. Portraits of the principal officers
of the commission and local directory,
scenes of the work of construction in
progress at Jackson Park, magnificent
views of all the great buildings of the Exposition; engravings showing the principal buildings of Chicago and the other
leading cities of the Union, fine full page
portraits of President Harrison and Secretary Blaine, engraved by Lautenschlager,
and an imposing triple-page birds-eye
view of the Exposition grounds and buildings from designs by the Bureau of Construction, are some of the more prominent
features of this truly ambitious work.
It is now on sale at all the principal
news stands of the country at 50 cents
a copy.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
TRADE  MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRICHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
$mvXxiu
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, 383.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo
As pretty as a Daisy. We have just received No. 2 of Vol. II The Daisy, an illustrated Monthly paper, published in Chicago.
Those interested in the cultivation of flowers, either in the home or garden, will find
every requirement met in the columns of
the Daisy. Send fifty cents to Horace R.
Hughes, No. 09!) W. Van Buren St., Chicago,
111. and obtain this very excellent little
paper.
THE NEW iDEA.
One of the trite sayings that is frequently
proven false is the saying, "There is nothing
new under the sun." Surely it is disproven
by a recent publication which holds the
quintessence of all our highest literature in
a single volume. It is a condensation, with
critics' review, of the fifty master-pieces of
the world's greatest minds; and is entitled
"The Best Fifty Books of the Greatest Authors; Condensed for Busy People." It is
not merely a collection of choice extracts,
and elegant quotations. It is a Condensation
not a book of quotations : not a book of extracts, not pedantic criticism; the reader is
given the whole story and scheme of the author, long pages of descriptive and dialogue
being boiled into a line, the whole work compressed. It contains full-page portraits of
each author, printed on slate paper, and a
concise biography of each. Its 771 large royal octavo pgs. cover the whole range of literature from Homer's Iliad 1200 years B. C.
to Lew Wallace's Ben Hur of 1880'A. D., and
conjures with such names as Shakespeare,
Dante, Milton, Cervantes, Pope, Byron, Hugo, Dumas, Dickens, Carlyle, Hawthorne,
Goethe, Thackeray, and scores of others. It
is from the Complete Art-Printing Works of
The Matthews-Northrup Co., of Buffalo, N. Y.,
and that insures the perfection of manufacture. We understand that it is selling wonderfully where introduced; most people are
willing to buy when they get a great deal for litle money, and this book is cheap at
$3.75. Its circulars are certainly very fine,
and from them we infer that BROOKS <&
CO., 35 Hanover st., of BOSTON, MASS., are
the general agents for this field. We advise
our local canvassers to look this up, for it
certainly would sell well.
Yol. XXII.
MARCH, 1892.
No. 3.--><pb n="49" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival. no. 15" TEIform="index"/> THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/> By Richard M'Nemar</byline><p TEIform="p"> of Union Vii.lagk, Ohio. Published in Albany, N. F., in 1808. No. 15. Explanations. These
                            high imaginations served for a season to amuse the people, but tlit ir eccentricity from the
                            leading light of the revival is easily perceived by a little attention to the "Observations
                            on Church Government." While the work of God continued in any degree of purity, it was not a
                            sacred name the subjects of it were in quest of, nor was it the communion and fellowship of
                            the millions who assumed the name of Christ, that they sought. It was the power of God unto
                            salvation, and that living spirit of Christ in the heart, by which they might grow into a
                            holy temple in the Lord. A scheme of human imagination, which proposed to organize all the
                            denominations into one great body of Christ, was very suitable wherewith to confront a
                            little testimony, which simply encouraged souls that were seeking salvation to confess and
                            forsake their sins and set out to follow Christ, in a life of new obedience. For the
                            distorted features of Shakerism, the erroneous sentiments and wicked practices of those
                            called Shakers, mankind in general are indebted to those who by way of eminence are called
                            Christians. In perusing an account of this distinguished profession in "Brown's Western
                            Calendar," written at Springfield, O., the following sentence particularly attracted my
                            attention. "They are not so vain as to think that all their thoughts, words and actions have
                            always been exactly right; and they will thank any, who in the spirit of meekness, will
                            point out to them wherein they may be wrong, that they may amend." This concession and
                            request from one of the first ministers in this new Christian society, in behalf of the
                            people in general, although I conceive it furnishes me with no authority to accuse them with
                            ought, yet in reason, it must prevent their taking offence, should they know that a number
                            of their words and actions are recorded in a spirit of meekness, which are conceived to be
                            essentially wrong. When the testimony was opened at <pb n="50" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> Turtle-Creek, what
                            was spoken by the brethren could not reasonably be condemned by those who heard it. Others
                            at a distance, tossing about with the wind of imagination, and conjecturing things that had
                            no .reality, imbibed a spirit of prejudice against this doctrine of the cross ; and
                            especially as it bore an unfavorable aspect toward the great body of Christ which they had
                            in contemplation. Therefore, the first words which T conceive were not exactly right, came
                            forward in a letter from Springfield, dated April, 1805, a few of which words were as
                            follows ; "It matters not to me who they are, who are the devil's tools whether men or
                            angels, good men or bad. In Hip strength of God I mean not to spare. I used lenity once to
                            the devil, because he came in a good man. But God respects no man's person. I would they
                            were even cut off who trouble you. I mean in the name and strength of God to lift his rod of
                            almighty truth against the viper." Admitting that these were the most wicked men on e?rh, I
                            am far from thinking that such menacing words, from one unprovoked, could be justified ; and
                            how much less when on the same sheet, this concession appears ; "I do not say that they are
                            not good men, or that the body of their sect are not such; perhaps they have more light than
                            any other sect; perhaps they have had more power." Where then could be the propriety of
                            crushing them, or cutting them off, even upon the generous Christian plan of a coalition of
                            sects ? In a foregoing letter it was complained that through faith in the testimony, the
                            ordinances of Baptism, and the Lord's Supper, were likely to be cast away. In the epistle
                            from which I have just been quoting, are the following words : ' 'These men have turned the
                            gospel into a law of commandments contained in ordinances." Now from these two Christian
                            ministers, who could learn the true account ? Their words could not be both exactly right,
                            for they stood in pointed contradiction. Considering that brother T. in the same letter
                            acknowledged that he was far behind, not only in the light and liberty of the revival, but
                            on every important subject, I conceive it was not exactly right i'or him to form such hasty
                            resolutions to combat the testimony, even before h&gt; had properly heard it; and with that
                            resolution, to come up to the camp-neeting at Turtle-Creek, raise a sudden and passionate
                            outcry against these peaceable men, assume the authority of leading the meeting, enter upon
                            a public investigation of their doctrines, and in the close of it, pronounce with a loud
                            voice, they are liars! According to the fable, "A liar is not to be believed even when he
                            speaks the truth." Although it was readily granted, that these men spoke the truth, yet
                            there remained this pretext for not believing them, that they were declared to be liars; and
                            upon this principle it was, that they were debarred by many from speaking at all in public.
                            A man may be under an error, or he may be mistaken, and yet merit some degree of respect
                            from his fellow-creatures; but a willful liar, a deliberate teller of lies, who can away
                            with. Therefore <pb n="51" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> under this opprobrious character, a bold Christian
                            could curse Issachar Bates, and while a wicked man followed John Meacham from place to
                            place, spitting in his face, and crying aloud to make a great fire and burn these false
                            prophets, some of the foremost who professed the worthy name Christian, were at his back,
                            laughing at and encouraging him. This and such like treatment, appeared so far from being
                            exactly right among a people who aimed at monopolizing the name of Christ, that I am
                            confident similar treatment from the wildest savages towards any men of civil deportment,
                            must have merited severe reflection. At a succeeding meeting at Salem, in May following, I
                            have no doubt but Br. Thompson may have justly reflected, that he was not exactly right in
                            debarring from the privilege of speaking, one whom he had long acknowledged his equal, and
                            his guide; excluding all who believed the testimony, from any further communion or
                            fellowship with the Christians, especially as it was in pointed contradiction to their
                            general Christian plan ; "Let none be excommunicated but for a breach of the divine law."
                            Setting his own prejudiced spirit to speak in the Scriptures, as if it was the spirit of
                            God. Thus asserting that the Holy Spirit had made him overseer of the flock, and that these
                            Shakers were false Christs, false prophets, wTolves in sheep's clothing, deceitful workers,
                            transforming themselves into the Apostles of Christ, creeping into houses and leading
                            captive silly women, dumb dogs, and every hateful name and character which the Scripture
                            could furnish. In consequence of which, they wrere railed upon by the Christians under these
                            names wherever they went, and henceforward these members of "the great body of Christ,"
                            conceived they had good authority from the word of God, to impeach them with everything that
                            was erroneous, wicked and base, and not only palm upon them every filthy character named in
                            the Scriptures, but treat them as they supposed such characters deserved. If it was not
                            exactly right to take the private interpretation of John Thompson on those occasions, and
                            upon the strength of that, refuse any personal acquaintance with these men, it will follow
                            that ail the rough treatment they received in consequence was exactly wrong. I further
                            conclude it was exactly wrong for my kind brother Stone, after inviting me by letter to
                            attend the general meeting at Concord the second Sabbath in August, to forbid me to speak on
                            the occasion or even to come to his house, and by a council of the Christian clergy, to
                            impose upon brothers Dunlavy, Benjamin Youngs and Malcham Worley, the injunction of total
                            silence through the whole of the meeting, and at the same time that many were soliciting us
                            with tears to preach, and we thus pointedly forbidden on pain of being prosecuted as
                            disturbers of the meeting, to propagate among the people that we were the dumb dogs spoken
                            of in Scripture ; with which title we were often taunted. On the last day of the meeting,
                            six of the Christian brethren, J. <pb n="52" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> Thompson, R. Marshal, B. W. Stone, D.
                            Purviance, J. Stockwell and A. Brannon, alternately delivered each his opinion of the
                            Shakers in an address, in which some of them were named out, pronounced liars, defamed by
                            many slanderous reports which they could have proved false, had they been allowed to speak.
                            If such treatment was right, the spirit of the revival, which allowed every man liberty of
                            conscience, must have been wrong. As I conceive it to be right for every man to hear and
                            believe whoever he pleases, the above conduct appears not only subversive of the liberty of
                            conscience, so warmly contended for a little while before by the same brethren, but of the
                            very spirit of a free government. In all those places the people were anxious to hear the
                            Shakers, and considered themselves as much related to those who were forbidden to speak, as
                            to them who forbade them ;* until by the din of false reports and misrepresentations of
                            their faith and practice, they were frightened into a spirit of prejudice. (to be
                            continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farewell sermon of the venerable head of the South Union Shakers. Spirit and intellect, no. 2" TEIform="index"/> "SPIRIT and INTELLECT," No. 2,</head><p TEIform="p"> Fare-well Sermon of the Venerable Head of the South Union Shakers. Iktellect is the spirit's
                            servant and profitable in its place, but when it usurps that of the spirit, God's work is
                            reversed and what is done cannot receive his blessing and will not prosper. It was not the
                            gift of the Ministry to set aside God's laws ; but they yielded to the intellect and
                            external pressure of others, and wrote to me some years since that "it was not intended to
                            set them entirely aside," as has been done, but said there were some corrections needed. It
                            is true there are some verbal inaccuracies, but the spirit and substance of every law is
                            spiritual and necessary to Zion's prosperity; for "where there is no vision, the people
                            perish." It is now plain to be seen that every movement in all Zion, differing from them,
                            has been one step more toward the world, until all Zion now stands naked before them, as did
                            typical Israel when marching around the golden calf. You may consider this si voice from the
                            tomb, while I feel compelled to ask all the spiritual minded in Zion: Is it not time to
                            remove the pressure so that the gift of the Ministry may be carried out by our return to God
                            in obeying the spirit and substance of his laws? I hear the general response, yea; but
                            intellect is persistent, and will still oppose it, and would do so until we should see "her
                            walls all broken down and the wild boar of the forest passing through and eating the
                            grapes." "The fear of man is a snare, but whoso putteth his trust in God shall be safe."
                            "Every word of God is pure" and the laws are his word, and such-as oppose them will be found
                            fighting against God and the prosperity of his people. So, let "no man deceive himself. If
                            any among you seemeth (or thinks himself) to be wise, let him become a fool, that he may be
                            wise ; for the "wisdom of this world is foolishness with God." It has been my teaching,
                            public and pri- <pb n="53" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> vate, for half a century, to follow me as I follow
                            Christ, and wherein I fail to obey und follow him, you need not obey nor follow me. But one
                            thing I have learned, and that is, no one can be both Christ and Judas at the same time. The
                            conflict between spirit and intellect is too greatone cannot maintain the spiritual gift of
                            Cod for himself and people, with the burden of trade and commerce, and all temporal things
                            resting on him ; it will follow him into the house of Avorship and weaken his ministrations.
                            I have had some experience in this line. Intellect will always say: "There is no love in
                            trade : get the best of the bargain ; cheat rather than be cheated." While the spirit says:
                            "Don't take something for nothing. It is better to be cheated than to cheat." I will here
                            give you one instance, to show you what real, true Shakerism is in trade. It was in the
                            leading Society in early days : A neighbor came to the Trustee to buy a horse, and described
                            the kind he wanted, and said he would give one hundred dollars for him. The Trustee, not
                            having him, but knowing where he could get one for half that sum, told the neighbor to come
                            on a certain day and he would furnish the horse. The Trustee went and bought the horse,
                            paying fifty dollars for him and sold him to the neighbor for one hundred dollars. Thinking
                            he had done well, he reported the transaction to the Minister expecting praise; but instead
                            of that, he condemned the proceeding and severely reproved the Trustee, and had him go and
                            return the fifty dollars to the neighbor, reserving only enough to pay himself for his
                            trouble ; this shows the difference between spirit and intellect, and the necessity of a
                            spiritual leader to say : "Get thee behind me, Satan." As I am still speaking, as it were,
                            from the tomb, I will state some of my past observations and personal experiences for the
                            edification of younger persons. I have been a close observer ever since my call to the
                            ministry, more than sixty years ago, and am compelled to say, with no ill-feeling toward
                            any, that I have never known prosperity and God's blessing to follow any gift where
                            intellect had the ascendency over the spirit; nor has any one who gained promotion by
                            selfish intellectual intrigue ever been prospered. Such, God cannot prosper ; for He is
                            unchangeable and no respecter of persons. This should be a lesson for all. I will say
                            further, without boasting, that in all my appointments as teacher (by me unsought,) I have
                            been greatly blessed and prospered in every sense of the word, and the same also of the
                            Society or families under my charge, up to the day of my final releasement. I humbly give
                            thanks to God for this. It did not come from any superior intellectuality, but more from my
                            faith and trust in God, and personal obedience to his Holy Laws, though not permitted to
                            require it of others. I never allowed myself to be drawn off into any worldly fashion, nor
                            could I now feel justified in so doing. Some intellects think all that is now necessary is
                            the celibate life and property in common, when this existed, and was lived by thousands
                            before Christ was born, and is only a begin- <pb n="54" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> aing in his work; and
                            millions are living it now. Christ set the pattern of something far superior to this, by
                            sever allowing intellect to dictate what should be done, and all his followers should do the
                            same. Could we be satisfied with celibacy and property in common, we would follow in the
                            footsteps of the Catholic Church that drove out of Jerusalem all the true followers of
                            Christ. Every one that clung to Matthew's Hebrew Gospel was purged out and the Church
                            allowed intellect to take the .ascendency over the spirit and has kept it so to this day,
                            and in material greatness has eclipsed all others, and it is bow the head and shoulders of
                            the great Apocalyptic Beast, which is worshiped, and if we are content with the same, we
                            will only be a pig's tail to that anti-christian church. 0 nay, we must return to God's law,
                            says the voice from the tomb, and become fools that we may be wise, for "the foolishness of
                            God is wiser than men." Any person or number of persons are far wiser and better off without
                            houses or lands or earthly goods, having spirit guidance, than they would be under
                            intellectual control with all the kingdoms of the world at their service. Christ, though in
                            poverty, knew this, when He said : "Get thee behind me, Satan." He knew it was better to
                            have spiritual than mortal life, which he afterward gave to maintain the spiritual. I am now
                            asked: Is it right to obey a leader when we know he is moved by the envy and aspiring
                            intellect of others ? AnswerCertainly. Implicit obedience is obligatory upon all, unless the
                            requirement is sinful. It is as necessary in the spiritual army as it is in the material,
                            and should always be rendered, if physically and mentally able, without question or evasion.
                            The words, "I will not obey, should never pass the lips of a consecrated soul; but as all
                            are liable to err, when any one knows a leader to be in the wrong, he may be as free as Paul
                            was with Peter and no harm will follow. But whoever is appointed leader all should obey, for
                            "Obedience is better than sacrifice" and "Order is Heaven's first law." I have put this in
                            practice in all the changes of my long life, which ha\re been many, nor did I ever ask the
                            reason why, and have always had God's blessing. When some intellectual arrangements did not
                            prosper, I heard a leader in the West say: "If God intends to let his work run out, we must
                            be reconciled, for we can not help it. Can not help it! We are the very ones to help it."
                            Rise up, obey the Spirit, and cast the net on the spiritual side of the ship and we shall
                            have all we can take on board, then let the Spirit do the assorting, and keep all that are
                            fit for the Father's use and let the rest go back into the ocean from whence they came. If
                            we, his chosen people, will not obey Him, a scattering will be the consequence, as was in
                            the type, but this need not occur. The intellectual wisdom of men has taken the Ship of Zion
                            far away on the tumbling billows of the wide ocean, until we scarcely know our latitude, and
                            "she has sprang aleak," and all our prayers, tears and cries will avail nothing until we
                            will listen to the Spirit and resolve to re54 <pb n="55" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> turn and obey God. Then
                            angels will appear and God will cause a wave to stop the leak; then all hands to the pumps
                            and we are safe. Then, instead of being cold, formal, artistic and world-like, God's
                            inspiration will flow in like a mighty river, and then we shall sing and dance and leap for
                            joy, and shout and clap our hands and praise the Lord, and go on rejoicing evermore.
                        Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Closing the world's fair" TEIform="index"/> CLOSING THE WORLD'S FAIR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederick W." TEIform="persName"/> Frederick W. Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is stated that fifty thousand gospel Ministers have been served with blank petitions for
                            their respective flocks to sign; praying Congress to enact unconstitutional "religious
                            legislation" to close the World's Fair upon the ConstantineHeathen Sunday. If the American
                            government, were a Church and State government, which it is not; and if all the world, who
                            are invited to the Fair knew that this was a Christian nation and had a "Christian
                            Government," which its father, "Washington, declared it was not; and that, if they came from
                            India, from South America, from Spain, China, Africa, Turkey, Russia, France and England,
                            they would be compelled to lose one seventh of their time in the observance of a Sectarian
                            unscriptural Sabbath,* in addition to their own Sabbath, coming upon another day; and they
                            still choose to come. Well! but they are being invited to come, not to an Infidel, an
                            ecclesiastical, Christian, nor even to an American Fair, but to a World's Fair, open to
                            Anabaptists, -Jews, Buddhists, Mohammedans, who have their own Sabbath days, to say nothing
                            of the millions of nonsectarian or the religious people, who, like Shakers, regard all days
                            alike, and to be kept holy by ceasing thereon to do evil, and learning to be and to do good.
                            Infidels to Church and State governments, like Paine, Franklin, Washington and Jefferson,
                            wrote and signed the Declaration of Independence, and framed a constitution that expressly
                            forbids all "religious legislation." The "Age of Reason" had arrived, the "Rights of Man"
                            were boldly set forth, and when "The Crisis" came, the truth and "Common Sense" prevailed.
                            All men were legally equal and had inalienable rights to entire liberty of conscience, even
                            down to the Priests of Balaam, who, for their salaries, seek a union with Balak. Religious
                            freedom, perfect exemption from Priestly rule and dominatiom is the great honor and glory of
                            the secular government of these United States. But "eternal vigilance" will alone maintain
                            it. Under God, we are all indebted to the Skeptical classes for our Secular government. The
                            anti-Christians ought to be thankful to them for they have returned good for evil, and do
                            not persecute their persecutors. Paine was the master-spirit of the American Revolution.
                            Washington, whose private Secretary he was, declared that Thomas Paine had done more with
                            his pen for the ultimate success of the American Revolution than he had done with his sword;
                            the Infidels never persecute. The Priesthood have white-washed Washington, <pb n="56" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> who would very seldom go into a Steeple Housea Churchand have blackballed,
                            belied and vilified Paine, as the Rebels in our Civil War, slandered, contemned and finally
                            killed Lincoln. By what the Church and State Christians have done in Tennesee without law we
                            may jndge what they will do when they have the law in their hands. They tore a good American
                            citizen from his home and family, imprisoned Mm, worried, brow-beat and tortured him to
                            death. His soul in the Spirit land, is "marching on" to vengeance upon his Inquisitors. He
                            was doing what he, and all of us, have a perfect U. S. constitutional right to do, plow our
                            fields whenever we choose. Where is the Ecclesiastical Court to determine upon which of the
                            seven Sabbath days we must not plow? Could there be a greater absurdity than the stamp upon
                            our coin, "Tn God we trust," when thousands of good citizens do not believe in any God at
                            all ? Yet their inalienable rights remain intact, as do the rights of those who profess to
                            believe there are three Gods, all masculine, ignoring woman. Are there any Christians except
                            Shakers ? And are there any human beings in the Spirit World, in heaven or hell, or upon
                            this earth, who may not become Christians ? "A great company of Priests were obedient to the
                            faith." And if the Inquisition-Clergy may become Christians, who shall despair of being
                            saved r Belief is the result of evidence. There is no virtue in it, nor is there any vice in
                            unbelief. It is want of evidence ; having evidence, belief is the result. Jesus said: "My
                            kingdom is not of this world, therefore my servants will not fight." If the Chaplain is a
                            Christian, what is he doing in a secular, worldly, masculine legislature, that is spending
                            the principal revenues of the country in manufacturing war material? And what place has he
                            in the Army and Navy, or on the bloody battle field. Is it not fifty thousand Balak Priests
                            who are going to move heaven and earth to fill their Churches and increase their incomes ?
                            Lincoln was an Infidel and became a Spiritualist; so, according to "Free Thought" the
                            Jesuits killed him. Let us have peace, but not the "peace of Warsaw." Let Infidel, Jew or
                            Turk be left in perfect liberty of conscience to do by others, as they would be done b}7.
                            Did Jesus ever denounce the skeptical Sadducees as he denounced the believing Pharisees? For
                            untold ages, the wise of this world thought that the earth was flat. One man arose who said
                            it was round, and that it turned around. The Christian Priests arrested, imprisoned and
                            tortured him to death, just as they have arrested, imprisoned and killed King of Tennesee
                            who kept the true SabbathSaturday and plowed his field on their Sabbath. Either open the
                            World's Fair upon the seven Sabbath days, or close it upon the seven Sabbath days and tax
                            the Church and State "fifty thousand Balak Priests" to pay the outlay and all losses to the
                            Exhibitors. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">The "Home Notes" from three Societies were received too late for insertion. Ed.</p><pb n="57" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agreeably to the suggestion in the ''Home Notes'' of our Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Agreeably to the suggestion in the ''Home Notes'' of our Manifesto...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Enfield, December 1891" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H., Dec. 1891.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Agreeably to the suggestion in the "Home Notes" of our Manifesto, I have taken down some of
                            the testimonies given in our Sabbath Morning Service. Here is one given in our last meeting
                            by Sister Isabella Russell that I deem too valuable to drop just where it was uttered, and
                            am sending it to you with the idea that perhaps some extracts from it may be worthy a place
                            in the Manifesto. Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Keniston, Marinda" TEIform="persName"/> Marinda Keniston.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We read in the Oct. No. of the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We read in the Oct. No. of the Manifesto...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "We read in the Oct. No. of th^ Manifesto that a meeting had, recently, been held at New
                            Lebanon, during which, Elder Frederick spoke upon the fundamental principles of our
                            institution ; first of which he claims is the Communistic principle. Second, the Celibate or
                            Virgin Life principle. Third, the principle of Peace and good-will toward all mankind. I am
                            a believer in just these principles, because they meet the needs of my spiritual being.
                            There comes a time in the life of every person, no doubt, when he must realize that he has
                            outgrown the period of childhood and youth, spiritually, no less than physically, and this
                            condition does not depend altogether upon the number of years he has lived. Speaking from my
                            present standpoint it would seem like indulging a spirit of indolence to depend upon others
                            to do my thinking for me. The advice of Elder Giles to us was, not to be content to subsist
                            merely on what had been done, but to be producers of those elements that constitute
                            intelligent, spiritual beings. We have inherited a noble birthright; our parents have given
                            us a good start in life, and it becomes our duty to make the most of ourselves by improving
                            our opportunities which did not exist one hundred or even fifty years ago; always bearing in
                            mind that the present time is the most acceptable for service. This view of the subject
                            answers in some measure a question which perhaps we have asked ourselves a great many times.
                            Why is it, that so many young people lose their union, and fall from our ranks ? Some of
                            whom, we have known all through the period of their childhood and youth were morally good,
                            honest and obedient to the advice of their teachers and best friends, as we ourselves have
                            been, but after having consumed all the food which had been prepared for them, and reached
                            that stage of development when it became necessary to earn their own living, do their own
                            thinking, reasoning, wrestling, praying and working, in the direction of maintaining the
                            faith that had been given them by their spiritual teachers, they chose to take a different
                            course to find happiness and peace of mind, and possibly in some instances they find what
                            they seek, simply, because they have never known the enjoyment of a life of purity and true
                            consecration to the highest principles of truth, by the exercise of their own God-given
                            powers. They have never sought it by incorporating these graces into their own lives, until
                            they became a part of their very being, which is the only way to obtain that immortal
                            treasure which the world can never give nor take away. After w^e become sufficiently
                            enlightened to realize the difference between <pb n="58" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> a vital principle, and a
                            mere form, habit, or custom of society, we shall be able to accept the truth which will make
                            us wholly free; we shall find within the limits of our own Church ample scope for the
                            development of ear best thoughts and our highest aspirations. To illustrate this, Let us
                            take the first Communistic principle of our Church aud see if it is possible to live a
                            perfect Christian life fey ignoring it. It is one of the grandest subjects ever presented to
                            the human mind. We sometimes hear the remark that this principle is running out from our
                            Church. Admitting this to be true to some extent, we can but see that some of the best minds
                            of our day, are giving this subject consideration. If any individual holding in trust the
                            consecrated property of the Society is taking advantage of his position, and selfishly
                            Appropriating for his personal interest the funds in his keeping, then that individual is
                            running this principle out of his own life, and if every other member in the Soeiety is
                            doing the same thing to the extent of his opportunities for acting, then indeed we may
                            truthfully make tlie statement that the communistic principle is running out from our homes.
                            Let us bear in mind, however, that principles founded on truth are eternal and although the
                            forms and customs erf our communistic life may change in the progress of time, the result
                            produced will be the same. Whenever we are convicted that the one thing lacking to perfect
                            us in the Christ-life is to sell all and give to the poor, to share equally with our
                            fellow-beings of whatever we may possess, whether earthly treasures, or kind deeds, pure
                            thoughts and earnest prayers, thus making a full and willing sacrifice to become useful in
                            our Teacher's service, or, as was remarked in our meeting last Sabbath "enjoy the gospel by
                            coming into it with our whole souls." Whenever this conviction reaches us individually, or
                            as a Church, if, instead of obeying it, we "go sorrowfully away," then we shall lose the
                            blessing, and others more worthy will take our crown and our birthright."</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Nancy E. Moore, no. 3" TEIform="index"/> Eldress Nancy E. Moore. No. 3.</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="South Union, February 1864" TEIform="index"/> South Union, Feb. 1864.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Companions :I am impressed to write the testimony of my unswerving faith in the
                            gospel of Christ, and my desire for the prosperity and honor of our gospel home. We should
                            feel that it is our home, and watch over it with a devoted interest, as our parents have
                            done before us. They gave their lives to God and laid a foundation upon which we may build.
                            Every one should realize that he has a work to do, a home to protect, and a religious
                            interest to sustain to ensure a lasting happiness to the soul. It is a gospel requirement
                            for each one to be prudent and careful of every good thing that is entrusted to his care for
                            the benefit of the Community. To study a wise economy becomes a matter of great importance
                            in the prosperity of our home. There should be <pb n="59" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> an interested feeling
                            to save the property from waste, deeper and stronger than in those who work merely for self.
                            In this way we may look for prosperity to crown our efforts as it formerly has done, and for
                            a blessing to be upon all our labors. This is our home, and each one should feel himself to
                            be an active member of a living body of Believers. "Waste not," is an important lesson to
                            learn. After the Brethren and Sisters have toiled faithfully through heat and cold, and with
                            the help of an over-ruling Providence have provided a good supply of food for the support
                            and comfort of all, we should see that none of these things that come under our notice or
                            care, are left carelessly to be wasted. It is a heavy tax upon the family to obtain the fire
                            wood, and we should be thoughtful and saving and not burn it needlessly. A special care
                            should be taken of the utensils and machinery used on the farm, and everything should have a
                            place-where it can be secured from thieves during the night. The mechanics have many costly
                            tools under their charge and when not in use should be returned to their proper places, that
                            they may not be lost or stolen. We should remember that it takes our time and labor to earn
                            these things, and if we are prudent much may be saved. To be industrious, neat and cleanly
                            and to maintain good order is also a visible mark of a true Believer. This outward
                            manifestation is quite a sure index of the spiritual work that should have its proper place.
                            In this way we rise from the low estate of a selfish life, and are enabUsd to stand in the
                            light. Yea, to love the light for the peace and joy which it brings to the soul. Never be
                            willing to be dishonest, nor to act the lrypocrite; it will harden the conscience, but
                            rather let us bear in mind that every thought, word and action must be brought to judgment,
                            there to be approved as righteous or condemned as wicked. Let us work for this reward ;
                            "Well done, good and faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy Lord," and enjoy the
                            blessed fruits of our labors. These are the blessings that are worth more than all this
                            world can give. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of eldress Mary Vance" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of ELDRESS MARY VANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bennett, Margarette" TEIform="persName"/> By Margarette Bennett.</byline><p TEIform="p">Methinks the joy of the Angel band Is heightenedaye, renewed, For Mother is safe in the
                            Summer Land, Has passed the mystic flood. We've often prayed, dear suffering one, This
                            bitter cup might pass, That thou with us might longer dwell, As guide through righteousness
                            And though thy voice be silent now, Thy willing hands at rest, Thy children should no murmur
                            know, Since they through tliee are blest. All nay, for thou art still with us In sympathy
                            and prayer, Thy spirit presence oft shall bless And bring us heaven near. By faith we see
                            thee robed in white Upon thy head, a crown Encircled with celestial light Reflected from the
                            throne: And hear thy promise to return In some glad, future day To take thy loyal children
                            home, To live with tliee alway. Alfred, Me.</p><pb n="60" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. MARCH, 1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Community. Its aim. is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of
                            the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousaess. All communications should be
                            addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy per year,
                            postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample copy, free. .75 .40 Entered at the Post
                            Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The article which we publish from the pen of our venerable..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The article which we publish from the pen of our venerable...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The article which we publish from the pen of our venerable Elder F. W. Evans, having
                                reference to the so-called Christian Sabbath, and to the opening of the "World's
                                Exposition" on Sunday, leads us into a more extended thought on the subject. It seems
                                that a wonderful representation of names has been brought forward by a class of
                                petitioners that the first day of the week may be regarded as God-ordained for a special
                                purpose, and that all nations be forced to regard it. The foundation for the keeping of
                                this day has been embodied in the Mosaic regulations. It reads, "Six days shalt thou
                                labor and do all thy work; but the seventh day is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God ; in
                                it thou shalt not do any work." That Moses found this to be the best thing for his
                                people is evident from its rigid enforcement during the wilderness journey to Canaan. If
                                a man was found gathering sticks or even chips that he might comfort himself by the
                                warmth of a fire, he was by the unsympathetic law of Moses, to be stoned to death. No
                                burden of any kind was permitted to be carried on the Sabbath, and hence the trouble
                                that arose among the Scribes and Pharisees when Jesus said to the sick man, "Take up thy
                                bed and walk." Even the healing of the sick was an infringement upon the law and those
                                who unfortunately fell victims to some malady on that day were obliged to possess their
                                souls with patience till the dawn of a more secular day. Restful Sabbath ! It was a
                                panacea for many of the ills of both soul and body, and equally comforting to both man
                                and beast. Moses did not frame a code of laws in the interest of man and leave out
                                thecare and kindness that should be extended to the faithful beast of burden. At the
                                close of the six days of unremitting labor, under the lash of the cruel driver, the poor
                                beast could have twenty-four hours of un- <pb n="61" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> disturbed rest, and eat
                                and drink or chew his cud with perfect composure. No Jew would dare to touch the yoke or
                                lift the goad stick on that day. Moses had no special fear of being disturbed by the
                                exhibition of a "World's Fair" on Sunday and hence the marked silence on that subject;
                                and we may venture to entertain the belief that the first world's fair on record, so
                                fully illustrated by the Preacher, was also closed on the Sabbath, or some Scribe or
                                Pharisee would have a special note of the sad departure. Jesus, it seems had but little
                                sympathy with this one day religion, and we incline to think that he took every
                                favorable opportunity to illustrate his views on the subject. The plucking of corn and
                                rubbing it in their hands was sufficient accusation against the disciples to warrant
                                their death by stoning. It was working on Sunday. To rub the grain was work, and the
                                liability of dropping a few grains on the ground would be a process of sowing, and this
                                would be a criminal act. The healing of the withered arm on the Sabbath was enough to
                                set the whole synagogue in an uproar. Such audacity proceeding from a laboring man was
                                not to be tolerated. The Sabbath must be respected ! Jesus, however, who says of
                                himself,I came not to do my own will, but the will of Him that sent me, was evidently
                                impressed with the fact, that every day was God's holy day, in which he must work for
                                the good of mankind. His mission was to preach "glad tidings" to the poor on every day
                                of the week, and he often found occasion to manifest his faith by his works. My Father,
                                said he, works hitherto or has worked up to this time and now "I work." It is in
                                accordance with his love and law. "The Sabbath was made for man, and not man for the
                                Sabbath." One writer on this subject remarks,"No rules for the observance of the Sabbath
                                are ever given by the Apostles ; its violation is never denounced by them. Sabbath
                                breakers are never included in any list of offenders ! The Christian Sunday of modern
                                times is not the Bible Sabbath, but rather a Roman Catholic Sunday, officially
                                established by the edict of Constantine A. D. 321. In heathen Rome the same day was used
                                for religious observance and dedicated to the worship of the sun. The Emperor advised
                                those in the cities to "rest on the venerable Sunday, but in the country the husbandman
                                may freely and lawfully apply to agriculture, since it often happens that the sowing of
                                corn and planting of vines cannot be so advantageously performed on any other day." But
                                there were other nations in existence who held religious observances and had a "Holy
                                Day" as well as the Christians in heathen Rome, and these may be teaching <pb n="62" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> us as othera have, that God is no respecter of persons. That every nation
                                may have a special holy day and that every day, throughout the whole year is God's holy
                                day. The sacred day of the Egyptian or of the Turk is equally as valuable to them as is
                                a Sunday to the Christian, and may work in their hearts a corresponding amount of
                                righteousness.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. January. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1891. 26.63 4&gt;a'
                                in. 22 9-16 in. 1892. 24.64 3% in. 19 in. Center ITmily. Feb. 10, 1892. Beloved
                                Editor;Sisters of Center Family do not complain, only they are not quite satisfied with
                                our last "Home Notes" though good so f a&gt;r as they went. Thought we would just step in
                                and tel] you how it is. Besides making gilt-edge butter, Sister F. S. improves her spare
                                moments stitching on cloaks to sell. Two or three Sisters work on fancy pin-cushions to
                                sell. Thousands of paper boxes for sending out the medicine, are made by the Sisters,
                                with Brethrens' help. The small paper wrappers for thousands of bottles a year, for
                                "Narwood's Tincture," are made by the Sisters; (said wrappers are made on a form just
                                large enough to slip in a fourounce bottle.) Preparing fur yarn and knitting gloves to
                                sell, is the daily employment of one Sister, when she is not making said wrappers or
                                doing something else. Since Jan. 1891 she has knit fortyseven pairs of gloves. Fur yarn
                                is nearly used up. Sister Mary will have to get some more dead Coon-robes for us; then
                                we shall have a great bee, or a small wasp! and every Sister who can or cannot
                                (seemingly) must go to pulling and picking, until the coarse robes are made soft and
                                fine enough to manufacture into glove yarn. This part of the business is not quite so
                                pleasant as it might be, so we "hurry up" and finish the job in a jiffy. Have not told
                                all that we do; let this suffice. Our Society has been fortunate in escaping thus far
                                that fatal scourge, La Grippe. Have secured a good crop of ice for use next summer, and
                                have our winter's work mostly finished such as hauling wood, threshing, etc., etc. With
                                heart-felt love and best wishes to all, we close. ET. R. A. North. Family. Well at last
                                we have some sleighing. Have not secured our ice yet. We have had to renew our ice
                                house, which was completely decayed. We think we have somewhat improved it, but
                                experience will tell the tale. When the house was first built the door through which we
                                drew the ice was put in the lower side; so we have for the last 25 years been drawing
                                our ice away below the level of the house, then drawing it up with a horse. In repairing
                                we have put a door in the upper side so that the ice would go in of itself. This set us
                                to thinking and we have discovered that the ice will slide directly from the pond into
                                the house if we only give it a chance. So we have been figuring away on this for some
                                time, to have it slide in and not knock the house over. The pond is more than one
                                hundred feet above the house and only a few hundred away from it. Well we thought of a
                                slide and endless chain, with a break &amp;c, &amp;c. Finally we erected a slide
                                which has about 4 in. to the foot grade, (on the average.) We have automatic scratchers
                                hinged above the ice on all the steep part; and at the lower end just outside the ice
                                house door we have a large screw, so we can close the lower end and let the ice in- <pb n="63" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> to the house just as we need it. The slide will be kept full of
                                ice, and let out only as fast as it can be suj&gt;plied at the upper end. We have now a
                                company of eight boys; and we have plenty of music, not all in harmony, or perfect
                                unison. One good Elder is reported as saying, that, agitation was better than
                                stagnation: and so we think. We take children among us, and we try to make good, noble
                                men and women of them; and if possible permanent members of our order. Blessed be the
                                children and the kingdom of heaven will never be without them. In kindest love, D.
                            O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Keeping the heart is spoken of in Proverbs as worthy "of all diligence," because "out of
                                it are the issues of life." All that makes life truly noble depends upon the heart being
                                kept or guarded from evil. The heart is the seat of principles, and is the center of
                                thought and feeling. If the fountain is impure the stream will also be impure. If the
                                heart is sinful the life must be wrong. Jesus teaches that all sin proceeds from the
                                heart. (By nature) "the heart is deceitful above all things." This being the natural
                                state of the heart, the first thing must be to cleanse it by a life of purity. But even
                                a purified heart must be kept with all diligence. The Apostle's injunction, "Watch ye,
                                stand fast in the faith, be strong," is wise counsel. 2417 spaces of cream were sold in
                                January. To have early garden tomatoes, seeds may be sown in a box now, and when two or
                                three inches high, they may be transplanted into flower pots or fruit cans. Those who
                                live some distance from greenhouses can do this with little labor and it will pay well.
                                A large poultry house presupposes too many fowls in one enclosure. To have a warm house
                                for every 40 fowls and a separate yard is much better. Too large poultry houses have
                                caused poultry growing to be a failure. Unless fowls can be kept warm, winter eggs are
                                an impossibility. D. Obcutt. Feb. 7, 1892. The wheels of time fly around in quick
                                succession, reminding us that another month has gone with others to return no more, and
                                in the past one winter has given us one or two eai*nest touches, enough to show what he
                                could do were he to awaken, but these have enabled us to "secure some very fair ice from
                                ten to eleven inches thick. We have found out that an iceplow is a great saving of time,
                                money and labor in securing the ice crop; also we have tried a patent ice creeper on our
                                horses' feet, to save sharpening their shoes and thus far they work well. 3277 spaces of
                                cream made in Jan. from 20 cows. We have witnessed what to us was an interesting natural
                                phenomenon on a small scale. Some potatoes having been frozen were placed in a tub of
                                cold spring water in the morning; by night the water was frozen nearly solid. The
                                potatoes were scraped from the ice and placed in another tub of spring water; the top of
                                J that water was lightly frozen, after several hours. The potatoes on being reI moved
                                from the last water were cooked and eaten, and proved excellent. We truly believe that
                                Providence is a good power to trust in. We find all our wants well supplied if we reach
                                out to take the gifts that are offered us. It is unnecessary to attempt any illustration
                                of this, and but little discrimination to see it, and we constantly admire the beauty of
                                that system which indicates universal benevolence. A general time of health prevails at
                                present. M. W.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Feb. 1892. Dear Editor:As we enter upon the last winter month, we find our zeal for
                                labor has not entirely diminished, although we have had but little snow. 125 cords of
                                wood have been hauled to the door-yard, for sawing and 80 tons of ice housed. <pb n="64" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> Our herb and broom business have been ably managed. Good and faithful
                                Sisters have had more than their share this winter, of the burdens of life. Not only the
                                common duties of the family have demanded attention, but there has not been a week
                                without sickness, and this has received their willing attendance. With all this we have
                                not suffered from Winter of the Heart. Our pathway may lead us among trials which for a
                                time would seem to impede our progress, and shut out the very light of heaven; but if we
                                have the love of heaven in our hearts we have a solace that will support and give
                                strength and enable us to meet every trial. We have no need to fear the future while our
                                trust is in God, our heavenly Father and Mother. Winter days will be changed to summer
                                days and our pathway will be made pleasant in the sunshine of God's love. Pleavenly
                                flowers and fruits will abound and make of life an eternal joy. Let us extend this
                                sunshine to every one as there is nothing that will do so much good as the spirit of
                                kindness, administered in a cheerful spirit. "Kindness is the music of good-will to men
                                and on this harp the smallest fingers may play heaven's sweetest tunes on earth." Of all
                                blessings there is nothing better or more desirable than a cheerful, happy home, and it
                                should be our duty to promote these blessings in our own home circle. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Record, for Jan. 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 48. Lowest " " Mean " "
                                Total Precipitation Total Snowfall, 1ST. 8. " 18.4 3.78 in. " 10 in. A. BEiaGs. Feb. 5,
                                1892. Just now we are rejoicing through hope of having a few days for good sleighing. Up
                                to this date the farmers have indulged largely in speculations about the woi'k that must
                                be done on runners before spring. Now the horses and oxen may be used to advantage in
                                the hauling of wood and timber. One paper says: "Now is the time for revivals;" and the
                                sleepy boy says at an early hour,"Now is the time to go to bed," and the last remark is
                                about as spiritual as the first. The ice harvest has been secured and it is said to be
                                of excellent quality. It was fifteen inches thick, but being cut into cakes with the aid
                                of horses, it made the work comparatively easy, and at the end of the second day the
                                house was well filled, and 150 tons had been secured for the warm season of 1892. Even
                                this quantity of ice is insufficient to supply the demand. Referring to an old record we
                                find that in 1840 a boy with a wheelbarrow could take the needed supply of ice to the
                                kitchens and dairy, while at the present date it requires one or two men and a span of
                                horses several hours during the day and this not less than twice each week. The drinking
                                of iced water becomes a habit the same as does the drinking of tea and coffee and is
                                probably quite as injurious to the system.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eads, Harvey L." TEIform="index"/>DEATH.</head><p TEIform="p">We have just received notice of the death of Elder Harvey L. Eads of South Union, Ky.,
                                which occurred on the morning of the 13th. inst. His age was 84 yrs. and 10 mo. Of his
                                virtues we need not speak for they are known wherever the true principles of the gospel
                                are planted. J. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Feb. 10, 1892. Winter at Sonyea is marching on, snow continues falling, and winds
                                continue blowing, farmers are busy in the logging business, while the woodmen are active
                                hewing forest trees for home repairs and home comfort. Our ice harvest was completed in
                                good time and its quality quite satisfactory, as it measured eight inches in thickness;
                                several tons have been secured from the pond, enough for practical purposes, which is
                                sufficient for the coming days when the hot rays of the summer sun come to abide with
                                us. The majority of La Grippe patients have lost their grippe, which we are thankful
                                for, too much Grippe is worse than no grip; a few still hold to it or it holds to <pb n="65" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> them, but they will recover in time (or eternity.) The Bible
                                teaches us that sinners stand on slippery places. We find this is the season when saints
                                as well as the former class stand on the same platform, that is, when the highways are
                                covered with all that makes a path slippery. If caution is not exercised by the walking
                                public, we daily hear of a great fall in dry goods. jSTow all beware and practice care,
                                whereever you. may roam and with open eyes see the path that lies away and near at home.
                                G. D. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/> Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> Already two months of the year 1892 have passed, and soon the swift wings of time will
                                bear us away to the other shore, where we hope to find one of the "many mansions"
                                prepared by our Father. We have had real winter weather, which is preferable to the mild
                                winters previous, yet how utterly unable are we to change one of the inimitable laws of
                                our Creator" We think we are very fortunate to have our ice-houses filled. The "La
                                Grippe," has not abated, but our dear aged ones are selected as victims, and although
                                many of the sick are those who have passed the allotted three-score and ten years, we
                                are loath to give them up. We have had some bright, beautiful days since Feb. came in,
                                but are not sure that the winter is gone. We have much to be thankful for temporally,
                                and although but few seek to be saved from their sins, we know if we are faithful
                                laborers in the vineyard we shall surely find a blessing. The few warm sunshiny days
                                were improved by the gardeners and farmers, in enriching the ground and plowing but
                                these days are few and far between. The epidemic that has opened, has spared neither
                                patrician nor plebeian, has attacked both East and West families, as well as the Center.
                                Happily so far we have lost no one. "Not my will, O Lord, but Thine be done." We have
                                heard from our gospel friends at South Union of the extreme illness of our venerable
                                Elder H. L. Eads, whose very name is a house-hold word. We know he is beyond the
                                eightieth mile-stone, yet when we see the aged pass away to their rest, we feel sorry to
                                know that there are few who are of the pioneer stock, who paved the way and laid a
                                foundation for succeeding generations. Let us in life not withhold the kind words and
                                deeds that flow so readily from our hearts when we know they have gone from us. M. C. S.
                                South Union, Ky. Feb. 9, 1892. Dear Brother:The weather is very warm, but the health of
                                Society is quite good with few exceptions. Elder Oliver C. Hampton arrived at this place
                                from Union Village on the 3rd. inst. J. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Feb. 12, 1892. Dear Editor:Winter seems to have finally become disentangled from the
                                other seasons, and has asserted his supremacy. We can scarcely realize that the second
                                month of the Xew Year is so nearly spent, but our reliable calendar gives indisputable
                                evidence of the fact, and we hasten to forward our meagre offering for the columns of
                                your valuable pamphlet. In the past few weeks the roads have been in excellent condition
                                for sleighing; which has been well improved by all classes. Teams have been busy in all
                                directions securing the ice crop. Our people have harvested their supply which Avas
                                about nine inches in thickness, but of good quality. The usual routine of winter
                                business is being closely pursued. Hauling and sawing loirs, preparing wood for a future
                                cold, winter, and the daily necessary duties that come, serve to occupy our time and
                                keep us briskly moving. While performing these manifold duties may our hearts each day
                                be drawing nearer to God and our future home in the world supernal. Our meetings abound
                                in spiritual blessings and heavenly ministrations. A fair degree of health prevails at
                                presen in our Society. J. L. S.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I will not speak against my neighbor" TEIform="index"/>I will not speak against my neighbor
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I will not speak against my neighbor.</p><pb n="66" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Synopsis of discourses delivered by Dr. Cyrus Teed of the Koreshan Unity, on Dec. 11th and 13th, at Mount Lebanon, N. Y." TEIform="index"/> A Synopsis of Discourses Delivered by Dr. CYRUS TEED of the Koreshan Unity, on Dec 11th
                            and 13th, at Mount Lebanon. N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> On the evening of Thursday, Dec. 10th, we were quite surprised by the arrival at our home of
                            a distinguished visitor, no less a personage than L&gt;r. Cyrus Teed, the leader and founder of
                            the "Koreshan Unity and College of Life" in Chicago. He had made a day's call at our sister
                            Society in Canterbury. If our minds had been biased by slanderous newspaper reports, the
                            Docter would have been an unwelcome guest; but, knowing from experience that false
                            representation and defamation of character is the portion of those who devaite from the
                            common course of the world, we were disposed to give the stranger-friend a fair hearing, and
                            were favorably impressed with his honesty and sincerity of purpose from the first interview.
                            The Elders decided to call a family meeting on Friday evening to which the Ministry and
                            Elders of the first families were invited. The Brethren and Sisters convened at quarter past
                            seven. The choir sang an anthem entitled "The Day of the Lord," after which Dr. Teed was
                            invited to address the meeting. At first he showed some embarrassment, but soon warmed up to
                            his subject, and spoke most eloquently for an hour and a half on the faith and principles of
                            the new order. His views in most respects coincided with those of our Society. He believes
                            in the Duality of Deitya grand truth expressed throughout the kingdom of nature, but
                            preferred the term Bi-unity, as meaning two in one, this idea also was manifest in some
                            forms of life, which was clearly illustrated from known facts. There was one God including
                            Father and Mother; one Christ embodying the masculine and feminine principles, revealed
                            through Jesus and Ann Lee, emphasizing the text, "He that hath the Bride is the Bridegroom,"
                            as proving bi-unity in the baptism of both. Celibacy is the corner stone of the kingdom of
                            righteousness. Equality of the sexes is based on the law of justice, and in the College of
                            Life and Communal Home, woman has an equal share in all places of honor and trust.
                            Christianity, as expressed by modern churchianity, has proved a failure, it is a gigantic
                            system of selfishness and pride, creeds, and not the spirit of Christ rule the members of
                            the great sectarian denominations. The churches hold the power of persecution and
                            inquisition; they are ever ready to torture and put to death any prophet of G-od that may
                            arise whatever their testimony of truth may be. He dated his spiritual illumination back to
                            eighteen hundred and seventy, just one hundred years after Ann Lee received her divine
                            revelation; and he claimed, that the light and truth emanating from this Society, had a
                            potent influence in his baptism. All through these twenty-one years of mental struggle and
                            outward persecution, he had turned for strength to the spiritual center, but never until now
                            was he permitted to meet face to face, and commune with those whom lie believed were living
                            out the vital truths of Christian life. He explained the astrological signs in the heavens
                            as pointing to a new and glorious dispensation. The entrance of the sign Aries into
                            Aquarius, of Leo into Libra and of Libra into Yirgo, marks the second coming of Christ, the
                            execution of judgment and the emancipation of woman. Koresh means the sun of being, and the
                            system of religious and secular truth called Koreshanity, purposes to deal with all the
                            facts and questions relating to human life, both natural and spiritual; to establish
                            communistic homes, where by equal distribution of labor all shall be fed and clothed, and
                            there shall be no more want, and no great accumulation of riches. He had lately visited the
                            society of Harmony in Pennsylvania, had been cordially received and heard, without feeling
                            the venom and contumely of sectarian bitterness : in fact, the celebate societies were the
                            non-persecuting organizations, be-, <pb n="67" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> cause they abstained from the
                            lusts of the flesh, which stirred up the warring, fighting propensities in human beings,
                            while the opposite elements of peace, love, justice and toleration were engendered in those
                            who lived the true Christ-life. Between these Christian fraternities he would establish
                            friendly intercourse and a system of commerce that would do away with the use of money,
                            which is the root of all evil, for out of it grows the sensuality and degradation of
                            humanity, extremes of poverty and wealth and all their concomitant evils. He clearly
                            elucidated his views on the systems of exchange, and said that commerce as it existed in the
                            world, was like the fishes in the sea, the larger were continually devouring the smaller
                            ones. Much more was said that might be chronicled, but a short space must be left for our
                            second meeting. On Sabbath afternoon at two o'clock, the whole Society convened in the
                            Church family's large meeting room to hear our friend and brother; for he had simply
                            accepted our rule of initiation into the order, that of confession of sin, and felt
                            strengthened in a spiritual union with the body of Christ. A thorough knowledge of
                            physiology, the science of astrology, psychometry and chemistry, with an intuitive
                            perception of the interior spiritual sense and meaning of the Scriptures, makes him an able
                            exponent of esoteric cult. There seems to be no limit to the resource of his knowledge. The
                            second lecture was no less interesting than the first. He gave us a sketch of his
                            experience. Told how he studied medicine from the age of ten years; had taken degrees in
                            three colleges, and had a thriving practice in the city of l?tica, which he lost because he
                            undertook to give to the Baptist church the benefit of his spiritual illumination; they not
                            only did not accept his testimony, but actually froze him out, and put a boycott on his
                            business; a few would have patronized him, but he would not go in their back doors, as he
                            believed in being frank and open in all he did. He came from a long line of Baptist
                            preachers, and his friends were anxious in his younger days that he should enter the
                            ministry, but he could not feel that it was the call of God to him, hence he chose the other
                            profession, although in his childhood days he made three prayers; one was that he might be
                            an orator, another, that he might be a minister, and lastly, that he might be a publisher.
                            All along through the years he had been bold to promulgate his ideas of the true Christian
                            religion, but like the good Master, ' 'his own received him not.'' ISTot until five years
                            ago, when he went to Chicago did he get any reasonable hearing; and in that wicked city, the
                            true representation of Babylon the great, he had been bitterly persecuted by the churches.
                            One Baptist minister said in the pulpit, that he would head a mob and raze the College of
                            Life; and he would be the first one to throw a stone to dash out the brains of Dr. Teed.
                            Right in the heart of the cifcy, a Koreshan society was established that grew in spite of
                            opposition. It now numbered one hundred and fifty members sixty of whom lived in the
                            communal home. When they hired a double house of thirty-two rooms, they had nothing to
                            furnish them with; many of them slept on the floor and lived on the inost meagre fare for
                            several months, in fact they were often very hungry, yet were not discouraged, but kept on
                            working and praying and fortunately some persons came to their aid. One young Jew, whom he
                            converted to Christianity, gave succor in the time of dire necessity, by placing his funds
                            in the common treasury. Their small printing office had grown to the proportions of a
                            publishing house; they edited and printed a paper called the "Flaming Sword," and other
                            Koreshan literature, besides outside work. They contemplated buying some land outside the
                            city limits, where they could pursue agriculture besides their other business. Though their
                            discipline and form of worship was different from ours, yet the same spirit of truth was
                            working in them for purification and redemption from the <pb n="68" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> sins of the
                            world; he hoped to introduce greater order and uniformity among them. He gave an earnest
                            address to the young people, and told them that the pleasures of an interior spiritual life
                            far outweighed the follies of the world; when they had fully entered the way of eternal life
                            they would have no desire to return to the elements of unrest and bitterness. In speaking of
                            the ties of natural relationship, he said, "Of families who enter our home those who receive
                            the Christbaptism which consumes the carnal tie, are actuated to yield their selfish wishes
                            and give up their children to be under the care and tuition of appointed guardians, where
                            they can be educated and trained together. This rule is not enforced, but people soon grow
                            to feel in a communistic relation, tliatin the love of the Divine Parentage all souls are
                            alike precious." The life work of Mother Ann Lee was highly eulogized, her mission was
                            recognized as the one great good that had brought to woman releasement from the thraldom of
                            sexuality, and placed her in the spiritual kingdom on an equality with her brother man. He
                            rejoiced and gave thanks when he looked over the assembly before him, in the realization
                            that Christ had come, the Bride and the Bridegroom were one, and there was harmony and peace
                            in the perfected household. He asked the strength and prayers of the body of Believers, that
                            he might be empowered to go forth with even greater courage, to meet the taunts and flood of
                            lies poured forth from the mouth of the dragon; and have the recognition of our people as a
                            help to the little gatherings of brethren and sisters of the Koreshan faith in the various
                            states where they were located. The second meeting was two hours long, about two hundred
                            were present, yet none wearied, but listened with unabated interest to the end. The choir
                            rendered some appropriate music, and the meeting was closed with some excellent remarks from
                            the Elders, and a vote of thanks to the speaker. It is impossible in one article to give all
                            the points of interest in two long discourses, even much that one remembers must be
                        omitted.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clapp, Charles" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of Elder CHARLES CLAPP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Goepper, Annie B." TEIform="persName"/>Annie B. Goepper.</byline><p TEIform="p">Elder Ciiaki.es Clapp, the subject of this memorial was one of those few men who combined all
                            the qualities essential to the true and polished Christian gentleman. Brave as a lion when
                            circumstances required, his every-day life was marked by courtesy, hospitality and
                            affability. A true Christian! He practiced his religion in his daily walk. In his death, the
                            Community has lost one of her most faithful members, and our family, a kind father and
                            affectionate friend. He was ever ready to aid and strengthen the weak and erring and welcome
                            the prodigal son and daughter back to the fold. His end was that of the just man. Calmly,
                            peacefully and without a struggle, his spirit was wafted on high to reap the reward of a
                            well-spent life. "By tlio bright waters now thy life is cast .Joy for thee, happy friend thy
                            bark is j)ast The rough sea's foam ! Now the long- yearnings of thy soul are still'd, Home!
                            Home!thy peace is won, thy heart is file;1,, Thou art gone home !" Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Accounts reflecting upon the conduct of affairs at Alfred..." TEIform="index"/>
                            "Accounts reflecting upon the conduct of affairs at Alfred...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Accounts reflecting upon the conduct of affairs at Alfred, have appeared in a
                                    Boston paper, upon no better foundation than the statements of a girl, wh, at the
                                    request of her mother, was committed to the reformatory in Massachusetts, as
                                    hopelessly incorrigible. The young woman informed the judge who committed her, that
                                    "no jail could hold her." Elder Vance who has the general esteem of the community,
                                    in which he has so long lived, says the reports are entirely without foundation,
                                    which is the belief of all having means of knowing the facts.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">"Portland Transcript.<index level1="Portland transcript" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I think that by far the most impudent and shameless attack..." TEIform="index"/>
                            I think that by far the most impudent and shameless attack...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"I think that by far the most impudent and shameless attack I ever knew to be
                                    made in a newspaper on any man or body of men unconnected with politics, is that <pb n="69" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> made in the Boston Herald on the Alfred Shakers, an attack
                                    that would justify the banishment of the Herald from every decent household in the
                                    land. Either the Herald sent no reporter to Alfred to investigate the matter, or the
                                    reporter lied when he said that his statements were founded upon information given
                                    him by reputable men. There is not a man of good repute in all the town of Alfred",
                                    doctor, or lawyer, or hotel-keeper, or of any other respectable calling, who will
                                    say that he believes the report in the Herald to be true, or that he has ever
                                    furnished a reporter with any evidence upon which to base it. There is not a man,
                                    reputable or disreputable, in that town, who has lived in it any considerable time,
                                    that puts any credence in the report. The life of the Shakers, though reserved and
                                    isolated, is pure and godly, always open to a kindly and sympathetic inspection, but
                                    not to the visits of idle and impudent curiosity. I have known the Shakers ever
                                    since I Was a child, and know them to be a kindly, charitable and God-fearing
                                    people. Without reproach, they should be protected from calumny."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Eastern argus" TEIform="index"/> Eastern Argus.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> [The above notices were received from Elder John B. Vance of Alfred, Me., upon whom such an
                            ungentlemanly attack was recently made. "It is a pity that any reporter, of an influential
                            paper, should allow himself to write such slanderous articles. Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the memory of our dear sister, Marietta Brainard" TEIform="index"/> To the Memory of Our
                            Dear Sister, Marietta Brainard.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davis, Margaretta" TEIform="persName"/> Margaretta Davis.</byline><p TEIform="p">Life's Reaper has gathered our Sister From earth and her frail house of clay Yet assured as a
                            ministering angel We feel her loved presence to-day. Though in mid Summer she has been
                            garnered, Her fruit was well set, with no blight, Yet we sorrow that our precious Sister So
                            soon is removed from our sight. We fervently prayed to kind heaven To grant a new lease of
                            her life, The answer returned irresponsive, [strife" "She has done with earth's conflict and
                            Her hands ever willing in duty, Her heart ever ready to bless, A monument lasting have
                            builded, Her goodness to this will attest. The breath of her kind gentle spirit Has shed a
                            rich fragrance around, And deep in the hearts of the faithful Sweet memories of kindness
                            abound. But keenly we feel the bereavement Of parting, though but for a day, Yet sweet is
                            the thought of reunion We are aiming to walk the same way. Life's journey is short at the
                            longest, With each ebb and now of the tide We are nearing the shores immortal, Our home on
                            that brightOther Side Where parting is said to be over, And friends are united again. With
                            joy we will then greet our Sister If like her we serve to the end. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hamilton De Graw. Esteemed Friend:--As the Manifesto has come again..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Hamilton De Graw. Esteemed Friend:--As the Manifesto has come again...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Washington D. C., December 1891" TEIform="index"/>Washington, D. C. Dec. 1891.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Hamilton De Graw. Esteemed Friend :As the Manifesto has come again laden with good things,
                            and seeing your article, "Looking beyond the Shadows," I feel that I can not be silent nor
                            let my pen rest any longer. I live in the same hope expressed by a good Brother when he
                            says, "But I live in hope and trust that Divine Providence will guide me aright and give me
                            strength to do his will." I have not seen this Brother but know his spirit language, and may
                            God grant those petitions going up to his throne. I agree with Elder A. L. Work, that "the
                            world seems all right so long as we are content with her ways ; but after we get a glimpse
                            of that higher, <pb n="70" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> Christ-life, then the colrl .shoulder is turned to us
                            and it seems we no more belong to her." Thank God the messenger of good news, "The
                            Manifesto," goes to the aid of those who are in sympathy with its work, and who hope in his
                            own good time to be gathered together to that better partthe spiritual life and love, where
                            God and Christ shall reign supreme in the soul. Greetings to the Sisters and to our friend
                            A. L. Work, and to you my beloved Friend. If opportunity presents itself, I long to see you.
                            God bless you and all the household. Yours in sympathy,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Toepper, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. Toepper.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children:--You cannot look after your habits too carefully..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Children:--You cannot look after your habits too carefully...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, 1891" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Ct. 1891.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children :You cannot look after your habits too carefully. Bad habits are often
                            contracted by example of others. Bad habits grow by what they feed upon and they are ruinous
                            to the soul. It is little by little that sin increases in strength upon its victims by
                            repetition. To be safe from sin the voice of conscience must be regarded in little things.
                            Beware of the first wrong step. "Avoid the appearance of evil," is the only safeguard. When
                            you feel that a bad habit is controlling you, resist its despotism, tyranny. Evil habits
                            must be conquered or they will conquer, and destroy your happiness. Living in sin brings
                            grief and pain, dying to sin brings eternal gain. Correct your mistakes. Let your
                            aspirations be away from the wrong toward the right. "Hold fast that which isgood,'' and
                            keep a clean conscience. The purer you live the better fitted are you to benefit others.
                            Fight the good fight and you will overcome. Persistent self-denying struggles will win.
                            Watch your thoughts closely and bear the cross freely. Thoughts produce actions. Eesolve to
                            give up sinning, to-day make a beginning. Kegard good counsel. Never sacrifice principle for
                            pleasure. Associate only with the virtuous. "Good company will improve the mind, And wisdom
                            will impart, But bad, the bi.ne of all mankind, Will sure corrupt the heart." Your Brother.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/> Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spectacles" TEIform="index"/> SPECTACLES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Harriet Hastings.] If within our own homes we would use the same
                                    "specs" That we use when we visit next door, And search for the flaws as we did over
                                    there, I think we would find many more. If we'd use the same "specs" when we look at
                                    ourselves That we don when our company's near, I fear we would need what would
                                    magnify less, Or astonished we'd be, never fear! But I find all possess (where'er
                                    they may live) For their own use a kind deftly made, With the glasses all darkened,
                                    to hide half the view, So their own faults remain in the shade. But the ones which
                                    they use when at others they glance Have the glasses transparently clear, With a
                                    power to magnify things twice the size [appear That the same through the dark ones
                                    Now I think that the world would much happier be If the "specs" once for all, we
                                    would change, And within our own rooms use the spectacles clear, [range, With the
                                    dark for the much broader Then, the faults that appear to us jaggedly rough, Would
                                    melt into outlines so fair We would find that the world was a beautiful place, And
                                    good people lived everywhere.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Good housekeeping" TEIform="index"/> Bertha P. Englet, in Good Housekeeping.</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Englet, Bertha P." TEIform="persName"/></byline><pb n="71" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright day" TEIform="index"/> BRIGHT DAY.</head><p TEIform="p"> " Out of Zion, the perfection of beauty, God hath .shined" Psa. 1, 2. Canterbury, N. H.
                            1891. There has come unto thee, O thou Zion of God, A day of thanksgiving and prayer; With
                            thy sons free and strong let thy daughters rejoice, And blessed be the heart that is pure.
                            The heart that is pure and the hand that is true, The feet swift to carry glad news I will
                            gird with my strength and clothe with my love, And my pow'r in their spirits renew.</p><pb n="72" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.
                        </head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Feb. Contents. Dr. 11. S. Tanner; Treatment of the Sick;
                                Is Sugar a Food? Anti-Vaccination; Food; etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co.,
                                Kokoino, Ind. Somebody has said, "There is no new thing under the sun," but we rather
                                incline to think that Pomeroy's Golden Thought Diary for 1892 is entitled to be called
                                new and attractive. It is :t book of 366 pages, six by nine inches and affords a page
                                for every Day in the year. At the to)) of each page is printed an Advanced Thought which
                                may aid. materially, the mind of the writer as he transfers his golden thoughts to this
                                unique, golden -Journal. The book may be obtained by sending one dollar to the Advance
                                Thought Co. Rooms 46, World Building, New York City. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>THE PHRENOLOGICAL
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE PHRENOLOGICAL. The new Speaker
                                of the House of Representatives leads in the Phrenoeogical Journal and Science of Health
                                for -January. He looks the characteristic commonly ascribed to Ms surname. Dr. Lowlier
                                talks well but briefly on Moral Science Made Practical, and a good description of the
                                ancient Syrian methods in art and industry, with illustrations, follows. Dr. Amariah
                                Brigham figures as one of the immortals who helped along in the early days of American
                                Phrenology. A right noble-looking man was he. A poem on February is above the average
                                magazine verse. How Phrenology Saved Her Reputation appears to be a true sketch, and A
                                Teacher's Testimony is in a similar vein. A Review of Phrenological Doctrine is the work
                                of a scholar, the social and selfish faculties being considered. Governing Children, On
                                Using Both Hands, and Let Us Live with Our Children are conspicuous features in "Child
                                Culture." Modern Football is practically and sensibly scored by H. S. D. Why a
                                Vegetarian and The Little House are right to the point, and the latter deserves special
                                circulation all through the country. If its advice were obeyed there would be little
                                grippe. The Notes in Phrenology show a clever hand in selection and arrangement; they
                                are very instructive. And so, for that matter, are all other departments of this
                                admirable number of the veteran monthly. Published at $1.50 a year, 15c. a number.
                                Address the publishers, Fowler &amp; Wells Co., Pub., 777 Broadway, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's
                                Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's
                                Journal of Health. February. Contents. The Coming Woman; Talks with Dr. Manderville; A
                                Curious War Incident; A Ghostly Warning; Personal Beauty; Antics of Watches; National
                                habit of Drinking; Eye Troubles; Catarrh; The Sky; Luck in Old Shoes; Self-Supporting;
                                The Ear; Mythical Snakes; etc., etc. Office 340 West 59th. St., New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> An
                                -interesting article in the February New England Magazine is "The Granite Industry in
                                New England," by George A. Rich. It is finely illustrated by J. H. Hatfield and Louisa
                                A. Hoi man.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Preter, Charles J." TEIform="index"/>Charles J. Preter
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Charles J. Preter, at Union Tillage, O. Jan. 17, 1892. Age 80 yrs, and 10 mo. Br.
                                Charles has been a faithful member of Society for some 54 years. He was born in Nassau
                                Germany. C. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leecth, Charlotte" TEIform="index"/>Charlotte Leecth
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Charlotte Leecth at South Union, Ky. Jan. 23, 1892. Age 90 yrs. 8 mo. and
                                1 day. Sister Charlotte has been a member of our Community for twenty-two years and a
                                virtuous, honest and upright Sister. She loved the life of a Believer. N. C. ..</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clapp, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Elder
                                Charles Clapp
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elder
                                Charles Clapp, at Center Family, Union Village, O. Jan. 24. 1892. Age 84 yrs. 7 mo. and
                                22 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brainard, Marietta" TEIform="index"/>Marietta Brainard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Marietta Brainard, at Canterbury, N. H. Jan. 27, 1892. Age 38 yrs. 3 mo. and 12
                                days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trousdale, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Trousdale
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Martha Trousdale, at South Union, Ky. Jan. 28., 1892. Age 84 yrs. 11 mo. and 5
                                days. Sister Martha has been a faithful member of this Society sixty-eight years. She
                                was lovable, generous and noble. All regretted her departure, as a dear Sister. J. C.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Edwards, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Edwards
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Edwards at South Union, Ky. Feb. 6. 1892. Age 84 yrs. and 8 mo. Sister Mary has
                                devoted not less than sixty years to faithful service in the Community. Of her it may
                                well be said, "Thou hast been faithful over a few things, I will make thee ruler over
                                many, Enter thou into the joy of thy Lord." J. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rhodes, Nazar" TEIform="index"/>Nazar Rhodes
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  
                                Nazar Rhodes, at Pleasant Hill, Ky.
                                Feb. 10, 1892. His former residence was in Tenn. He was in the eightieth, year of his
                                age. From toil he wins his spirit's light, From busy day the peaceful night, Rich from
                                the very want of wealth, In heaven's best treasures, peace and health. J. W. S.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
"Brilliant"   Poppy,  packet ...........................15c.
Roses, Waban and DeGraw, both for............50c.
6 Rare Chrysanthemums,   each 50c.; set $2.50
6 Choice Geraniums, each 25c; set............1.00
Sweet Corn  " Golden Nugget,'  packet.........15c.
Any one not now a subscriber can have
Vick'S Magazine one year free\ -who orders $i worth from us before May ist.
Garden Pea "Charmer," packet.....................15c.
Potato " American Wonder,' per lb,............30c.
Pansies, our superb strain, look almost human   packet.............................................50c.
Extra choice, packet.......................................'-.3c.
JAMES VICK'S SONS,
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
Perfect in Construction.
Artistic in Design.
Matckless in its Light.
Some folks  get
cheated in buying
a lamp.     Nobody
ever gets cheated that
buys the  lamp with
this    stamp,  " The
Rochester." Old eyes
are made new by
its use; its light
issofterthanelectric light, brighter than gas light, and more cheerful than either.
Insist upon seeing the stamp of the genuine,"The Rochester;" and ask for the written
guarantee. If the lamp-dealer has not the genuine Rochester and the style you want, send
to us for illustrated price list, and we will send you (boxed) any lamp safely by express.
ROCHESTER LlItlF CO.,   43 Park Place,  New York,
Inspirational Hymns and Sonys, illustrative of the Resurrection Life and Testimony of the Shakers.
A Shaker's Answer t<> the oft-repeafed
question, "what will become of the World if
all become Shakers?"           Price 10 cts.
A  summary   view of   the    ' Millennial
Church " or United Society of Believers.
It treats of the Rise and Progress   of the
Society, together with the general principles
of the Faith and Testimony.    Price 50 ct>.
Address H. 0. Blinn, East Canterbury, N. H.
MOTHER ANN LEE

A brief account  of
HER LIFE
While   in   England,   and   subsi-quently
in the
UNITED   STATES;
also  her Experience as   a  Messenger
of the
WORD  of  GOD.
Price   10 cts.
OVER FORTY 1892 NOVELTIES.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure*
A cream of tartar baking powder. Highest of all in leavening strength.Latest U.
S. Government Food Beport.
JOHN   F.   STRATTON   &.   SON'S
CELEBRATED
nportersofand Wholesale Dealers in nil kinde o f
MUSICAL     MERCHANDISE,
Violins, Guitars, Banjos. Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas, &c, all kinus of Strings, etc.,etc.
43 & 45 Wlk                                NEW YOKK
onicas, &c, all
43 & 45 Walker St.,
 ngs, etc.,etc.
 NEW YOKK
DO YOU KEEP BEES
If so, send your name and address for a
Free Sample of the AMERICAN BEE
JOURNAL Weekly32 pagesOne
Dollar a year.
Thomas G. Newman & Son,
PUBLISHERS
CHICAGO, ILL.
LIBERAL and MUSICAL.
"Shakes Music".is the title of a book
of 250 pages, beautifully printed and neatly bound. It was published by the Believers of Mount Lebanon, N. Y..
We will send the Manifesto during the
year 1892 and a copy of the Music Book,
to any address for $1.25 postage paid. If
desirable the Book and paper may be sent
to different persons.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury, N. H.
IF you wish  to  advertise anything anywhere  at
any time, write to GEO. P. EOWELL & CO.,
No. 10 Spruce St., New York.
TH VEEY one in need of information on the subject
_Hj of advertising will do well to obtain a copy of
"Book for Advertisers," 368 pages, price one dollar.
Mailed, postage paid, on receipt of price. Contains
a careful compilation from the American Newspaper Directory of all the best papers and class journals ; gives the circulation rating of every one, and
a good deal of information about rates and other
matters of advertising. Address ROWELL'S ADVERTISING BUREAU, 10 Spruce St. N. Y.
Every-Day Biography.
Containing a collection of nearly 1400
brief Biographies, arranged for Every Day
in the Year, as a Reference for the Teacher,
Student, Chautauquan, and Home Circles.
By Amelia J. Calver. A large handsome
vol., nearly 400 pages, handsomely bound;
price, $ 1.50.
"Every-Day Biography," is an outgrowth
of the increasing popularity of observing the
birthdays of noted people.
Nearly 1500 names are here found, representing sovereigns, rulers, statesmen, founders of colleges, institutions, etc., besides
pioneers in every art, science, and profession.
To Chautauquans it will prove invaluable,
since every week will bring some name to
mind prominent in that universal study.
This work will be found a valuable addition to any library or collection of books.
Agents wanted to introduce this, and take
orders for it. Sent by mail, postpaid, on receipt of price, $ 1.50.    Address,
IWLEK & WELL'S 00., 775 BK0ADWAY, New York.
The Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing, exemplified by the principles and
practice of the true Church of Christ.
History of the progressive work of God,
extending from the creation of man to the
"Harvest," comprising the Four Dispensations now consummating in the Millennial
Church.                              Price $1.50
Address H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury, N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>