<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0801" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18780101" TEIform="date">January 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <pb id="p1"/> 
                        <p>Vol. VIII. NO.1 JANUARY. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE
                        UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT CANTERBURY. N. H. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD.' 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT
                        SHAKER VILLAGE, N. 11 N. A. BRIGGS. Publisher.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <p> TERMS OF ADVERTISING. Subscription will begin when order is received.— No back numbers. CONTENTS. The Source of
                        Happiness • . 1 Christian Culture Np. 9 . . 2 Sin No. 1....... 3 The New Year..... 4 Thoughts for Today ... 5 To The
                        Evangel . . . . . ('ause and Effect .... 7 The Dignity t" Humanity . . .8 Procrastination . . . . . " What was
                        original Sin 1* Liberal League Convention . . 10 L'nleavened Bread To my pupils . . . . . 11 The Lord's Prayer ....
                        13 WHEELER & MELICK CO. MANUFACTUHEliS OF Threshing Machines, Horse Powers, Shingle Machines. Horse Forks,
                        Sulkey Horse Itakes, &c. ALBANY, N. Y.. God's hand to help as . . . 13 Is there a demand for tiif. MANIFESTO
                        14 Editorial Notes . . . . .'15 For the Children . . . . 16 Selected...... 19 How to be Somebody If we had 1 ut a
                        Day . . . 20 Work cheerily, Boys . . . . " Farm & Garden Home Topics . . . . .21 Cures for Fits ..... To
                        remove marks from Tables Obituary ..... " Music. Christian Pilgrim ... 22 SHAKER SEEDS BY MAIL! GENUINE SHAKER
                        GARDEN SEEDS. Farm ers and Gardeners get your genuine Shaken GARDEN Seeds directly from the grower. Send for
                        CatalogUE and Price List ready by Feb.. 1. We will send the Best Seeds of all kinds at very lowest cash prices,
                        prepaid by mail. Attention, Fanners and (hardeners! Try us,—Address PHILIP SMITH. Shakers, ^V. T, Mention "The
                        Shaker Manifesto" in replying to advertisements. Address, N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co..N. H..</p>
                        --><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS----Editor. VOL. VIII.—JANUARY, 1878.—No. I.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Source of happiness" TEIform="index"/>THE SOURCE OF HAPPINESS</head><p TEIform="p"> Wishing every one a "Happy New Year," we bring up for consideration, what is most needed by
                            all to make this, and every future year a happier year than its predecessor. To the vast
                            majority, the various indulgences of the -cnses mean happiness ; and with such, there is no
                            propriety in putting limits to the products of those titillations, that reach no higher than
                            the senses. It is nevertheless true, that the perverted indulgences of the senses are the
                            causes of all unhappinesa, and are, in reality, none other than "the broad road that leadeth
                            to destruction." Pleasure added to pleasure, until nature is exhausted ; and nature, even
                            then, pines at its limits, and does not thank God for the boundaries. To "take care of
                            ourselves" means largely to "beware of ourselves ;" and the cup of true pleasure, and the
                            years of real happiness are very strongly tinctured with "touch not, taste not, handle not."
                            In our unusually free country—in America—true freedom, and its happiness are terribly
                            misconstrued ! To the infant in the cradle, obedience to parental control 'S to be of
                            infantile length only ; and then, to do as it pleases, is considered its inalienable right;
                            while the silver years of age, if ever reached, too commonly are left to teach the serious
                            truth, that whoso follows inclination to do as he pleases, becomes the slave of the basest
                            tyrants—the passions. The experience of individuals and of nations ever testifies that the
                            valuable and sacred of all institutions, are made and maintained by the denial of
                            selfishness. By the exercise of self-denial, prosperity ensues. With an increase of
                            self-denials, happier years begin ; a higher life is begun, and a Christian character
                            established. Self-denials make the good citizen ; the excellent government; while the want
                            of them, invariably fills our penitentiaries, State prisons, and brings hundreds to the
                            guillotine or gallows ! Self-denial makes peace, and keeps it lively in families and in
                            nations. The more self-denial, the more happiness ; and we may measure the happiness of the
                            year before-hand, even as we mete out to ourselves "the narrow way" of self-denial. Such was
                            the life of Jesus ; self-denying and heavenly; and "heaven on earth" means sufficiently more
                            self-denial to make it so. With our wish of happiness for the year, we point out Self<pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. denial as the true source of all happiness. To
                            those who are lovers of the world, and sufferers of the penalties it inflicts, we plead you,
                            for an increase in your daily lives, of self-denial. Is there trouble where nome should be ?
                            Use more self-denial. The more you use, the happier home will be, until there will be
                            established in the households of the land, heavens on earth begun. Let us write
                            "Self-denial" over our doorcaps ; and whoever enters with it, will leave all discomforts
                            without.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 8" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN CULTURE. No. 8</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName">WM. H. BUSSELL </persName></byline><p TEIform="p">. Activity. Life is action; death, the cessation of action. But, in its strictest sense,
                            there is no cessation of action, hence, no death. Every particle of matter in the universe
                            is instinct with activity. It enters into combination with other particles, producing the
                            vast variety of forms in the mineral, vegetable and animal worlds, and constituting the vast
                            assemblage of spheres where Divine Love and Wisdom hold limitless sway. There is no limit to
                            growth. Change, or progress from lower to higher forms of life, is incessantly going on.
                            Action is an essential attribute of beauty. The decaying tree gradually ceases to charm,
                            because that which constitutes its life is retiring. The human form may please by reason of
                            the regularity of its various parts, but the magnetic, intellectual, moral and spiritual
                            forces serve greatly to heighten and intensify the beauty arising from regularity of form
                            and features, and, in fact, not only to conceal positive defects, but to cause them to be
                            regarded by many as beauties rather than blemishes. "Bury the dead out of my sight," is the
                            language of even the intensest affection. Anc why? Because that is not the one that was
                            loved so ardently. The smile, the merrj laugh, the kindly word, the eagerness to please and
                            be pleased, in a word, all that constitutes the living and active soul, are gone, and one
                            tcanno be satisfied with the mere shadow s The dead are mourned because that which had power
                            to charm has departed, apparently forever. "The friends of my youth, where are they?" is the
                            cry of many an affectionate heart&gt; and to many only echo answers—"Where are they?"
                            Not so with those whom the divine inbreathings have aroused to a consciousness of the life
                            beyond the seeming death. "They mourn not as those who have no hope." To them the so-called
                            dead are still the living and active, endowed with a higher form of life, and favored with
                            conditions of existence superior to those of the present state. The life of the Christian in
                            its highest stage corresponds to the life of God, which is action in its supremest sense.
                            The Divine action evolves worlds and systems of worlds and sends them forth on their
                            never-ending journeys. It develops therefrom the various grades of life, both material and
                            spiritual, and carries them forward in their continually ascending course. The apostolic
                            injunction,— "Be ye imitators of God as dear children—" applies to Christians as active,
                            creative beings. God never made a hermit, not even a fasting, praying Simon Stylites. "Those
                            who live in pleasures, or lusts, are dead while they live,'' and so also those who under
                            pretense of greater sanctity, lead indolent lives. The Divine Providence has always
                            performed its part in behalf of man. How capacious, and fertile, and beautiful the earth
                            which has been bestowed upon him! But how many indolent ones still occupy it! Is it a matter
                            of wonder at all that so many thousands are destitute of the means to sustain the physical
                            existence, which is the foundation of all life and activity? Is it a matter of astonishment
                            that the grand metropolis of France should for a time have been under the control of those
                            who knew well that themselves and offspring had been wronged, though they knew not how to
                            rectify their wrongs? Or that society even in this land of equality! should sometimes be
                            startled out of its sense of propriety by what so many are pleased to style the foolish
                            movements of the laboring classes? Granted that they are foolish and criminal even, some of
                            them, yet where shall we lay the blame of the manifest folly? When all persons, whatever
                            their rank in society, shall put their hands, heads and hearts to useful work, and keep <pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER IVLAJSTTEHEISTO. them to work, there will be no strikes nor
                            any necessity for them. Universal activity will bring universal wealth—wealth that is worthy
                            of the name—such as blesses man corporeally, intellectually and morally. The church in the
                            apostles' day had an inkling of this truth; and the words of Paul, "If a man will not work
                            neither shall he eat," are in accordance with the soundest principles of justice ¦and
                            economy. If an individual employs his hands in useful labor, he is entitled to bodily
                            support; if he applies his mental faculties to the acquisition of useful knowledge, he is
                            entitled to the benefits arising from such appli- cation ; if he gives his heart to God in
                            the cultivation of every virtue, he will reap the reward of such devotion in "the peace of
                            God which passes understanding;" in power to subject his inferior inclinations and passions
                            to those more exalted and unchanging dispositions that belong to such as have arisen to the
                            serene heights where truth and purity forever reign. All these are the especial prerogatives
                            of every Christian. But, at the present time, there are obstacles to the universal
                            attainment of these blessings. How many thousands are willing to employ their hands in
                            useful labor and yet are unable to do so through no fault of their own. Being destitute of
                            this primary means of culture, they are, as a necessary consequence, deprived, in a great
                            measure, of those that appertain to the intellectual and moral powers. And yet the world is
                            in pursuit of glory and the immortality that accompanies glory! From the grand heights built
                            of human flesh and bones and flowing with human gore, the conquerors of the world Jook down
                            upon it with apparent satisfaction ! With what complacency the rich man looks upon his
                            possessions! "These are all mine, the result of my ingenuity and skill; I have made me an
                            everlasting name, I want no more !" Yet it is true that he "who had not where to lay his
                            head," and who bid his disciples to sheathe every sword but that of truth, now sits upon the
                            throne of infinite love, of peace, and of a stability never to be shaken. His •disciples
                            attain to the same throne by the same means that he did; by an activity that subdues the
                            world of selfishness; that makes the hand the instrument of a clear head and a pure heart;
                            that works for the purpose of making the whole earth a garden filled with whatever is
                            delightful to the purest sense, and will not cease until the reign of peace and love shall
                            become universal. Groveland N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sin, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>SIN. No. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName">ALONZO HOLLISTER </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The Apostle says, "Sin is transgression of the law, for where there is no law there can be
                            no transgressions." God is subjection to law, for there cannot be order without law, and
                            where order is not, there cannot be heaven. The existence of heaven depends upon obedience
                            to those laws, that produce happiness. When Jesus the Christ began his travail in the
                            regeneration, by obedience to the law of eternal life, he commenced to "create a new
                            heaven." Hence, he is the beginning of the new Creation of God, and all who follow in his
                            steps, are co- workers with him, in forming the new heavens, or heavenly order. Confused
                            elements mingled together without order and laws, are called chaos. If it is admitted that
                            God is the fount-, ain of order, it will follow that the nearer we come to God, the more
                            order He requires ; and by so much as we depart from the laws that God ordains for the
                            regulation of our conduct, just so much we depart from heaven, and transgress against the
                            universal economy of sentient life, of which each individual constitutes a part; and
                            transgression is sin, whether willfully, or iguorantly done. Among God's typical people, the
                            High priest was required to make atonement once a year for sins of ignorance. We presume
                            that for their known sins, they made their own atonement, by con3 <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. fessing and forsaking. Sin obstructs the channel of God's blessing, by
                            interpos ing a barrier between the sinner and his Source of elementary spiritual life ;
                            thereby cutting him off' from the tree of life Hence, said a certain seer to the
                            transgressors of old, "Your iniquities have separated between you and your God and your sins
                            have hid His face from you. MEANS OF ATONEMENT. The only way God has provided in compassion
                            for frail humanity, even through His beloved Son, is by confession and repentance. "Not one
                            soul may be forgiven, except he repents," and true repentance includes forsaking the ivrony
                            confessed. It is evident that the spirit which causes a soul to honestly confess sin, is
                            directly opposed to the disposition to commit sin. Consequently the tongue when moved by an
                            honest spirit to confess, becomes as a sword to slay the evil; and so long as the spirit of
                            truth keeps the control, the evil disposition has not power to act; and the certainty of
                            exposure, lessens the power of temptation in many points, almost to cipher. , BUT WHY
                            CONFESS TO MAN ? We do not confess to man, but to God in man. When Ananias deceitfully kept
                            back part of the price, while professing to consecrate his possessions, the Apostle told him
                            he had "not lied unto man, but unto God." Ananias and Sapphira lied unto God, by acting a
                            lie before His appointed order, with intent to deceive His ministers, and were taken away in
                            their sin. By bringing all our sins and useless burdens, and laying them open before His
                            order appointed to hear confessions, we feel them removed, and a new clean spirit comes
                            within, which restrains us from sinning, so long as this honest spirit is preferred. WHY
                            SHOULD MAN OR WOMAN HEAR OUR CONFESSIONS? First; because the Spirit of wisdom and justice
                            requires it. Second; because no soul can find God, and be truly joined to Him, except
                            through union with his fellow man. "Inasmuch as ye have done it unto the least of these my
                            brethren, ye have done it unto me," said the son of God. Hence, if we find a true spiritual
                            union with the Brethren and Sisters of Christ, we find it with him, and through him, draw
                            nigh to God the Father. And there is no other avenue of access to God; for the Son declared,
                            "None can come to the Father, except through me." Jno. xiv. G. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL ORCUTT </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Commence the Qew year with the determination to turn over a now leaf in the volume of your
                            existence, and be- come a self-reformer, and let the determination call forth daily
                            cross-bearing effort. Some persons are always reforming, but never reform ; they are always
                            learning, but never "come to a practical knowledge of the truth." A reform, to be genuine,
                            must be deeprooted, throughout. The whole duty of nan may be comprised in two precepts, viz
                            ; Do that which you should do, and omit that which you should not do. You lave a
                            self-denying work to perform in this probationary life. Begin now. Let your chief aim, your
                            guiding star be purity of heart, otherwise you will fail to 4 <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                            MANIFESTO. obtain real happiness—heaven. Success in the Christian warfare is the result of
                            heart labor, the right improvement of time, the application of energy. "God helps those who
                            help themselves." "Well begun is well half done." Then start fair, that is the first point,
                            and keep in the right path ;—it is plain. Upright walking is safe-walking. It is a fixed,
                            steady aim in the overcoming work that subdues sin, and gives power to triumph in the higher
                            life. Be firm. The winds and waves may beat against a rock, firmly planted in the troubled
                            sen, but it remains unmoved. Be like that rock. Vice may entice. Beware, stand fast at your
                            post. Let your self-denying principles shine forth unobscured. There is glory in the thought
                            that you have resisted temptation and conquered. Your bright example of virtue will be to
                            the world, what the light-house is to the little acts" will have no remorseful shadows over
                            them. Your life will then be real; for only as you grow better, do you really live ; only as
                            your heart advances in purity, does your spirit move on, over the rough sea of nature, to
                            the haven of peace. Enfield, (Joint.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts for today" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR TODAY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL FRASER </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> will guide others have apmariner on the sea, it to the way of safety. Did you ever see those
                            who peared to be the very embodiment of virtue and goodness, in whose presence there was a
                            heavenly atmosphere ? They seemed to you "like an oasis in a dreary desert, like green spots
                            on a barren waste.'' You have desired to be like them, as good and pure. Yon can be, if you
                            will make the effort; you can adorn your soul with such purity. You can make your life so
                            virtuous that you will possess the power most heavenly and divine ! Constant self-denying
                            struggles will enable you to do it. When you have striven earnestly, and felt at the close
                            of the day, that you have been made better by those strivings, when you have overcome some
                            mighty temptation, what a flood of happiness fills your soul to overflowing! Strive to so
                            live, that "life's As a man feels, so he thinks ; as he thinks, so he is. Therefore, watch
                            your heart, your emotions with all diligence, for out of your emotions are the issues of
                            good and evil to yourself and others. Keep physiological law; moral law can then be easily
                            kept. The destiny of nations, communities, and individuals, is in their own hands. Their
                            history is but a chapter in physiology and morals—a photograph of the results of compliance
                            with good or evil emotions. The perpetuity of just governments can only be maintained, by
                            every person being a land-holder ; and land limitations being enforced. Land monopolies
                            breed discontent; they ruined the Republics of the past. Financial laws, schemes, and
                            customs, that enable any man, or set of men to change the value of labor, or property not
                            theirs, are ruinous to -private and public morals : they even strike the land with
                            sterility. Why? A high rate of interest tempts the farmer to skin his land, and invest
                            elsewhere than in Ms farm. Tramps are the results of hard-heartedness ; usurious
                            speculations ; corruption, and blind selfishness. They are a Force, and may become terribly
                            so. <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE SHAKER M-AJSTIIT'ESTO. They render life and property now,
                            everywhere insecure. It is cheaper to feed, than to fight them. Christian sentiment demands
                            that they be decently provided for. Make them and their children landholders, and they, even
                            they, will become the bulwarks of free institutions, useful and productive. Ignore them you
                            cannot ; neglect them, drive them from your doors, and you may be driven from your own
                            doors. Up and be doing, avert the coming storm ! Secure the welfare of others, and your own
                            will be sure. Gentleness, is better than Force.Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the Evangel" TEIform="index"/>TO THE EVANGEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M. and Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. PEEBLES [and] ELVAH F. COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Speed! Zion missionary, speed The gospel light to spread! Afar in distant, heathen lands 0,
                            break the living bread ! Those lands, where nature sweetly smiles, And rich response is
                            given, Those lands, where luxury wealth outvies, And earth seems almost heaven. Fair lands !
                            in all that there could teem To make it paradise. Blest homes ! where man might holy live,
                            And in redemption rise. But ah! the blight that finds him now In idle sin's disgrace, Has
                            spread its dark and shady pall O'er all the human race. We love to sing of spicy isles, Or
                            Afric's burning clime, Of India's brilliant coral reefs, Of Asia's glorious prime. But soon
                            our song is changed and sad, The pensive strain soon hushed, To know that where earth's Eden
                            lies, The higher life is crushed. Crushed in the multitude, where Ignorance has ne'er let in
                            The glowing light of truth that shows How progress climbs to win. We know that hearts in
                            every land Have sought to live to God, Preferring sacrifice, to sin's Relentless chastening
                            rod. But angel mercy, would reclaim The many prone to wrong, And swell in heaven a song of
                            joy That earth might echo strong. All blank were life, without the hope Of immortality,
                            That's born within the human heart, Though buried it may be. God bless the hand that takes
                            the plough? To break the solid clay ! And delves to find the precious ore, Long hidden far
                            away. God bless the sower, and the seed That germinates for good ! And bears the fruit of
                            holiness, The soul's sustaining food. We bless, and angel spirits bless The missionary true,
                            And oft on silent wing we go To help, and comfort you. We place the cord of sympathy In firm
                            and friendly hands, They bear it over ocean wave, And desert-whitened sands. They twine it
                            round your spirit form That often seems alone, Amid the apathy of heart, That knows not
                            meat, from stone. With steady unremitting grasp, We'll hold this cord of love Till to its
                            limit you have gone, And turning, homeward move. We pray, in blended prayer, for heaven: To
                            shroud you in its power, We sing, to call the angel choirs To cheer the lonely hour. And
                            then we send the message glad Across our cable strong, And fancy we can hear you say, "How
                            thrilling is the song!" 0, bright the oriental stars That stud th' ethereal dome! But
                            brighter are the golden gems That light our Zion home. <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. And fair the fruits that grace the land That eastern breezes fan, But fairer are
                            those angel gifts, That Mt. Zion's mountains span. So, we would draw your toiling soul From
                            labor's weary field, (When you have seen the truth take root, And pruned till errors yield.)
                            To share the blessed recompense Of peace, and harmony, Where not a ripple breaks, to stir
                            The calm untroubled sea Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect" TEIform="index"/>CAUSE AND EFFECT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName">WATSON ANDREWS </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> If the forty days fast, the years of travel in suffering, the agonies of Gethsemane and
                            death-throes of the cross of Jesus, were necessary, being causative for the production of
                            the first Pentecostal wave ; and the long years of similar toil and sufferings of Ann Lee
                            until her excessive labors in the works of God often reduced her to the helplessness of an
                            infant, were similarly producing causes of the second; can Tve reasonably expect a third,
                            and as we hope a far greatter out-pouring of the spirit and power of God, without similar
                            labors and preparation, by those who are to be the ministering agents in such an important
                            event ? Verily the storm rages and the ship is engulfed in the waves. If the Christ is
                            asleep, is it not our duty to awaken him ; if we do not, whose fault will it be if we perish
                            ? We have reason to hope a far more wide-spread work in the coming Pentecost, as the number
                            of qualified agents is far greater. But if when the "midnight cry is heard," the work of
                            supplying our lamps with oil has to be entered into, should we not fear that the doors will
                            be closed before we are ready ? If separation from all worldly influences, and untiring
                            labors for the love and power of God, together with the purity of life and self-denying
                            habits of the founders of this gospel, scarcely sufficed to give us the victory ; and the
                            seekers of to-day can hope for no other means by which to gain their salvation than the
                            adoption of Christian life practices ; where is the safety for any if we relax our labors or
                            our zeal? If our zeal has already so cooled that we are satisfied with but one meeting a
                            week, instead of one or two meetings each day, as in the early years of our travel was found
                            a necessity for protec- tion ; and if our spiritual tastes have become so perverted that
                            business, politics and worldly amusements can satisfy, instead of "that bread which Cometh
                            down from heaven ;" shall we be able to give that bread to others ; can we hope to cultivate
                            those tastes in others, which we, by neglect, have lost? Can we minister what we do not
                            possess? a love we do not feel? a zeal we do not manifest ? Or has human nature become so
                            changed, that now, self-indulgence is to be the means of salvation, instead of self-denial?
                            Brethren and Sisters, "let us not deceive ourselves with such delusive hopes ; what we sow
                            that shall we also reap.'* Like will produce like, every time, at least in spiritual
                            organisms. Do not tell me that we are aged and weak, that we cannot engage to much purpose
                            in the worship of God : "Bodily exercise profiteth little ; but God seeketh such to worship
                            him as worship in spirit and in truth." Though we can but barely crawl to the church room,
                            if 7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>we come there full of the love of God and for one another, (instead
                            of the last newspaper gossip on our minds,) which was gained by a full, hourly consecration
                            of all our energies to tin; cause ; depend upon it, each one so coming, will add a glowing
                            brand to the burning, and all so uniting, will ere long produce a fire that will ''kindle
                            the dry leaves afar off." North Union. Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dignity of humanity" TEIform="index"/>THE DIGNITY OF HUMANITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName">ANDREW BARRETT </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Is there any joy greater than that experienced by any one when they unselfishly help
                            another? There are some men so low down in the scale of humanity that it is said they would
                            not have the smell of their clover go into the high-way, for fear that othe*s will get
                            something that they own without paying for it. Others it is said envy the bees the honey
                            they find in the flowers, grown on their land and take without leaving some pay. But we may
                            call this imaginary. A man whose heart does not respond to any act of kindness of his
                            neighbor is no longer a man. He has passed the line of manhood. And we must give him a place
                            at the stall with others of his kind. True dignity of character and manliness through all
                            the vicissitudes and trials of life, are very different things than a generous nobility at
                            the hour of death. Let me see the man who takes life's burdens upon his shoulders early in
                            the morning, and travels with them until nature calls for rest; without a frown upon his
                            countenance, nor a murmuring word from his lips, working merely from the sense of duty.
                            Don't we respect that man ? Don't we look with hope, to see him fill some important station
                            in the drama of life ? Though his coat may be patched, and his trowsers made of two kinds of
                            material, what of that! We see the mind, and that speaks louder than broadcloth, velvet or
                            satin. It must and will have a place. Out of the humble stations of the blacksmith, the
                            tailor, and the shoe maker what have we seen rise up ? We have seen minds who have governed
                            the destinies of nations ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Procrastination" TEIform="index"/>PROCRASTINATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL ORCUTT </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Procrastination is a besetting sin. Putting off, putting off! How many things are lost or
                            periled by putting off. It is never safe to defer until tomorrow, that which should be done
                            today. Of all the losses in consequence of delay, the greatest is the loss of the soul ! The
                            Holy Spirit, and the still small voice of conscience, warn us of the danger of delay : and
                            we see there is danger. We are on the stormy sea of life; we see the darkness gathering
                            round, and the waves rolling high. We look for refuge, and hear the cry, "Come un- to me !"
                            "Now is the accepted time ;" "now is the day of salvation." Do we heed the call of Christ,
                            the good pilot ? or, are we waiting for "a more convenient season ?" It will never come. We
                            will not be saved unless we are anxiously willing to be saved. Put off, and we will go down,
                            we will be lost! Hesitate not. Today, if we will hear his voice, "harden not our hearts." He
                            nowhere promises to receive us tomorrow; tomorrow may be too late. He insures a safe passage
                            in the "Gospel Ark," which is provided with "bread of life and waters of salvation" in
                            abundance ; but lie accepts only "working hands." "Work out our own salvation." The voyage
                            is from time to eternity, and the Ark never "puts back." There are billows of Pride, rocks
                            of Infidelity, quick-sands of Destruc-. tion and whirl-pools of Mammon to encounter, hxit
                            the great Pilot knows them all, and He will safely guide us to the port of rest—all who put
                            their trust in Hun. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Removing stains" TEIform="index"/>Removing Stains</head><p TEIform="p"> If you have been picking or handling any acid fruit, and have stained your hands, wash them
                            In clear water, wipe them lightly, and while they are yet moist, strike a match and shut
                            your hands around it so as to catch the smoke of the sulphur and the stains will disappear.
                            8</p></div2><pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What was original sin?" TEIform="index"/>What was Original Sin?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Griffin, A. L." TEIform="persName"/>A. L. Griffin</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Indiana, Richmond" TEIform="index"/>Richmond, Ind.</dateline><p TEIform="p">[The following extracts are copied to show our readers the leaven that is working among
                                those not of our body. The writer has been a reader of The Shaker, and we leave all to
                                witness how well he sustains his scholarship. Ed.] In relation to his creating a certain
                                individual, placing him in a literal garden, a few years ago, and calling his name Adam,
                                and giving him a law, and saying to him if he disobeyed he should surely die, 1 would
                                say that the Garden of Eden is to be considered as the various powers "and passions of
                                the mind of each one of us in our primeval state. The command is that we are to
                                cultivate and cherish all the powers of mind to his honor and glory. But to go out of
                                this state or condition of innocence and purity, or Eden-like state, is to transgress a
                                plain law that God lias written in letters "1' living light upon the heart of every
                                intelligent creat" ure; and the whole story of Adam and his family is a figurative
                                representation of us in our entrance into being. The Garden of Eden, then, is only a
                                condition of soul, a paradise, and not a piece of ground, for it is said that a flaming
                                sword was placed at the gates to guard the tree ol life. This flaming sword is the sword
                                of God's spirit, and not a literal sword. The tree of the knowledge of good and evil
                                explains itself to any intelligent mind. The knowledge of good or evil can only be
                                understood in a spiritual sense, and it is represented in the figure as a tree bearing
                                fruit, and eating fruit therefrom is the gratifying of our lusts; and If we put our
                                minds upon those gratifications, they become corrupt, and die a spiritual death, or
                                separation from that purity and innocence which we were in when we came into the world.
                                If we thus alienate ourselves from the blessings of God's spirit, we fain would eat the
                                husks that the swine had left. I believe there are just as many Adams now, and ever have
                                been, as there were prodigal sons, literally, and no more nor less. The meaning of
                                prodigality is the Adam-like or rebellious spirit in man. Each of us has two natures,
                                and our spiritual life is controlled by whichever nature we cultivate. These two natures
                                are represented in the persons of Cain and Abel. The first characterizes a wicked, cruel
                                and murderous spirit, full of sin and transgression. The second represents a meek and
                                quiet spirit, obedient to the teachings of the holy spirit, a state or condition of
                                acceptance with God. So it is plain that if we choose to go down to ruin by earning the
                                mark of Cain, the fault is our own. All of us can fall or rise, as we choose, and the
                                theory that another individual has fallen for us is entirely groundless. Therefore, the
                                text, as in Adam all die, so in Christ shall all be made alive, means that as many of us
                                as practically emulate the character of a rebellious, or Adam-like spirit, shall die a
                                spiritual death and that eternally, unless we accept the offers of divine grace, and
                                return with a penitential heart to our Father's house. (I mean by death, an eternal
                                separation from the joys of heaven.) It is imposaible for us to get into that typical
                                Adam, literally, in order to sin, so it is very plain that we only get into the spirit
                                represented n the type. But we must all personally know of getting into the spirit of
                                Christ practically, in order to be made alive again after we have sinned. "When T say
                                Christ, I mean the law of the spirit of life, that was in Jesus of Nazareth. That is the
                                only power that can set us free from the law of sin and death, and this spirit of Christ
                                is our Savior, always has been the Savior of the world and is universal in its
                                character, eternal in its duration, infinite in power, is with God and is God, and was
                                fully manifested in his son, or is in all his obedient sons and daughters. This spirit
                                of Christ is dispensed as a light shining bright in the inmost recesses of the heart of
                                every one who will receive it. Each one of us then is an Adam to all intents and
                                purposes, and subject to the law of God individually; and if we eat forbidden fruit, the
                                flaming sword will cut us off from the never-ending joys of the paradise of God. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My friend:—Your welcome letter of the 10th..." TEIform="index"/>My friend:—Your welcome letter of the 10th...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers, December 22, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y. Dec. 22,
                                1877, A. GRIFFIN</dateline><p TEIform="p">My friend:—Your welcome letter of the 10th but. is at hand, also the article on Original
                                Sin. The views expressed therein, so nearly coincide with my own, that I have little
                                disposition to cavil. Truly, we fall by yielding to the corrupt propensities of a
                                fleshly mind, which are the greatest Devil we need to fear; or we rise into newness of
                                character, by ft spotless life of virtue; even aJesos overcame the nature by which lie
                                was tempted in all points, even as we are. That we are all Adams and Eves by nature, and
                                that we need the resurrecting power of the second Adam, to elevate us above our
                                rudimental conditions, are self-evident truths. The germ of this quickening Spirit is
                                the breath of life, breathed into the intelligent part of every rational being, as an
                                aspiration for a higher life, aided by the redeemed Spirits from the heavens, which will
                                at some period, prompt man to become a living Soul. In your article, on "Original Sin"
                                you explain death (spiritually) as an eternal separation from the joys of heaven. Do you
                                mean the old theological heaven, in some perpendicular height? Or, do you mean the
                                heavens of virtuous souls, united in the bonds of gospel love, as children of one
                                household? These Heavens are not confined to location. Nor is hell confined to some
                                extreme end of the universe. Individuals and societies, create their own heaven, or
                                hell, whether on Earth, or in the spirit world. Again dear brother, what provision do
                                you make for the benefit of degraded spirits, who enter the spirit world nnregenerated?
                                Are such eternally separated from the joys of heaven? Are they not rational, accountable
                                beings, still free agents? Have they no opportunity for growth or reform, by retracing
                                their 9 <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 1O THE SHAKER IVLAJSJTir'JES'rO. missteps, and rectifying
                                their wrongs? This subject is inexplicable, in the light of general sectarianism; an
                                inexcusable defect in common theology, but deeply interesting and important, to all who
                                sympathize with mortals in unfortunate conditions. Our conceptions of the Parental
                                attributes of Deity, forbid us to exclude the most fallen penitent, from a part in the
                                tender mercies of God, either here or hereafter. I am your friend, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>Chauncy Dibble </byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberal league convention" TEIform="index"/>LIBERAL LEAGUE CONVENTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans </byline><p TEIform="p"> Ed. Shaker: As you are aware, I attended, with Bro. Emil Bretzner, the convention at
                                Rochester. It was a very interesting assembly. It was composed of representations of all
                                parties, sects and creeds, religious and anti-religious—yet, in reality, it was
                                religion, goodness and truth that brought them together and rendered the Convention a
                                truly harmonious Congress of Liberals. And the greatest variety and contrariety of
                                theological and antitheological views and feelings—the most extreme presentations of
                                opposite and antagonistic problems and propositions—Infidel, Spiritualistic, Orthodox
                                and Christian. In one thing all were united—that all theology, in the Civil Government,
                                is a violation of true, pure Americanism. All agreed that the founders of our Government
                                intended to form a constitution that was not Church and State Christianity, nor Church
                                and State antichristianity, but simply Humanitarian, as free from any thing offensive to
                                a Jew, Mohometan, Materialist, Atheist, Hindoo, or Chinese Pagan, as to a spurious, or
                                real Christian. </p><p TEIform="p"> P. S. On Saturday, a Spiritual Medium (female) spoke in a trance state for an hour and a
                                quarter. Good, sound, Shaker theology. Does not this show that Spiritualism and Orthodox
                                Infidelity are one and the same ? Babylon is fallen. The Rochester Rappings have done
                                good service in the course of human progress. </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Brother G. A. Lomas, I inclose recipe for making unleavened bread..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Brother G. A. Lomas, I inclose recipe for making unleavened bread...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, December 2, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Dec. 2. —77</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Brother G. A. Lomas, I inclose Recipe for making unleavened Bread. The wheat is the
                                starting point. The wheat must be home ground, or you will not have home made bread. We
                                might as well go to Moody and Sankey for pure Christianity, as to go to a worldly miller
                                with our wheat to grind; much less to buy thfl flow to make Shaker whole wheat, or
                                coarse ground, unleavened bread—That is the bread I talk about. The Sisters insist that
                                the unleavened bread cannot be made of the fine ground, or mercantile flour—I believe
                                it. I quite agree with the God of Israel, that the first step in the work of human
                                redemption is to make and eat good bread. "Beware of the leaven of the Pharisees" should
                                not be made of no practical effect by a pretended spiritualization— Give us the physical
                                and physiological good of the Law, as a basis^ or substance for soul truths—I want
                                something solid and substantial—want to inherit substance—I want to see the redemption
                                of the Stomach, redemption of the land; and the redemption of the creative forces of man
                                and woman. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unleavened bread" TEIform="index"/>Unleavened Bread</head><p TEIform="p"> 1. Good clean wheat, coarse ground in a Centennial Hand Mill. 2. Scald one third of the
                                flour in boiling milk. When cool, mix in the remaining two thirds of flour. 3. Mold
                                lightly, with a little dry flour, add- ing a very little salt. 4. Bake in a hot oven, on
                                the oven bottom.</p></div3><pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To my pupils" TEIform="index"/>TO MY PUPILS</head><p TEIform="p"> My Dear H-, I am pleased to know that what I have written respecting God's word has
                                drawn forth some criticism from, at least, one of my pupils; in replying to which, the
                                opportunity is afforded me of addressing them all. It will never do for Shakers to cross
                                swords, or write merely to controvert another's statements, or to appear smart; but
                                always to enlighten each other: In this spirit I propose to partially analyze what you
                                have written and show its distinctive features—not only for your sake, but for other pu-
                                pils who have desired a further word from me on the subjerts embraced by you. I would
                                first advise all of moderate reading and education, to adopt the hypothetical and
                                interrogatory mode of criticism if they wish to avoid exposure. What I mean by
                                hypothetical, is conditional; thus : "If I understand you, do not such conditions follow
                                ? If your first position is true, is not the second false? It seems to me that both
                                cannot be true etc." By this mode of criticism any subject may be discussed without
                                offense, exposure or breach of union, and ful| as much light shed, as can be by the
                                categorical or dogmatic mode, which is generally offensive : I hope all my pupils will
                                bear this in mind. I will further add that none can be absolutely certain of the
                                legitimacy of their conclusions on complex subjects, without conforming to the canons of
                                logic, which demand that we never impute a word to the criticised that was n-t used by
                                them : never sum up conclusions until the propositions have been reduced to their
                                simplest elements. That nothing new be added—and no phrase used of a merely sarcastic
                                nature etc. Had my pupil and criticiser observed these few rules—it would have been of
                                much benefit to him. It now becomes my duty to point out some of the mistakes made in
                                the criticism under review. (1.) In your quotation of the fixed throne being a chimera;
                                it seems you failed to observe that it was only applicable to the Infinite; but admitted
                                in the finite. (2.) In reply to the question : "Where is God's Kingdom ?" I would repeat
                                the words of Christ: "It is within you"—in all humans. God is ever there to direct, to
                                approve or condemn every word or act of the earth life. But there is another Kingdom :
                                Christ says, "I go to prepare a place for you1' This place is doubtless his Kingdom in
                                the spirit world—of which, the one we enjoy here, is but the shadow. . Two conditions
                                are absolutely necessary to the existence of a Kingdom ; first, a King, second,
                                subjects; it cannot exist in the absence of either. We ha\e Christ and Ann for our King
                                and Queen, who must ever appear in their vicegerents and appointees—reign and rule, so
                                long as God's Kingdom shall exist on eartii. This is impregnable and as unchangeable as
                                Deity himself. Any person in theKingdom, who aspires to lead, and prates about personal
                                rights, in contradistinction to the gift of God in the Lead, has need to go to school
                                bodily ; such are not out of their a. b. abs— have not yet learned to spell Baker, Brier
                                nor Cider, and should at once g) to the foot of the class. (3.) You speak of "following
                                the teacher a. round the infinite circle, only where he variesfrom it." The teacher must
                                inform his pupils, that an infinite circle is an absurdity,—space is infinite, but with
                                a circle around it, it woulf? be finite. (4.) Are you not mistaken in assertinff that
                                your teacher says: "God is everything and everything is God ?" He has uniformly en
                                deavored to impress his pupils with the fact; that there are two and but two substances
                                in existence—Spirit and matter. That thought was the attribute of one, and extension the
                                attribute of the other ; they being contradictory and not interchangeable. (5.) My pupil
                                now proceeds to the task of God-making. (Excuse me, I would avoid saying this if I
                                could.) He firstly speaks of a "force not always visible," should have said, never
                                visible Secondly: he says, "this force is motion, life." We may here ask, if this force
                                is the mo. tion, what C uised the motion ? Thirdly : he then uses the term God to
                                represent this force or motion, and further says it is God—then says, this God appears
                                to him to be an element or part of infinity"(!) Is not this, when analyzed, simply
                                declaring that force is an element—motion is an element—life is an element and God is an
                                element and only apart o' infinity ? <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. This
                                part then, is God No. 1. Next in order comes God, No. 2. whom my pupil sets up in a
                                personal form and locates him in the skies, in order to show his contempt for him, when,
                                a personal God, is the very one whom he should first respect and obey : For "he that
                                receiveth whomsoever I send, receiveth me, and he that receivetl) me, receiveth him that
                                sent me.''— Ckrist. Thus we see the immediate persona' comes first—the remote personal
                                second—the impersonal third : This is God's order : Thus •s the finite swallowed up in
                                the infinite : "Hid with Christ in God." Thirdly my pupil gives us the modus operandi,
                                by which he makes God No. 3. whom he tells us he recognizes, and to whom he bends the
                                knee in worship and prayer. This feat is performed by taking only two of the attributes
                                of Deity, which he personifies. Now if my pupils prefer an Attributal God, instead of
                                the being who possesses them, I would suggest the propriety of adding a few more.
                                Humility, might come in along with the attributes of Justice, Mercy, Charity and others.
                                But in choosing two qualities only, for his God, he has secured himself from
                                punishment—perhaps this was his object. He says: "This is tine God whose voice we hear*
                                * * This is the God we will worship and pray to." A God that can neither hear, speak,
                                understand, reward nor punish(!!) I would much prefer the God of Moses—the author of the
                                Ten Commandments. In fact, I would prefer a fetich at once ; and bend the knee to the
                                rising sun ! I would really be glad to know how many of my pupils were included in his
                                plural pronoun we, would hope not many. (6) But further; he says: "The application of
                                the term God, to any compound of ideas is a pun that does for conceited theologians to
                                quarrel over; but [over which,] lovers of truth have no time to waste." Thissarcastic
                                fling at theologians is not in good taste : seeing my pupil has placed himself in their
                                category, by compounding his God of two ideas—the very thing he ridicules; and, being •
                                lover of truth, it logically follows, that he has no time to waste over the God of his
                                own creation ! We should all be careful after having set a trap, not to put our own hand
                                in it. (7.) After quoting '¦'¦Vox populi Vox Dei.'' He says : "With highest regard for
                                our veteran Elder, but none the less distaste for the sentiment, we cannot discover in
                                what sense the phrase is false." And then mistakenly adds : '.'according to our
                                teacher's definition, all voices must he God's voice." Except if you please, the free
                                agent man, who can speak either God's word or his own : of whom Locke says, if not
                                wholly free, is free enough to do or not to do, to speak or not to speak—to obey God or
                                disobey, and is thus accountable for every act or word. It is God's word when directed
                                by the operation of his spirit on the higher consciousness—and man's word when induced
                                by .selfishness or the lower propensities. Jesus spake from the former, hence his word
                                was the word of God. It seems to me this is plain enough for the "simple mind." Now.
                                what is really meant by Democracy and a vox populi government, is, the popular voice of
                                the people as opposed to the unpopular—the majority against the minority. Two voices
                                either singly or in the aggregate, that are opposed to each other, cannot both be God's
                                voice. It will not be disputed that there are more persons, the world over, who speak
                                from the selfish stand-point, than those who do not, whence it logically follows that "
                                Vox populi, is not Vox Dei'' or the voice of God. This conclusion is irrefutable. Does
                                my pupil now see the point ? It was the popular voice that crucified Christ, and today
                                it is opposed to his kingdom on earth. (8.) My pupil's definition of Democracy and
                                Theocracy is obscure and unsatisfactory. I will try to define them. First: A Democracy
                                is a government of men, with the power lodged in the body and controlled by the popular
                                will. Vvlgaris quotidian us : hence the protempore head is appointed by the power below.
                                It is a government in which every man wants to be on his neighbor's shoulders : and the
                                aspirant for headship, who has the most money, and is the most skillful in manipulating
                                the vulgar herd succeeds, whether he be best or worst. It is a scramble for the top
                                shelf, governed entirely from the selfish stand-point, and in the event of equal forces,
                                war comes in as a necessary adjunct and final arbiter, with all the passions of the
                                Beast and whore let loose upon the world. This is Democracy with its X3 <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 13 clothes off. Do we want any of it in Christ's
                                kingdom? Second: A Theocracy is the government of God, in which the head is appointed
                                from a. bove. A government in which the selfish and passional nature of man, can have no
                                voice, nor controlling influence. "Even to this man will I look, saith God, who is of an
                                humble spirit and contrite heart." The headship is thrust on him against his will—He
                                seeks it not. He lays down hTs life for God and his fellow-creatures. Party and division
                                ;ire the life of Democracy—but the same is the death of Theocracy. They are antipodal;
                                what is life to the one is death to the other. But I am asked: "Of what avail is a the-
                                ocracy or its God, if the people fail to recognize it?" Ans : Such as fail to recognize
                                it, have no business in it. It is a day of freedom—either accept the kingdom and be
                                subject to it, or reject it and depart from it. These are the kind spoken of by the
                                Apostle whom he says : "Not discerning the Lord's body, eat and drink damnation : for
                                this cause many are [spiritually} sick among you, and many are asleep." 1. Cor. ii.
                                29.—Six persons joined together forming the Lord's body, with a Godappointed head, are
                                better than (iOO or 6000 with a vox popvili head. You think "Aristocracy and Theocracy
                                are closely allied," when they are asunder world-wide. The one seeks power of his own
                                will, the other shrinks from it. The one rules by his own will, the other by the will of
                                God. The one gratifies the passional nature. The other crucifies it. In fine they are
                                unlike in everything, allied in nothing. Let me notice further : you say, "the quali-
                                ties of our leaders are much higher appreciated when strongly tinctured by the essence
                                of Democracy, making them like unto the people."' Should the head seek to be like the
                                body, or the body like the head? Should Christ's followers seek to be like him, or he
                                seek to be like them? Should Christ bear rule, or the body bear rule ? O ! blind
                                infatuation ! as well allow your own body with its passions and carnal desires to
                                control your head, as to allow the popular voice of the multitude professing membership,
                                to be the governing power of the body of Christ. But I am asked : "Suppose the head
                                should fail ? what then ?" Even should this occur, it would only hasten entire
                                dissolution to make a head of the fingers and toes—this done, it would not squirm long.
                                We have examples enough in typical Israel to fully satisfy this inquiry. But I must
                                close. What I have written has not been prompted by any selfish motive ; my days, yea
                                even my very last hours of earthly existence, seem fast closing over my head; and I
                                trust all my dear pupils will ac- cept these words from me kindly, as they are kindly
                                given.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, Harvey L." TEIform="persName">Harvey L. Eades</persName></byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, South Union" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky</dateline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lord's Prayer" TEIform="index"/>The Lord's Prayer</head><p TEIform="p"> Did you ever think, short though it is, how much there is in it ?—Oh lit is beautiful! And,
                            like a dia" mond in the crown of a queen, it unites a thousand sparkling gems in one. It
                            teaches all of us—every one of us—to look to God as our parent—"Our Father." It teaches us
                            to raise our thoughts and desires above the earth—"Who art in heaven." It tells us that we
                            must reverence our Heavenly Father—"Hallowed be Thy Name." It breathes the
                            saints'reward—"Thy Kingdom come.1' And a submissive and obedient spirit—"Thy will be done on
                            earth as it is in heaven." And a dependent, trusting spirit—"(Jive us this day our daily
                            bread." And forgiving spirit—"Forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass
                            against us." And a cautious spirit—"Deliver us from evil." And, last of all, an adoring
                            spirit—"For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory, forever Amen."—Nature'*
                            Arcana.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's hand to help us" TEIform="index"/>God's hand to help us</head><p TEIform="p">What is the hand of God, but the power that is within us from Him? The power to will and to
                            do what ig right; to stand fast in the front of temptation; to walk securely in the strength
                            He gives us? We grasp his hand, when we use this power. The true order of life is the
                            government of reasonThis must rule over all the lower things of sense. The appetites and
                            passions must be held in complete sub. jection. (Jod is with us and in us; gives us of His
                            strength, and keeps us in safety so long as we maintain this true order of life. If we will
                            not maintain it, He cannot do it for us; and the same law must rule in restoration and cure,
                            as in normal order. We must use the strength God is always giving, and use it for ourselves.
                            We would be only machines, if He merely lived in us the mainspring of all our actions.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Arthur, T. S." TEIform="persName">T. S. Arthur </persName></byline></div2><pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is there a demand for THE MANIFESTO" TEIform="index"/>Is there a demand for THE MANIFESTO
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert" TEIform="persName">GEO. ALBERT LOMAS </persName>, EDITOR. SHAKERS N. Y.</byline><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO Is there a demand or a necessity foxit ? Among the thousands of
                            publications, periodicals, and general literature, printed in modern times, there is not
                            anything of a religious character,'that bears any comparison with the entire testimony of
                            The Shaksb Manifesto. There is not one that we know of, that encourages sexual purity, to
                            the extent it demands of every follower of Jesus, the Christ. Does not the world need a more
                            radical Christian testimony than any other religious periodical has as yet pre- sumed to
                            advocate ? Are not the lusts of the flesh, through sexual impurities the roots of all the
                            deviltry operating in the world today ? And are not these impurities winked at by the
                            general churches of the land ? and a stillness that can be felt operating with the religious
                            press, representing these churches? Where this side of Mosaic statutes, can be found a
                            severer denunciator of the perverted uses of the generative functions, than in Shaker
                            testimony and its organ The Shaker Manifesto ? Where will be found more manifest rebukes,
                            that more are not born with sound minds in healthy bodies, than in the poverty of material
                            necessary to make good Shakers ? Where else is the organ that testifies of the two natures
                            of humanity, patterning the first man Ad- am, and the second man Christ? or which teaches
                            that the generation of the species human is of the earth, earthy— yet unchristian ? or that
                            makes celibacy on the part of the whole church of Christ a necessity with all its
                            Communicants? We cannot point to such a periodical. We are familiar with the fact that the
                            Roman Catholic Church has an enforced celibacy in several of its orders ; but that it as
                            truly deals with marriage and the propagation of the species as sacraments of the Christian
                            Church, and implies a necessity that the Church shall make the marital bond ! The Shaker
                            Manifesto is the only exponent of the gospel of that radical Christianity which declares
                            human propagation right—rightly conducted—by "the children of the world ;" and against this
                            propagation, by these parties, guided by Mosaic statutes, utters no vjord of protett. And it
                            is the only advocate of the superior life, that the kingdom of Christ, of heaven, is peopled
                            with celibates for this kingdom's sake; that while "the children of the world marry," and
                            engage in human generations, however properly, the children of the resurrected Christ
                            neither marry nor propagate, but live as did Jesus, strictly, virgin celibates without
                            exceptions. There are other periodicals that advocate community of goods as does The Shaker
                            Manifesto, but none more so ; none advocate the measures of peace more strongly, nor as
                            radically, when viewing all contentions and wars as the consequences of "the lusts that war
                            within your members." Still there are numerous organs of societies God be praised,
                            advocating more brotherhood and less inequalities ; less of wars and their causes ; and more
                            of the heavenly relations on earth. But until there shall burst forth a herald of testimony,
                            as deep and deeper in all that constituted the Primitive Christian Church, with the it <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 15 added self-denials, economy and organizations
                            of the Second Appearing of the Christ Spirit, than does The Shaker Manifesto proclaim, we
                            hold its issue a necessity demanded for a fuller salvation of the people.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Congratulation" TEIform="index"/>CONGRATULATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We bow respectfully to our patrons, appearing as we do in Vol. 8. with form and features
                                expressive of improvement. We congratulate all our readers upon the signs of our
                                progress, and are happy to state that all is the work of Shaker hands. We ask for a
                                thorough perusal, kind criticism, and happy reflection. Our object is to do good alone.
                                We have no right to harm any one's feelings nor would we do so. Our first object is to
                                promote radical, Christian religion among all people, regardless of name or
                                denominational persuasion. We congratulate you and ourselves that we have been
                                vouchsafed the encouragement that permits us to go on rejoicing in the good cause.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit communication" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT COMMUNICATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The spirit communication published in Nov. Shaker, purporting to come from Mother Ann
                                Lee attracted very wide attention, and has been commented upon most profusely, and
                                always favorably. Had the most astute Shaker of today written that message, it would not
                                have ¦embraced more of the radical, early faith than it did. Many mediums have persuaded
                                themselves to believe that Mother Ann influenced them to write out messages for her.
                                These would almost invariably contain clauses that would imply recantation of her
                                mission, instruction to "progress" out of so much sexual purity ; aiming at the
                                destruction of the foundational pillars, etc. But here is one we can afford to believe
                                to be genuine, because it agrees with the communications we receive from time to time ;
                                and the fact that it came through a boy-medium, an entire stranger to us as a people,
                                out on the Pacific Ocean, yet true to the letter of our principles ! Spiritualists and
                                Spiritist Free-lovers, take notice !</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Continuous thank offering" TEIform="index"/>A CONTINUOUS THANK OFFERING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> That was a beautiful paragraph in N. Y. State Governor's Proclamation, that suggested,
                                amid "religious services, happy family reunions and social enjoyments incident to the
                                occasion, the poor and unfortunate be remembered with generous liberality." When our
                                love and thanks to God shall alway take this form of expression, there will be more
                                practical religion in the world than Bibles, Prayer Books or Churchal ceremonies can
                                ever inaugurate. "I prmy thee then, said Abou, Write me as one who loves my fellow men;
                                And the next night he came again, With a great awakening light, S/inuinij the )innen
                                ichom ] km of Cod had blest, And lo! Ben Adhem's name led all the rest!"</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angels of judgment" TEIform="index"/>ANGELS of JUDGMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The signs of the times indicate that the detective and judgment angels are active, and
                                are spreading their warning cry to the yet unexposed defaulters to honest instructions.
                                The various cities of the Union are being visited, and we hope for the continuance of
                                abode to these ministrants of justice. Let all <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 16 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. "flee from the wrath to come"—let the honest remain so ; and let the
                                dishonest confess and repent. "God is not mocked !" Strange that men and women will
                                commit themselves to a career of crime, which, if concealed from mortal eyes for a few
                                years, works in them corruption of humanity, arid is sure of exposure at immortal courts
                                !</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberal League" TEIform="index"/>LIBERAL LEAGUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> An account, too short however, of the doings of the Liberal League Convention, from the
                                pen of Elder F. W. Evans, will be read with a curious pleasure. As we followed the
                                proceedings, in type, we could not well help thinking of a menagerie of noble, wild
                                animals. Each had his or her roar, and nearly every tout' and color was presented. We
                                are glad to learn, there was one chorus, which they all had learned sufficiently well to
                                sing together—Distinction of Chwch and Slide Governments—and may thai chorus and its
                                reverberations never be hushed!</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rarity" TEIform="index"/>"A RARITY."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> "A good Shaker is a rarity ;" was the remark of a kindly disposed neighbor. Wonder not
                                at it. "A good Shaker," means, synonymously, "a perfect Christian !" One who lives in a
                                state of continual self-abasement, self-sacrifice, in behalf of others. No desire nor
                                time for selfgratification nor recreative pleasure, until serving God by saving souls
                                becomes gratifying and recreative. Picture to yourselves the most thorough type of a
                                follower after Jesus ; one walking in the footsteps of Jesus' life, and you may safely
                                point out such as "a good Shaker" however rare.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moody and Sankey" TEIform="index"/>MOODY AND SANKEY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Elder Evans means no disrespect, we are sure, by the remark upon their kind of
                                Christianity. Any party who aims to resurrect humanity, and does make them better shall
                                have a "God bless" from every Shaker heart; just as Paul does in his attempts, and those
                                who follow Paul. Hut Paul, Moody, and Sankey are apologists for the flesh : and the
                                genuine life of Christ is not found in the gospel they preach. Paul found the people un-
                                equal to a full cross against the flesh, and for a virgin life ; so he "'fixed up" a
                                gospel that has better pleased the worldly mind ever since. Just so with too many
                                evangelists today. They preach part of Christ, and adulterate the true gospel. Let Moody
                                live the life Jesus lived, and Sankey sing the self-denials and hates of tlie beloved
                                Apostle, and in these, preach from the spirit of Christ, and the world at large, so
                                stirred by their appeals now, would soon get over the curiosity and look upon them as
                                they now look upon the Shakers—very good doctrine, but very unpalatable !</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be noble" TEIform="index"/>BE NOBLE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName">BY THE EDITOR</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The children are not forgotten by any means; neither through neglect nor through an
                                abundance of else to do and to think of! They must have a department in every number. We
                                will begin the series in this volume, by saying, that your friends are desirous you
                                should be interested and profited. One of the children's friends has written, that "the
                                    <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. first step towards being instructed in any
                                good thing, is to become thoroughly interested." I am confident you all would like to be
                                considered noble ; and the first step towards being so, is to be true to think and act,
                                as you have been taught is right; and while making few or no mistakes, you will grow up
                                to be noble men and women. The little boy who raised a stone to kill the toad, thought
                                he heard something speak to him, "that it was a wrong act," and he did not throw the
                                stone. It was conscience that spoke to that boy, and it will speak to you too. One boy
                                was at work in a linen shop, and his employer wanted him to help stretch a piece of
                                linen, to make it longer, so as to get more money for it. "I cannot do it!',' he cried,
                                "for it is wrong to do so!" His employer discharged him, stating he would never make a
                                salesman ; but he grew up a godly man, and was none other than Dr. Adam Clarke, of whom
                                your friends can tell you, a great deal of nobility for which he was noted. Be kind to
                                those who need help; and who cannot easily help themselves. Not long since, a
                                School-house in the city of New York caught fire. One noble boy remained, until he saw
                                all the little fellows were safe, and then, choking with smoke, carried in his arms a
                                poor, crippled boy, whom he induced to sit still, under promise that he would save him;
                                and he did save him! The School authorities summoned this noble fellow before them,
                                spoke very many good words to him, and presented him with a valuable medal! But the
                                noble feelings he can always have that he so helped the needy, are worth more than all
                                medals! It was a noble little girl, (who after became a very noble woman,) who begged
                                that some naughty boys would stop teasing and stoning a deranged woman, telling them
                                that "it is somebody's dear mother, may be!" And not another stone was thrown, nor any
                                further disrespect shown. Conscience will be near you, if you do not drive it away by
                                many acts of disobedience; but too oft this is the case, and it is left to stand afar
                                off, like a reproving angel, who cannot get nearer because of repeated acts of
                                rebellion. See what happens, oftentimes to those who are not noble enough to be obedient
                                to what they know is right: Three boys stood close by the Hudson river ; one boy
                                suggests that they all go in swimming; two agreed to do so, the other said he had
                                promised his mother he would not go in swimming unless she knew of it. The other two
                                laughed at his noble stand to obey his mother. They went in swimming; and thence into an
                                old boat; the boat turned over and both boys were drowned. It was afterward learned,
                                that these two boys had given their parents the same promise of the noble boy who kept
                                his, and saved his life. Be noble, dear children in all things.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Elizabeth, In reading 'The Shaker,' I observe many good things for grown people..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Elizabeth, In reading 'The Shaker,' I observe many good things for grown people...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, December 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Dec.
                                1877</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elizabeth, In reading "The Shaker," I observe many good things for grown people; but
                                little children hardly come in for their share. Be sure, the editor has a "Children's
                                Grotto," and some other little tokens that childhood is remembered, but would not a
                                short story be nice for some weary mother to read to her little ones, for pleasure to
                                them, and a much needed rest to herself? You have often promised to help those like
                                me—and I am only a little larger girl— when I would knock, so I want to write a story
                                out of whole truth, and then knock for criticisms; but I will only tell what my eyes
                                saw, and ears heard, as wise folks say. To be sure I interest the children, I shall
                                imagine many of them clustered about me in a listening attitude: Little friends, I will
                                repeat to you what I have just told my teacher. I will tell you only truth, for I was
                                there, and saw and heard all I will tell you. Just in front of the house where I lived,
                                when about ten years old, were some low spruce trees ; low, because they had not grown
                                tall since placed in the yard for a shade. In one of these, a little brown sparrow had
                                built a nest, in which she had laid three tiny, spotted eggs. You may be sure I watched
                                the old bird, and saw all she did that young eyes could see, for I knew that dear little
                                birdlings were the natural result of those eggs, and don't you think I laid many girlish
                                plans of feeding them, and coming into selfish ownership of the little family. I waft 17
                                THK <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE SHAKER never'apt to be behind when selfish pleasures
                                were to be enjoyed, so you can see how much I am like the little boy or girl before me,
                                who wants to own something all to his or her- self. One quiet Sabbath morning, when
                                stillness was as real as noise could have been, I heard the sparrow mother making
                                decided notes— shall I call it scolding? that is not a pretty word, but a robin was
                                striving to get possession of the nest, and I tell you, the brave mother sparrow, was
                                stoutly defending her rights. The conflict w:is short, and sharp, when the naughty
                                robin, as I then thought, flew away. My poor, dear sparrow, how she panted, and how good
                                she seemed to me, that she would not desert her little eggs, though sadly persecuted.
                                That is just like any good mother who loves her children dearly. I was still at the
                                window in an upper loft, when three, robins—instead of one—returned, and oh, such a
                                battle as followed ! Well, the result was, in a very short time, my sparrow was
                                vanquished, and hanging by the neck outside the nest. When peace was restored, for the
                                robins left the premises at once, as if guilty, or in fear of the Sheriff—several small
                                branches were taken from the tree, and what do you think we found? The nest secure upon
                                one, and the poor mother made fast thereto, by several horse hairs, securely twisted
                                about her neck, and fastened to small twigs ! She was dead, for in some mysterious
                                manner she had lost her life while seeking to defend her home against those bold
                                intruders. Would you have thought it? Others examined the case, but if I had not been
                                present, I might have felt just as you; so been left to wonder how it all came about. My
                                dear little listeners, I would like to talk longer, but our editor makes us afraid to
                                write long stories; but this is a true one however short. Now run and do some good thing
                                for the dear mother who is with you, and I will talk with you again, if you will like to
                                have me. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Forest, Jeannette" TEIform="persName">Jeannette Forest </persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor, As my age places me among the fathers..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Editor, As my age places me among the fathers...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, December 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Dec.
                                1877</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor, As my age places me among the fathers, And as good fathers always love to
                                please the children, I have wondered if the boys and girls would not be interested with
                                some account of my former life, as a sailor, and the events which conspired to bring me
                                to my peaceful home with the Shakers. I offer some inci- dents connected with my
                                experience, hoping, by so doing, to do a little good to those for whom I feel a father's
                                love and interest. We will commence with the description of one little Coral Island in
                                the midst of the Pacific Ocean on which we staid about nine weeks. Its position is about
                                4 deg., North latitude, 157 West longitude, from Greenwich, London, in England. The
                                width of the Pacific Ocean is stated by Geographers to be ten thousand miles, and its
                                entire length from North to South nearly or quite a thousand miles greater than its
                                width. O, it is a vast Ocean! We have sailed on its waters, weary days, months and
                                years; from the latitude of sixty degrees South, in doubling Cape Horn, to that of
                                fifty-two degrees on the North West coast of America. But to return to our Coral Islands
                                whose existence we first learned when a boy, about twelve years of age, from reading
                                "Fanning's Voyages." Fanning, as perhaps some of the boys know was a Seal-man from
                                Stonington, Conn, and visited many of the islands in the Pacific Ocean, situated in the
                                South Temperate, and South Frigid Zones, for the purpose of obtaining the skins of the
                                Fur Seal and other fur-bearing amphibious, animals, that were very plenty in these
                                islands. These Seal men used to take their furs to China, and exchange them for teas and
                                silks, which they shipped to Europe and America at an advanced price. It was while
                                making a passage from the islands where he had collected his cargo of fur seal skins,
                                that Fanning discovered the island that now bears his name. He went ashore in his small
                                boat, and found the cocoa nuts growing so near the shore, and so abundant, that his
                                boat's crew by forming a line, were able to pass the nuts from one to another, until
                                their boat was filled. He remained but a short time at the Island, and proceeded on his
                                way to China. Fanning's brother, afterward visited the island and remained three months;
                                collecting Beech de Mer, or Sea Slug; a substance that looks very much like an old india
                                rubber MAJsranffiSTO. <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKBE MANIFESTO. 19 shoe. We have read
                                that the Chinamen put it in their soup. After this preface we will relate the cause of
                                our being on this island, and what transpired there; classing our future correspondence
                                under the title of the Autobiography of a Quondam Sailor.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM G. LIBBEY </byline></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam Sailor, chapter I" TEIform="index"/>CHAP. I</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We belonged to a whale ship, called the Wm. C. Nye, of New London, Conn. She was one of
                                the ships destroyed by the pirate Shenandoah, in the Pacific Ocean, after the close of
                                the Southern Rebellion. At the time we were in her, she was a fine, strong ship, well
                                fitted, and manned by a crew who were mostly young men, and natives of Connecticut.
                                Their intelligence, and general good conduct was above the average of whaleship crews,
                                with whom we have sailed. We visited a group of islands in about 9 degrees South
                                Latitude and 137 degrees West Longitude, where we remained about a week, obtaining a
                                good supply of bananas, sweet potatoes, crook-neck squashes, cocoa-nuts, bread fruit,
                                and a large number of swine. The last mentioned, were the occasion of our calling at
                                Farming's Island. We sailed from the group of islands, whose position we have already
                                given, towards the Equator, working to the westward under easy sail, a strong current
                                setting the ship in that direction. We fed our swine on cocoa-nuts, and having only
                                enough to keep them for a few weeks, a fresh supply must be procured to keep them alive.
                                Knowing that cocoa-nuts were plenty on Fanning's Island, our officers 'decided to visit
                                it and procure a supply. As soon as we learned that our ship was to call at this Island,
                                1 felt a strong desire to make a home among its trees, which we had seen in passing on a
                                former voyage. Let me now respectfully ask liberty for a more frequent use of the
                                personal pronouns, I and my, not so much to express selfish possession, as to make my
                                story more familiar. Our island settlement was on a community basis, for all things
                                there were free, and very common too. My reasons for leaving our ship for this desolate
                                island, were of a religious nature; while there were other causes ihat had some weight
                                in my decision to leava&gt; the ship, my religious motives were the most weighty,
                                tipping the reasoning scale in favor of forsaking all my little earthly gear, and going,
                                nearly destitute upon this speck of a Coral Island, uninhabited, desolate, and more than
                                one thousand miles from any human beings, civilized, or savage. With so many miles
                                between me and all others of my race—with my little Bible too—from which I could get so
                                much religion—wouldn't I be good? Ah, but I did not realize then, that desolate islands
                                could never hide one from his own thoughts ! I had intended to go alone, but wishing my
                                brother John tA have my chest, books, clothes, tools, bed, &amp;c. I informed him
                                one night, in our watch, of my intention to leave the ship, and become a hermit on the
                                island we were then approaching, and asked him to stay and take possession of my outfit.
                                He seemed surprised at my undertaking. I shall never forget with what scorn he rejected
                                my proposal for him to pursue the voyage ! His answer came squarely: "I won't go any
                                further in this ship unless you do. If you go on this island, I will go too." [To be
                                continued.]</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="lesson" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><p TEIform="p"> When a man chooses the rewards of virtue, he must remember that to resign the pleasures of
                            vice is part of his bargain. To think kindly of each other is good; to speak kindly of each
                            other is better; but to act kindly one towards another is best of all. The love which does
                            not lead to labor will Roon die out; and the thankfulness which does not embody it-self in
                            sacrifices is already changing to ingratitude.</p><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to be somebody" TEIform="index"/>How to be Somebody</head><p TEIform="p">Don't stand sighing, wishing and waiting, but go to work with an energy and perseverance
                                'hat will set every object in the way of your success flying like leaves before a
                                whirlwind. A milk and water way of doing business leaveR a man in the lurch every time.
                                He may have ambition enough to wish himself on the topmost round of the ladder of
                                success, but if he has <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> not the goaheaditiveness to pull himself up
                                there, he will inevitably remain at the bottom, or at best, on the very low rounds.
                                Never say I can't, never admit there is such a word; it has dragged its tens of
                                thousands to poverty and degradation, and it is high time it was stricken from our
                                language ; but carry a whole lexicon of I cans and I wills with you, and thus armed,
                                every obstacle in the way of your success will vanish. Never envy your neighbor his
                                success, but try and become like him, and as much better as you can. If at first you
                                don't succeed, don't wilt down with despondency and I can't, but gird on the armor of I
                                can, and my word for it you will.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we had but a day" TEIform="index"/>If We Had But a Day</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dickinson, Mary Lowe" TEIform="persName">Mary Lowe Dickinson </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> We should fill the hour with the sweetest things If we had but a day; We should drink
                                alone at the purest springs In our upward way; We should love with a life-time's love in
                                an hour If the hours were few; , We should rest, not for dreams, but for fresher power
                                To be and do. We should guide our wayward or wearied wills By the clearest light; We
                                should keep our eyes on the heavenly hills If they lay in sight; We should trample the
                                pride and the discontent Beneath our feet; We should take whatever a good God sent With
                                a trust complete. We should waste no moment in weak regret If the day were but one, If
                                what we remember and what we forget Went out with the sun; We should be from our
                                clamorous selves set free To work or to pray, And to be what the Father would have us
                                be, If we had but a day.</p></div3><div3 type="aphorism" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We ought as much to pray for a blessing upon our daily rod, as upon our daily bread" TEIform="index"/>We ought as much to pray for a blessing upon our daily rod, as upon our daily bread
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Owen" TEIform="persName">Dr. Owen</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> We ought as much to pray for a blessing upon our daily rod, as upon our daily
                            bread.—</p></div3><div3 type="aphorism" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we accustom ourselves to self-denial" TEIform="index"/>If we accustom ourselves to self-denial
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bond" TEIform="persName">Bond </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> If we accustom ourselves to self-denial, we break the force of most temptations.—</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work cheerily, boys" TEIform="index"/>Work Cheerily, Boys</head><byline TEIform="byline">From the <persName reg="Ohio farmer" TEIform="persName">Ohio Farmer</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Do your work bravely and cheerily, boys, Whatever the duty may be; Work thoroughly done,
                                without bluster or noise, Is the kind that's delightful to see. Then rouse in the
                                morning with never a plea For 'a few minutes longer' in bed; But up! like the wide awake
                                boys you should be, With so many pets to be fed. Your chickens have called you, and
                                called you in vain To come with their oats and their corn; And the roosters proclaimed
                                in their cheeriest strain That their breakfast time comes with the morn. And the little
                                white rabbits with tender pink eyes Look timidly out from their nest : I know they are
                                watching for two little boys To bring them what rabbits love best. Then up and be
                                stirring! I care not how much You whistle and sing at your work: If you throw your
                                good-will into all that you touch, You will never be tempted to 'shirk.' So whatever you
                                do, boys, though hard it may be, Do it cheerily, bravely and well; Then you will be boys
                                most delightful to see, And men who will make their deeds tell!</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Improved bloom" TEIform="index"/>Improved Bloom</head><p TEIform="p">Powdered charcoal strewed thickly at the base of plants in blooni; will increase the
                                richness of the flowers to no inconsiderable extent.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lice on plants" TEIform="index"/>Lice on Plants</head><p TEIform="p">The fumes of tobacco is the best curative of lice and other insects on house-plants. Set
                                a little smoking tobacco on fire under the plants, and let the fumes be directed thence
                                to all parts of the plant. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curculio" TEIform="index"/>Curculio</head><p TEIform="p">We tested the plan of strewing tomato vines under plum trees, as a preventive of the
                                curculio; and on a tree that we have invariably lost all, or nearly every plum, we had a
                                nice quantity of most beautiful fruit. We shall practice the simple provision.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Melons" TEIform="index"/>Melons</head><p TEIform="p">A dry, warm season has proved the very best to develop melons, in size and flavor. We
                                wish to render praise, in especial manner to the variety of muskmelon known as "Sill's
                                Hybrid," as foremost in the estimation of all who tested it hereabouts. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cut the feed" TEIform="index"/>Cut the Feed.</head><p TEIform="p">A recent test of the difference of cut and uncut fodder, resulted in fa- vor of one ton
                                of cut hay, straw and stalks being worth a third more than the uncut, as food; and the
                                waste saved by cutting, pays for the cutting. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Potatoes as cattle food, will probably come into common use this season..." TEIform="index"/>Potatoes as cattle food, will probably come into common use this season...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Potatoes as Cattle Food, will probably come into common use this season, in
                                        those districts where heavy crops glut the local markets and MAJNTrFICSTO. <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE 8HAKF.E 21 heavy freights preclude distant ones. In
                                        this connection the results of a series of experiments by Dr. Wolff, a German
                                        chemist, may be profitably instructive to some of our readers. He experimented
                                        in raw and cooked potatoes to two cows, together with hay and rape-seed cake.
                                        When fed on cooked potatoes the animals did not give as large a quan* tity as
                                        when fed upon raw; but the milk made nearly a third more butter, forty-two
                                        pounds of milk having been required to make a pound of butter in one case and
                                        only twenty-seven pounds in the other.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Rural new yorker" TEIform="index"/>Rural New Yorker</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To prevent moss from growing on young fruit trees it should be removed by..." TEIform="index"/>To prevent moss from growing on young fruit trees it should be removed by...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To prevent moss from growing on young fruit trees it should be removed by washing with
                                weak lye, or thin lime whitewash, or strong soapsuds ; or it may simply be scraped off,
                                if thick, and the bark then washed with soapsuds. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A reader of the Maine Farmer makes a statement respecting the value of ashes as a                                     fertilizer..." TEIform="index"/>A reader of the Maine Farmer makes a statement respecting the value of ashes as a fertilizer...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A reader of the Maine Farmer makes a statement respecting the value of ashes as a
                                fertilizer; and says he is acquainted with an instance in his own vicinity, where
                                unleached ashes were liberally applied to a field more than twenty years ago; and their
                                good effects over surrounding land, to which they were not applied, are still plainly
                                visible. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If every farmer made it a rule, rigidly adhered to, to keep stirring the soil..." TEIform="index"/>If every farmer made it a rule, rigidly adhered to, to keep stirring the soil...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If every farmer made it a rule, rigidly adhered to, to keep stirring the soil not only to
                                destroy weeds, but to improve the land, farming would be so suddenly advanced that it
                                would amount to almost a revolution. Three important advantages are secured by this
                                simple operation; clearing the land of weeds, mellowing it and enriching it.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ventilation" TEIform="index"/>Ventilation</head><p TEIform="p">All the disinfectants that can be used in sick rooms, unless accompanied with good
                                ventila tion, are useless, or at least comparatively useless. Ventilation _/frs, in all
                                cases; this is of primary impor tance and should never be forgotten.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oatmeal" TEIform="index"/>Oatmeal.</head><p TEIform="p">—Oatmeal contains the largest amount of nutriment of any cereal. A man could live and
                                grow fat on a quart of milk and six cents' worth of oatmealper day. Persons who wish to
                                live economically can thus reduce their expenses to seventy-five cents per week.
                            -?*?</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If the sufferer from sore and enlarged joints..." TEIform="index"/>If the sufferer from sore and enlarged joints...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If the sufferer from sore and enlarged joints in the feet will bathe the
                                        parts with iodide of ammonia he can be relieved as speedily as I have been.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American Farm Journal" TEIform="index"/>[American Farm Journal. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are not innocent..." TEIform="index"/>We are not innocent...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We are not innocent when w« do anything to harm ourselves.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. C. </byline></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why are cultivated flowers called Florist's flowers..." TEIform="index"/>Why are cultivated flowers called Florist's flowers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Why are cultirftted flowen called Florist's flowers? BecMM they owe tlieir
                                        variations to the skill of florists, and not to the ordinary processes of
                                        nature. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="U. S. Agri. Report" TEIform="index"/>U. S. Agri. Report. </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Paris Journal states..." TEIform="index"/>A Paris Journal states...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A I'mis Journal states that the bad smell and taste of Butter may be entirely removed by
                                working it over in water mixed with Chloride of Lime. Take a sufficient quantity of
                                water to work it in, add twenty-five to thirty drop! Chloride Lime, for every ten lbs.
                                Butter. When thoroughly worked in this solution, it should be worked again in pure
                                water, when it will be as sweet as when first made.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cures for fits" TEIform="index"/>Cures for Fits</head><p TEIform="p"> 1. For a fit of passion.—Walk out in the open air: you may speak your mind to the winds
                                without hurting any one, or proclaiming yourself a simpleton. 2. For a fit of
                                Idleness.—Count the ticking of a clock: do this for one hour, and you will be glad to
                                pull off your coat the next and work at anything.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove marks from tables" TEIform="index"/>To Remove Marks from Tables</head><p TEIform="p"> Hot dishes sometimes leave whitish marks on varnished tables, when set as they should
                                not be, carelessly upon them. For removing them, pour some lamp oil on the spot, and rub
                                it hard with a soft cloth. Pour on a little spirits, and rub it dry with another cloth,
                                and the whole mark will disappear, leaving the table as bright as before.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Obituary</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Littlefield, Betsey" TEIform="index"/>Betsey Littlefield
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Littlefield, Betsey" TEIform="persName">Betsey Littlefield</persName>, at West Gloucester,
                                Nov. 6, aged 70 years and 7 months. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Style, John" TEIform="index"/>John Styles
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Style, John" TEIform="persName">John Styles</persName>, Poland Hill, Maine, November 1, aged
                                G2.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Yarrington, Clinton" TEIform="index"/>Clinton Yarrington
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Yarrington, Clinton" TEIform="persName">Clinton Yarrington</persName>, 34 years of age,
                                while crossing the Rail-Road track was struck by the cars and instantly killed at South
                                Union, Ky., November 17.</p></div3></div2><pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian pilgrim do not falter" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN PILGRIM DO NOT FALTER. From the
                            Spirit of John Bunyan</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName">James G. Russell </persName>. Enfield, N. H</byline><p TEIform="p"> Christian pilgrim, do not falter : Dost thou dread the towering Cross ? Take it
                            quickly, bear it meekly, And thou wilt in truth rejoice. One has borne the cross be fore
                            thee—Tasted 22 <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER death's most bit ter cup, Give thy self,
                            like him in 2. Christian pilgrim, do not falter : Are there Lions in the way? Heed them not,
                            they cannot harm thee, Let not fear thy heart dismay. Thine Example, bright and lovely
                            Passed these dreaded monsters here. Be like him in faith abounding, Pass them without doubt
                            or fear. 3. Christian pilgrim, do not falter : Is Apollyon coming on? Seize thy sword,
                            prepare for battle* Here's a victory to be won. Tho' the strife be fierce and bloody, Keep
                            thy zeal a burning flame ; One has conquered this Apollyon— Thou canst now achieve the same.
                            4. Christian pilgrim, do not falter : 5. Hastthou reached the Shadow'd Vale ? Tho' with
                            death-like terrors streaming, Let not now thy courage fail. He who walked this vale before
                            thee. Braved its dangers all alone ; Trust in God thy Heavenly Father, He will uow protect
                            hid own. Christian pilgrim, do not falter : Dost thou fear the river's flow ? One has
                            entered here before thee, Thro' these waters thou must go. Oh ! the glories that await thee
                            Just ahead on yonder shore ! Christian, great is thy deliverance,. TIk&gt;u art blest
                            forevermore.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meneeley Co. of West Troy New York..." TEIform="index"/>Meneeley Co. of West Troy New York...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Meneeley Co. of West Troy N. Y. are competing with the U. S. government in civilizing
                                the Indians! Government sending destructive, horror making cannons; Meneeley Co. sending
                                sweet sounding Church Bells ! Meneeley Co. were a long way ahead at last accounts. We
                                are using a number of The Bickfobd Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory
                                indeed. Being among "the wonders in this age" of machinery, their utility and expedition
                                in business should be expe. rienced by all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of
                                wood variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or
                                rely on the metal ones offered us by Washburn, MoenCo. Please read advertisement
                                ofWASsoN and Martin si \ral times. They form an enterprising and reliable firm. The
                                Estey Organ scarcely needs our praise. We have many of them in our Societies, and every
                                one is a "Home Delight." We further say, that Cluett has furnished us. We are at a loss
                                to speak as yet, of the best Water Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the firms
                                of Leffel &amp; Co. and X. F. Burnham, who enter into friendy competition in our
                                columns, are both most honorable. Every farmer will yet be his own Miller; grinding out
                                his "religious bread" as Elder F. W. Evans would say; then they will send for one of
                                Sedgebeer's "Non. pareil." Send for a circular DOW. Van Deusen's Tree Label and
                                "Business Cards" are a desiderata long looked for. Send for a Circular and sample. The
                                U. S. Piano Co. enter a challenge to other man. ufacturers and salesmen. We mean to make
                                ourselves more acquainted with their instruments. People wilj have Pianos, and they will
                                look where to get them, in The Shaker Manifesto. By reference to our Br. Philip Smith's
                                advertisement, it will be seen that Farmers, Gardeners, Amateurs, and "the rest of
                                mankind" can get genuine Shak_ er Garden Seeds by mail, at the very lowest cash prices.
                                Try the seeds, coming immediately from the grower; it will pay you. The Hon. Clute Bros,
                                of Schenectady,N. Y.. present most excellent encouragements for parties wishing En.
                                gines, Boilers, etc. We know, also, of the "Clute Plough" being the best plough yet
                                created, for al&gt; kinds of cross ploughing. jg-Parties answering advertisements:
                                Will you please mention The Shaker Manifesto? We have been acquainted with F. T. Van
                                Patten for more than twenty years, and assure our friends, who need Broom Machinery, or
                                anything in his line of business, that they will receive the best of satisfaction. Send
                                for his Circular. A Useful Apparatus : John Bunyan said, that "an idle boy's or girl's
                                bead was the devil's workshop.'' (Jet them the "Keystone Self-Inker" with* complement of
                                type. See Adv. Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that there are un- scrupulous persons,
                                who, realizing the solid benefits of judicious advertising, will use it most freely on
                                some useless or worse than useless articles, and soon retire with fortunes of ill-earned
                                gains. But we can stil* point to thousands who by a wholesome judicious judgment, have
                                used advertising to their exceeding profit! and to the most creditable advancement of
                                useful materials. Sucli, we believe our patrons to be.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We repeat, any parties sincerely desirous of learning more of "The People, CALLED SlIAKEUS
                            ;" uANNL,EE.and iikr people ;" "Community Principles," etc. may be accommodated with
                            speakers, by reference to this office.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steadiness of purpose" TEIform="index"/>Steadiness of Purpose</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> In whatever you engage, pursue it with a steadiness of purpose, as though you were
                            determined to succeed. A vacillating mind never accomplishes anything worth naming. There is
                            nothing like a fixed, steady aim. It dignifies our nature, and insures our success. Who have
                            done the most for mankind? Who have secured the rarest honors ? Who have raised themselves
                            from poverty to riches? Those who were steady to their purposes. The man who is one thing
                            to-day and another to-morrow—who drives an idea pell-mell this week, while it drives him the
                            next—is always in trouble, and does nothing from one year's end to the other. Look at and
                            admire the man of steady purpose. He moves noiselessly along, and yet what wonders he
                            accomplishes. He rises, gradually we grant, but surely. Dipping nails in oil, or even
                            wetting them with water or spittle greatly prevents splitting of the lumber, and the bending
                            of the nail. The longer linseed oil is kept for painting purposes the better, in regard to
                            its drying qualities, transparency and durability. Almost any sting—except the sting of
                            conscience- may be cured by applying Spirits of Turpentine.</p></div2><!-- 
                    <pb n="25" id="p27"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> SHAKER'S "WINDOW" SASH LOCK. .1 new device for securing ventilation, SIMPLE AND EASILY MANIPULATED. ADJUSTABLE
                            TO ALL WINDOW BASH, SAFELY HOLDING EITHEB AT ANY POINT, WITHOUT MARRING PAINT OK VARNISH. It consists of a clamp
                            bar let loosely into the left side of the window frame, haying two small lever eccentrics attached thereto by •
                            screw or rivet, at the center, where the sash comes together. The strip which holds the sash in place is let on
                            the eccentrics, the lever or points only being risible. If a parting strip is used it should be cut oft' at the
                            bar. so that the top may be used at pleasure By pressing on the points the position of the eccentrics are
                            changed so as to press against the lower sash, causing the catch on the end of the bar to pull against the top
                            sash, thus locking them so tight that it is impossible to move either without opening the points. Also, the
                            eccentrics, if desired, may be put on the left face of each sash frame, in which case they will perfectly lock
                            and tighten the sash and destroy all shaking and rattling by winds or otherwise. In this case the eccentrics are
                            visible. The strip must be sawed off from the lower eccentric upwards, the thickness of the eccentrics, so that
                            it will work against the under frame. When the sash is too loose to be tightened by the eccentric, tack two bits
                            or a strip on the right-hand edge. In short, it is the simplest, safest and best sash lock in existence, and
                            needs only to be seen to lie appreciated. Sample sent by mail for twenty-five cents. South Union, Logan Co., Ky.
                            S. J. RUSSELL. SCHENECTADY, N. Y.. Builders of Marine,. Stationary and Portable Steam Engines and Boilers. Shaker
                            Broom Handle Lathes, (the best Lathe in Market.) Engines for Farm work, cutting and steaming feed, driving
                            \Threshing Machines, fr., from \ horse, to 10 horse power. Send for Price List. THE POOR OLD TRAMP. Is the title
                            of a new and beautiful song and chorus, by Will L. Thompson, Author of the famous "Gathering Shells from the Sea
                            Shore." Dealers are ordering it by the thousand. The whole country will soon be singing "The Poor Old Tramp."
                            Price, with handsome picture title, 40 cents.—Pittsburg Dispatch. Published by W. I.. THOMPSON & CO.,
                            East Liverpool. Ohio. <pb id="p28"/> Washburn & Moen ManTg Cc. WORCESTER, MASS. Jtmuftciurns East cf
                            Chicago, of PATENT STEEL BARB FEMCM& A STEEL Thorn Hedge. No other Fencing so cheap or put up to
                            quickly. Never rusts, stains, decays, shrinks, nor warps. Unaffected by fire, wind, or flood. A complete barrier
                            to the most unruly stock. Inpassabje by man or beast TWO THOUSAND TONS SOLD AND POT UP DURINGTHE LAST YEAR. For
                            sale at tha leading hardware stores, with Stretchers and Staples. Sciwl for ill actuated Pamuhlet Also
                            Manufacturers of all kinds of IRON AM) STEEL WIRE. A Speciality made of TINNED BROOM WIRE. Satisfaction
                            guaranteed. Samples by mail for $1.25. Agents wanted to canvass in all parts of the United kjites. Addreit S.
                            ¦). WB8SXLL, Patentee, South Union, Ky. TRY SHAKER'S CORBETT'S SARSAPARILLA, li'or Purif3-ing the Blood; best
                            Medicine at all Seaons. Ask for it at your Druggists. Maynard & Noyes Boston. SUAKEB FLANNELS &
                            KNIT GOODS, CORN BliOOMS & BRUSHES. OUR CORUNDUM POLISHER, A Tool for Cutting. Leveling and Polishing
                            Furrows in a Mill Stone. With the ttse of this tool the miller can make ;i uniform, level and .smooth furrow,
                            and do the work in one-tenth the time required to do it with a Mill Pick. It is acknowledged by millers usinjj
                            them to he the most practical and lahor-savinjr Tool for the miller's use. The frame is iron, with wood handle.
                            The cutting face is a composition of recently discovered mineral, the hardest and fastest cutting material known
                            to the .scientific world. One of these tools will last, in an ordinan mill, from one to two years, and can be
                            refilled at a cost of $2. By sending amount you will save expense. PRICE $3. 50. Manufactured by WEED &
                            CO.. 13 AY TOM, O. IiiiOOlVI MACHINEEY AND Wheelbarrow Factory, F. T. VAN PATTEN, Proprietor, MANUFACTURER OF
                            BROOM WINDERS, VISES, SCRAPERS, TRIMMERS, PLANTERS AND WHEELBARROWS. S 'HENECTADY, JS". Y. P. O. BOX, 26. NOTE.
                            I desire to call attention to the extreme simplicity of all machines made by me, also to the fact that they are
                            all made by experienced workmen, and from the best seasoned timber. £g|P»Answering advertisement: Please mention
                            The Shaker Manifesto. Address, if. .A.. Hriggs Shaker Village, K. H <pb id="p29"/> Improved Shaker Mangle. This
                            Mangle is very heavy and strongly built?; runs smoothly, and performs EXCELLElsTT WORK AND IS EASILY KEPT IN
                            REPAIR. Even to Laundries already supplied with STKAM CYLEXTDRIOAIj M-AISTGrLESThis machine is a very necessary
                            addition, as it is more economical. We confidently recommend this as the BEST BOI MANGLE IN THE COUNTRY. N. A.
                            BRIGGS, Shaker Village, N. H. <pb id="p30"/> JS It is so simple in const ruction and runs so easily that a
                            child can operate it. flgp It has the straight, self-netting needle, our improved shuttle, with a perfect
                            tension, which does not change as the bobbin becomes exhausted. 83All the wearing points are adjustable, and it
                            combines every desirable improvement. >86y Every Machine is sent out ready for use, after being
                            thoroughly tested. Notwithstanding the GREAT REDUCTION TN' PRICKS we continue to use the best material and
                            exercise the greatest care in their manufacture. VICTOR SEWING MACHINE CO., Western Branch Office, 381 Wost
                            Madison St., Chicago, HI. PEIITCIPAL 0TT1C1 and Manufactories, Middetcwa, Com. ??????»»????????«»?«??????????
                            Improved Shaker Washing Machines. For Laundries. Hotels. Asylums and other large Institutions. Preference given
                            in Report of Judges at the Centennial Exhibition. Medal and Diploma Awarded. N. A. liri^irs Shaker Village. N.
                            II. j'ttfi'itlctl .1 nlif 2'.). 1*77. John NvikiTKi„ i •: v. Manufacturer of SHAKER BROOMS, Shirley Village,
                            Mass. A&BNT V tit "The Shaker"—monthly-60 cts. per annum. "The Divine Afflatus"—10 ets. pet copy. "The
                            Shaker's answer"—C> ets. per copy. "The Divinity of Humanity"-:? Ct8. per copy. Liberal discount in
                            qua.iititii'«. A Practical Christmas Present. $2 Self-Inker Keystone l'nss, loo Printing Letters, Roller, Ink,
                            Reglets, Lends, Cards, Type, and Outside Case. All for $3. Stamp for Catalogue. "\V. "C. Evans, 50 X. Ninth St..
                            Phila., l'a. CORN BROOMS & BRUSHES. N. A. BRIGGS, Shaker Village, N. H. <pb id="p31"/> J. SEDOEBEER'S
                            PATENT NONPAREIL SelfSharpening, Reversible Motion erughlnnftUd Grinding Farm, Boue and Drug Mills. 12 sizes.
                            Send for free illustrated descriptive Catalogues and Prlco-ligt. Address J. SEDUEIIEICK, PainesvilUs • MMMIM
                            BELLS. The genuine THOY CHURCH KKLI.S known to the public since 1826"Inch have ac [uired a ropu'.alion uuequaled
                            by any, and a sale exceeding that of fur others. No agencies. P.O. address, either Troy or West Troy,N. Y..
                            MENEELY&CO. W K sell a First-Class J-ia, cheaper than any othei louse in Ani'tici. Have nn Agents, hut
                            sell DIRECT TO FAMILIES AT FAC1ORV PRICfc. and warrant 5 years l'i.utos sent for trial at our expense.
                            Illustrated Circular Free, giving full Mtt'cular*. and names of over 2,00.1 I'ankers, Meichants r.nd F milirs
                            using our Pianos in every State ami Territory. Address, XT. S. PJ4JV" f'O-. S tO JtrotKltrni,, X. T. 520
                            KNITTING MACHINE. The NEW BICKFORD FAMILY KNITTING MACHINE all complete for $20. (former lowest Price $30-1
                            Delivered at any Express office in the U. S. or Cana.a Free, on Receipt of Retail Price. Send for New
                            Descriptive Circular. A splendid chance for AGENTS' one wanted in every Town. Exclusive Ri^ht of Sale given
                            FREE. Address, BICKFORD KNITTING MACHINE tfFG; CO., TREE LABELS, Patent MicaFantl Labels for Trees, Sli ruL*.
                            Vines, Plants, etc. ¦¦¦ AdmitUd by '¦w-ldiWK Horticulturists, to be till' best Label ever invented. Impervious
                            to the weather, and in reality, an excellent article. Price 50 cents jier dozen, $300 per hundred, all orders to
                            be accompanied by the (\ish. Any name desired. Samples sent to parties sending two 3 cent stamps. Orders
                            promptly executed. Direct to K. VAX OKI'SKA, 3mo. Shaker Station, Ct. uau in vkii Et. TKOV. X. V. "Enlusim
                            Agini" f r Steinway, Chickering's & HAINES' PIANOS. & Jvwt cy 1'l;;iiik. 11' iu SEARCH of First
                            Class Bargains in PIANOS, or OBGANS, and desire a CHOICE tVom the Best manufactured at the. most attractive
                            Prices for Cash. Do not fail to call upon N. F. lUliNIlAM'S 1K7 l Water WHEEL Is di; i. \Ki;i the 'STANDARD
                            TURBINE,' by iiVKit 800 persons who I oughi and use tin in \\ i h PART and FULL GATE open. Illustrated and
                            descriptive Pamphl t, free. Address N. F. BURNHAM, P. O. Box 513. York. Pai (fearing for "Factories, Flouring
                            Mills, Paper Millx ¦ SOU Iili/lx (I xjirria/li/ 1/1/ BBOQMELL « BURNHAM, Christiana. Lam a t r Co., Pi. ' FOR
                            THAT IIIIKIMATIS}!. Try Dr. Dean's Rheumatic Pills, the old, popular standard and efficacious remedy. Ask for
                            them ar j our Druggist*. MAYNARD & NOYES Agts. BOSTON. iKiffl WATER WHEELS. With recent improvements.
                            Prices Greatly Reduced. 7000 in successlul operation. iTOE NS"7T PAKIHLET FC2 1!77. Jcnt free to those
                            interested. James Leffel & Co, Sjirintzrield, O. Y. Titv. The Societies at Canterbury and Watervliet
                            have used thi; iv f, rmanv years, and they unhesitatingly recommend it as a good, reliable article; of goodcoj.
                            or, flows freely, ami does nut fade. Msi.v nurd &Noyes, Bostbn. <pb id="p32"/> J. ESTEY &
                            COMPANY, To. 160.—Tront View. Mb. 160.—Back View. BRATTLEBORO, VI Onr new Organ, express'7 desig-ned for Sunday
                            GcliaoZA, Chapels, etc., is provinga g-:el:e.a.t suoobss. Be sure to send for full descriptive Catalogue before
                            purchasingany other. IHE LARGEST WORKS (OF THE KINO) ON THE GLOBE. Illustrated Catalogue sent free. TIIK A I.HA
                            NY ROOFING AM) GALVANIZED IRON WOEKS. Will furnish on application estimates on all styles of ROOFING! Slate, Tin
                            & Warren's (Jravel Roofing. AI.so Galvanized Iron Cornices, Window Caps, Conductors,
                            &c,Lightning Eods a specialty. A liirye line of Roofing Material, Sheathing Paper .£, Felt always in
                            stock. Nns. 7 and 9 JAMES STEEET. M* tf* & W* WfXCtlESTER'S FAM1TA' SOAPS. By C. BERKLEY JOHHSOW, Senior
                            member of the late ftrm of E. A. It W. WINCHESTER. The character and qunKfy of E. A. &W. Winchester's
                            Soap is fully equal, in every respect, to its former Standard. Tts Style is plain. Tt is not garnished with
                            Showy Labels. Tt recommends itself liy its excellence. It U designed for family use more than for trade. Trade
                            generally demands somethinir cheaper, consequently inferior. Address, r. BERKLEY JOIIXSOX, 16 Chatham St.
                            JtOSTOX, MASS.</p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>