<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2907" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18990701" TEIform="date">July 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-112</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1899.
Wmmm strange

DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
-EXPLAINING
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
A SUMMAEY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL church,
OB
"United.   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avery.    Price 15 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  TEE
Principles and. Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish to join it.            50  cents a year;
specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 2819 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
JULY,
REVELATIONS
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The Outlook publishes annually In June a
special illustrated issue called its "Recreation
Number."   This year the eleventh of these
numbers appears.   As usual, it is devoted
chiefly to out-of-door tobies, and includes
many illustrated articles of seasonable interest.   The Golfing Woman; by Mr. Van Tassel
Sutphen, is a warm plea for golf as, above all
other games, a sport in which women can
play on a plane of real competition with men,
because of the handicap possibilities.   There
are portraits of Miss Hoyt, Miss Griscom, and
other famous women players, and several
picturesque golfing scenes.   The "America's"
Cup Race for 1899 is treated by Mr. W. J. Henderson, probably the best yachting writer in
the country.   Four full-page pictures of famous yachts (including one of this year's defender, the "Columbia") and of famous yacht
races give the magazine a breezy, seagoing
atmosphere.   A cheerful article on A New
England Country Road; by Professor Bailey,
of Cornell, is beautified by a dozen or more
really remarkable photographs of typical
New England scenes taken by Mr. J. Horace
McFarland.   A charming and humorous story
of Canadian life by Macdonald Oxley, several
summer poems, an excellent article of suggestions for foreign travel, and other features,
make up a magazine fresli with vacation flavor and attractive to the eye.   The cover design, by Mr. Harold Brown, is in close keeping with the character of the number.   ($3 a
year.   The Outlook Company, New York.
In Mrs Burton Harrison's new serial, The
Circle of a Century, which is to begin in The
Saturday Evening Post of June 10, the author deals with two periods of society life in
New York City, separated by the lapse of a
century, but linked together by the kinship
of the characters.     Part I pictures New York
at the close of the Revolution, and shows the
humble beginnings of a family which has
since become immensely wealthy, and the departing splendors of their aristocratic neighbors.   In Part II the scene is shifted to the
New York of to-day, and the story follows
the fortunes of the new generation of Hopes
and Warriners.   Each part is a complete novelette.   Always in her element when writing
on society themes, Mrs Harrison has outdone
herself in The Circle of a Century, and has
produced a romance of absorbing interest.
Word and Work for June, 1899 is at hand.
It contains articles embracing religion, phi
lanthrophy, biography, home and foreign
missions, science and even the story for
children is not missing.   Mr. II. L. Hastings
has an interesting contribution which is good
advice in "The Choice of Food."   Published
monthly by "Christian Worker's Union," S. G.
Otis, Supt. Springfield, Mass. 5 cts. a copy, 5o
cts. a year.
It is far less easy to get to the President of
Hayti than to Mr. McKinley of the White
House.   The pavilion-like palace in the
Champ de Mars, surrounded by its litte park,
enclosed by a tall iron grating, with lookout
boxes at the angles, a large and strong military barrack at the rear, and field cannon
posted here and there, could stand a considerable siege, and, with a faithful garrison,
would be proof against almost any mob attack.   There is no end of etiquette involved
in the approach to Son Excellence.   Yet I was
favored with fortunate opportunities for seeing Mr. Simon Sam.   Tall and massive, with
an immense paunch, and features and hue
that are typically African, as you gaze at
him in his sumptuous uniform gorgeous with
gold lace and a brilliant silk scarf, you can
not help picturing to your mind's eye his hypothetical appearance as a mid-African chief
with huge feathers in his topknot, only a
rattle-beaded clout about his loins, a nailstudded war club in one hand and about him
a band of dusky savages more naked than
himself, instead of these strutting gentlemen
in tall hats and European clothes, and these
other prancing gentlemen in gaudy trappings
with tinkling spurs and jingling swords.
President Sam, however, is not, as it appears
thus far, a man to be personally feared.   His
selection was a compromise, and he is only
the figurehead of the present oligarchs, posing as a moderate statesman, while in truth
he is only a rather dense-brained, slow-witted
and lethargic old soldier.   It is understood
that in state affairs he is almost wholly guided by his ministers, of whom Brutus St. Victor,
in charge of the foreign department, and
Tancrede Auguste, of the department of the
interior, are probably the ablest.Reuben
Briggs Davenport, in Frank Leslie's Popular
Monthly for June.
The June Ladies' Home Journal reaches the
top notch of excellence in both its pictorial
and literary features.   It opens with a page
drawing of Longfellow's "Evangeline," and
gives a group of pictures showing some "Fetes
of College Girls."   An interesting description
is given of "The Creole Girl of New Orleans,"
and "Housekeeping on an Ocean Steamship"
is graphically portrayed.   "How a Young
Man Can Work His Way Through College"
has a practical value for every poor boy ambitious for higher education, and "Telling the
Character from Handwriting" is interesting
and entertaining.   Bishop, priest, rabbi and
minister contribute to a symposium on "What
is the Good of Going to Church?" and the
Rev. Newell Dwight Hillis, D. D., discusses
"Pains that Polish Perfection."
The fiction of the June Journal includes the
second installment of Anthony Hope's "Captain Dieppe," Sophie Swett's story, "The Revolt of Sar' Abby Quint," the first of -'Ol
Peckham's Opinions," and four chapters of
"A College Courtship."   There are two new
departments: "Five-Minute Talks on Good
Health," by expert physical educators, and a
boys' page, to which Dan Beard contributes--><pb n="97" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's promises" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S PROMISES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE promises of God as illustrated in the Scriptures are beautiful re minders of our home in
                            the new and spiritual Jerusalem which the Revelator saw coming down from heaven to dwell
                            among men. Those promises are for encouragement to those who will accept them in God's name.
                            "If thou shalt hearken diligently unto the voice of the Lord thy God, to observe and to do
                            all his commandments, All these blessings shall come on thee." "I will give you the rain of
                            your land in his due season, that thou mayest gather in thy corn, and thy wine, and thine
                            oil." "1 will send grass in thy fields for thy cattle." "The land which the Lord thy God
                            giveth thee, thou shalt possess it and dwell therein." "When thou passest through the
                            waters, I will be with thee, and through the rivers they shall not overflow thee; when thou
                            walkest through the fire, thou shalt not be bprned, neither shall the flames kindle upon
                            thee." From an early age mankind have been known in the religious order, as the obedient or
                            the disobedient. One class has been subject to law, while the other has assumed an
                            independent course. One class has been called the sons of God, and the other the sons of
                            Belial. They have walked the journey of life, and ascended or descended with the influences
                            around them, whether they were of a religious or worldly character. It was very much like
                            the growing together of the good and evil plants unto the day of harvest. From the world God
                            calls a nation, and he calls them "My people." They <pb n="98" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 98 THE MANIFESTO.
                            become an especial order under the protection of divine Providence. Laws are framed, rules
                            are given, and everything pertaining to a life on the earth is brought under divine
                            inspection. God leads them on their journeys, protects them from their enemies, opens a
                            passage through the sea for their escape, feeds them with miraculous food and gives to them
                            an inheritance in the fruitful land of Canaan. God gives them this promise, "I will bless
                            thee in basket and in store. I will take from thee all sickness and all the diseases of the
                            Egyptians." Those who have read the history of this people can see how successfully this was
                            accomplished, and their prosperity was like the prosperit}7 of all who follow the law of
                            truth and right. God's laws are imperative, and a careful regard for them insures
                            prosperity. "So transgression can pass unnoticed. The Psalmist has said, and that very
                            wisely"Though hand joined in hand the wicked shall not go unpunished." So long as the Jewish
                            nation made the Mosaic Law their line of life, they were in every respect a prosperous
                            nation. The law of human kindness was enforced, which made them largely a nation of
                            brethren. Sickness was rare among them, and the physicians were at a discount. The same rule
                            followed the king in his palace and the peasant in his cottage. It was God's law and he is
                            no respector of persons. "All these blessings shall come upon thee! for I have put my words
                            in thy mouth and I have covered thee in the shadow of my hand." The spirit of the New
                            Testament is the voice of advanced experience. It is God's law and demands the same implicit
                            obedience. Jesus informed his disciples of this important fact. "The Scribes and Pharisees
                            sit in Moses' seat. All, therefore, whatsoever they bid you observe, that observe and do."
                            The laws of our spiritual well-being are equally essential for our peace. "There shall in no
                            wise enter into it [the New Jerusalem] anything that defileth, neither whatsoever worketh
                            abomination or maketh a lie." Jesus, to sum up the whole matter, says, "If ye love me, ye
                            will keep my commandments." Then follows the divine promise of an hundred fold of blessings
                            in this world, and in the world to come, eternal life. God has given to us, light, and
                            truth, and hope. Shall we not as faithful servants work for God, and for that testimony
                            which is to save the world from sin? God has given to us our home as an inheritance and our
                            prosperity and happiness depend wholly upon the obedience which we render to the light and
                            truth which is made manifest to our souls. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We should live in the present..." TEIform="index"/>We should live in the present...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We should live in the present, vitally, nobly, courageously; commune with the past, soberly,
                            wisely sincerely; plan for the future thoughtfully, hopefully, broadly. Let the past be a
                            teacher of the present, and the present an instructor to the great untried future.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., M. E." TEIform="persName"/>M. E. H.</byline></div2><pb n="99" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why not think!" TEIform="index"/>WHY NOT THINK!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Joseph A." TEIform="persName"/>By Joseph A. Wilson.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN these lattor days, when nervous energy is pushed to its fullest extent along commercial
                            and governmental lines, when theology is straining its utmost to reconcile theory with fact,
                            when accumulated wealth on the one hand laughs arrogantly at the humble petitions of the
                            poor, there is still abroad in the land, in an increased measure, the same thoughtless,
                            unthinking spirit that has ever been a curse to humanity. As a rule, people are well enough
                            read; in musty book lore, they are well enough equipped; in current topics they are
                            sufficiently versed ; of all the effects that exist, they know enough,but the sad feature of
                            it all lies in their careless indifference to the causes that produce the effectsto their
                            lack of serious, thoughtful investigation of the results that are extant. The world, in its
                            general sense, is wise enough, but it does not think enough. Generally speaking you can
                            interest a person in a result, but it is difficult to induce him to investigate the causeand
                            it has ever been thus. The world, at large has ever declined to indulge in serious thought
                            until driven to the last extremity. History discloses numerous instances, indeed, it is the
                            same old story, oft recurring, France suffered the debauches, extravagances and outrages of
                            the Aristocracy until hunger and want of the barest necessities of life induced a thoughtful
                            investigation into existing circumstances, and then as a result, a revolt followed with a
                            long step toward freedom as an end. And so it is, the world over, every day,even to-day.
                            People suffer want and misery, because they fail to think. There is scarcely a day that the
                            great newspapers do not chronicle the self-destruction of some despondent, unthinking
                            person, who is out of joint with life and has no interest in things mundane. A rapid
                            career,a drunken debauch,loss of friends, despondency, self-destruction are all links in the
                            same chain,all means to the same end. It is the old story too often repeated. To those who
                            can be induced to think earth offers a charm, and life has its victories. To those who can
                            spare time to make thoughtful study, there is still in store for them a "balm in Gilead,"
                            even in these latter days of strife, unrest and increasing want. To those who can spare time
                            to investigate, there is still a pure, healthy home life open to them, where peace and
                            plenty exist, where honest, conscientious brotherhood and sisterhood abound, and all is in
                            tune with nature. Such a life as this is a living, existing fact among the Believers whose
                            clean theology is a source of comfort to its followers. If society can be brought to think
                            seriously of the inwardness of this true life, then, surely, we shall be numbered as the
                            grass. But, can society,the world,be induced to think? Must dire disaster, as ever, be the
                            medium to the end? Must still an empty stomach and a depleted wardrobe induce thought? Must
                                <pb n="100" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 100 THE MANIFESTO. still a crisis prompt action ? We hope not. In
                            this life of ours, removed from public haunts, we can follow the true path,the ideal
                            life,the divine end, and this life is open to the world,to all. To the interested we would
                            say,"come,"to the indifferent," Why not think!" White Water, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soliloquy" TEIform="index"/>SOLILOQUY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>By Asenath C. Stickney.</byline><p TEIform="p">AH ! Here comes the May Manifesto, full of good thoughts and hopeful aspirations, I presume.
                            It being the month of May, when all Nature is robed in a new dress, methinks one might liken
                            these pages to a series of newly prepared gardens, wherein to enter and select rare plants
                            for transference. So, on the first page in fancy I discover a large unwalled garden, where
                            one can roam at liberty, it seems, since no scare-crows are present to caw their
                            displeasureno bylaws confront us like the following: "Don't pluck this blossom," or "This
                            specimen is reserved for seed" or "Keep off the grass," &amp;c. Soon by continuing my
                            walk, I am attracted to a beautiful perennial blossoming right in my path. Its ancestry
                            dates back to nearly nineteen hundred years !yet it seems as fresh as a lovely arbutus
                            sparkling with dew and this is the language of its pure petals, viz :"Other foundation can
                            no man lay than that is laid in Christ Jesus." A little farther on, one meets a veritable
                            "Immortelle" in character which bears upon its surface this: "Love your enemies, and pray
                            for those that despitefully use you." A few steps more bring us to another of similar
                            character"Verily, unless a man forsake all that he hath, he can not be my diociple." Who
                            will not say that such are plants of the Heavenly Father's planting! Although pleased with
                            my selections, I am glad to know that I have not robbed the owner of this garden. On this
                            page I find a little garden plot fragrant with the balm of consolation emphasizing this
                            truth: "The Lord reveals his grace to men Avith healing in his wings." O, we must have this
                            plant, this healing balm. "The New Life" in the next garden is found growing unselfish,
                            universal love. This plant may be easily traced to the dawn of the Christian Era, when our
                            Savior reiterated this immortal truth: "Greater love hath no man than this, that a man lay
                            down his life for his friends." "Self-denial,"what a wide field these two wTords embrace!
                            Here grow the healthful sturdy plants, the real tonics in character. If these receive the
                            right culture, they wrill finally cover the whole field with the rich blossoms of conscious
                            integi'ity. 'Discovery,"this title sounds as if something new had been found. Per- <pb n="101" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 101 chance I see it is an exotic, it proclaims the
                            Christ method of conquering evil, thus, "Get thee behind me, Satan, thou savorest not the
                            things that be of God, but those that be of men." No specimen of the "touch-me-not" thrives
                            in this garden; cm contraire, the blossoms of humility carpet the whole extent and heart's
                            ease, lilies of the valley gladden the eye of the casual passer-by as well as of the
                            investigator. Last, but not least I come in view of "Bring the Best." Here I find the
                            superlative in degree 'and value is wanted, viz. a total surrender of self, a generous
                            giving of the brightest hopes, the finest talent, the choicest fruits; in a word the best we
                            have to God. All the choice plants indigenous to luxuriant vales of humility nourish in this
                            garden. Shall we term them lilies of the valley or Easter lilies ? Thanking the owners of
                            these several gardens for their liberality, I wend my way homeward satisfied that I have a
                            selection worth setting in my own small enclosure, and from which, by careful culture, I may
                            realize lasting benefit. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unerring principle" TEIform="index"/>UNERRING PRINCIPLE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">"T3EHIND all visible and invisible phenomena,back of all the wheels of I } evolution,below
                            all the energies of human destiny lies a profound, unerring principle. This principle is
                            Organization or Systematic Arrangement. It permeates and dominates every force and movement
                            of the universe. It constitutes the Infinite mathematics of all that is. Its modus operandi
                            is such as alwa}Ts secures the greatest good to the greatest number. Another of its
                            sequences is that as Paul announced, "Without all contradiction, the less is blessed of the
                            better." Parenthood is a peculiarly bright illustration of this, and the illustration is as
                            rife in the spiritual as the physical spheres. The fact of father and mother, son and
                            daughter, ought to convince us all that we are in no sense of the word, independent
                            creatures. Our origin and existence are both practical proofs of this, if we look at the
                            subject in its true light. Jesus said, "Swear not by 3Tour head, for you can not make one of
                            your hairs white or black." Again, if God has made of one blood all the nations of the
                            earth, then surely we have not made ourselves, and so must have depended upon some higher
                            source in the great mathematics of the universe for our origin. Moreover let us look at
                            ourselves as wre exist at the present moment. How can we predicate independence of
                            ourselves, when we are so bound up in the bundle of universal life, that almost all we drink
                            and wear, and almost all the mental and spiritual comfort we have in existence comes <pb n="102" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE MANIFESTO. from our fellow-beings, either visible or
                            invisible. What would the existence of any one of us be worth, if that of all others was
                            wiped out? When I think of these things and compare myself with the mighty Allness behind,
                            beyond, below and above me, I almost wonder how such an infinitesimal speck of creation
                            should receive any notice from God. That great principle of Organization is such, however,
                            that I find myself blessed with a niche in the sublime systematic arrangement. On the whole,
                            I am glad we are all in this category1 of dependence;it seems to me far better than a state
                            of solitary isolation. I therefore can not agree with our friends the Christian Scientists,
                            that we must be entirely independent, by virtue of what they call our individuality. Must
                            not do anything because somebody says do it; must ignore all teaching outside of ourselves.
                            And yet they quote Christ as saying that unless we receive the kingdom of Heaven as a little
                            child, we shall in no wise enter therein. Does a little child set itself up as a being who
                            by virtue of something he calls his individuality, is independent of every other man, woman,
                            or child on the earth? I think not. He is not only wholly dependent upon his parents, but
                            confides in them with entire trust. Furthermore, every time we speak of prayer, some say we
                            should not beg or beseech, but rather demand of God, whatever we need. Now does a little
                            child demand this or that of his parents in an arrogant manner? Does he not rather humbly
                            beseech that he may have this or that? In fact the theory of each one for himself, seems to
                            preclude all possible ideas of organization, and to depend altogether upon the isolated
                            condition for beneficial results hoped for. The happiest, purest, and most harmonious
                            organization that was ever on the earth, is a Shaker Community. Obedience to its principles
                            promotes order, purity, and equality. I do not think that there ever was or will be, a
                            person who can become a member of the Community from religious convictions who, after a
                            solid experience therein, will deny, that it is the very best Institution in the land for
                            the religious, mental and temporal comfort of its members and which carries out the
                            principle and practice of peace and goodwill to man. If we only had the Thaumaturgic element
                            of Christ's evangel, we would be ready to go on in the approaching century with a prosperity
                            and a glory surpassing all that has preceded us since the world began. Union Village,
                        Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mission of disciples of christ" TEIform="index"/>THE MISSION OF DISCIPLES OF CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="King, Emma B." TEIform="persName"/>By Emma B. King.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN Matt, x., we read that Jesus called unto him his twelve disciples, appointing to them
                            their spiritual mission in the words, "Go rather to the lost sheep of the house of Israel,
                            and as ye go, preach, saying, The kingdom <pb n="103" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 103 of heaven
                            is at hand. Heal the sick, cleanse the lepers, raise the dead, cast out devils ; freely ye
                            have received ; freely give." The disciples were men whose lives had been spent in pursuing
                            one particular trade, and we may well think they were quite unprepared to embrace the
                            mission of preaching the gospel, but with the command, "Go ye, and preach the gospel," came
                            power and authority from the Christ to meet all the requirements of the mission thus
                            placed'upon them. They were to provide nothing for the journey, that they might learn
                            dependence and trust in divine guidance, and as they walked in obedience to this guidance
                            they possessed the Christ power against unclean spirits and to heal all manner of diseases.
                            At this time the disciples were not firmly established in the faith, and it seemed a word of
                            wisdom. "Go not into the way of the Gentiles, and into any city of the Samaritans, enter ye
                            not." The Jews would have no dealings with either Gentile or Samaritan, such was the
                            existing animosity between them, aud this retaliation could not be approved by our Savior,
                            whose forgiving- ministration drew all men unto him. Jesus warned his disciples that they
                            would receive persecution, but never left them without the assurance of a comforting
                            promise. At one time he said to them, "If they have persecuted me, they will also persecute
                            you, If they have kept my sayings, they will keep yours also." "The disciple is not abore
                            his master, nor the servant above his Lord, but every one that is perfect shall be as his
                            Master." "Ye shall be hated of all men for my name's sake, but he that endureth to the end
                            shall be saved." His great concern, was lest the disciples lose the power of God by carnal
                            reasoning and would speak less of gospel truth, fearing accusation before the courts and
                            councils of men. "Behold, I send you forth as sheep in the midst of wolves, be ye therefore,
                            wise as serpents and harmless as doves." But when they deliver you to finite judgment, take
                            no thought how or what ye shall speak ; for that power which hath anointed thee with thy
                            mission shall grant thee words of wisdom to speak "For it is not ye that speak but the
                            spirit of your Father which speaketh in you." What could express more plainly the work of
                            Christ in the soul! A oneness with God and godly principles which permeate thought, word and
                            action that others recognize not the natural ambition or selfish aspiration wrought out
                            through natural ability, but a disciple of Christ whose life efforts are directed by the
                            Father who dwelleth in and speaketh through the soul. The disciples received much
                            instruction from Jesus, but did not receive a spiritual baptism into the work until after
                            his crucifixion. From the day of Pentecost they commenced to understand the mission of
                            Christ. Then they became living preachers of the gospel testimony and brought many souls,
                            both Jews and Gentiles, to righteousness. Unto us the Savior has appeared with the simple
                            injunction, "Follow me," "I have chosen you," I have ordained ^ou to preach and live the
                            Christ life. <pb n="104" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE MANIFESTO. He hath granted that we become
                            partakers in the life of regeneration. He hath appointed to us our mission in life. As we
                            learn so we must teach, find conversion of soul; and as the Pentecostal blessing meets each
                            soul become baptized with the Holy Spirit which shall enable us in love to win souls to God.
                            East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cycles and magnets" TEIform="index"/>CYCLES AND MAGNETS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">rpWENTY-THREE years ago, Eldress Elizabeth Farr of Union Village, _L_ Ohio, gave to the
                            reading public the following testimony. I retired to rest, feeling anxiety in mind as to the
                            growth of Zion, and the prayer on my lips, O Lord, what will attract souls to Zion? What
                            will make them accept the cross, and build up the waste places of Zion? What will bring
                            laborers into the Lord's vineyard? Immediately a ponderous wheel rolled up before my vision,
                            being in perpetual motion. Each cog of the wheel appeared to represent a cycle of time
                            within a general cycle. Attached to the axle of the wheel, and connected in groups, by fine
                            thread-like fibers, each group in its place, was the advancement of science, art and
                            religion. Every element and principle was represented that bears close relation to the
                            practical affairs of life, and is necessary to the harmonious growth of intelligence. The
                            constant motion of the wheel, brought within the sphere of mind, some one of these which
                            appeared to engross the general attention of mankind at a given time. Then came these words;
                            "It is as easy to excite the religious element, as any other, when the time rolls around ;
                            and souls will as surely be attracted by the magnet of truth in religion, as in any other
                            science." Here was a spiritual vision which applies to our day, as really and
                            authoritatively as any vision recorded in ancient Scripture. Intelligent minds can see proof
                            of its verity in the character of the literature issued through a series of years, to meet
                            the ever changing interest of the people. It speaks of the magnet of truth in religion. Then
                            truth is a magnet. It attracts hungering souls to whoever possesses it. This is what
                            attracted people to Jesus and his Apostles, also to Mother Ann Lee and her co-laborers.
                            Truth is the bread of life to those who hunger and thirst after righteousness, and to all
                            who seek rest and emancipation from the world, in the everlasting kingdom of Grod. Truth is
                            the eternal substance of being. However far, or however long creatures may wander in the
                            land of shadows, enchanted by illusions of the senses and dreams of pleasure, like the
                            prodigal in the parable, who wasted his substance in riotous living and would fain appease
                            his hunger with the <pb n="105" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 105 food of swine, they will
                            sometime come to themselves,to a realization of the truth. They will experience a hunger
                            that will not be quieted with earthly riches nor pleasure, nor by any application of natural
                            science, or art, or worldly knowledge,but can be appeased by the truths of life eternal,
                            given to man through specially prepared and inspired messengers of the eternal Spirit. Such
                            as were Jesus and Mother Ann,and such as were those who were taught by them, and obeyed
                            instructions, and have communicated it to successors, who continue to be instructed by the
                            same Spirit. They who obey the truth taught by those Divine messengers, crucifying the lower
                            self and the world within, laying down their lives in daily service for the living members
                            of the bod}T of Christ, are storing up truth such as will feed hungry souls in the body and
                            out of the body. They incorporate truth of the higher life vrith their own being. To the
                            worldlings, they appear narrow in aim and accomplishment. They contract their pleasures on
                            the lower, visible and natural plane, that they may be enlarged on the higher and spiritual,
                            and become magnets of truth, to draw all truth-seekiug, God revering men and women to them,
                            for the only bread which can save them from perishing. Even like Jesus, who said I am the
                            way, the truth and the life. I am the bread of life. If I be lifted up, I will draw all men
                            unto me. He is the magnet. How is he lifted up?. By showing his example and teaching through
                            the everlasting gospel, which is the gospel of the judgment, the gospel of the harvest and
                            the end of the world. Because those who come into it, are thereby cut off from the life of
                            the world, and it is brought to an end in them. And by this gospel of confessing and
                            forsaking sin and of slaying self in mutual service, made known to us by the Holy Spirit of
                            Truth which dwelt in Mother Ann, and her faithful successors, all souls will be finally
                            judged, and will decide their own ultimate destiny hy accepting or rejecting it. We know
                            this the same spirit that dwelt in Jesus because it brings forth the same fruits in all who
                            obey it. By the fruits the tree is known, and not by any form of words or profession of
                            belief. The doctrine is the same, plus the increase which comes of or by the redeemed other
                            half of humanity. Jesus did not teach his disciples all truth, for the reason that it can
                            not all be received at once, any more than a child can receive all the knowledge contained
                            in books by the time he has learned the alphabet. Hence Jesus promised that the Spirit of
                            Truth which the Father would send in his name, should abide with them to the age
                            everlasting, and guide them into all trutheven to a knowledge that the second coming of
                            Christ into human nature, would be in a woman, the Comforter. There is increase in knowledge
                            and charity and growth of understanding, which comes to every individual by travel. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="106" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JULY 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year, postage paid.
                            .50 A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances for
                            subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">May. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1898. 56. 3.875 in 1899. 58.48
                                1.75 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 88 above 0. Lowest " " " " 3(3 " Number of rainy
                                days " " 5 " " clear " " " 11 " " cloudy " " " 15 June, 1899. There is but little, if
                                anything, unusual transpiring that would be of interest to the general reader, unless it
                                is the extremely dry weather that prevails in this vicinity, which causes vegetation to
                                droop. We have no tornadoes to record,1 such as devastate Australia, stripping forests
                                of their leaves and branches and driving stones into the trunks of the trees. We are
                                pursuing the "even tenor of our ways," cultivating the crops that are to be converted
                                into aliment for support of the human and the animal. Some of us are growing better who
                                were somewhat ill. For this we should be thankful. "Thanks to God for every blessing,
                                thanks to God for what we've gained." The project that has engaged the powers of Xew
                                York State in the building of a State Road along a route where nothing but woodchucks
                                burrow and cattle feed seems to us quite misplaced energy. Not a single dwelling is
                                located along the whole line of the road. With the expense of half the cost of the
                                present road, a turnpike could have been built through our village, far superior to the
                                present shunpike. The Second and South families will be entirely deprived of its use.
                                Calvin G. Reed. Second Family. June 1899. The beautiful weather with which we have been
                                lately favored has not been unimproved by us for we haveas is said of the politician or
                                statesman who is looking after his re-electionbeen "mending our fences;" not only our
                                fences but also our gates, our agricultural implements and all that, until now we think
                                they are in prime order. Last fall we put up a new round silo, under cover in our cow
                                barn, 26x12 feet and filled it well with ensilage; on opening it three or four weeks ago
                                we found the contents in excellent condition, perfect, and much relished by the cattle.
                                This new silo with the square one of double the capacity which we already had, gives us
                                a large and valuable reserve of food for our cows. Our live stock, horses, cows, calves,
                                sheep, lambs, hogs and little pigs is in splendid condition. <pb n="107" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 107 Our fruit trees and small fruits are coming on finely; the large variety
                                of vegetables will more than compensate us for all the trouble they have been and will
                                be and make us the more thankful that we are vegetarians, really, if we are not strictly
                                so. Our good Sisters are having most satisfactory results from the attention they have
                                given their flower gardens; an hour or two in the mornings and evenings given to this
                                pleasant work is beneficial to one's health and the returns made by the plants are very
                                gratifying. Occasionallynot very often, I am sorry to adda Brother volun teers to assist
                                the Sisters but then he must be very careful as his touch is not so delicate, nor his
                                step so careful as that of the Sisters and his hoe will sometimes cut a pretty plant
                                instead of a noxious weed; but even then, if he is so unfortunate, he is not frowned on.
                                Henri/ C. Farmer. North Family. June, 1899. The locust trees are in bloom. The bees
                                found it out first, and should you find the North family developing a spirit of prophesy
                                in the future, will you not attribute it to a diet of honey and wild locust? And will
                                not a reverse of its form be also a reverse of the fate of our vegetarian of the Judean
                                long ago? It is to be hoped so. We are trying to keep ourselves in sympathy with the
                                brightness if not with the greenness of our hills, but next to a flood a drouth has the
                                most depressing effect upon the mind of a farmer, and a drouth is upon us now. So
                                stealthy has been its approach some of us are just realizing its dreary, dusty presence.
                                But good cheer! there is a moist prophecy in the whistle of the rising wind and for
                                several days the thunder has been growling below the horizon. The "Arena" comes to hand
                                with a Japanese view of Kipling that is most delightfully daring in this day of Kipling
                                worship. Ah, com'age is a fine thing! Indeed it is the only perfectly fine thing in
                                existence excepting truth,and what is truth but courage? Sister Catherine is away among
                                the haunts of her childhood, and we are expecting her to return to us rested and filled
                                with new vigor to carry on with hand, heart and brain, the battles we all must wage for
                                the right against the wrong. Sister Olive is still waiting in the "land of Beulah" for
                                the welcome from the "City Beyond," and we all feel that keeping friends with the
                                Shining Ones on our journey is the only way to win, like dear Sister Olive, a peaceful
                                pause in Beulah Land. The ministry are with us. Is it necessary to say that they are
                                here to bless? G. Ada Brown. South Family. June, 1899. June, one of the rarest months of
                                the year, dawned with brightness in its wake. Surprises new and joyous were ours the
                                past week. Thursday morning the 8th inst. we were favored with a \isit from Elder
                                William Briggs of East Canterbury. We hope when he comes to New York state again his
                                tarry will extend beyond the limits of a few hundred minutes. We learn with much joy
                                that our venerable Minister and honored Editor, Elder Henry C. Blinn, is once more only
                                a short distance over the mountain, enjoying the invigorating atmosphere of the
                                Berkshire hills making his summer home among his friends of the West Pittsfield Society.
                                We shall surely see him now and trust the good Lord will spare him to earth for many
                                days to come. Our prayers and best wishes are with him. Sister Louisa Rice, the faithful
                                and patient Samaritan of our family, enjoyed a few day's vacation at the West Pittsfield
                                Community. She reported rest for body and mind and says the "Berkshire air is
                                wonderfully invigorating and healthful." <pb n="108" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE MANIFESTO. The
                                cold rainy days of May hindered farm labor somewhat, but the sun now shines on a
                                thriving and prosperous Community. Geiievieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1899. Lovely June ! We greet thee with thy roses, as a benefactress who teaches us
                                that life is more than a dreary conflict of the elements with their snow and sleet; that
                                it is also sunshine and beautiful flowers, and it is no doubt best that thou canst not
                                always stay for we then anticipate and appreciate your coming. We were very pleasantly
                                surprised a short time ago by receiving a presentation copy of "The Altheia," by Sister
                                Aurelia G. Mace, of Sabbathday Lake, Maine. It is a compilation of essays in the form of
                                letters illustrating the principles and precepts of our Society in a very able manner.
                                We extend our hearty thanks to every one who, having light is willing and anxious to let
                                it shine that others may be able to perceive the truth and render thanksgiving to the
                                divine Spirit from which comes, as from an overflowing fountain, the power that is
                                lifting all who receive it into higher planes of thought and action. The International
                                Peace Congress recently held has accomplished one object. It has given every thinking
                                person something with which they can occupy their minds on the line of human progress,
                                though its work has been only preliminary, casting up the highway, pointing out the
                                obstacles to be removed therefrom that the future may attain to that condition of
                                universal peace which we at the present time are anxious for, but as yet are unable to
                                accomplish. It has proved to those pioneers of advanced thought who are reaching out
                                with a strong arm, seeking to lift the nations out of their barbarism, that all earth's
                                rulers who sit on thrones are not lost to the truth and humanitarian principles, nor
                                intoxicated with the power that is given them, for a short time, to exercise. The
                                illumination of the eastern horizon proves that there is dawning a glorious day, and we,
                                as an organization, can render thanksgiving and praise for the increasing light. We were
                                one of a party of ten from the North family that attended by invitation "Children's Day"
                                by the Verdoy Sunday School on June 11, at Verdoy, N. Y. The School was held in
                                Lothridge hall, commencing at 2:30 p. m. The service in both song and recitation,
                                adapted to the day and occasion, under the direction of the teachers of the school, was
                                interesting. Rev. C. P. Dedmire of Niskayuna addressed the School on "The Importance of
                                Little Things in the Formation of Life's Character." Although quite unexpected, Elder
                                Alexander L. Work of the North family was called upon to address the School, which he
                                did as a loving Father would address children; giving counsel to the older members to be
                                careful and set a good example to those who were forming their characters, and to teach
                                them lessons that the rising generation can call them blessed. Certainly the world is
                                moving as was manifest by the character of the songs and speaking. Nothing said that was
                                objectionable to spiritually minded persons whatever denomination they may be associated
                                with. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1899. What a combination of melody our Notes this month would produce could we
                                transfer the varied tones we hear around us, to paper or imitate them with the voice.
                                Nature's orchestra holds free concerts daily and never a false note mars its sweetness.
                                The trees hold the flutes, and pipe notes sometimes weird, sometimes joyful, the
                                mountains send forth minor or major chords from their.deep-toned organ; <pb n="109" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 109 the birds with violin, guitar and banjo trill their
                                merry lays; the bees with trumpets and insects with drums; the brooks with tinkling
                                bells, and the breezes with tuneful harps, all perform their part in such perfect
                                harmony, that we marvel at their skill. Their master, the sun, has kept them in such
                                constant practice however, that we fear the longdrawn notes may merge into a chant,
                                unless relieved by a little interlude of showers. At present the ground is very dry, and
                                the farmers are predicting a light hay harvest, and small crops, unless the clouds open
                                their treasure store for us. The potatoes even, though credited with keen sight, fail to
                                see a ray of hope and bow their tops dejectedly. Our garden, however, as usual is nobly
                                doing its part, the result of constant coaxing and care and applications of patience and
                                powders. Asparagus was excellent and plentiful, but now that its reign is over, other
                                articles are succeeding iu their order. The fruit trees blossomed in fulness of
                                promises, but now have removed their holiday attire and in work-day dress are busy at
                                their labors, converting sunlight, moisture and earth minerals into delicious fruits.
                                They too petition for a little essence of the clouds to insure the perfect flavor.
                                Failing to find it in the atmosphere they send the roots down deeper and deeper, thus
                                finding a source of suppiyShall we apply the lesson thus taught? All the power necessary
                                for soul growth can not be drawn from the outward helps given, but those who earnestly
                                search, drawing closer and closer to the fountain itself, the living waters, shall there
                                find unlimited measure. Our school is in session with a membership of sixteen pupils.
                                They were visited on the 6th inst. by a party of five, committee and teachers from
                                Hancock. Two of our buildings are renewing their youth, at least in appearance, by the
                                application of a fresh coat of paint, and the very air surrounding them seems less
                                cloudy since they commenced smiling in brightness. Cheerful countenances are so
                                contagious. We are pleased to say that our beloved editor, Elder Henry, is wi'th us once
                                more. Elder William Briggs accompanied him and is making a short stay with us. We will
                                now touch the finale of our Xotes, which is love to all our Brothers and Sisters in
                                other homes, and an earnest wish that daily blessing be theirs. Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1899. June is here and the days are long and fine. Xo rain of much account has
                                fallen for two months and the land is suffering for the want of it. Xot even a shower
                                condescends to stop in this section. The fruit will probably be spoiled. Hay a very
                                light crop. As for vegetables and flowers we can only hope as to-day is dull and foggy
                                that rain may come and save them. Sister Aurelia's books are now ready and selling fast
                                at a dollar apiece. The guests from Poland Springs are much pleased with them. We are
                                glad as Sister Aurelia has taken much pains to have the work a success and books, we
                                know will live long after the visible form of the author is consigned to dust, so we
                                believe her's will be a testimony to prove her love to her work and her people. We are
                                glad to record success in the sale of our plants, as at this writing the greenhouse is
                                cleared of all salable plants, only enough left for home use. Xot long since, Dr.
                                Bailey, a veterinary surgeon called here to examine our herd of cows, and pronounced
                                them free from tuberculosis. This examination was necessary as the Ricker Brothers
                                "wished to engage our cream for the summer. We hear that Elder George Clark and three
                                Sisters from Enfield, Conn., are on their way to our home but are stopping at Old
                                Orchard Beach. We shall be glad to extend to them a cordial welcome. Ada S.
                            Cummings.</p></div3><pb n="110" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1899. Hojie Notes seem so almost indirect in their communication between the
                                inmates of our several gospel homes, that it is with pleasure we remark upon the almost
                                tangible nearness of the mansions at West Pittstield, Mass, and Enfield, Conn. Safely
                                ensconced in the former, our beloved Editor is at date, and it is satisfactory through
                                this column, though narrow, to greet him in behalf of home friends, who throng to the
                                pen-point with loving congratulations and best wishes for a healthful sojourn. We are
                                also especially mindful of the genial, hospitable friends who were so successful in
                                their persuasions, and to whom we are attached by the bond which is dependent upon no
                                human expression, yet may be manifest in every human expression. Sometime they may try
                                the effect of our climate, as they have not recently done so. Someone ventures to
                                suggest that Canterbury air is especially good in case of asthma, and we think so, too.
                                At any rate, most of us are entirely free from the complaint, and this is no meagre
                                testimonial. Our kind welcome, long imprisoned in the heart waiting for action and
                                circulation, is now upon the lip, but not till the 21st shall we have occasion to
                                express it in the hearing of our beloved friends from Enfield, Conn, who have agreed to
                                visit us in the name of the gospel interchange, so necessary to maintain the firm, equal
                                pulsations toward the "exceeding righteousness,", which true progress demands of our
                                life forces. Weather, drouth, crops, June roses and whippoorwills are prominent on the
                                home almanac, but the Home Note rule forbids more extended mention. We and the robins
                                must furnish the last word, however"More wet." Jessie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1899. The morning is pleasant, with clouds thinly covering the sky, and some signs
                                of showers are present. We think we have had a sufficiency of rain for the present.
                                Strawberries are coming in fine and large, and our black and raspberry bushes are full
                                of blossoms and promise to be abundant. We raise to-day a stock barn at our Westlot
                                Farm, 100x35 ft. In a few days we shall raise another at the North family 40x30 ft. All
                                crops at present look promising and if we could only persuade people who need salvation,
                                to come in and partake with us of all these great blessings, and of that infinitely
                                greater boonthe everlasting gospel;then we should have nothing left to be desired. If we
                                all would agree to adopt the ideas of Edward Bellamy into practical life and surrender
                                our selfishness, and live on terms of equality, we might then hope gradually to see the
                                beauty of the genuine Christ life. Now is an excellent time for the study and practice
                                of that "patience of the saints" spoken of by the inspired Seer of Patmos. Nothing is
                                more necessary for Believers, than the exercise and continual practice of patience. Our
                                health is very good and this reminds me that we neglected to send to The Manifesto, an
                                obituary of our brother, Henry Tobin, who deceased July 9, 1897. Age 81 years, 9 mo. and
                                13 days. He had lived in the Church family about 20 years. Faithful in duty, orderly in
                                conduct and an excellent miller. We try to abound in charity, but we find it at the
                                expense of no little self-abnegation. May we abound still more in this first of all
                                spiritual gifts. We also abound in many beautiful flowers and flowering shrubs, which
                                look splendid at this time of year and seem to indicate that we are determined not to
                                have "All cross and no glory." We love to read the Home Notes of all the Shakers, east,
                                west, north and south. O- C. Hampton.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wisdom is often concealed..." TEIform="index"/>Wisdom is often concealed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Wis-dom is often concealed under a threadbare garment.</p></div2><pb n="111" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food we eat, no. 5" TEIform="index"/>THE FOOD WE EAT. NO. 5.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder H. C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">West Australia. There are races now in Australia (1898) who live on snakes, lizards, worms
                            and anything living which comes within the grasp of these ugly looking creatures. "Chinamen
                            eat the chrysalis of the silk worm, and feast on cats, dogs, wharf rats, sea slugs, sharks,
                            bats and caterpillar soup." "The Indians of Florida eat horses, dogs, foxes, cats, skunks,
                            crocodiles, hawks, crows and buzzards." "Indians on the Rocky Mountains eat a dog stew."
                            "The Esquimaux eat putrid flesh of seals, putrid whale's flesh, reindeer chyle, brain oil
                            and unhatched eggs." Of course, the most of this is the food of the uncivilized races, but
                            in many respects it comes quite near to those who have the honor of being civilized. By a
                            close investigation we may now find that the highly civilized and Christianized nations of
                            Europe and America are quite like our savage neighbors in the preparation of their food.
                            Professor Mussey thinks the command to eat every living thing was given because man
                            transgressed in regard to the first law, which was to eat of the fruit and of herbs.
                            Believers in the inspiration of the Bible should make a note of this, and make straight
                            their crooked ways. irthe food that we eat to sustain life has anything to do with the
                            ruling of our mind or body, and a large class of intelligent people, to-day, entertain that
                            thought it becomes highly important, especially for those of the Christian faith to examine
                            the subject with great care, As we study the order of food, of some of the savage nations,
                            so repellent to our mind we invariably remark,That, is pretty low in the scale of humanity.
                            And then if we should reflect, how trifling the ascendency of the ace has been in the past
                            4000 years, we may well conclude that the millennium will still be in the far distant
                            future. We copy from an article in "The Temple of Health." Men grow to be like what they
                            feed on . We are told of a man in Colioe's who to show bravo caught and ate a mouse. His
                            comrades were shocked. But why, why worse to catch and eat a mouse than to catch and eat a
                            pig? In the eyes of an Israelite the latter would be far the more disgusting! No gastric
                            strainer nor digestive net-work is sufficiently potent to transform putridity to purity.
                            What a sight to see a family of Christians boasting of progress,singing of the "tree of
                            Life," and talking about angel's food, sit at a table and devour diseased meat." While we
                            may think it is very singular and even vulgar that uncivilized races should eat nearly all
                            that may be taken from the body of an elephant, the Christians can eat, with a peculiar
                            relish, almost all that is taken from the inside of the scrofulous swine. Indeed, the swine
                            although refused by Moses as unclean and wholly unfit for food, is more carefully saved than
                            almost any other animal. "No other kind of food is so largely used as is pork in its various
                            forms of preparation. In the western states, pork and potatoes constitute the most
                            substantial portion of the farmer's bill of fare. Pork is considered such a delicacy that
                            not a particle should be wasted. The fat and lean portions are eaten fresh, or carefully
                            preserved by salting or smoking or both. The tail is roasted, the snout, ears and feet are
                            pickled and eaten as souse; the intestines and lungs are eaten or made into sausages; black
                            pudding is made of the blood; the liver, spleen and kidneys are also prized; the pancreas
                            and other glands are considered great delicacies, while even the skin is made into jelly."
                            And more modern ingenuity has even utilized the digestive ferment of the gastric juice, to
                            mix with the wonderful chewing gum that has such a fabulous sale. A piece of taffy and some
                            juice <pb n="112" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 112 THE MANIFESTO. from a pig's stomach, mnst be a nice article
                            to have in the mouth!! What next? "In fact nothing is left of the beast but the bristles,
                            which the shoemaker claims. The terms scrofula and measles are so intimately connected with
                            the raising of swine, that they become familiar to every school boy. Many who eat the swine
                            hold in contempt the Frenchman who eats a horse, or the Chinaman who eats a dog. The
                            trichina which develops in swine's flesh produce in man an incurable disease." Oysters and
                            clams are eaten as a rarity, and the American thinks it nice to eat the whole creature as it
                            comes from the shell. In this the Americans and Patagonians and Fuegians have corresponding
                            tastes. The one eats his oysters and clams without removing any of the refuse, and the
                            others eat their crabs and turtles in the same way. The English and Americans eat shrimps
                            just as they are taken from the sea, with a sprinkling of salt, the same as the Arabs eat
                            their grasshoppers. Then the Americans eat the little crabs that are found among the
                            oysters, without removing even the shell, chewing and swallowing them with as much relish as
                            do the Patagonians. Herrings are smoked when taken from the sea and then eaten, while
                            sardines are packed in oil and eaten without removing any of the inner parts. Turkeys are
                            fastened to a board and forced to eat till they become diseased and their livers are swollen
                            to an enormous size, when these are eaten by the epicures of the most civilized and
                            Christianized of nations. Like the savages of Africa we make puddings of bullock's blood and
                            extol them as choice articles of food, Tons of edible snails are brought to the United
                            States every year and served as a delicacy to the highly civilized class. We also have "clay
                            eaters" right in our midst, who will eat a ball of clay from the size of a pea to one of
                            three or four inches in diameter. The chewing, smoking and snuffing of tobacco is common
                            among the men, women and children. Snakes and eels are eaten in some civilized countries,
                            and served to travelers by inquiring whether they preferred the "eel of the ditch or the eel
                            of the hedge." The fishermen of Tangiers call everything fish that comes to the net.
                            Limpets, snails, muscles, horseshoe crabs, toad fish, sea anemones, as well as the fish
                            better known to other nations, and these are all bought and eaten.Donahoe1 s Magazine. While
                            there may be great need of advancement in regard to the selection of our food, for the
                            general health and for the comfort of the individual, it should be also, through the growth
                            of intelligent minds. There are not only individuals, but also nations who thrive on a diet
                            excluding the flesh of all animals, and there are nations who rarely eat anything except the
                            flesh of wild and domesticated creatures. The advice given by the apostle to his brethren,
                            may prove profitable even in this case. "Let every man be fully persuaded in his own mind."
                            The health and happiness of the individual becomes of the first importance, even though as a
                            matter of taste, other things may have a great influence. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty is ours..." TEIform="index"/>Duty is ours...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ditty is ours; results, God's. Sincerity is the parent of truth.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bruce, Willa" TEIform="index"/>Willa Bruce
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Willa Bruce, at Shaker Station, Conn. May 1, 1899. Age 13 years and 2 months. Death is
                                often a welcome visitor to the old and infirm, but it is sad to see blight and decay
                                fasten upon the young. L. S. B. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Massie, Charles" TEIform="index"/>Charles Massie
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Charles Massie, at Union Village, Ohio. March 24, 1899.
                                Age 79 years, 11 months and 5 days. He was for some years acting Trustee and Deacon of
                                the Center and South families. True to the trusts confided to him he was respected by
                                all. O. C. H.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
an illustrated article on "A Boys' Underground Club House."   Two pages of photographs show "Where Our Presidents aie
Buried;" other picture "Children's Day in the
Church," "Picturesque Bits of Gardens," etc.
Mrs. S. T. Borer teaches "The A. B. C. of Ice
Cream Making," and gives menus for outdoor
gatherings.   "The Journal's Prize Model
House" is shown, with others built from plans
previously published.   There are numerous
practical articles on woman's work and woman's wear.   By the Curtis Publishing Company, Philadelphia.   One dollar per year;
ten cents per copy.
The Wide World Magazine for July, 1899 is
full of matter especially interesting to the
reading public.   Articles upon Charles Neufeld's "Twelve Year's Captivity in Chains in
Omdurinan," "Saved from Hydrophobia" by
B. H. Julian add the history of the Ruskin
Co-operative Socialistic Colony are alone
sufficient to recommend the last current number.   Price 10 cents.   $1.20 a year.   The International News Co.   84 and 85 Duane St.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Invention,
NPIMPArchesology, ElectricityIICII TU
LllOChemistry, Mineralogy.fiHAL I II
Health, Hygiene, Medicine.
Formerly  Boston  Journal of Chemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular monthly contains a large number of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent reader,
even though he knew little or nothing of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers with a similar name.
Monthly,  $1.60 per year.    Nswsdsalsrs,  15  cts.
largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.
LILLAED & CO.,
108 Pulton St., New York.
Mention this paper for a sample copy
IN
Eldresses
Dorothy A, Durgin,
Joanna J. Kaime,
The book contains photographs of the
Sisters, and also a short biographical
sketch.    A notice of the Memorial Service
including several pieces of music.     Manyletters of sympathy from friends not of
the Community.
A copy of the book may be obtained by
addressing Hart & Shepard,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Price, Cloth, 75 cts.    Boards 50 cts.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER  PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   $1 a year.
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Hope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth,
liittie Men aud Women,
Weekly Articles by Georgre . Scott
Talmage's Sermon,
Money and Business,
World-Wide Field,
Our Family Story,
Farm and Garden,
Market Reports,
MEMORIAM
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
ROYAL
BAKING
Powder
ABSOLUTELY PURE
Makes the food more delicious and wholesome
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
SHARER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cu.ts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
oases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs "or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract.    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Aethuk Bbuce,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific Jlmcrlca.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific Journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $1.  Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN &Co.36lBfoadwa>' New York
Branch Office, 626 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHOEISED   KTJLES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Ordek must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
HAVE YOU ''COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
Chicago, 111.
The exponent of West Gate Philosophy.
A. new occult system.An unlimited field of labor open to teachers, lecturers
and healers.   Address,
The OBACLE, Sta. A.    Boston, Mass.
to advanced thought peoplesample copy of the most, original and
practical occult iournal of the age.
FREE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>