<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0806" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18780601" TEIform="date">June 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">126-152</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p>Vol. VIII. NO. 6. JUNE. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE
                        UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT WATERVLIET, N. Y. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD.'! 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT
                        SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. <pb id="p2"/> The Supernatural Our Social Relations Rational Funerals
                        Waiting Indians No. 4. The Essenes The Shaker Novitiate Covenant Christ in the order of male and female Ann Lee Can
                        Christians fight? Scintillations from Peebles 127 128 130 132 132 133 13G 137 I 138 140 141 Correspondence 142 The
                        Shaker Manifesto :—Preaching of Songs 142 Editorial Notes 144 For the Children 145 Home Topics 146 Farm and Garden
                        147 Selected 148 Music 150 Fill the Lungs 152 The Impersonality of Truth 152 TEEMS OF ADVERTISING. For one inch, one
                        insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column, " " $ 3. 00 one " " * " $ 6. 00 page, " " $12.00 Continued insertion for three
                        months, 20 per ct. discount. " six " 25 " " " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address, N. A.
                        Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription will begin when order is received.—No back numbers. CONTENTS.</p>
                    --><pb n="127" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL. VIII.—
                        JUNE. 1878.—No. VI</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Supernatural" TEIform="index"/>THE SUPERNATURAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName">ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">A belief in the supernatural, in intercommunion of spirits with mortals in some form,—is as
                            old as the history of our race. This belief, under whatever name it has passed, has been to
                            human kind, like the fructifying rays of the sun in spring time. However different its modes
                            of application, to meet unfolding conditions, as we trace it through the history of past
                            ages, it has been the same soul-pervading, absorbing element, in effect, from the day that
                            the angel of the God visited Hagar by the fountain of water in a wilderness, until our own
                            time. We trace the same undying trust in especial providences—in angel ministrations- good
                            and evil omens—visions, revelations and prophetic inspirations in every age and cycle of
                            human existence. What greater evidence could be given, that the essential soul-part in man
                            and woman, lives on eternally in spheres above and beyond the earthly stage of existence?
                            and that there is one Source and Center of life and light, from which the strong
                            faith-living hopes, thoughts and desires, have come down to us in one unbroken chain. We
                            need to be clear-sighted not to impute imperfections of historians in many instances to real
                            events as they transpired, and thus judge that the chain, if not broken, was inperfectly
                            linked together. It is stated that "God created every herb of the field before it grew." The
                            plan was formed, but there could be no expansion or growth-no outward expression—until the
                            Creative Power in the inner worlds stimulated and quickened the germs, each in its proper
                            order and place. From inorganic matter, through animated nature up to man, the acme, we
                            trace God's handiwork, and mark His footprints ; but in man and woman alone do we find the
                            dual image of the great and good Powers that formed and gave birth to worlds, and peopled
                            them with intelligent beings capable of reasoning with God the Father, and of entering into
                            close communion with the Heavenly Mother and rejoicing in her love. God breathed this dual
                            life into man and woman-in-spirited-and gave them living souls ; and placed them a little
                            lower than the angels, and endowed them with capacity to hold communion with intelligent
                            beings, both in the terrestrial, and celestial spheres. Hence, the never dying faith in
                                super<pb n="128" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 128 THIC SHAKKB MANIFESTO. natural agencies which has been
                            apparent in all ages, tribes and nations ; however crude their ideas may have been, yet they
                            have had their deities, and forms of worship, and belief in some great overruling Spirit
                            that controlled destinies. That belief has been a vitalizing principle in human hearts—a
                            preserver if not the main spring of action. Pagans have had their oracles—kings, their
                            prophets ; Hindoos, their One invisible God, manifested through millions of spirits, whom
                            they approached through the mediumistic agencies, and chanted praises in conjunction with
                            the Spirits of Singing Stars. Greece and Rome had their temples of deities, where miraculous
                            cures were performed—their consecrated mountains and grottoes where they worshiped, and
                            their deep caverns held so sacred that they were guarded by nymphs. Some of those caverns
                            were so sacredly esteemed that they were visited by people from all the surrounding States,
                            and Nations ; even kings and law-givers went to consult the oracles there. Those caverns
                            were usually guarded by females, who were required to dress in simple style, and to be
                            strictly pure and temperate in life. It is quite possible that those caverns were vaulted
                            sepulchers of some of the early Christians, who fled to, or built caves in the earth in
                            which to hide from the ruthless rage of their persecutors, and where thousands lived arid
                            died. Would it be unreasonable to suppose, that having been thwarted in their mission in
                            earth life, that by permission, or command, they should return in spirit, and from the
                            mouths of the very caverns, where they suffered for the maintenance of principles that were
                            dearer to them than life,—speak truths in the ears of the people through anointed mediums,
                            that they were not permitted to pronounce while in human form ? There may have been more
                            "method thaa madness" in those cavern utterances. If the avenues between the visible and
                            invisible worlds had been entirely closed to mortals, long ere this would the race to which
                            we belong have perished or become extinct. Now, as in the past, there are false prophets or
                            mediums extant in the land ; such mediums are false in their own life practices, and are
                            liable to be ministered to by spirits who are like them. Others, who live purely and truly,
                            receive ministrations from a divine source—from spirits who scale the ladder of truth that
                            leads to higher circles in spirit life. Faith in spirit intercourse was never more prevalent
                            among aarth's inhabitants, than at the present time. Multitudes openly avow their belief,
                            while others less honest,—or through fear of losing popularity, resemble Saul of old- en
                            time who disguised himself and went secretly to the woman of Endor—a materializing
                            medium,—and sought an interview with the spirit of Samuel. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our social relations" TEIform="index"/>OUR SOCIAL RELATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName">O. C. HAMPTON</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Perhaps it may appear reasonable tosome persons, that mankind should be good merely for the
                            abstract, intrinsic value of goodness in itself; and consequently in the pursuit of it, we
                            should not confer with any motives looking to the securing of our own happiness, considering
                            this would be directly selfish. This argument seems plausible to <pb n="129" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THIS
                            SHAKER 139 some minds. To others, however, it seems to have no foundation in common sense
                            but an insane attempt to stand upon nothing. We once asked one oi these transcendental
                            persons this ques- tion : Suppose you loved God or good, with all the unselfish noble
                            disinterestedness attainable, and he should decide to consign you,—soul and body—to a
                            burning hell fire forever ; do you think you could have so much devotion and love for Him
                            and so little reference to your own happiness, as to go on loving God for his own sake, and
                            good for its own sake, the same, as if your devotion and love ultimated in your own eternal
                            blessing and happiness?* This brought him at once face to face with the extreme results of
                            his own theory, and he paused for a time as if undecided, whether to take the fearful leap
                            over the precipice of insane attachment to his creed, or risk his condemnation by desiring
                            his own happiness. But he deliberated not long. Insanity was more than a match for him—his
                            creed was inexorable and over he went. If social relations could possibly be built upon such
                            foundational theories as this, they would be worth nothing when obtained. Neither would they
                            add one atom to the sum of human weal, albeit they might add infinitely to the woe thereof.
                            But near of kin to this error, is another, which is this, that the soul's progress to higher
                            perfections necessitates an everlasting increase of cross, more and more painful conditions
                            of d'scipline as we go farther and farther Heavenward forever. * This, to us, appears to beg
                            the question, for, such a decision and consignment, without just cause could not, possibly
                            proceed from a good source, it is contrary to the nature of goodness-----Editor. This
                            doctrine is another Calvinistic abomination annihilating every bit of the light, peace, and
                            freedom legitimately belonging to the gospel scheme. Besides it is a superstitious error,
                            and that is the least of its bad qualities. It represses ardor, extinguishes hope and
                            kindles the flames of a hell of a suicidal despair. Persons who are brought conscientiously
                            to believe in such gloomy doctrines, must necessarily become gloomy, disconsolate and unable
                            to minister comfort and contentment of mind, to those around them. These tenets for this
                            reason are poor material (nay, worse than none,) out of which to evolve the warm magnetism
                            of the social state. The best argument against them however is to be found in the invaluable
                            archives of experience. And though it would be easy to deduce their falsity from the very
                            bedrock of reason and common sense, yet absolutely impregnable proofs are to be afforded
                            from a gospel experience and progress, to higher and holier conditions ; and these proofs
                            are within the daily, practical reach, all the time. We have been more than half a century
                            laboring, and earnestly reaching, after greater perfection in practical purity and personal
                            righteousness. Over every single one of those years have been able to look back and notice
                            an unmistakable improvement, both as to fitness for the comforts and joys of communistic
                            life, and also in individual goodness. Each one of these years, have some of the low
                            rudimentalisms of our natures been swept from the path of existence, never more to return.
                            And with these have gone all the painful discipline neo- MA.TNTXF'ICSTO. <pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 13O essary to enable us to slough them off. Each one of these years, after we had plowed,
                            sowed and reaped the harvest of the year's labor, we have, uniformly found more good wheat
                            and less tares ; and have rejoiced therein more, and suffered less than the previous one.
                            Throughout all these years we have diminished the necessities for bondage, and opened wider
                            the fair vista of freedom which of late years seems to stretch away into the almost infinite
                            "Liberty of the sons (and daughters) of God.!' Where now are those feelings of painful
                            pressure and severe discipline of self, which we felt absolutely indispensable in earlier
                            experience, to subdue the lower elements and produce material fit for the growth of the
                            higher, elements of life ; together with the days and nights of trials, temptations and
                            tears? "Gone, all,—to mingle with the years beyond the flood." And though the ghosts of the
                            sorrows of yore, stalk silently in the dim and distant galleries of memory, yet they only
                            bring up by contrast, a feeling of more serene peace and security ; like unto the mariner,
                            who, for years tossed on the billows of the ocean, is at last safely moored within harbor,
                            hearing, only the distant boom of the terrible tempest. Even external confidence has been
                            gradually developed in others, with whom we hold responsible relations, who might be easily
                            excused for not being able to trust our inexperience, when we could not trust it ourselves.
                            Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We want less of creeds, but more trust..." TEIform="index"/>We want less of creeds, but more trust...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We want less of creeds, but more trust; less of ceremony, but more of work; less of
                            solemnity, but more genial honesty; less doctrine, but more of love.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rational funerals" TEIform="index"/>RATIONAL FUNERALS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">ELDER F. W. EVANS</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">A year or two ago the American Soialist published an article upon "Shakr Burials." It has
                            been going the rounds of the press ever since. A few weeks ago the New York Times had a
                            cleverly-written burlesque of the same of two columns. Now the Pittsfield Eagle republishes
                            the original article with some happy remarks. It says : "The coffins of the Shakers are made
                            of good pine timber, with neither paint nor veneering, vamish, glittering metal nor any
                            ornamentation whatever about them. A pane of glass near the head of the coffin permits the
                            friends to take a last look upon the face of the dead ; and the pall is a simple white
                            cloth. The funeral discourse consists of a few kindly Avords for the good the departed had
                            done, or of candid criticism of faults and weaknesses, that others might know how to avoid
                            them. It would be a great relief to the poor and middle classes to have Shaker funerals
                            become as popular as Shaker brooms and garden-seeds." Generations avIio have drawn their
                            sustenance from the earth should contribute at death to the support of those who follow
                            after. Burial grounds should be converted into public parks; the graves twenty feet apart,
                            at each grave a tree upon which the name of the deceased may be cut, as Virgil wrote ages
                            ago: "The rind of every tree a name shall know, And as the rind extends the name will grow."
                            Soon there would be splendid groves of valuable timber all through the nation, ornamental
                            and sanitary, instead of the unsightly and wasteful common graveyards, or the extravagantly
                            expensive cemeteries of Auburn and Greenwood. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. <pb n="131" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER 131 Two old grave-yards at Mt. Lebanon are planted with ti'ees, with head-stones
                            removed. From an article published in the Sunday Sun Feb. 17, upon the Chibehas, a
                            pre-historic people of South America, I quote : "According to Ballart, the mass of the
                            people were buried with their jewels, arms and food, in the open country, with no other sign
                            but a tree to mark their grave." Nothing new under the sun ; what is has been, and what has
                            been will be reproduced. The trees were rational; the burial of treasures and sacrifice of
                            friends irrational. From some of those cemeteries vast quantities of objects of gold and
                            deer's horns have been taken. Near Bogota, 24,000 ducats' worth of gold was extracted at one
                            time. In 1535, in the province of Carthagena, an immense number of burial-grounds were
                            found, so ancient that tall trees were growing upon them, from which cemeteries the
                            Spaniards are said to have realized a million ducats. Golden emeralds, medals, serpents,
                            eagles, mitres and crosiers, crescents, bracelets, rings and beetle-shaped figures were
                            found of the same metal. A golden porcupine, weighing five arambas and a half; also the
                            image of a boy holding a stone for grinding music, all of gold. In a temple were found
                            ingots, tiles, and figures of men, birds, serpents and insects, in fine gold. Look at these
                            ancient, pre-historic evidences of national customs in the earlier ages of the human race.
                            Schliemann is unearthing treasures of Eastern people buried with the dead. Recently he took
                            $25,000 from one tomb, and altogether has made his immense labors pay. The loss to a nation
                            with such irrational habits of burial is incalculable. Take ancient Egypt. The labors of her
                            people, that were worse than wasted upon the dead, must have been sufficient to banish
                            poverty from the whole nation. Her embalming of humans and animals was immensely expensive,
                            enough so to have impoverished any other nation, not as rich as Egypt. Moses wisely reversed
                            this whole national practice, and instead of embalming the dead made it a defilement to
                            touch a dead body ; and instead of a grave being a place to visit, it was a place to be
                            avoided. For forty years the Israelites were buried in the wilderness, and their bodies went
                            to enrich the land that furnished them their manna. In an economical, rational point of
                            view, simple Shaker burials, with the planting at each grave of a timber-tree as above
                            suggested, would save millions of property, now lost, and add millions in valuable timber to
                            each coming generation, as the result of adopting a system of Rational Burials. The doctrine
                            of the resurrection of the body is the foundation of the honors paid to the body after the
                            soul has left it. Spiritualism, which proves that the soul exists in spirit-life independent
                            of the body, annihilates the doctrine of a physical resurrection. Shakers being
                            Spiritualists repudiate the physical resurrection, and dispose of "remains" in accordance
                            with the idea of "dust to dust;" hence their strictly Rational Funerals. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a glorious occupation..." TEIform="index"/>It is a glorious occupation...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is a glorious occupation, vivifying and self-sustaining in its nature, to struggle with
                            ignorance and discover to the inquiring minds of the masses the clear, cerulean blue of
                            heavenly truth.</p></div2><pb n="132" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waiting" TEIform="index"/>WAITING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dore, Lizzie C." TEIform="persName">LIZZIE C. DORE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Who of mature years has not sometimes lifted his eyes in mute envy to great Nature which is
                            so calmly waiting? Every heart lives in the expectation of a time to come. But the floods of
                            time have often swept away all the old landmarks of the past ere the expected season
                            arrives. Only those are worthy of the noblest things, who have exercised God's gift of
                            patience—who have proven their firmness and ability by remembering that waiting does not
                            mean, to single out some object or desire and sit down listlessly by the way-side, waiting
                            for the wheel of fortune, in its revolutions, to cast the treasure at our feet, while we are
                            anticipating our own cherished joys, we can perform, daily and hourly, work for our brethren
                            and sisters. We can wait when we are tempted to censure; we can wait before uttering the
                            unkind retort; we can wait a thousand times upon the weakness of others. And when we have
                            ceased to question, whether life has most sour or sweet, and have learned to make doing good
                            the burden and care of life, God will send to us in some quiet noon-time the reward for all
                            loss, all pain, all grief, and in the hush of that holy hour, our souls will grow stronger,
                            and we shall yearn for a larger and closer inheritance, with Him who is waiting for our
                            perfection. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 4</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">JAMES S. PRESCOTT</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> When human rights are invaded it moves to action the discordant elements of human society
                            and arouses the combative principle; and when these gain the ascendancy over the moral and
                            spiritual faculties, they lead to "bruteforce," which terminates in war and bloodshed. All
                            wars are antichrist and demoralizing to the morals of the people ; and those nations which
                            engage in wars, calling themselves Christian are against Christ, and nearly two thousand
                            years behind the age. It is said on good authority that within the last seventy five years
                            the United States have expended more than a thousand millions of dollars, besides
                            sacrificing thousands of human lives in carrying on wars with the Indians. If we look into
                            the cause of these vast expenditures and sacrifice of lives, we shall find that all wars
                            originate from the violation of human rights, in one form, or another, and sometimes on both
                            sides, these choosing rather to settle their difficulties with the sword than by peaceful
                            arbitration. What was it that brought on the war of the American Revolution? It was the
                            violation of human rights. It was "taxation without representation." And what was that but
                            an invasion of human rights? What was it that brought on the war with England in 1812? It
                            was the violation of human rights—the law of "free trade, and sailors' rights." What was it
                            that brought on the war with Mexico ? It was the violation of the international law of human
                            rights. What was it that brought on the Florida war ? It was the invasion of human rights.
                            What was it that brought on the "civil war" between the North and South in the U. S. ? It
                            was the violation of human rights, caused by holding four millions of human beings in
                            oppression under a free govern<pb n="133" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> 133 ment, and not allowing them any
                            rights before the law whereby they could gc redress for their grievances. What was it that
                            brought on the war with the Indians on our western borders? It was caused by robbing them of
                            their jus rights ; by punishing the innocent and letting the guilty white man go free and
                            this kind of vicarious atonement wil never apply to the Indians, without pro- voking
                            hostilities, because of its gros injustice. The Indian believes that "he that doeth wrong
                            ought to suffer for the wrong he doeth," whether he be a white man or an Indian ; and we
                            cannot see why the Indian is not right in his con elusions. The same cause brought on all
                            the Indian wars for the last two hundred years. It was, in not giving them equal rights
                            before the law, whereby they could get redress for their grievances. When solemn treaties
                            are made and entered into with the Indians, the same as with civilized nations, and ratified
                            by the highest authority in the U. S. government; and then treating them as outlaws and
                            vagabonds, having no rights; hunted, and shot down, as wild beasts of prey, we say it is an
                            outrage upon humanity and a disgrace to our civilization. The law of human rights is not
                            only invaded but has been grossly violated on the part of the U. S. agency or by
                            irresponsible persons connected with it in dealing with the Indians. This is proved from
                            official documents iv. the "Reports of the Commissioner of Indian Affairs." We believe
                            however, that there are some honorable exceptions in the U. S« agency. It would not be
                            creditable noj" complimentary to our nation, to say, that out of forty millions of people in
                            the U. S. there were not some honest and honorable men employed in the Indian agency. We
                            believe there are many, and espe- cially so, was Gen. Grant's Quaker Agency. But, it must be
                            admitted, that in the best of families a black sheep is sometimes found ; or having "black
                            legs" at least, even as among the twelve elected ones, there was one Judas ; but this did
                            not make them all dishonest. When the first founders of the American Republic openly avowed
                            and publicly declared before the world, "that all men were created equal, and endowed with
                            certain inalienable rights among which were life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness," we
                            believe they were inspired to pen that document, and they were honest, and earnest in their
                            declaration, and that it was intended to be just as applicable to the African, and to the
                            Indian of the forest, as it was to the venerable Fathers themselves, who gave utterance to
                            such noble sentiments. All men means all races, colors, and peoples ; red, copper, black,
                            and white, and the Indians were included in this equality. Hence in denying the Indian this
                            equal- ity before the law, is a flagrant violation of human rights. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Essenes" TEIform="index"/>THE ESSENES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Josephus, Flavius" TEIform="persName">Flavius Josephus</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">There are among the Jews, three Philosophical Sects, distinguished by the different
                            denominations of Pharisees, Sadducees, and Essenes, which last maintain a more rigid
                            discipline than the rest. The Essenes are Jews by birth, and seem to have a greater
                            affection for one another than the rest of the Sects. THE SHARER MANXF-ICSTO. <pb n="134" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 134 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. They reject pleasure as an evil; but esteem
                            continence and a conquest over the passions, as a cardinal virtue. They neglect wedlock ;
                            but select the children of others, while they are young and docile, and adopt and train them
                            up as their own. They do not absolutely deny the moral fitness of marriage, and the
                            succession of mankind continued thereby, but guard against the frailty of women, and can
                            hardly admit an inviolable attachment to one man. They hold wealth, and what are called the
                            good things of this world in con- tempt ; so that they are equally strangers to riches and
                            poverty, as they have all things in common; or, in other words, the whole society live like
                            brethren ; being all equal sharers in one common patrimony: upon such principle, no man can
                            be contemptible for being poor, nor honorable for being rich. They think oil a defilement,
                            and value themselves upon the simplicity of their appearance, provided their garments are
                            white and clean. They appoint stewards for the man- agement of their common stock, and leave
                            it to their discretion to make distribution out of it to every man in proportion according
                            to his need. They have no certain place of abode, but disperse themselves through different
                            cities, towns and villages, where they are ever open to receive and entertain any of their
                            own sect, and treat them, though strangers, with the same familiarity as if intimately
                            acquainted. They carry nothing with them, when they travel, but arms for the security of
                            their persons. They appoint, in every place, some one to take care of their strange
                            Brethren, and provide them with lodging, food, apparel, and necessaries n general. The dress
                            they wear rensembles that of children when they are under the charge of masters and
                            governors. Nor do they change their garments, or shoes, but when one is torn, and the other
                            worn out. They neither buy nor sell, among themselves, but supply each-other's wants ; not
                            by way of exchange, but an obligation on the one party to give, and the other to receive.
                            Their piety towards God is extraordinary, as they never speak a word of the common affairs
                            of life before sunrise, but, upon certain traditional forms of prayer, imploring divine
                            protection for the day. After this act of devotion they betake themselves to their several
                            occupations and employments in which they labor, with great diligence to aru hour before
                            noon, when they assemble in white veils, and bathe in cold water. Upon this purification
                            they retire to their apartments into which it is not permitted to any one of another sect to
                            enter. From thence they enter into a refectory or dining hall, as into an holy temple, and
                            sit down without uttering a word. The attendants place their loaves in order, and bring each
                            one a plate of a, single kind of food, which is not touched, before the priest pronounces a
                            blessing ; and in like manner he returns thanks to the Divine Donor, after meat. This duty
                            performed, they lay aside their white garments, as in some degree sacred, and resume their
                            ordinary occupations till evening; when they return tosupper in the same manner, and, if
                            there be any strangers they sit down with: them. Their houses are free from clamor and
                            disturbance. They speak by turns, and observe a gravity and silence which excite the
                            veneration of stran<pb n="135" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THJC SHAKER MANIFESTO. 135 eers, and arise from a
                            constant course of moderation and sobriety. Every man is free to help the virtuous, though
                            they are restrained from relieving their kindred, without permission from their superiors.
                            They curb their passions, and are eminent for their fidelity, and preserving peace and good
                            order. Their word is as sacred as an oath, which they avoid as worse than perjury,
                            accounting man, who cannot be believed without bringing God for a witness, as a liar, and
                            unworthy of confidence. When a person is disposed to become a member of the society, he is
                            not immediately admitted but prescribed the mode of living for one whole year, and presented
                            with an axe, a girdle, and a white garment. If, in that course of time he has given evidence
                            of his continence, they, in some respects, change his diet, and allow him the benefit of the
                            water of purification. But, he is not permitted to enter the refectory, till he has passed
                            two years probation of his integrity, upon which trial he is taken into the society upon the
                            following conditions. He is first to bind himself by solemn declarations to love and worship
                            God, and observe justice towards man, to injure no one. of his own accord, nor at the
                            command or persuasion of others ; to declare himself an enemy to the wicked, and a friend to
                            the righteous ; to show fidelity to all men, and especially to those in authority ; as they
                            are the ministers of God ; by His own appointment. He is likewise to declare, that, if ever
                            he should attain to an elevated station, he will never abuse that power to the injury of
                            those who are subordinate to him, nor distinguish himself by any peculiar ornament of dress;
                            that he will love, and embrace the truth, and reprove those who speak falsehood. He binds
                            himself also, to keep his hands free from theft, and fraudulent dealing, and his mind [from
                            the desire of unlawful gains. Those who are detected in heinous offences are excluded from
                            the society, and generally come to a miserable end, as they are bound, by an oath not to
                            receive even a morsel of bread from the hand of a stranger, and thus compelled to graze like
                            beasts till they perish. In this distress the society sometimes compassionates a case, and
                            receives the delinquent again, deeming the punishment, in some degree, an atonement for the
                            of- fence. In the administration of justice they are singularly strict, determining nothing
                            without the concurrence at least of an hundred voices ; and from their sentence, once
                            passed, there is no appeal. Next to the supreme authority of God himself, they hold in
                            reverence that of their Legislator, Moses—whom, if any one blasphemes, he is punished with
                            death—they ascribe great honor to their Elders, and to a majority of the people, deeming it
                            highly reasonable to obey the one, and hearken to the other. When there are ten members in
                            council, no par- ticular one is to speak, if the other nine are against it. They hold it
                            indecent, and even immoral, to spit toward the middle of the assembly, or upon the right
                            hand of it. They observe the Sabbath with greater strictness than any other sect of the
                            Jews; as they not only prepare their food the preceding day, to avoid kindling a fire upon
                            that day, but will not move a utensil from one place to another. <pb n="136" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 136
                            THE SHAKER They live to a great age, many of them to an hundred years, and upwards, which
                            must be ascribed to the simplicity of their diet, and their temperance in general. They are
                            also firm and hardy, contemning the miseries of life, and accounting an honorable death more
                            desirable than an inglorious existence. Upon divers occasions neither burning, nor the most
                            exquisite torture could force from them an irreverent word of their Legislator, (Moses,) or
                            the breach of one of their rites. Tortures they endured, not only without supplication and
                            tears but with cheerfulness of countenance, defying their tormentors, and yielding up their
                            breath with serenity and composure, in the assurance of exchanging the present life for a
                            better in the future. They firmly believe the mortality of the body, and, that the soul,
                            being of the nature of the subtilist air, is incor- ruptible and immortal, and, by a kind of
                            attraction enclosed in the body, as in a prison ; but, that when it shall be freed from
                            these corporeal bonds, or from a long slavery, it shall ascend to the re- gions of bliss.
                            There are those among the Essenes who pretend to the spirit of prophecy, founding their
                            presages upon holy writ, and using preparatory purifications to fit them for the work ; and
                            it is observ- able that they seldom fail in their predictions.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker novitiate covenant" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER NOVITIATE COVENANT</head><byline TEIform="byline">DRAWN UP BY, <persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName">ELDER H. L. EADES</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Whereas, I, the undersigned, have this day attached myself as probationa- ry member to the
                            United Society of Believers at (----------------------------------¦ -----------------------)
                            and it being my desire to live with said Society according to the known faith and customs
                            thereof, that I may receive the benefits arising from the observance of the rules,
                            regulations, moral, and religious instructions of the same. Therefore, agreeably to the
                            custom of said Society, I hereby covenant, promise and agree, that I will never pre- fer any
                            account, claim, nor demand against the said Society, or any member or members thereof, for
                            the Use of any money or property brought into said Society, nor for any labor or service
                            which I may perform or render while residing in the same, over and above what I may receive
                            in food, clothing, washing, and other necessary support: And, whereas, it is further
                            mutually understood and agreed that I shall be free to withdraw from said Society whenever I
                            am dissatisfied therewith, and that after sufficient and timely notice shall have been given
                            by me I shall receive all the money and other property which I brought into said Society, or
                            their value at the time it was brought in. Therefore I further agree and promise that so
                            long as I am permitted to enjoy the benefits and privileges of said Society I will
                            faithfully conform to the rules thereof, and will not find fault with the said rules,
                            require- ments, regulations, worship nor teachings, by acting or speaking against the same
                            so as to create dissatisfaction, disunion, or inharmony in the family ; provided this shall
                            not be so construed as to prevent a free and respectful inquiry of the leading authority
                            into the reasons of said rules and regulations ; and if I shall Pail to comply with this
                            agreement such. MAJsrrF'icsTO. <pb n="137" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE 137 failure shall be deemed
                            sufficient cause for loss of membership with said Society, and upon being desired so to do
                            by the leading authority of the family in which I reside, will peaceably withdraw from the
                            same. Witness my hand the—day of—A.D.18— Attest:--------South Union, Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ in the order of male and female" TEIform="index"/>Christ in the order of Male and
                            Female</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">ELDER F. W. EVANS</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">The question may be asked : If Christ be the Son of God, the second Adam, the Lord from
                            heaven, of whom the first Adam was a figure,—Where is the second Eve, the Bride? Answer : It
                            is according to the figure when "their name was called Adam," before the woman was
                            separated. So was the Christ when they first descended in the form of a dove from heaven,
                            and lighted upon Jesus. To this important fact we have the clear testimony of Christ's
                            witness,— John,—who says "Ye yourselves bear me witness, that I said, I am not the Christ;
                            but that I am sent before him, to bear witness of him;" adding, "He that hath the Bride is
                            the Bridegroom. But the friend of the Bridegroom, who standeth and heareth him, rejoiceth
                            greatly because of the Bridegroom's voice. This my joy therefore is fulfilled. He must
                            increase ; but I must decrease. He that cometh from above is above all." (John ill. 28, 29.)
                            Did Jesus come from above? Nay! "He was made of a woman ;" "made under the law,"—born in a
                            stable. uHe" (Jesus) "that is of the earth, is earthy; and speaketh of the earth." uHe"
                            (Christ) "that cometh from heaven is above all; and what he hath seen and heard, that he
                            testifieth ;" as he said, "I proceeded forth and came from God." (John viii. 42.) Here,
                            then, we have the testimony of John, that this wras the Christ, the Bridegroom; and that the
                            Bride was with him. He already '•'•hath the Bride;" -which Bride had yet to be manifested in
                            a chosen vessel of her own order,—a female whom God would, in the time appointed, prepare
                            and raise up for that very purpose. This would be the second appearing of Christ; and this
                            is the reason why there must of necessity be a second appearing. The first Adam made his
                            second appearing in Eve, the mother of all living. The second Adam must needs do the same,
                            by appearing the second time in a second Eve, the Mother of all living in the new creation ;
                            or evidently the figure would not be fulfilled. And, like as there was no natural offspring,
                            until after the appearance of the first Eve ; so neither could there be any spiritual
                            offspring, or true Christians, "sons and daughters of God," until after the appearing of the
                            second Eve, in and through a natural woman, even as the first appearing of Christ was in and
                            through a natural man. Therefore it is our province to testify to mankind, that Christ has
                            made "his second appearance," in and, through the female order, "without sin unto salvation,
                            to those who look for him," as assuredly as he ever made his first appearance in and through
                            the male order eighteen centuries ago. And, in so doing, we explain why the primitive
                            Christians only saw things "as through a glass darkly," "knew but in part," and could only
                            prophesy of the <pb n="138" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 138 THE SHAKER MAJNTOTESTO. other "part" :—why they
                            cried "Abba, Father," by the spirit of adoption only, and not as real sons and daughters :—¦
                            [they, being only "a kind of first fruits," were "groaning within themselves, and waiting
                            for the manifestation of the sons (and daughters) of God," in the future :] —and why all the
                            doctrines of real Christianity, revealed in that day, have been either perverted, entirely
                            lost sight of, or are rendered of none effect, as to the salvation of the soul from sin, or
                            of the body from physical suffering, by antichristian traditions and commentaries. Also, we
                            render an intelligent reason, even to the Materialist, as to why there had to be two
                            appearings of Christ at all, and we show how, and in what way and manner, these two
                            appearings could and have taken place. We say, if the people called Shakers do not exhibit
                            and show forth, with an increase, before all men, the faith, spirit, doctrines, and
                            principles of the primitive Church, together with power over evil, (in their own souls,)let
                            that decide the whole question. But if they do give incontrovertible evidence of living in
                            possession of all these spiritual gifts and graces, and also of having that love one to
                            another which puts beyond a doubt their relationship to "the Author and" now the Finisher"
                            of the true and pure Christian faith, (by which love, he foretold that all men would be
                            enabled to "know" his disciples in his second appearing;) then, notwithstanding the words
                            and arguments which we set before you, if ye believe not that Christ has made his second ap-
                            pearance, yet, we still ask you to believe us for the very "works' sake." If Christ has
                            come, but has done no works that evidence the fact of his coming to the children of men,
                            then they do not sin in not believing and receiving him. But, if he has done the works, (in
                            and by his people,) which no other man ever did, then is there "no cloak" for those who see
                            and know it, for not closing in with and obeying the greatest manifestation of truth that
                            has ever been made upon the earth. We close, with feelings of love and kindness towards all
                            our fellow-creatures, however much they may differ from us in works, or upon this or any
                            other subject; being confident, that time, and the inevitable course of events, will clearly
                            and satisfactorily demonstrate the entire truth of the above testimony. And that Holy and
                            Eternal Mother Love, will yet be fully revealed and made known to all rational, intelligent
                            souls, whether in or out of their mortal bodies ; and also, that then will the firstborn
                            Daughter,—"Love," the Heavenly Mother of the new creation of God,— the spiritual order, be
                            "justified of all her children" in Zion, who, by words and works, have borne faithful
                            witness to her existence and appearance, to redeem the lost sons and daughters of earth. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, fourth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE Her
                            work, her People, and their Critics Fourth Paper.</head><p TEIform="p"> It is not possible at this late day, to know precisely what were the inducements, that
                            attracted Mother Ann and her faithful few to the wild, swampy district of Watervliet, where
                            now stands the beautiful Church Family ; and we are left to conjecture that the reasons
                            were, preferences of seclusion, to the <pb n="139" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SECAJKIDR MLAJSTIFVIDSTO.
                            139 continual embarrassments of persecution and imprisonment. It is certain, however, that
                            no spot within an area of miles would better answer the description given their location— "a
                            dark and dreary wilderness." A few acres were secured by John Hocknell, and a log house
                            erected, about three hundred rods North of the present Center family, and in this they lived
                            for three and a half years; and herein, and contiguous to it, they held their very solemn
                            meetings, which soon created intense excitement, calling out many investigators. It was at
                            this place, that, the company being too great for the limits of the house, that Mother Ann
                            addressed the people from the doorway, saying: "We have but little room in our house, but we
                            have a great deal of room in our hearts." In the year 1779 a deeply religious revival was
                            enacted at New Lebanon, N. Y. among the Baptists, under the leadership of Joseph Meacham. Of
                            its being a revival of the real Christian religion, in distinction to the bubbling so-called
                            revivals of later times, it may be stated, that it led to an earnest looking after, and
                            preparation for the Second Coming of Christ; which preparation caused them to change their
                            lives as far ns they could, conformably to the life of Jesus; and did not result, as
                            commonly in these days, in an increase of marriages commensurate with the zeal of the
                            revival spirit. As before stated, exciting rumors had gone abroad, concerning Mother Ann and
                            her peculiar faith and testimony, some of these ru. mors being construed into deadly
                            ridicule and hate, others, prompting investigation. Having held his Church under the baptism
                            of the revival spirit, as long as he coiild without assistance, and looking around for
                            relief, Elder Meacham, hearing ofthe strange people forty miles distant, despatched
                            messengers of inquiry, who returned with the most glowing accounts of what they had seen,
                            heard and felt, and demonstrating to their people that "these people are from God, having
                            the very gospel of Christ for which we have been waiting." Then, in the spring of 1780, did
                            the gospel, now known as Shakerism, open in earnest. Very many members of the Churches of
                            New Lebanon, N. Y. and Hancock, Mass, visited Watervliet, heard the testimony of Mother Ann,
                            to return converts to the faith, that "Christ had verily made the second advent in and
                            through the testimony of this woman Ann Lee!" Among the rest, came Joseph Meacham himself.
                            He was a man of the sterner kind of material; not easily moved without just reasons ; and
                            until he had completely exhausted his batteries of opposition, he was determined not to
                            believe. It is stated, that having met and answered every other question of Meacham's, that
                            of her being a woman and a teacher finally came up for adjustment, Elder Meacham putting the
                            question in all' bluntness : "What right have you, a woman, to teacli or to preach, when the
                            scripture plainly forbids it?" With that readiness of reply for which Mother Ann was
                            notable, she simply answered: "When the man (Jesus) is gone, then the woman (Ann) has her
                            right!" This ended all controversy on Elder Meacham's part—was "the feather that broke his
                            camel's back"—and he immediately submitted himself to her instructions as simply as a little
                            child, returned to his people with the Shaker Cross, upon which he first crucified him- self
                            unto the world, and ever afterward held it up as the hope of the nations, and to his own
                            people in particular. Mother Ann termed him her "first-born son in America," and well did he
                            merit the honor. It became necessary, in consequence of the multiplicity of inquirers to
                            Watervliet, that some extra provisions should now and then be made, for the sustenance of
                            "the little flock;" and these were variously sent by those journeying thither for counsel
                            and instruction. The country being in the midst of its war for Independence, occasions were
                            sought by those inimical to the faith, to arouse public indignation. And it was while David
                            Darrow was on his way from Lebanon to Watervliet, driving a flock of sheep as a donation to
                            the founders of the faith, that he was followed by evil men, arrested, taken back to Lebanon
                            on a charge of treason, and was from there sent to Albany with Joseph Meacham, under guard,
                            to be there tried by commissioners for the great offense of treason. His sheep they stole,
                            dividing them among themselves. <pb n="140" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14O THIS SHAKER Being arraigned, they
                            were required to make such promises as were inconsistent with their faith, and they utterly
                            refused to do so. They, together with John Hocknell, were cast into prison; and soon after
                            Hczekiah Hammond, Joel Pratt, then Mother Ann' Mary Partington, William Lee, James Whittaker
                            and Calvin Harlow were arrested for the same cause, and kept, them company in incarceration.
                            Those Believers that were not arrested, were allowed communication with those in prison, and
                            to bring many comforts for their bodily sustenance; and it is our high honor to add, that
                            every kindness that could he accepted by them, was amply tendered by the citizens of Albany,
                            N. Y., an,l their descendants have never unto this day, learned to be unkind to us, the
                            people called Shakers ! It is remarkable, too, that while they were in bonds, they were
                            visited by many, who there became converts to the new faith, confessed their sins,
                            frequently in the midst of a crowd; and otherwise did the faith grow, in direct opposition
                            to the calculations of its enemies who had thus deeply planned its obliteration. Soon,
                            however, Mother Ann and Mary Partington were separated from the rest, taken to Ponghkeepsie,
                            N. Y., it being the intention of their persecutors to banish them to the British army then
                            lying at New York. Being foiled in this, they remained in prison, until Gov. George Clinton,
                            getting information of the outrage of imprisoning these par. ties for conscience' sake, when
                            the country was fighting for freedom of conscience, he speedily released them all, when with
                            the greatest joy, they returned to their swampy home, where they were visited by large
                            numbers from several of the eastern states, many of whom became converts. To those who would
                            read of the swampy eurroundings of this settlement in Watervliet, at that and a later date,
                            we refer them to The Shaker for June, 1877. Today, these swamps are nowhere to be seen ; but
                            instead, fertile fields occupy their places. During the great advent of Spiritualism among
                            us, between the years 1837 and 1841 John Rogers of martyr fame, came to our people and sung
                            the following hymn, which he asserted he, in company with one hundred other spirits had sung
                            on the spot where the Church now stands, more than fifty years before : the hymn was used
                            for many years afterward, in our celebrations upon the 6th of August: 'Come, lovely eagle,
                            Liberty, and free Columbia's shore; Break loose the bands that bind her, to old England's
                            power. For lo! a bright star has arisen in England, But severe persecution shall cause it to
                            flee To Columbia's siiore for protection. May God, in his wisdom hasten thy flight, Oh,
                            lovely eagle, Liberty! Come to Wisdom's Valley;* This is the place prepared for thee;
                            Though, now a dark and dreary wilderness, Yet it shall become a fruitful field. Come pretty
                            Mother—come pretty mother— We wait for thy coming—we invite thee to come!" * The spiritual
                            name that Watervliet was christened with at the great influx of Spiritualism before alluded
                            to. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Can Christians fight?" TEIform="index"/>CAN CHRISTIANS FIGHT?</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="May God hasten the time war shall be buried..." TEIform="index"/>May God hasten the time war shall be buried...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">May God hasten the time when war shall be buried—that grim old breaker of hearts. Carry
                                him out on a rusted shield. Put him down in the most desolate part of all the earth.
                                Bury his sword with him. Heap on his gravestone broken chariot wheels. Let widowhood and
                                orphanage clap their hands over his burial and the winds howl for requiem.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Talmadge" TEIform="persName">Talmadge</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War is the fruitful parent of crimes. It reverses all the rules of morality..." TEIform="index"/>War is the fruitful parent of crimes. It reverses all the rules of morality...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, Robert" TEIform="persName">Robert Hall</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> War is the fruitful parent of crimes. It reverses all the rules of morality. It is
                                nothing less than a temporary repeal of the prin- ciples of virtue. It is a system out
                                of which almost all the virtues are excluded, and in which nearly all the vices are
                                included. The morality of peaceful times is directly opposite to the maxims of war. The
                                fundamental rule of the first is to do good; of the latter to inflict injuries.—</p><p TEIform="p"> War is the barbarous custom of duelling extended to nations.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One murder makes a villain; millions a hero !" TEIform="index"/>One murder makes a villain; millions a hero!
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Porteus, Bishop" TEIform="persName">Bishop Porteus</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> One murder makes a villain;—millions a hero!—</p></div3><div3 type="aphorism" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We praise men for fighting, and punish children for doing the same thing" TEIform="index"/>We praise men for fighting, and punish children for doing the same thing
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We praise men for fighting, and punish children for doing the same thing.</p></div3><pb n="141" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The slavery of a soldier is worse than that of a negro" TEIform="index"/>The slavery of a soldier is worse than that of a negro
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The slavery of a soldier is worse than that of a negro.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Franklin" TEIform="persName">Franklin</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No two things are more opposed than the Christian..." TEIform="index"/>No two things are more opposed than the Christian...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> No two things are more opposed than the Christian and warlike spirit.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parley" TEIform="persName">Parley</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When will Christians learn that it is just as wrong to kill..." TEIform="index"/>When will Christians learn that it is just as wrong to kill...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">When will Christians learn that it is just as wrong to kill at the command of governments
                                as to do it of their own free wills.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The greatest of human calamities, after a defeat, is victory" TEIform="index"/>The greatest of human calamities, after a defeat, is victory
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The greatest of human calamities, after a defeat, is a victory.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wellington" TEIform="persName">Wellington</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The news of war, the description of cities taken, of victories won..." TEIform="index"/>The news of war, the description of cities taken, of victories won...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The news of war, the description of cities taken, of victories won, of men killed, are
                                of a poisonous moral influence. They paganize a Christian people. They make them forget
                                the sermon on the Mount, and the prayer on the Cross.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Livermore, A. A." TEIform="persName">A. A. Livermore</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whence is it that wars still disgrace the self-styled Christian world..." TEIform="index"/>Whence is it that wars still disgrace the self-styled Christian world...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Whence is it that wars still disgrace the self-styled Christian world! It is owing to the
                                doctrine of expediency. If Christians had boldly looked in the face of their duty, as
                                developed in the New Testament, this senseless infernal system of wholesale butchery
                                must long ago have ceased.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Southey, Robert" TEIform="persName">Robert Southey</persName></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scintillations from Peebles" TEIform="index"/>SCINTILLATIONS FROM PEEBLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Christianity, as it was uttered and lived by Jesus Christ, was divine ; but modern
                            Christianity, with its political intrigues, immense estates, aggressive wars, cramping
                            creeds, ceremonies, and superstitions, is a sham—a cancerous blotch upon the civilization of
                            the nineteenth century. Salvation is a process—a soul-growth—a blossoming and ripening up of
                            the spiritual nature. It comes to nations and to individuals through the Tau of the Chinese;
                            the Buddha of the Orientals; the Logos of John, and the Christ of the New Testament—comes as
                            vegetation, flowers, and golden harvests come through the warmth and light of the sun. This
                            Christ-principle is the "savor of life unto life." Demons are not necessarily spirits
                            peopling the spirit-world. The other day I hastily jumped into a third-class railway coach.
                            It was crowded with men, excitedly engaged in talking war, in swearing and cursing—three of
                            them were shamefully intoxicated. Listening to their babble, I wondered that so many good
                            and beautiful things come to us from over the river of death. So long as men put such filthy
                            and poisonous stuff' into their bodies, as tobacco, and beer, and swine's flesh, so long
                            will war continue on earth, and the dying swell the demon-sphere of existence. The body must
                            be purified. The very atomic materials must be hyper-vitalized and spiritualized. Herbs,
                            nuts, vegetables, precious grains, and delicious fruits, ripening in the sunlight, deposit
                            such rich and refined tissue* only, as can build up a pure bodily temple for the soul. True
                            and genuine Spiritualism is the gospel of Jesus Christ; and the good spirits come to us to
                            demonstrate a future conscious existence ; to guide our feet in the paths of virtue and
                            wisdom ; to comfort all that mourn, and lead us into the green pastures of purity and peace.
                            The light of their love is the sunshine of our souls. They call upon us to overcome the
                            world—to create the heaven now that we hope to enjoy hereafter. Spirit-life is an active
                            life, a social life, a retributive life, a constructive life, and a pro- gressive life.
                            Eeason and affection, conscience and memory, go with us into the future state of existence.
                            It is real life. Spiritualism settles three questions of momentous import: I. That man has a
                            conscious existence beyond the grave. II. That all individuals commence that existence
                            precisely as they leave this, mentally and morally, retaining their identity and memory.
                            III. That this future existence is one of mental progress and spiritual unfoldment for all
                            human intelligences. </p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little boy who went to church was told to remember the text..." TEIform="index"/>A little boy who went to church was told to remember the text...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A little boy who went to church was told to remember the text, which was: "Why stand ye here
                            all the day idle? Go into my vineyard and work, and whatsoever is right, that I will pay
                            thee." Johnny came home and was asked to repeat the text. He thought over it awhile, and
                            then cried out; "What do you stand round here doing nuffin', for? Go into vnj barnyard and
                            work, and I'll make it all right with yon."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="142" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Shaker, Dear Brother : Last Sabbath, came to hand our beautiful Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>Editor Shaker, Dear Brother : Last Sabbath, came to hand our beautiful Manifesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, North Union, May 1, 1878" TEIform="index"/>North Union, Ohio. May 1, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker, Dear Brother : Last Sabbath, came to hand our beautiful Manifesto, calling
                                to mind the "Tree of life," yielding its fruit every month, and whose "leaves are for
                                the healing of the nations." And if these truths—these life freighted leaves do not
                                exert a powerful influence in healing the nations, so much the worse for the nations.
                                The man who can read these pages and not feel his spirit stirred with the noblest
                                emotions of which the human soul is capable, is, it seems to me, "fit for treasons,
                                stratagems and spoils." The professor of Christianity, who has attentively perused the
                                last issue,—April— and whose faith still remains unshaken in the ¦dogma of vicarious
                                atonement, is, I think, sadly lacking, either in candor or discernment, or both. The two
                                articles alone, "Teachings of the Shaker Manifesto" and "Should all be Shakers?" carry
                                the reflective mind into a region of thought where sophistry dispels as a mist, and
                                Truth shines in upon the soul 4'with healing in its leaves." Where the fall of man is
                                seen to be the transgression of God's laws, and his redemption, a return to obedience;
                                where reproduction stands out prominently, as the one important feature in the natural
                                order of creation ; its perversion to purposes of mere pleasure by the human race, the
                                cause of their spiritual death, and the entire renunciation of the works peculiar to
                                that order as exemplified in the life of Jesus and his followers, the only possible
                                means of being "born again" into spiritual life. Here one stands, as it were, upon "the
                                pinnacle of the temple," and sees "the kingdoms of the world and the glory of these"
                                pass away like the imagery of a dream, and, as a mighty wave, the knowledge of the way
                                of life sweeping over the earth with a rapidity and force which nothing can suppress.
                                Yours in love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName">Watson Andrews</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are all pleased with the improved appearance of The Shaker Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>We are all pleased with the improved appearance of The Shaker Manifesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, South Union, May 3, 1878" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky. May 3, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">We are all pleased with the improved appearance of The Shaker Manifesto— though it seems
                                that all do not endorse your theology. For my part, you can handle Paul and the rest as
                                you may please, I think they need bringing down ; they have been worshipped too long for
                                humanity's good. If we are to believe the records that have been handed down for our
                                perusal—they "went a fishing" more than once ; and for all the world were like some of
                                these flesh and blood creatures with whom we now eat, drink and have our being.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., J. R." TEIform="persName">J. R. C.</persName></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto: the preaching of songs" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker Manifesto:--The
                            Preaching of Songs</head><p TEIform="p">In nothing, is the mere sentimental, or the really practical of religion more clearly
                            demonstrated, than in the tone or embodiment of hymns and songs. Those denominations that
                            are indifferent to good ivories, unless they are accompanied by a peculiar faith; which,
                            relying on the good physician to take the medicine that the patients may get well, find a
                            redundance of mere sentimentalism in such versifications as begin : "Jesus paid it all—all
                            the debt I owe; "Nothing—neither great nor small— "Remains for me to do;" as also, in "There
                            is a fountain filled with blood," drawn from the veins of somebody else ! In the pretty,
                            much-used hymn, "Jesus, lover of my soul," we have excellent evidences delineated, by the
                            faith of grateful, but impractical, helpless and lazy sinners ; while in "Nearer my God to
                            thee" we have evidences of a generous leaning toward something to be done, in order to
                            accomplish the nearness, "e'en though it be by a cross." m: AisrrEHESTO. 143 <pb n="143" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. We have been singularly moved, while reflecting that
                            the practical sentiments expressed in the little song : "Must Jesus bear the cross alone,
                            "And all the world go free? "Nay, there's a cross for every one, "And there's a cross for
                            me;" are sung with as much zeal, by the same denominations, using the first named! Looking
                            through a score of "hymnals" and "gospel song" books, we found much to admire—much beautiful
                            sentiment to which we paid willing tributes of admiration—but a predominance remained of the
                            merely grateful, indolent, lazy sentiment—grateful that some one- Jesus—was going to do the
                            salvation, while the holders of such a belief were to be the saved ! The sentiments of many
                            hymns and songs are pretty, but ignis fatuus like, misleading and dangerous ; having little
                            else to recommend them than a pleasant tune, and meaningless, devotional sentimentalism. In
                            such songs, the consecrated, life-element of the ivorher for Jesus—the imitator of Jesus'
                            life—is wanting ; and without this practical element, in becoming in deeds, a follower of
                            the life of Jesus, there is, even in the beautiful eulogies expressed for him, much that is
                            as useless and dry as dust. While we can join, with much unction, in songs of praise to God
                            for the knowledge of the way of salvation, and of Jesus who first taught and lived this
                            salvation, we realize how meaner than lip service it is, to sing in praise of a life we will
                            not magnify except in songwill not live its precepts and practices— but in our hearts
                            despise all thoughts of the copy, and scorn the company ol those who choose to live as Jesus
                            did ! Turning from much sickly sentimentality in song, we commend for criticism and study,
                            the practical sentiments of Shaker hymns and songs. In them will be found a working ardor, a
                            practical religion, of which all professedly Christian people should be possessed. No
                            idolatrous bowing and bending to a person ; but a constant adoration of principles, that
                            mean all the time, casting off the bad, and putting on good life. Many of our home songs are
                            fully as plain, more so, in sentiment, as they are beautiful in tune ; and they mean much
                            more for Christian life than merely pleas- ing the ear ! But many of our later hymns can be
                            reached by multitudes ; and we challenge the Churches for better, practical following of the
                            Master, than is found sung out by our singing pilgrims, living under the continual crosses
                            imposed by genuine Christianity. We name first, u The Christian Pilgrim''1—no hiding behind
                            an "atonement" in it—no "faltering" to please a carnal mind. In ilFaith in God," and
                            il-Power of Faith" we get ideas of -a faith, that means works all the time—one that requires
                            active efforts and a clean, pure heart. We would call particular attention to
                            "Resurrection"—a beauty—every line of which is filled with a progressive theology and living
                            religion. We quote : 'Dying daily, 'tis the conscious evolution of the soul, !'In a life of
                            endless progress, as the ages onward roll; 'Dying, just as seasons changing, leave the forms
                            tliat pass away, 'Higher life, new growth unfolding, smites the old with sure decay." and so
                            on for several stanzas, and all, most beautifully practical. As a call to duty, true
                            theology and pure religion, what can excel "Spirit Voices?" "Season of Devotion" is
                            delightfully instructive ; so is LLOver the River." What can bring us into practical
                            sympathy with Jesus more than '' Christ's Sufferings?" and when, having made the prac143 <pb n="144" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 144 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. tical of all good sentiments ours, by a
                            clean, self-denying life, like unto Jesusthe best worship imaginable—what can exceed the
                            beauty of "My Savior?" We particularly refer to this last named, as worthy of xmiversal use.
                            If there is a denomination that more clearly expresses practical Christianity in its songs
                            and hymns, than does the Shaker Church, we want to know what denomination that is, that we
                            may pay it our worshipful respects. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inconsistency" TEIform="index"/>INCONSISTENCY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">England is now roused by the spirit of war ; the people demanding of the government an
                                opportunity to kill and be killed. Very probably their request will be granted; and
                                after the fullest gratification of their godless, savage, blood thirsty feelings, then
                                will come the strongest appeals for, and jubilation over a peace that should never have
                                been broken. Now, the wildest enthusiasm is for war ; assassination staring him in the
                                face, who being prominent as an official, dares plead for peace. By and by, the same
                                punishment will be meted out to those who would prolong the war ; while rejoicings will
                                be the order of the day, that the butchery, privations and worse than death are brought
                                to a close. Our testimony is for Peace, now and alway. No Christian can use carnal
                                weapons nor fight; never did so. We oppose wars of households, and wars of nations. All
                                wars are the results of lusts for lands and women. Elder Evans says: "Those who marry,
                                will fight." As we claim that Marriage, as well as War, is without the pale of
                                Christianity, the proper parties do the fighting—but these are not Christians. ''Else
                                would my servants fight."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Powerful compliment" TEIform="index"/>A POWERFUL COMPLIMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Boston and Albany R. R. Co. has recently placed on the road, a new, beautiful,
                                powerful and speedy locomotive, giving it the name of "The Shaker !" Alive to such a
                                compliment, we hope "The Shaker^ may be worthy of its name, profitable to the company,
                                meeting with no mishaps, and alway carrying with it a reminder of the prin- ciples of
                                the people whose name it bears. Thus will it be an active, rushing missionary.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God bless the aged" TEIform="index"/>GOD BLESS THE AGED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">From Maine to Kentucky, and from all the Societies and hamlets corresponding with us, a
                                unity, of blessing The Manifesto by the aged, is recorded, with the first exception to
                                be heard if there is any. On a flying trip to Mt. Lebanon, recently made, we met nearly
                                a score of these saints, whose ages included 75 and 102 ! Had we been some one much
                                better than the editor of The Shaker Manifesto, we might have been more worthy of the
                                long line of blessings showered upon us. Every one of these took especial delight in The
                                Manifesto ; and with the blessing of one such saint in its favor, we can very pleasantly
                                bear contumely and the croakings of the other class, until death relieves them or they
                                reform.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every one wishes to have truth on his side..." TEIform="index"/>Every one wishes to have truth on his side...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every one wishes to have Truth on his side; but it is not every one that sincerely wishes
                                to be on the side of the Truth.— </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whately" TEIform="persName">Whately</persName></byline></div3></div2><pb n="145" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondom sailor, chapter V" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP. V</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName">WILLIAM G. LIBBEY</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Having decided to make the place described in the previous chapter, our home, we settled
                                into a somewhat regular manner of life, which was indeed more comfortable than
                                journeying through tangled bushes, and over sharp coral with our bare feet. Our domestic
                                habits were each day pretty much alike. When we awoke in the morning, it was my practice
                                to read aloud from the Bible to my brother John. This I did in a devotional way,
                                commencing at Genesis. We had proposed to read it through by course, but after a few
                                chapters I found John had very little interest in the exercise. On being awakened he
                                would listen a few minutes and then go to sleep again, leaving me to enjoy the Bible
                                alone. This soon became rather a dull affair, and after plodding along through Genesis,
                                Exodus and into Leviticus, it was given up. We often read from it as our devotional
                                feelings came and went, like the rise and fall of the tide in the lagoon,—which was not
                                very bad—as it ebbed and flowed daily. Now let me describe how we managed our cooking,
                                when settled at our port of entry. When we arose in the morning the fish for our
                                breakfast were swimming in the sea, but they were so easily caught that we were quite
                                sure of a nice mess of white fish, after we learned their habits. By taking a handful of
                                small bits of coral and throwing them into the water scattering them well over the
                                surface, our white fish would come rushing up, then we would throw in the hooks baited
                                with some kind of shell fish, and seldom failed of catching sufficient before the flurry
                                was over. The reason we assigned for the fish rushing up when the pebbles were thrown
                                in, was that they feed upon flying fish, which, in rising from the water, make a noise
                                similar to that made by the pebbles. When they come up, the sharks would frequently come
                                with them, and as they were too heavy for our fishing gear, whenever they bit, we were
                                sure to lose our hooks and line, which was a very serious loss, as we had no means of
                                procuring more. After having lost several hooks and lines by sharks, I took most of what
                                line T had left, and twisting two parts of it together, and attaching one of our largest
                                hooks, started out. Casting the hook and line into the tidal passage, ¦—which was about
                                thirty yards distant from the hut, my brother called my attention, and losing sight of
                                the fish-hook by attendingto his call, a large shark had seized the bait, and was
                                closing his vise-like jaws upon it, while I held out a bit of stick, to which the line
                                was made fast, with all my strength, but it availed nothing, for the shark in his native
                                element was too strong for even two parts of good cord line, and it parted within six
                                inches oi my hands, leaving me ready to cry with vexation, from so serious a loss. This
                                may seem rather childish, but we were more than a thousand miles from any inhabited
                                island, and knew of no way to supply our need. But necessity is said to be the mother of
                                invention, and it proved thus in our case, for finding an old whale lance-head, and
                                fastening it to a stick, it made a tolerable good spear with which to kill fish. My
                                brother proving very skilful in its use, succeeded in taking a nice large fish very soon
                                after he began to use it, and thus by hook or spear we had a good supply during our stay
                                on the island. As already stated, seabirds were plenty, and so very tame, that whenever
                                we wanted a booby to roast, we could easily catch one without going very far from our
                                hut. This was not very often, for we preferred our good fish, to the flesh of these
                                sea-fowls, which had a rancid, oily flavor quite disagreeable to the taste. We did not
                                see but one kind of land bird, this was the Paroquet, dressed in all the colors of the
                                common parrot, only much brighter. They were rather shy, and we did not catch any alive.
                                My brother killed one as he was curious to examine its beautiful plumage. One morning,
                                John awoke me saying he MLAJNTFES^rO. <pb n="146" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> heard a rooster crow; on
                                listening a few moments, sure enough, we heard old chanticleer sound out his notes loud
                                and clear on the morning air, reminding us of our dear !New England home, five or six
                                thousand miles away in the East John was very anxious to catch this crower, and rising
                                early he went off through the wet hushes and darkness, in the direction of the sound. He
                                was absent until about sunrise, when he came back out of patience with his ill success,
                                in not capturing the little Spanish bantam,—the only real wild fowl we found on the
                                island. I told him I would try to catch him the next morning, at this he pouted a little
                                saying : "You will succeed about as well as I have." The next morning I arose very
                                early, and taking a course in the direction we last heard our chanticleer, proceeded
                                very softly; soon he sounded the first note of the morning, then I stepped briskly
                                forward, stopping only when the crowing ceased. The second time I started, I came within
                                a short distance of the little harbinger of domestic life. He had stationed himself in
                                the midst of a clump of Palmetto bushes, which were inaccessible to my further progress,
                                except by crawling, and this was no easy undertaking, as the trunks of these bushes are
                                interlaced in a wonderful manner. As I could only move when the bird was crowing, it
                                .took me some time to reach the part of the clump where he was stationed. At last, by
                                using great care, I drew myself directly under the bush on which he was perched; and as
                                it was now day light, I had a good view of the object that had drawn us from our easy
                                huts, for two mornings. He was a small bird, not larg enough to pay us for our labor,
                                but the famil iar sound attracted us, being a pleasant re minder of civilized life.
                                While lying on the ground, thinking of th best way to secure my prize, the littl bantam
                                turned his head, bringing his littl sharp eye to bear upon me. ¦ One loo seemed to be
                                enough, for he gave a sudde hen-like squall and flew, where, I neve knew; for that was
                                the first and the last tim I ever saw the coveted prize. Going back to our cabin, I was
                                met b John, with the cool remark, that he knew should do no better than he had done; th
                                as all very well to him, but really I felt uite sorry at the ill success of my morning's
                                alk. (to be continued.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Graham crackers" TEIform="index"/>Graham crackers</head><p TEIform="p"> One pint sour cream, one half teaspoonful oda, one tablespoonful sugar, a little salt,
                                tiffen with Graham flour sufficient to roll ut quite thin; cut in diamonds, and bake n a
                                quick oven. If sour cream cannot be procured, use milk, adding a small piece of butter.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glassware" TEIform="index"/>Glassware
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Glassware.—Tumblers that have had milk n them ought never to be put into hot water.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washing" TEIform="index"/>Washing
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Washing.—Borax, put in the water used for washing ginghams and highly colored prints,
                                will preserve the colors.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corns" TEIform="index"/>Corns
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Corns.—-Troublesome corns, it is said, can be entirely cured by rubbing them over with
                                ordinary white chalk each day for a number of days.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To penetrate smoke" TEIform="index"/>To penetrate smoke
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To Penetrate Smoke.—By wetting a silk handkerchief, and placing it over the mouth and
                                nostrils, one can pass through the densest smoke with but very little inconvenience as
                                to breathing.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For wounds" TEIform="index"/>For wounds
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">For Wounds. The aching and stiffness caused by wounds can be almost entirely
                                        re- lieved by holding the wound over the smoke of burning sugar. One of our
                                        correspondents, who gives us this information, punctured his right leg with a
                                        large awl, and the limb became in consequence very painful and stiff, so that he
                                        walked with great difficulty. A tablespoonful or two of sugar poured on some
                                        live coals in a shovel and held under the wound so relieved him that the day
                                        after he could walk as well as ever. It is said that if a poultice of pounded
                                        peach leaves is placed upon a wound so soon as it is received, lockjaw need not
                                        be feared. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune" TEIform="index"/>Tribune</bibl></cit></p></div3><pb n="147" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hot water for wounds" TEIform="index"/>Hot Water for Wounds</head><p TEIform="p">Hot water in the treatment of bruises and wounds is strongly advocated by certain medical
                                authorities. In proof of its efficacy, the New York Medical Journal states the following
                                case : The hand of a workman in a machine-shop was crushed under the fall of a
                                trip-hammer weighing 700 pounds. The hammer was arrested when within a halfinch of its
                                bed, but the palm of the unfortunate hand receiving the blow was reduced to a pulp. The
                                metacarpal bones were extensively comminuted, yet, in the hope of saving the member, it
                                was kept immersed in hot water for two or three weeks, and then taken out and dressed..
                                In three months the patient was dismissed from the hospital, and in nine months was able
                                to move his fingers and demonstrate that he still possessed a useful hand. The
                                temperature of the water employed in such cases should be about 103 deg. Fahrenheit.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of house plants" TEIform="index"/>Care of House Plants</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lady in Kansas" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> A lady in Kansas gives her plan of caring for house-plants as follows: "I live in a
                                frame house, and last Winter kept fifty pots of different kinds of geraniums, roses,
                                fuchsias, and remontant pinks, all of which received the same kind of treatment, and in
                                the spring my plants were more healthy and the leaves a dark-green color. Many came to
                                me for slips in preference to the green-houses. Every two weeks all the Winter I would
                                take a handful of tobacco-stems and steep them by pouring boiling water over them until
                                it looked like strong tea; then when the tea cooled enough to bear the hand, I poured it
                                over the plants. Sometimes the leaves would wilt for a few moments, and then straighten
                                out and Jiave that bright, fresh look they have in summer after a shower. Then I would
                                weaken the tea a little more and wet the ground in the pots, and I had no red spider nor
                                green fly."</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church is God's jewelry" TEIform="index"/>Church is God's jewelry
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The church is God's jewelry—His working house, where His jewels are polished for His
                                palace; and those He especially esteems and means to make most resplendent He hath
                                oftenest His tools upon them.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of a prosperous farmer" TEIform="index"/>Signs of a prosperous farmer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Signs of A Prosperous Farmer.—When you see his barn larger than his house, it shows that
                                he will have large profits and small afflictions. When you see him driving his work,
                                instead of his work driving him, it shows that he will never be driven from good
                                resolutions, and that he will certainly work his way to prosperity. When you always see
                                in his wood-house a sufficiency for three months or more, it shows that he will be more
                                than a ninety days wonder in farming operations, and that he is not sleeping in his
                                house after a drunken frolic. When he has a house separate from the main building,
                                purposely for ashes, and an iron or tin vessel to transport them, it shows that he never
                                built his dwelling to be a funeral pile for his family, and perhaps for himself. When
                                his sleigh is housed in summer, and his farming implements covered both winter and
                                summer, it plainly shows that he will have a good house over his head in the summer of
                                early life, and the winter of old age.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sudden changes in the weather..." TEIform="index"/>Sudden changes in the weather...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sudden changes in the weather are very trying to poultry, and no poultry-keeper is up to
                                his business who does not keep a few remedies at hand to promptly meet any
                                indisposition. Simple remedies are generally sufficient, if used at the first appearance
                                of trouble. Sulphur, charcoal, and cayenne given in soft food, will generally restore
                                them, but in the case a distinct disease appears, remove the affected bird for special
                                treatment.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A tablespoonful of guano..." TEIform="index"/>A tablespoonful of guano...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A tablespoonful of guano, dissolved in one gallon of warm water, and used twice a week,
                                or every fourth day, is also an excellent stimulant for all kinds of plants. Liquid
                                fertilizer, made from horse or cow manure, is equally good; but care must be taken not
                                to use it in too strong doses, as it will burn up the tender rootlets and kill the
                                plants.</p></div3><pb n="148" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give us a breed of walking horses" TEIform="index"/>Give us a breed of walking horses
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">&gt;Give Us a Breed of Walking Horses. What use are fast horses to farmers? Can
                                        they put them to work in the plow, harrow, cultivator, roller, reaping-machine,
                                        cart, or wagon? No, A storm might arise and the whole crop of hay be ruined, if
                                        they had to depend on 2: 40 horses to haul it in. There is but one use that we
                                        can see that a farmer might put them to,—sending for a doctor; but as farmers
                                        have very little occasion for this professional gentleman, and never get very
                                        sick, a slower and surer horse will answer better. Why, then, parade these
                                        horses at the head of the lists at agricultural fairs, and give them the biggest
                                        premiums? No wonder our practical farmers complain of this, while there is no
                                        premium at all for walking horses, which are a thousand times more useful,—we
                                        mean to the farmer, and for general agricultural and industrial purposes.
                                        Thoroughbred horses have their uses, and we do not de^re to utter a word against
                                        them, but many good words in their favor. They, however, must fill their own
                                        places, and work-horses theirs ; and neither should be advocated to the
                                        exclusion of the other. Both should be recognized according to their value.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Germantown telegraph" TEIform="index"/>Germantown Telegraph</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Mechi, the famous scientific farmer of England, estimates that..." TEIform="index"/>Mr. Mechi, the famous scientific farmer of England, estimates that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Mechi, the famous scientific farmer of England, estimates that fifteen hundred sheep
                                folded on an acre of land for tyventyfour hours, or one hundred sheep for fifteen days,
                                would manure the soil sufficiently to carry it through a four-years rotation.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loving friends" TEIform="index"/>Loving Friends</head><p TEIform="p"> Never cast aside your friends if by any possibility you can retain them. We are the
                                weakest of spendthrifts if we let one drop off through inattention, or let one push away
                                another, or if we hold aloof from one through petty jealousy or heedless slight or
                                rough- ness. Would you throw away a diamond because it pricked you? One good friend is
                                not to be weighed against the jewels of the earth. If there is coolness or unkindness
                                between us let us come face to face and have it out. Quick, before the love grows cold!
                                Life is too short to quarrel in, or to carry black thoughts of friends. It is easy to
                                lose a friend, but a new one will not come for calling, nor make up for the old one.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Facing its positions" TEIform="index"/>FACING ITS POSITIONS</head><p TEIform="p">The New Jerusalem Messenger says : <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In a recent address made by Mr. Macrae, one of the Scotch "heretics," he
                                        uttered bold and radical expressions. Such men in the Old Church will certainly
                                        bring it face to face with its untenable positions. This Scotch man, and others
                                        like him, must break up the spiritual soil of mankind for new truth and new
                                        life. The following are Mr. Macrae's words : "The real heretic is the
                                        Westminster Confession. It misrepresents the character of God, and a false view
                                        of the position and destiny of man naturally follows. Carried to its issue, it
                                        robs God of his goodness, his mercy, and his justice. It robs him even of his
                                        sovereignty "The first necessity, in the present state of things, is that the
                                        present policy of evasion and concealment should be reversed, and the Church's
                                        real convictions be made known. The second is that her Confession should be
                                        squared with her actual faith. The third is that this should be done on grounds
                                        that would make her new creed a help and not a hindrance, and allow her
                                        henceforth to advance freely, as God shall guide, to the full knowledge, and
                                        proclamation, and practice of the truth."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jerusalem messenger" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A minister was riding through a section of the state of South Carolina..." TEIform="index"/>A minister was riding through a section of the state of South Carolina...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A minister was riding through a section of the State of South Carolina, where custom
                                forbade innkeepers to take pay from the clergy who staid with them. The minister in
                                question took supper without pra3'er, and ate breakfast without prayer or grace, and was
                                about to take his departure when 'mine host' presented his bill. 'Ah, sir,' said he, 'I
                                am a clergyman!' That may be,' responded Boniface; 'but you came here, smoked like a
                                sinner, and ate and drank like a sinner, and slept like a sinner; and now, sir, you
                                shall pay like a sinner.'</p></div3><pb n="149" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seeds" TEIform="index"/>SEEDS</head><p TEIform="p"> We are sowing, daily sowing. Countless seeds of good and ill. Scattered on the level
                                lowland, Cast upon the windy hill; Seeds that sink in rich brown furrows, Soft with
                                heaven's gracious rain; Seeds that rest upon the surface Of the dry, unyielding plain.
                                Seeds that fall amid the stillness Of the lonely mountain glen; Seeds cast out in
                                crowded places, Trodden under foot of men ; Seeds by idle hearts forgotten, Flung at
                                random on the air; Seeds by faithful souls remembered, Sown in tears and love and
                                prayer. Seeds that lie unchanged, unquickened, Lifeless on the teeming mold ; Seeds that
                                live and grow and flourish When the sower's hand is cold; By a whisper sow we blessings,
                                By a breath we scatter strife ; In our words and looks and actions Lie the seeds of
                                death and life. Thou who knowest all our weakness, Leave us not to sow alone ! Bid thine
                                angels guard the furrows Where the precious grain is sown, Till the fields are crowned
                                with glory, Pilled with mellow, ripened ears— Filled with fruit of life eternal From the
                                seed we sowed in tears. Check the froward thoughts and passions, Stay the hasty,
                                heedless hands, Lest the germs of sin and sorrow Mar our fair and pleasant lands.
                                Father, help each weak endeavor, Make each faithful effort blessed, Till Thine harvest
                                shall be garnered, And we enter into rest.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Arabian maxims" TEIform="index"/>Arabian Maxims</head><p TEIform="p">The little which suffices is better than the much which disturbs us. The best possession
                                is a sincere friend. The eulogium made on the absent, serves to incline our hearts to
                                the present. The best of riches is contentment, the worst of poverty is low spirits.
                                Labor for this life as if thou wert to live forever; and for the other, as if thou wert
                                to die to-morrow. Desire not either the wise man or the fool for thine enemy, but guard
                                thyself equally from the cunning of the wise man and the ignorance of the fool. The man
                                who contents himself to-day with that which he has, will content himself to- morrow with
                                that which he may have.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS</head><p TEIform="p">As the breath of the dew on the tender plant, they gently fall upon the drooping heart,
                                refreshing its withered tendrils and soothing its burning woes. Bright oases they are in
                                life's great desert. Who can estimate the pangs they have alleviated, or the good works
                                they have accomplished? Long after they are uttered do they reverberate in the soul's
                                inner chamber, and sing low, sweet, liquid strains, that quell all the raging storms
                                that may have before existed. And oh, when the heart is sad, and like a broken harp, the
                                sweetest chords of pleasure cease to vibrate, who can tell the power of one kind word?
                                One little word of tenderness, gushing in upon the soul, will sweep the long-neglected
                                chords, and awaken the most pleasant strains. When borne down with the troubles of life,
                                we are ready to sink fainting by the way, how like the cheerful rays of sunshine do kind
                                words come. They disperse the clouds, dispel the gloom, and drive sorrow far away.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evil thoughts" TEIform="index"/>EVIL THOUGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">You are not guilty on account of anything you cannot control. Evil thoughts follow some
                                principle of association, some old channel of thought, or inherited predilection. The
                                remedy does not lie in a frantic opposition to them. This only makes the impression
                                deeper. Turn your attention away from them. Do not oppose them so much as neglect them.
                                Above all, never let one of these cast-out devils find the house empcy, swept and
                                garnished. Fill your mind with other things-. Be careful what you read. Read abundantly,
                                and of the best books. An idle brain is the lodging-house of evil thoughts, as an
                                unoccupied house gives shelter to tramps and unclean beasts.</p></div3></div2><pb n="150" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Father's kingdom" TEIform="index"/>OUR FATHER'S KINGDOM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName">James G. Russell</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Onward, upward, through the labyrinths of darkness, Lo the glorious
                            heights of per feet freedom we're attain ing. Let the music sweetly roll from each living joyful soul, Evidencing <pb n="151" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 151 sure and
                            full the vict'ry we are gaining. All along our heav'nly way, Brighter grows each glad
                            some ray ; Clouds of doubt are disappearing, Leaving clear our vision. Angel bands are
                            gath'ring near, Leading on and <pb n="152" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 153 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. man siod
                            In our Father's Kingdom.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impersonality of truth" TEIform="index"/>The Impersonality of Truth</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles. B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We recently received the few lines following, from Elder G. B Avery, of our Central
                            Bishopric; intended as instruction for us in dealing with personal controversies. We hope,
                            all, from Kentucky to Maine will take warning, and leave personal, argumentative collisions
                            where they more properly belong— "without"—see Eev. 22 : 15. ed. "Truth will not arrange any
                            person's opinions in the capacity of a target of error, for some other erring gunner to
                            shoot at. It will simply, kindly shine, and lovingly enlighten all concerned with it.
                            However rusty any may be, few, or none will sit willingly still, and quietly be rubbed until
                            they shine brightly; for they will think, and with some good reasons too, that the dust,
                            made in the process of scouring, will so blind the eyes of the operators, that they will
                            never see the shining."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy are they who think seriously of the truths of religion; but far more happy are they who                                 feel and love them." TEIform="index"/>Happy are they who think seriously of the truths of religion...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Happy are they who think seriously of the truths of religion; but far more happy are they who
                            feel and love them.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fenelon" TEIform="persName">Fenelon</persName></byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ware, William" TEIform="index"/>William Ware
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky., April 13, <persName reg="Ware, William" TEIform="persName">William Ware</persName>,
                                aged 48. Plad been installed Elder of the East family just 5 weeks previous.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We notice in The Western Star (Lebanon, 0hio)..." TEIform="index"/>We notice in The Western Star (Lebanon, 0hio)...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We notice in The Western Star (Lebanon, 0.) an elaborate essay on "Forest Culture,' by our
                            Bro. Cephas Holloway. Though intended only to affect Ohio State, it contains invaluable
                            hints worthy to be acted upon in every section of Country. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We do not accept the responsibility of any articles..." TEIform="index"/>We do not accept the responsibility of any articles...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We do not accept the responsibility of any articles inserted in The Shaker Manifesto. That
                            department is under the management of the Editor—The Advertisements and general business
                            management is in charge of the Canterbury, N. H. Publisheu. giv ing cheer; Soon we'll reach
                            the glo rious </p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!-- <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Editorials"/>Editorial Notes</head>
                        <p> We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory indeed, Being among "the
                            wonders in this age" of machinery. Their utility and expedition in business should be experienced by all, at so
                            small coat. Material for Fencks of wood variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no
                            fences, or rely on the metal ones offered us by Wash- burn, Moen Co. - ?»•A Useful Afpakatus : JohnBunyan
                            said, that "an Idle boy's or girl's head was the devil's workshop." Get them the "Keystone. Self-Inker'1 with
                            complement of type. See Adv. -*o» - Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that there are unscrupulous persons, who,
                            realizing the solid benefits of judicious advertising, will use it most freely on some useless or worse than
                            useless articles, and soon retire with fortunes of ill-earned gains. But we can still point to thousands who by
                            a wholesome judicious judgment, have used advertising to their exceeding profit! and to the most creditable
                            advancement of useful materials. Such, we believe our patrons to be. - to * - We have taken considerable and
                            particular pains to acquaint ourself with Dr. Frazier's remedies, and find from those using them, only a good
                            report. His Bitters are purely medicinal, and not an intoxicant bev- erage. Elder James S. Prescott gives his
                            endorsement of Dr. Frazier's Cough ilemedy— and he is good authority. For thirty years, Mrx, the jeweler and
                            watchmaker, has stood high in the estimation of honest people in these parts. We. find Stinson and Co. very
                            honorable in their dealing. Try them. None will rejrrei wearing Boots and Shoes from Schuster's shop. Send in
                            your measure, please. E. C. Koonz's Adv. is a very modest showing, for such extensive and beautiful emporiums
                            for Carpets and Oil Cloths. We hope parties the world over, will send their patronage, to this house. We hope
                            "everybody an;] his neighbor" will send us six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for too copies
                            post paid. It is a pretty book. Please procure it and present it to your friend. Look out for The Buckeye Mower!
                            Et is coming; and we give this timely notice. The U. S. Piano Co. enter a challenge to other manufacturers and
                            salesmen. We mean to make ourselves more acquainted with their instruments. People will have Pianos, and they
                            will look where to get them, in The Shaker Manifesto. Every farmer will yet be his own Miller; grinding out his
                            "religious bread" as Elder F. W. Evans would say; then they will send for one of Sedgebeer's "Nonpareil." Send
                            for a circular now. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the best Water Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say
                            that the firms of Leffel & Co. and N. F. Burnham, who enter into friendjy competition in our columns,
                            are both most honorable.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>Ayek & Son's Manual contains more information of value to advertisers than any other publication. Sent
                            free. Address N. W. Ayer & Son, Advertising Agents, Times Building, Philadelphia. MATHEWS' CARRIAGE MART
                            CONCORD, N. H. Manufacturer of and Dealer in fine Carriages and SleigllS, secondhand Carriages and Sleighs
                            constantly on hand. J3©S~t Bargains in the City. GTMS8! JEMGHE BUTTER. MAJiJEK. - TKE COOLEY CREAMER Raises
                            all the cream the milk contains inside of 10 hours in its greatest perfection, With the Least Amount of Labor.
                            4®- The only perfect system of Butter-Making. Send for Circular to Vermont Farm Machine Co., Bellows Falls, Vt.
                            Endorsed by The Shakers. Pianos, Organs, CXiUESTT cfc iSOlSPS Illustrated Catalogue REDUCED PRICE LIST, ««5
                            ItXVElt SOT. XH.O1T, W. Y. i MJE.19 M. Offers the greatest possible attracr" ai iii-vt tions in t-liicJ^e^ine's*
                            ULUi, 1 S Stein way ,&IIalne PIANOS and ESXEY OM.«AMTI». Don't fail to write for Catalogues and Prices—
                            Warerooms, IBOT, ar. Y. <pb id="p30"/> AD VERTISEMENTS. AUTOMATIC Family Knitter. For full particulars and
                            lowest prices for the Best Family Machine send to BECKFORD Knitting Machine Mfg.Oo. BKATTLEBORO, VT.
                            Tlir«»«liins>^Hisc'lainc'!* «& Morse Potvcn Best at Centennial Trial. Threshers for all sizes of
                            Horse Powers and Steam, Lever Powers for 4 to 10 Horse, and Endless Chain Powers for 2 and 3 Horses—and Engines
                            from 4 to 10 Horse Power. All with late and important improvements. Send for Circular. CJ. WEiSTiaftiMOIJlSi:
                            & CO., Schenectady, N. Y. (TP Pa week in your own town. Terms and $5 outfit 4)00free.
                            AddressII.HallbttA Co.,Portland,Me. JOHN GJ-. KAIJLBACK, Jr. & CO., WHOLESALE DEALER IN WEST INDIA GOODS
                            AND GROCERIES of all kinds, Of unexceptionable quality and low prices, AT 13© and 13O WATEK St., Boston. Special
                            attention paid to 2'eas& Spices. DEALER IN TXTBS «Ss BB.OOMS Also, SHAKER P^lIL^. gggP^Answering
                            advertisement: Please mention The Shaker Manifesto. SPECIAL NOTICES. PEIOELESS DIS00VEBY. A SURE CURE FOR PILES.
                            A sure cure for the blind, bleeding, itching1, and ulcerated piles has been discovered by Dr. William, (an
                            Indian remedy,) called Dr. William's Indian Ointment. A single box has cured the worst old chronic cases of
                            twenty-five and thirty years' standing. No one need suffer five minutes after applying this wonderful soothing
                            medicine. Lotions, instruments and electuaries do more harm than good. William's Ointment supports the tumors,
                            allays the intense itching (particularly at night, after getting warm in bed), acts as a poul- tice, gives
                            instant and "painless relief, and is prepared only for Piles and nothing else. Thousands of cured patients
                            attest its virtues, and physicians of all schools pronounce it the greatest contribution to medicine of the age.
                            It matters not how long or severely 3-011 have been suffering, you can be cured. Mr. Joseph M. Ryder, Cleveland,
                            Ohio, writes : I suffered for years with Itching' and Ulcerated Piles, tried remedy after remedy advertised, and
                            consulted physicians in Philadelphia", Louisville, Cincinnati, Indianapolis and this city; and spent hundreds of
                            dollars, but found no relief until I obtained a box of Dr. William's Indian Ointment some four months ago, and
                            it has cured me completely. I had a part of the box left which I gave to a friend of mine who had doctored with
                            many physicians, and as a last resort went to the noted Hot Springs, Arkansas, for treatment. He informs me that
                            the Indian Ointment has also cured him of the Piles. It is certainly a wonderful discovery and should be used by
                            the many thousands who are now suffering with that dread disease. 4£g=$10.000 Reward will be paid for a more
                            certain remedy. Sold by all Druggists. Dr. G. W. Frazier, sole proprietor, Cleveland, O. DON'T NEGLECT A COUGH.
                            or Cold, when 25 cts will buy a bottle of Dr. Frazier's Cough Syrup at any drug store. It has wrought a complete
                            change in the Cough Medicines, is pleasant as honey and always cures. TO CONSUMPTIVES. 4®=-Dr. Frazier's Cough
                            Syrup used ill connection with Dr. Frazier's Root Bitters will cuke CONSUMPTION. Standard Steam Laundry,
                            Cleveland, O., Oct. 30, 76. Dr. Fkazieb. Dear Sir : I feel it a duty I owe to Buffering humanity to write you.
                            For some time I was sorely afflicted with u cough, raising bad stuff, with every symptom of being a confirmed
                            consumptive. I tried different medicines and cures without finding relief; I also consulted three of our most
                            prominent Cleveland physicians, the last one of which pro- nounced my case serious, and informed me that I could
                            not live more than a few months. About this time, hearing of your wonderful success, I commenced taking your
                            Syrup in connection with your Root Bitters, and was at once benefited, and after using the medicine some two
                            months I find myself entirely cured. TORENCE DUNN. 4f5~Mr. Dunn again writes, under date of Aug. 4, 1877,—Dr.
                            Frazier, Dear Sir: I endorse your medi- cines more strongly than ever from the fact that it is now nearly one
                            year since I was cured. My lungs are to-day strong and sound; having no return of the disease. 4Sg= The above
                            Medicines speak for themselves. DR. G. W. FRAZIER, Proprietor, Cleveland, O. For sale by all Druggists. I/IND
                            READER, if you are in any way interested in K BEES ar HOIS, we will, with pleasure, send you a sample copy ot
                            our Monthly "GLEANINGS IN BEE CULTURE.'. Simply write your address plainly on a postal card and ADDRESS. A. I.
                            ROOT, Medina, Ohio. THE BICKFQRD <pb id="p31"/> AD VERTISEMENTS. THE AMERICAN TURBINE WATER WHEEL FRENCH BURR
                            MILLSTONES, eral FLOUR, IMCII^L and I»^M2TT jVETT^I^ Machinery. And full line of mill ftirnishmg. The AMEEICAN
                            TUKBINE WHEEL produces the best average percentage of any Turbine ever known. Large illustrated catalogue sent
                            free. ADDRESS, STOUT MILLS & TEMPLE, DAYTON,OHIO. SOHENEOTADY, N. Y. "Builders of.Warine, Stationary and
                            "Portable Steam J?n(/ines and "Boilers. Shaker JSroom Handle Lathes, (the best Lathe in Mark-1.) Engines for
                            Farm work, cutting and steaming feed, driving Threshing Machines, tfc. from, 1 horse, to 10 horse power. Seiicl
                            for 3?riee List. WE sell a First-ClasiPlan, cheaper than any other house in America. Have no Agents, but sell
                            DIRECT TO FAMILIES AT FACTORY PRICE, and warrant 5 years. Pianos sent for trial at our expense. Illustrated
                            Circular Free, givins; full particulars, and names of over 2,000 Bankers, Merchants and Families using our
                            Pianos in every State and Territory. Address, V. 8. PIANO no., 810 Broadway, N. Y. P £11 Fi Any worker can make
                            $12 a day at home. CostUUL'lflyOutfLtfree. T True & Co., Augusta. Me.J No. 5 Beaver Block Oor, SOUTH
                            PEARL & BEAVER Sts, ALBANY, N. Y. A large assortment of Watches Spectacles constantly on hand.
                            2£epah'inr/ in all its branches. and tactical Christmas Present $2 Self-Inker Keystone Press, 100 Printing
                            Letters, Roller, Ink, Reglets, Leads, Cards, Type, and Outside Case. All for $3, Stamp for Catalogue. W. C.
                            Evans, 50 N. Ninth St., Phila,, Pa. TET SHAKER'S COEBETT'S SAESAPAEILLA, For Purifying the Blood; best Medicine
                            at all Seasons. A sk for it at your Druggists. Maynard & Noyes, Boston. HOLYOKE, MASS., MANUFACTURERS OP
                            IRON WIRE, Orders solicited for TINNED BROOM WIRE, quality guaranteed. Geo. W, Prentiss & Co., <pb
                                id="p32"/> AD VERTISEMENTS. ATLANTIC WHITE LEAD LINSEED OIL CO. ROBT. COLGATE & Co., GENERAL
                            A.G-EHNTTS 287 3PEA.E.X. ST. IV. Y. The Atlantic White Lead is warranted pure, and is manufactured exclusively
                            from the best selected refined leads and ground in refined Linseed Oil. It is packed in, Casks of 200 and j 1000
                            pounds. Kegs of 25, 50 & 100 pounds. Wooden Buckets (with handles) of 12.5 25, & 50 pounds. Also
                            in Tin Pails (with handles) of 12.5 & 25 pounds Cans and carefully put up in wooden cases 4 or 8 in a
                            case. LINSEED OIL WARRANTED PURE. RAW, BOILED ATSTD REFINED, iisr CASKS J±NT) BAERBLS. AND SMALL NAILS, OF BVBKY
                            SIZE, A.3STI3 VARIETY HADE BY American Tack Co., Fairhaven, Mass. 4ES~Parties answering advertisements: Will you
                            please mention The Shaker Manifesto ? To Our Patrons Everywhere: Anything you desire, or may wish to obtain in
                            the line of Dry Goods, Cai-pets, JFurniture, Upholstery Goods, 'JLadieft' &, Cliildrpns' {boys as well
                            as girls,) Ready Made Suits, go to, or send to the Wholesale &Retail Emporium of W. H. Whitney
                            &. Co., ALBANY, N. Y. IDI3CFOBIIDA,. Wholesale Dealer in faiotis, cots, ©iuass, ©YE STATE YOoCYS KTKEET
                            .A-3STID <pb id="p33"/> AD VER TISEMENTS. N. F. BUENHAM'S X874. Watei WHEEL Is DECLARED the 'STANDARD TURBINE,1
                            by over 600 persons who boug'ht and use them with PART and FULL GATE open. Illustrated and descriptive Pamphlet
                            free. Address P4. F. BURNHAM, P. O. Box 513. York, Pa. Gearing for Factories, flouring Mills, Paper Mills dt Saw
                            mills a specialty by BROOMELL & BURNHAM, Christiana, Lancaster Co., Pa. OUR CORUNDUM POLISHER A Tool for
                            Cutting, Leveling and Polishing Furrows in a Mill Stone. With the use of this tool the miller can make a
                            uniform, level and smooth furrow, and do the work in one-tenth the time required to do it with a Mill Pick. It
                            is acknowledged by millers using them to be the most practical and labor-saving Tool for the miller's use. The
                            frame is iron, with wood handle. The cutting face is a composition of recently discovered mineral, the hardest
                            and fastest cutting material known to the scientific world. One of these tools will last, in an ordinary mill,
                            from one to two years, andean be refilled at a cost of $2. By sending amount you will save expense. PEIOE $3.
                            50. Manufactured by WEED & Co. DAYTON, O. Such is the title of a Shaker Pamphlet, in- tending to
                            exhibit, in brief, Shaker Polity and Principles ; being answers to ever-recurring questions concerning The
                            Shakers ; also answering " What shall I do to he a Shaker?" Cost Price, Five Cents, postage One cent. Address,
                            The Editor of The Shaker Manifesto. Washburn& MoenMan'fgCo. WORCESTER, ESASS. Sole HarafKiuMrs East of
                            Cairago, of A STEEL Thorn Hedge. No other Fencing so cheap or put up so quickly. Never rusts, stains, decays,
                            shrinks, nor warps. Unaffected by fire, wind, or flood. A complete barrier to the most unruly stock. ImpassaWe
                            by man or beast. TWO THOUSAND TONS SOLD AND PCJT UP DURING THE LAST YEAR. For sale at tha leading hardware
                            stores, with Stretchers and Staples. qoe_(X fo? illustrated PamDhlet Also Manufacturers of all kinds of IRON AND
                            STEEL WIRE. A Speciality made of TINNED BROOM WIRE. <pb id="p34"/> AD VERTISEMENTS. JOHN WHITELEY. Manufacturer
                            of SHAKER BROOMS, Shirley Village, Mass. AGHElNrr FOB, "The Shaker"—nionthly-60 cts. per annum. "The Divine
                            Afflatus"—10 cts. per copy. "The Shaker's Answer"—-6 cts. per copy. "The Divinity of Humanity"—3 cts. per copy.
                            Liberal discount in quantities. J. SEDGEBEER'S PATENT NONPAREIL Self - Sharpening, Keversible Motion Crushing
                            and Grinding Farm, Bone and Drug Mills. 12 sizes. Send for free illustrated descriptive Catalogues and
                            Price-list. Address J. SEDfiEBEEB, Puiaiesville, O. FAMILY SOAPS. By C. BERKLEY JOHNSON, Senior member of the
                            late firm of E. A. & W. WINCHESTER. The character and quality of E. A. & W. Winchest- er's Soap
                            is fully equal, in every respect, to its former Standard. Its Style is plain. It is not garnished with Showy
                            Labels. It recommends itself by its excellence. It is designed for family use more than for trade. Trade
                            generally demands something cheaper, consequently inferior. Address, C. BERKLEY JOHNSON, 15 Chatham St., BOSTON,
                            MASS. HENRY CUMMINGS, MANUFACTURER & DEALER IN SHAKER BEOOMS, PAILS, TUBS; OLID GROWTH FI3STB. PAILS
                            & TUBS a specialty. Also all grades of second growth Pails, Tubs &c. HENRY CUMMINGS, Enfield, N.
                            H. Please send for price list &c. WHEELER & MELICK CO. MANUFACTURERS OF Threshing Machines,
                            Horse Powers, Shingle Machines, Horse Forks, Sulkey Horse Rakes, &c. ALBANY,, N. Y. SHAKER PLA]O!ELS
                            & KNIT GOODS, CORN BROOMS & BRUSHES. Address, 1ST. A.. Briggs Slialrer Village, 3ST. H.
                            Established 1816. The Societies at Canterbury and Watervliet have used this IJVIt for many years, and they
                            unhesitatingly recommend it as a good, reliable ai'ticle; of good color, flows freely, and does not fade.
                            Maynard «fc Noyes, Boston. BT Wm.. A. BINDS. This book contains, in brief a succinct account of all the
                            Communities now in America, and is a valuable, almost invaluable accompaniment of the students of moral reform,
                            and political economy. Price 60 cts The Shaker Manifesto for 1878. and American Communities §1.00 FOR THAT
                            RHEUMATISM. Try Dr. Dean's Rheumatic Pills, (lie old, popular standard and efficacious remedy. Ask for them at
                            your Druggists. MAYNARD& NOYESAgts. BOSTON <pb id="p35"/> A D V Fit VIS EM HNTS. QT It is so simple in
                            construction and runs so- easily that a child can operate it. Q It has the straight, self-setting needle,
                            oarimproved shuttle, with a perfect tension, which does not change as the bobbin becomes exhausted. US" All the
                            wearing points are adjustable, and: it combines every desirable improvement. 4S5" Every Machine is sent out
                            ready for uset afterbeins; thoroughly tested. Notwithstanding the GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICES we continue to use
                            the best material and exercise the greatest care in their manufacture.. 111. BURR STONE GRIST MILLS VICTOR
                            SEWING MACHINE CO. PEH'CIPAL 0mC3 and Manufactories, MiMetown, LEFFEL WATER WHEELS With recent improvements.
                            Pr$ces Greatly Reduced 7000 in successful operation. 1TOZ NSW PAMFHLET FOS 1S77, ^ent free to those interested.
                            James Lefiel & Go, Springfield, O 109 Liberty St., N. Y. City. From, the Scientific American, Our
                            illustration represents a very simple and ingenious device, which does away with the usual cords and pulleys on
                            windows, making one sash balance the other. It is cheap and readily applied and will afford all the means of
                            ventilation that sideweights do. Samples by mail for $1.25—Agents wanted. Address. S. J. Russell, Patentee,
                            South Union, Kt. (T C in (£. 0 nPer day at nomeSamples worth $5 free i 4)0 10 4>/UAddre99 Stinson
                            & Co., Portland, Mb <pb id="p36"/> Is the only harvesting machine whu-h has stood tub; test of time, AND
                            is everywhere recognized as the most Perfect in Principle, The REST IN MATERIAL and The SIMPIjEST, the
                            STRONGEST, the LIGHTEST DRAFT THE ADRIANOE REAPER I so much superior to all other Single Reapers that it cannot
                            fail to be preferred by any farmer WHO WILL EXAMINE IT. ADRIANOE,PLATT So GO., 165 GREENWICH ST., NEW YORK.
                            Manufactory Poughkeepsie 1$. Y. DESCRIPTIVE CIRCULAR FORWARDED BY MAIL. WORKMANSHIP. The Most Durable!</p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>