<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2411" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">24</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18941101" TEIform="date">November 1894</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">246-268</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="24" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
NOVEMBER.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXIV.
" Cast thy bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many bays."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1894.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
I'age.
History of South Union, No 13,    -              -         245
Hazel Blossoms,           .....             248
Health,                .......         249
Continuance in W_-!l-lohig,             -       .             250
Correspondence,             .....         251
C. C. C,           .......             252
Faith,          ....- - -.         253
Solemn Thoughts,                ....             254
The Christian Mission,         ....            256
MusicMy Home,       -                                                                       258
Home Notes,              ......            25!)
Trio ite to .lunette Angus,      -       -       -         265
Autumn,          -                .....          266
In Memory of C. Walker                                     "
LetterD*. Orcutt,        -                                            267
In Memory of S. Boisstau   -       ...                           "
Death.-,    *           ....-.."
Books & Papers,          -                                 268
After five years of labor, with the help
of 247 editors, and the enormous expenditure of nearly one million dollars, the
Funk & Wagnalls Company announce
that the last page of the second, the concluding, volume of the new Standard Dictionary, is now in type. This volume will
be ready for delivery in November.
Fukx & Wagnalls Company.
83 Lafayette Place, New York.
MISS  JEROME'S BANNERS
JOY   B^VISTNER,      REST    BANNER
BVERY.DAY BAjVUNTER. WHAT
WILL   'PI-IE   VIOLETS   BE
Each Banner consists o^ four panels utrautifully decorated in colors and gold, atlached
by ribbons of appropriate colors, combined
with elegant extracts from popular authors,
and enclosed in decorated envelopes. Facsimile of artists' designs.
Miss Irene Jerome's happy faculty in grouping and interpreting beautiful thoughts by
means of colored and illuminated designs is
highly appreciated by all book-buyers and
her work is welcomed by all lovers of the
beautiful. Her precious creations "One Year s
Sketch-book" "Nature's Hallelujah" "A Bunch
of Violets" "The Message of the Bluebird" etc.,
are the most popular illustrated books published in this century, and are welcomed by
people of artistic tastes in all walks of life.
And now, following her late success in
color work "I have called you Friends" we
have a new revelation of the resources of her
genius, and one well adapted to grace and
beautify the beloved homes of our land.
COMPLETE CATALOGUE SENT FREE
LEE    AND   8HEPAED   Publishers
10 Milk St. Boston.
SOMFOUM  CONCENTRATED
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. Hydkiodatk of Potassa to 12 Bottles.
 PREPARED AT
 Shaker Village, Merrimack
Co., N. H.
This medicine has proved to be most
valuable in the following diseases:
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs ; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Rheumatism ; Salt Rheum ; Secondary Syphilis ;
Functional Disorders of the Liver ; Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous
diseases and disorders arising from impurities of the blood. It is also an excelent remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption.
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or iive times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
PLAIN TALKS
ON
PRACTICAL RELIGION,
Being    Candid   Answers   for Earnest
Inquirers.
By  Geo.  A.   Lotnas.
Price, 10 els.--><pb n="245" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 13" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. No.
                            13.</head><p TEIform="p">"TTVEB. 14. Most of the Brethren and Sisters are up all night watching -J_ the premises, as
                            great excitement prevails throughout the town on account of the rumor that Bowling Green is
                            on fire, and the Confederates have threatened to burn our village. At two o'clock, a. m.
                            some of the same company that had been with us the day previous, pass through the village,
                            leading some ten or twelve horses that they have taken from our neighbors. Some were robbed
                            of every horse or mule that they owned. A little boy of twelve years, Thomas Rule, had come
                            to the village on an errand for his sick grandfather. He rode a beautiful horse. We hastily
                            had the horse taken to the rear of one of the buildings and carefully guarded till the
                            robbers were out of sight. He was soon on his horse and reached home in safety, but in a few
                            days his home was visited by the same gang and the horse stolen, although the owner was a
                            good Confederate. A company of wild, lawless characters are out stealing all the horses and
                            negroes that they can and taking them farther to the south. They threaten to burn all the
                            houses and mills on the line of the railroad between Nashville and Bowling Green. Our
                            Brethren and Sisters are encouraged to be prayerful, and to seek the protection and blessing
                            of God on our labors. It is a time of sorrow for all the Believers in the state of Kentucky,
                            and we seem to be, largely, under the domination of wicked men. Some of the horses have been
                            driven to the woods to hide them from the robbers, and the poor animals must suffer very
                            much from the cold, during the night. Some of our neighbors not only tie their horses but
                            also hide their slaves. One man took a load of his slaves and hid them in the woods.
                            NOVEMBER <pb n="246" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 246 THE MANIFESTO. One night we carried almost every valuable
                            article out of the Trustees' Office, as we were afraid the building would be burned. Feb.
                            15. Three inches of snow fell last night, but as no buildings wore burned we felt quit e
                            well. At eleven o'clock a company dash up to the Woolen Factory. They alight and enter the
                            mill. Robbers.Can we get some cloth? Brother.-You can not. Robbers.What is going on down
                            stairs? Brother.Nothing. Some ladies are there. Robbers.We do not want to disturb the
                            ladies. I must take off this canteen or the ladies will think I have been drinking. They
                            concluded not to go down stairs. We learn that the Federals are in Bowling Green. We can
                            distinctly hear the canonading, and see the smoke from the buildings, which the Confederates
                            set on fire before they left. Robbers visit the East family again this evening, and act like
                            mad men. They threaten to burn the buildings. They search the stables for horses and then go
                            into the cow barn and after much coarse and vulgar talk they leave the place. Feb. 16.
                            Mercury stands at 15 deg. above zero. The coldest day of the winter. The Confederates
                            threaten to burn all the mills and say that the Federals shall not have the mills to make
                            flour in. This makes a very anxious time for our Brethren and Sisters, and a company of them
                            go down to our Woolen mill to protect the property as well as they can. Sabbath, Feb. 17.
                            How thankful we are for the protection of our heavenly Father. May we be worthy of this kind
                            protection. At three o'clock p. m. a company of Union Cavalry ride in front of our family
                            Dwelling. They are well armed. Their appearance is very different from the Confederate
                            soldiers. In a few minutes Elder Solomon went and spoke to the Captain, and made enquiry
                            about Bowling Green. Captain.I guess matters are getting about right there. Have you seen
                            any soldiers before who have just the appearance we have ? Eld. S.We have not. These are the
                            first Union soldiers we have seen. Captain.How long since you have seen any Confederate
                            soldiers ? Eld. S.We have not seen any for thirty-six hours. All the Brethren and Sisters
                            seem to be very grateful for this change of scene. We carry out to the soldiers some pies,
                            bread, apples and milk, and all is thankfully received. They talked freely about the
                            destruction of property at Bowling Green. What the Confederate army could not carry away
                            they were piling up in the streets and setting it on fire. As Br. Jefferson and those who
                            were hauling the sugar came in sight, the soldiers were anxious and enquired, "What does
                            that mean?" <pb n="247" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO, 247 Two of them dashed off in a hurry to
                            find outAfter a short interview they all went east, saying,"We shall be back in an hour or
                            two, aud some of us may want to stop over night." Br. Urban informed the soldiers how our
                            horses had been taken from us; and one rough-looking fellow remarked,"That is right in
                            the.usages of war. If I was in need of a horse, and could get it in no other way, I should
                            do the same." This remark made us a little suspicious, parhaps we were talking to
                            Confederates in disguise. Possibly we had been too confiding. Looking toward the East
                            family, we saw the flames arising and our imagination was at once aroused, as we thought of
                            the buildings at that place, and the distress of the Brethren and Sisters. Several of the
                            Brethren mounted their horses and went to ascertain the cause of the alarm. Gn their return
                            they were sure that the soldiers belonged to the Union army and were only obeying orders to
                            burn the bridges, to prevent being surprised by the Confederates. The Brethren assured them
                            that there was no real danger, and the soldiers very considerately closed their work of
                            destruction. We were now assured that these were Union soldiers, and the O. V. C. on their
                            caps wasOhio Volunteer Company. Some of these soldiers returned and remained with us for
                            several days, when they were confident that no more harm would come to us. Feb. 18. Union
                            soldiers are now constantly passing through the village. One hundred and fifty Cavalry
                            stopped here last night, about two hours, and were treated .to some bread, meat and milk.
                            They did not wish the people to get up and cook for them, and this consideration seemed like
                            a great kindness. Feb. 19. One hundred and ten Union Cavalry call for breakfast. We are
                            right glad that we can give them some good coffee. If a battle had been fought at Bowling
                            Green, and the Confederates had been victorious, they had contemplated making a hospital for
                            the sick and wounded, at South Union. But that penalty was not inflicted upon us, and we
                            have great reason to be thankful that we escaped. Feb. 20. Ninety Union Cavalry of the
                            fourth Kentucky regiment pass through our village on their way to Greenville. Corporal James
                            Pike, of Texas, is very sick with the ague, and not able to go with the company. Several
                            soldiers are now boarding at the Trustees' Office. Three of this company visit our neighbors
                            where they find two sick Confederate soldiers. They make the men promise to support the
                            government of the U. S. and then taking away their guns, return to the Office. They visit
                            another southern sympathizer, but all the white people are hid from sight. On their return
                            they tell the story and say they shall go again. They made three visits and on the third
                            they found one of the family. They asked him for some liquor. <pb n="248" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 248 THE
                            MANIFESTO. The young man said he had none. The soldiers said they knew better and should
                            have some of it. Frightened by this threat the liquor was brought in. The soldiers told him
                            to drink some. He said he did not wish to drink any ; but they commanded him to drink some,
                            and finding himself in so close a place he drank the liquor. The soldiers then drank and
                            soon ordeivd the young man to show them every room in the house. On their return to the
                            Trustees' Office they told their story as something very amusing, and laughed heartily. Feb.
                            23. Five soldiers attend Divine Service with us. Feb. 24. The two Brethren who have been in
                            Union Village about three months, return to South Union. On learning that the Union troops
                            had entered Bowling Green they were very anxious to return. Feb. 26. Seven box cars and four
                            platform cars that have been in the possession of the Confederates for some six months, are
                            taken by the Federals and sent to Bowling Green. The Union soldiers who board at the Office
                            prefer to sleep on the floor, and have their weapons near them. A wat h is kept out all
                            night. Some of our horses are kept in the woods. One night one of them broke his halter and
                            came neighing to the stable gate. The guard gave a shrill whistle and instantly the whole
                            company were out of the house to ascertain the trouble. The Brethren also went out and
                            finding one of our horses, put him in the stable, and soon all was quiet again. (To be
                            continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hazel blossoms" TEIform="index"/>HAZEL BLOSSOMS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, Lydia" TEIform="persName"/>Lydia Staples.</byline><p TEIform="p">It was but yesterday, on woodlands wild The sweet brier twined its strong and thorny stem
                            With leaves of green, and set its blushing gem Of pink, where fell the shades that day
                            beguiled And early sunbursts where the morning smiled. But now, when brown leaves skirt the
                            forest's hem, The hazel wears its tawny diadem, And follows on, a lonely pilgrim child.
                            Again its time to bloom will come and go, We may not see it in the lonely way, But, in that
                            love which bade its gold to blow Along the flowerless paths in autumn grey, We can like it,
                            though late, a chaplet bring, And lay Upon life's shrine, an offering. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        T.</p></div2><pb n="249" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>HEALTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha" TEIform="persName"/>Martha Burger.</byline><p TEIform="p">(WRITTEN FOR THE SELF-IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY.) 
                            TT^O my understanding this little word comprehends a meaning that is JL magnificent; that for
                            which we express our aim in the motto of our society; ''Harmony of being; physical,
                            intellectual and spiritual." "The wonderful harp of a thousand strings," all attuned to the
                            divine thought of our Creator. Of the various departments of our being each has its laws,
                            and these should be studied systematically, and obeyed in the love of truth and in reverence
                            to the God in our own being, One has written, "Cultivate the physical forces exclusively and
                            you have an athlete or a savage; the moral only and you have an enthusiast or maniac; the
                            intellectual only and you have a diseased oddity, it may be a monster. It is only by
                            training all together, the physical, intellectual, social and spiritual faculties that the
                            complete man, the true image of God can be formed." We, as a Society and Order of people,
                            have opportunities for such training unequaled by the greater part of the human family. In
                            the neglect of these we must not only bear the reproach which will be manifest in our
                            individual being, but we shall be responsible for our short-comings in the lessened power
                            for good which we might otherwise exert upon the lives of others. On the present occasion we
                            will limit ourselves to a few remarks and rules relative to our physical being. Among the
                            Ancient Spaniards it was an adage that "every man at thirty was either a physiologist or a
                            fool." I suppose we should all like to be certain as to which class we belong; and will
                            therefore be willing to give some attention to the structure of the "house we live in."
                            First, a few words upon the vegetarian diet may be in place, as there are still in our own
                            time many intelligent and earnest reformers in some lines, who hold that animal food is
                            essential to health and strength; but to us this seems a mistake even in theory, when the
                            best authorities on the subject teach us that as human beings our anatomical structure is
                            decidedly graminivorous rather than carnivorous, and the weight of evidence in favor of
                            physical endurance is on the side of the former, in races, nations and all burden bearing
                            animals. Aside from this, to all who are striving to develop the divinest and most interior
                            faculties of being, ethical considerations are paramount to all others, and the more refined
                            and spiritual natures turn with abhorrence from the scenes of the slaughter house and meat
                            market, and shrink from the idea of slaying innocent creatures and mingling their dead
                            bodies with the life blood of their own, while favored with soil and climate adapted to rich
                            harvests of grains and fruits. <pb n="250" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 250 THE MANIFESTO. Being thus blest and
                            having also abundance of the best and purest of all beverages gushing from our hillside, and
                            so situated that we nifty breathe deeply of the exhilarating mountain air, we realize the
                            worth of the only genuine blood purifier, and may enjoy that priceless boon of health and
                            happiness which all the contents of a drug store would b?. powerless to bestow. It is well
                            for us in eating and drinking to observe use rather than pleasure, and accustom ourselves to
                            regular habits. Condiments and stimulating drinks should rarely be used. The skin should be
                            kept clean aud active, the temper even, and the mind contented; thus we may indeed make of
                            our bodies k'temples of the Holy Spirit." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Continuance in well-doing" TEIform="index"/>CONTINUANCE IN WELL-DOING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emerson, Mary K." TEIform="persName"/>By Mary K. Emerson.</byline><p TEIform="p">TTTE sometimes discontinue a course of well-doing, simply because we do VV not fully realize,
                            our well-doing is doing well, or in other words, do not see the immediate result of our
                            efforts and think, cause is or should be followed promptly by its effect. So, many a noble
                            work though well begun, fades away before that negative, wilting, withering power,
                            discouragement, or what is worse, is laid aside as impossible, impracticable and unworthy of
                            further consideration. Thus, consigned to the tomb of forgetfulness, another may feel it
                            folly to attempt its resurrection, or renewing, b ing so condemned. When the real cause of
                            its failure and unfortunate termination, is our blindness and impatience. Blind, because we
                            do not consider that all growth or development, whether natural or spiritual, is by slow,
                            progressive steps. Impatient, because we look for fruit too soon after the planting; for
                            harvest too soon after the sowing. There is a close analogy between the natural and
                            spiritual. From nature, that never failing source of knowledge and beauty where God holds
                            forth in grandeur and loveliness, truths for the happiness and uplifting of mortals, let us
                            learn lessons in patient well-doing. Innumerable examples are afforded us by the wonders of
                            scientific research. The great variety of strata, the deposits of ages found at great depths
                            below the earth's surface ; the coral reefs, the untiring work of the coral insects ;
                            achievements of wind and wave, also the gradual transformation of the acorn into the mighty
                            oak, still, the humblest instruments ofttimes teach us the greatest lessons in patient
                            well-doing, because they are accompanied with humility, sweet angel guardian of thought and
                            act. Thus each atom of matter so minute, does well its work in forming the general mass. The
                            rain-drop, even after it has lost its identity absorbed by withering grass, wilting leaf or
                            parched earth, keeps on renewing with life-giving power, or aided by the sunbeam acting
                            prismatically, assists in reflecting the beautiful colors of the <pb n="251" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 251 rainbow*. Similar examples meet us on every hand avid in the great economy of
                            nature, in her decay is life. She only sinks to rise again and continue in well-doing. Let
                            us therefore consider our motive in the putting forth of effort; its source, its object; is
                            it for fame, notoriety or the praise of men? Or is it for the holy purpose of doing good in
                            a quiet, unobtrusive manner and being a co-worker with God, the "Father of Lights" and the
                            giver of every good and perfect gift. Such a motive, having its source in the divine
                            fountain, will, like a stream flow on with persistent activity, overcoming every obstacle in
                            its way, while the heavenly echoes heard along its banks, help it on its course, until at
                            last it reaches the "Sweet Summer Land" where, amid augelic greetings, it receives the
                            commendation, ' 'Well done thou good and faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy
                            Lord." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Henry:--Your favor of the 6th..." TEIform="index"/>Elder Henry:--Your favor of the 6th...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Bangor, August 7, 1894" TEIform="index"/>Bangor, Me. Aug. 7, 1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder Henry:Your favor of the 6th inst. came to my house to-day. I am working in my
                                Master's cause to help set free his erring children of earth and I have no time of my
                                own to go and see you. Work, eternal work, not prayers, is what is going to free the
                                captives bound in chains of darkness, and in prison. We can not bring in the Millennium
                                in any other way than by working for it, and it is my opinion that we shall not have to
                                work one third as long, if we go to work in earnest, to bring it in, as the people have
                                been in praying for it. Faith and prayer are of but little account without works. We
                                must plant and cultivate in order to have a harvest. The Shakers have been praying for
                                nearly fifty years for an increase, and all this time have been growing less. Now let
                                them go to work in real earnest regardless of dollars and cents, to bring it about, and
                                I believe their efforts will be greatly rewarded. "Perpetual vigilance is the price of
                                liberty." All that is worth having is worth laboring for, and the article of our good
                                brother, A. W. Dowe, in the July Manifesto is right to the point and if all the
                                Believers of the several Societies would act up to it they would become a power in the
                                land for the liberation of mankind, from ages of errors and superstition. Your brother
                                forever, to spread the light of truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emery, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>Simon Emery.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Errors, like straws..." TEIform="index"/>Errors, like straws...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Eeeoes, like straws upon the surface flow, He who would search for pearls must dive below.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dryden" TEIform="persName"/>Dryden.</byline></div2><pb n="252" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="C. C. C." TEIform="index"/>C.C.C.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/>By Ernest Pick.</byline><p TEIform="p">fT^HERE are many people who would give almost anything for the qualifL _JL cation of a F. R.
                            S. L. or F. R. S. or even the less pompous M. A. or L. L. D. attached to their name, but are
                            too old or otherwise hindered to spend the necessary time and application to study that wins
                            such distinctions. But as long as we have not got through with th' school of life we need
                            not lose all hope and begin training and aspiring for a distinction qtial, if not superior,
                            to all the high-sounding titles that colleges or societies may confer upon a person. Now C.
                            C. C. looks fully as well as D. 1). and is fraught with meaning and importance, nor can we
                            attain it without much study and a persistent application of all the lessons that life and
                            its experience teaches. You will look in vain for the meaning of C. C. C. in Webster's
                            Unabridged ; I, therefore, will give you a detailed explanation of it. The first C. stands
                            for cool and applies to the body. Many persons are born, live and die without ever getting
                            on friendly terms with their next door neighbor, their own mortal body. Yea, more, as if by
                            all means they intended to ruin his welfare they feed him with things they could not be
                            persuaded to offer to dogs or pigs, let alone their horses and cows. Now it is of great
                            importance for our happiness to keep our body in good condition and working order, by
                            investigating its real needs and best methods of supply. We would think it an insane
                            proceeding to "water" our stock with whiskey and beer to insure their strength, or to
                            increase their tone or spirit with coffee and tea. Still men think it is good for them, and
                            the world spends many tim s more money for these articles than for bread and flour. Such
                            unhygienic drinks added to any amount of improper food create an unhealthy quality of blood
                            which irritates the most vital organs, like heart, lungs and brain, while passing through
                            and feeding them. The whole body is kept in a more or less feverish condition, subject to
                            contagion and disease. At the other hand a body built up with the most simple and natural
                            food will constantly keep in a pleasant, cool equilibrium, not easily thrown out of balance
                            even if exposed to exceptional conditions for a long time. The second C. stands for calm,
                            and applies to the mind or soul principle. Very few persons have a distinct idea of the
                            division between body, soul and spirit though they frequently use this classification of the
                            three fold composition of man. Especially the last two elements are often ill understood,
                            and confused as to their distinct nature and functions. This can be made very clear to the
                            understanding by first putting the body entirely out of our consideration. Then only two
                            objects remain for investigation; of these the ever-ebbing, ever-tiding element is the soul;
                            it is the battle ground of our <pb n="253" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 253 lower and higher
                            self, upon which defeat takes turn with victory, and where grief follows closely unto joy.
                            Experience in life's happenings, and the nacessity of our coming out victorious will teach
                            as the most profitable choice for us; to be calm, like a good ciptain during a wild storm or
                            a strategist in a fierce batttle. Self-knowledge is of greatest importance; next to
                            self-control in gaining that calm mind which alone will insure our happiness. "He to whom
                            sorrow is the same as joy, And joy the same as sorrow, May thank God for his equanimity."
                            With the third C. we enter the realm of the Spirit,our highest attribute. It stands for
                            comfortable in its original meaning (cum-fortis-strong) strong in spirit (Not as this word
                            is usually used implying ease or repose.) The Spirit ;.s the highest attribute of man's
                            nature, it is the part of God within us, it is the immutable, the divine of which we must
                            get fully conscious before we can realize a close union with God. There is no battling or
                            wavering in the realm of the Spirit, no weakness, no uncertainty but all is decision. There
                            is strength that knows no weakness, victory that knows no defeat. "He to whom time is the
                            same as eternity, And eternity the same as time, Is free from all contention." We may well
                            perceive that it will take more than a term of three or four years in the college of life,
                            before we graduate and become C. C. C. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith" TEIform="index"/>FAITH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lane, Mabel E." TEIform="persName"/>By Mabel E. Lane.</byline><p TEIform="p">While on the sea of life, what faith is mine, I walk upon the wave, nor fear the tide; When
                            earth-born ebon clouds arise and hide The azure sky, like Bethlehem's star 'twill shine And
                            lead the way to perfect light, divine. 'Tis like the form of Christ when storms betide, It
                            whispers to the soul, "Oh e'er abide In God, and kneel at Truth's pure, sacred shrine." The
                            voice of doubt speaks not of holy peace, Nor of the gifts we covet as the best. Thus while I
                            hold this light within my breast My soul shall know no failing, but increase In that pure
                            way whose blessings ne'er will cease, Not e'en when passing life's severest test. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="254" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solemn thoughts" TEIform="index"/>SOLEMN THOUGHTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wayne, Sophia" TEIform="persName"/>By Sophia Wayne.</byline><p TEIform="p">How lengthened seems each passing year A memory spreads her pictures clear, And brings again
                            our loved ones near From the celestial shore. We would not wish them to remain To undergo
                            earth's grief and pain, Yet joy to know they come again To greet us as T)efore. Our mortal
                            life is fleeting fast. Time's pilgrimage will soon be pastr Will we regret to leave at last
                            This tenement of clay? Tet some at thought of death have fear, They dread its presence
                            drawing near. Terrestrial joys to them seem dear, No future hope have they. Those who have
                            comforts shared below., And felt not pangs of want and woey Care not another state to know,
                            Nor seek for purer blissYet when the final change they meet, They find their heaven is
                            incomplete, For barren paths await their feet, As they have walked amiss. The poor, the
                            lowly and despised, Who selfish loves have sacrificed, Rejoice in bowers emparadised And
                            virtue's ways pursue. Adorned with flowers that bloom thro' prayer, The fruits of blessing
                            grown by care, These shall the upright ever share,. Whose souls are pure and true. . The
                            Master, by love's impulse led, The naked clothed, the hungry fed, Yet had not where to lay
                            his head In Palestine's fair land. <pb n="255" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO, 255 The mount he
                            sought to pray and fast, Till, trials and temptations past Truth's golden hights he gained
                            at last, The home where victors stand. Though low is brought our nature proud, And deepest
                            griefs our way enshroud, A silver lining hath the cloud That ofttimes veils the goal. We
                            shrink because of little faith, The change to life we think is death, Yet, know the grave no
                            triumph hath, O'er the immortal soul. BaUston N. F.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Belden, Emoretta" TEIform="persName"/>By Emoretta Belden</byline><p TEIform="p">What shall I do Lord? Acts xxii, 10. Hearken diligently unto me, Isaiah lv., 2. Abhor that
                            which is evil, Rom. xii., 9. Turn to me, and I will turn to thee. Zech. i.. 3. Set your
                            affection on things above, Col, iii., 2. Holding faith and a pure conscience, 1 Tim. i., 19.
                            And be not conformed to this world; Eom. xii., 2. Let love be without dissimulation; Rom.
                            xii., 9. Live peaceably with all men, Rom. xii., 18. Incline your ear and come unto me,
                            Isaiah lv., 3, Dread not, neither be afraid, Deut. i., 29. Obey my voice and I will be your
                            God. Jer. vii., 23. Lay aside every weight and sin, Heb. xii., 1. Overcome the wicked one, 1
                            John ii., 13. Remember how I walked before thee, 2 Kings xx., 3. Draw nigh to God and he
                            will draw nigh to you. James iv., 8. West PitUJMd, Mass,</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is always easy to count our trials and difficulties..." TEIform="index"/>
                            It is always easy to count our trials and difficulties...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is always easy to count our trials and difficulties, but we should not be unmindful of the
                            sweet scented gardens through which we pass, nor of the angels of comfort with whom we
                            frequent, who present us with heavenly flowers, which in our hearts die not, neither lose
                            their sweetness, the blossoms of faith, hope, innocence and love, and the white lily of
                            purity which I would guard most sacredly from aught that would wither or blight.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Allen.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every thing that exists..." TEIform="index"/>Every thing that exists...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Every thing that exists that can be conceived of, material or immaterial, shadow or
                            substance, can be named as one word (viz.)Energy.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. H.</byline></div2><pb n="256" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian mission" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRISTIAN MISSION. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">WE are inclined, sometimes, to think that it almost needs a special inspiration in order to
                            be able to do good, and instantly our minds are carried to the words of the apostle, "When I
                            would do good, evil is present with me." If unfortunately our conditions are such as to hold
                            us under unfavorable influences, then it may well be said that an inspiration is needed to
                            keep our feet in the path of right. To be good and to do good, is indeed, a very simple
                            sentence, and at first thought might be laid aside as of little value. But when we speak of
                            our pilgrimage though this life, and the great responsibility that devolves upon every one
                            to so live that the world may be made better by our presence, then those little
                            monosyllables become wonderfully magnified in their influence for righteousness and peace.
                            God is good,and that in a superlative degree, but inasmuch as we are recipients of the
                            spirit of good, in that same degree are we god-like, and are made able to be and to do good
                            on our pilgrimage toward the Holy City. No order of religious profession, nor any system of
                            ancient or modern ceremonies can do fur an individual or for a community what may be done
                            through the influence of this simple sentence. To live in the spirit of consecrated
                            righteousness is to live in the inspiration of God. It is allowing the inspirational light
                            to shine into our own hearts and no less into the hearts of those around us. "Him that
                            overcometh will I make a pillar in the temple of my God, and he shall go no more out." A
                            deeper and a better inspiration now enables the soul to be a pillar in the temple of God,
                            and its quality of goodness must determine its value in this sacred place. Certainly its
                            whole life is now absorbed in doing good. The whole of the Christian mission has for its
                            foundation the work of doing good. It was to the poor that the gospel was preached and they
                            soon learned that it was, to them, the glad tidings of great joy. The deaf were made to
                            hear, the blind to see and the lame to walk. All were healed of their infirmities and sent
                            forward on the mission of doing good to others. The establishing of a Christian Community
                            which Jesus entered upon so soon as he began to preach was included in his mission of doing
                            good, and it was from this incentive that the apostles were able at a later date to
                            establish an organization that represented the Christianity of Jesus in <pb n="257" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 257 its perfected state. When the twelve were engaged in their
                            evangelistic work they appointed one to take charge of their financial interests and to
                            provide for the company as circumstances demanded. This was the first lesson of consecration
                            that was given out by the divine Teacher. "Whosoever he be of you that forsaketh not all
                            that he hath, he can not be my disciple," and in conversation with the rich young man, Jesus
                            was free to tell him that he had not where to lay his head. That is, he had no selfish home,
                            and when Peter spoke for himself and his brethren, "Behold, we have forsaken all to follow
                            thee," he was in a corresponding state. It was the brotherhood of Jesus. All that the
                            disciples possessed was consecrated to the good of the Community. Here begins the work of
                            mercy and of charity and of deep interest for the good of mankind at large, and this leads
                            us to this conclusion. To be a follower of Jesus the Christ, one must forsake all that he
                            hath. He must become as said the apostle,"Crucified to the world." Here then is the
                            opportunity to be good, agreeably to the instruction of the Teacher. There is nothing very
                            mysterious about it, and it requires no extended time in which to study the simple lesson of
                            consecration. If we are diligent pupils in this school of Christ we shall regard the Teacher
                            in that he says,"Learn of me." As he went about doing good, his disciples can do no less.
                            And here comes the place where the inspirations from a higher source need flow into the mind
                            and mould the thoughts, words and actions, agreeably, to the pattern. Inspired! Can a man be
                            otherwise than inspired if he accept "the wisdom that is from above, first pure, then
                            peaceable, easy to be entreated, full of mercy and good fruits, without partiality and
                            without hypocrisy ?" Again we may profitably be reminded of the admonition of Jesus, "Learn
                            of me," as it is so easy to be careless of the words we speak. No one for a moment would
                            believe that Jesus was indifferent to the influence which he exercised over the minds of
                            others, or that he used a style of language, on any occasion that was below the standard of
                            Christian propriety. To do good requires of us a corresponding care, as the life of Christ
                            must be that of a careful disciplinarian, and whether at home or abroad, nothing should be
                            allowed to enter the heart that will not bear this test.</p></div2><pb n="258" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My home" TEIform="index"/>MY HOME.</head><p TEIform="p">"Lord, I have loved the habitation of thy house, and the place where thine honor
                            dwelleth."Psa. xxvi., 8. Canterbury, N. H. 1891. Bright Elysian fields of truth! Gardens of
                            God's gifts divine! Fountains of his boundless love! Here's my home forever. Sacred home!
                            all other climes Pale before thy wondrous light. These will change as works of time, Thou
                            wilt fail me never.</p></div2><pb n="259" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1894. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75
                            .40 One copy per year, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. September. Thermometer. Rain. 1893. 56. 10.125in.
                                1894. 64.1 5 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 87 above 0. Lowest " " " " 32 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 13 " clear " " " 11 " " cloudy" " " 6 C. G. Reed. Oct. 1894. The
                                protracted drought of summer is at last ended. Since the 10th of September, the needed
                                rains have changed the sered pastures, orchards, and lawns to a thrifty and beautiful
                                green and our mountain springs are again supplied. Like the bee and the ant, which are
                                so often cited as examples of industry, we are gathering our winter stores, which the
                                faithful toils through summer, aided by the sunshine and shower have given us. I see by
                                Notes from Harvard, that by reason of drought, apples though plentiful are small. It is
                                not so here. Never in our recollection, has good fortune given us such a crop of
                                colossal apples. Through the September Notes, we could trace the visit of the loved
                                Ministry and Elders from the West, and on the 1st inst it was our happy privilege to
                                welcome them to Lebanon. We have enjoyed their association, more than pen can express,
                                and especially so since though brief their stay, we could say "Home Again" to our worthy
                                Elder Joseph Slingerland, who from early childhood, to mature and useful manhood, was
                                with us through joy and sorrow, toil and spiritual growth. We are happy to "cast our
                                bread upon the waters," though we may hunger ourselves, for by it we feel the benefits
                                of a sympa. thetic cord of union and fellowship, with our Western friends which holds us
                                all to our noble purpose. On the evening of the 4th inst. our family were invited to
                                attend with the Social Improvement Society at the North family, with our own loved
                                Central Ministry, and friends from the West, and a profitable and delightful evening was
                                spent. Flowers and sweet music both vocal and instrumental were appropriately
                                interspersed with original productions of the class, both extempore, and prepared. This
                                revives anew the faith which has been ours .from early life, that a perfect gospel
                                growth, includes the entire being, physical mental and spiritual. It should purify both
                                body and soul, quicken and consecrate the intellect, and refine every thought word and
                                action. These beautiful privileges which our gospel gives us, are authenticated by the
                                words of Father James". "There is nothing too good for the people of God;" also by our
                                Savior's promise "Seek ye first the kingdom of God and its righteousness and all these
                                things shall be added." Amelia J. Culver. TERMS. <pb n="260" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> SCO TEE
                                MANIFESTO. ^orth Family. Oct. 1894. The harvest is past, the summer is ended and it we
                                are not fully saved we know t!ie essentials of salvation and hope by a faithful
                                continuance in well-doing to be so some day. Through all the vicissitudes of a
                                remarkable spring and summer we have lived and been well cared for, and at the end have
                                harvested very satisfactory returns for our labors all around. When a young boy I heard
                                a sermon preached from the text, "I have been young and now am old, yet have I not seen
                                the righteous forsaken nor his seed begging bread." Listening to the preacher I was
                                inspired with a faith in Divine Providence that has been a stay and consolation through
                                life. "Trust in God and do the right." Living up to our highest light, in the daily
                                practice of gospel principles in the spirit of peace and union, neither drought nor
                                flood, fire nor wind can destroy the confidence and satisfaction and benefits that will
                                flow to us. Our reward will be to us according as we love and serve each other. Our
                                beloved gospel friends the Ministry and Elders of the Western Societies paid us a visit.
                                We enjoyed a rare privilege which we much appreciated. On the evening of one of the days
                                they spent with us, our "Self Improvement Society" entertained them. The Central
                                Ministry and a company of Elders, Brethren and Sisters of the Church and Center families
                                were also present. At the close very appreciative and encouraging remarks were made.
                                Eldress Harriet expressed the thankfulness and satisfaction she felt as a spiritual
                                parent to see her young charge making such earnest and successful efforts to cultivate
                                their minds in all that is good and beautiful and useful, that they might thereby be of
                                greater service in the cause they have espoused. Taking up this thought Elder Daniel
                                remarked that Elder Frederic used to say that young people brought up under our care
                                were more credit to us if they excelled us in virtue and knowledge than if they were
                                behind. During the meeting the question was asked by one of the Sisters, "What of the
                                future of Shakerism?" and replied to by another Sister. Which at the close of the
                                meeting called forth a few remarks. Whatever the future may have in store for the Shaker
                                Institution, Shaker principles are imperishable and are finding wider and firmer
                                acceptance continually. The question f )r us is "Has the Shaker Society leaders to put
                                it upon a basis for the better and more complete practice of its principles." Time will
                                prove. I for one will trust in the spirit of God in my Elders, Brethren and Sisters and
                                strive to do the right myself. Walter S. Shepherd.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Oct 1894. Lately, while thinking upon the subject of thankfulness and
                                realizing the importance of showing gratitude for the many blessings we enjoy, we found
                                an extract from a poem by Celia Thaxter, entitled "Courage" which we copy. "Why should I
                                hug life's ills with cold reserve To curse myself and all who love me? Nay A thousand
                                times more good than I deserve God gives me every day. And in each one of these
                                rebellious tears Kept bravely back, He makes a rainbow shine Grateful I take his
                                slightest gift, no fears Nor any doubts are mine." The cultivation of the faculty of
                                looking on the bright side and contemplating the blessings of life, rather than the ills
                                is a necessary one, especially in these times when the daily press is filled with
                                catastrophies and the elements of the physical world seem to have declared war on
                                humanity, destroying the means of sustaining life and often life itself. In the struggle
                                to grasp the lion's share of material blessings, man forgets the rights of his fellow
                                man, until the demoniac forces are roused and are united with <pb n="261" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 261 the physical elements and it is destroyed, for the prophetic announcement
                                will be fulfilled. "And the old heavens and earth shall pass away with a great noise,"
                                but we will "hide in the Lord's pavilion till the tempest and the storm pass by." We
                                will second the motion or suggestion by Elder Oliver and should also like to see our
                                "Manifesto make weekly visits." A silo 11x26 and 30 feet deep has been erected and at
                                present writing, is receiving the corn fodder from the sweet corn after it has been
                                picked and dried. Properly preserved ensilage is more relished by stock in general and
                                the milk producing properties are greater than dry fodder. To all lovers of Lima beans,
                                we would say, try Burpee's Dwarf Lima, they are fully equal to the large Pole Lima in
                                quality. We consider them a necessary adj unct to our garden. Hamilton DeGrnw. Second
                                Family. Oct. 1894. While blest with cares and burdens, we might make excuses for some
                                neglect of one duty, but instead will say, we will try and do 'better. We have just
                                finished drying sweet corn. Had a good crop for this season as corn has not been good
                                generally in this section on account of drought. We have had one frost thus far but it
                                did very little damage and should good weather continue shall have more tomatoes to can.
                                We are busy filling silos. Apples are not secured. The crops in this section are good as
                                were pears. While we are harvesting temporal blessings, may the Giver of all good send
                                us souls who have conviction, and a desire to leave the world and its sinfulness. As the
                                harvest is great and the laborers few, may the vacuum caused by departed and departing
                                saints to the shores beyond, be filled, and Zion again flourish and grow. When we cast a
                                mental glance over Zion's spiritual condition and ask,Lord when will the forty years in
                                t his spiritual wilderness be over? the answer comes, though few the number, yet like
                                Gideon's Army there are too many yet who will not lap the spiritual waters. Let us gird
                                on the armor of strength, and like the few Spartans who stood in the pass, stand as firm
                                in the spiritual gap and bid defiance to all weakness. Union is what we need, which
                                binds us together with one feeling; that the spiritual cloud must be lifted and we will
                                work together to that end. Isaac Anstatt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. "In the world ye shall find tribulation," said Jesus, "but in me ye shall find
                                peace." In a worldly life there is no shield from trouble and sin. Thousands are seeking
                                for peace and happiness in sinful pleasure but they find it not, that aching void is
                                still in the heart. Sin promises joys but pays sorrows. Self-denying struggles bring
                                sweet home peace and never ending joy. The true cross-bearer is sure to win though long
                                and severe be the struggle. Only as the heart advances in purity does the spirit move on
                                over the rough sea of nature, to the haven of peace. Let us contend for peace. "The
                                baobab tree, in Asia is considered one of the most wonderful of the vegetable creation.
                                It appears that nothing can kill this tree, hence it reaches an astonishing age as well
                                as enormous size. The natives make a strong cord from the fibers of the bark, hence the
                                trees are continually barked, but without damage, as they soon put forth a new bark. It
                                appears impervious to fire, and even the ax is resisted, as it continues to grow in
                                length while it is lying on the ground. ******* It is well to feed a variety of
                                nutritious food to hens and chickens in moult. Hens are now in annual moult, and
                                chickens in first natural moult. Poultry raising is a business that can be commenced
                                with very limited means. Daniel Orcutt. <pb n="262" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 262 THE MANIFESTO. South.
                                Family. Oct. 1894. How lovely and consistent is the order of the seasons as they come
                                and go. The harvest is nearly completed for the present year, and for the bountiful
                                blessings which we have recieved we would be truly thankful. The potatoes which it was
                                feared would be a short crop on account of the dry season has yielded fairly well and
                                very good quality. The corn was also a fair yield. Our silo has been filled with an
                                extra quality of ensilage. We used several different varieties of corn. Hickox sweet
                                corn proved very good, the large western corn made a great growth but was considered
                                unprofitable, much of it was thirteen feet in height, but there was three times as much
                                stalk as fodder, while the corn we have grown here for years gave the best results of
                                any, there being three times as much fodder as stalk, and an average of 1)4 ears to a
                                stalk. This is a flint corn and a phenomenal yielder. It took eleven acres to fill our
                                silo of 150 tons, so we must yield the palm to others, but will try to do better in the
                                future. It took about four days to fill the silo the cutter being run by steam power.
                                There has been some painting done on our buildings the past two weeks which improves the
                                appearance of our quiet home. Have not the unwearied labors of the summer been rewarded?
                                While many are suffering from want and hunger, we can reap the benefits of labor, and
                                industry, in having all our wants supplied, while many destitute ones call at our doors
                                for bread. The health of our family is good, and for all these blessings, thankfulness
                                prevails. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. "The harvest now is over, the summer days are gone." Our silos are filled and
                                corn all gathered We have had an average crop of apples, which we finished picking on
                                the 9th. The potato crop is below the average, which is never very large with us, at
                                best. This summer the old seed-house near the Ministry's Dwelling has been taken down,
                                and since the ground has been leveled, it adds quite a little to the children's
                                playground. Some of our buildings are being shingled and repaired in various ways, which
                                means work for "busy hands." Our roots are nearly all dried and cut. We are fast getting
                                short of water for power for our mills. Our large reservoir on the mountain is lower
                                than for many years. We are still blest with enough for domestic use. Everyone is
                                wishing for rain. We heartily sympathize with our gospel kindred who have been visited
                                by the fire fiend so recently. We hope the end of it has come, as three fires in about a
                                month, is quite enough to hear about. G. H. Kirkley.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. Beloved Elder Henry:-1-We are reminded of the pleasant duty of writing a few
                                lines for The Manifesto, in regard to our home. The days of the harvest are passing.
                                Potatoes are already stored, a sufficient crop for home use and some to sell. We are now
                                gathering the apples, of which we have an abundance for cooking, for drying and for
                                eating. Many barrels are being packed away for sale and we shall have more than usual to
                                make into cider for the Shaker Apple Sauce. Sweet corn seed is secured and drying;
                                ensilage cut and silo filled. The young Brethren have been quite interested in raising
                                vegetables and melons. O! the melons have been delicious that they have furnished for
                                the family table! They took a collection to the New Gloucester Fair. One squash weighed
                                76 lbs. and a tomato over 2 lbs. One of the young <pb n="263" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                263 Sisters found a wild ripe strawberry September 21st. By consulting the Office
                                Register we find 1250 names of visitors who have called upon us since the opening of the
                                summer season. The autumn woods are perfectly beautiful now. Sunday afternoon a meeting
                                was held on the shores of Sabbathday Lake. From our windows we could see them baptizing
                                the people. We know not from whence they came nor whither they went but we do know that
                                at the same time, we enjoyed a most heavenly meeting and received the baptism of the
                                Holy Spirit. Ada S. Ciimmlngs.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Maine.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. We enjoy reading the Home Notes in The Manifesto which tells us what our
                                Brethren and Sisters are doing in our sister Societies; and perhaps there are others as
                                interested to know how we are prospering. The last week in August and the first in
                                September, the Brethren carried to the Factory from ten acres planted, five hundred
                                dollars worth of sweet corn, and lat. er one hundred and sixty tons of corn ensilage was
                                stored in the silos. The Bordeaux mixture did not save the pota_ toes from rust as was
                                hoped. The worms also have troubled them, but we have harvested nearly six hundred
                                bushels which is enough for home use and some to spare. The time between haying and
                                harvesting was used in removing stone from land that formerly was an orchard and has not
                                felt the plow for eighty years. The work done has improved it greatly but a number of
                                years will be needed to make the work perfect. We can not say much for the fruit crop
                                excepting apples of which we have a fair quantity. Of garden vegetables we have a good
                                supply and they are of good quality. Onions and turnips took the first and second
                                premium at the Sanford Fair. We are pleased to have all know what our faithful Brethren
                                have accomplished, but must add that the good Sisters have not been idle. They have kept
                                Br. Henry Green busy at the mountains and at the sea-side disposing of the pretty
                                baskets made by their busy hands. The young people have had no time to tempt the
                                adversary, and while their hands have been busily employed, they have not forgotten to
                                keep the remainder of our Mother's injunction in giving their hearts to God in earnest
                                suplication and prayer, that conviction and deep searching may enter the heart and
                                cleanse each soul. They have felt as a young Sister of Watervliet once wrote us, "When I
                                am feeling right in my spirit no task seems arduous." O the beauty of the gospel which
                                gives vis a heavenly relationship to every soul who will take up his cross and deny
                                himself. We had a privilege of meeting with some of our gospel kindred from the Western
                                Societies. How much we enjoyed their presence we could not tell, nor of the strength,
                                love and encouragement we felt from them, suffice it to say, we gained such a love for
                                them that we will strive to be as faithful; thus meet them again,in Heaven. Fannie
                                Casen.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, New York" TEIform="index"/>Canaan, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. Our protracted silence is not caused from a lack of interest in our little
                                harbinger, by no means, for we are deeply interested in every effort made to spread the
                                tidings of this blessed gospel, which we are zealously striving to keep by applying its
                                principles to our daily lives that we may build up a home worthy to attract truth loving
                                souls. We have been greatly blessed the past season. Haying and harvesting all done and
                                well done by interested, consecrated young Brethren and boys who though having worked
                                hard have found true enjoyment in the labor because it was unselfish and therefore
                                sanctified. Our yield of potatoes is much greater <pb n="264" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 264 THE
                                MANIFESTO. and better quality than for several years; the corn which seemed so doubtful
                                on account of so much rain in the spring proves very good. While our neighbors and
                                friends all around us have suffered inconvenience, from the drouth we have had a
                                superabundance of good sweet spring water, resulting from the provision made last year.
                                Our school-room is being repaired by which means better ventilation will be obtained, so
                                essential to the health and happiness of both teacher and pupils who will occupy it
                                eight months of the year according to the new school law. So much for our blessings, now
                                for our afflictions. For three months we have been contending with whooping cough.
                                Whence it came or how we got it is among the mysteries not likely ever to be solved. We
                                have had thirteen cases the youngest being a little girl three years old. May we never
                                repeat the experience. By a deeper baptism of the spirit which shall quicken every
                                faculty of the soul, we hope to learn how to avert such evils. "The wise man seeth the
                                evil afar off and hideth himself," taking this for our criterion we must conclude that
                                we are numbered among the foolish in this respect. It is the first time that Canaan was
                                ever thus visited and we pray it may be the last. We have just enjoyed a social time
                                with our beloved Western Ministry and Elders and every such occasion tends to strengthen
                                the bond of gospel friendship. Emily Offord.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. As the papers have given a very distorted account of the fire which recently
                                occurred in this village, we thought that a more detailed statement might prove
                                acceptable to the readers of The Manifesto. On Sept. 20th at about 11-45 a. m. the cry
                                of fire was heard, and we soon learned that our large barn was in flames, and no
                                possibility of saving it. Several animals were in the building, but fortunately, these
                                were driven out. Some of the farming implements were also saved. In about forty-five
                                minutes after the alarm, the fire engine company from Ayer were on the ground and doing
                                effective service in saving a large pile of cord wood, as at this time the barn was
                                beyond being saved. We also lost one hundred tons of hay three hundred bushels of
                                potatoes, two horse power machines, one new cart, also a quantity of farming tools, and
                                five hundred gallons of vinegar and cider. A smaller barn, an ice-house, a store-house
                                for lumber, and several sheds were all consumed. WTe succeeded, however, in saving our
                                cider mill and the shed attached, and shall soon be able to engage in the making of more
                                vinegar. Our loss can not be less than $15,000. and having an insurance of only $4,000
                                This is our first experience, in Harvard, of so destructive a fire, and although we feel
                                our loss greatly, yet our hearts overflow with gratitude that our home is left to us. We
                                have many thanks to render to the timely assistance of the fire department of Ayer, and
                                to every one who afforded us aid in this time of our great need. The cause of the fire
                                must have been from some undue carelessness, as no engines, stoves nor lamps were in use
                                about the premises. Marcia M. Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. Autumn is here with its soft, mellow light, and gorgeous coloring of russet
                                and brown, yellow and scarlet, emerald and crimson, all so richly blending in one
                                harmonious whole. The yellow corn will soon be ready for the crib and the baldwin,
                                pippin and gennet apples are ready to be gathered, to be <pb n="265" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 265 canned, dryed or stored away for winter use. We have some good Brethren
                                and would appreciate more. The farm hands are drilling in the wheat. The first two weeks
                                in October, is the best time to sow it, in this climate. The little ridges and furrows
                                that run across the level of a hundred acre field, looks very pretty to the eye. Then to
                                think of how the little grains of amber-colored wheat that are dropped so regularly in
                                the ground by the drill-mill, first through the chemic force of heat and moisture burst
                                its hard covering and start a little rootlet in the ground and then a little stem
                                upwards for light and air; then comes the stalk and blade and full grown grain ready for
                                the harvest. We had a picnic in the woods the past summer. The place was one within easy
                                reach of home so that the young and old enjoyed the recreation of a day. We went also to
                                the County Fair and to the dedication of a Methodist Church which bordered on our own
                                lands. James Carr.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1894. We have been blessed with several good showers since we last wrote for Home
                                Notes. The order of the day is cutting up corn and gathering fall crops. We are also
                                improving our time repairing, putting on a new shingle roof on our corn crib etc. We
                                number thirty in our Society at present writing. We had the privilege of enjoying a few
                                pleasant days with Elder Oliver Hampton at our Society recently. The writer had the
                                pleasure of meeting the Ministry and Elders of Union Village at Dayton on their way to
                                the Eastern Societies. May they enjoy a pleasant visit while in the east. We are having
                                very good meetings here. Thursday evening we have a singing meeting, Sabbath morning a
                                bible meeting, Sabbath afternoon meeting for exercise and in the evening prayer meeting,
                                so we try to improve our time in doing good to ourselves and others. We enjoy the good
                                readfngs in The Manifesto very much, and always make it welcome to our Society. We
                                herewith extend our love and blessings to all who are striving to build up Zion. Henry
                                W. Fredrick.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fire record" TEIform="index"/>FIRE RECORD.</head><p TEIform="p">On the night of the 18th of September at a little past 11 o'clock p. m., we were awakened by
                            a wild cry of fire. It was at the old Brick Yard family which has been vacated for several
                            years, but used as a store place for drying corn, roots etc. All the buildings of the Brick
                            Yard family proper, were destroyed, except a small house. The Dwelling, Laundry, Dry kiln,
                            Store-house, Seed-house, Sisters' dwelling, Brick shop and Office and the Office barn, with
                            all their contents were entirely consumed. Brother Robert Valentine, Trustee, had all last
                            year's crop of roots, his wagon, hay-racks and a large part of the farm tools and machinery,
                            stored there. The value of the roots alone, was over fifteen hundred dollars. Most of the
                            buildings belonged to the Church family. The Brick dwelling and Office, and the Office bnrn
                            belonrred to the North family. The new barn put up by the North family some years ago was
                            saved. The slate roof was its protection together with the earnest efforts of a few persons
                            and a little water. All the buildings were insured, except the Brick dwelling and Office;
                            which is one building. Total insurance paid, a little over five thousand dollars. It was
                            undoubtedly set on fire.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Offord.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the memory of sister Janette Angus" TEIform="index"/>A Tribute to the Memory of
                            Sister JANETTE ANGUS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/>By Orrin Beaver.</byline><p TEIform="p">Loving Sister thou hast left us, Laid life's heavy burdens down, For a home in yonder
                            mansion, For the faithful soul prepared. <pb n="266" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 266 THE MANIFESTO. Long a
                            patient toiler here, In the vineyard of the Lord, For the good of all around thee, Ever has
                            thy life been found. Many souls have cause to bless thee. For thy kind and loving care, So
                            unselfishly bestowed, On every child of Mother's fold. Never did thy faith forsake thee,
                            Though many faltered at thy side; But trust in God sustained thy spirit, Through each dark
                            and adverse hour. Oft we've heard her precious counsel, To the young in days of yore;
                            Pleading with their thoughtless spirits To uphold this blessed cause. To live a pure and
                            virtuous life, Renounce the vanities of youth; For treaures that can never die, As lasting
                            as eternity. True unto each earthly trust, Through the shifting scenes of time; We feel thy
                            pure and gentle spirit, Has found a home of rest at last. Where many souls who' ve gone
                            before. To realms where dwell the pure in heart Will hail thee as their guiding star, Blest
                            savior from a life of sin. No greater joy can souls possess, Who consecrate their all to
                            God, Than love of kindred souls in Heaven, Who from all evil are set free. Then let us bear
                            a daily cross, Against each secret inbred foe; That would involve our souls in loss, While
                            dwelling in this lowly vale. That when our work is done below, And our mortal race is run;
                            We may meet our Sister's spirit, In mansions of the justified. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The love of God..." TEIform="index"/>The love of God...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The love of God to an earnest devotion in his service uplifts from the narrowing sphere of
                            self-pleasing aims, into the realm of those soul-expanding ideals which are crystalized in a
                            life of holy deeds.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, C." TEIform="persName"/>C. Allen.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of sister Catharine Walker" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of Sister CATHARINE
                            WALKER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williamson, Sara" TEIform="persName"/>By Sara Williamson.</byline><p TEIform="p">Thv spirit rests in peace 'neath angel care, The angel ones who with thee unaware Did all thy
                            days with watchful wisdom guide; With love and wisdom, all thy steps beside. Thou hast gone
                            from the dream of toil and And turmoil, called the earthly life; [strife And awoke to the
                            new and sweet surprise, That in gladness met thy wearied eyes. And thou hast found, that
                            kindness and love And justice, weave in the realms above The spirit robes of radiant light
                            That enfolds each soul that doeth aright. And thy faith sincere, and thine earnest zeal, Are
                            set in thy crown to ever reveal In its gems of light and beauty rare, Each deed of duty and
                            watchful care . And to all who are faithful in deed and word, In immortal life comes the
                            rich reward; When the Mother saith, "My child, well done, Enter into thy joy, and receive
                            thy crown." Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autumn" TEIform="index"/>AUTUMN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>By Ada S. Cummings.</byline><p TEIform="p">Come friends who love the autumn time And take a stroll with me; Down on the shores of S. D.
                            lake, And view the scenery. The leaves are turning brown and gold, Combined with green and
                            red; While every tint of color bright Seems waving over head. The trees, so grand and
                            beautiful Are mirrored from the shore, When the waters of the lake are still, And the sun is
                            shining o'er. We'll linger here a moment now, To us 'tis great delight, For everywhere we
                            turn our eyes The woods are gay and bright. The scenes of autumn beautiful We love them in
                            their prime With zephyrs sighing thro' the trees In indian summer time! And as we gaze
                            enraptured thus On wood and lake so gay, One thought unbidden comes, how soon The beauty
                            fades away! <pb n="267" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 267 And trees enrobed in loveliness Must
                            then be stripped and bare For even now the wintry blast Is lurking in the air. These autumn
                            days are warning us Of winter sure to be, When all the leaves have fallen off From every
                            branch and tree. Thus earthly friends are leaving us Their autumn being past; And thus the
                            winter of our lives Will come to us at last. Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children:--'Blessed are the pure in heart'..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Children:--'Blessed are the pure in heart'...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, October 1894" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn. Oct.,
                            1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children:"Blessed are the pure in heart." The heart is the seat of principles and the
                            fountain of action. If the fountain is impure, the stream will be impure. If your hearts are
                            sinful, your lives must be wrong. If your hearts are pure, your souls will be lovely. All
                            sin proceeds from the heart. Cleanse the fountain and the streams of thought and action will
                            be pure. How can pure thoughts enter within, if the heart becomes a dwelling for sin? Guard
                            your souls against the approaches of evil. Use every means at your disposal for becoming
                            virtuous. Purity is the brightest jewel that can ever adorn your characters. Get a good
                            start for heaven. "Well begun is half done." Start with pure motives and high ideals of
                            Christian life. How inspiring the thought. What golden opportunities are yours. Results of a
                            virtuous life are glorious in actual fruitage. Virtue's path is pleasant and plain, walking
                            therein is eternal gain. Consider what evils may result from one wrong step. One habit, one
                            sin, one companion, one book, may affect your whole life and character. "Take heed what you
                            read." Bad books better no one. I want to say to those I find reading that which is
                            improper, "Eschew that which is evil, cleave to that which is good," which will be as safe a
                            maxim to follow with regard to what they read, as to what they do. Bead that which will make
                            you think good thoughts and live good lives. Good books make one feel that truth and purity
                            are beautiful and possible; they make it seem worth while to strive to live nobly. Pure
                            reading refines and brings soul cheer, and gives us strength to persevere. Have pure
                            reading, pure thoughts, pure hearts. Learn virtue, and when you learn from a book or
                            elsewhere that which is wise and good, proceed at once to practice it. Walk in the way of
                            eternal life. May your peace be like a river and your joj, like the waves of the sea. May
                            your years be many and bright with truth and virtue.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of brother Stephen Boisseau" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of Brother STEPHEN
                            BOISSEAU.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Louisa" TEIform="persName"/>By Louisa.</byline><p TEIform="p">Away from earth and all its cares, His spirit finds a rest Remote from changing scenes of
                            time And all that can molest. God shall wipe away all tears from our eyes, and there shall
                            be no more death, neither shall there be any pain, sorrow or affliction. Blessed assurance.
                            Oh! saddened weary mortals a little while longer and tears sh all be unknown to thee; and we
                            shall be rejoicing with thousands who like him have been freed from all those troubles. So
                            try to live that when the sun of our existence sinks in night, memorials sweet of mercies
                            done may shrine our names in memory's light. Not for thee our tears are shed, our sighs are
                            given. Why mourn to know thou art a free partaker of the joys of heaven. Finished thy work
                            kept thy faith, glorious reflection! may we ever cherish the memory of the good example and
                            faithful toil in loving gratitude. The departed Brother has heard the glad sound, welcome
                            home, come take thy rest, for peace and happiness is thy just reward. Gone but not
                            forgotten, in the mind of every one. Blessed Lord, thou didst give and thou hast taken. If I
                            could express in words, the feelings my heart contains, it would be only in a feeble way.
                            Pleasant Hill Ky.</p></div2><pb n="268" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Egypt in history and prophecy" TEIform="index"/>EGYPT IN HlSTORY AND PROPHECY
                            </head><p TEIform="p">EGYPT IN HlSTORY AND PROPHECY, BV Kt)B. ert Patterson. This little work of nearly sixty
                                pages is an interesting and valuable his toricul collection of just that form to meet
                                the needs of enquiring minds of every age. \ While it may have been written especially
                                for j that class called Infidels, urd certainly they | would not hesitate to read it,
                                the church goers and Christians may be immensely profited by a careful peiusttl of its
                                pages. "Men and bcu&amp;ts, too, arise from the dead.in Egypt, to preach to the
                                living. Not only do we possess colored pictures and statues of men and animals; we have
                                actually the men and animals themselt-es, preserved by the process of embalming."
                                Published by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>The Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health for October is a very interesting and valuable number. In the Contents
                                we findA study of Beethoven; How to study Strangers; The Ideal; What is a Dream?
                                Sketches of Phrenological Biography; etc., etcPublished by Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 27
                                East 21st St. N. Y. Price $1. 50 per. year, 15cts. a number. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy. October, Contents. The Temperature of the Body; Doctors and their Cures;
                                Foundation Principles; Anti-Vaccination; The Pride of Company; Know Thyself; Social
                                Purity; etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' Home Journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For the first time in
                                his literary career Jerome K. Jerome, is about to write directly for an American
                                audience. This work consists of a series of papers similar in vein to his "Idle Thoughts
                                of an Idle Fellow," but addressed to American girls and women. The articles will begin
                                shortly in The Ladies' Home Journal, which periodical will print the entire series.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="French, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary French
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary French, at Watervliet, N. Y. May 23, 1894. Age 79 yrs. 7 mo. She was gathered home
                                as a sheaf of wheat fully ripened for the harvest. I. Greaves. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angus, Janette" TEIform="index"/>Janette Angus
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Janette Angus, at
                                Shakers, N. Y. Sept. 30, 1894. Age 84 yrs. and 2 mo. Undebneath the waves of time and
                                chance, may we feel the deep ocean of God's love.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers and socialists" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERS AND SOCIALISTS.</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of The Tribune. Sir: Having just read in Monday's Tribune R. G. Horr's able
                            article, "Socialism Run Mad," I wish to recommend, not only to Socialists, but to all of the
                            thinking class in society, that they read it carefully and without prejudice. The Socialists
                            are striving for that condition which it is utterly impossible for them to realize, only in
                            the Church of Christ's Second Appearing in the female the Shaker Churchthe Church of the
                            "Great American Republic." "That which is born of the flesh ia flesh, and that which is born
                            of the spirit is spirit." "The children of this world marry, and are given in marriage," but
                            the children of heaven live pure, celibate lives in this world, and are engaged in
                            establishing the Republic of Heaven on earth, where they have all things in common. An
                            attempt was made after this sort by the Apostles at the day of Pentecost; outwardly it was a
                            failure, but they left a spiritual seed behind which culminated in the establishment of the
                            Shaker Church, 120 years ago. The seed took root then, and is now bearing its fruit. The
                            Shaker communities are so many signs in the spiritual heavensmanifestations of the signs of
                            the timesof Christ in the female part of man. Woman is the natural organizer of earthly
                            homes, and much more so of heavenly homes. Your friend for equality,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greaves, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLES GREAVES</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, September 20, 1894" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N. Y.,
                            Sept. 20, 1894.</dateline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manners" TEIform="index"/>MANNERS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Did you ever think what beautiful manners Christ had? It is evident that in a few
                                    minutes he could make friends with a total stranger. What a, charm his recorded
                                    conversations have! How courteous his greetings and parting words! Surely, if we try
                                    to copy him at all, we should try to copy his manners, for they are among the least
                                    of the beautiful examples which he set us.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A brief Mccount   of
HE 11 LIFE
While   iti    England,   and   mi1>m qucntly
UNITED
al-o   her Exuericnci'  an   a   Mi>m nj,vr
of ihe
WORD  of  GOD.
P ice  10 cts.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF   THE
 CHURCH,
on
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progre.su or' the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
THE
TESTIMONY
CUEIST'S  SECOND APPEASING.
Exemplified hy the Principles and Practices of the true CHURCH of CHRIST
A History of the, progressive work of God,
extending from the Creation of man to
the "HARVEST," comprising the Four
Dispensations now consummating in the
MILLENNIAL CHURCH.
Price, $1.50
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
TO THE OFT REPEATED QUESTION,
"What   will   become   of   the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
Till:   AL.T1MJN
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. ">(> cents a< year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Lonoley.
901 Olive St.',   St. Louis, Mo.
THE DIVIDE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price,   10 cts.
tions strictly confidential, A II anribook ot Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scie: :i'ic books pent iree.
Patents tazsn through Munn & Co. receire
special notice in the Scientific American, and
ttus are brought widely before the public without cost to tho inventor. This snlendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in tha
world.   S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, 82.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., iVbv Yo::s, Hill BiiOADW
SKETCHES
OF
SHAKERS & SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the
United Society of Believers in
Christ's Second Appearing.
By G. B. Avery.
Price, 15 cts,
MOTHER ANN LEE.
STATE
in the
MILLENNIAL
A
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar   baking   powder,
Highest of  all in  leavening strength.
Latest   United   States    Goveriment
Focd Report.
Koyal Baxing, Powder Co.,
IOC, Wall St., N.  Y.
110 W I CAME
TO   BE
.A.   SHAKER.
Price 5 cts.
Alacli knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage p;ihl to any address in the
U. S. \\Te have on hand a lew copies of
"Hip Van Winl.de and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4x:i.                              10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horsey' by Dr. B.
Kenda'.l. J)0 pages. 5x7'2- Profusely illustrated.                                        12 cts.
Ari old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.             $65.00
An eight day brass time piece made in
1810   by  Dr.   Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Second vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1725.                                       .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
Address   H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
(Establislit-d n-Bi )
 |S )]dest, Lur-es,. Ke-1,
 1 ('heaiie^-t, aii(i tiic Only
weekly Bf -Paper in all
America. IV? pi'g< s. %\ .00
 year.   Send for te Sample.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREE
. W. YORiZ & 00.. 199 Baudolph St., Chica-^, 111,
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cs.
Reliable men to
sell our choice and
" " hardy Nursery Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line. Many varieties can only be obtained through us.
Commission or salary paid weekly, and
promptly. Exclusive and choice of territory given. Don't delay, write at once
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
American Bee Journal.
T
H
WANTED.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>