<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0402" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18740201" TEIform="date">February 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">9-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="9" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. IV. No. 2. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. FI"' Mt Lebanon, Col. Oo. N. Y. February, 1874. F™?ZZ</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What poor?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT POOR?</head><p TEIform="p">" Sett what thou hast, and give it to the Poor." The Protestant world has lost the true
                            import and meaning of this saying of Jesus. Hence they consider it impracticable — utterly
                            abstract, if not absurd — having upon them no saving force. Consequently, they quietly
                            ignore it. For instance : " What" (say they) " would be gained by the heads of ten fam-
                            ilies, in Stephentown, who, by patient, longcontinued toil, economy, and good manage- ment,
                            have accumulated houses and lands, and a surplus in funds, should they sell all, and collect
                            all, and then distribute it in the town among those families and persons who, from lack of
                            ability, or the non-exercise of the virtues above-named, are comparatively poor? Would
                            Christianity — godliness — be thereby increased and promoted in the town ? Not in the least.
                            Those who earned the property are its best protectors, and, in the aggregate, will make the
                            best and wisest use thereof. " Sell that thou hast, and give the proceeds to the Church,"
                            was probably what Jesus did say to the " rich young man." For he desired to found a
                            Community of goods; but the time had not then come. When it had " fully come," rich men and
                            women sold their property, and gave the money to the Apostles, to establish therewith a
                            religious Organization, the Pentecostal Church, with its " all things common." And that is
                            just what rich men and women will do in these modern times, by and by. For G-od's people, "
                            in the day of His power, will be a willing people." Look upon the ripening harvest fields of
                            the earth to-day; are they not almost ready for the "sickle" of her who sits upon the "
                            white cloud "—¦ the Shaker Order — looking so " like unto the Son of Man ?" What means this
                            general Communistic spirit, that is so wide spread, and so potent ? Combination,
                            Association, Co-operation, Community : these are the watchwords of the advancing hosts of
                            Reformers and Progressists. The Christ Spirit broods over and upon the embryonic elements of
                            the New Creation, which is already in process of forming and organizing in dissolving
                            Bablyon. A few more shadows, and the nucleus of Pentecostal Churches will be plainly dis-
                            cerned, here and there, throughout Christendom ; and the " cities of refuge " already ex-
                            isting, will be found by the wanderers on the mountains of desolation, and by the pilgrims
                            who are seeking a " city which hath foundations," where they will be welcomed home, even as
                            Joseph welcomed the fathers and founders of the twelve tribes of Israel, of which himself
                            was two—Ephraim and Manasseh—-father and mother. The rich in this world's goods, when "
                            called," will cheerfully affiliate with the "poor in spirit," and " rich in faith," although
                            they may have gathered but little of this world's manna; and the rich and the poor, male and
                            female, those of high and those of low degree, will be all one in the kingdom of Christ
                            Jesus and Christ Ann, the federal Head of the Grentile Pentecostal, or Mother, Church.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker pentecost" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER PENTECOST</head><p TEIform="p">Advertisement.— Wanted. —Men, women and children can find a comfortable home for life, where
                            want never comes, with the Shakers, bv embracing the true faith, and living pure lives.
                            Particulars can be learned by writing to the Shakers, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. In consequence of
                            the publication, on the 7th ult.,of the above advertisement in " New York Herald " and " Sun
                            " we received, on the 8th, 56; 9th, 42; 10th, 23; and 12th, 14 -total, 135 letters,
                            containing either direct applications to join the Society, or asking information to that
                            end. Two-thirds of these are from young men ; and all (with some two or three exceptions)
                            are well written, and show intelligence, culture, and earnestness of spirit to find the
                            Kingdom of Heaven, if it exists upon earth, and to have a lot and place in it. To each of
                            these writers we have sent publications, and have written to as many as time would permit
                            thus far. Many more will be written to; and will receive this No. of the Shaker and
                            Shakeress. To these friends, and to all who contemplate "joining the Shakers," we address
                            the following: 1. Faith is the first requisite — a belief induced by evidence consequent
                            upon rational inquiry and scientific investigation — that the same Christ Spirit that
                            created the primitive Pentecostal Church, composed of Jewish Israelites, has made its "
                            Second Advent" upon this earth, and has created Pentecostal Communities, composed of Gentile
                            Israelites. They have " come from the East, and the West, and the North, and the South, and
                            have sat down in the kingdom of heaven," so much and so long prayed for. 2. Conviction for
                            sin will result from faith; and obedience to the Christ Spirit will " take away all the sins
                            of the world," whether physical or spiritual, of " men, women, and chil- dren." He that
                            confesseth and forsaketh his sins shall find an " inheritance in the kingdom of heaven." 3.
                            Eiches and Poverty come from false organic laws, and form a large part of the world's sins.
                            They cause luxury and destitution ; wasteful, riotous living, and pinching starvation;
                            unphysiological food and drinks, which induce the use of poisonous medicines ; extravagant,
                            health-destroying, and body-deforming dresses, and a scanty wardrobe and rags. Thus is God
                            dishonored by the sufferings of humanity ; and Christianity has become a by-word and a
                            reproach, as being no antidote for the ills to which flesh is heir. 4. " All things common "
                            — a Pentecostal Order — is as possible now, to-day, as it ever was, to those who, before a
                            witness, will " turn the battle to the gate," and confess their individual sins, and do that
                            which is " lawful and right," and thereby " save body and soul alive." 5. Now " the poor and
                            the rich have the Gospel preached unto them ;" and, if these rich will sell all that they
                            have, and give to these poor, thus leveling the mountains and filling up the valleys, there
                            will be Pentecost — a re]igious Community. 6. Be just toward yourselves, and the Society
                            with which you are about to unite, by collecting and retaining in your own possession, all
                            property, whether in money, goods, or clothing, that you may be not only selfsupporting, but
                            a help to those who are poorer than yourselves. He that provideth not for his own kindred in
                            the Lord is worse than an infidel. 7. God's House being a house of order, expect to be
                            subject to the laws of the " household of faith." Community is society in its most compact
                            form ; hence there is the greater necessity for laws ; as " where there is no government,
                            there is no God." Perfect liberty, in a wordly sense, means individual isolation from all
                            human association. Faith makes obedience practical, and the burden and yoke thereof easy and
                            light. 8. The probationary member is expected to place his property in the hands of the
                            Elders or Trustees, returnable without interest, until, by his own faith, and the consent of
                            the authorities, he is privileged to dedicate it. It does not appear that, in the first
                            pentecost, they waited long for that condition of consecration. 9. The Society puts
                            confidence in individuals as they gain confidence in the Pentecostal Order of the Church;
                            but the Ananias and Sapphira spirit should remain without. 10. Married persons are not
                            received, unless the husband and wife come together; or that they separate by mutual
                            consent, or legal agreement, in relation to their marriage, their property, and their
                            children. 11. We neither take nor reject persons because of riches or poverty. Where many
                            embrace our faith at one time, we may not always be able to provide a home for them
                            immediately, but will do the best we can, according <pb n="10" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> to our ability.
                            Those wishing to visit should notify us, if possible, before they come; and none should come
                            expecting, if not received, the Society to pay their expenses back. 12. " Where a person's
                            treasure is, there will their heart be also." Therefore those who dispose of their property
                            to relatives in the world should remain with it. 18. Persons who dedicate property, and
                            afterward withdraw, may have their property returned, without interest, but it is optional
                            with the Society. 14. Probationary members sign an agreement binding themselves to observe
                            the rules of the Order during their sojourn, or until they are prepared to sign the Covenant
                            of the Society. 15. All correspondence is subject to the supervision of the Elders, whether
                            letters, etc., be sent or received. 16. As no person could join the primitive Quakers, or
                            Methodists, and change from their worldly ways in language, dress and demeanor, without
                            suffering a degree of death, how much less shall they become " new creatures " in all things
                            in this Pentecostal Church, and not become partakers of the sufferings of Jesus, which he
                            has " left behind for his body's sake," of which he was only the Head. 17. Our worship is in
                            spirit, and consists in speaking, singing, marching, and sometimes in " battles of shaking,"
                            and again in solemn or joyful dances ; in divers operations, as the Spirit moves, and often
                            in prayer and sweet spiritual communings. " Where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is
                            liberty."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological theosures [corrected title: Theological treasures]" TEIform="index"/>THEOLOGICAL
                            THEOSURES</head><p TEIform="p">Herewith I begin a series of papers which will form my theological bank, or treasury. I
                            purpose depositing therein my best tlioughts upon God, and upon Christianity. To me,
                            theology is merely a talk upon God ; while religion is an expression in life of the teach-
                            ings of theology. Many theologies contain much that is good ; others are mixed, being very
                            dark with error; while there are few, if any, that are wholly bad, or yet without fault;
                            while some do approach nearer to the standard of " when that which is perfect is come." The
                            best theology will produce the best religion ; and this will be demonstrated by the best and
                            purest life. We care but little for theologies, per se; but are more desirous of knowing
                            what their demonstration in life imparts. Of itself, theology is like the leaves of a tree,
                            useful, but not the fruit. " I will show you my theology by my fruits." Better is the
                            expression of a good life, than the world full of theology, without the life. There is much
                            ado over much doctrine ; but the result of Christian theology will be a life like unto Jesus
                            Christ. Theologians, draw up your analogies, illustrate, by the comparison of your lives
                            with his, how near, or how distant you are from him who was " without fault; " and learn to
                            value your theologies by the comparison. Are we, a professedly Christian people, followers
                            of Jesus ? If so, what a world of sin and sorrow we are exterminating, and what an
                            incalculable amount of false theology we are burning by the light and fire of truth!
                            Claiming Jesus, endowed hy the Christ influence, to be the standard-bearer of our theology,
                            if we fail to draw this comparison, our claim is unwarrantable, and more : if we discover
                            dissimilarity between our theology and the life of Jesus, we must change our theology,bring
                            tip arrears by a confession and renunciation of our practices in life that differ from the
                            same in Jesus — or we are hypocrites — wandering sheep, who want no shepherd ! The world is
                            growing better in its theology, because there is very much less of it than formerly. The
                            people read and accept truth easier. Even theological expositors have a distant respect for
                            the truths of Paine, however much they hate him for so boldly enun- ciating some justice to
                            them as a class. We are unable to find in the whole area of " Paine's Works," a single
                            passage that is more opposed to Christian theology, than are the every-day lives of the
                            bright stars of the popular churches of to-day ! If Paine's theol- ogy was not Christian,
                            let us recollect that he did not so profess ; nor did Washington, Jefferson, Franklin,
                            Lincoln, etc. ; but in these, and thousands of the same ilk, we find the spirit of goodness
                            active — which very much resembles Christianity; and these have con- sciences far clearer
                            than those who profess Christ with their lips, but who hate the idea of having to follow him
                            in their daily lives ! The persecutors of truths uttered by Paine and others, we are
                            reminded, do make Christianity a profession ; are very noisy about it; and express it in
                            every other way better than in their lives! Let us be very careful about the character of
                            our theology — be the same Judaical, Mohammedan, or Christian. So-called " Christian nations
                            " deal rather in Judaism, than under Christian influences, and in very poor Judaism at that;
                            while common and popular theologies are a conglomeration of " What is its," rather than a
                            resemblance to simple, unostentatious Christianity. Now, we believe in the theology and
                            religion of Jesus, under Christ; and in the same of his followers in life, no matter by what
                            name they are designated. They had, and have, but little theology, but it leavened the whole
                            lump of life — their lives being true religion — practical Christianity. Our deposits in the
                            Treasury will be simple ; our endeavors most sincere. We love Jesus; nevertheless we do not
                            purpose to make an idol or a god of him. We know that he was simply a good Jew ; yet became,
                            by his baptism and subjection to the Christ principles, a good Christian ! Come ye Jews and
                            Gentiles, can you do better than accept his life as your guide ? What among the Jews he
                            wished to be saved from, all will wish to be saved from, if they ever believe in the
                            theology of Jesus, and will make the same endeavors, and take upon them his cross and
                            selfdenial ; for these made a Christian of the Jew! There is only one road to this mill —
                            who wants salvation, let him " follow," and live as Jesus lived. Said Pilate: " I find in
                            him no fault"—the clearest definition of a truthful theology ! And, though the theology of
                            Jesus, under Christ, has been usurped by passion, and profaned to unholy uses, through all
                            time since its enunciation, still its principles are eternal and true.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following extraordinary accident recently occurred at Brescia, Italy..." TEIform="index"/>The following extraordinary accident recently occurred at Brescia, Italy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The following extraordinary accident recently occurred at Brescia, Italy; Two boys caught a
                            mouse, which they bathed in kerosene oil, then set lire to it. The frightened animal seized
                            one by the leg, and before they could detach it from its hold both were so severely bitten
                            that they died within three days.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Capital and labor" TEIform="index"/>CAPITAL AND LABOR</head><p TEIform="p">While thousands, with hearts sensitive to the woes of their fellows, are awakened to study
                            the causes which produce such widespread misery among the poor throughout the country, it
                            can but hasten the coming of that golden age when all suffering and wrong are to cease, if
                            the subject be studied from different points of view, and reviewed by the light of many
                            minds. The immediate cause of this suffering is the disemployment of the laboring class. But
                            why disemployed? Here we meet the evil at the door; the incipient cause is the innate
                            selfishness of the human heart, that prompts the owners of all capital, or wealth in landed
                            estates and manufactories, to use and manage such capital without regard to the normal
                            rights of the laborer. The greed of gain will not perceive the implied and moral obligation
                            contracted by capital to furnish labor a constant means of obtaining a livelihood. Though no
                            human law enforced this obligation, yet the necessities — mutual relation of labor and
                            capital — seal the obligation of capital to sustain, and the right of labor to use, each the
                            other; and every movement of capital which imperils its capacity to fulfill its part of this
                            moral contract is treacherous alike to the interests of both parties; and. when the risks
                            and ventures of capital are extensive, pervading large sections of country at the same time,
                            they sooner or later entail unmitigated suffering upon, the laborer. The broad acres upon
                            which man treads, the air, the sea, and the accumulated wealth of all the earth, owe him a
                            living, if he is willing to return an equivalent in labor. What wonder that crimes increase
                            three-fold during times of destitution? Apparently, the solid men of our great cities would
                            gladly precipitate the demon war upon our already overburdened country, in order to furnish
                            employment to the forty thousand unemployed starving poor. These panics and business
                            revulsions, with their unmeasurable crimes and miseries, are as surely the offspring of
                            tyrannical selfishness as the constant depression and want which old country people suffer,
                            are the outgrowth of selfishness in their arbitrary gov- ernments, which is as subversive of
                            the liberties of the laborers in America as is the present or prospective tyranny of any
                            government that ever ruled and enslaved people. It is easy to show that the ruling relation
                            of the wealthy to the poor are relations of self- interest and fear. In the most prosperous
                            sections of the grain-producing West, the speculators in grain have doubled their
                            purchase-money in the past half-year, and the carriers of this grain, while prices were
                            still ascending, reduced the wages of employes ten per cent at the outset of winter.
                            Self-interest may possess a moral value as a motive for action ; fear does not; it is always
                            an infliction; and, in such times as these, the fears of capitalists are illy disguised,
                            being forced to give a pittance of employment to their dependents, when, to withhold such
                            charity would invite unmeasurable evils upon themselves, because the unemployed laboring
                            class, if capital should persist, even for a short time, to withhold employment, would
                            inevitably help themselves, although it should fill the country with riot. 1O <pb n="11" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEESS. 11 Humanity is progressing away from present conditions, from
                            bondage to selfish customs and conventionalism; they are impelled by a little love, great
                            fear, and greater self-interest, toward the plane of human equality — primal truths — and
                            true liberty, which is begotten by the love of brother. We look with confidence for the day
                            when all unscrupulous claims will cease, when wealth shall minister to universal need and
                            comfort, and not to individual pleasure and aggrandizement, when all implied obligations,
                            and the normal rights of created beings, will be respected, although no human laws enforce
                            them; when co-operation of interests (material and spiritual) will become the necessity of
                            society, and the medium of progress toward the ultimate of the highest practical economy,
                            celibate communism — the guarantee of social protection, and the only possible realization
                            of practical love of one for another as professed disciples of Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Henry Hollister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light and truth" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT AND TRUTH</head><p TEIform="p">When the light of the sun shines upon objects that are in darkness, the difference between
                            supposition and reality becomes strikingly apparent. So, when the light of Christ, the Sun
                            of Righteousness, shines clearly and fully into the mind, and makes manifest the quality of
                            the thoughts, words, and doings, of a comparatively good man or woman, the amount of
                            difference between what he or she really is, and what he supposes himself to be, and what
                            others may suppose him to be, is rendered quite plain to him, and perhaps to some others,
                            and is truly astounding. But how much more is it so in the case of a person whose character
                            is formed of impure thoughts, false words, and unjust deeds ? How necessary, then, it is
                            that we always endeavor to be as pure, and true, and good, in all our thoughts, words, and
                            actions, as we know we should be ; and that we be what we seem to be, and seem to be what we
                            really are. So also is it when a false statement of any one's sayings, motives, or doings,
                            have caused improper reflections, deductions, opinions, feelings, and conclusions, in the
                            minds of others who ntay be ignorant of the true character of the misrepresented person; how
                            wonderfully the light of truth will change the whole aspect of the case. Therefore, if
                            falsely accused, or spoken of, or thought of, by any one, and (as a consequence) lowered or
                            lessened in the estimation or esteem of others—perhaps even particular and closest
                            friends—endure it with patience and quietness ; and wait a little while, till the Sun of
                            Truth shall shine upon the willful or ignorant falsifier, and upon all those who may have
                            heard and believed the falsity, and who, as the result, may have become unfriendly, or at
                            least distant in their feelings and conduct; for the whole of the darkness and trouble will
                            then be instantly dissipated, and a peculiarly-blessed feeling of justification, compla-
                            cence, satisfaction, gratitude, and sweetness, will rest upon and within the honest and pa-
                            tient individual so accused or misrepresented. That will be his and her reward, which is
                            insured, and will be secured to them, by the iustice and righteousness of our immutable
                            God—the Eternal Fountain and Source of all goodness, light, and truth. Truth is a perfectly
                            straight line, which holds, in one unvarying correspondential union, Cause and Effect. That
                            is : the thing produced is the exact result of, and perfectly expresses the cause that
                            produced it. Therefore it is plain, that truth is a prominent and essential quality in the
                            perfect righteousness of God, as is clearly seen in all his works. In other words, the thing
                            created and brought forth by God is an outward expression exactly corresponding to the
                            inward power and wisdom, and to the goodness of the design, of its Author, " with whom is no
                            variableness, nor shadow of turning." The outward words and acts of Jesus Christ were but
                            the perfect expression of, and precisely corresponded with, his inward life, condition, and
                            motives ; so that those who understood his words, more or less partook or received of his
                            spirit; and hence he called himself " the Truth." Truth is the axis, or central power, that
                            should run through all words and actions ; causing words, at the time of their utterance,
                            actions, at the time of their performance, and even gestures, stillness, and quietness, to
                            express the condition and action of the mind. That is, the motive, as well as the meaning of
                            the word or act, should be in the word spoken, or act performed. For words and actions
                            should so precisely correspond to the condition, motive, and intention of the mind of the
                            utterer, as to be the real representation and exponent thereof, just as a shadow of any
                            thing is the real product of the substance that causes it. Departure from truth through
                            ignorance may be termed error. But a willful, designed departure therefrom, is a falsity—a
                            lie. It causes words and actions to convey an entirely different view of the utterer's mind
                            from that which he really possesses, and which should be expressed. Therefore any departure
                            from truth, even if through ignorance, is a departure from God. How much more crooked,
                            false, and distant from God, then, is the way of him or her who designs, by words or
                            actions, to deceive the hearer or observer of them, in reference to their true meaning? or
                            in reference to the motive and intention which caused their utterance ? All truth proceeds
                            from, and leads to, God and goodness ; while all error and falsity proceed from the devil,
                            and lead to evil. To say what we mean, and mean what we say; To be what we seem, and seem
                            what we be, As truly as Truth demands in this day, Is truth truly clad in simplicity. All
                            truth is quite straight, and all truth is good, To all honest souls ; for that is their "
                            rod." May truth, in our acts and words, be our food, And ever evince our union with God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Offord, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile visions" TEIform="index"/>JUVENILE VISIONS</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Frederick . On Monday evening, the 29th of December last, I had a pain in my stomach
                            and could not work. I went into the shoe shop and lied down on the counter. I shut my eyes,
                            and, after lying there live or six minutes, I, all at once, began speaking upon religion;
                            the words came into my mouth as fast as I could utter them. Suddenly it became very light;
                            and, although my eyes were still closed, I could see all around me ; I also spoke a few
                            verses in poetry, one right after the other. I then discerned a man in the midst of a lot of
                            tall weeds. He, at first, seemed contented; after which he began to feel uneasy. Outside of
                            those weeds there were some beautiful flowers and fruits of all kinds. As I said, he became
                            a little uneasy, not being quite contented among those tall weeds which swamped him. When he
                            caught sight of those beautiful flowers and fruits, outside of his weedy prison, it made him
                            the more restless. Then I understood that the weeds were bad spirits, and the fruits and
                            flowers good spirits, who desired to bring him out of his sad condition; and I also saw that
                            he himself wished to come out, to be delivered; so both parties worked together to that end
                            against the evil spirits. I next saw a seed, as it were, fly over the weeds, and take root
                            at the feet of the man, at which he was much pleased. This seed was a good spirit; and then
                            more good spirits went over to him, until, at last, the evil spirits began to diminish, and
                            the man became more comfortable, and soon the good became so powerful that the evil died out
                            and the man was surrounded entirely by good spirits. This taught me a lesson that I shall
                            not soon forget. It taught me that, however much a person might be surrounded by, and
                            swamped in, evil habits, if they once feel a desire to become good they will be spiritually
                            assisted, and that, as good is more powerful than evil, the victory is certain ; the
                            greatest wrong will be removed, and the sinner's heart uplifted, until he becomes fully
                            redeemed from his lost condition. I am young (fifteen), and this is my first spiritual exr
                            erience, and I will labor to profit by it practically, for it is an evidence to me that good
                            spirits are sometimes very near me, and I pray that they may ever be near me, and guide me
                            in the path of righteousness and peace. Sam. Witham, Mt. Lebanon. A few weeks since, another
                            boy (thirteen) was sent from the North Family to Canaan (three miles), early in the morning,
                            while it was yet dark. On coming opposite the meeting-house, a ball of light appeared in the
                            road just before him. It was as large as a cocoa-nut, and rolled before him, lighting his
                            path fully, until it was dawn of day. On a previous occasion, this same boy, Ami, was by the
                            watering tub, at the Upper House, Canaan, where he lives, when Charles Haggitt (a youth who
                            had left the Family, but had made application to return, and was then a hundred miles away),
                            came out of the barn and spoke to him as he passed (rubbing against him), and then went on
                            north, Ami being entirely unconscious in regard to its being a vision, if vision it was. I
                            hail these notices of the youth as good omens and signs of a return of the spiritual
                            manifestations among Believers. They are small beginnings, but more is coming, until the "
                            sinners in Zion will tremble, and fearfulness take hold of the hypocrite," as was the case
                            in the former manifestations, when nothing could be hidden that worked abomination or that
                            loved or made a lie. </p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>Ed.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the shaker and shakeress:" TEIform="index"/>To the Shaker and Shakeress :</head><p TEIform="p">I have spent a portion of my leisure moments in reading, very attentively, the Shaker and
                            Shakeress of several months' issue, and am fully persuaded in mind, and decided in feelings,
                            that it is a pure and wholesome sheet, breathing a purer air from heaven, and a more
                            Christian spirit than can be found in any other journal in our land. Peace, truth, kindness,
                            and love, dwell within its columns; such as was never taught but by the divinelyinspired and
                            lowly Nazarene. How very harmonizing it is to the weary soul, in times of trouble, a panacea
                            for every earthly ill. The Christ principle is here more fully inculcated than I have ever
                            seen it before. We shall never see the dawn of the great and glorious Millennial day, so
                            long as we instruct our children in the art of war. How long, O how long, shall we continue
                            to tread in the footsteps of our predecessors, and follow the counsels and dogmas of the
                            dark ages ? The law of progression tells us that there is to be a turning and overturning in
                            the political and religious world, when war and strife among nations will be abandoned. This
                            grasping after power and wealth, oppressing the poor, and aggrandizing the rich, must have
                            an end, and every man and woman must be free, and entitled to hold and occupy land in
                            common; as God, in his wisdom, hath dealt out to each his blessings of sunshine, air, and
                            water. Then all will be recognized as the children of one Father and Mother. Our souls must
                            be fitted for the society of redeemed spirits before we can enter into the blessings and
                            joys of eternal life. Sincerely presented by</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jenett, Solomon W." TEIform="persName"/>Solomon W. Jenett, Rutland, Vt.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste-basket sympathy" TEIform="index"/>WASTE-BASKET SYMPATHY</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editor : Knowing that our little Monthly has its waste-basket, I have resolved to
                            contribute my mite to its support. Truly, by the aid of the " Shaker and Shakeress," light
                            is increasing. It is a messenger of truth, and that too from the center of Christ's vineyard
                            on the earth. I am with you, in spirit, in your effort to direct, through its columns,
                            mistaken souls to the Fountain of eternal life. Its manner of dealing such persistent,
                            untiring blows at the root of the tree of evil; of defending truth against error; of holding
                            up light against darkness; and the sharp testimony it maintains against all sinful
                            indulgences, make it, not only a bulwark of defense, but an invading power, before which
                            depraved hearts must quail. For not only the Divine Searcher of the heart, but his chosen
                            people also, by and through his Spirit, are made able to discern between him that serveth
                            God, and him that serveth him not. I enjoy much satisfaction in perusing the truths set
                            forth in the little sfteet for the edification of those who have ears to hear and hearts to
                            receive ; that they may be as a lamp to their feet, and light to their path, to lead them
                            from Babylon to Zion. I believe many souls will date the origin of their first light <pb n="12" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> and conviction in the present testimony of Christ's second appearing —
                            yea, and their final salvation, to the impressions received through this herald of truth.
                            Then, how encouraging to continue its publication. I am thankful for this means provided for
                            the extension of the knowledge of the way of salvation, that honest seekers after truth
                            maybe convinced that in Zion is opened a fountain, where sin-sick souls may be washed from
                            uncleanness, and rejoice that they have found their Father and Mother's House. I unite, with
                            every feeling of my soul, in this call of the still, small voice of the Spirit, to the weary
                            and heavy laden.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>David Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friendly" TEIform="index"/>FRIENDLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We have to acknowledge a very handsome notice of the " Shaker and Shakeress," by the
                            Religio-Philosophical Journal; which paper I am happy to recommend as belonging, since the
                            division upon the sexual question, to the clean class of Spiritualistic Journals. It is free
                            from Free-Loveism, and can be had for three months for 25 cents, or $2 per annum. Editor, S.
                            S. Jones, corner of Fifth Avenue and Adams street, Chicago, 111. Also, Friend Williams, of
                            the " Hudson Gazette," has the following: Tfie Shaher and Shakeress. We have before spoken
                            in complimentary terms of this neat and very readable publication issued by the Shakers at
                            Mt. Lebanon, but the following from the Boston Index expresses as much as it would be
                            possible to crowd into so brief a paragraph : '" The Shaker and Shakeress, published by the
                            United Society of Shakers, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., is a neat, sweet, fresh, and liberal
                            publication."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lecture season" TEIform="index"/>THE LECTURE SEASON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Murray, William H. H." TEIform="persName"/>THE REV. WM. H. H. MURRAY ON "THE CIVILIZED HEATHEN."</byline><p TEIform="p">That Music Hall was so well filled such a night as was last, certainly speaks well for the
                            attraction which brought together the audience. The second of the Lyceum course was the
                            allurement last evening, when the Rev. Wm. H. H. Murray delivered his new lecture on " The
                            Civilized Heathen." The lecturer began by stating that he had intended, originally, to open
                            up the inner life and character of the American people, so that the faults in each might be
                            seen and avoided. But after investigation, he had found the picture so dark that he shrank
                            from holding it up to view. We live, said he, in a missionizing age. The attempt to civilize
                            a heathen people was based on the idea that American life, customs and religion are better
                            than theirs. This he doubted, and he would put American Christianity against Buddhism, and
                            the American republic against the Chinese empire. He said that if we must call Buddhism
                            heathenism, we must call it civilized heatt enism. It is the most popular religion on earth,
                            the people who profess it numbering over 400,000,000. While the basal idea of Christianity
                            is love, the God of Buddhism is the all-knowing one, and the germ of the religion is a
                            belief in the infinite capacity of the human intellect. The religion is pure rationalism,
                            and seeks converts only by argument and persuasion. Against the oppressions, persecutions,
                            and bloody wars, which go to make up the history of Christianity, he placed the 2300 years
                            of peaceful existence which Buddhism has known. It inculcates as simple duties the doing of
                            what we have regarded as intended to ornament and beautify, such as the planting of shade
                            trees along highways. The building of hospitals for the poor and the rich, not only for men
                            but for animals, is a high duty ; for of the humblest creatures the Buddhist religion
                            teaches that something of God's mind has passed into it. The Bible charges us to entertain
                            strangers, which we do — at hotels and at our homes, if they are rich and have letters of
                            introduction. But with the Buddhist the stranger, whoever he be, is a guest from God. Should
                            some stranger come to our door, very likely it would be shut with a Christian-like slam in
                            his face. Against the happy nation of the Burmese people and their universal decency,
                            decorum, modesty, and temperance, he arrayed our statutes against prostitution,
                            night-walking, drunkenness, and the long list of foul, dark, and muddy crimes. Massachusetts
                            is hardly able to keep the prohibitory law on her statute-books, which, if nothing more, is
                            a protest in the name of morality and Christianity; but the Chinese Government, when urged
                            to license the sale of opium, on the ground that it would give a revenue of hundreds of
                            millions, refused because it was an evil which woiild prove injurious to the morals of the
                            people. He spoke of Christianity as exemplified in our business life, our politics, our
                            literature, and the aspirations of our youth, as a spectacle any thing but edifying.
                            Christianity is not a mere system of verbal truth, but is national life and character, and
                            to Christianize China would be to Americanize China. He then spoke of characteristics of the
                            Chinese empire, with an area twice as large as the United States and densely populated
                            throughout; of its wondrous mechanical works ; of its antiquity ; of its knowledge thousands
                            of years ago of sciences and arts modern to us ; of its mode of government and admirable
                            civil service, making officials who are brave, courteous and dignified scholars, with whom
                            even the New England office-holder presents a pitiful contrast, and of the immense
                            devoutness of the people In contrast with the deplorable and growing absence of the
                            religious element in our midst. Where, then, he asked, is our moral superiority ? The
                            religion of the Bible he thought as superior to that of Buddha as the flower to the naked
                            stalk; but we do not exemplify it in our lives. Looking far ahead in the distant future, he
                            could see the time when the nation would be wholly and really Christian. Then, and not till
                            then, will the assumption be justified that we are superior to these people.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Incident" TEIform="index"/>AN INCIDENT</head><p TEIform="p">On Thanksgiving day, a visitor, attending our meeting, arose and spoke as follows: " I have
                            been a silent witness of what my eyes have seen, and my ears have heard, and I am reminded
                            of that beautiful passage in Scripture, where Jacob (after leaving his father's house,
                            knowing not whither he was going), saw in vision a ladder, reaching from earth to heaven, on
                            which the angels of God ascended and descended ; and he said,' Surely the Lord is in this
                            place, and I knew it not; this is none other but the house of God, and this is the gate of
                            heaven.' So I feel that the Lord is with you, and good angels are among you. The words of
                            the Psalmist will apply to you. ' Give thanks unto the Lord, praise and exalt His name, for
                            He is good; let the redeemed say so, whom He hath ransomed from the hand of the enemy, and
                            gathered out from all lands, from the east and the west, the north and the south ; they
                            wandered in a solitary way ; they found no city to dwell in; hungry and thirsty their soul
                            fainted in them ; and He led them forth by the right way, that they might go to a city of
                            habitation.' It is my sincere desire to be joined with you in spirit and be one with you,
                            that I also may be led in the right way unto a ' city of habitation.' His desire is
                        granted.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taking cold" TEIform="index"/>Taking Cold</head><p TEIform="p">If a cold settles on the outer covering of the lungs, it becomes pneumonia, in- flammation of
                            the lungs or lung fever, and in many cases, carries off the strongest man to the grave,
                            within a week. If cold falls upon the inner covering of the lungs, it is pleurisy, with its
                            knife-like pains and its slow, very slow recoveries. If a cold settles in the joints, then
                            it is rheumatism, with its agonies of pain, and rheumatism of the heart, which in an
                            instant, sometimes snaps asunder the cords of life, with no friendly warning. It is of the
                            utmost practicable importance then, in the wintry weather, to know not so much how to cure a
                            cold, as to avoid it. Colds always come from one cause, some part of the body being colder
                            than natural for a time. If persons will always keep their feet warm, and never allow
                            themselves to be chilled, they will never take a cold in a lifetime, and this can only be
                            accomplished by the exercise of due care in warm clothing, and an avoidance of drafts and
                            exposure. While multitudes of colds come from cold feet, perhaps the majority arise from
                            cooling off too quickly after becoming a little warmer than is natural, from ex- ercise or
                            work, or from confinement in a warm apartment.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Titles of a secular character are convenient and unobjectionable..." TEIform="index"/>Titles of a secular character are convenient and unobjectionable...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Titles of a secular character are convenient and unobjectionable, as they denote one's
                            occupation. Thus doctor, 'squire, captain, editor, merchant, artist, etc., are appropriate
                            titles ; but rev." is the silliest handle that was ever put to a man's name, and nobody who
                            is not vain and pompous would ever allow himself to be called by it. Only once, we believe,
                            is it used in the Bible, and then applied to no other being than God — " Holy and reverend
                            is his name." Yet almost every beardless boy in a pulpit (except, perhaps, Elder Grant) is a
                            "rev." The title of "elder," as a gospel teacher, is rather modest, and it is Scriptural,
                            too; but just think of saying the Rev. Jesus Christ, the Rev. Dr. Paul, the Very Rev. John,
                            the Rt. Rev. Matthew, and the Most 'Rev. Father in God Stephen Barjona! It would be thought
                            an insult, and perhaps indictable aalylasphemy by the statute made and provided. We
                            Americans are great hands for wearing honorary titles, so that plain and democratic "Mr.,"
                            when superscribing a letter, for instance, is going out of fashion. "Is the Professor here?"
                            shouted a man as he poked his head into a Boston city street car. "He is!" answered thirteen
                            men, as they all rose up.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is one thing in which the Jews excel..." TEIform="index"/>There is one thing in which the Jews excel the Christians...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is one thing in which the Jews excel the Christians : and that is, funerals. The Jewish
                            service is exactly the same for rich and poor. They consider the grave a leveler. Thus, at
                            the recent funeral of Sir David Solomons, the eminent English Jew, there was a magnificent
                            absence of all display—no elaborate trappings, no plumes, no gaudy hearse, no gold-mounted
                            coffin. It is well to live as a Christian, and die as a Jew.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress and conservatism" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESS AND CONSERVATISM</head><p TEIform="p">The Church is progressive, and the individual is progressive; therefore, either may be
                            conservative toward the other. The progressive must bear and forbear, while the conservative
                            is taking the comfort of ease. But woe to the party, whichever it may be, that in such a
                            case is at ease in Zion. " The wrath of man worketh not the righteousness of God "— does not
                            help the sinning party out of the error of their ways ; therefore, the sword of the Spirit —
                            of the true Reformer— must be as keen, in its edge, toward the reprover as it is toward the
                            reproved ; toward the progressive as it is toward the conservative. Timidity. — A timorous,
                            dictatorial person, who, when riding in a wagon, exercises constant supervision of the
                            teamster, is broken of the habit by riding in cars where they have no voice or control over
                            the train or its conductor. If such men can give up to the judgment and skill of others in
                            the one case, why not in the other ? If in a wagon there be eight persons, have not each the
                            same right of superintendence of the team ? Again, the tim- orous person will often be the
                            most frightened when there is the least danger, and the most quiet when danger is imminent.
                            " 'Tis education forms the common mind. Just as the twig is bent, the tree's inclined." We
                            may educate ourselves a good deal, if we cannot change constitutional proclivities.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All these things shall be added unto you" TEIform="index"/>"ALL THESE THINGS SHALL BE ADDED
                            UNTO YOU."</head><p TEIform="p">Some individual writes to the "People's Column " of the Boston Herald for Oct. 11th,
                            presenting the following request, with which we think Mr. Beecher himself would find it hard
                            to comply : "Mr. Beecher, in his last lecture, spoke with great pathos of the sorrows that
                            come from being finally wrecked in business. There is no feeling heart that does not at once
                            ask, 'Is there no remedy for this?' and could the lecturer suggest one, he would do more
                            good than he has as yet done in all his useful life. And I want to ask of him why he has not
                            rescued from the twaddle of comment in which it has been seeking to pass so long the
                            business rule given by his Master; 1 Seek ye first the kingdom of God and His righte-
                            ousness, and all these things shall be added unto you.' This promise may have philosophy to
                            it. It may be the very thing we want, but it has never yet had any philosophic exposition.
                            All explanation of it thus far has been dishwater. The man who shall show it to be a
                            reliable working principle will do the world more good than a discoverer of the
                            philosopher's stone. I, for one, could excuse the clergymen of Boston from a defense of the
                            cosmogony" of Moses, the astronomy of Joshua, and the zoology of Jonah, if they would take
                            the time thus saved to do the thing 1 suggest." Gentlemen of the creedal stripe, whose
                            attention is at present turned to God-in-the-Constitution schemes for the suppression of
                            free speech and thought among your fellow-men, here is an opportunity to be of real,
                            practical good. You have the floor—can you answer the inquiry? — Banner of Light.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alimentation in its relation to national prosperity" TEIform="index"/>ALIMENTATION IN ITS
                            RELATION TO NATIONAL PROSPERITY</head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Hamlin, Bangor, Me. read a paper upon "Alimentation Considered in its Relations to the
                            Progress and Prosperity of the Nation." He said that the subject was far more important than
                            it seemed at first sight, and that it was well worthy of the future consideration of this
                            association. The effect and value of alimentation was a question for the philosopher as well
                            as for the physiologist, and the gourmand gave utterance to a truism when he said that the
                            destiny of nations depended upon the manner in which they were fed. The chemical composition
                            and physiological action of food affected us all, and should meet with universal attention.
                            In the selection of meat for the purpose of food there was not observed in the large cities
                            and towns the care and judgment which health required. Animal food was easily affected in
                            its nutritive qualities. It contained the elements of vir- ulent poison, and a change in its
                            condition converted it into a source of disease and death. The frequent and excessive use of
                            fermented bread had a disastrous effect upon infantile life, for children fed upon this
                            fashionable food and potatoes possessed but little power of resistance to the diseases to
                            which human life was inevitably exposed. At the conclusion of Dr. Hamlin's report the
                            members took a brief recess, to re-assemble at 7:30</p></div2><pb n="13" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: the shepherd's fold" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: THE SHEPHERD'S FOLD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">When Jesus said, " Other sheep I have that are not of this fold ; them also I must bring,
                            that there may be one fold, and one Shepherd," he undoubtedly had reference to the scattered
                            witnesses who were strangers and pilgrims on the earth, suffering for truth's sake ;
                            preferring to have their names cast out as evil among the pleasure-seeking throng, and to
                            dwell in caves, and wander upon lone mountains, and in desert places, clad in sheep skins
                            and goat skins, rather than disregard the behests of conscience. " Of such the world" (those
                            who gave their lives and strength to please themselves) " was not worthy." God has always
                            had Prophets and witnesses on the earth, who endured the cross, and bore the burdens of
                            their day, and testified against the sins of the people; and He gave his angels charge
                            concerning them, to uphold, feed and clothe them spiritually; for upon their integrity and
                            firm adherence to principle, depended the progress and weal of the race. By the history of
                            past ages, we le,arn that the unprogressed condition of the people was not adapted to
                            organization upon a basis that could stand. Hence, when the Spirit called, saying, " Gather
                            my saints together, they who have made a covenant with me by sacrifice," there was not
                            cohesive power enough to hold them together, and they soon scattered into fragmentary parts.
                            As it would be difficult — we might say impossible — to establish a perfect household in the
                            natural order, without a mother, to counsel, guide, and direct the inmates; so would it also
                            be quite as impracticable to organize and sustain a spiritual Family, or Church, without a
                            Mother's influence and care. The most successful attempt to organize and hold such a body
                            together, of which we are cognizant, was the first Pentecostal Church. Jesus told his
                            disciples that it was expedient that he should go away ; that the Comforter, whom the Father
                            would send in his name, would not come, except he went to him who sent or baptized him
                            (Jesus) with the Christ Spirit. The Trinitarians have always placed the Holy Ghost, or
                            Spirit, among their male Gods. But, why was Jesus so anxious to go to the Father, to
                            intercede and plead for the Comforter to visit the little band of disciples (which only
                            numbered about a hundred and twenty at that time) with whom he had labored, and traveled,
                            and had finished the work that was given him to do ? Did he not yearn in spirit that they
                            might also receive a blessing from the Mother in the heavens ? And, was not the Comforter
                            that came to them and baptized them on that memorable pentecostal day, a manifestation of
                            the Mother Spirit, sent to gather them as a " kind of first fruits," and cause them to see
                            and feel, in part, the glories and beauties of the future Church of Christ, when " the Bride
                            would come forth from her secret chamber," and when Christ would appear in his full glory,
                            to establish a kingdom with foundations so deep and broad that nothing could prevail to
                            overthrow it ? While the primitive Christians were true to the Spirit that baptized them,
                            and taught them Virgin Purity, Commtinity of goods, and Non-resistance, they were filled
                            with universal love to God and man, and were " as a city upon a hill, whose light could not
                            be hid;" and they possessed a power that was stronger than men; and a glory rested upon them
                            brighter than earth could give. But it seemed to be well understood, that there would be a
                            falling away of the first Christian Church, before the Church of the second appearing could
                            be established on the earth. The Apostles predicted a declension prior to the time of the
                            second advent, at which period, angels would be sent to sound the trumpet, and gather the
                            scattered sheep — the waiting witnesses — the " elect," from the four winds of heaven, to
                            the feast that should be prepared when the united dual voice of the Spirit and Bride should
                            be heard, saying, "Come, for all things are now ready." That trumpet has begun to sound. It
                            is not the work of a day of twenty-four hours; but of a day of the Lord — a prophetic period
                            running through many years of time; and those eyes that were steadfastly looking for the
                            second appearing of the Christ " without sin unto salvation," have seen and felt the Divine
                            presence and power. And all who had ears to hear the voice of the Spirit, caught the sound,
                            "Now is come salvation and strength, the kingdom of our God, and the power of his Christ;
                            for the accuser of the brethren" (the generative life) "is cast out" (crucified). And that
                            trumpet will continue to sound, and the angels will pass to and fro in the earth, in search
                            of the scattered sheep, and will gather them one by one to the good Shepherd's fold.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit power" TEIform="index"/>SPIRIT POWER</head><p TEIform="p">We do not propose to write a biography, nor an obituary, at this time, but to narrate what
                            was, to us, one of the most marked manifestations of spirit power it has ever been our
                            privilege to witness. On the 15th day of December last, Sister Margaret Pattison, aged forty
                            years (eighteen of which had been spent in the North Family Shakers of Mount Lebanon), was
                            taken ill. There was nothing alarming in her symptoms until the 17th, when she was attacked
                            with pleurisy. For fourteen hours her sufferings were intense, after which, by the great
                            exertions of those who attended her, she was relieved from acute pain; but, having in-
                            herited a frail, diseased body, the weak tenement could not withstand many such violent
                            shocks, and consequently she was left in a very feeble condition, and could only speak in a
                            low whisper. However, she gained in strength a little, and, on the 21st, she was lifted from
                            her bed into an easy chair, and was able to take a little nourishment. On the 22d the pain
                            struck the other lung, and then all hope of her recovery fled. For two hours her sufferings
                            were indescribable; she then sank into an unconscious state, and so remained about two hours
                            more, when she revived and commenced speaking with a loud and clear voice, as if addressing
                            a large assembly. About thirty sisters gathered into the room to hear the utterances of one
                            whose voice (as those who were watching around her bedside thought), it seemed, would never
                            be heard again on the shores of time; but she was resuscitated by spirit agency, and
                            rendered able to speak for about forty minutes. She called every individual by name, and had
                            an appropriate message to every one, and spake as she could not have done except by the
                            inspiration of spirit power. She said, " 0 how beautiful you look ! I see bright lights all
                            around you. You are far prettier than the lambs that skip upon the mountains ; for you have
                            reason and conscience to guide you; but you all have your natural dispositions to contend
                            with; remember, the power of God will enable you to conquer them. " My dear young sisters,
                            always speak kindly and gently to each other, under all circumstances, however much you may
                            be tried, and you will feel the blessing of so doing. I know this is true, for I have proved
                            it." To one of the sisters she said, " 0 Olive! dear Olive! God blesses you, and the angels
                            bless you." To another, " 0 how many times we have walked and taken sweet counsel to- gether
                            !" To another, " You have always been so kind and good to me, and all have been good to me,
                            every one. 0 how I thank you !" In speaking to the young sisters, she said, " The angels
                            have come down to bless you ; do you know it? We have formed a bond of union that can never
                            be broken. Keep your faith in view, and never lose sight of the blessed gift of purity!
                            Without purity of heart and life, you will never accomplish any thing in the Gospel work. Be
                            modest and comely in your dress ; and, if you are tempted to do or say any thing to attract
                            the opposite sex, and draw them away from the path of innocence and purity, stop and reflect
                            whether you are honoring God, in thus doing, and turn to your spiritual faith and lend all
                            your influence to uplift your brother into the divine life. Heed the monitions of conscience
                            ; for, under the light of the Gospel of Christ, which shines so clearly in this day, we
                            cannot sin with impunity." While those who stood and listened to the words of wisdom which
                            fell from the lips and floAved from the heart of one they loved so dearly, and, as they saw
                            the shadows of the death angel gathering over her, the deep feel- ings of love and
                            affection, mingled with sorrow, found relief in tears, she said: Why do you weep? this is a
                            joyful meeting! Come near to me, loved ones, and dry up those tears ; if I go away, I will
                            often come back, and will dance and skip with you on the ever-green hills of Zion. After
                            expressing great thankfulness and joy, that she had found a Heavenly Mother, as well as a
                            Heavenly Father, a theme upon which she dwelt some time, she sang the following words in a
                            full voice : " I am never forgotten —never forsaken— While I trust in my Mother above; She
                            careth for me, and hath set rue free ; I joy in her unbounded love. O Mother ! bright in thy
                            glory, I see thee, 'mid halos of light, Crown'd in thy victory, bathed in purity! Thy robes
                            are eternally white! " When the song was ended, she said to some of her companions, " Did I
                            not tell you that I should go to Heaven singing? " Again she sank into an unconscious state,
                            and some who saw her, thought she could not live an hour. But, after remaining in that
                            condition about two hours, she again revived, and requested to see the brethren, and, as
                            they gathered into the room, we said to her, Margaret, the brethren have come, do you
                            recognize them ? " To be sure I do," was the reply; " I know them all." She then commenced
                            speaking to them with great earnestness; but her voice was as mild and sweet as the
                            whisperings of an angel. She said, " How thankful I have always been to meet with you on
                            consecrated ground, to worship God. Be faithful, brethren, to devote your strength and life
                            to the upbuilding of the Zion of God in all things. O beautiful Zion ! Many of you are young
                            in faith ; but you are men of intellect, and have come in at a good age. You have proved the
                            world and could not find peace and rest to your souls there. Now be ' true to your call, and
                            you will grow as willows by the watercourses,' and become rightful inheritors, and Sons, in
                            the blest Israel of God." To one she said, " You have forsaken all for the Gospel; and now
                            you will not shrink from its increasing work." Again she said, " 0 here is Brother Timothy !
                            You are one who has ' stood by the stuff' many years. In the strength of young manhood you
                            consecrated yourself to the Gospel work ; and now you pray that you may be re-baptized; and
                            I know you will never <pb n="14" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER A-ISTD flinch in duty, nay, never! Many
                            are looking up to you for strength and example ; and you will be one that will support and
                            help to hold up the hands of the Anointed Leaders in Zion, who watch over and guard the true
                            Israel of God on earth." She said, " A number of you came across the big waters to hear and
                            receive the blessed Gospel of salvation. There is Brother Emil, who left father and mother,
                            brothers and sisters, houses and lands, in a distant country, for the Gospel of Christ; and
                            our Mother in the heavens owns him as her son, and she blesses him ; for he loves his
                            spiritual faith more than the riches, honors, and pleasures of this vain world. I once heard
                            Brother Emil say, that, when he engaged in certain duties where he felt that a great
                            responsibility rested upon him, he first bowed his spirit in prayer that he might be
                            directed aright, and honor God in his efforts." Thus she continued to speak for about 80
                            minutes, and again joined her voice in singing ; but it was a little tremulous and
                            faltering. The last words she was heard to utter were, " My spirit is gathering into heaven
                            !" She then closed her eyes, and lay motionless several hours, except a gentle breathing,
                            when the spirit, quietly, and without the least con- flict, left the frail casket of earth,
                            for its home in a brighter land. The angels have taken a lamb from our fold, that was almost
                            without blemish! Those who have been the most intimately connected with her in life, say
                            they never knew her to speak unkindly, even under the most trying circumstances; and that,
                            in all her deportment, she has been like a ministering angel of purity. We are aware that
                            our account of the last hours of our beautiful departed sister is meager when compared with
                            the real; indeed, the scene could not be described. Eye and ear witnesses alone know and
                            declare that it can never be forgotten. A number of persons said, it was as much of a
                            miracle to them, as if one had arisen from the dead ; and many who saw her, agree that it
                            was the most complete triumph of Christian faith over the power of death that they ever
                            witnessed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. D.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My mite" TEIform="index"/>MY MITE</head><p TEIform="p">" Obedience to God was the first great command Which in the beginning was given ; And every
                            Believer may now understand That this is the passport to heaven." Dear Editors op S. and S.
                            Is not the spirit of obedience as requisite to insure happiness at the present time as in
                            the beginning, or past ? " Order was heaven's first law." Where there is no order, confusion
                            reigns, and consequently unhappiness. But where good order and purity are the prevailing
                            desires of the inhabitants, especially of a Shaker community, the countenances of such
                            self-sacrificing souls beam with happiness and contentment, knowing that by true self-denial
                            they are preparing robes of righteousness with which to adorn their spirits here, and conse-
                            quently in eternity. Learning to live as the angels do in heaven whether we inhabit mortal
                            bodies on this earth, or are divested of them, and dwell in the spirit land, the same
                            self-denying work will be requisite to insure happiness. Therefore my happiness increases ;
                            for it is a privilege to commence this work while on earth, and have my " sins go beforehand
                            to judgment." If this work of confessing and forsaking sin be faithfully performed in time,
                            shall we not, when we enter eternity, be met with the joyful " Well done ; enter into the
                            joys of the Lord? " While, if otherwise, we might have to wander in darkness until our proud
                            natures were humbled, in order to be in a condition to accept the Gospel. The testimony of
                            the Christ Spirit, in his first as well as second appearing, requiring a life free from all
                            indulgences of the sexual nature, it behooves all who would be called by that name, to deny
                            self, and bear the cross of Christ. And, as was promised, this Christ Spirit is not left
                            without a witness, but abides in those who are living that life and who constitute the body
                            of Christ. And, as this body is no monster, it has a head to lead and direct it in all
                            matters, whether spiritual or temporal, " a body fitly framed together, growing unto an holy
                            temple." If sin is the only separation from God, true confession and repentance before these
                            witnesses for God, will do much to lessen the distance from Him, and start us on in " the
                            narrow way." Therefore we would " give honor to whom honor is due," and love and respect our
                            leaders for their works' sake. And we would respect ourselves and walk worthy of our
                            vocation, thus gaining the love of all with whom we come in daily contact. If this we do, we
                            shall feel our union to the angels, and to our heavenly Parents, and shall be daily
                            traveling home to God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Godfrey, Lucretia" TEIform="persName"/>Lucretia Godfrey, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Devotion" TEIform="index"/>DEVOTION</head><p TEIform="p">" How blest is the season when, calm and retired, The soul is by feelings angelic inspired.'
                            The soul of man possesses no deeper devotional power than that of silently sending out to
                            the Creator its profoundest affections and yearnings, with solicitations for present help
                            and future good. The strength and sweet influence drawn into the inner life by those who
                            pray, is evidence of the worth of prayer. By it, the whole thought and feeling is turned
                            within, and sacred converse is held with pure spirits, by the angel part of our nature,
                            which frequently prompts resolution to better action in the performances of life. O what an
                            elevation, far above all that is gross and earthly, the spirit feels, when engaged in the
                            sweet exercise of prayer. Jesus made use of prayer, and also taught his followers to pray,
                            and declared that the Father would reward them for so doing. If our great Exemplar had need
                            of prayer, then how much more, at the present time, does humanity need, in its conflict with
                            temptation and besetting sins, to both watch and pray. Prayer, in the economy of spiritual
                            growth, is like soil to outward vegetation; and, if thoroughly labored on, will increase the
                            growth and fruitfulness of the heavenly graces in the spiritual garden of the soul: from
                            this soil, too, flow those streams which shall be as " a well of water in the soul,
                            springing up into everlasting life." It is sweet to only taste of those waters; but what
                            satisfaction and completeness of joy will be realized in the full supply! By prayer, and a
                            contrite spirit, this fullness may be gained. O Father speed the blessed day When peace on
                            earth shall bear the sway; When love divine shall fill the heart, And all shall choose the
                            better part; When universal growth shall tend Discordant sects in one to blend ; When
                            freedom to live right shall rule, And all be taught in Wisdom's school; When, meeting
                            injuvies with love, All seek the spirit of the dove, And prize far more the bread of life
                            Than wealth and fame with worldly strife; When young and old alike shall know That sensual
                            pleasures never flow But from a lawless selfish state, And pains upon them ever wait; When
                            voice of Justice shall be heard, And man revere her every word, When woman shall, with
                            purpose pure, Seek life and love that will endure. O speed the full and perfect day, When
                            life of Christ shall bear the sway, And one vast Brotherhood a;jrree, In love complete, to
                            worship Thee !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Johnson, Tyringham, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved editress" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Editress :</head><p TEIform="p">I bless the "S. and S.," and will lend my influence to its support. I bid it God-speed, and
                            pray that it may be as an angel of conviction and mercy, bearing upon its golden wings glad
                            tidings of salvation from sin to many weary ami sin-sick souls. May it find its way to
                            different nations and kingdoms of earth, and be a minister of living faith to souls, and
                            lead them to walk in obedience to truth, in the straight and narrow path ol." self-denial
                            and the cross, and to thankfully make an honest confession of every sin they have committed,
                            with a full determination to forsake it forever. This is the " Door of Hope;" and those who
                            enter therein "find rest unto their souls." I feel that a heavenly invitation is sounding to
                            many souls to come to the fountain of pure waters which is opened in Zion in this day of
                            Christ's Second Appearing. The call is, "Come all who will, and partake freely, without
                            money or price." Enter into mansions of peace and rest —rest from the turmoils and confusion
                            that are abroad in the earth —the fruit of sin and wrong-doing. This will be an ample reward
                            for all sacrifices made in leaving a worldly life fraught with so much misery, and entering
                            upon a new life in the kingdom of righteousness and peace.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parsons, Elsa" TEIform="persName"/>Elsa Parsons, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sympathy" TEIform="index"/>SYMPATHY</head><p TEIform="p">The subjects of Monopoly and of Capital and Labor have engaged the attention of many
                            philanthropic minds, and much has been written thereupon by far abler pens than mine,
                            showing cause and effect, and the existing relations between the rich and the poor of this
                            world; therefore, I do not purpose to dwell so much at this time upon the producing causes
                            of the poverty and suffering that are among the populace in this and other countries, as to
                            express sympathy and grief of spirit, that so much wrong and injustice abound, especially in
                            this broad and favored land of liberty; and that, while there are millions of acres of
                            unemployed, uncultivated lands, there are also millions of inhabitants without adequate
                            labor to supply themselves and helpless children with food and clothing. From a youth, to
                            the present time, I have felt a deep pity for, and sympathy with, the suffering poor, the
                            down-trodden and oppressed ; and oftentimes, on my bended knees, have I prayed that through
                            the Providence of God the causes of so much human suffering might be removed. And, as I
                            increase in years, which now number threescore and ten, I feel a growing anxiety, and deep
                            sorrow of heart, in the cause of the poor and needy ; and more especially since the recent
                            financial upheaval has deprived so many of the laboring class of the necessary means of
                            subsistence. And when I hear of the increase of crime, so many thefts and robberies, and of
                            the expenditure of capital in supporting judges and lawyers to try criminal cases of this
                            kind, and to enlarge and build prisons to hold such within its ponderous walls, O how much I
                            wish that public morals were strong enough to hold them from committing such crimes, and
                            that Justice would enfold and shield them from the inclement storms of vice, which beat so
                            rudely and mercilessly against their frail weak minds, often rendered so by the sins of
                            their parents, and frequently they are driven, as it were, by penury and want, to yield to
                            temptation. If money that is expended to punish could be applied to prevent crime, by
                            supplying the destitute widow and homeless orphan with bread, what a blessing it would be.
                            We are aware that it is easier to talk than to do, to plan than to execute. There are some
                            who are too conscientious to steal, others are too proud to beg, and prefer to eke out a
                            miserable life, or fill the premature grave of the suicide, rather than stoop to do either.
                            Were it in my power, I would do much to ameliorate the condition of the honest, suffering
                            poor. But I rest in the hope that the day is fast approaching when there will be less
                            monopoly, and more equality of labor, and a more just and amplified distribution of the
                            products of industry, and that a remembrance that " the earth is the Lord's," and that all
                            his creatures have a right to the elements of subsistence, will lead many to observe the "
                            golden rule," to " Do unto others as they would that others should do unto them."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crosman, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Crosman, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Has anyone wronged you?..." TEIform="index"/>Has anyone wronged you?...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Has anyone wronged you? Be bravely revenged; slight it, and the work is begun; forgive it,
                            'tis finished. He is below himself who is not above an injury. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Herbert Spencer considers it absurd to believe that intellectual culture contributes..." TEIform="index"/>Mr. Herbert Spencer considers it absurd to believe that intellectual culture contributes...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Herbert Spencer considers it absurd to believe that intellectual culture contributes to
                            moral excellence. He cannot understand what connection there is between learning to read and
                            getting a higher sense of duty, or what effect the ability to make written signs can have in
                            strengthening the desire to do right, or how the knowledge of the multiplication table, or
                            quickness in adding or dividing, can so increase the sympathies as to restrain the tendency
                            to trespass against others, or in what way the attainment of accuracy in spelling and
                            parsing can make the sentiment of justice more powerful, etc. He does not go so far as to
                            say that intellectual culture is positively demoralizing; so far as the morals are
                            concerned.</p></div2><pb n="15" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Volutary sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>VOLUNTARY SACRIFICE</head><p TEIform="p">The present is, to some extent, an era of inquiry and speculation, if not of application.
                            Many minds are perceiving and giving assent to truth, and are discarding error, to a greater
                            degree than they have hitherto done ; yet, alas ! how far short they come of the real work
                            that will renew and perfect the whole life and character. Many approve the celibate life,
                            and practise it; this is good, and commendable ; but more is requisite to wholly fill the
                            Christian character. They who really " put on Christ," by being baptized with his baptism, "
                            crucify the flesh with all its affections" as well as "its lusts;" whence spring selfish
                            relation, and individual private property, etc. In the life and character of Jesus may be
                            seen the heavenly attributes and graces; and he proved his love to souls, by the voluntary
                            sacrifice of his own carnal life—self-indulgence and ease, worldly ambition, and love of
                            riches and honor, that he might receive the Christbaptism and be a Minister of the same to
                            others. And herein is a marked distinction between the true Believers in Christ's Second
                            Appearing, who come out of the old inheritance altogether, and form a new home, upon the
                            basis of a Pentecostal Church, in things temporal and spiritual, and those who cling to the
                            old systems, whether they profess to be within the pale of old theologies, or are borne upon
                            the waves of Spiritualism ; it matters little, if the life and fruits produced are the same.
                            True Love, which emanates from the Divine, always incites to individual sacrifice for the
                            general good. It is not narrow, and limited to kith and kin, or to partial preferences ; but
                            it extends to all humanity as God's creation, who, if deserving of his care and notice, are
                            worthy of our love and sympathy. Objections are sometimes presented against the Divine Order
                            which recognizes, and seeks to practically carry out the universality of God's Law of Love
                            and Justice, by those who dwell in the limited precincts of selfish loves, and who cannot
                            see much of interest beyond the generative life, and the conditions and relations which grow
                            out of it. Of course to such there cannot be much form or comeliness in such a life, for
                            they are not prepared to enter into a work that would deprive them of their idols. The
                            reasoning of carnal minds is ever earth-ward, and it is difficult for them to comprehend
                            spiritual things. To such we would recommend that they " order their " thoughts and "
                            conversation aright "—on the natural plane of life where they belong at present, and strive
                            to fulfill the law of reproduction according to the original design; then they will soon
                            begin to reason heavenward, and will gradually progress from the natural to the spiritual,
                            and be able to perceive that they who dwell in .the higher Spiritual Order draw around them
                            Divine influences, which elevate them above the earthly, and lift them into angelic life and
                            love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Knight, J. D." TEIform="persName"/>J. D. Knight, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth and right" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH AND RIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">When the "morning stars sang together, and all the sons of God shouted for joy," was it
                            merely because the Creator had laid the " corner stone," and fastened the foundation of a
                            new world, that they thus felt to express their delight and gratitude ? Or did they feel the
                            inspiration of that Divine truth which cometh from above, and is stronger than the
                            foundations of the earth, and more expansive than the sea which He inclosed within the
                            limits of His Power and Wisdom; that truth which would eventually overspread the earth, and
                            bring its inhabitants, high and low, rich and poor, under its pure rule and equitable
                            government, that caused them thus to lift their hearts and voices? Undoubtedly, by the eye
                            of faith, they looked through the unborn ages of time, and saw something of the work which
                            God would execute in the earth, and felt to exclaim, " O, ever blessed Truth! hasten thy
                            mission, and speed the work of justice and mercy ! " If, at so early period of time as the
                            laying of the foundations of the material world in which we live, " the sons of God shouted
                            for ioy," how much more cause have the daughters of God to raise a shout of freedom and
                            gladness that the foundation of a new heavenly temple is already laid, and that there is a
                            spiritual power at work that will destroy the sinful works of man's creation, and cause all
                            error to be swept away by the mighty waves of the sea of Truth. The spiritual order is not
                            designed to destroy the true natural order, but to condemn its perversions, and by
                            righteousness (right doing) bring happiness to the hearts and homes of many who, through
                            ignorance of a better way, have sought comfort in dissipation and vain amusement, which, at
                            best, being but a momentary respite to the troubled mind, perhaps to react upon it with
                            fourfold vigor. The daughters of Zion feel deeply interested in the cause of Woman. We own,
                            as our sisters, all womankind of our race, though many are very low in the scale of morals,
                            and in a willing and forced condition of servitude to vile passions; yet there is a germ of
                            immortality somewhere in the soul that belongs to God, though it may be buried beneath much
                            rubbish. And we pray that they may come to the knowledge of saving truth and willingly obey
                            it. True knowledge and obedience thereto will emancipate them from that slavery which now
                            binds them down to the low animal plane of existence, where they are trammeled by fashion,
                            fettered by pride, and are a prey to vile insinuations. Then they will understand what are "
                            Woman's Rights." Their first great duty is to study to know themselves, and to understand
                            their duty to God and to their fellow creatures, and to purify their hearts and fit
                            themselves to enter upon the duties of life, feeling the responsibility of acting well their
                            part.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Olive" TEIform="persName"/>Olive Shepherd, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Antoinette—" TEIform="index"/>Dear Antoinette—</head><p TEIform="p">I inclose one dollar for the " Shaker and Shakeress " another year. It is more beauti-
                                ful to me than all the newspapers that flood the land, for its pages are not blotted
                                with a catalogue of sin and crime, but are as refreshing as the springs of Mount
                                Lebanon. I hail its visits as the face of a loved friend in a strange land. It tells me
                                of a Summer Land, where souls grow beautiful, true, and good. My spirits are often heavy
                                laden, and I long for that rest of soul that dwells with the chosen people of God. Yours
                                in love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="J., Sylvina" TEIform="persName"/>Sylvina J. Hannibal, Mo.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Betsey Bates, in the Spirit Land..." TEIform="index"/>Eldress Betsey Bates, in the Spirit Land...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Betsey Bates, in the Spirit Land, sends greeting to the Brethren and Sisters as
                                follows : The Angels in heaven, and saints upon earth, Are blending together in heavenly
                                mirth, Inviting us all to be of good cheer, And greet ev'ry one with "A Happy New Year!"
                                Though cold-hearted Death, with sharp sickle in hand, May reap from among you, for the
                                immortal land; Yet we 're not divided, our spirits are here, To encourage and strengthen
                                through the coming new year. The Sunbeams of light are shedding their rays; With courage
                                look forward for far brighter days: For faithful Believers are hastening near An
                                increase of the Gospel for the ensuing year. Stand firm in the Gospel, and keep in the
                                Ark; The trumpet is sounding for souls to embark : The blind shall see God, the deaf his
                                word hear. The dumb shall sing praises, and hail the new year. The harvest is great, and
                                the lab'rers are few; There's a work for each faithful Believer to do. Be true to your
                                trust, and be of good cheer, And you will rejoice at the close of the year. Eldress
                                Betsey says : With this receive my affectionate Gospel love; and I should be pleased to
                                have every family share of this Union Greeting.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., E." TEIform="persName"/>Instrument, E. P.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work of the century, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>THE WORK OF THE CENTURY No. 1.</head><p TEIform="p">She stood upon the mountain's height, The morn of freedom round her shone ; Beneath her were
                            the years of night, With blood-stained hands and eyes of stone. They were not her ancestral
                            train, Her lofty aims they never knew; She came to bid the people reignTo form a system
                            grand and new. She was a stranger sent of God, Through whom all nations should be blest; She
                            laid foundations strong and broad, , Provided for the earth's oppress'd. Priests, kings, and
                            conquerors were they; The Church and State their throne had been ; By law Divine they
                            claim'd their sway, And spurn'd the rights of toiling men. The heritage that God reserved To
                            be the refuge of the race, By daring courage she preserved, Nor gave to Tyranny a place;
                            Where e'er his direful plans were laid, Where e'er his treach'rous armies moved, By sure
                            defeat he was repaid ; Triumphant still the century proved. And, even in our little day, How
                            great the struggle that arose To banish slavery away— That monster of all household foes.
                            With glass reversed, we view it o'er, And strive to fix it on the past; And yet the fearful
                            guise it wore Will haunt our memories to the last. The angels brought the high command, To "
                            Make Columbia's children free." They sought the noblest of the land To hew a path for
                            liberty, They call'd the justice-loving Friends, Whom they had taught, in silent hours, To
                            give the country's eyes a lens Through which to scan her crushing powers. They thrill'd the
                            cords in woman's heart, Drew sympathy from every tone, Until she made that cause a part Of
                            all the wrongs that were her own. Where e'er a generous nature glow'd. Where e'er was
                            breathed the gift of song, The floods of inspiration fiow'd, In burning waves against the
                            wrong; Where e'er the thought was clear and brave, These angel messengers were found In
                            earnest pleading for the slave, Whose limbs and hearts alike were bound. The hearth, the
                            pulpit, and the press, Were all invoked to lend their aid ; The lowly heart was claim'd to
                            bless The efforts that the mighty made ; Until there rested in the air, An element like
                            subtile flame — A pressure as of mingled prayer — Yet who could tell from whence it came ?
                            The angels shook the Nation's gates, And blew their trumpets long and loud, Until the
                            crime-encumber'd States Rebell'd with spirit fierce and proud ; And Sumter's gun that woke
                            the land, Sent echoes to the unseen realm, Which brought a war-like spirit-band To take the
                            Nation's broken helm. O paradox in human life ! The hands that sought the captives' weal
                            Were nerved, amid that blinding strife, To dye with kindred blood their steel. Yea, those
                            whose hearts for freedom felt, And strove by righteousness to win, Because in Babylon they
                            dwelt, They were partakers of her sin. The work the angel spirits did Seem'd lost below that
                            passion blaze; And yet the gold was only hid, To be restored in after days. Those legions of
                            the earthly plane Performed their work with dauntless rage, Achieved with speed a precious
                            gain, But brought a loss that none can gauge: We pass beyond the broken homes, The ties that
                            cannot be replaced, The hearts where never sunshine comes, The unapprized external waste,
                            And think of what the Nation lost In weight and talent richly earned ; Of what her reeking
                            altars cost, While souls were scarr'd and bodies burn'd. 0 loathsome fields ! O prison pens
                            ! ' Be ye no more the Nation's shame : With you all vindication ends For violence in
                            Freedom's name. Henceforth must Legislation stand The only Arbiter of right: For God has
                            call'd this glorious land To be redeem'd from battle's blight. There but remains a vail of
                            days Till Woman's servitude shall cease ; 1 see her, through its shining haze, The
                            star-crown'd guardian-friend of Peace. For she who gave the bondman aid While cruel shackles
                            were her own, Shall yet, in Council Halls, persuade That Love and Wisdom are but One.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="16" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="City of light" TEIform="index"/>CITY OF LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Andante. Canaan South Family. 1. There opens before me, invisions of glory, Bright scenes of
                            that fair summer land, 2. When the rude storms of life and its tempests have ended, Sweet
                            praises our hearts shall employ, C1 Where, in beauty and Where the soft, bal my A grandeur,
                            God's City of Light A beacon for ever will stand; zephyrs of soul cheer ing love Brings
                            gladness replete with true joy. There, pure crystal fountains forever are Invision I see
                            thee, thou beautiful flowing, Whose rivers make glad the oppress'd, City! There's nothing so
                            lovely below; f And music supernal breathes tidings of And, when I've relinquish'd the ties
                            o* this peace, To earth, To m welcome the pilgrim to thy bliss ful mansions I'll rest,
                        go.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visitors" TEIform="index"/>VISITORS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Casual visitors are expected to pay for tlieir entertainment. Parents having children, or
                            persons who have relatives, among Believers, are not expected to make those circumstances
                            occasions for rendering our Societies places of resort, or a visit to the country at the
                            expense of Believers. Visitors seeking religious information, with a view of uniting, are
                            always welcome. DIRECTIONS. While the post-office address is F. W. Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Col.
                            Co., N. Y., visitors* should take the Harlem Railroad which runs to Chatliam Four Corners,
                            whence, by changing cars, they will be brought direct to New Lebanon depot (via the Harlem
                            Extension Railroad), one mile from the North Family of Shakers.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Focalized light" TEIform="index"/>FOCALIZED LIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">Hail ! all hail the hosts immortal, Toilers from the worlds above; Lo I they leave the pearly
                            portals, To extend the work of Love. They are earnest; shall we trifle With the precious
                            truth they bring ? Shall our hearts their kindlings stifle, To retain some worthless thing?
                            Have we shackles, they can break them, If we ask their blessed aid ; Have we germs, they can
                            awake them To a bloom that will not fade. Nature's tree is split and blasted, Gnarly, bitter
                            fruit it bears ; Spring and summer quickly pass'd it, Autumn takes it unawares. But the tree
                            of Life is bending With its rich eternal fruit; Food for souls who are ascending From the
                            cravings of the brute. Still the sword of truth is wielded By the hands of Cherubim ; But
                            the pure in heart are shielded Underneath each laden limb. Man has fail'd of true
                            progression, Crippled by the serpent's bruise, Though he holds in his possession Strength
                            that he has but to use. 'Tis the power of self-denial, Scholars, statesmen, know its worth ;
                            All unquestion'd is its trial, In the outward things of earth. He who seeks for star or
                            planet, Will not join the midnight dance ; He who studies plant or granite, Does not leave
                            his thoughts to chance. There is system, there is order. In the wondrous realm of mind,
                            Science' far extended border Vanguards forward press to find. From the ruby tide,
                            thought-freighted, Flowing through each throbbing frame, To the spirit chain'd and grated,
                            By the griefs without a name ; From the mosses on the mountain, To the sky's bright fleece
                            of snow; From the bubbles on the fountain, To the gems the oceans know; From the wealth that
                            heaven discloses, To the riches earth conceals ; All proud Intellect encloses In the circle
                            of his seals. But the Soul has been neglected In this royal, mental reign — Crush'd,
                            unknown, or misdirected; Hers, the years of cloud and pain ! Let her have emancipation, Give
                            her sunshine, pure and warm ; As she rises, all creation Will assume its highest form. Let
                            us meet in council holy, To discuss the laws of heaven, Bravely, yet with spirits lowly, To
                            receive the truth that's given. Who would shrink, O, who would waver, Weighed by stamp of
                            leaden creed? Who would give his heart in favor Of the serpent and his seed? At this time
                            light focalizes, To consume the power of sin, To destroy the soul's disguises, And to usher
                            glory in. Is there one who would awaken, One with aspirations true ? Know, the heavens and
                            earth are shaken, To convey this call to you. Come ! O come! e'er yet within you Turns to
                            darkness every gleam, Come ! the Angel bands would win you To the Home of which you dream.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Persons receiving this number may consider it a kindly invitation to remit fifty cents for
                            1874, from January 1st. The more and the greater are life's difficulties, the more honorable
                            it is to carry off the victory. Man may be disappointed in his greatest hopes in life,
                            without, on that account, becoming unhappy.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stroud, Louisiana" TEIform="index"/>Louisiana Stroud
                            </head><p TEIform="p">October 19th,<persName reg="Stroud, Louisiana" TEIform="persName">Louisiana Stroud</persName>, aged 55, at
                                Whitewater, O.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fosgates, Luke" TEIform="index"/>Luke Fosgates
                            </head><p TEIform="p">November 26th,<persName reg="Fosgates, Luke" TEIform="persName">Luke Fosgates</persName>, aged 88, at
                                Harvard, Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pattison, Margaret" TEIform="index"/>Margaret Pattison
                            </head><p TEIform="p">December 23d,<persName reg="Pattison, Margaret" TEIform="persName">Margaret Pattison</persName>, aged 40, at
                                Mt. Lebanon.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brooks, Julia" TEIform="index"/>Julia Brooks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">December 24th,<persName reg="Brooks, Julia" TEIform="persName">Julia Brooks</persName>, aged 69, at Mt.
                                Lebanon.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Powers, Eleanor" TEIform="index"/>Eleanor Powers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">December 27th,<persName reg="Powers, Eleanor" TEIform="persName">Eleanor Powers</persName>, aged 64, at
                                South Union, Ky.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>