<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2204" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">04</biblScope><date value="18920401" TEIform="date">April 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="04" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
APRIL.
THE
MANIFESTO,
Published by the United Societies.
VOL. XXII
"For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVI., 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
The Kentucky Revival, No. 16.         .      -       73
The Angel Choir,        ....          76
Messiahs,       -         -         -                 -      -       77
In Memory of,.....          78
Diary of Eldress N. E. Moore,        -        -       "
Kind Words,           ....        .          81
In Memory of,            .....       "
Which Spirit,.....          82
Inquiry, No. 3.       -          -          ..."
Little Things of Life,         ...          83
Light,          ......
Editorial,......       84
Notes about Home,       -                             86
Health Notes,             ....              92
Charlie's Faith,             ....         94
Music,Bountiful,                                                                  95
Books & Papers,          ,         -                    -          96
Deaths,         ...          .                                "
THE WORLD'S COLUMBIAN EXPOSITION.
Send 50 cents to Bond & Co., 576 Rookery,
Chicago, and you will receive, post paid, a
four hundred page advance Guide to the Exposition, with elegant Engravings of the
Grounds and Buildings, Portraits of its leading spirits, and a Map of the City of Chicago;
all of the Rules governing the Exposition
and Exhibitors, and all information which
can be given out in advance of its opening.
Also other Engravings and printed information will be sent you as published. It will be
a very valuable Book and every person
should secure a copy.
The Cosmic Vital Friends is a Church in
which every thing that lives, moves and
breathes is considered a member. And every
one who has a standard principle and lives
to it, and would die rather than deny it until something better is found, is welcomed
to register his name as an active member
without fee, and can have ten minutes at
least upon the platform relating experience
or unfolding truth, as that one understands it.
Those who wish to co-operate as active
members of the Church may correspond with
Victor B. Hall. No 1245 Wood St. Philadelphia, Pa.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
901 Olive St.,  St. Louis, Mo.
THE NEW IDEA.
One of the trite sayings that is frequently
proven false is the saying, "There is nothing
new under the sun." Surely it is disproven
by a recent publication which holds the
quintessence of all our highest literature in
a single volume. It is a condensation, with
critics' review, of the fifty masterpieces of
the world's greatest minds; and is entitled
"The Best Fifty Books of the Greatest Authors; Condensed for Busy People." It is
not merely a collection of choice extracts,
and elegant quotations. It is a Condensationnot a book of quotations; not a book
of extracts, not pedantic criticism; the reader is given the whole story and scheme of
the author, long pages of descriptive and
dialogue being boiled into a line, the whole
work compressed. It contains full-page
portraits of each author, printed on plate
paper, and a concise biography of each. Its
771 large royal octavo pages cover the whole
range of literature from Homer's Iliad 1200
years B. C. to Lew Wallace's Ben Hur of 1800
A. D. and conjures with such names as
Shakespeare, Dante, Milton, Cervantes,
Pope, Byron, Hugo, Dumas, Dickens, Carlyle, Hawthorne, Goethe, Thackeray, and
scores of others. It is from the Complete
Art-Printing Works of The Matthews-Northrup Co., of Buffalo, N. Y., and that insures
the perfection of manufacture. We understand that it is selling wonderfully where
introduced; most -people are willing to buy
when they get a great deal for little money,
and this book is cheap at $3.75. Its circulars
are certainly very fine, and from them we
infer that BROOKS & Co., of 35 Hanover St.
BOSTON, MASS., are the general agents for
this field. We advise our local canvassers
to look this up, for it certainly would sell
-vv ell.
Scientific American
Agency far
CAVEATS,
.     TRADE  MARKS,
DESIGN PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, $3.00 a.
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUHN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New Yorli.
Vol. XXII.
april, 1892.
No. 4.--><pb n="73" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival. no. 16" TEIform="index"/> THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/> By Richard M'Nemar</byline><p TEIform="p"> OF Union Village, Ohio. Published in Albany, N. Y., in 1808. No. 16. Explanations. Br.
                            Stone, in the introduction to his Letters on Atonement, observes that the arguments used by
                            his opponents, are "bold unscriptural assertions, hard names, delusion, error, doctrines of
                            devils, Arminianism, Socinianism and Deism. Such arguments," say he "have no effect on a
                            candid mind, but they powerfully influence dupes and bigots. The candid look for tru^h and
                            plain unequivocal arguments." Who then could he suppose would be influenced by the following
                            statement in the postscript of his reply to Campbell's strictures ? "You have heard, no
                            doubt, before this time, of the lamentable departure of two of our preachers, and a few of
                            their hearers from the true gospel, into wild enthusiasm, or Shakerism. They have made
                            shipwreck of faith, and turned aside to an old woman's fables, who broached them in New
                            England about twenty-five years ago. These wolves in sheep's clothing have smelt us from
                            afar, and have come to tear, rend and devour." If bold unscriptural assertions and hard
                            names are wrong, I presume Br. Stone's postscript is not exactly right. What plain
                            unequivocal ai'gument was ever advanced to prove that the conduct of these men, in a single
                            instance answered to such a bold assertion. When Benjamin Youngs was forbidden to speak at
                            Concord, by R. Marshal and B. W. Stone, the only reply he made was, "I am sorry to see you
                            abusing your own light." When to these innumerable hard speeches, are added, their inviting
                            these strangers to their houses, stopping them at the door when they came, and forbidding
                            them to enter, or at other times ordering them from their houses and laying them under the
                            necessity of seeking their lodging among the weeds, and by such acts of inhumanity as a
                            Deist would be ashamed of, encouraging a spirit of persecution ; I think the Christians may
                            well acknowledge that all their thoughts, words and actions, have not always been exactly
                            right. <pb n="74" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> "What but the example of this latest genus of Christians could
                            have instigated any part of a free and friendly republic, to beset the houses of the Shakers
                            in the night, assault their persons with clubs and stones, break their windows and burn
                            their place of worship, throw down their fences, and turn in beasts to destroy their grain,
                            cut and tear to pieces their apple trees, crop and disfigure their horses, beat and abuse
                            some of their bodies, and fcy every kind of mockery, railing and cursing, collaring and
                            threatening, disturb and molest them in their worship. Did the citizens of Ohio and
                            Kentucky, know of a truth, that it was the meek and humble followers of Jesus Christ that
                            they were treating in this manner? Nay verily, but a people as they supposed, of the most
                            corrupt and mischievous principles. As I apprehend the general statement which the
                            Christians gave of their principles was not exactly right, I shall mark ut some of those
                            mistakes. The first rough lineaments of Shakerism portrayed on the public mind, were, that
                            it went to disannul and cast away the Bible, to set up the word of man in room of it, to
                            deny Jesus Christ, the resurrection and final judgment, to throw away the gospel and seek
                            salvation by the works of the law. That these Shakers were enemies to the revival and came
                            to destroy it. Their scheme was to get the land and property from the people, by parting man
                            and wife, ruining and breaking up families. That they actually forbade to marry, and
                            commanded to abstain from meats, and therefore without hesitation, they were seducing
                            spirits, and their doctrine that of devils. This general draught laid a foundation for great
                            improvement, both upon their principles and practice. The Christian minister, who set the
                            example of characterizing from his own private studies, without any personal acquaintance,
                            had soon abundance of followers who felt entirely at liberty to publish any thing which a
                            fruitful imagination was capable of composing, and from this source it was, that the public
                            generally received their information. Such reports and conjectures, of which there was an
                            infinite variety, were generally taken upon the authority that Mr. Such-a-one heard a man
                            say, that he saw a woman, who had it from a very respectable man, who saw the person who saw
                            it. But in some instances, persons said to be of great respectability, would affirm, whether
                            they meant with their natural eyes or the eyes of imagination, that they themselves saw such
                            things. For such liberty Br. Thompson, no doubt, laid a foundation in the following sentence
                            of his letter of April. "I see the mark of the beast on that church as plain as 1 see this
                            paper while I write, and I know that I see it by the light of God." In the light of the same
                            god, I doubt not but ten thousand beastly actions have been seen among this people; not one
                            of which, the Christians, and all the world to help them, are able to prove, after sending
                            out spies and watching their houses by day and night. It has ever been foreign from the <pb n="75" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> feelings of the Believers, to counterplead such vague insinuations.
                            They believe that God has called them to another work, in the progress of which the truth
                            will show itself without any strife of words. Bat as a number of things of considerable
                            weight have been stated by way of objection, which have been maintained with some show of
                            argument, I shall briefly investigate some of those particulars, merely to show the
                            difference of sense and understanding on those subjects according to the evidence on both
                            sides. The Christian minister, after forbidding the Shakers to speak or the people to hear
                            them, roundly asserts : lOP" "These men say that we are in a new dispensation, that Christ
                            is come the second time, and the resurrection and final judgment begun." The young Believer
                            would reply : "Very well: A new dispensation is what every enlightened soul has been looking
                            for and the coming of Christ is that for which ten thousands have been praying; and he must
                            now be somewhere on earth, if the Scriptures are true. For the time is up, according to
                            Daniel, John, and all the prophets, for the sanctuary to be cleansed, and the power of the
                            holy people restored ; the authority of antichrist taken away, and the saints to possess the
                            kingdom. And what other resurrection is there to life, but to come out of that state of sin
                            into which the first Adam fell, and come into Christ the second. Adam, who is the
                            resurrection and the life ? The matter we now animate and which is constantly upon the
                            change, we are not to expect after its dissolution, to be again subtracted from the elements
                            of this globe and re-possessed in its primitive form, at the expense of every other body
                            with which it may have been incorporated. What other final judgment are wre to expect, but
                            simply and honestly, in the presence of God, and Christ, and before the saints who are
                            appointed to judge the world, confess all that we have ever done amiss, repair our wrongs,
                            set out to forsake every evil, and grow up into Christ, as the infant grows into a man ?
                            There is a natural body, and there is a spiritual body ; the former belongs to the fall, the
                            latter to the resurrection. Therefore it is not old skulls and decayed flesh that are to be
                            raised up in glory, but that spiritual body of which we are called to be members; which is
                            already raised up by the power of God, and ascending into the heaven of heavens, far out of
                            sight from this lost world. "These men say that each one of them is a Christ, and we must
                            throw away our Bibles, and follow them." This statement is not exactly right. They testify
                            that there is but one Christ, whose footsteps they follow, and though they are by nature no
                            better than other men, yet in following Christ they may be safely followed, according to the
                            Scriptures. If three honest republicans, in order to reclaim a band of tories, should invite
                            them to become their followers even as they followed George Washington or Thomas Jefferson,
                            would this furnish a sufficient reason for stating that each of these men professed <pb n="76" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> to be a Thomas Jefferson? and therefore they must be liars, there being
                            only one man in America of that name. Or if these tories had a copy of the United States'
                            Laws, which they abused, would it be proper for them to say that the honest citizens wanted
                            them to throw away their law-book, because they would have them to live according to these
                            laws? With no less impropriety were the Shakers charged with professing to be each a Christ,
                            and requiring the Christians to throw away their Bibles. The subjects of the revival had
                            unanimously believed that Christ would make his abode and appear in man, and that it was
                            their privilege to believe and follow the truth delivered by man, according to that measure
                            in which it was opened and revealed. This was certainly the faith of brother Thompson
                            himself, when in the spirit of the revival, as appears from the following expression, in a
                            letter, dated April, 1803 : "The Lord may have made known to one what another.is ignorant
                            of. I bless God that He has made you capable to teach me in the things of God." And even in
                            his letter of April, 1805, he has so much remaining candor as to say: "God in mercy visited
                            your soul with light while I remained in darkness. He sent you to this country with the
                            light to sow it here, and made you the instrument of bringing the heavenly fire to
                            Springfield, where my soul caught the flame of this revival. Ever since that time you are in
                            my heart to live and die with you." (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel choir" TEIform="index"/> THE ANGEL CHOIR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/> Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The light of day had vanished, The cares and toils were done; The twilight gray departed And
                            sable curtains hung. A silence brooded over; The night was hushed and still, Save the
                            moaning of the wind-harp Along the pine-clad hill. I sought my couch at even To find from
                            toil release, But ere my weary eyelids Were wrapped in slumber's p,eace,My thoughts flew
                            back and forward Like a shuttle in a loom, The fabric of my vision, Was tinged with shade
                            and gloom. I thought of life's strange meaning, Its suffering, trial, pain; How many hearts
                            to woe were tuned, Instead of hope's refrain. When lo! I heard above me As if in upper air,
                            Sweet angel voices swelling, Divinest music there. With ecstasy I listened, What heavenly
                            harmony, A grand antliemnial chorus, And then sweet melody. I thoughtit is the ransomed Who
                            in God's mansions shine, The psalms of triumph singing, The Lamb's grand song divine. It
                            floated nearer, nearer, Until my inner sight Perceived that choir immortal, Arrayed in
                            vestments white. I reached my hands in trusting To touch their snowy hem, That I might be
                            made holy By coming near to them. When lo! they spread their pinions And vanished from my
                            sight; And then I pondered deeply The vision of the night. Not lofty ones descending From
                            out the great unknown, <pb n="77" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> Who sing and play on golden harps Around the
                            Jasper Throne; But hlessed angel guardians/ Who know our common needs, Whose gentle,
                            God-like presence From sin's dark path-way leads. 0 heaven-sent evangels! Descend the bright
                            stair-way; Come often, cheer and guide us, Direct us day by day. Oh, that sweet song of
                            gladness! Of hope, and joy and love, Hath tuned my heart to noble themes, To live as they
                            above. 1 sing a sweeter cadence, Life seems more bright and fair, Since I heard that angel
                            chorus, The music in the air. Mount Lebanon, N. Y. ,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Messiahs" TEIform="index"/> MESSIAHS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/> Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Nothing is more indicative of the culmination of the old and the ushering in of the new
                            dispensation that is about to unfold to the world higher spiritual revelations and
                            possibilities of growth, than the Messianic movement that has simultaneously effected
                            sensitives in different parts of the country. Drawn from the orbit of normal conditions, the
                            erratic movements of those impressible minds puzzle the exoteric understanding of the masses
                            and the too common conclusion is arrived at, viz., insanity. Preceding the expected Messiah
                            in all ages, a period of intense unrest and disappointment pervaded the minds of mankind.
                            Dissatisfaction with present social, religious and political conditions was prevalent. The
                            expected Messiah was to right those wrongs and bring out of chaotic conditions order. The
                            present essay is to dwell more particularly upon the one that directly preceded the present
                            expected Messianic advent, viz., the mission and revelations of Ann Lee. Mother as her
                            followers are pleased to speak and think of her. All the revelations that have come to man
                            in the order of the Messiah, have heretofore been masculine. One very important object of
                            her mission was to unfold the sublime and eternal truth of the Motherhood of God, and with
                            what faithfulness she labored to give to the world evidence of the truth of her mission the
                            present awakened thought of the world can testify. Beginning to realize the truth of the
                            divine Motherhood the feminine principle is asserting itself in efforts for the emancipation
                            of woman from the thraldom that ages of one-sided teaching have bound her. Like a
                            mathematical problem easy after solution, so the truth of the Heavenly Parentage is dawning
                            upon the race. Through intense suffering of both body and soul she travailed out of and
                            above the environments that surround the ordinary mortal and became one of the world's
                            Messiahs, an adept in the esoteric science of spiritual things. She asserted her right to
                            enter the temple, the holy of holies, and there commune with the divine, and woe to any man
                            that dare to deny her that right, as the career of her former husband, after his rejection
                            of the revelation of God through her can testify. The question will be propounded, who was
                            Ann Lee? She was the founder of the order of Shaker Com- <pb n="78" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> salinities
                            that have flourished for the last century in the United States. But the founding of a sect
                            is a small matter when compared with the farreaching results of her complete mission. At the
                            time of the great tidal wave f spiritual baptism that visited our Societies prior to the
                            advent of modern Spiritualism, she said through one the inspired media that her mission
                            would directly be closed and cease with her people and that she would go where she was not
                            known or wanted. In all ages the higher revelations have first come to illuminated souls
                            that far in advance of the body stand as an advance guard, and many times a forlorn hope,
                            "who take into their breasts the sheaf of hostile spears and break a path for the
                            oppressed." Such constitute the Messiah of their time and race, and such was Ann Lee. Her
                            testimony so little understood eoie hundred years ago by only a chosen few of her direct
                            followers, now through the evolution of soul is beingaccepted in its fullness or in part
                            (according to development) by more than the organized body of her immediate followers. As
                            the on-rolling ages unfold to human perception higher and more exalted thought, enrolled
                            among the illustrious and illuminated saviors of the race, Ann Lee will hold the position of
                            Mother in the new dispensation already dawning for the redemption of the race. Sonyea, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He that hath it not in his power to do much..." TEIform="index"/>
                            He that hath it not in his power to do much...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He that hath it not in his power to do much, should content himself with doing as much as he
                            can.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines in memory of our beloved sister, Marcia E Hastings" TEIform="index"/> Lines in
                            Memory of our Beloved Sister, Marcia E. Hastings</head><p TEIform="p">Who let her light so shine, that others seeing her good works were led to glorify God. We oft
                            recall with chastened heart As in life's school we learn, One precept which our Sister
                            taught, "All unkind words a harvest sure Of soitow will return." E'en now we seem to hear
                            her voice As when she gently said, I've sought to heal the slightest wounds Which words of
                            mine have made. And when I meet with early friends Upon the other side, I'll plead;
                            "Forgive, if aught unkind Within your memories bide." The knowledge whicli I prize the most
                            Has taught me how to live And pattern him whose rule was love, The erring to forgive. 'Twas
                            thus she lived, 'Twas thus she loved, And thus her spirit blest Ascended to its heavenly
                            home A worthy, welcome guest. We'll take the lesson that her life In daily practice taught;
                            And pray for grace that words of ours, May be with kindness fraught. And should we fail in
                            any case To speak with Christ-like care; We'll seek our errors to erase Through penitence
                            and prayer. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="From the diary of eldress Nancy E. Moore. no. 4" TEIform="index"/> From the Diary of
                            Eldress Nancy E. Moore. No. 4.</head><p TEIform="p"> A WORD TO THE YOUNG. Always be respectful to age. Treat those who have borne the burden of
                            life for you with tenderness and due regard. Be ready and willing to receive instruction
                            from them and never speak unkindly to or about them. <pb n="79" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> My heart has been
                            pained with the cruel treatment of the poor, dumb animals of God's creation. I am thankful
                            that I was taught in my childhood that it was wicked wantonly to ill-treat any living thing.
                            This is necessary to be taught to every one who would be a Christian. I would write of my
                            thankfulness for having been so favored in my childhood and youth. The Brethren and Sisters
                            spared no pains to instill into my mind the love and fear of God.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My beloved companions:--A deep sense of the swiftness..." TEIform="index"/>
                            My beloved companions:--A deep sense of the swiftness...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, South Union, April 1865" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky., Apr. 1865.</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Beloved Companions :A deep sense of the swiftness of time admonishes me that my days on
                            earth are rapidly fading away, and I am impressed to write my unwavering faith in the
                            testimony of the blessed gospel of Christ, manifested through our ever blessed Mother Ann,
                            also my fervent desire for the prosperity, honor and well-being of our home in South Union.
                            That this may be honorably effected let each one feel resolutely determined t/O keep the
                            gospel Orders sacredly, as they were given to us. "Order is heaven's first law," and in this
                            comes a blessing. Every one who has the least capacity for business can see there has been a
                            people, here in this place, who have made a willing sacrifice of self and selfish interests.
                            They gave their lives t At this date the Societies in Ky., and especially the one at South
                            Union, were reaping the fruits that had grown out of the War of the Rebellion. It was a
                            period of lawlessness, and brought great anxiety to the Believers. Ed. to urge forward the
                            wheel of progress, and labored hard to lay a foundation upon which other souls could build
                            in safety. Let us consecrate our lives as they have done and build upon tha foundation which
                            is laid. Be assured that all these buildings, with these extended improvements, together
                            witb. the machinery and all the conveniences of our home have not grown to their present
                            state by mere chance. Nay, in no wise. Those who established this Community, toiled
                            diligently day and night to secure an inheritance. I now feel inexpressibly thankful that I
                            enjoyed the privilege to live with Believers when good impressions could be easily made on
                            the mind. Also that my soul was susceptible of receiving these good impressions and that I
                            learned the necessity of living in obedience to the counsel of my guardians, that I might
                            share in their love and approbation. Through all of my faithfulness I can feel the blessing
                            of heaven, a treasure in the soul. I have no occasion to boast, but I do feel thankful for
                            every sacrifice that I have ever made for the gospel, by the cross, while I know full well
                            that through thoughtlessness, carelessness and ignorance I have made many blunders and often
                            missed the strait path. Through purification and through humility my conscience has been led
                            to take the proper steps by which to return to the right way, and this was by an honest
                            confession of all that led me astray. I was taught to reverence and to love my superiors,
                            and to maintain a good union with my equals, and to seek their forgiveness if any errors <pb n="80" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> were manifested before them. In this I have enjoyed a blessing and a
                            heavenly rest on earth, which could not have been enjoyed, had I wasted time in selfishness
                            or in worldly pleasure. It was enjoined upon us to be true and honest; that it was wicked to
                            tell that which was false or to^ hide the wrongs that were presented to us. We should never
                            take that which belonged to another, in a clandestine manner, Bor openly without permission.
                            We were instructed to let our love, nnion and good-will circulate throughout all the
                            household of faith, as preferable to the cultivation of any partial r carnal union at home
                            and abroad. We were to do unto others as we wculd that they should do unto us in like
                            circumstances. A care was maintained that we should walk softly through the halls and rooms
                            of the dwellings, and especially while in the house of worship. The doors must be closed
                            gently, and while speaking the voice should be mild and pleasant. I received the impression
                            that worked as a law in my mind that no false covering of goodness before mortals, would
                            ever profit'me in anything, but that I should be known as I was at heart. For humanity's
                            sake and individual honor, we should never stoop so low as to make sport, or ridicule any
                            one who may have been so unfortunate as to become deformed by infirmity or old age. It is by
                            no power of our own that we have escaped a like infirmity. Had we been born a cripple, an
                            idiot or a slave, how could we have changed our condition? It is the same with all. We need
                            take no credit to ourselves for what we are by nature. Let us be thankful for every talent
                            given to us, and remember that where much is given, much will be required. These are days of
                            sore. trial and deep tribulation, and great care is needed for the protection of souls. The
                            whole south is disorganized, and a thoughtless indifference and recklessness, allows many
                            daring outrages to be committed which are a discredit to those in or out of the Church. The
                            religious interest is very low and the power of conscience seems to have lost its power for
                            good. Our prayers are earnest and continued for the inexperienced, that they may take
                            warning before they are beyond the power of mercy. As I work I cry, alas ! in view of the
                            passing events and rely upon that power superior to my own. I have a staff to lean upon; a
                            hope in adversity ; and through this I look for prosperity to the vineyard of our Lord. It
                            is said that the darkest hour precedes the dawning day. It is now dark ! very dark ! ! Even
                            childhood and youth share in the rebellious spirit that war and bloodshed has brought upon
                            the land. Repentance is deferred and even true modesty and virtuous refinement is often
                            sadly neglected. Yet wTe have the promise and wait patiently for the better day that is
                            coming, when peace shall dwell in the land and righteousness in the hearts of men. In tender
                            regard for all the human race, Farewell.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Moore, Nancy E." TEIform="persName"/> Nancy E. Moore.</byline><pb n="81" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ladd, Maggie" TEIform="persName"/> Maggie Ladd.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What a blessed thing is a kind word; but how few, how very few there are in this world. Kind
                            words are just as easily spoken as cross or harsh words if we will only teach ourselves to
                            think so. We should always have a good supply of kind words on hand, ready to fall from our
                            lips, the minute they are needed. How many bruised hearts have been bound up for new trials,
                            just by afew kind words, spoken at the right time and in the right spirit. The one that
                            speaks them is blessed more than the one to whom they are spoken, for it makes him more
                            Christlike. Every kind word that a person speaks, adds a star to his crown. Some people will
                            have so many stars and jewels for their crowns that they will need more than one crown to
                            contain them. The number, however, will be few to those who will not have enough even for
                            one crown. What an example Jesus set for us. He scattered kind words everywhere, upon all,
                            none were excepted who came within hearing. He gave his life for us that we might follow his
                            example in loving those that "hate us and despitefully use us." A kind word can do more good
                            than all the gold that ever came from the Black Hills. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eads, Harvey L." TEIform="index"/> In Memory of Elder H. L. EADS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Settles, Mary C." TEIform="persName"/> Mary C. Settles.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Death loves a shining mark, and found one in our good Father, Elder Harvey, whose spirit, on
                            the morning of Feb. 13, 1892, returned to the God who gave it. Of him it may be said,his
                            entire life was spent with Believers. At a tender age his natural mother, consecrated her
                            boy to the Lord. Elder Harvey was a grand man. Intellectually, he had few peers. He had in
                            his youth many temptations to go forth into the world, to enter college, and fit himself for
                            a minister of the gospel, but when he was called to the work of Christ he dashed away all
                            ambition for worldly distinction, and inclined his ear to this command, "My son, give me
                            thine heart." Very sacredly has he kept the trust reposed in him, steadily and unflinchingly
                            treading the pathway of duty prescribed for him, even to the sundering of hometies and local
                            attachments, to go to a distant society, thereby showing the obedience that was better than
                            sacrifice. He occupied many positions of trust in bis long life, and worthily acquitted
                            himself. Let us all remember that we are human, prone to err, and as we have been admonished
                            to say some of the kind words to our friends in life, I can say that he was a father and
                            friend to me individually and no less to the whole household of faith. How much we shall
                            miss him, even though he was so advanced in years. We shall miss his bright, cheerful
                            letters, and good counsel. The evening of his day was made peaceful by loving hands and
                            willing feet. Dearest friends smoothed his dying pillow, and did many things for his
                            comfort. One only of his associates in the ministry, survive him,Eldress Betsy Smith; may
                            her path be the path of peace during her declining days, is the wish of her many friends. I
                            trust that those who remain will be "faithful even unto the end," as has been our loved
                            Elder Harvey. Let us remember his many virtues, and Be to others' faults a little blind, Be
                            to their virtues, very kind. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Matthew Henry, a little before his death, said to a friend..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Matthew Henry, a little before his death, said to a friend...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Matthew Henry, a little before his death, said to a friend, "You have been used to take
                            notice of the sayings of dying men; this is mineThat a life spent in the service of God, and
                            communion with Him, is the most comfortable and pleasant life that any one can live in this
                            world."</p><pb n="82" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which spirit" TEIform="index"/> WHICH SPIRIT?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Semelroth, Carl" TEIform="persName"/> Dr. Carl Semelroth.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Apostle speaks of the possibility of believers receiving another spirit which they had
                            not received at first. When Jesus said to the apostles who sought to call down fire from
                            heaven and destroy those who did not accept their words, that they knew not what manner of
                            spirit they were of. The Spirit of God is of love and labor. It is the spirit of Him who
                            created all things and who works in Ms people to benefit and bless and save all mankind. It
                            is not the spirit of idleness or self-seeking. It is the spirit of him who said " I must
                            wTork the work of him that sent me" and who said,"the zeal of thine house hath eaten me up."
                            If we have a spirit that shirks the labor or shuns the work which God has bidden us do, a
                            spirit which seeks for ease and covets personal comfort and enjoyment, then we may doubt
                            whether the spirit of Christ dwells in us. The spirit of Christ is a spirit of prophecy, a
                            spirit of proclaiming, a spirit of invitation, for "the spirit and the bride say come." It
                            is the spirit that loves and yearns over lost men, that pities the perishing and invites and
                            entreats and seeks to bring home all mankind to the blessed gospel of love into the Master's
                            fold. It is far from the spirit that seeks for worldly gain and earthly glory or pleasure,
                            for the friendship of the world is enmity with God. It is the spirit which enables us to
                            sing with the spirit and understanding, and helps us to find our place of prayer where the
                            spirit is to discern of something that is around us that we may be saved from deception and
                            misleading. It truly is the spirit of truth which causes us to love truth and hate error. It
                            is the spirit which sometimes wrorks wonders, for God hath given to some the gift of healing
                            and the working of miracles by the same spirit. It is the spirit of power and of love, and
                            of a sound mind. It is the spirit which bears the fruit of love, joy, peace, long-suffering,
                            meekness, gentleness and faith and enables those who possess the spirit to crucify the flesh
                            with the affections and desires. As many as are led by the spirit of God they are the sons
                            and daughters of God. But if none have the spirit of Christ they are none of his. Let those
                            wlio know the power of the Holy Spirit see to it that they quench not the spirit, that they
                            grieve not the Holy Spirit of God. And let those wTho have not yet known the force of the
                            spirit of love and truth, seek to know it as it comes from God who will give unto them that
                            spirit so that being partakers of the spirit of God they shall be the sous and daughters or
                            God,'the Father and Mother, and the heirs of everlasting glory. Peoria, Ill.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inquiry. no. 3" TEIform="index"/> INQUIRY. No. 3.</head><p TEIform="p"> What is the difference between the Quakers and Shakers? While the Quakers believe in the old
                            Adamic relation of "marrying and giving in marriage," the Shakers believe in the testimony
                            of the Christian <pb n="83" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> resurrection, in which Jesus said, "they neither
                            marry nor are given in marriage." The Quakers are believers in the Trinity, the Father, Son
                            and Holy Ghost,three male persons in the Deity. The Shakers teach that God is our Father and
                            our Mother. The Quakers believe in the plenary inspiration oi' the Scriptures, while the
                            Shakers believe that the Scriptures are a record of God's work among a specially favored
                            class of people. The Quakers amass to themselves all the private, selfish property that time
                            and ability will afford. The Shakers live in a Christian Community and have no private
                            property, but hold as said the apostles,"All things in common." While there are essential
                            differences in the two orders, there are some things in which they quite nearly approach
                            each other. The Quakers are stanch non-resistants and a worthy example of this Christian
                            principle. They accepted the words of Jesus,"my soldiers will not fight." The Shakers
                            accepted the same testimony, and are also, non-resistants.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little things of life" TEIform="index"/> LITTLE THINGS OF LIFE.</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by Amelia Tait.] Little words, not eloquent speeches or sermons; little deeds,
                            not miracles, nor one great act, nor mighty martyrdom make up the true Christian life. The
                            little constant sunbeam, not the lightening; the waters of Siloam, "that go softly'' on
                            their meek mission of refreshment, not ^'the waters of rivers, great and mighty, rushing
                            down in torrent noise and force, are the true symbols of a holy life." The avoidance of
                            little evils, little sins, little inconsistencies, little weaknesses, little follies, little
                            indiscretions and impudences, little foibles, little acts of indolence or indecision, or
                            slovenliness or cowardice, little equivocations or abberrations from high integrity, little
                            bits of worldliness and gayety, little indifferences to the feelings or wishes of others,
                            little outbreaks of temper and crossness, or selfishness or vanity; the avoidance of such
                            little things as these go far to make up at least the negative beauty of life. And then
                            attention to the little duties of the day and hour, in public transactions, to private
                            dealings, or family arrangements, to the little words and tones, little benevolences or
                            forbearances, or tendernesses, little self-denials, self-restraints, and thoughtfulness,
                            little plans of quiet kindness and thoughtful consideration for others; punctuality and
                            method, and true aim in the ordering of each daythese are the active developments of holy
                            life, the rich and divine mosaics of which it is composed. What makes yon green hill so
                            beautiful? Not the outstanding peak or stately elm, but the bright sward which clothes its
                            slopes, composed of innumerable blades of grass. It is of small things that a great life is
                            made up.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light" TEIform="index"/> LIGHT.</head><p TEIform="p"> This morn the sky was cold and gray, The sun was hid from view, The cloud which shadowed all
                            my soul Concealed G-od from my sight. To-night the clouds are breaking 'way The stars of
                            heaven shine through, And I lift up to G-od my soul, For he has sent me light. Mary Agnes
                            Leavens. [The above was contributed by one who has loved the "Believers" from early
                            childhood.Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I will not speak against my neighbor" TEIform="index"/>I will not speak against my neighbor
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I will not speak against my neighbor.</p><pb n="84" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. APRIL, 1893. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious views of
                            the Oedee and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should be
                            addressed to Henby C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. ne copy per year, postage
                            paid, .75 " " six months, " " .40 Send for sample copy, free. Entered at the Post Office at
                            East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It may not be an objectionable feature in the life..." TEIform="index"/>
                                It may not be an objectionable feature in the life...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> It may not be an objectionable feature in the life of a Christian, to be interested in
                                that which makes the heart to rejoice. Holiness, honesty, truthfulness and a general
                                consideration for others can never pass without its reward of peace and happiness. These
                                are appreciated as among the treasures that are worthy to be placed beyond the reach of
                                moth and,rust, and in this world and that to come, they will be treasures over which one
                                may always reap the reward of "Well Done." But to rejoice when despoiled of our hard
                                earned earthly pittance and enter into prayer for those who are our active persecutors
                                is quite another thing. The very essence of life is in obtaining and in being able to
                                hold all that may accrue to our advantage through temporal blessings and no less through
                                heavenly assurance. It was in the early part of the mission of Jesus that he found it so
                                necessary to acquaint the disciples of the great privileges of their high calling. They
                                had accepted a new order of life. They were learning to become the sons of God and this
                                certainly was antagonistic to the selfish life of the world. It would create talk. It
                                would arouse persecution. Ignorant and prejudiced minds would oppose the more virtuous
                                life, and if necessary, use force to destroy it. Persecutions had existed in the world
                                from the earliest day. Hardly had the gates of Eden been closed to the family of Adam
                                before a dispute arose which terminated fatally in the death of the younger brother.
                                This was the first step in religious persecution. The selfish propensities in the
                                composition of man were so liberally bestowed that "Might," as a general rule, became
                                "Right," and accepted every opportunity to destroy whatever came in its way. Jesus,
                                without doubt, knew that the prophets had been killed, and that many other messengers
                                sent from God had been stoned and he <pb n="85" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> could easily foresee the
                                persecutions that would overtake his defenceless disciples. As an encouragement to them
                                under these afflictions, he says,"Be happy when men shall persecute you and speak evil
                                against you falsely." To accept this doctrine was indeed, to accept something new and so
                                new that it had never before been known on the earth. It was decidedly beyond what Moses
                                and the prophets had taught. Instead of hatipg our enemies, we must love them as we love
                                ourselves. The secret of success in every human being is to learn to do right. To
                                possess an exceeding righteousness and to sustain this in advance of the righteousness
                                of the children of this world. When Moses said, "An eye for an eye, and a tooth for a
                                tooth," he was teaching a growing principle of righteousness that stood before other
                                nations, and yet to-day we should call this treatment inhuman. The destruction of the
                                Sepoys at the mouth of the cannon by Christian England, was its best idea of right, but
                                it was at variance with the teaching of Jesus. The murdering and imprisoning of those
                                who chose to think for themselves was as heathenish as were the English and not at all
                                in harmony with the sermon on the mount. It is quite another thing for us to suffer
                                persecution for righteousness' sake, than it would be for us to make others suffer.
                                "Happy are ye when men shall say all manner of evil against you falsely." And this they
                                will do against any person or any class of persons who may accept and teach others to
                                move forward into any increasing light. Here comes the grand opportunity to exercise the
                                patience of the saints. Overcome evil with good. Live in the light, so that whatever may
                                be said or written may bear the genuine stamp of the great and good Teacher.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Believers who went to Ohio in 1800 as missionaries..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The Believers who went to Ohio in 1800 as missionaries...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Believers who went to Ohio in 1800 as missionaries, were subjected to more or less petty
                            persecutions. The new lights or schismatics who had seceded from the Presbyterian church and
                            were preaching in the revival meetings, a doctrine at variance with their former faith, held
                            the authority during the times of service and willed who should and who should not speak.
                            Some of these so-called religious bodies have at times very singular freaks that are called
                            manifestations of the spirit. The very same thing if it should appear in any other body of
                            men would be regarded as underhanded and mean. The Brethren had been invited to attend a
                            meeting that was under the direction of several of the anti-presbyterian ministers. They
                            went in good faith and expected to take part in the exercises, but those ministers of this
                            world were wiser in their generation and in their audacity than <pb n="86" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> their
                            invited guests and in some dark hour or dark corner had met together and voted that their
                            visitors should not be allowed to speak one word during the meeting. By the ungodly of this
                            world, this would be called sharp practice, but in this case we shall call it incipient,
                            religious persecution. These ministers of the gospel ( ?) in seemingly good faith had
                            invited their Brethren to be with them and then took the opportunity, individually to
                            ventilate their minds by denunciations and the free use of vile epithets. Of course there
                            were no stakes, no chains and no faggots preparatory to a burning. That had gone by, but
                            such men only needed the right of a dominant power to have produced a first class Smithfield
                            burning for the glory of God. Persecutions, wherever they may be, are always the outbursts
                            of the lowest passion of man. It makes but little difference what the designated term may
                            be, whether Holy Inquisitors, Ku Klux or White Caps or whether it comes in the form of an
                            excommunication, an imprisonment, an execution or a holocaust. Some of these instances of
                            diabolical temper flame, are phenomenal, and one of the remarkably singular features is,
                            that those professing to have forgiving minds and even in their theological zeal can put a
                            premium on wickedness, and then in a heated passion, on the addition or omission of only one
                            letter in some theological word, are ready to brand the honest disputant as a heretic and
                            destroy his life by inflicting the most excruciating torture that the human mind can invent.
                            Indeed, more of the brotherhood of man can do no harm.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. February. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1891. 28.78 2.25
                                in. 23 in. 1892. 23 .25 in. 21.25 in. Mar. 1892. And thus passes the winter, which used
                                to be a long, cold season, full of ice and snow; the only reminder of summer being dried
                                fruits. Now by the skill of manand woman the seasons are so intermingled, that the
                                blessings of each, are, in a measure shared through the year. Canned fruits and
                                vegetables nearly as good as fresh ones are possible. Flowers blooming in every part of
                                the house, to counteract the too dry atmosphere of artificial heat; with now and then a
                                surprise of crisp and delicate greens raised somehow and somewhere by our skillful
                                brother Martin Jones, all contribute to add summer to winter; and when we can garner the
                                sun's rays direct, as easily as we do the gelid stores of the winter king, we shall not
                                mind whether it is December or May. Once upon a time only crows and snowbirds ventured
                                into our icy latitude during winter, now we can count six different kinds of birds two
                                of which really cheer us with song. Nor is the feathered songster all that brings us
                                cheer. From the Granite Hills, welcome messengers have alighted in our midst. It was so
                                good to see our worthy Elder Abraham once more in Lebanon; <pb n="87" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> and to
                                realize that though the snows of eighty-four winters have made hoary his locks, he is
                                one of the number spoken of by the prophet, who because they wait upon the Lord shall in
                                spirit, mount up with wings, shall renew their strength, etc. Bro. Franklin Youngs who
                                accompanied him was also welcome to our home, and though it was a first visit, we trust
                                it will be repeated oft, when in the near future, the isolation of our several Societies
                                shall yield to the influence of a closer communion. Our venerated father Elder Daniel
                                Boler, who has been quite a sufferer, is slowly improving. Job is not the only example
                                of heroic patience and fortitude. May his last days like Job's contain a double
                                blessing, for his upright life and walk with God have earned it. Health of family about
                                as usual. No La Grippe, and we hope that no March wind will blow it toward us. A. J. C.
                                Center Family. Mar. 1892. There is not much of anything going on at present. Br. Henry
                                George with the help of some of the young Brethren, is at work building a silo in the
                                west end of our cow barn. It is 8 ft. x 11 ft. and a little over 30 ft. deep. Our stock
                                is in very nice shape much to the credit of Brother Henry. We have had quite a stormy
                                month so far but to-day it shows some signs of returning spring. There is a little snow
                                lying around, somewhat covering up the defective points of mother Earth. a company of
                                three young folks (two of them teachers) attended a Teacher's Institute held at Chatham,
                                N. Y., Mar. 711. It was very interesting and instructive, having some of the leading
                                educational men of the State of New York as presiding officers. The majority of the
                                family are enjoying good health, while several are afflicted with slight colds, showing
                                that La Grippe is making a gentle though uninvited call and we all hope that he will not
                                prolong his visit. Our good father Elder Abraham Perkins with Brother Franklin Youngs
                                paid us a very interesting visit two weeks ago. Elder Abraham seemed to be enjoying
                                quite good health considering his years. W. J. P. 3N~ortli Family. March, 1892. Nothing
                                very special moving at our home except that the writer is in the healing apartments.
                                Having fallen under the weather, of which we have had a great abundance, but was
                                mercifully picked up and landed clear of the storm: is now about ready for another
                                battle with wind and tide, and with whatever else constitutes the weather. I cannot stay
                                long under conditions in which I have no faith, and against which I am fighting to the
                                best of my ability. As we grow in understanding, we more and more realize that effect
                                follows cause: and if we are not prompt to remove the first cause, the effects become
                                cause for other effects, and if we are unwise, we go from bad to worse in geometrical
                                ratio. No other way can a wise soul pursue, than to remove the first cause. To be ever
                                learning, and never coming to a practical knowledge of the truth, would seem to indicate
                                that the indulgence of self was the chief object of life. But to practice what of truth
                                we know will lead us to the front from whence all truth doth flow. As the practice of
                                the truth is the only thing that will make us free, there is no hope of salvation only
                                in obedience. On the 17th ult. we were very much blessed in having our beloved Elder
                                Abraham, and Br. Franklin Youngs from Enfield N. H. with us: we had a very interesting
                                and profitable time. We had a very interesting and rather an amusing occasion, (though
                                somewhat dangerous) getting our ice. AVith all our devices of springs, scratchers and
                                vice, we were unable to control the ice coming down the slide; so we just loaded it on
                                the sleighs and drew it down. We had set out to be willful, and make it come just as we
                                wanted it; but for this season got beat: <pb n="88" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> however, we are not
                                discouraged and shall try again, if the powers that rule do not veto. Have been shipping
                                quite a large quantity of hay and straw. It is a ques- j tion with us, whether we can
                                keep up the fertility of the land with commercial fertilizers and sell off the hay and
                                straw. We have commenced the experiment, and shall give it a thorough trial. If at the
                                end of five or ten years, we find larger crops and better quality, it will be evidence,
                                somewhat, of the success of the experiment. In kindest love, D. O.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/> Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mar. 1892. It is a general time of health. No one laid up with the Grippe, but some have
                                colds and that is enough. Our good Elder Nathaniel Fry is suffering from a cancer. The
                                several families are busy sawing their fire wood and getting ready for spring work on
                                the land. We have been selling apples and potatoes. The price is one dollar per barrel.
                                Last year they were worth three dollars. Elder Abraham Perkins and Br. Franklin youngs
                                of Enfield, N. H., have made us a short visit. All were pleased to meet them and gave
                                them a warm welcome. The Sisters at the Church and South families are busy making
                                shirts. The music of the sewing machine is the first thing heard in the morning and the
                                last thing at night. Elder Joseph Holden and Eldress Harriet Bullard have paid us flying
                                visits, but they came and went so quickly that one could hardly catch a glimpse of them.
                                We are endeavoring to keep the testimony alive and are praying for ourselves and for all
                                others. J. B. Second Family. Mar. 1892. Some time has elapsed since we have written
                                anything for the Manifesto, and when our pen is idle, we notice Watervliet is not
                                represented in Home Notes; so we will again take up our pen. We were blest with a visit
                                from our esteemed Elder Abraham Perkins, and Br. Franklin Youngs of Enfield, N. H., on
                                Mar. 3rd. Elder Abraham is always a welcome visitor, as indeed, is every Brother and
                                Sister, but he was doubly so at this time. Owing to his advanced age, we did not expect
                                to have the pleasure of another visit from him. From our early childhood we have heard
                                of Elder Abraham, and we feel that his life and example is, and should be, an
                                encouragement to every Zion traveler. Coming among Believers in his youth, he has lived
                                a life of consecration to the Lord; has fought the good fight, and overcome the world in
                                his own soul, and now at the age of four score . and four, he can still proclaim the
                                testimony of truth against sin in every form, and express his thankfulness for the
                                gospel. When we think of the many bright stars that have shone so brilliantly in the
                                firmament of our Zion, and are now passing from our mortal vision, the thought makes us
                                sad, knowing there are so few to fill the vacant places and to minister the life and
                                zeal of the gospel, as these precious souls have done. Elder Harvey Eads, so lately
                                passed away, was another we had learned to love and esteem for his faithful and untiring
                                zeal and devotion to the Cause. Health of Society good with few exceptions, among the
                                aged. Elder Nathaniel is a great sufferer and may ere many days, pass away and be
                                numbered with the saints who have gone before. We shall miss his bright example, his
                                words of encouragement, and the life and zeal he has always shown in our worship. He
                                has, for many years, stood for Zion's support, and a minister of love and peace. Weather
                                at present is mild, snow fast melting. We extend our love and sympathy to the Society at
                                Maine for the persecution they have lately met with. It comes from the same source that
                                did the persecutions of Mother and our first parents in the gospel. We think should we
                                ever visit Boston, we shall steer clear of the "Boston Herald" fearing we might find
                                among them a "chile takin notes."</p><pb n="89" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> "Praying always with all prayer," saith the Apostle. When we pray to our heavenly
                                Father, it is an acknowledgment of our dependence on Him. We should live day by day in
                                the spirit of prayer. How blessed is the thought that we can be engaged in prayer when
                                performing our daily duties. Our supplication can ascend to God without moving our lips.
                                No matter how earnest or zealous we may be, without prayer and watchfulness we shall be
                                overcome by the Adversary of souls. Watching and prayer is a safeguard each hour. Let us
                                strive to attain to this prayerful spirit, and commit all our trials and burdens to One,
                                who has promised to guide and protect those who trust in Him. 3417 spaces of cream were
                                sold in Feb. A large crop of ice. We should be generous to our poultry. One third each
                                of wheat, oats and buckwheat steamed, is an excellent ration for hens. Why poultry
                                should be expected to be profitable without care more than any other stock is what we do
                                not understand. It is the little matters that should receive the most careful attention,
                                as the observance of method and system is certain to prove beneficial at all times. Poor
                                nests will not be occupied by hens if they can get better places to lay. High perches
                                often cause deformed feet. The prevention of dampness in the house avoids roup, which is
                                a terrible scourge in a flock. D. Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> March, 1892. The way to be happy is not to try too hard to be so (for selfish purposes)
                                but we enjoy the purest of happiness by trying to make others happy. There is no place
                                that needs so much the sunbeams of cheerfulness and happiness, as does the chamber of
                                the sick. Under the burden of hours of pain or wasting away by some fell disease it
                                becomes our privilege as faithful attendants to bring to them the beauty of the sunbeams
                                of cheerfulness. Riches never brought true happiness, although they may be one of the
                                primary necessities of a life upon the earth. Many cheerful spirits are leaning upon the
                                toils of to-day for the food which to-day demands. It is a cheerful trust in Providence.
                                Such dispositions would exhibit a loving spirit whether in a palace or in a cottage.
                                Some persons are constantly beset with difficulties. Nearly everything goes wrong and
                                you will probably find that there is "a want" somewhere. A want of changed conditions; a
                                want may be of more wealth than Providence has seen proper to bestow. This we may call a
                                canker of the heart, and it is the destroyer of all happiness: hence the great wisdom of
                                the Scripture injunction:"Seek first the kingdom of heaven and its righteousness," and
                                then if we are not happy with our surroundings, we should awaken to more interest in
                                temporal duties or to a change of heart or disposition. I am often admonished by the
                                wise words of our fathers and mothers, who. while speaking of their journey in life,
                                taught us the necessity of a contented spirit. It was to them a continual feast and
                                worked out the great problem of community life. "There is nothing that helps us to feel
                                that our lives have been worth living, so much as the humble and grateful consciousness
                                that we have helped some other soul to fulfill its destiny." The unwelcome visitor which
                                we so reluctantly carried into the New Year still holds a firm Grippe upon some of our
                                little family. During these visitations our anxiety increases, although our hope
                                stimulates us to work carefully and patiently. Fire wood is all sawed and the larger
                                part well housed. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> March, 1892. Deab Editor:It is with difficulty, that we bring ourselves to realize that
                                these few representative lines are to be <pb n="90" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> April Notes so swiftly
                                has the winter passed, and we wonder a bit if the robins' notes will be as much belated
                                as these will prove to be, each one of which should have been audible, or rather
                                visible, a month ago. We cannot tolerate procrastination at all, so will say, it was not
                                this insidious element that caused the delay, but"One left it for the other, and the
                                other left it for one," as is often the case, in matters of more vital importance even
                                in our Community homes, where we aim, at least to have matters systematized. The removal
                                of our worthy mother Laura Foster, from this rudimentary school to a higher department
                                did not get forwarded. Beyond a doubt, she was greeted with a loving welcome home to the
                                land of realities and light in season:no delays there. Having been almost entirely blind
                                for the last few years, she must rejoice in her promotion: the elderly portion of our
                                Society know of her genuine, sterling worth, while younger members who only have
                                knowledge of her less active life, must have been impressed with her integrity of
                                character. We say a kind farewell, without one regret, for we know her joy and
                                satisfaction in the change is complete. We would not even mention the prevalence of the
                                G- - - - -among us, (we cannot write the Avhole word) only as we wish to say a modified
                                good riddance, and we modify, out of self-respect, none whatever for the tyrant, if any
                                one, professional or non so, espies a microbe of this dread disease next winter, we do
                                desire they clothe it with another name, for this one has become a curse. The ice
                                harvest was completed earlier than is usual with us. We must belong to the conservative
                                party, for the old fashioned wheelbarrow still does duty for us, in conveying it to the
                                Office, Dining Hall and Infirmary, the Dairy having an especial provision in this line.
                                No span of horses for this business, it would make our eyes open wide; however, we have
                                enough as a rule, allowing that there are exceptions to all rules, even good ones, and
                                "Enough is as good as a feast." We may not be able to tell about spaces of cream, nor an
                                abundance of milk, yet, when we reflect upon the millions of human beings, whose cries
                                for bread to sustain life are incessant, we say in humbleness of heart, would that
                                others might share in our many blessings. With kind regards to all. E. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mar. 1892. We almost know that winter is over. At the present writing we have but very
                                little snow on the ground.' The lumbermen are having a hard time striving to get their
                                logs out of the forests and with all they can do a greater part of them will have to
                                remain in the woods until another winter. The time is drawing near when we shall have
                                bright, warm days and enjoy the cultivation of our beautiful flowers, some of which we
                                are already starting under glass for early blossoming. Sisters are busy on their sale
                                work and whenever a stormy day presents itself the services of the Brethren are enlisted
                                sawing out boards for boxes &amp;c. We were very much interested reading in the last
                                Manifesto of that good meeting at Enfield, N. H. Our meetings are also profitable and we
                                should be glad if the testimonies which are borne with such earnestness by our Brethren
                                and Sisters could be heard by thousands and be to them the same blessing that they are
                                to the small number who are thus privileged. A. S. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, Ohio.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mar. 1892. To-day I feel unusually happy. Contentment and peace of mind fill my soul and
                                the words of good Elder Joseph still ring in my ears. "Surely, if people can not be
                                happy here the fault must lie at the individual's own door." Not what have I to be
                                thankful for but what have not I to be grateful for. We are surrounded by kind and dear
                                friends, always <pb n="91" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> willing to help us in our trials as well as our
                                joys. The Society meeting this morning was very entertaining and all must have felt
                                encouraged and strengthened. Eloquent and interesting sentiments were expressed by
                                several, namelyElder Joseph Slingerland, Elder Napoleon Brown, Leopold Goepper, Edward
                                Webber, Eldress Ellen Ross, Mary A. Holland, Susan Liddell and Harriet Shepard. I trust
                                I shall profit by what was said and be awake to take a decided interest in this home
                                which we are all trying so hard to beautify. In telling a friend not long since some of
                                the trials I was brought to bear and thinking the fault all lay with the party I was
                                talking about, said he, "I can make but one remark and that is, Do your duty and go
                                ahead. Think what Jesus said at one time, 'What is that to thee, follow thou me.' " This
                                remark did me much good and I shall not forget it. We have had plenty of rain lately,
                                but the health of the Society is good, although for a few weeks things looked serious
                                enough, as La Grippe seemed determined to have a full introduction. I had almost
                                forgotten to make mention of the most important news of all, and it was thiswe had a
                                visit paid us not long since by two Brethren from Watervliet, Elder Henry Frederic and
                                Br. Moore Mason. Elder Oliver Hampton has been at Watervliet the past week. On his
                                return he will be greeted with a cheery "Welcome home" by his Lyceum scholars, who have
                                been impatiently waiting for him. We have only one sick person in our family at the
                                present time. One person in particular deserving especial mention in Home Notes is our
                                beloved Sister Emily Hampton. She wrestled with La Grippe a few weeks this winter, but
                                is now about as well as usual. She is remarkably bright and active for one of her years.
                                We all love and look upon Sister Emily as a precious jewel and hope she may be spared to
                                us for many years to come. A. B. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> March, 1892. With the busy whirl of time February with many lights and shades has
                                renewed its final march. Even so. Can February March? Yea and April May, didn't June
                                know it? Snow is descending in abundance. March still wears the royal seal of winter,
                                sleighing remains the very best and will till its close. Hay pressing will again be
                                renewed the coming week. Time is always passing and pressing. The active, the
                                far-seeing, the enterprising and unselfish portion of humanity, can find" something in
                                the great universe of mind and matter to do, something that is good and useful and
                                "Something that is lasting that forever will endure." The saw mill that has rested in
                                silence the past summer will soon become a busy factor in home industry. Broom handles
                                will be manufactured and much more work of the sawing kind will be perfected in days to
                                come. Brother Henry Hollister of enterprising fame is abiding with vis, and is a trusty
                                helper in guiding the Sonyea Craft; his vigorous spirit is a great blessing in our
                                family; we value his presence, and prize his inspiring ministration. In our Sunday
                                services and in our daily avocations he is ever helpful. Brother Clark Coburn recently
                                moved from his old house to a new one, a house not made by hands but one secure in the
                                heavens where moth and rust can not corrupt, nor thieves break through and steal. Br.
                                Clark has been a member of Society for five years. During his membership and life in the
                                Community he was ever interested in performing some good and never wearied in well
                                doing. G. D. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/> Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> We have been favored with a brief visit from Eldress Elizabeth Downing of Union Village,
                                Ohio. We are always glad to welcome her to her old home. She was called here to see Sr.
                                Sarah Weatherford, <pb n="92" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> an associate Eldress of Eldress Adaline Wells,
                                who was vei-y ill, even unto death, but now she is pronounced out of immediate danger.
                                Our kind physician and brother, W. F. Pennebaker, has safely carried many patients
                                through La Grippe as well as other ills. We feel thankful that so many of our aged ones
                                have been spared to us. March came in with storms, but in a day or two all was as calm
                                and pleasant as May. The sun shines brightly, the grass is springing up, the birds are
                                chirping their matin songs of praise, and who could fail to appreciate a home amidst
                                such surroundings. Our district school has just finished its winter term and the
                                interest has been kept up thoughout the session. The Trustees have been faithful to the
                                teacher, and she in turn faithful to the children. On the 22nd of Feb., the school held
                                suitable exercises. Recitations, select readings and songs appropriate to the birth,
                                life and death of Washington, who paved the way to freedom, and liberty of conscience.
                                We have much, indeed, to be thankful for, in this home of liberty, and we pray that no
                                cruel war shall again devastate our fair land. We love our little missionary and we
                                trust many may, from its perusal, become converted, and "Cease to do evil and learn to
                                do well." With these notes please accept our love and kind wishes, and may we realize
                                that "All things work together for good to them that love God." M. C. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/> South Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> Mar. 1892. Elder Henry:We write you of the death of our good Br. John. We are sorry that
                                he has been taken from us. Weather here is extremely inclement. The spring birds have
                                been with us, but now have all left and we cannot see where they have gone. We are
                                pleased with the Manifesto land hold it as the true Standard Bearer of our religious
                                faith. J C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Record, for Feb . 1892. Highest Temp, during the mo. 48. Lowest " " " " 4. Mean
                                " " " " 23.3 Total Precipitation " " 1.79 in. Total Snowfall, " " 16 in. 1ST. A.
                            Briggs.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health notes from Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/> HEALTH NOTES FROM MT. LEBANON.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/> Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">The Culinary Department.It is essential to good health that meals should be eaten at regular
                            intervals; and in the orderly round of our Shaker life, we never vary from stated hours.
                            Breakfast is at six in the summer, half an hour later in winter; dinner at twelve and supper
                            at six. We have a light and airy kitchen, divided into cooking, baking and dining rooms;
                            good soapstone ovens, heated with coal from beneath; a first-class range with large copper
                            boiler; suitable cookingutensils, mostly agate ware, Avith plenty of hot and cold water in
                            the various departments, and this makes our work comparatively easy. We have also another
                            model arrangement, a cooling room on a level with the kitchen, which saves much backache and
                            weariness, and answers the place of a refrigerator, or down-stairs cellar. It is built of
                            stone by the side of the coal receiver; around the sides are coils of iron pipe through
                            which the cold mountain water circulates, and passes into two Portland cement sinks where we
                            set away the food in earthen crocks, and we find it keeps much better than when put on ice.
                            There are some board shelves at the side, which we find very convenient. For a family of
                            between fifty and sixty members, we have six sisters and a little girl to perform kitchen
                            duties, and one to attend to company; no other work is required of them outside the culinary
                            department; these change with others every second or third monthfrom four to six weeks is a
                            term. It lessens the labor considerably not to <pb n="93" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> cook meat, and after
                            some twenty years' experience we find we can do as well without it. There are veteran
                            vegetarians among us who have worked many years in the field of reform, but with most of us
                            it has been a gradual growth. Our breakfast usually consists of oatmeal or wheat mush, baked
                            or boiled potatoes, tomatoes cooked with milk and bread crumbs, warm apple sauce and Graham
                            pie. Dinner is more varied. There are three kinds of vegetables, sometimes the addition of
                            soup, plain fruit sauce, either pie, pudding or other desert. SupperBoiled rice with sugar
                            and cream, or mashed potato, tomato stew, apples baked or in sauce, and preserves. We
                            frequently have the addition of fresh creamed cottage cheese or crisp celery; the latter we
                            think good for the nerves. The green stalks of celery are cut up in small pieces and cooked
                            until tender, which takes several hours. Season when half done; when ready to take up add a
                            little thickened milk or cream, and put on nice fresh slices of toasted bread. The water in
                            which the potatoes are boiled makes a delicious soup, by adding a little egg batter, a pinch
                            of parsley, seasoning, and a cup of milk, cream, or a bit of butter The best part of the
                            potatoes is usually thrown away. We put up three or four hundred gallons of tomatoes every
                            season. Cooked in various ways and eaten in moderate quantities; we consider them a
                            healthful article of food. Our chief method is this: To one quart of boiling tomato add one
                            quart of cold milk (if it all strings together do not be alarmed it will boil out;) when it
                            foams up well, add some rolled cracker or bread crumbs, let it boil the third time, season
                            to the taste with salt and pepper, add a little cream or butter and serve boiling hot from a
                            covered dish. "Anti-fowl potpie" (as one of the sisters has named it) is made thus: Prepare
                            the dough as you would for bread, either Graham or white; when it is light cut it off in
                            small pieces and put it on a steamer in a tightly covered cooker; it takes about an hour and
                            a half to steam; have ready a gravy made of hot water thickened with drawn butter, or cream
                            and flour paste; season to the taste, and add a little fresh parsley, put the dumplings in a
                            large dish and pour the gravy on them. Tea and coffee are used on our table in moderate
                            quantities, no one taking more than one cupful at a meal; some prefer hot water. Hot
                            beverages should be made of freshly boiled water; if it has stood in the tea-kettle over
                            night it is not fit for use. iSTo one can well abstain from a meat diet unless he has good
                            bread. We have three kinds on the table at each meal; white bread, also unleavened and
                            leavened bread made of unbolted wheat, which is washed and ground fresh at home every week.
                            Warm rye and Indian bread, baked six hours in a covered iron dish is nice for break Last, so
                            is oatmeal made into bread. With a moderate amount of skill and an interest in hygienic
                            methods of preparing food, a good housekeeper can place on the table many appetizing dishes
                            cooked without fat or soda, and the more one becomes accustomed to plain food, the finer
                            grows the sense of taste, and rich greasy viands become alike obnoxious to sight, palate and
                            stomach. Would it not be better for the poor to save their hard earned dollar and buy fruit
                            for their families and thus prevent a feverish condition of the blood engendered by too much
                            heavy food? We are increasing our fruit crop every year. Grapes are especially wholesome,
                            and they are much cheaper and more palatable than drugs. Sickness.We have but little serious
                            sickness in our family, and seldom call on the doctor. People are not as strong physically
                            as were their ancestors; but those who come among us in ill health usually improve in a
                            short time. Especially is it so with children; we have taken some very frail ones who have
                            grown stronger; some must always battle with inherited tendencies to disease, but if they
                            live strictly moral lives, and adhere to hygiene laws they will live more <pb n="94" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> comfortably. Great good is attained in this direction by fortifying the mind
                            against the ills of the body, and rising superior to them. We have not had a fever in the
                            family for thirty years. Judicious water treatment, simple massage, and the use of hot herb
                            drinks, are our methods of cure in cases of sickness. Heat and Ventilation.Three of our
                            large houses are heated by steam. The dwelling containing the sleeping apartments breathe.
                            In the roof, directly over the stairways at each end there is a large Archimedian
                            ventilator; they are kept open in warm weather, but are closed in winter because cold air
                            comes down in large quantities. In the base boards of the rooms are ventilators; also over
                            the doors and in the chimneys. From the outside of the house directly back of the heater
                            there is an aperture which conveys air up through the tubes of the radiators, so there is a
                            warm as well as fresh atmosphere to breathe; it is a circulating current all through the
                            room: the cold air is drawn from the floor and heated, so we have no cold feet nor
                            overheated heads. Two inch width boards are used under the lower part of the windows; this
                            gives a current of air between the sashes, and there is no draught. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charlie's faith" TEIform="index"/> CHARLIE'S FAITH.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "Father and son stood side by side Gazing o'er fields and orchards wide, Acres
                                    of corn were turning white, Withering fruit trees met their sight. "Charlie, my son"
                                    the farmer said, "Look at the corn, the wheatall dead. Why must I lose my fruit, my
                                    grain, Which might be saved by one day's rain." Thoughtful a moment looked the boy,
                                    His bright eyes beamed with holy joy, 'Father, you told me once to pray For what I
                                    wanted, day by day. Many an answer's come to me When I've in earnest bowed the knee.
                                    Ask what you will it shall be done, Said our High Priest and God's dear son. "I'll
                                    kneel right here beneath the treesLet my petition with the breeze Rise to the ear of
                                    the Holy One, Maker of earth, the stars and sun. He'll hear the prayers of those who
                                    strive To seek their crowns beyond the skies." Upward he gazed, a smile of hope
                                    Lighted his features as he spoke. "Jesus send down the cooling rain, Else this
                                    year's toil will be in vain. Elias prayed and thou did'st hear, Hear us, whom thy
                                    dear name revere." Rising, he said; "the rain will come Ere sets to-morrow's burning
                                    sun. Father have faith, do not despair, But lift to God another prayer." Speedly
                                    came the boy's reply, Darker became the summer sky, Thunder and lightning, pealed
                                    and flashed, Charlie his parent's hand then clasped. "Father," he said, "See prayer
                                    has power To bring from heaven this cooling shower. Nothing we need will be denied
                                    If by Christ's precepts we abide." Dear Youth and Children:I think you may learn a
                                    lesson of faith in God, and of the power of prayer by reading this simple narrative.
                                    It is beautiful. I wish all had as strong faith as this little boy. Though some
                                    expressions in the piece are objectionable, like appealing to Jesus, yet underneath
                                    there is a deep feeling of confidence and trust in a higher power. It is to this
                                    faith and trust I would have your minds center. External things will readily attract
                                    from the internal, unless the whole being is absorbed with a desire for spiritual
                                    things. Faith and a sweet confiding trust in the Order of God wTill bring them.
                                    Plentiful showers of blessing will fall from the bright world above sufficient for
                                    every lamb of the fold. But how simple and child-like you must be to receive them,
                                    and above all you must be pure and clean. Then when you ask for a Father's
                                    protection and a Mother's love, and are willing to bow the knee, as did this child
                                    of faith when he prayed for rain, you will receive. Let Christ rule the stubborn
                                    will and subdue the obdurate heart in you, then every spiritual and temporal
                                    blessing will be yours to enjoy. And as you stay the flood-tide of youthful
                                    temptations by relying upon this higher power and keep in control every passion of
                                    nature by a daily cross, in time the world will look upon you as Saviors of the
                                    race. All power will be given you. Even the winds and storms obeyed himour Elder
                                    Brotherbecause the Christ was in him. So may this quickening spirit permeate and
                                    abide with you, is the sincere prayer of your true friend and gospel Sister, Anna
                                    White.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal" TEIform="index"/> [From the Boston Journal.]</bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/></byline><pb n="95" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bountiful" TEIform="index"/> BOUNTIFUL.</head><p TEIform="p"> "They shall hunger no more, neither thirst any more; neither shall the sun light on them nor
                            any heat"Rev. vii., 16. Canterbury, N. H. 1890. Divoto. O let us not hunger nor thirst, The
                            fruits of the spirit abound; The riches of immortal truth I'm reaping on hallowed ground. My
                            gospel companions, we'll rise, Rejoice in the light of today; We see as never before, How
                            God doth his mercy display.</p><pb n="96" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.
                        </head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological JOURNAL AND SCIENCE OF HEALTH
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The March number of the Phrenological JOURNAL AND SCIENCE OF HEALTH Is more than usually
                                supplied with interesting personal or biographical sketches. The editor speaks feelingly
                                and judiciously regarding the late Duke of Clarence and Avondale, and is rather pointed
                                in his condemnation of those who show a fire-eating spirit as concerns the Chilian
                                affair. We have a striking portrait of the Chilian president and views of Valparaiso.
                                The eminent observer and writer, Dr. J. R. Buchanan, is well depicted by Charlotte F.
                                Wells, and a lively summary of the Del Sartes and their works, with two admirable
                                portraits, is given by Carrica Le Favre. Practical Phrenology is well filled. A new
                                series of "Hits" is introduced, that show the success of such publications. Florence
                                Hull contributes a very valuable paper on Governing Children. Lady Somerset, the
                                temperance advocate, receives appropriate notice. In Science of Health we find some
                                Deductions from Anthropometry, Massage Treatment, Typhoid, The Scotchman's "Parritch,"
                                etc. The new department of Notes in Anthropology contains a list of items that is very
                                valuable for their solid information. The fact of the increase of insanity among
                                Southern negroes since the civil war is very significant. Price $1.50 a year, with
                                Premium Phrenological Head, $1.65. Address Fowler &amp; Wells Co., Publishers, 777
                                Broadway, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Sort of Digital Depression. Did you ever notice, when a man smites
                                his thumb with a hammer, while putting down a carpet under wifely supervision and
                                criticism, how quickly he thrusts the bruised and throbbing member into his ready mouth?
                                writes Robert J. Burdette in the March Ladies' Home Journal. People think it is because
                                the application is soothing. But no: it is an involuntary movement, same as winking. The
                                man cannot help it. Nature knows what the man would be apt to say under the
                                circumstances, and so she has provided him with a stopper, and has ordained that
                                whenever he hits his thumb hard enough to hurtand it doesn't take very much to nearly
                                kill a man when he is doing something he doesn't want toby a sort of interlocking system
                                the thumb flies into his mouth and stops him up, so that he can't say anything. Some men
                                whom you and I know should be provided with an extra thumb which they might carry about
                                in their hand all the time it wasn't in active use. It would be a great thing, wouldn't
                                it?</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life of Charles H. Spurgeon" TEIform="index"/>Life of Charles H. Spurgeon
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The "Life of Charles H. Spurgeon," which is offered by John K. Hastings, 47
                                Cornhill, Boston, in connection with The Christian, for $1.50, well deserves the
                                attention of all our readers.The Golden Rule, Boston, Mass., March 10, 1892. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's
                                Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hall's
                                Journal of Health for March. Contents: La Grippe; A queer Matrimonial Mart; Talks with
                                Dr. Mandeville; Animals that never see daylight; What salt will do; Treatment of a cold
                                ; Prevention of Influenza; Women and their duty; Thought and Brain; A Swim in Salt Lake;
                                What ants can do; Peculiarities of the pulse, etc., etc. Office 340 West 59th. St., New
                                York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A HUCKSTER OF RELIGION. "Talmage, to-day, employs very nearly the same methods as
                                those employed by Beecher; but one must not for a moment place him on the same plane,"
                                says Walter Blackburn Harte in the March New England Magazine. "In spite of his
                                occasional sensationalism Beecher was in earnest; he did not flinch from uttering his
                                convictions, though perhaps the opposition he encountered in orthodox quarters imbued
                                those convictions often with a militantism they could have dispensed with. Talmage is a
                                mere poseura mouth- He is a shepherd whose work in the Lord's vineyard, and the
                                sensational, Sunday papers, makes one wonder whether the Lord is fully cognizant of his
                                self-called servant. Talmage is a huckster in emotional religion; a man whom Barnum (who
                                was not such a great humbugas he claimed to be, giving, as he did, everybody the worth
                                of his money) could have claimed, and perhaps did, as a brother." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy. March. Contents. Treatment of the Sick; How Doctors Differ;
                                Anti-vaccination; Proper use of Words; Isms and Dogmas; Hygiene and Therapeutics; Light
                                for the Consumptive; A way to make the difficult matter easy; Cause and Effect; Dietary
                                Department, etc., etc. Dr, T. V. Gifford &amp; Co., Kokomo, Ind.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ferguson, Caty" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Caty Ferguson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Caty Ferguson at Shakers, N. Y.. Nov. 18, 1891. Age 55 yrs. 8 mos. and 15 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foster, Laura" TEIform="index"/>Laura Foster
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Laura Foster, at Enfield, N. H., Feb. 5, 1892. Age 87 yrs. and 11 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Granger, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Anna
                                Granger
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Anna
                                Granger, at Shaker Station, Ct. Feb. 21, 1892. Age 83 years. Eldress Anna has lived at
                                the North Family during seventy-three years. Faithfulness, frugality and purity of
                                spirit, are among the many virtues that adorned her long and well spent life. S. C. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eastin, John W." TEIform="index"/>John
                                W. Eastin
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 
                                John
                                W. Eastin, at South Union, Ky. Mar. 6, 1892. Age 11 years. Br. John has been a member of
                                the Community for IT years. J. C.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
GALLERY OF BIDA ENGRAVINGS.
One hundred Descriptive Scenes from the Life of Jesus, by
Rev. Charles H. Dodd.
One hundred Full page
Engravings unrivaled in
elegance of illustration, by
Alexander Eida, the Converted Jew. It is exceedingly attractive and one of
the finest art works ever
published.
No. 1. In extra fine Garnet and olive cloth. Design
embossed in gold. Top
edge gilt                  $2.50.
No. 2. Full morocco,
Design embossed in gold, all
edges gilt                4.00.
No. 1. and the MANIFESTO will be sent to any
address one year for   $1.75.
Address    THE MANIFESTO, East Canterbury,  Mer. Co., N. H.
OVER FORTY
"Brilliant"   Poppy, packet ...........................15c.
Hoses, Waban and DeGraw, both for............50c.
6 Rare Chrysanthemums,   each 50c.; set 3.50
6 Choice Geraniums, each 25c; set............1.00
Sweet Corn  "Golden Nugget,'-1 packet.........15c.
Any one not now a subscriber can have
Vick'S Magazine one year free, who orders $1 worth from us before May ist.
NOVELTIES.
Garden Pea "Charmer," packet.....................15c.
Potato " American Wonder," per lb,............30c.
Pansies, our superb strain, look almost human   packet.............................................50c.
Extra choice, packet.......................................35c.
JAMES ViCK'S SONS,
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
DO YOU KEEP BEES
If so, send your name and address for a
Free Sample of the AMEEICAN BEE
JOURNAL Weekly32 pagesOne
Dollar a year.
Thomas G. Newman & Son,
PUBLISHERS
CHICAGO, ILL.
LIBERAL and MUSICAL.
"Shaker Music" is the title of a book
of 250 pages, beautifully printed and neatly bound. It was published by the Believers of Mount Lebanon, N. Y.
We will send the Manifesto during the
year 1892 and a copy of the Music Book,
to any address for $1.25 postage paid. If
desirable the Book and paper may be sent
to different persons.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury, N. H.
1892
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking Powder.   Highest of   all   in  leavening   strength.Zatesl
United Stales Government Food Report.
Royal Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall St., N. Y.
LIFE OF C=H.SPUh!btu"r
By the noted Author, Pastor, Journalist
and Platform Orator,
RUSSELL  H. CONWELL.
5OO Pages,
ELEGANTLY  ILLUSTRATED,
ONLY   $1.50.
75c. OUTFIT FOR 30c.
Greatest  Chance you
ever had to Make Money.
EVERY CHRISTIAN FAMILY WANTS HIS LIFE.
It is full of intensest interest from beginning
to close.   It is a mine of valuable information, and filled with the purest thought, keenest
wit, richest experience and truest philosophy.
It WILL PAY YOU to WORK for US.
Remember we allow our agents to give to
every one who buys this book, which retails
for only S1.5O, a tree six months' subscription to "The Christian," which was
Mr. Spurgeon's Favorite Paper,
he having had it for years, and having said of it:
" 'THE CHRISTIAN' is the Best Paper that comes to me."
It requires? a salesman to sell some books;
this one anybody can sell, because the people
want it, and the premium we give (The
Christian) makes the work still easier.
The people are anxious to have the book,
and  wait -with  the money to pay for it.
WILL YOU TAKE IT TO THEM?
Sample Book, prepaid, and " The Christian "
six months, for only $1.6O.
HP" Best  Terms        Ig^Act  Quick!
To Our Agents.     |    No Time to ].ose!
The first to send 30c. (postage) for Outlit, gets
the territory.   Address JOHN K. HASTINGS,
Mngr. of "THE CHRISTIAN," 47 CORNHILL, Boston, Mas*.
(Preserve this, it may not appear again.   Mention this paper.)
JOHN
F.   STRATTON
CELEBRATED
SON'S
BANJOS,
Importeriofand Whole
MUSICAL    MERCHANDISE,
violins, Guitars, Banjos, Mandolines, Accordeons,
Harmonicas. &c, all kinds of Strings, etc.etc.
43 A 46 Walker St.,                     NEW 10KK.
I     you wish to advertise anything anywhere at
any time, write to GEO. P. ROWELL & CO.,
No. 10 Spruce St., New York.
EVERY one in need of information on the subject
of advertising will do well to obtain a copy of
'Book for Advertis ers," 368 pages, price one dollar.
Mailed, postage paid, on receipt of price.    Contains
a careful compilation from the American Newspaper   Directory of all the best papers and class journals ; gives the circulation rating of every one, and
a good deal o f information about rates and other
matters of advertisin g.   Address ROWELL'S ADVERTISING B UREATJ, 10 Spruce St. N. Y.
Every-Day Biography.
Containing a collection of nearly 1400
brief Biographies, arranged for Every Day
in the Year, as a Reference for the Teacher,
Student, Chautauquan, and Home Circles.
By Amelia J. Calver. A large handsome
vol., nearly 400 pages, handsomely bound;
price, $1.50.
"Every-Day Biography," is an outgrowth
of the increasing popularity of observing the
birthdays of noted people.
Nearly 1500 names are here found, representing sovereigns, rulers, statesmen, founders of colleges, institutions, etc., besides
pioneers in every art, science, and profession.
To Chautauquans it will prove invaluable,
since every week will bring some name to
mind prominent in that universal study.
This work will be found a valuable addition to any library or collection of books.
Agents wanted to introduce this, and take
orders for it. Sent by mail, postpaid, on receipt of price, $1.50.    Address,
P0WLEE & WELL'S CO., 775 BK0ADWAY, New York.
The Life and Gospel   Experience of
Mother Ann Lee.                   Price 10 cts.
Address H. 0. Blinn, East Canterbury, U. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>