<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1202" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18820201" TEIform="date">February 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25- 48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p> Vol. xii. FEBRUARY. No. 2. MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. '' Blessed are they that hear the word of
                        God and keep it." Shaker Village, N. H. 1882. Canterbury, N. H.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="25" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Responsive" TEIform="index"/>RESPONSIVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith</byline><p TEIform="p"> '¦'•Not authority for truth, hut truth for authority."—Lucretia Mott. "The despotism of
                            custom is on t' e wane ; we are not content to know that things are, we ask whether they
                            ought to be." Among the many good things with which the November Manifesto, comes freighted,
                            I see we again have the Bridegroom and Bride with us; excellent company, and a fruitful
                            theme, although the article seems to be more of a correction of my humble self, than an
                            answer to the questions propounded. Personally, I can afford to let Father Time correct the
                            fact of my being young ; and if he will only deal as kindly with me, in his endeavors to
                            convince me of the fact, that because I am young, therefore I cannot be "clear, logical, and
                            concise," he will probably do it by some other method than by simple assertion. I accept
                            always the spirit of correction, but I respectfully demur to the assumptions and conclusions
                            reached by my good Elder in rectifying what he deems my mistakes ; he misapprehends me, in
                            thinking that it was "unintentional" on my part to use the following ; "The cause seems to
                            be that they restrict their ideas, beliefs, and rewards to very narrow circles ; a few are
                            chosen, a few saved, one man or one woman controls the salvation of the world, or one set of
                            men only, possess authority to interpret all truth, especially any new truth." My Elder says
                            "exactly so,' quoting Jesus to sustain the clear cut position that Jesus and Ann attained,
                            and gave the ultimatum of progress, thus reproducing the infallibility of Catholicism. I can
                            see nothing in the Spirit of Christ as manifested in Jesus and Mother Ann to sustain any
                            such claims. Jesus says, "If I be lifted up I will draw all men unto me."—"He that believeth
                            on me, the works that I do he shall do also, and greater works ;" and how very different is
                            the Spirit of John, xvi. 12, <pb n="26" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 26 SHAKER MANIFESTO. 13, 14. "I have yet
                            many things to say unto you, but ye cannot bear them now, Howbeit, when he, the Spirit of
                            Truth is come, he will guide you into all truth, for he shall not speak of himself, but
                            whatsoever he shall hear, that he shall speak ; and he will shew you things to come, Pie
                            shall glorify me, for he shall receive of mine, and shew it unto you." This means
                            progression. It seems to me that a bigoted spirit is both illogical and unchristian. Truth
                            is universal in its action, and no man, or class of men hold the keys to lock or unlock her
                            treasures. If to thus believe is to "forget that wide is the gate, and broad is the way that
                            leadeth to destruction, and many there be that go in thereat," then I am sublimely ignorant.
                            I concur with correction No. 2, in so far, that, if new men are needed in every age, "they
                            should be those who will more vigorously prosecute the work of our exemplars," and they can
                            safely build upon the foundations laid. As I have no desire to destroy these foundations I
                            decline the honor of striving after this "world's greatness and applause ;" believing with
                            Jesus that in the truth are hid and will be continually revealed, "all the treasures of
                            wisdom and knowledge." It must be that sometime, we shall have to do something besides lay
                            foundations, these being only preliminary to the building, which will rise story above
                            story, and is composed of many living stones, many brethren and sisters, of whom Jesus and
                            Ann were only two stones, albeit the chief corner stones. The corrections of Nos. 3, 4, and
                            5, touch the vital question at issue, viz ; our religion has nothing to do with matters
                            pertaining to this life, and the inference is drawn that whosoever meddles with these things
                            is "weak and defiled ;" it strikes me as not a very true or graceful assumption. "Like
                            causes produce like effects," and if Jesus Christ was the product of the training of Israel
                            for 3000 years, the same causes will produce in us like effects. He says, "Jesus under the
                            law was not our exemplar." What does this mean? When was Jesus law-less, not under the Law ?
                            Would it not be well to remember that it was after his baptism by John, after he was
                            "baptized by the Holy Ghost and fire into a resurrected life," that he made his memorable
                            declaration as to the value and stability of the Law and its hold upon his followers ? There
                            is nothing to prove that at any subsequent period of his life, he classed the Law as a dead
                            letter. Elder H. quotes me saying, "Obedience to the higher law abrogated the lower penal
                            law," then says "very true, whence then the necessity of blending with that which is
                            confessed to have no existence?" "This," he says, "is no play upon words but stubborn facts
                            ;" either I have been very unfortunate in conveying my ideas, or else my words are very much
                            misconstrued. In speaking of the higher law of the Mosaic dispensation, as distinguished
                            from the lower penal law, which was framed to punish infractions of that higher revealed
                            law, I did not refer at all to the Spiritual Law of Christ's Kingdom. This lower penal law
                            of ceremony and punishment, added because of transgression— necessarily disappeared (to
                            him,) when a man like Jesus came, who did not transgress, but fulfilled the higher law of
                            the Mosaic dispensation. Of course he did not need to embody in his kingdom the <pb n="27" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 27 lower, penal law. He had no need for it, it was made for
                            the transgressor; but the higher laws of life, pertaining to the earth, to generation, food,
                            property, health, government, the land etc. in fact, every thing upon which depended human
                            life and comfort, was as much to be embodied in His Spiritual Kingdom, as it was in the
                            Mosaic, for the Law, as a foundation for the Gospel, was to go forth from Zion,—to where?—to
                            the new earth, for the earth no less than the heavens was to be redeemed. In mistake No. 6.
                            virtually the same question is up, only while Elder II. says that Mother Ann's followers do
                            accept in its fullness, all the culture of the Mosaic work, as embodied in the testimony and
                            life of Jesus Christ. I understand him to say, as an exponent of Her, that it is all
                            foolishness. I wonder how long such arguments as he puts forward in regard to diet, will
                            pass current among religious people for truth. It is exactly the argument of the medical
                            profession in regard to Generation and Celibacy. Please note. "Every thing is poisonous in
                            too great quantity, and nothing is poisonous with proper quantity. What is considered the
                            most virulent poison, sufficiently diluted, becomes harmless." This diet question, with its
                            concomitants was not only "agitated in Christ's day," but before, and ever since, and always
                            will be, until settled by experience, truth, and science. In handling mistake No. 7. he is
                            combating things of his own creating. I made no statement to warrant any such construction.
                            I simply said, it is inconsistent to conclude that the restraints put upon generation under
                            Moses, ended in the Gospel with total extinction ; and then to say, that the restraints put
                            upon food, property, etc. under Moses, ended in the Gospel, in doing exactly as the Gentiles
                            do in food, property, and agriculture. In mistake No. 8. he says, "the removal of the flesh
                            showed the weakness of the law, because the law supports the flesh." This is strange
                            reasoning. A law is framed to restrict, chasten, and condemn the flesh in all possible ways,
                            and then forsooth, it supports it. How? There is no need of blending the two in the sense he
                            speaks of, viz, the Flesh and Spirit, for God never yet destroyed in one dispensation, the
                            good and truth of the preceeding dispensation. Perhaps my good Elder thinks it a simple way
                            of disposing of great prophetic longings, the utterances of Prophets and Sages of past ages,
                            and the revelation of John on Patmos ; to call it a "lullaby," and the old song of Moses ;"
                            nevertheless, there are sincere and intelligent millions who long, hunger—for its
                            consumation. In the discussion of truth, age disappears, personality or triumph is of no
                            importance. In logic, as in Christ we are all one. I wish to disclaim all love or desire,
                            for religious controversy, but with every intelligent being, I am anxious to know all truth,
                            and it seems to me, very childish to stigmatize, as weak, and disloyal, a brother who may
                            hold opinions differing from my own. If I might summarize my conclusions on these matters,
                            they would run as follows ; on the one side, Jesus Christ and Mother Ann revealed all truth
                            ; gave us all that we need ; all God has for us ; no need of any further progress. If this
                            be true succeeding Elders hold all truth. This truth consists in living a celibate life,
                            obeying without question, authority, then you will save your soul. <pb n="28" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 28
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. Your body may suffer the torments of the damned ; disease and weakness may
                            cripple useful lives ; egotism and bigotry may assume place and position; property may blind
                            justice ; trade corrode the heart; selfishness dictate against a divine gift; human will
                            shape government in its own interest; our crops may rot and fail; pestilence and pests wipe
                            out of existence human beings and human toil, but with all these the Gospel has nothing to
                            do. On the other hand, the Gospel of Christ is for all nations, kindred, tongues and peoples
                            in all worlds ; it is broad, liberal and saving. Jesus is only our Elder Brother, Mother our
                            Elder Sister ; they did their duty grandly and faithfully ; they spoke the truth committed
                            to them ; did their work, and occupy a position in the plan of salvation, from which nothing
                            can dislodge them. They only showed what other men and women would do when baptized with the
                            same Christ Spirit, and actuated by the same devotion to truth and progress. They never
                            closed the door to new truth. This Gospel is one of Peace, not only to the warrior, but to
                            the whole earth, to all animated creation. It will conserve the welfare of the body as well
                            as of the, soul; it will deal mercy in preference to animal slaughter ; will teach us to use
                            all the blessings of life for human comfort; it will teach equality of the sexes in the
                            administration of government ; show us that every age and epoch must have new revelations of
                            truth to act upon, that these new truths are as essential as fresh air, or new machinery, or
                            the thousand and one improvements which Progress has given us since Jesus lived. It teaches
                            us that Christ is a Spirit that can reach the hearts of all men and women, baptizing them as
                            it did Jesus and Ann. Does this deny Christ? So far from it, it exalts him into a far more
                            potent power for good ; gives him a reverence so much superior to authoritative reverence,
                            that all the tenderness and devotion of sincerity, responds to its call. This Spirit says to
                            men and women associated under its organization. Ye are all Brethren and Sisters together,
                            no one per se greater than another. These Brethren and Sisters choose the best and most
                            unselfish to lead them, and they acknowledge the divine unction upon whomsoever the choice
                            may rest; these leaders are not infallible men and women, who can do no wrong ; but are the
                            uplifted ensign of a consecrated, devoted body of human souls, and responsible to that body,
                            legally and morally. In this Spirit there is room for growth, not less obedience, but more,
                            because of clearer conceptions of duty. There is room for a home to be developed wherein
                            heaven on earth may be realized; a home where brethren and sisters can dwell together in
                            unity, and reach out after every good thing ; where the greatest shall be least, or servant
                            of all. May God speed the day when we shall actualize more of this home, where there shall
                            "nothing hurt or harm in all God's holy Mountain ;" wThere even the "pots in the kitchen
                            shall have Holiness unto the Lord written upon them;" where all men and women shall be
                            taught of the Spirit, needing neither Priest or infallible Pope; building up no more
                            Catholic Systems, but a brotherhood and sisterhood in God. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The babbling of the idle, is like a fool at play" TEIform="index"/>The babbling of the idle, is like a fool at play
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The babbling of the idle, is like a fool at play.</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let each one save a soul" TEIform="index"/>LET EACH ONE SAVE A SOUL</head><p TEIform="p">What gem so precious as the soul? For what such earnest toil, To bring above the miry clay
                            And place on virgin soil? Here lies the labor of the good, The work for all the strong, The
                            wise, the patient, who have stood For God and Him alone. Let Zion search her ranks
                            throughout For latent strength and power, To save a soul, each one for one, Lest guilt lie
                            at the door. The talent given is only loaned, Its use we should restore ; If not improved,
                            to be returned And given where there's more. Awake, anew 0 virgin band, And labor while 'tis
                            day, Our further call to understand, Our farther work obey. The lukewarm souls who trust and
                            wait Are not of blessing sure ; But he who works may also eat, And such shall heaven secure.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beginnings and issues" TEIform="index"/>BEGINNINGS AND ISSUES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. HoLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> As the germs of a forest may be contained in a bushel of seed, so the issues, or lost things
                            of life arise from small beginnings and gradually increase by the addition of many
                            tributaries, any one of which may seem a trifle, but the sum total is no trifle. It has been
                            said,—"Man is a bundle of habits." Every moment of our waking hours strengthens some habit
                            already formed, or sows the germ of a new one. The child that is properly born and tutored
                            feels dependent and grows in obedience to guardians and superiors. But in youth, which is a
                            transitional period, the germs of mental, moral and religious growth combine to form
                            understanding, which then begins to unfold as a preparation for a more enlarged sphere of
                            action. During this period of intensity the mind is often elevated on the summit of hope and
                            expectancy, from wherce it surveys the future with rapturous gaze. The vision is strongly
                            colored by the passions which are then vigorously pushing forward toward maturity. But like
                            an untrained steed, the passions must be subdued and inured to useful labor before they can
                            profit their owner or yield any abiding happiness that will satisfy the soul,—a happiness
                            which will be brief or long according to the quality of the labor, and the motives that
                            incite its performance. Experience shows that the day dreams and air built castles of
                            untrained youth are illusive in the extreme, and when pursued, often end in bitter
                            mortification and disappointment. The youthful mind is in a plastic state, and easily
                            moulded, if it has been properly trained ; for its infant purposes are like bones in the
                            gristle, but as habits form, they assume a control which is not easily changed. Evil habits
                            like laziness, begin in cobwebs and end in chains. Good habits also spring from little
                            things, that may be compared to seeds. Such are the influences contained in the counsels,
                            precepts, restraints and corrections of parents, teachers and friends ;— and in the
                            decisions of the judgment, formed by a consideration of consequences in the mind itself.
                            Frequent reflection upon ones own conduct, its effect upon others, and a comparison with
                            instruction received, and with convictions of duty, is a habit fruitful of good, and tends
                            largely to improve and perfect character. <pb n="30" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 30 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            Whatever instills virtuous principles and impresses the youthful mind with sufficient power
                            to restrain its wayward tendencies, and pursue an upright course of self-denial, will be to
                            future happiness and prosperity what learning a trade, is to the business of life. Correct
                            moral habits of self-restraint, began in childhood, are of more real value to life than any
                            endowments of wealth or of education, because the latter, however, useful as aids, cannot
                            confer essential happiness, which is the desire of every creature.- Integrity, truthfulness,
                            industry, philanthropy, temperance and self-control, are the ingredients of a good and
                            therefore a peaceful and happy life. Though good habits are easier changed at maturity than
                            bad ones, that which at first felt like the restraints of bondage, when it has become
                            habitual, is like a wall of strength and protection against the snares and temptations of
                            the carnal life, and turns at last to ornaments of beauty and glory. In this way the law of
                            the Lord becomes a sure fortress into which the righteous run and are safe. Ungoverned
                            children are void of gratitude because they learn to love only their own pleasures, and the
                            ungratefiq are ever unhappy. Those who are wisely governed, love their instructors in
                            proportion to the benefits received, however grievous may be the restraint or correction in
                            the time of its application. Whom the Lord loveth He chasteneth, and scourgeth every son
                            whom He receiveth. There is strength in the reproof of a friend, and chastening, even from
                            an enemy, often braces the energies to new resolves to overcome Indolence, which is one of
                            the greatest foes to happiness, and the progenitor and nurse of many others, all of whose
                            kisses aXe dangerous in proportion to their sweetness. How important that the seed sown be
                            carefully selected, for when sown, the seed of the Thistle and Deadly Nightshade may seem as
                            harmless as wheat, but what contrast in their products and compensations. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Veteran's offering" TEIform="index"/>A VETERAN'S OFFERING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Olive" TEIform="persName"/>Olive Brown</byline><p TEIform="p">The following was presented, a few days since, by one of our dearly beloved sisters, in a
                            Sabbath, devotional meeting. It contains so much love, light, and Christian Knowledge that
                            we thought it worthy of publication. Wishing our little paper, God speed, sister Olive
                            presents her offering, which is her soul breathing after a long and successful experience in
                            the Believer's life.—A. D. Dear Brethren and Sisters :—My thoughts, this evening, are upon
                            the many good things I would like to say, and upon the offering that I may be able to
                            present. It is not that I may occupy any portion of time allotted to me as a specialty, but
                            rather to be able to do good. For more than sixty years it has been my happy lot to be a
                            privileged worshiper in our devotional meetings. Never have I grown weary, or failed to find
                            spiritual support therein when I gave my mind to seek for good; and though I may not very
                            often give expression to what I feel, it is not that I have found the strife of no avail, or
                            have been disappointed in the daily reward of crossbearing. In reviewing my life with its
                            many blessings, I find I have so much for which to be thankful, that it seems an urgent duty
                            upon me, to speak often of <pb n="31" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 31 the good way of the
                            cross of self-denial. I wish that those who are just entering the strife, or who are bearing
                            the burden in "the heat of the day," may be encouraged in the good work. It has been my aim
                            to live an active life, spiritually, and equally so, temporally. I counted the cost at the
                            beginning knowing that to possess the righteousness of a spotless, virgin life, I must
                            sacrifice all that was in opposition to it; by so doing, the seeming cross has been
                            pleasure, "the yoke easy, and the burden light;"—and as age creeps over me, I do not find
                            the way cheerless, or the fruits of my labor, "nothing but leaves ;" for within my heart
                            there is a wellspring of peace which nothing can destroy. As one among you that serveth, and
                            as one who delights in the prosperity of a cause which has been "a savor of life unto life"
                            to me, I have a burden which I often wish to express. The question frequently arises in my
                            mind; Are we truly, the followers of Christ that we may possess the sacred seal of
                            discipleship which is, unselfish love for each other. Are we kind and forbearing ? Do we
                            possess that charity which thinketh no evil, and which we all want extended to us ? Is it
                            our meat aod drink to search for and speak of the good in our brethren and sisters ? Would
                            we report an unfavorable or unpleasant story concerning them ? This subject has been a
                            burden upon my mind, and I always feel to rebuke myself if I have, in the least, made a
                            report that tends to the injury of any one. Of course, there are sometimes, duties to be
                            done, but we ought to treat the failings of each other as though we were speaking of our
                            own. This we are not apt to do in public, and it often takes much conscientious courage to
                            find as much fault with ourselves as we deserve. Again, I ask, is there anything which will
                            produce such a spiritual dearth as unkind or unpleasant feelings existing in the assembly?
                            Did we ever read, or hear of a spiritual renewal among any denomination, where the unkind
                            were not brought to repentance, and real or imaginary enemies, became reconciled? I am sure
                            I can call for witnesses those who have been inhabitants of our home for years, and have
                            seen in every spiritual awakening, Sweet Peace descend like a dove in our midst, and the
                            voice of slander hushed ; verifying the truth of the proverb, that "When a man's ways please
                            the Lord, he maketh his enemies at peace with him." This dear friends, is the burden of my
                            mind. I love you with a love grown strong by the realization that we are toiling for the
                            prize of "salvation from sin." My loving interest for Zion can never cease. I shall live
                            with the hope and prayer that the spirit of the Lord may dwell with us, uniting us as the
                            heart oi one. May it comfort the aged, strengthen those who with wearied step, carry the
                            burdens of today, encourage and nourish the young who have not grown into the blissful
                            knowledge of the truth of the cross of Christ. I ask in my prayer, O that I could do more
                            for a cause that gives me peace and salvation, and prepares me for the company of the
                            redeemed, when the gates of earth are closed upon me, and I enter the new spiritual life
                            beyond. Your gospel sister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Engaged in thy duty, fear no danger" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Engaged in thy duty, fear no danger.</p></div2><pb n="32" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American institutions: where they are defective, and the remedy" TEIform="index"/>AMERICAN
                            INSTITUTIONS: Where they are defective, and the Remedy</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>Antoinette Doolittle</byline><p TEIform="p"> To the Editor of the Brooklyn Eagle: America is a great land, with her millions of
                            inhabitants, her boundaries reaching from sea to sea, her trade and traffic almost beyond
                            the limit of computation, and her vast resources inexhaustible. Her heavily laden ships of
                            commerce are seen upon many waters. Her schools, seminaries and colleges are numerous, and
                            are yearly expanding and widening their doors to admit more students ; and as fast as one
                            class finish their course of studies, and vacate their seats, others hasten to fill them. If
                            lessons of real virtue and integrity should be learned and accompany all upon their egress
                            from the popular institutions of learning, our country would be filled with bright,
                            intellectual stars, studding the moral universe. As it is, thousands upon thousands emerge
                            from the seats of learning, and launch out upon the world with cultured intellect, and to
                            them, and to incoming generations, the nation looks for perpetuity and the maintenance of
                            her free institutions. When we look over her large territories and compute the number of
                            inhabitants of home born and those of foreign birth who have found our shores, and taken
                            shelter under the American Government, and pledged allegiance thereto, the question is often
                            asked with profound and prayerful solicitude : LiShall the republic live, and her free
                            institutions be preserved?" Her governmental machinery has already been simplified, until it
                            is vast in proportions and moves as many wheels within wheels. If anything occurs to clog or
                            hinder the action of one of those wheels, the jar is felt, and causes agitation, if it does
                            not throw the whole machinery into disorder and confusion, and result in revolution. In the
                            past as in the present, this momentous burden and weighty responsibility rests upon the
                            shoulders, and is intrusted to heads and hands of male rulers. The voice of woman is not
                            heard in legislative halls—only as a special favor upon certain occasions, and by special
                            request. Why this bondage and servitude on the part of woman ? Has she no heart to feel ? Is
                            she destitute of reasoning powers, and unable to plead her own cause and the cause of her
                            down trodden and oppressed sisters, who do not find redress from wrongs inflicted upon them
                            at the tribunals, where male rulers alone preside, judge and decide? A change must and will
                            come in this respect. Woman possesses latent powers that need to be brought into action,
                            both for her own benefit and the good of humanity. Presidents and Government officials take
                            their wives with them to the Capitol of the United States, but when they enter the executive
                            chambers and legislative halls, it is more like gayly plumed show birds, to attract
                            attention, and to listen to a finely framed speech from the lips of some eloquent male
                            orator, than of feeling the weighty responsibility of helping to guard the nation's honor,
                            and of co-operating with her brother man in sustaining and framing just laws. When woman is
                            taken into the national councils and allowed to speak and act her part, she will think more
                            of developing her mind than of decorating the outward form. Virtue is said to be a plant of
                            slow growth. So we may think in regard to <pb n="33" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 33 the
                            rights of woman. Ever since Eden was despoiled of its beauty and glory by transgression and
                            man's confession of his weakness, "She gave and I did eat," and a voice was heard saying :
                            "He shall rule over thee," man has exercised his power over woman to a marked degree. On the
                            American Continent as dense forests have been cleared and wildernesses turned into fruitful
                            fields, and the march of civilization has been onward and upward, and religious freedom
                            proclaimed through the Declaration of Independence, the iron chains which still bind and
                            hold the female part of the population in the basest ignorance and servitude in the far East
                            have been melting away as the ice bound streams yield to the rays of the sun in Springtime.
                            What a notable change has been wrought in this respect within the last two decades. At that
                            time, with the exception of Shakers and Quakers, it was of rare occurrence that woman's
                            voice was heard, even from the freest platform then erected. Now, women lecturers are
                            passing from village to village, and from city to city, and even to foreign lands, giving
                            free expression to their thoughts concerning the problems of human life and its destiny, and
                            are treated with courtesy. True, popular theologians and ministers of the gospel, according
                            to St. Paul, strictly adhering to his opinion that woman's voice should not be heard in the
                            churches, would not dare to allow a woman to occupy their pulpits, even for a limited space
                            of time while they go to the seaside to recuperate, or to some hill or mountain to inhale
                            the healthful breezes, and ward off malaria, or other physical diseases. Plow would it
                            answer, seeing such is the case, if the female portion of the population who feel interested
                            in the matter should withhold their contributions from the renowned chxirches, and create a
                            fund of their own, and build a few small churches, wherein they could feel at home and give
                            expression to their own religious views and convictions, if they have any, irrespective of
                            the opinions or dictation of man ? Never mind if the steeple is omitted ; perhaps the Lord
                            will be as well pleased without the tall spire as He wrould be with it. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul travel, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>SOUL TRAVEL. No. 6</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Millions of people seem to move in this world as though entirely unconscious of the
                            possession of &amp;, soul! Their thoughts appear concentered upon, and riveted in, the
                            concerns of this present world ; their words are the expression only of animal desires,
                            troubles or enjoyments, and the delights of sense in an individual, selfish, and narrow
                            capacity; their acts manifest only a love of and desire for selfish pleasure and animal
                            comforts, and, like the beast, when the measured portion to the individual is consumed, make
                            a push to obtain and consume the portion allotted to a fellow creature. Soul emotions,—as
                            sympathy for a fellow being, love to another, philanthropy that desires the happiness of a
                            companion, or the human family at large, appears unknown to them ; to these realities of
                            genuine humanitarian life they are, seemingly, as insensible as a statue ; consequently, to
                            these, the idea of a soul travel, is as foreign as opposite polar attractions. <pb n="34" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. A language understandable by this class of the human
                            family, if such may be called human, must of necessity, be something addressed to their
                            animal sensibilities, either painful or pleasurable, hence, to these, at present, we do not
                            appeal. But, to those who live conscious of soul, and spiritual conditions, we would desire
                            to present, thoughts that kindle, and words that burn ! The goal to which genuine soul
                            travel is progressing is the dominion of soul over the entire active domain of life,
                            including the physical, mental and spiritual arenas, and the conformity of all, to the will
                            and purpose of the Divine Mind, so that in all the directing energies of the soul, its
                            interests shall have a singleness of purpose, to elevate and conform human destiny to the
                            dignified and glorious pattern of the heavenly intelligences, fashioned in the image of God!
                            For untold ages, the masses of mankind seem to have been chained to the car of self-love,
                            self-greed, and narrow self pleasure ; this has impeded the car of true heavenly progress,
                            manacled the hands of philanthropy,, and fettered the feet of benevolence, so that they
                            could not pass beyond the boundary line of "mewm et teum." Shall earth forever be the "pent
                            up Utica" of the dark death gorge of self? May neither the thunderings of the Law from
                            Sinai; the wailings of the Lone Wanderer of leathern girdle locust and wild honey
                            proscription and penetential baptism ; the bloody sweat prayers, in humanitarian agony and
                            plaintive pleadings of the reviled "King of the Jews" and "Father of the New Creation ;" the
                            blood shedding racked and torn suffering martyrs sacrifices, and examples of selfabnegation
                            ; the prison bound, rared, and persecuted Mother Spirit—the Bride of the Lamb of God ; nor
                            yet the gentle knockings for admittance, and the soft melodious strains of the harps of
                            pleading ministering angels from the heavenly shores of Paradise. Shall not a combination of
                            all these forces, at length move man from his fortress of selfish animalism, and give his
                            soul a birth into a new, heavenly, and angelic life? Is the tortoise like shell of
                            animalism, or the salamander scales of bigotry and selfishness so impenetrable that neither
                            the fires of judgment, nor the waters of the sweet river of life that makes glad the
                            inhabitants of the City of God can reach the incased human soul, and emancipate it from its
                            tomb of death ? Have the Children of earth no access to the angel whose vial holds the
                            panacea for these • sufferings ; these woes of unnumbered ages ? A writer has recently
                            remarked. "The Church seems to totter to its fall; the soul is not preached ; almost all
                            life is extinct; what hold the public worship had on man is largely lost, it ceases to keep
                            a grasp on the affections, of the good, and the fears of the bad." 0 let the Earth open her
                            mouth in prayer, let the Heavens distill the dews of repentance, and rain down the manna of
                            God's tender melting love ! O ye angels who fly in the midst of Heaven, having in your
                            censers live coals from off* the altar of God's baptismal furnace, we Dray thee, in thy
                            merciful and , tender kindness, kindle in the souls of men a desire for salvation from the
                            perils of sin ; ift them up out of the prisons of corruption, into the light and love of
                            Heaven ! Bestow some heavenly amulet to 34 <pb n="35" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 35 save
                            from the desolations of sin's betrayal ! Display some Divine charm which shall irresistably
                            win, to the safe portals of the blest, souls who are now sailing on the passion stormed sea
                            of life! Light the way of soul travelers, that they may. see how to choose "¦Wisdom's ways
                            of pleasantness" and love to walk in "all her paths of peace." Those Soul travelers, who, in
                            the journey of life so move that all the passional impulses of the lower life motives are
                            .subordinated to the dictates of purity, peace and heavenly righteousness, whose loves are
                            fixed upon objects and purposes above mere selfish interests, and directed to the well doing
                            and well being of the human family, who so command the emotions of the heart—the internal
                            man, that its every desire and motive is to do good to fellow man, and all the inferior
                            creation :f God, those souls are journeying to a vitalizing, eternizing heavenly purpose.
                            This order of soul travel so governs the tongue that no evil speaking, backbiting, revenge,
                            hatred, animosity or unki::dness, finds expression but its language is pure, true, and
                            lovely. This travel so dictates the mind that its intuitions and inspirations are
                            conformable to God's thought, and humanities' heavenly weal, so that, in truth, the
                            individual lives in those heavenly conditions of physical, moral and spiritual well being,
                            and well doing, which elevate, ennoble, and bless the whole race of mankind. By such a soul
                            traveler, life's daily toils, in all the minutia of servitude, in social, conventional, or
                            religious communion, one pure motive, directs every pulsation of life, and that is, the
                            happiness of the whole human family. Such a Soul traveler is cheerful in giving up time,
                            life, treasure, all, all that can contribute to the good of the human race, and culminate in
                            the glory of God, and rejoices in the sacrifice. These Soul travelers inherit the
                            fulfillment of the heavenly promise. "Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see
                            God." And these not only see God, but walk with Him in their hourly occupations. His spirit
                            energizes every effort in their life's eventful journey. Such have not one life for God and
                            another for the world, but every footstep is a walk with God ; in Him they live, and move,
                            and have their being; these may sing with the poet. "God is never so far off As even to be
                            near, He dwells within, our spirit is, The house He holds most dear, To think of Him as by
                            our side, Is almost as untrue, As to remove His throne beyond, Those skies of starry blue.
                            So while the worldling's worldly self, Is homeless, 'lorn and weary Missing his joy,. I
                            walked the earth Myself God's sanctuary!" Faber. Zion, Be thou peopled with souls like these
                            and thou wilt be the city of God, where saints find heavenly rest, and angels disseminate
                            the blessings of the Heavenly Parentage. Let earth be blest with such .soul travelers, . and
                            the Kingdom of Heaven will be found thereon. Such souls stand on Ezekiel's visionary "sea of
                            glass mingled with fire,"—the word of truth. Seen and known by each other as Servants of the
                            living loving God. Thus mutual confidence would be reciprocated, and the reign of God's love
                            be perpetual and supreme. O Earth, Earth ! Lift up thy soul in prayer for the advent of this
                            glorious dispensation of God's mercies. And O ye Heavens condescend thus low to stoop and
                            listen to the pleadings of thy prophetic Heritage. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="36" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watch, trust and wait" TEIform="index"/>WATCH, TRUST AND WAIT</head><p TEIform="p">While yet one star shall glimmer in the sky With soft, pale gleaming light: Continue thou to
                            watch, with wakeful eye Throughout the night. And if the darkness deepeneth, watch on. Faith
                            will be sight, [ing Soon comes the morning; then the questionWhat of the night? Though like
                            the mouldering embers of afire, Which long hath ceased to burn, Doth lie thy hope, thy love,
                            thy pure desire. Still trust, still yearn. Trust God, humanity,—trust gentle Love, Her
                            constance learn, And by thy trusting, unto thy dear Hope Shall life return. Afar may seem
                            the longed for, precious goal, But let not toil abate ; [soul, Let patience, meekness,
                            prayer possess thy Ah ! learn to wait. Weep not though hearts unsympathetic grow, God's love
                            is great, And He hath promised that all things shall be For those who wait. Canaan, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes from the life experiences of mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>NOTES FROM THE LIFE
                            EXPERIENCES OF MOTHER ANN LEE</head><p TEIform="p">Two of the brethren having business relations with a merchant in Albany, were unjustly
                            accused and wronged by him. One of the brethren made his complaint to Mother Ann,—"That man
                            has abused us ; and I will prosecute him." Mother replied :—You must not touch the law. He
                            that takes the sword, shall perish by the sword. If you take the law you will lose the
                            blessing of God. Trust in God. What! build the things that God will destroy? Go in faith and
                            God will deliver you. The law shall go forth out of Zion, and the Avord of the Lord from
                            Jerusalem, is the law in which you should trus^. Trust in that law and God will deliver you.
                            Mother and the Elders took unwearied pains to instruct and enlighten the Believers in the
                            things of God, and in the path of their duty. It was at Watervliet in 1781 while Calvin
                            Harlow and others who were gifted as public speakers were assembled that Mother addressed
                            them as follows : Hear ye my words ; It is but a light thing to speak words to the souls of
                            men, when compared to the duty of helping them. Those who help souls, must have the spirit
                            of Christ to administer to them : They must take upon themselves the infirmities of those
                            they would help, and be able to bear for them, and to suffer with them. As several of the
                            brethren and sisters who had been on a visit to Mother and the Elders, were about to return
                            home, Mother said—"Go and tell your brethren those things which you see and hear. The blind
                            receive their sight, the lame walk, the lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear, the dead are
                            raised, and the poor have the gospel preached to them ; and blessed is he whosoever is not
                            offended in me." In her instructions and labors for the increase of the gospel among the
                            young believers, she spared no time nor care. To those who came to see her she would
                            say,—The gospel is the greatest treasure that souls can possess ; go home and be faithful;
                            put your hands at work and your heart to God. Beware of covetousness, which is as the sin of
                            witchcraft; if you have anything to spare, give it to the poor. Mother's industry, prr.dence
                            and economy were equal to her zeal, humility and charity, so that, in all things she was a
                            pattern of godliness, and showed herself to be a Mother, indeed, in every good word and
                            work. As the Lord Je- <pb n="37" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 37 sus set an example of
                            righteousness to all men, and instructed all believers to follow his footsteps in order to
                            find acceptance with God ; so Mother Ann set an example of righteousness to all women, and
                            instructed all her followers to take up the same cross, in order to find their relation with
                            Christ. Do your work, said Mother, as though you had a thousand years to live, and as you
                            would if you knew you must die tomorrow.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My brother, my sister and mother" TEIform="index"/>MY BROTHER, MY SISTER AND MOTHER</head><p TEIform="p">Whoever takes up the teachings of Jesus, for careful perusal, cannot fail to become
                            interested in the manner in which he deals with every subject. Take, for instance, the
                            fiftieth verse of the twelfth chapter of Matthew, and see how clearly he illustrates the
                            relationship that belongs to those who would become the children of God. Whosoever doeth the
                            will of my Father which is in heaven the same is my brother and sister and mother.—Matt.
                            xii.—50. Nothing could have been more significant ; nothing could have been said that Avould
                            have given a clearer representation of the position which Jesus held as a teacher of a new
                            and living way. The old way, the cherished worldly way belonged to the Adamites and is said
                            to have had its origin in the garden of Eden. Its whole being formed the paradise of the
                            Jews. All the disciples belonged to this peculiar family of Hebrews, and under the
                            discipline of the Mosaic law had been taught to manifest a great regard for their parents.
                            "Honor thy father and mother," said Moses., "that thy days may be long in the land which the
                            Lord thy God giveth thee." In the establishing of the law there had been a peculiar
                            recognition of the duties that were to be enforced in the domestic relations. Indeed, the
                            law seems to have been given expressly for an earthly existence, and for the welfare of the
                            body. It defined what they should and what they should not eat and drink, and established a
                            system of sanitary rules having direct reference to the clothing and to the ablution of the
                            body. It was equally as explicit and as imperative in the relations which should be
                            sustained between the parents and children. The willing and obedient were the only class who
                            were promised the blessings of the land of Canaan. Jesus had grown up under the influence of
                            this rigid law. His obedience to his parents and care for the discipline of his own life was
                            so well ordered that the apostle thinks it worthy of a special notice. He was subject to his
                            parents, says St. Luke, and increased in wisdom, and in favor with God and man. Thirty years
                            of the life of this Carpenter's son had already passed when he began to preach. His baptism
                            by John soon followed, after which he was called God's beloved Son. From this date the
                            relationship which he had sustained, assumed a new form. He was now to be known not only as
                            the son of Joseph and Mary, but he was in an exalted degree to be denominated the first born
                            son of God. To do the will of his Heavenly Father now became the whole object of his life.
                            Joseph had been lost from sight for several years and his brothers and sisters, are reported
                            by the evangelists as <pb n="38" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 38 SHAKER MANIFESTO. not very friendly to his
                            religious mission. His mother, however, was with him till the crucifixion. The text we have
                            chosen was spoken at a time when Jesus was addressing a large body of people. Some one had
                            informed him that his mother and his brethren were anxiously waiting to speak to him.
                            Perhaps they had not realized, as yet, that he was divinely commissioned to establish a new
                            and spiritual relation where the fatherhood and motherhood was to be centered in God. These
                            brethren had only known him as one of the family of Joseph and Mary. Pie was, to them, Jesus
                            the first born son of the carpenter. He had at one time made a singular remark, when much
                            younger in years, and asked them if they did not know that he must be about his Father's
                            business. Seemingly, making Joseph and Mary of but little consequence. Nothing farther,
                            however, is known of his life for several years, or until the time of his baptism. Another
                            opportunity was now offering itself, and being fully baptized into the spirit of the
                            resurrection order, he gave an impressive lesson, which was not misunderstood by the
                            multitude, nor by his own natural relation. "Where is my mother" said he, "and where are my
                            brethren?" Risen as he had into the spirit of eternal life, all this relationship of the
                            flesh, the inheritance of the old Adamic order, had been left to perish where it
                            legitimately belonged. Stretching forth his hand towards his disciples, he said, "Behold my
                            mother and my brethren are those who do the will of my Father in heaven." Nothing could have
                            been more clearly expressed or brought more directly to the point, in demonstrating the
                            relations of the earthly order and that of the Kingdom of God. It may not have been
                            understood by the narrow and selfish minds of that day, as indeed, it is not understood by
                            the narrow and selfish minds or this day. The universal love of God through the life of
                            Jesus Christ must be lived to be known. There can be no compromise. One order belongs to the
                            world and has its relations in the flesh, while the other belongs to Christ and has its
                            relations in the spirit. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Libbey, William G." TEIform="index"/>WILLIAM G. LIBBEY</head><p TEIform="p">was born in Lowell, Mass. Oct. 3, 1820. He obtained the privileges of a common school
                            education, and made himself a useful member of his father's family. At the age of twenty two
                            years he entered service in a whaling expedition on the Pacific Ocean, where he met with
                            some thrilling adventures, as recorded in the narrative entitled, "Autobiography of a
                            Quondam Sailor." [See Shaker Manifesto of 1878.] In the Spring of 1844, he left his
                            sea-faring occupation and visiting the Society of Shakers in Mer. Co., N. H. ; became a
                            member of the fraternity, and a consistent Christian, to which he steadfastly adhered
                            through life. In Oct. 1848, he was appointed associate Elder at the Second Family, in which
                            place he remained till June, 1852, when he returned to the Novitiate Order. In 1858, he was
                            appointed to the Elder's Order of the North Family, which office he filled till Feb., 1864,
                            when he again moved to the Second Family to live with Elder Eli Kidder. In Nov. 18G7, he
                            returned to the North Family and was appointed to the Order of Elders and to the charge of
                            the Family. In 1870, he moved to the Church Family, and in July 1871, again moved to the
                            Second. In June, 1874, he returned to the Church. April, 1875, he made a journey to South
                            Un- <pb n="39" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 39 ion, Ky., and resided in the Church Family
                            till Feb. 1876, when he again returned to Canterbury. During all these years of official
                            duty, his life has been one of integrity and uprightness. He was a dear friend and father to
                            those of younger years. "None knew him but to love him." He was genial and affable and very
                            unassuming. His conversation was chaste, and his conduct discreet as became his profession.
                            We regret our loss in parting with him visibly, but pray that his chastened spirit may still
                            be with us and aid us in our efforts to promote and extend the cause of genuine
                            Christianity. A few days before his decease, he commenced the following letter to the sister
                            who had taken charge of his wardrobe ; but being unable to use the pen, he dictated the re"
                            mainder. Shaker Village, N. H. Dec. 1881. Beloved Sister, A ;—I intended, long ago, to have
                            written a response to your beautiful Christmas gift of last year, but have neglected it from
                            time to time, and now it is too late. But as sister A. steps in I will ask her to finish my
                            sheet,—to express in a few simple, words, my deep affection and regard for you and for all
                            the young sisters whom I have seen strive so nobly, to live according to the principles of
                            virgin purity, and thus emulate the teachings of the good founder of our faith, Mother Ann
                            Lee. I have watched your mental and spiritual growth with a great deal of interest, and
                            nothing will add more to my happiness, in the life which I am to enter, than to realize that
                            you remain true to your early vows. My last advice to each one of you is,—Be loyal to the
                            high trust committed to you, for, let me assure you, you will never regret it. My own
                            experience has been so blessed, so full of reward, that I can heartily recommend it to every
                            young brother and sister. I have received so many kindnesses from each one of you, that I
                            would be glad to thank you individually with my latest breath. I shall not leave your
                            interests even though I exchange worlds, so to speak, but I shall be with you in every
                            increasing step of gospel light and testimony. Please accept my love and thanks anew ;
                            impart to every dear brother and sister in our good, "sweet, Shaker home." Remember my love
                            in a special manner to the good sisters, L. A. and J. who are absent. I fear I may not live
                            to make them welcome home. Your Brother. William. We can feelingly add in his behalf:
                            Lamented, respected and honored, Dear Brother William goes home, Bearing the sheaves he has
                            gathered Through faithfulness, wholly his own. Brighter than beams of the morning, Shall his
                            soul's radiance become ; Freer than sunlight, his freedom. More boundless in joy his new
                            home. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of the Shaker sisters having occasion to visit a City of New England, found herself..." TEIform="index"/>One of the Shaker sisters having occasion to visit a City of New England, found herself...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">One of the Shaker Sisters having occasion to visit a City of New England, found herself
                            unprepared for a shower which came while she was passing to the Depot. To protect a nice
                            bonnet, she threw a kerchief over her head which adjusted itself without reference to style.
                            A few moments after this she overtook a company of children on their way to school, who, on
                            seeing her, opened their eyes with astonishment. As soon as she had passed them, she
                            overheard this remark;—"That is a crazy woman, 'cause I can tell!" Whether the others
                            accepted this revelation or not, never may be known. The dear Sister, however, soon left the
                            City, amusing herself over the speculation of the little children. "Never judge a person's
                            character by external appearances."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The general cry is against ingratitude..." TEIform="index"/>The general cry is against ingratitude...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pope" TEIform="persName"/>Pope</byline><p TEIform="p">The general cry is against ingratitude, but sure the cry is misplaced, it should be against
                            vanity. None but direct villains are capable of wilful ingratitude; but almost everybody is
                            capable of thinking he hath done more than another deserves, while the other thinks he hath
                            received less than he deserves.—</p></div2><pb n="40" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker manifesto" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Manifesto</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">FEBEUAEY, 1H83. Change of Office of Publication, The "Shaker Manifesto" for the present will
                            be published at Shaker Village, N. H. All business matters connected with the financial
                            department of the paper will be directed to the,— Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. All other communications may be addressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker
                            Village, Mer. Co., N. H. One Copy per. year, Postage paid, .60 " " six months, " " .35
                            Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid mistakes, those who send money,
                            should write the name of their Post Office, County and State. To One inch, one insertion " "
                            three " " " six " " " twelve " " column ----- ---- $ 1.00 each .75 " .65 " .50 — 6.00 Larger
                            spaces, rates in same proportion.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In loving kindness" TEIform="index"/>IN LOVING KINDNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">As it is generally conceded that "neatness is next to godliness ;" and, indeed, in close
                            proximity to that Divine Light, would it not be well for those who assume to be good or
                            godly, to take special thought having reference to personal cleanliness. To look forward, to
                            grow in knowledge, and to anticipate a union with that which is holy and angelic, is as
                            inherent in the minds of good men and women, as is life itself. It needs no especial or
                            arbitrary law by which to force the individual to action, that he may discard that which is
                            highly injurious to the system or injurious to the soul, for the spirit of intelligence
                            awakens him to this necessity. There has been a time when wicked Christians and dirty saints
                            were regarded with deference, but that same class, at the present day, are generally held at
                            a ruinous discount. In our list of Society regulations we teach that no person should ever
                            wear ragged garments, if consistent to avoid it, and the rule has a salutary effect upon the
                            minds of those who have not, as yet, forsaken the slovenly features of their old
                            inheritance. While it may be admissible and agreeable to the rules of propriety for every
                            one to dress, for the time being, as their occupation would warrant, it can form no excuse
                            for one to be present in company, at the table, or in divine Service with garments that are
                            offensive through want of cleanliness ; and yet this is a common practice in both City and
                            Village. The garments of the majority of worshipers, in almost any church, are noisome with
                            exhalations of tobacco and the thousand and one odors which they readily absorb. A Believer
                            in the testimony of our gospel work which is to redeem us from the careless ways of the
                            world, can never allow himself to do that which will bring a stigma upon the holy life which
                            he las espoused. Goodness and cleanliness must bear a very close relationship, and those who
                            denominate themselves "the chosen people of God" should zealously <pb n="41" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. "exalt their God," that others by seeing the fruits of a clean and
                            disciplinary life may be led to accept the same. We speak of the "great unwashed" and have
                            reference to the masses who have but little regard for their bodies and possibly less for
                            their souls, but to speak of those who have accepted the pure life of Jesus Christ, as their
                            pattern, as unwashed or unkempt, is certainly a very inharmonious association. There can be
                            no reasonable excuse in this day of multiplied conveniences for any person to neglect good
                            sanitary rules which are so conducive to the best of salutary influences. Chastity of the
                            body should be as thoroughly impressed upon the minds of those who are young as is that of
                            purity of spirit. It was a wise remark of the Apostle, when he advised his brethren to
                            present their bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and acceptable unto God. With this
                            enlightened idea of duty as a Christian, we cannot for a moment suppose that the Apostle
                            would allow himself in any habits or practice that would destroy him from being a holy and
                            acceptable sacrifice. Shall we do less than did this man of two thousand years ago?
                            "Whether, therefore, ye eat or drink or whatsoever ye do, do all to the glory of God." The
                            policy of the Manifesto, relative to religious and doctrinal matter, is to adhere closely to
                            revealed truths in accordance with fundamental principles and to keep severely aloof from
                            theological and questionable speculation. Contributions for the paper, for publication,
                            should be forwarded, at least, two months previous to their issue. We hope Believers in all
                            the Societies will promptly respond, relative to furnishing communications for the paper. We
                            also hope they have each and all some good and suitable words to speak to the public. We
                            doubt not, that among the many living spirits there are treasures that, perchance have long
                            laid buried, awaiting the opportunity of publication; if so, let them appear now, on the
                            house tops. We wish all may be blessed with pa tience and wisdom and fortitude. The interest
                            we feel for Zion's welfare should prompt us to do the little we can, kindly and peacefully.
                            We should be struggling to keep a gospel testimony and make some advancement in the Divine
                            life. With this is our ever increasing love for all who are resolved to follow Christ and
                            leave the world behind. We think that the Manifesto should be kept alive and that all the
                            Societies should feel interested in trying to make it what they desire it should be. We
                            should pray for its increasing success, and increasing circulation. The year just passed has
                            been one of the most remarkable for singular and strange events. Storms on land and sea
                            unprecedented in violence and destruction of life and property. Murders and robberies
                            frequent and awful, and crimes of every description, yet while these judgments and
                            calamities are abroad in the earth the inhabitants do not learn righteousness. O that God
                            would send forth angels of conviction throughout the land to convict mankind of their sinful
                            ways and turn their hearts to seek for the peaceable fruits of righteousness.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The soul that suffers is stronger than the soul that rejoices" TEIform="index"/>The soul that suffers is stronger than the soul that rejoices
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sheppard, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Sheppard</byline><p TEIform="p">The soul that suffers is stronger than the soul that rejoices.</p></div2><pb n="42" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God no respecter of persons" TEIform="index"/>GOD NO RESPECTER OF PERSONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, William E." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. E. Williams</byline><p TEIform="p"> That the Nineteenth Century is an age of progress, perhaps no one wall doubt; but
                                notwithstanding the numerous improvements, reforms, and advantages of civilization of
                                this period, many of the errors and evils of the past still remain; while education and
                                refinement has increased at a wonderful rate, still we have not yet arrived at
                                perfection. Man's greatest interest is ; his spiritual,—his eternal; his lesser, his
                                temporal, but, as a general thing the latter has more importance attached to it than the
                                former,—at least in practice, if not professedly. There are thousands calling themselves
                                Christians resting in the assurance that faith saves them: and gives a right and title
                                to heaven; that only to trust Christ without the least regard to following his example,
                                or living as he did, going about doing good, gives a passport to the eternal world. How
                                contrary to the commands of Christ; how at variance with the gospel teachings is much of
                                the doctrine and instruction of the pulpits of today; yes how inconsistant with the pure
                                and noble Christ, who healed the sick, fed the hungry, clothed the naked, and bestowed
                                temporal as well as spiritual blessings. How beautiful the character of Christ, ever
                                ready to cheer by word and action : no pride, no malice or selfishness. Oh!—what a
                                lesson for the churches, and their fashionable congregations, who have virtually closed
                                their doors upon the poor, and expunged from the bible the second chapter of the epistle
                                of James. The grandest type of Christ, to me, is that found in the good Samaritan. How
                                eloquent was that sermon of deeds to the wounded man. The promises of God are
                                conditional; We are told to strive, to seek, to search, to work in the Lord's vineyard,
                                as well as pray, to watch and pray to be not weary in well doing, to be diligent in
                                business, to love one another, to be zealous and active in good works. The gospel
                                declares that profession or faith without love is as sounding brass. Faith and good
                                works are twin sisters, always walking hand in hand. When? oh, when, will the present,
                                hollow, shallow, formal so called Christianity, die out and the pure and simple truths
                                of the gospel, that of love, peace and brotherhood be taught and practiced. God is love,
                                God is a spirit, and they that worship him, must do so in spirit and in truth. Faith is
                                the corner stone and foundation, and must be laid first, before the super-structure is
                                built, good works must follow, or the stone is laid in vain, is but a monument of folly.
                                Welcome the day that ushers in the true and simple religion of love to God and man. As
                                the tree is known by its fruits—so a genuine saving faith, acceptable to God
                                demonstrates itself by a labor of love, when churches cease to respect wealth instead of
                                worth and virtue, when the Church worships no longer broadcloth, silk, jewelry, money
                                and real estate, but extends a welcome to the poor,—looking only to the interest of the
                                souls of men, without regard to social condition, when brotherly love, shall take the
                                place of strife, hatred and envy. Then shall our souls rejoice and looking upwards
                                exclaim, "Glory to God in the highest, and on earth, peace—good will toward men." St.
                                Louis, Mo.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. 1882</head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. 1882 Dear Eldress Polly :— Lovely representative of the Christian
                                faith, we feel more strongly than ever today that you are with us, that today your
                                peaceful influence sheds tranquillity upon our sorrowing spirits and we are thus
                                rendered better able to realize the happy issue of a pious life. We feel the depth of
                                your sympathy, the strength of your love, the wealth of that impartial jnstice which
                                ever characterized your every deed. Here then, let us, Brethren and Sisters on this
                                befitting occasion present a tribute of gratitude due from every one who has shared the
                                society of our beautiful Sister. Accept a united thank offering dear one from your
                                hundred fold relation of brothers and sisters, and be assured, that although we deeply
                                lament that Death has so soon veiled from us the mortal, we shall cherish your <pb n="43" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 43 memory as a sacred reality, and strive to
                                perpetuate your good example by a virtuous activity in every duty. We glory in your
                                success as a Christian woman, as an exponent of the virgin life which you have
                                maintained inviolate for at least forty years. Your reward is freedom from the slavery
                                of sin, your crown immortal life. We may not attempt to enumerate your excellencies nor
                                recount your many good deeds, for, Are they not written upon the tablet of each filial
                                heart? Are they not inscribed on eternal records? In the language of Revelation we
                                repeat, "Blessed are the dead who die in the Lord." Rev. xiv,—13. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Van Valen, Martha" TEIform="index"/>Martha Van Valen</head><p TEIform="p">, at Hancock, Mass. Dec. 1, 1881. Age, 77 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="William G. Libbey" TEIform="index"/>William G. Libbey</head><p TEIform="p">, at Canterbury, N. H. Dec. 25, 1881. Age 61 yrs. 3 mo. and4days. (See p. 38.)</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nowell, Lydia" TEIform="index"/>Lydia Nowell</head><p TEIform="p">, at Alfred, Me. Dec. 31, 1881. Age 73 yrs.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Honey bee's song" TEIform="index"/>THE HONEY BEES' SONG</head><p TEIform="p">What the Honey Bee sings to the Children. I am a honey bee, Buzzing away, Over the
                                blossoms, The long summer day, Now in the lily's cup, Drinking my fill, Now where the
                                roses bloom Under the hill. Gayly we fly My fellows and I, Seeking the honey our hives
                                to supply. Up in'the morning— No laggards are we— Skimming the clover topsj Eipe for the
                                bee, Waking the flowers At dawning of day, Ere the bright sun Kiss the dew drops away. •
                                Merrily singing, Busily winging Back to the hive with the store we are bringing. No idle
                                moments Have we through the day, No time to squander In sleep or in play, Summer is
                                flying, And we must be sure, Food for the winter At once to secure. Bees in a hive Are
                                up and alive— Lazy folks can never prosper or thrive. Awake, little mortals, No harvest
                                for those Who waste their best hours In slothful repose. Come out—to the morning All
                                bright things belong— And listen awhile To the honey bee's song. Merrily singing, Busily
                                winging, Industry ever its own reward bringing. Anon.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little e" TEIform="index"/>Little E</head><p TEIform="p">Little E. was very anxious to write his composition like the "big boys." He thought he
                                would write to sister Mary, "cause she gives me such good things." He found it quite
                                difficult to spell and talked a little too loud inquiring how to spell "twenty five
                                merits." When advised to be quiet, he jumped up and replied; "I can't keep still when I
                                can't spell no better than a skeeter."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True to nature" TEIform="index"/>True to Nature</head><p TEIform="p">At a children's party, little S—was sipping some nice cocoa from a beautiful china cup,
                                bearing the motto; "Love the Giver." A sister bending over her, remarked, S—which do you
                                love best, the cup or the giver? The child was thoughtful a moment then replied; "I love
                                what is in the cup best, I do."</p></div3></div2><pb n="44" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Conn. Dec. 1881" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn. Dec. 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, Conn. Dec. 1881 Beloved Sister E. Your excellent letter came duly to hand. I
                                rejoice to know that your "spiritual parents are the treasures that lie nearest to your
                                heart." Whatever coming time may bring you, whatever may be your circumstances in life,
                                you honor yourself best, when you honor your spiritual guardians. Filial duty is due to
                                them, and it should not be set aside. They will tarry with you but a short time. Oh,
                                make for them a joyful time. Aid them down the the hill of life. Eulogize them now.
                                Keserve not cheering words till they reach the "summer land." Treasure their wise
                                counsel as a rich legacy. They are noble examples of virtue. Strive for what nearness
                                you may attain. Their work on earth will soon close. Many valuable lessons will you
                                learn from them, I know. You will never wish you had done less to make them happy. Make
                                their days golden days. Deal true affection and love to them, as they have dealt to you
                                Be your trials great, and your conflicts many, forget not your gospel parents. Accept
                                their gracious dealing; it will fit you to be "a living stone" in God's holy temple. As
                                you have been led gently by the hand, gently lead, and your reward will be in
                                proportion. Accept my heartfelt desires, and my earnest prayers, for your continued
                                increase in the way of God. Your Brother,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. Dec. 1881" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Dec. 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S." TEIform="persName"/>S.</byline><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. Dec. 1881 My Dear little L. I have just been reading the pretty
                                letter you wrote me last Sunday in which you say you would like an answer. This is not
                                strange, for your little sheet looked very nice, and for the care you took I love to
                                give you a reply. Did you ever see any flowers like .the ones I send you with this
                                letter? I think I hear you say.—"0, indeed, I have. A great many grow under the peach
                                trees north of our house." Don't you like to look into their little faces and see them
                                laugh so sweetly? Ah, my little L.— laughing flowers are pretty but I think good and
                                kind little children are much prettier, Don't you? I am glad you have such a good home.
                                Give my kindest love to your dear teachers as well as to your companions, and remember,
                                my child, that for you to be good and happy is the wish of all your friends. Good bye,
                            </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H." TEIform="persName"/>H.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882 My Darling little Girl ;— What nice little girls I can
                                claim for my sisters. Eeally, I feel quite rich when I count you all mine and ours. What
                                would our home be without the children and what will Heaven be unless you are all there?
                                It is the first month of the New Year, in which I trust you have commenced to be real
                                happy. Happy because you are trying to be good and have such a beautiful home. You
                                wished me to write you a letter. This is such a good wish, that I think it worthy of
                                notice. It does not seem very long since I too was one of the little girls, and can well
                                remember just how pleased I was when receiving my first letter, with my name
                                superscribed on the envelope. I felt quite womanly but acted very much like a child,
                                clapping my hands, and jumping with delight. So you see I know just what such wishes
                                are. I have always preserved my letters many having been written by precious friends who
                                have passed on to their Spirit Home. My ittle sister must learn to be a nice letter
                                vriter, and perhaps you will write one to your sister H.— at some future time.
                                Im&gt;rove all your golden opportunities in your nany happy schools and be like the
                                busy litle bee gathering honey from the fragrant flowers Gather all the good you can
                                fromyour many friends, and lose no opportunity or doing a kind act. I love your cheerful
                                Good Morning, and your pleasant Good Night. I hope you will always be such a good little
                                child that you an meet your sisters with happy expressions, 'hen you will be our sunbeam
                                giving brightness to the home, and carrying joy to the Angels. Please give my love to
                                your faithful Teach <pb n="45" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 45 ers. They are all very
                                dear to me, also take your loving companions by the hand, and give them my love. As I
                                kneel in prayer I ask the protection of guardian spirits upon all of them. Lovingly your
                                Sister, </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C." TEIform="persName"/>C.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Village, N. H. Jan. 1882 Dear Sister H. I am going to answer your pretty letter.
                                I love my nice home, and I mean to keep it by being good. I mean to keep my heart pure.
                                I am real pleased with my little letter. It is the first I ever had, I think a great
                                deal of it. It had such pretty words in it. When I rise from bed in the morning and when
                                I lie down at night I will pray to God, for He will hear me, and if I pray to Him with a
                                right heart He will bless me. I was pleased to write you a little letter. I think I have
                                a beautiful home. I love the little letter you wrote me. I will be a good girl for I
                                love you very much, and I think you love me. From your little girl,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make porridge" TEIform="index"/>TO MAKE PORRIDGE</head><p TEIform="p">The kettle must be clean, as the least roughness would cause the porridge to adhere to it
                                and burn After the kettle is placed on the stove, put into it two quarts of clean water.
                                While this is heating to a boiling point, mix together three table-spoonfuls of bolted
                                wheat flour, and two of indian meal with cold water; being careful not to have it lumpy.
                                This can be avoided by pouring in the water gradually, stirring at the same time to
                                dissolve the flour. When the water in the kettle is boiling, pour in this mixture
                                slowly, for thickening, stirring it all the time. Cover the kettle, and let it boil
                                twenty minutes. Add one half pint of milk; let this boil ten minutes. Then salt it to
                                the taste. 1^ is now ready for use. If more is made than we wish to use at that time, it
                                should be put away in an earthen dish, in a cool place. In order to make a good article
                                of porridge, it should be thoroughly boiled. If not, it has an uncooked taste, which is
                                nut palatable. Vary from this recipe according to the quantity you desire to make.
                                Canterbury. N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruit cake" TEIform="index"/>FRUIT CAKE</head><p TEIform="p"> lbs. of butter. I " " brown sugar. II " " flour. (i U it prrrr« u °P. 1 " " raisins. 1 "
                                " currants. ^ " " citron. 1 cup molasses. 1 teaspoonful soda. .Spice to taste.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our flannels" TEIform="index"/>OUR FLANNELS</head><p TEIform="p">The value of flannel next the skin cannot be overrated. It is invaluable to persons of
                                both sexes and all ages, in all countries, in all climates, at every season of the year,
                                for the sick and well; in brief, I cannot conceive of any circumstances in which flannel
                                next the skin is not a comfort and a scource of health. It should not be changed from
                                thick to thin before the settled hot weather of the summer, which in our Northern States
                                is not much before the middle of June, and often not before the first of July. And the
                                flannels for the summer must not be three-quarters cotton, but they must be all woollen,
                                if you would have the best protection. In the British army and navy, they make the
                                wearing of flannel a point of discipline. During the hot season the ship doctor makes a
                                daily examination of the men at unexpected hours, to make sure they have not left off
                                their flannels.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you have a sore throat..." TEIform="index"/>If you have a sore throat...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If you have a sore throat, slight or serious, a piece of camphor gum as large as a pea
                                kept in the mouth until dissolved, will give relief and oft-times cure. It is said on
                                good authority, if the gufn is used in season, you will never have diphtheria—it is a
                                good preventive.</p></div3></div2><pb n="46" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silo" TEIform="index"/>SILO</head><p TEIform="p">The South Family at Enfield, N. H. built a Silo the past season, nine by eleven feet
                                square, and thirty feet deep. The foundation was laid in the cellar of the barn, of
                                cobble stone, mixed with cement. The walls at the base are one foot thick and continue
                                the same to the height of some seven feet, when they are changed to ten inches in
                                thickness. They are formed of Newark cement, sand, gravel and stone. Doors open into the
                                Silo from the feeding floor above the cows, and also on the same floor where the cattle
                                stand, which makes it quite convenient for those who have charge of the stock. The Silo
                                holds about seventy tons of corn fodder, which was cut up very fine by passing through a
                                machine. While the reduced stalks were being thrown into the Silo, two men were employed
                                to even it and keep on a constant march that it might be thoroughly filled in all parts.
                                A covering of planks was placed over the cut fodder, and on these a weight of three
                                tons. To obtain this pressure, barrels were filled with sand. In five days the mass had
                                settled some seven feet. Tour more tons pressure was now added and at the end of foiir
                                weeks it had settled, in all, fourteen feet. The Silo was closed on the 27th. of Sept.
                                and opened on the 17th. of Nov.. That which was deposited as corn stalks, is now taken
                                out under the name of Ensilage. Although the mass had changed to a much lighter color,
                                yet there were no signs of mould. A peculiar odor escapes from the Ensilage, while to
                                the taste it has a slight acidity. Ten cows were selected and an average of twenty
                                pounds of Ensilage were fed to each one, three times a day. Once each day these same
                                animals were allowed a light feeding of poor hay. The preparation is eaten very
                                greedily, by the cows, and all have given an increase in the quantity of milk. The
                                herdsman was very anxious to have us see "our ensilage calf." Supposing that he might be
                                experimenting on one of his yearlings, we were interested to see the result; but "our
                                ensilage calf "proved to be only some two weeks old, and a splendid little animal. He
                                was full of life and could hardly be quieted long enough for an exhibition. The herdsman
                                thought we need not fear so long as a calf, from a cow fed on ensilage, could give such
                                signs of health and strength. "Great expectations" follow all this, and the eyes of the
                                farmer sparkle at the thought of his coming prosperity. Enfield, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Barefooted horses" TEIform="index"/>BAREFOOTED HORSES</head><p TEIform="p">The question of driving horses barefoot is being seriously agitated in England, and the
                                papers call upon some public-spirited horse-owner to try comparative experiments of the
                                ordinary plan of driving nails into the living substance of the horse's hoof, of the
                                Charlier method of using clamps, and, lastly, of the hoof in natural condition. That
                                iron shoes have been so long used does not necessarily prove them to be indispensable,
                                more than in the case of blinders, without which the last generation scarcely ventured
                                to drive at all. To be sure the weight of experience and custom entitle the existing
                                practice to the benefit of the doubt; but the matter is of sufficient importance to be
                                worth investigating, and it might not inaptly come under the attention of the Society
                                for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.—Our Dumb Animals.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ashes" TEIform="index"/>Ashes</head><p TEIform="p">.<cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Do not allow ashes of any kind to be wasted. It will pay to haul leached
                                        ashes several miles, when one has his own team and a laborer at fair wages. Coal
                                        ashes when spread around berry bushes of any sort, or around grape vines, will
                                        add materially in producing large and fair fruit.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Gardener's monthly" TEIform="index"/>Gardener's Monthly.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="California items" TEIform="index"/>CALIFORNIA ITEMS</head><p TEIform="p">Calafornia furnished the past year, 20,000, 000 oranges, 01,000 boxes of raisins, 1,200,
                                000 tons of wheat. Los Angeles has 6,500,000 grape vines under cultivation.</p></div3></div2><pb n="47" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism at the church congress" TEIform="index"/>Spiritualism at the Church Congress</head><p TEIform="p">By M. A. (Oxon.) With advice and information for Enquirers. Chicago ; Religio
                                Philosophical Journal. The book contains the addresses of several eminent men of the
                                Established Church of England, and may be found very useful to those who wish to make
                                themselves acquainted with the philosophy of Spiritualism.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Skepticism and divine revelation" TEIform="index"/>Skepticism and Divine Revelation</head><p TEIform="p"> . By John Ellis, M. D. ; Pub. by the Author. New York, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boys and thimbles" TEIform="index"/>BOYS AND THIMBLES</head><p TEIform="p">Girls' work and boys' work is not likely to be so separate as it has been. It is now
                                recommended that girls learn to drive nails, to sharpen knives, prune grape-vines; then,
                                sure enough, why should not boys practise with needles and thimbles? No man can, like
                                the writer, live sixty years, without often wishing he had learned to use a
                                sewing-thimble well in his early boyhood, especially if he has gone about the world
                                much. Buttons will come off, stitches will break, and how handy it is for boys at
                                school, for men at a hotel, at a friend's house, indeed anywhere away from home—often at
                                home—to be able to whip on a button, stop a starting rent, and do many other little
                                sewings, without calling on a woman, or perchance sending for a tailor, before being
                                able to appear at a hotel table. One seldom if ever, learns to use a thimble, if this
                                part of his education has been neglected in small boyhood. The writer has travelled a
                                good deal, and at a rough guess he has broken threads at least five hundred times in
                                attempting to work a needle through a button or garment without a thimble. Boys, take
                                our advice, and every one of you learn to use a thimble well before you grow up. Do it
                                this very Winter; it is not feminine to do so. Do it, and if you live long, you will
                                many times thank us for this advice.—Am.Agri.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cleanliness" TEIform="index"/>CLEANLINESS</head><p TEIform="p">As a rule, every boy and girl, every young man and woman who will, can have clean
                                clothes, a clean body, clean face, hands and feet, clean teeth, and a clean sweet
                                breath. Now, in your own mind, contrast cleanliness with its opposite. If we were only
                                seeking to please the eye, the former is worth all the care necessary to secure it; we
                                go farther than this, however. No one can be careless of his person, and unclean in his
                                habits, without producing or perpetuating like disorder in mind, and in all he does. Our
                                bodies are covered with innumerable pores or holes, so small that the naked eye can not
                                see thejn, and through these there is, or should be, a constant passage of effete dead
                                matter. In warm weather we are made sensible of this fact by the perspiration which
                                stands upon our faces and hands, or saturates our clothes. This effort of the system to
                                cleanse itself inside is constant, whether we know it or not. Suppose now that you
                                neglect to keep your body clean outside ; these little holes are stopped, the dead
                                matter which should come out is kept in, the blood becomes impure, the brain wearies or
                                gets lazy, we are lazy all over; then we are slack and careless; we do not like to study
                                or think, even of nice things, and so we are injured all through if we do not keep the
                                surface of the body clean. Of course, while we are at work or play, we get our clothes,
                                face and hands soiled, and sometimes our whole bodies are covered with dust and
                                perspiration; then what a luxury it is to bathe ! It is not bad that we sometimes get
                                dirt on us while doing our duty, but it is bad to be careless and let it remain
                                there.—The Guard</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man who sneaks through life..." TEIform="index"/>The man who sneaks through life...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The man who sneaks through life, unwilling to express his genuine sentiments
                                        through fear of becoming unpopular with the rabble, is beneath the respect of
                                        every intelligent individual, and should be ostracized by all truly intellectual
                                        persons.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Platonist" TEIform="index"/>The Platonist</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="48" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessings of today" TEIform="index"/>BLESSINGS OF TODAY</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. O the blessings rich and many, Which are mine to 2. E'en the path way
                            where I wandered Is illumed with share today! All the fountains of God's goodness Seem to
                            heavenly light! Showing where are error's footprints, Where the open in my way. steps to
                            glory's height. Blessed fruits of sweet repentance, Lead me still, O Righteous Power! Grown
                            while stricken 'neath the rod! Blessed lessons Stengthen when I climb the steep: Guide me
                            through the of instruction daily sowing Sent to lead me home to God! Till Eternal Life I
                            reap.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>