<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2812" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18981201" TEIform="date">December 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">177-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
1898.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL   CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
with large type  and on excellent paper.   Society,  together with  the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
It contains  130 pages and has                                                Price   50 cts.
ILLUSTRATI0NS                            "
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
 THE ALTRUIST.
of the Shakers and their
 Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
The work gives quite an extended ac-  live and work together, and hold all their
property in common,  all the  men   and
count of the Several SOCIETIES, their  women having equal rights in electing of                                        fleers and deciding all business affairs by
organization and general management.        their  majority vote.     50 cents a year;
Price, 50 cts.         specimen copy free.    Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OB1   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of  Believers  in  Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price, 15cts.
DECEMBER,
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
In 1882 somebody told me in London the story of an invitation which Lord Granville, the
Foreign Minister, had sent him.   Lord Granville, in a friendly note, asked him to dinner,
saying at the same time that he knew how
foolish it was to give such short notice "to the
most engaged man in London."   Lowell replied that "the most engaged man is glad to
dine with the most engaging."
*         *         *         *
Lowell was not only the Minister from the
people; he was a messenger to the people.
And he had sense enough and historical
knowledge enough to know that since there
has been an America on the western side of
the Atlantic, the English peoplethe rank and
filehave been in sympathy with the thought
and feeling and purposes of that American
people.    When my brother Charles was in
London in 1863, and the English Government
was acting, on the whole, as badly as it dared
toward the United States, a member of the
Cabinet said to him one day, "The clubs are
against you Mr. Hale, but the people of England are with you."   This was true then; it
was true in the American Revolution; it was
true in Cromwell's timehe has no title
which is more sure than that of the "Friend
of New England."   The same thing is true today.   Now, Lowell never said to himself, "Go
to, I will address myself to the people of
Great Britain," or "The people of Great Britain is one thing, and the clubs of London another."   But because he was the man he was,
he was always glad to meet the people and
the men of the people, and let them really
know what America is.The Outlook.
The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy for Octo
ber has an excellent chapter on Science of the
Life; and the Moral and Spiritual Characteristics; that should be wrought out in the life
of man.   Many other chapters of excellent in
struction, on the subject of life and health
will be found in the same number.   Dr. T. V.
Gifford & Co.   Kokomo, Ind.
A City of Confusion.   The Case of Dr.
Briggs, by Rev. Henry G. Ganss.   The writer
of this little work of some sixty pages has
brought forward a large number of witnesses
to prove the truth of his assertion, and to
show that the Protestant Episcopal Church is
one of "compliant flexibility," and "from
1552 and onward, the English Church was considered by friends and foes alike, to be for all
intents and purposes one with the Swiss
churches of Zurich and Geneva."   The Rev.
Catholic writer assures us that Dr. Briggs has
already entered the Anglican Church, although dismissed from the Presbyterian.   He
then comes forward with this long array of
powerful witnesses to prove that the Anglican Church is so like the Presbyterian, that
the change was accomplished with little or no
ceremony.   As the testimony of these witnesses has been accepted by the author of
the work, he is certainly fully justified in call
ing that church in which Dr. Briggs has
passed, A City of Confusion.   The price of
the book is 15 cts. net.   Address The Ave
Maria, Notre Dame, Ind.
How general the use of photography is coming to be adopted by the modern magazine
as a means of illustration is shown in the announcement of The Ladies' Home Journal that
it is about to publish six new, distinct series
of articles which will include not less than 400
photographs.   The idea of the magazine is to
present one hundred of the prettiest country
homes in America, to encourage artistic architecture;  one hundred of the prettiest gardens, to encourage taste in floriculture; seventy churches decorated for festal occasions
of all kinds such as weddings Christmass and
Easter services, etc.; some forty of the prettiest girl's rooms in this country; twenty-five
floral porches and vine-clad houses; and the
story of the native wild flowers in America
told in seventy-live photographs.   Over 8000
photographers, in every part o* the country,
were employed by the magazine to get these
pictures, and several thousands of dollars
were paid in prize awards for the best photographs.   The choice was made out of over
10,000 photographs received by the magazine.
We present the fourteenth edition to the
public with a due appreciation of the fact
that, from its beginning, the Columbia Desk
Calendar, like the Columbia Bicycle, has
been received with an approbation which has
increased annually.   We thank each and all
of our friends whose contributions grace
many of the following pages, and would suggest to each user of the Calendar that, aside
from its practical adaptiveness to the exigencies of every-day life, it possesses a large
and distinctive value by reason of these offerings.   We regret that owing to the limited
number of days in a year we have been obliged to omit many valued contributions.   Additional copies may be obtained by sending five
two-cent stamps to Calendar Department
Pope Manufacturing Co., Hartford, Conn.
Bethlehem, A Children's Rhyme of the
Olden Time by H. L. Hastings.   This little
book of some sixty pages is just what will
please every boy and girl.   It is a story of the
life of Jesus, and written in a style that will
prove pleasing and indeed very interesting as
do all the writings of the venerable H. L.
Hastings.   The work is neatly gotten up;
printed in large, clear type, and beautifully
illustrated.   Published at 47 Cornhill, Boston,
Mass.
That the spy sent by the United States government to Spain during the war should have
become the guest of Weyler himself, seems
incredible.   Yet there is nothing more true.--><pb n="177" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change the menu" TEIform="index"/>CHANGE THE MIND.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Repent for the kingdom of heaven is at hand."Matt. Hi. THERE is something very interesting
                            in the manner in which John introduced himself to his audience. He came, it is said,
                            preaching in the wilderness, and the beginning of his sermon was a lesson full of life. The
                            crowd that came to hear him must have listened with astonishment as he, without any
                            preliminary words called upon them to repent,to change their minds,to begin to think
                            differently from what they had been thinking, for the Kingdom of God was at hand. There was
                            no time to waste in foolish excuses, nor in telling him what they expected to do. The Jews
                            already understood that they were a people peculiarly favored of God, that Abraham was their
                            father and Moses and the prophets their inspired directors. In all probability, John had
                            made himself familiar with the Jewish history, and did not hesitate to tell them wherein
                            they had neglected to keep the Mosaic Law, and were worshiping false gods. The traditions of
                            men, in many cases, were more readily accepted while the commandments from Sinai had been
                            carelessly thrown aside. In their anxiety to be and to do like the idolatrous nations around
                            them, they had turned from God, only to be lost in their own selfishness. The Douay
                            translation of the text prefers to have John say,Do penance for the kingdom of God is at
                            hand. The Catholics and Protestants are a little at variance in regard to some few Biblical
                            expressions, but the difference <pb n="178" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 178 THE MANIFESTO. is very trifling.
                            Whether we repent or do penace it seems quite necessary that we should change the order of
                            our lives and do better in the future than we have done in the past. One commentator thinks
                            it should read,"Reform because the royal majesty of the heavens has approached." The making
                            of a change in the life of an individual seems to have been the essential feature, as Jesus
                            used the same language on the introduction of his first sermon. John and Jesus must have
                            been very much in harmony in their revival work. Both taught their followers the necessity
                            of leading a new life and of walking more uprightly before God. John not only considered it
                            necessary that his converts should be baptized in the water, but that it was equally as
                            necessary for them to confess their sins. While the Protestant church seems to hold
                            tenaciously to the baptizing of the new convert in water, the last, and we should say the
                            most essential part is wholly neglected. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind Elderess Mary Whitcher..." TEIform="index"/>Kind Elderess Mary Whitcher...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="South Groton, September 14, 1863" TEIform="index"/>South Groton, Sept. 14, 1863.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Kind Elderess Mary Whitcher ;I should have complied with your request long ago and have
                                sent you the little narrative, related by Brother Abijah Worcester, concerning
                                Lafayette, but I now send it with many thanks for former favors and with my best love to
                                all. To render it a story with a beginning as well as an end, and to show the
                                consistency of his being attracted by the inspiration of Believers, I will introduce the
                                matter by a few remarks upon his evidently peculiar organization. Believers in special
                                providences, have long considered that the Marquis de Lafayette was one of the best
                                mediums ever brought under natural inspiration. His physical, moral and circumstantial
                                qualifications were happily adapted to his remarkable intuitive capacity. He came
                                forward in life a young man, uncontrolled by others, before he was of age. He was of
                                noble lineage, great powers, strong mind, ardent love of character, strict moral
                                integrity and his sweetness of disposition, inspired for him love and universal respect
                                in all circles of Society, in an extraordinary manner. He was born to move among the
                                highest aristocracy at the French Court. At the age of nineteen he was in public life;
                                and among the millions of Frenchmen none had more fairly entered the road to earthly
                                glory and honor. Before he was twenty years of age, he was commissioned in due form to
                                hold rank in the French army. It was at this period, that the American Colpnies were
                                struggling for independence. Prince William of England was making a tour through France,
                                near where Lafayette's regiment was quartered, <pb n="179" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 179
                                and was a guest of a French nobleman in that neighborhood. The loquacious English
                                prince, tho among the more liberty-loving Frenchmen, commenced an unreserved
                                conversation respecting the American wTar. Perhaps none at the table but himself had any
                                definite knowledge of the character of that struggle, or the true object the Americans
                                were contending for. With great frankness the duke talked the whole matter out without
                                the least duplicity or covering. There is no believer in inspired cause and effect, but
                                would discern at a glance, that his caution was controlled, his perception beclouded,
                                and his descriptive powers excited, by some higher presiding agency. He is reported to
                                have been very eloquent, candid, and to have represented the Americans an opprest people
                                struggling for liberty, tho he seemed unconscious of what he was doing. Deep down in the
                                soul of the youthful Marquis, lay slumbering a noble patriotism, unbounded liberality, a
                                universal love of his race, and a disposition which would prompt him, when rightly
                                inspired, to sacrifice all, and pour out his life blood like water, in defence of the
                                rights of man. The story of the prince, and the spirit that inspired it thrilled the
                                inexperienced soul of Lafayette like holy fire. It awakened the budding powers of his
                                manhood and aroused the newer and greater qualities of his being into action. In
                                contemplating the man, to many he seemed quickened and transformed into a new being. He
                                suddenly became developt in the wisdom of a Sage, and the courage and daring of a hero.
                                He soon presented himself as the champion to crush out tyranny that human freedom might
                                be erected upon its ruins. He seemed moulded for the very age in which he lived ; his
                                whole career in the new and old world, and the part he took in both, proves it. On the
                                world's wide plane, upon which he acted, no man ever had a better opportunity to show
                                the weakness and blemishes of the human character; but tho moving among the most varied
                                and corrupt masses, and effecting the most fearful overturns, his character through life
                                for consistency, firmness and moral virtue, ever stood untarnished. Lafayette's first
                                interview with Washington, goes far to prove that he was a strong medium, passing review
                                under the severe inspection of a Master spirit, of the same organization. With a board
                                of Officers, he sat down to dine with Washington, and before the hour had expired, by
                                careful observation and deep impression, his whole character was read, and read
                                correctly, by the great American Chief. Tho a child in years, by clear penetration and
                                the impulse of an incomprehensible inspiration, he was attracted to Washington, as to
                                some guardian angel. In him he saw all the qualities of sage, soldier, and civilian for
                                which he longed; and drawing near to the great chief to study there, he was
                                unconsciously influenced by spirits, which ministered to the Father of his Country. We
                                introduce this singular man in this manner, to claim that it was not <pb n="180" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE MANIFESTO. possible for him to enter where any kind of inspiration was
                                agitating human beings, without being excited by it. Among the many confidential labors
                                and missions entrusted to Lafayette, he was sent from Albany to negotiatewith the Indian
                                tribes, to take up the war hatchet for the Americans. In his intercourse with them, he
                                commanded their veneration and enlisted many of the red warriors, in defense of the
                                colonies. It was on one of these missions as he past that way, he called on the
                                Believers iu Watervliet. It was an important period in the inspiring commencement of
                                "the latter day." A time when many were flocking to Mother Ann and the Elders to hear
                                the gospel requirements, and the tidings which brought salvation; a period when all
                                became quickened by the power and inspiration which attended the first witnesses of
                                truth who proclaimed Christ's second coming. When the Marquis entered the neighborhood
                                at Watervliet, where the gathering was fast progressing, he heard of their meetings, and
                                in company with another officer, he called to visit them. Among the Believers there were
                                many who had been connected with the army from the beginning; some who had joined
                                before, and some after Lafayette had entered the service, and as both officers were in
                                second regimental dress they were easily recognized. He entered very quickly the little
                                dwelling where they first held their meetings. Some were conversing, some passing in and
                                out, and some were under singularly inspired operations. Among the most eccentric of
                                these cases were the outward manifestations of Abijah Worcester. He and many others were
                                men and women of strong minds. They had investigated diligently, had received faith
                                correctly, and believed that Mother Ann was inspired by Spirit power to declare to them
                                the most self-sacrificing word of God ever uttered. According to the laws that, control
                                organizations, it was utterly impossible for Lafayette with his singular powers, to
                                enter a place with such surroundings and not feel the state of the atmosphere and the
                                electrical current into which he had entered. Lafayette was tall and majestic and he
                                silently and busily engaged himself in closely inspecting the strange scene before him.
                                True to his mediumistie powers, where the most remarkable inspiration was apparent,
                                there he was the soonest agitated and attracted. Abijah Worcester was at that time under
                                perpetual agitation, jerking, shaking, twisting in sudden convulsion. Seated in the rear
                                of the room, Lafayette past directly through the crowd, and quietly seated himself by
                                his side; to him he devoted his undivided attention. He looked steadily and watchfully
                                upon him, and when agitated and moved,, he would lay his hand upon the limbs of the
                                subject. Thus closely observing him at all times, embarrassed Abijah greatly. He said he
                                felt him to be a powerful spirit, that brought him into great bondage. Wishing to break
                                thisdisagreeable spell, and find relief from the singular freedom thus taken with his
                                gifts and person, he said to Lafayette, "You seem desirous of obtaining this power," but
                                the only answer received was, "It is desirable." <pb n="181" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                                181 By this time, Abijah became so disconcerted, that he suddenly arose and walked out
                                of the door, but Lafayette rose as suddenly, and iollowed him. Determined to make good
                                his escape from Lafayette, he cast about in his mind to determine what he should do
                                next, and finally went down to the barn ; but his investigator followed. The condition
                                of the pursued was rendered more awkward, in every movement the pursuer made, and to
                                make it appear to the latter that he had business there, he seized the broom and went to
                                sweeping the barn floor; taking all the pains to clean and put the place in order that
                                was necessary, but the patience of his inquisitorial friend was not to be exhausted, for
                                speechless and motionless, he serenely waited to see what the next move would be. The
                                sweeper of the threshing floor now started for the house but close in his footsteps
                                followed the man. Resolved to escape at all hazards, he lifted the hatchway and walked
                                down into the cellar, Lafayette still following. The confusion of Abijah at this period
                                of the chase, may be imagined, but not easily described, but resolved upon one more
                                effort to escape, a rude ladder extended from the cellar to the room from whence they
                                started; Abijah, ascended hastily, but as hastily was he followed up by the unrelenting
                                Lafayette. In all these moves, turns and round turns nothing like levity or ridicule was
                                apparent in the man, but a settled determination to learn what power or impulse
                                controlled Abijah and caused these slrange movements. When they returned, Mother and
                                some of the Elders and others were in the room, and by these Lafayette was soon drawn
                                into conversation. Abijah seized a favorable moment to slip away from the company. What
                                followed, he learned from those who were present at the interview. Lafayette enquired
                                what the nature of the religious movement among them was, that brought so many people
                                together. Mother Ann described to him the work Believers were engaged in. That the
                                kingdom of Christ was gradually opening upon the earth, and many were awakened to see
                                their lost con dition, and were coming to judgment. That after passing through a
                                preparatory work they received the spirit of Christ and became inspired with the true
                                light and power of salvation. Lafayette enquired why he could not share in this power as
                                well as others. Mother Ann now under inspiration, plainly declared to him, that his time
                                had not come to share this blessing. She seemed to understand his plea and informed him
                                that a great work lay before him on the earth plane, and that he would have to pass
                                through a wide field of suffering before he could ever receive this gospel of salvation.
                                In after years he may possibly have recalled the words of this singular prophetess, when
                                what was promist under inspiration became a fact in his sorrowful life. It may often
                                have come back to his meditations as he lay bound for years in the cold dungeons of
                                Olmutz and Magdeburgh. However this may have been, in the bloody struggles of the French
                                Revolution or in <pb n="182" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE MANIFESTO. his exile in foreign lands
                                something of this kind was unquestionably revived in his recollection when his spirit
                                took its flight from the noble earth form of the Marquis de Lafayette. Many, I think,
                                remember the startling intelligence that reacht America of his sudden death. After his
                                decease was reported in Paris the first packet that came to America, brought the sad
                                news, but ministering spirits at the time of his death, honored Believers with the first
                                reliable dispatches. The night after his death, one of the Brethren at New Lebanon saw
                                Lafayette and others near him in a vision, and from his own spirit he learned that he
                                had past into the regions of immortality. Daniel's vision was no more certain to him
                                than this was to the more modern visionist. From the impiession made, the dreamer was so
                                confident of the fact, that when he arose with the morning, he stated without
                                qualification that Lafayette was dead. The statement made its impression; the dream of
                                course was remembered ; the date recorded; and when the tidings reacht this continent
                                the statements were proved. Washington was born to break the strong chains which bound
                                the colonies to the old world. Lafayette was led by that power which guided the destiny
                                of nations, to join hands with Washington and pass through this first fiery struggle and
                                be taught by his genius, and to drink deeply of his inspiration. Their leal labors lay
                                in two hemispheres. Washington ever cherisht the same tender recollection of Lafayette,
                                that a father would for a beloved son. In the bloody struggle of the French Eevolution
                                the sympathy of Washington was the strongest power which supported the Marquis; and
                                while suffering through gloomy years of prison life, the toil he had shared and the good
                                he had done under the Father of our Country, were among his most sustaining
                                recollections. After he obtained his liberty, he still toiled for the welfare of France,
                                and died, as he lived, imitating the example of the man he held dear and who had long
                                used his influence to obtain his liberation. On the hard fought fields of the American
                                revolution, he formed a tender acquaintance with the old patriots and heroes, who gained
                                for America her independence. When his tried soul was releast from the fetters of
                                mortality his spirit instinctively turned to his dearest friend Washington, and to his
                                old associates in arms, of revolutionary notoriety in this hemisphere. When his stormy
                                life was closed and he was awakened to realize his entrance into the abodes of the
                                departed dead, the first consolation he "sought, was the sympathy aud friendship of the
                                noble patriots who first found a place in his youthful affection in this far-off nation.
                                Inspiration teaches that many of these spirit friends were then in the work of God in
                                the spirit land. At the head of these stood Washington, who like a guardian angel stood
                                ready to gather into the order of redemption all who had suffered and bled with him in
                                defence of the rights of man. It would seem certain that many of these early friends
                                hovered over the dying couch to soothe the last agonies of the noble French hero. No
                                doubt they were anx- <pb n="183" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 183 ious to conduct him to
                                that resting place, where they had found the treasures of immortality and eternal life ;
                                and when his soul had broken the fetters of clay they tenderly conveyed him to their own
                                resting place. Under these considerations how singular appears to have been his first
                                attraction to Mother Ann and the Elders, while he was a soldier in arms, a man of earth,
                                and destined to act as the champion and leader for long years, in some of the most
                                thrilling scenes which man ever suffered. How simple are heaven's mysterious
                                providences, that such a man could be thus inspired and touched by hallowed fire, in the
                                morning of life, in his attraction to Believers, to fix his attention upon the great
                                fact which was to secure his salvation, when scenes of earth should close upon him
                                forever. From your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Leonard.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Dear Good Elder Brother..." TEIform="index"/>My Dear Good Elder Brother...</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Boston, October 14, 1898" TEIform="index"/>Boston, Oct. 14, 1898.</dateline><p TEIform="p">[ I would be pleased to have you insert
                                the following letter in The Manifesto, as the writer is an interested reader of our
                                publication. J. W.]
                                My Dear Good Elder Brother ;I received two charming letters, filled with the love
                                spiritprest down and overflowing from you. I have been to the Fair twice and find much
                                there to interest and instruct. It is wonderful what progress has been made in the
                                present century to promote man's comfort and convenience. What a stride in electricity
                                from Benjamin Franklin's bringing electricity from the clouds, which was deemed little
                                short of a miracle, to what is being accomplisht in the present time, by its means, and
                                we as it were standing upon the shore looking out upon the limitless ocean of its
                                possibilities. How the assurance "he gave man the dominion over them" is being verified
                                daily. Truly He who through the ages led man upward and onward, will in these latter (or
                                as Theodore Parker would say these) .older days surely watch over and protect his
                                children for the Mother love, that wonderful gift that cometh from above, will never
                                weary. Oh! that the ages of the past had dealt more with the Mother God whose heart
                                always yearned for the cry of her children. It would not have taken poor humanity so
                                long to have learned that the Father of us all is not a God of wrath, "an angry God and
                                an avenging one" but filled to overflowing with love, who searches for the sheep that
                                has strayed, and resteth not until it is safe again, and then his angels rejoice! So my
                                beloved Brother, go on in your uplifting work preaching love in God and love in man. The
                                seed may appear to fall in barren ground, but it has not, and does not, but will bring
                                forth fruit abundantly! With what pleasure do I look back upon that quiet Sabbath morn
                                when it was my privilege to meet with the Believers and receive into my soul a love
                                spirit from the good Father and Mother, that the world can not give or take away. And
                                    <pb n="184" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 184 THE MANIFESTO. inasmuch as then, you caused it to enter
                                into one of the least of his children, ye did it unto Him, and into your heart will come
                                "well done good and faithful servant, "inasmuch as ye have done it unto one of the least
                                of these my brethren, ye have done it unto me." May God's blessing and Mother's love
                                rest on you and yours is the sincere wish of your friend and brother.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Model prayer" TEIform="index"/>THE MODEL PRAYER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lizzie D." TEIform="persName"/>By Lizzie D. Horton.</byline><p TEIform="p">WE may define the beautiful prayer of our Savior, as the true model of prayer. "After this
                            manner," he says,tracing the lines on which we should frame our petitions. The words so
                            wonderfully and beautifully combined, counteract the selfishness with which we often express
                            our desires and heighten our aspirations, to comprehend the welfare of the whole world. One
                            grand feature of this prayer, is the word "our," which sets aside the ceremony of the priest
                            alone in the holy place and the people in the outer court and illustrates the one faith and
                            one baptism through Jesus Christ, and the worship of one God for all nations, that with one
                            voice in public praise and private prayer, we worship our heavenly Father. "Which art in
                            heaven," implies that all our aspirations, desires and affections, should ascend above the
                            earth. In the words,"Give us this day our daily bread," we are taught to recognize our
                            dependence upon Divine guidance for all our temporal and spiritual needs. Linkt with this
                            invocation we pray,"forgive us our debts, as we forgive our debtors," asking also for
                            deliverance from evil; not to be saved from the consequences of our sin, but to be kept free
                            from the indifference in which all failure originates. If we pray sincerely and in our daily
                            lives we hallow his name, and subject ourselves unto his truth, wre shall be establishing
                            within and around us the kingdom of Christ. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who is pure in heart..." TEIform="index"/>He who is pure in heart...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He who is pure in heart can never be vulgar in speech, and he who is meek, can
                                    never be rude in manner. Man is never so sincere as in his idle moments. Idle words,
                                    more apparently than any other, are genuine manifestations of character. A life of
                                    use is a life of holiness, and a life of idleness is a life of sin</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ingratitude comprises in itself..." TEIform="index"/>Ingratitude comprises in itself...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ingratitude comprises in itself all the other vices.</p></div2><pb n="185" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. DECEMBER, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the
                            *'United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .50 One copy one year,
                            postage paid. A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed. Remittances
                            for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">October. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1897. 52.23 .75 in. 1898.
                                54. 7.75 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 80 above 0. Lowest " " " " 36 " ' Number of
                                rainy days " " 8 " " clear " " " 8 " " cloudy" " " 15 Nov. 1898. It is but a short time
                                since we left our mooring at Port Aquarius to take a sail in our terrestrial ship around
                                Old Sol, and here we are again almost in sight of the port we left but a few days ago.
                                How rapidly the seasons fly! We take no note of time but from its passing. Yesterday we
                                commenced life's journey full of life and brilliant anticipations. To-day we behold
                                life's sun rapidly approaching its western horizon. To-morrow we sink from mortal sight.
                                What have the years of toil and strife availed us? Is the prospective harvest cheering?
                                Have the anticipations of life's rising sun been realized. In the course of its
                                revolution has its lustre been augmented, giving brilliant hope of a glorious
                                immortality? It is said;Natural things are typical of the spiritual; that our mortal
                                existence is only the nursery sphere of our eternal fruition. Then how careful should we
                                be to have it trained to virtue, grace and goodness. The seasons each have a special
                                influence in the production of the varied results of the natural world, and the
                                perfection of the varied fruits, whether they be mineral, vegetable or animal, are
                                dependent on the degree of perfection of the seasons as to their growth and development.
                                Entire clouds or entire sunshine; entire moisture or entire drouth are not conditions to
                                produce perfection in any domain of nature, but a consistent alternation of these is
                                essential to produce the desired result. As are the natural, so are the spiritual
                                conditions properly and wisely administered, necessary to develop a perfected spirit.
                                These are home reflections. On earth we've no abiding home, hut tost as billows beat;
                                Then Father in thy boundless love permit us a retreat. Permit us life and joy in Thee,
                                as purer we become, And at the last, O gather us to Thee, our peaceful home. Things with
                                us in this mundane sphere, are pursuing their wonted course. Plenty of work for both
                                heart and hands. The products of the soil are chiefly garnered. Winter work will soon be
                                ours. Health of the family is convalescent. Idle hands are absent. We have received
                                calls of late from the two Enfields of Conn, and N. H. Such visits are like sweet
                                reviving terms- <pb n="186" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 186 THE MANIFESTO. showers, or pleasant sunshine;
                                they are feasts of joy. New York hands and teams are working on the State road. Their
                                ambition is to have it graded by New Year's, and to have it ready for travel by next
                                July. Calvin O. Heed. North Family. Nov. 1898. All, good things come to those who wait,
                                and Italy has come to us in the several scores of laborers upon the new State road
                                running through our choicest meadow lands and apple orchards. Our gift to the State is
                                certainly a freewill offering, and no compensation will come to us in any way excepting
                                the happiness of making the traveling public more comfortable and probably, for that
                                very reason, the State government more secure. For comfort brings contentment, and
                                contented citizens are always the most loyal. The old earth seems to be swinging in
                                spirals, moving higher and higher at every revolution and we are rejoicing at the
                                broadening and deepening of the light. Visitors still come, of the highest order of
                                intelligence and aspiration, and some are asking entrance to our homes, that here,
                                withdrawn from the strifes and tumults of business they may work for God and for His
                                Christ. More and more do we feel the necessity of being prepared for these eager seekers
                                and questioners. More and more do we feel that we must keep ourselves close to the heart
                                of the all-pervading Christ; that the best of mind and heart and spirit must be ours
                                would we attract and secure the best. That to stand on a plane above the spiritual of
                                the outside life means t now to stand very high indeed. We feel that we must keep
                                constantly in mind the truth, that not the customs of our Order, grown stiff and mouldy
                                with years, attract and retain, but the principles of which no jot or tittle shall ever
                                fail; for God is eternal and they are of God. u' Ada Brown. South Family. Nov. 1898; On
                                a sunny afternoon of Sept. last we took a ramble in quest of new scenes and pleasures.
                                Our first call was at the Office of the Church family where we found a busy band, sowing
                                the seed of industry. There was Eldress Dorothy Wright, who is a faithful worker in the
                                cause of right, Sister Florinda Sears, one of the "Sears of the Ages," Sisters Emma J.
                                and Sadie Neale who kneel daily in prayer and praise, and our younger Sister Carrie Wade
                                who will wade through time a trusty helper in the "cause that needs assistance." All
                                were engaged in the manufacture of cloaks, and fortunate are they who purchase of them,
                                for their work is perfection. Leaving the genial company of cloakmakers, we past to the
                                family dwelling where we found Brother Ferdinand who guided us through unfamiliar halls
                                to the neat and airy kitchen. A party of Sisters were completing the noon work. Here we
                                met Sister Amelia Calver, who isknown as a writer, scholar and teacher participating in
                                the duties of domestic economy on which she is the best authority. She piloted us
                                through the winding ways of their light, convenient cellars where order and neatness
                                reign supreme. Then through the well cultivated vegetable gardens we went, where the
                                harvest had commenced. Elder Calvin G. Reed has special care of the garden and a better
                                one would be impossible to find. In a nook by the dwelling house may be seen a mound of
                                small stones, overgrown with flowers of various colors forming a pretty and unique fancy
                                flower bed. This is the work of Brother Martin Jones. We called on some of the ancients
                                of the city and found Sister Mary Hazzard busy and bright, tho eighty-six new years have
                                past since she commenced the battle of life; Yet she is happy at her work, The nicest
                                things she makes, She knits fur caps and nice fur gloves And moulds out sugar cakes. <pb n="187" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 187 And baskets, dainty ones they are, They're
                                blue and pink and white, With pretty cushions nicely wrought, Which would a queen
                                delight. And Sister Matilda Reed who has witnest the frosts of eighty-two winters, makes
                                and repairs garments for the brotherhood, and executes some of the finest work on the
                                cloaks. Verily, verily I say unto you she runs with patience the race which is set
                                before her. Sister Matilda was for many years the presiding Eldress of the Church
                                family. We had a pleasant visit with Sister Ann Maria Greaves who, like the others, was
                                stitching on cloaks. Sisters Cornelia French and Sarah Cutler, makers of the pies and
                                bread and other goodies, entertained us most agreeably and we sampled some of their
                                delicious dishes. Thus the afternoon was pleasingly and profitably spent. Nov. 7th
                                Sisters Caroline Whitcher and Myra Green of Enfield, N. H. made us a flying visit.
                                They only paused to rest their wings, but we were just glad they were weary enough to
                                rest among us. We hope others will be induced to seek rest and find it. Genevieve
                                DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1898. We have been reminded of the words of a good old hymn commencing, "Let names
                                and sects and parties accost our ears no more." The reminder came while comtemplating
                                the fact that even if used aright they were only temporary instrumentalities in the
                                development of life; in the advancing of its ideal to a higher plane and causing it to
                                more fully understand the universal scope of the power of truth, but its ultimate
                                triumph does not depend upon the success or failure of any 'sect or party. We have
                                increast in hopefulness and had our conscious knowledge of the progress of truth
                                strengthened by the perusal of "The New Man,""A magazine devoted to the mastery of sin,
                                disease and poverty." Truly the testimony of the everlasting gospel is going forth in
                                the earth, not in the forging of creeds that only cause the human soul to place a limit
                                to its advancement, bvit in the proving that the universal brotherhood of the race is
                                not afar off but is even nearer than our limited vision and understanding is willing to
                                admit. The literature that has been placed before the public and is constantly renewed
                                dealing with the questions of the responsibility and obligations of human society to
                                more intelligently understand what is its duty and how to proceed in the elimination of
                                the wrongs that have largely been transmitted from the past as well as those which the
                                present age must be responsible for, is increasing at a ratio never before known. We
                                have had placed in our hands for review a work entitled, "The New and True Religion," by
                                Charles M. Stebbins. It deals vigorously with the questions that are calling for reform
                                in the Political,. Social and Religious world. We certainly can not help but be
                                encouraged to keep toiling for an increasing light on the lineswhich as an organized
                                body of religious communists we believe is right, when we realize that all who with an
                                honest heart are seeking for a more perfect understanding of the truth are being blended
                                together in spirit as the heart of one, regardless of external environments. November
                                records the first snow of the season, on the 7th. inst. and tho of that amount it needed
                                the operation of the imaginative powers to help in the observation, enough to say we had
                                a flurry of snow. Our autumnal season has been very fine giving us beautiful weather for
                                harvesting our crops, of which on the whole we can not complain, tho some have fallen
                                short of the average. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1898. The first snow storm arrived in this vicinity on the 10th inst., just one day
                                earlier than last year. About one inch fell&gt; <pb n="188" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 188 THE MANIFESTO.
                                which the small boys were quick to use for architectural purposes during its brief stay.
                                About five hundred bushels of apples have been kiln dried this autumn; and for the first
                                time with us a squash-bee was held, during which fifty large squashes were cut into
                                sections about an inch thick. The process of drying the latter occupied a day and a
                                half, and results gave good satisfaction. General Kepairs is in active service at
                                present date and a lively "hammering campaign" is before him. Leaky roofs and uncertain
                                flooring have occasioned several vigorous attacks already. We decide to give the "minute
                                men" winter quarters here, that any sudden uprisings may be settled at once. These
                                northern winters are calculated to test the enduring qualities of all tilings animate
                                and inanimate, and the approaching one is to be among the keenest, so say the
                                weatherwise. The chickadees and'sparrows have decided to cast in their lot with us, it
                                seems, and the crows are still in the neighborhood. Sewers not sowers are brought to the
                                front this season, the farmers' favorite topics fall off with the leaves. Sisters report
                                brisk motions and fanciful notions in the line of sale needlework, in anticipation of
                                additional calls during the holiday shopping. Jessie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1898. There is nothing more discreditable to the southern agriculture than the slow
                                neglect of cultivating some of the different grasses, and stop the large importation
                                from the north. It is a common thing to hear this argument,"The grasses of the tropics
                                grow wide apart and are coarse, while those of the north are fine and sweet. They are
                                far more nutritious and better for animal food." But why should this justify the neglect
                                when many of the northern farmers, even of our nation, are trying some of the northern
                                grasses, and thus far give good testimony as to their growth here in the sunny south.
                                Our own experience has taught that Crab Grass can be grown to profit when rightly cared
                                for and cured. That our animals will eat it with willingness as they would eat the fine
                                Timothy grass. Crab Grass is the natural grass of this state. Grass culture has always
                                been the index of progressive agriculture in newly settled countries. The first aim of
                                the farmer, always has been, in our northern states, to make good feeding grounds for
                                the animals. This has been a total neglect on the part of our southern farmers with
                                their great plains and prairies as they have depended on the wild grass that nature has
                                given them. Thus we see the cause of the inferior breed of cattle that has filled the
                                state. But northern people who are now looking to the sunny south for a home in old age,
                                and know the value of a northern acre of grass, are making a gradual change, to prove to
                                our southern friends that certain northern grasses will flourish here as well as in the
                                north. Slavery rendered cotton and orange growing general and almost exclusive, because
                                of the limited capacity of the negro race. Most every improvement had been neglected
                                until the freeze of 189495, which was an experience unknown to this generation, and in
                                fact without a parallel in the history of the state. The farmers seemed dazed and knew
                                not what course to pursue. Destruction and ruin stared them in the face. These people,
                                however, did not give up to despair. Not depending wholly on fruit culture, they entered
                                largely into the raising of vegetables, which is proving of untold wealth to. the
                                country. We now see car loads of vegetables as well as of fruit, pass out of the state.
                                Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1898. No other event ever cast the pall of <pb n="189" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 189
                                gloom over our town as did the suicide of Bertha Huse, on Oct. 31, when she left her
                                home at early morning and last seen on Shaker Bridge, spanning Mascoma Lake. Divers from
                                Boston were engaged and spent two days inspecting both sides of the bridge. Failing to
                                discover the body, dynamite was purchased with the purpose to dislodge the body. Large
                                companies of men explored the hills thinking she might have strayed there. On Nov. 3rd.
                                Mrs. Geo. Titus of Lebanon, N. H., a clairvoyant and a stranger to the Huse family,
                                appeared upon the scene and stated that she could locate the body. She walked to the
                                middle of the bridge on the left side, and said the body would be found there, the head
                                in a hollow and the feet upward. With many scruples, and amid the hum of skepticism of
                                the people, the diver went to the place indicated and returned with the astonishing news
                                that the statement of Mrs. Titus was correct. He had previously made what he considered
                                a thorough search of the locality, but owing to the brush and logs which comprise the
                                foundation of the bridge, failed to discover the body. Is not this wonderful case one
                                more impeachable fact in proof of Spirit power? Is it unreasonable to believe that the
                                unfortunate one, forced to her rash act by the power of inherited blood, after the
                                receding waves of diseased materiality had rolled away and she came in contact with
                                incoming waves of spirit life, her first awakened thought was to relieve the heavy
                                burden of anguish from her grief stricken relations? and through the sensitive organism
                                of Mrs. Titus, found the channel of so doing? The closing of the harvest season records
                                300 bushels of apples dried, 1400 weight of beet seed, 300 weight of onion seed, 20
                                barrels of seed corn, 26 barrels of pickles, many hundreds of heads of cabbage, beside
                                other products of consecrated labor which merits praise and helps to keep in circulation
                                the spirit of goodwill and blessed faith that sanctifies and hapGeorge H. Baxter. pifies
                                life.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1898, Perhaps a brighter, pleasanter November morning never dawned upon us, than the
                                present. Weather moderate; sky clear, and the colored leaves dropping to the ground. The
                                union, love and good feeling in the family, all that could be desired, as each goes
                                about his particular vocation. Our crops are all in and well housed but corn, and that
                                is coming in as fast as husked. It proves to be a very good crop, but some of it is a
                                little soft, which can be fed to the pigs and chickens before it moulds. Our potato crop
                                was very light as is mostly the case in the S. W. section of Ohio. On the whole the
                                season has been very propitious in the supply of plenty of rain, and also fine days for
                                harvesting the grains and fruits of the earth. Tidings seldom reach us from the Georgia
                                Colony, but we hope they are doing as well as the drawbacks of our day will allow. One
                                of these, and perhaps the greatest, is the spiritual death and darkness covering the U.
                                S. A. at this time. Money greed, sensual pleasure, political gambling seem to have
                                absorbed the average American citizen and all religious feeling is supprest beneath its
                                crushing influence. It seems uncertain whether or not the war is over, but we earnestly
                                pray that such is the case. What a hideous relict of barbai'ism war is. What a dismal
                                blot on the escutcheon of any people. Just think of it,A nation professing Christianity,
                                which demands of its votaries, Love to all enemies, and prayer for those who
                                despitefully use them and abuse them; meeting one another to see who can kill the
                                greatest number of his fellow-beings aye! and Christian priests acting as Chaplains for
                                their encouragement in shedding the blood of their brethren!and these Christians
                                continue to inflict capital punishment upon murderers, as tho one murder was one atom
                                better than another. I would no sooner destroy a man's life, under sanction of law, than
                                outside of it. <pb n="190" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 190 THE MANIFESTO. O Christianity!What unspeakable
                                crimes have been and are committed in thy name. But God will sooner or later correct all
                                this. But notwithstanding all this our Heavenly Father is gradually moving this and all
                                other worlds into higher, happier and holier conditions. So let us be patient .and one
                                of these days we shall see the right prevail. O. C. Hampton.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Day by day" TEIform="index"/>DAY BY DAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Coolidge, Susan" TEIform="persName"/>By Susan Coolidge.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If I were told that I must die tomorrow, That the next sun Which sinks should
                                    bear me past all fear and sorrow For any one, All the fight fought, and all the
                                    short journey through, What should I do? I do not think that I should shrink or
                                    falter, But just go on Doing my work, nor change nor seek to alter Aught that i s
                                    done; But rise, and move, and love, and smile, and pray For one more day. And lying
                                    down at night for a last sleeping Say in the Ear Which hearkens ever: "Lord, within
                                    Thy keeping How should I fear? And when to-morrow brings Thee nearer still, Do Thou
                                    Thy will." I might not sleep for awe; but peaceful tender, My soul would lie All the
                                    night long; and when the morningsplendor Flashed o'er the sky I think that I could
                                    smile, and calmly say "It is His day!" Let me keep on, abiding and unfearing Thy
                                    will alway:Selected. Through a long century's ripening fruition Or a short day's;
                                    Thou canst not come too soon, and I can wait If Thou come late.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy and his mother" TEIform="index"/>A BOY AND HIS MOTHER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Armour, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>By Annie Armour.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Can a boy get away from the prayers of his mother, Or sink to a depth that her
                                    love can not reach? Can the billows of time pile so high on each other, That he
                                    can't see her form on the white, shining beach? Can the dark clouds of sin fold, so
                                    closely about him, That the light of her faith does not shine on his way? Can he
                                    feel all the friends of this world spurn and doubt him, While his mother has faith,
                                    love and trust to still pray ? Ah, no! not a boy can escape from the pleading.
                                    Ascending each day from her bedside to God. He will still hear the tones of her
                                    voice interceding When the dear form is laid 'neaththe flower strewn sod. Then pray,
                                    motherSj pray while the boy still is breathing, And pray if Death's angel has sung
                                    in Ms ear, That God in his mercy the boy is receiving, For the sake of the prayers
                                    you have said for him here.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility" TEIform="index"/>HUMILITY.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Humility is perfect quietness of heart. It is to have no trouble. It is never to
                                    be fretted or vext or irritated or sore disappointed. It is to expect nothing, to
                                    wonder at nothing that is done to me, to feel nothing done against me. It is to be
                                    at rest when nobody praises me, and when I am blamed or despised. It is to have a
                                    blessed home in myself where I can go in and shut the door, and kneel to my Father
                                    in secret and be at peace as in a deep sea of calmness when all around and above is
                                    trouble.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fish, Lizzie C." TEIform="index"/>Lizzie C. Fish
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Lizzie C. Fish, at East Canterbury, N. H. Nov. 14, 1898. Age 37 years 11 mo. and 27
                                days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="191" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">INDEX. A. Acrostic, An All Faiths Represented, Anchored, Safely Being, Center of Bethesda, c.
                            Ceeley, Sally, In Memory of Christian, Am I a Charity,..... Communism, Christian Page. 31 -
                            72 70 85 103 129 159 161 61 85 95 146 153 190 Dead, Is the Old Year - w' - "" Dress, Receipt
                            for a Lady's Deming, Wm. Notes from Diary of Day, Beginning the ... Diary, Notes from Our
                            Dow, Nancy, In Memory of Day by Day - - - -XI. Enroute,..... 19 Effect, Cause and ... 105
                            Evolution,..... 117 Exchanges, 30, 96, 112, 128, 144, 160. W. Forgiveness, - - - - - 23
                            Friendship, - 63 Faith, - - - - - - 99 First, Let the Mud Dry - - 127 Farnum, Louisa,
                            Tribute to - - 143 a. Gillespie, Frances, A Tribute to 71 Gospel, From the Social - - 72
                            Grasses, Prest Flowers and - 79 Gates, Ximena, A Requiem to - 158 Page. M. Home, Notes About
                            11, 26, 42, 58, 74, 90, 107, 122, 138, 155, 171, 185. Hope,..... - 31 Helpless, A Plea for
                            the 38 Hastings, H. Remarks at Funeral of 55 Home, My - 95 Highway, The Spiritual - 97 Home,
                            I Have Dreamed of My - 176 Humility -I. - 190 Influence, Unconscious - - 160 K. Knew, If We
                            - - - - 62 I. Life, A Holy - - - - - 15 Life, True to 31 Love, The Law of - - - - 40 Life,
                            True - - - - - 65 Lessons, Frost ... - 133 Life, Ascending - 145 Loved Ones, Our - - - - 158
                            Leonard, Wm.Letter - 166, 178 Letter, - - - - - - 183 Morrill, Ezekiel, Testimony of - ' 9
                            March, - - - - - - 36 Mission, Our - 49 March, In thought of - - - 56 M. B- - - - - -
                            -Letter ... 115 Mind, Change the - 177 Mother, A Boy and his - - 190 O. Offering, The - ...
                            81 Olive Branch, Our - 153 <pb n="192" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 192 THE MANIFESTO. Page. Praise, - 22
                            Prayer A - - - - - 25 Press, How not to write for the 78 Peebles, Dr. J. M. Visit of - 101
                            Pilgrimage, Our - - - 113 Path, The Silent 135 People, Perfect - 159 Prayer, The Model - - -
                            185 n. Russel, Isabella Remarks in Service 67 Resurrected - - - - 119 S. Shakerism, Progress
                            of - 3, 17, 33 Science, vs. the Christ - - 6 Sanitary, - - 15, 30, 78, 160, 175 Shepard, H.
                            P. Remarks at Funeral 37 Saviors, ..... 52 Stratton, Ee A. Remarks in Service 57 Song, Life
                            a 68 S. F. T.Letter - - - 117 Shakers, Persecutions of the Early 132 Spiritually-Minded,
                            What is it to be 135 Self, The Shadow of 144 Sail, The Coming - - - 164 Selfishness, - - - -
                            169 Truth, The Everlasting Thomas,Letter Thank You, Twine, Turnkey, The Trust, V.
                            Visitation, Angel Voice, The Child's Vision, A - - W. Warning, A Friendly Way, Which is the
                            Better 24 - 39 57 - 62 93, 126, 141 121 83 92 119 112 DEATHS. Page. Anderson, Martha J. - -
                            15 Angus, Ann Maria 63 Birde, William - ... 144 Copley, Sophia 79 Ceeley, Sally 112 Conklin,
                            Angeline Alvira - - " Curtis, Mary Ann ... 175 Durgin, Dorothy Ann ... 144 Dow, Nancy ....
                            iqo Dunning, Daniel - - - - " Edwards, Rebecca - 112 Fish, Lizzie C. - - - - 190 Gillespie,
                            Frances ' - - - 791 Gregory, Sophia ... 9$ George, Irena - - - - " Gates, Ximena - 128
                            Hubbard, Melinda - - 47 Hastings, Harriet - " Kendrick, Samuel - - - 9d McBride, James ...
                            128 McCoemack, Fannie ... 144 Noyes, Thomas ... 47 Pilkington, Indiana 31 Pilot, John ...
                            144 Shepard, Hannah P. - - - 47 Taylor, Ann .... 15, Truair, Jerusha - - - - 112.</p></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The government selected as its agent a man
of position who has lived much in Germany.
It was necessary for us to have a trained intellect that would make no mistakes.   His
story is told in the November Cosmopolitan,
and the most exciting pages of Dumas's fiction seem tame in comparison with the facts.
Crossing the frontier in a first-class carriage,
he was by a trifling accident brought into
conversation with a young Spanish nobleman,
presently who should come along but the son
of General Weyler.   This acquaintance led to
his receiving many attentions from Weyler
"when they reached Madrid, and the General
actually gave up a day to a trip to the Escurial.   Imagine this grim arch-enemy of ours
laying himself out to please the secret agent
whom the government had sent to find out
the weak places of Spain.   How trifling the
demarcation between the position of honored
guest and that of spy who, if discovered,
would have been all the more quickly sent to
his death!   The same issue of The Cosmopolitan contains four pieces of fiction by such famous authors as Frank Stockton, Zangwill,
H. G. Wells, and the lamented Harold Frederic
but none of it half so exciting in its interest as
this true story.
Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly for November is the initial number in the new and
improved form of this longtime favorite illustrated family magazine, with a handsome
cover in colors and gold.   Its price is reduced
to ten cents, one dollar per annum.   This is
unquestionably a wise an<\ popular move on
the part of the publishers; and the return of
Mrs. Frank Leslie to the editorship of the
magazine assures for it a future as brilliant
as its past has been prosperous.   The current
(November) number of the new Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly makes good its
promises in a splendid table of contents,
which includes; An illustrated symposium on
Greater America; with contributions by Col.
A. K. McClure, Gen. Fitzhugh Lee and Senators Chandler and Davis; With Wheeler and
Roosevelt at Santiago; by the Rev. Peter
MacQueen; Clara Barton on Red Cross Work
in Cuba; Walter Camp on Football; Mrs.
Frank Leslie on The Southern Woman; Converting Silver into Goldan account of the '
wonderful discovery of Dr. Stephen H. Emmens; the opening chapters of April Bloom;
the new serial story by Egerton Castle (author of The Pride of Jennico;) illustrated by
Wenzell; complete short stories by Frank R.
Stockton, Margaret E. Sangster, Etta W.
Pierce and E. Louise Liddell; sketches and
poems by Louise Chandler Moulton, Lillian
Whiting, H. Villiers Barnett, Madison Cawein,
Isaac W. Eaton, Charles Crandall, R. K. Munkittrick and Henry Tyrrell.   The illustrators
of this number include; Albert Wenzell, S.
Werner, Ch. Grunwald, Hugh M. Eaton, Frank
Adams, Florian Peixotto and Walter Goltz.
Frank Leslie's Publishing House, 141-143 Fifth
Ave., New York.
The Niksur Magazine Vol. I No. 1 comes
to us this month, from the "Niksur Co-operative Association" of Minneapolis, Minn.   This
Co-operative Association is certainly moving
on the up grade.   It proposes to establish
pleasant homes for the members and then to
establish schools and to have libraries and
art galleries.   Ir also proposes to shut out "saloons and other useless parasites."   We shall
be deeply interested in the success of this
worthy enterprise.
AGENTS!
This is  the   opportunity  of your life
Agents are making $50.00 to $150.00 a week.
Fitzhugh Lee, Maj. Gen. U. S. V., and late
Consul General to Cuba, writes
A BOOK ON CUBA
We have on press for early issue, General
Lee's own story of Cuba and the Spanish War
to be produced in a substantial book of over
500 pages, 7x9% inches in size and almost
ONE HUNDRED ILLUSTRATIONS
This is the only authentic work piiblished
on the one subject occupying the minds of the
entire civilized world.
OUTFITS READY.
Liberal commissions will be paid and credit
given.   Address for full paiticulars,
THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY,
91-93 ITFTH AVENUE, NEW YORK.
PUBLISHERS OF GKENEKAL LEE'S BOOK.
We have authorized distributors everywhere
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring  minds.    Price 5 cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
AND   THE
SPANISH WAR.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
50  YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific Htncrican.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a
year; four months, $L Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.361Broadwa^ New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHOEISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Okdeb must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Pric, 10 cts.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.   Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Abthub Bbuce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
Baking Powder
Made from pure
cream of tartar.
Safeguards the food
against alum.
Alton baking powders are the greatest
menacers to health of the present day*
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>