<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0803" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18780301" TEIform="date">March 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">53-77</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. VIII. NO. 3. MARCH. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE
                        UNITED SOCIETIES, OUR HOME AT CANTERBURY, N. H. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD." PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER, N.
                        H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. 1878 <pb id="p2"/> Moderation ..... 53 Sweet Vale of Prayer ... 54 Washings of
                        Regeneration . . 54 Live for a Right Principle . . 55 The True Secret .... 55 Childhood & Theology . . 56
                        Indians No. 2..... 56 Science of Silence .... 57 Salvation by Education . . . 68 Christian Culture No. 10 . . . 60
                        How be Accepted ? .... 61 Blessed Sabbath . . . 61 Proposed additions to the Rochester Platform ..... 61 Ann Lee . .
                        . . . 62 Thou Art Our God .... Correspondence .... Speak unto Me Excellent Things The Shaker manifesto :—Shakerism
                        tl world's Spiritual Metre Care of the aged .... Editorial Notes For the Children .... Farm and Garden . . . Home
                        Topics ..... Society Record . Book Table...... Selected ...... Obituary . . . . . . : Music ...... i TEEMS OF
                        ADVERTISING. For one inch, one " one half column, " one " " insertion $ 1. 00 $ 3. 00 $ 6. 00 page, " $12.00
                        Continued insertion for three months, 20 per ct. discount. " six ' " 25 " " " one year, 33£ v " Subscriptions, Sixty
                        cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. Subscription will begin when order is
                        received.—No back numbers. e r CONTENTS.</p>
                    --><pb n="53" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. O. A_. IL.OM.A.iS Editor. Shakers, W. Y. VOL.
                        VIII.—MARCH. 1878.—No. III. </p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moderation" TEIform="index"/>MODERATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName">O. C. HAMPTON </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> ' "ls it is a time when all manner of theries except those based on absolutely | nmutable
                            principles, are crumbling round us and tottering to their fall, loderation in every
                            movement, and lorough deliberation and prudence in 11 directions, in thought, word and
                            acion, will naturally suggest themselves 3 the advocate of progress, to higher nd holier
                            conditions. Intelligent investigation into many iews and theories, both of religion and
                            hilosophy seem of late years to have nfixed the foundations upon which they ested of old;
                            and so far is this the ase, that the very technical terms once sed to teach them, are now
                            without leaning and inapplicable. Of Theology, Evolution, Biology, to- gether with the newer
                            doctrines of the "nmaterial nature of Heat, Light, Elecficity, Galvanism, ¦" Odylic force
                            etc; "he old technical terms are in many ases entirely ruled out, and an almost ntirely new
                            system of Technology subtituted. This being the case, great patience, orbearance, and above
                            all, charity seem ecessary to be exercised toward all nth whom we converse, that no
                            unpleasant feelings may arise to disturb union or produce unnecessary antagonisms. Let us be
                            sure that we understand clearly this theory not only, but the terms which our interlocutor
                            uses to explain it. This will go a great distance in main- taining peace. No argument is of
                            any value, which has to be maintained at the sacrifice of the union of Christian fellowship,
                            let its intrinsic merits be what they may. Persons are very different in their organizations
                            ; and in nothing is this more discernable than in the elements of conservatism and
                            radicalism. Especially is this the case when persons possessing these diverse elements of
                            character happen to be extremists ! To calmly discuss the merits of a theory, between ex-
                            treme radical and extreme conservative, is a very difficult matter if not impossible ;
                            indeed quite so, unless both, or at least, one of them, has had an extended experience in
                            self-discipline. Wisdom would seem to dictate, that where any two persons of warm, excitable
                            temperaments wish to freely discuss the merits and demerits of a theory, they should first
                            agree on some definite <pb n="54" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE arrangements and rules of discourse, by
                            which they would be held in such limits of moderation that their Christian fellowship and
                            union would remain unimpaired. This, on the principle, that being forewarned is being
                            forearmed. These suggestions are not given to discourage, but rather to encourage discussion
                            and investigation ; by proposing means whereby good feelings may remain unmarred amid long,
                            elaborate, and thorough discussions of the most intricate subjects. Finally, this is a
                            transition season; "wherein all theories are subjected to the crucible of a most searching
                            and inexorable analysis; and much new and rich truth is thereby elaborated, and vast
                            quantities of the feculence and chaff of error burned up, no more to appear in the way of
                            progress, forever. And happy shall we all be, if with the freedom and emancipation from
                            ignorance and error, we can also manage to reap a rich harvest of peace and union through
                            the medium of the necessary self-discipline. Union Village, 0. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet vale of prayer" TEIform="index"/>SWEET VALE OF PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName">MARIA  WHEELER </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> O quiet vale of prayer, sweet prayer, The fragrance of God's peace is there : Its holy paths
                            o'er-shining sod, Are watered by the hand of God. Lone weary hearts oppressed with grief,
                            Can wander there and find relief, Or, for the toil of life prepare, Within that sacred vale
                            of prayer. © quiet vale of prayer, I've found A treasure on thy hallowed ground; The
                            precious seal of trusting love In God, who rules the spheres above. And though my falt'ring
                            feet may stray, From truth, to error's troubled way, Forgiving love will meet me there,
                            Within that quiet vale of prayer. Union Village, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washings of regeneration" TEIform="index"/>WASHINGS OF REGENERATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">ELDER F. W. EVANS </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> A man, or woman, who should go for weeks, or months, without washing with water, would be
                            untidy, uncouth, unclean, dirty. A wagon, or any kind of running machinery, in use for a
                            long time, or even a short time, without oil, or some kind of lubricating substance, would
                            be out of order, injured. Instead of doing duty quietly, smoothly, almost self-acting, there
                            would be harsh screeching sounds proceeding therefrom, indicating disorganization, going on
                            to destruction. Is it not thus with natural men and women coming in contact with the Gospel?
                            Morality, external right, going from policy rather than principle—exter- nal observance of
                            the Rules of the Order, to maintain an external relation thereto, may be good as far as it
                            goes, even as a perfect threshing and winnowing machine is a necessity to a farmer, having
                            large crops of grain to take care of; yet, as that machine requires the superadded oil, and
                            that continuously and regularly supplied, so does the most perfect natural moral man, or
                            woman require the oil of gladness to make glad the City of our God. In other words, they
                            require the daily washings of regeneration, while traveling in the regeneration. That is,
                            they require a daily Spiritual baptism, induced by meeting with their brethren and sisters
                            from a spirit home, when they meet with their brethren and sisters in earthly homes. Meeting
                            should be a meeting of the members of the Church in the Spirit World, with the members of
                            the Church on earth, a union of spir54 SEL^JKLER M^JNTrFESTO. <pb n="55" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHATKBR MANIFESTO: 55 it and oneness of aspiration after God,—the living God—in each soul.
                            To every one is given a measure of the Spirit to profit withal. Let no one fail to receive
                            and utilize it. All will leave such a meeting with their souls as much changed, cleansed,
                            refreshed, as their natural bodies would be, after the toil and labor of the day, by a
                            John-theBaptist immersion in some running river. Shall not the washings of regenera- tion of
                            the human soul, be as real, as frequent and as efficacious, as are the washings of the human
                            body? And are they not as necessary, to cleanse us from all unrighteousness, after we have
                            done the will of God by confessing and forsaking sin, as frequent ablutions are to the
                            physical system? Let us bring no more vain oblations, but in our devotions be earnest,
                            sincere, in the purification of ourselves from all filthiness of flesh and spirit, of soul
                            and body. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Live for a right principle" TEIform="index"/>Live for a Right Principle</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName">RUTH WEBSTER </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> If we would fully accomplish any important aim in life, either of a spiritual or temporal
                            nature, we should give the thing to be done due consideration, in order to ascertain whether
                            the object will pay the cost of time, study and labor, it will necessarily take to make our
                            aim a success, and promote right principles. When once having settled in our minds, that the
                            duty of whatever nature it may be is based on true and honest principles, let us never
                            swerve nor falter, but press forward with a determination to conquer through every discour-
                            agement. This we have been taught by the Father and Mother of the New Creation, through
                            precept and example. They had a mission of which they never lost sight, but pressed on
                            through the greatest sufferings and the most determined opposition. That the kingdom of God
                            might be established on earth, and souls saved from sin, was what they labored for. And as
                            children of such parentage, our mission is the same ; and should we not strive with an
                            ardent zeal to accomplish it ? Not only when the tide runs smoothly but in the midst of
                            difficulties, when our faith is put to the severest test ? Here is a quotation worth
                            repeating with which my sentiments accord : "Not by mere emotions can we hope to rise to
                            higher spheres ; but by self-subjection, by actual works of charity, and by efforts that
                            prove the sincerity of our aspi- rations." Would the youth of the present age but stop to
                            consider, and start on life's voyage with a determination to live lives founded on high and
                            holy principles, it would be impossible to estimate the a- mount of good they might do here
                            on earth, or to judge the value of the treasure laid up for them in the Spirit world. Union
                            Village, 0. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True secret" TEIform="index"/>The True Secret</head><p TEIform="p"> How many take a wrong view of life, and waste their energies and destroy their nervous
                            system in endeavoring to accumulate wealth, without thinking of the present happiness they
                            are throwing away. It is not wealth or high station which makes a man happy. Many of the
                            most wretched beings on earth have both; but it is a radiant, sunny spirit, which knows how
                            to bear little trials and enjoy comforts, and thus extract happiness from every incident in
                            life. </p></div2><pb n="56" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Childhood and theology" TEIform="index"/>Childhood and Theology</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tilden, William P." TEIform="persName">Rev. Wm. P. Tilden </persName> (Slightly changed.)</byline><p TEIform="p"> An artless girl with a joyous skip, [Who ne'er at the Sectarian cup had sipped,] Was
                            trundling her hoop on the graveled way, When a stranger, watching her idle play, Lifted his
                            finger as much as to say, 'A word if you please!' [She stopped to hear] [With uplifted eyes
                            and listening ear.] 'Have you found the Savior?' he gravely said, [In thoughtful mood she]
                            dropped her head Seemed turning the question o'er and o'er, As one she had never heard
                            before: Then sadly replied as her hands she crossed, 'Why, I didn't know the Savior was
                            lost!' 'You don't understand what I mean my child', The stranger replied, as he almost
                            smiled. 'Do you love the dear Jesus?' O, yes, indeed, And I love to hear my mother read How
                            fondly he loved every little child And I know when he spoke HE always smiled, And whenever
                            I'm as good as I can be, I am very sure that he smiles on me. 'But do you trust in the
                            blood, my child? Do you know you are totally denied? That on the dark waves of sin you are
                            tossed, And without the blood you are certainly lost?' Her thoughtful eyes dropped, but she
                            raised them again, As a child-thought flashed through her little brain. 'Oh! yes Sir; I
                            trust in the blood,' she said, *'Tis my blood that keeps me from being dead; And please do
                            not think that I am lost, For right down there where the cars just crossed. Is my papa's
                            house. You see I could run Right home in a minute. It would be fun. Get up, old hoop'—and
                            away she went, Far down the walk, on her play intent,— Leaving the stranger to sigh for the
                            teaching Of good old times, and doctrinal preaching, And he sadly mused, as away she ran,
                            'The germ of A UnitakianF We copy from a late, Cape Town, South Africa paper: The Hon. J. M.
                            Peebles, M. D., late American Consul at Trebizonde, is now on a visit to Cape Town. At Natal
                            Dr. Peebles excited a warm interest in the sufferings of the famine stricken inhabitants of
                            India, lately witnessed by himself. In Cape Town Dr. Peebles has been lecturing on
                            Spiritualism in which he is an ardent believer. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">JAMES S. PRESCOTT </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> We could not but admire the spirit in which President Hayes received the Indian Chiefs, on
                            their late visit to Washington, and the interest he manifested in their behalf, promising
                            them that he would do all in his power to better their condition by laying their case before
                            the great council, Congress, inviting the cooperation of the Indians in whatever measures
                            might be adopted to promote their future welfare and happiness. And in his annual message to
                            Congress, we find him true to his promise, by inserting this remarkable passage in favor of
                            the Indians : "I see no reason why Indians who can give satisfactory proof of having, by
                            their own labor supported their families for a number of years, and who are willing to
                            detach themselves from their tribal relations, should not be admitted to the benefit of the
                            homestead act, and the privileges of citizenship, and I recommend the passage of a law to
                            that effect." What could he do more ? Let this be done and the Indians will be recognized as
                            having "rights that white men are bound to respect." If any doubt the ability of the Indian
                            Chiefs to plead their own cause, let them read the following spiritual communication
                            received by us, and which we here transcribe, with some slight emendations, expressive of
                            the feelings of many of the noble Chiefs now in the form : "O YE WHITE FACES OF NORTH
                            AMERICA ! Come listen a-while to the words of an Indian Chief, who lived and flourished
                            about 320 years ago, in that section of country now known as the six New England States. <pb n="57" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> TTTK SHAKER MANIFBISTO. My name among the red men of the forest who
                            lived at the time I now speak of, was known as Tecumwega. Though my name was scarcely known
                            to the white man, yet among my people it was known even beyond the Rocky Mountains. When I
                            bring up to view the long list of grievances, for more than two hundred years past, and of
                            the many vows and promises the white man has made to the red man of the forest, and has so
                            often broken them, I cannot help shedding tears of sympathy, in behalf of my poor, red
                            brethren, who as it were are scattered to the four winds. Even at the early period I first
                            spoke of, my countrymen had fears of the white man becoming a strong and power- ful nation,
                            and we would be driven from our beautiful forest homes and hunting grounds to some far
                            distant clime, we Juiew not where, or slain by hundreds and thousands by the hand of our
                            enemies. For we plainly saw by the few white men that came among us, that they were very
                            deceitful, unjust, treacherous, and cruel. In after times, I admit, the red man committed
                            many depredations and massacres on the white man, and, for all of which he surely will have
                            to suffer, and will not go unpunished, but must meet the strict justice of the Great Spirit.
                            But, when we duly consider the much greater advantages the white man has in obtaining
                            knowledge, goodness, and wisdom, (with the arts and sciences included,) I say, those sins
                            the red man has committed sink as it were into insignificance by the side of those of the
                            white man. O MY PEOPLE ! MY RED BRETHREN OF NORTH AMERICA ! Of the past, I think back with
                            sorrow. Of the present, I am filled with lamentations. And the future I grasp in fond hopes
                            of imagination, as a tender Mother holds her infant to her bosom. O Red Man ! O Red Man !
                            Thy fore-fathers delighted to sit by gentle streams and hear the sweet songsters in the
                            foliage above ; while the green mantle of nature was spread beneath their feet, yet, they
                            were happy. The Great Spirit made them happy and contented. For their hearts were as light
                            as the lark in the morning, and their feet were as swift as the fawns upon the mountain. And
                            they loved to ride in their bark canoes on the beautiful rivers, and ride their ponies over
                            the western prairies of this fair soil of America. But, where are they now ? They have gone
                            to their spirit homes. And you, O my brethren ! Where are you gone ? Where have you fled ?
                            You have passed away like the dews of the morning, save a remnant only to tell the sad
                            story. I behold the once beautiful forest, homes and hunting grounds of the red man,
                            occupied by large cities, and flourishing towns, built by the white man's hands, and in
                            these splendid mansions he likes to sit, make and devise plans, not only to cheat the poor
                            Indian out of his just rights and privileges, but even to cheat his own white brethren."
                            North Union, O. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science of silence" TEIform="index"/>Science of Silence</head><p TEIform="p"> Blessed is the man who knows enough to keep his mouth shut. Some people live sixty years
                            without learning the art. Indeed, the older they grow, the wider their mouths open. A man or
                            woman who is a gabbler at forty-five is a dreadful affliction to a house or a church, or
                            community. There are two things this age needs to learn—when to say nothing, and when it
                            says anything to say it well. "If any man among yon seem to be religious, and bridleth not
                            his tongue, thift man's religion is vain." 57</p></div2><pb n="58" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation by education: a plea for the universal education of youth" TEIform="index"/>SALVATION BY EDUCATION A plea for the universal education of youth</head><p TEIform="p"> The benefits of education should be extended to all children without exception. Even at this
                            late day it is not a superfluous task to vindicate the claims of the offspring of the poor,
                            of the poorest, of the vilest, to that mental cultivation, which it is in the power of every
                            nation to bestow. That old notion is not yet stowed away among the forgotten rubbish of old
                            times, that those, who were for labor and servitude, were born for nothing but labor and
                            servitude ; and the less they knew, the better they would obey, and that the only
                            instruction which was necessary or safe for them to receive, was that which would teach them
                            to move like automata, precisely as those above them pulled the gtrings. I say we still hear
                            this false principle asserted, though perhaps in more guarded and indefinite language ; and
                            a more selfish, pernicious, disgraceful principle, in whatever terms it may be muffled up,
                            never insulted human nature, nor degraded human society. It is the leading principle of
                            despotism, the worst feature of aristocracy, and profane contradiction of that indubitable
                            word, which has pronounced all men to be brethren, and in every thing which relates to their
                            common nature, equal. In short it is only to the domestic animals, to the brutes that God
                            has given for our use, that this principle can with justice be applied. Their education is
                            not to be carried beyond obedience, because their faculties will not authorize a more
                            liberal discipline. We are to feed them well, and use them gently, and our duty toward them
                            is performed. But to say that this is the extent of our obligations toward any class or
                            description of our fellow beings, is to advance the monstrous proposition, that their
                            capacity is as low as their circumstantial situations ; and that their degree is among those
                            who wear the yoke, and eat the grass of the field. But the truth is, that the minds of any
                            one class are as improvable as the minds of any other class of me, andn may be therefore,
                            improved in the same way, by the same means, and to as good purposes. Once grant that all
                            human beings have the same human faculties, and you grant, to all, the complete right of the
                            unlimited cultivation of those faculties. Nor is it at all more rational to suppose, that a
                            judicious education of the poor, conducted to any attainable extent, will be liable to abuse
                            in their hands, and lead them to forget their station and their duty, than that it will have
                            similar effects on those who are nourished on the lap of affluence. The experience that has
                            been collected on this point, only strengthens the deductions of analogy, and confirms the
                            important position, which has hitherto gained too little practical faith in the world, that,
                            the more a people know, the less exposed they are to every description of extravagance.
                            Wherever there is an uninformed mind, there is an unknown amount of lost usefulness and
                            dormant energy. If this is so through the negligence or perversity of the individual, with
                            him is the guilt, and with him be the punishment; if this is so through the influence of
                            sentiments which are current in society, the fearful responsibility rests with those who
                            avow and maintain them. I see not why the man who would repress, and who does repress, as
                            far as in him lies, the moral and intellectual capabilities of a fellow creature, is not as
                            culpable as if he abused and destroyed his own. I have said that the children of the vilest
                            and lowest portion of the community share in the general right to the advantages of
                            education. Their claim possesses a peculiar title to our consideration. Some have spoken as
                            if such were beneath or beyond our assistance and bring contamination from their birth
                            place. Their lot is in the region of irreclaimable wickedness it is said, and as their
                            parents are, so are they destined to become. Destined! and so they are if you will not help
                            to save them. They are destined and forever chained down to a state of moral loathsomeness,
                            in which degradation seems to be swallowed with the food, and vice breathed in with the air.
                            And shall they stay in such a pit of darkness? Is not their situation the strongest possible
                            appeal, which can be made to your pity, generosity, sense of justice, and love of good? <pb n="59" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAEEB 59 Does it not call on you most loudly and imperatively, to
                            pluck the brands from the burning, ere yet they have been scorched too deeply and darkly by
                            the flames? Nothing is more probable than that such children may be preserved to virtue by a
                            timely interference ; nothing is more certain, than that they will be lost if they remain. I
                            know of no call, which promises such ample success and reward to the spirited efforts of
                            benevolence as this. Vice may be cut off, in a great measure, of her natural increase, by
                            the adoption of her offspring into the family of virtues; and though it is true, that the
                            empire of guilt receives constant emigrations and fresh accessions of strength, from all the
                            regions of society, yet it is equally true, that they whose only crime it is that they were
                            born within its confines, may be snatched away, and taught another allegiance, before they
                            have become accustomed to its language, familiar with its corruptions, and have vowed a
                            dreadful fidelity to its laws. Religion is the only sure foundation of virtue ; and what is
                            any human being, young or .old, rich or poor without virtue? He cannot be trusted, confided
                            in or loved. Religion is the only sure index of duty; and how can any one pursue an even or
                            a reputable course, without rules and without principles? Religion is the only guide to true
                            happiness, and who is there so hardy as to assume the tremendous responsibility of
                            withholding those instructions and consolations, which dispel doubt; soothe affliction, make
                            the bed of sickness, smoothly spread the dying pillow, and open the gates of an effulgent
                            happiness? Let, then, religion be the primary object in the education of the young. Let it
                            mingle naturally, and gracefully, in all their pursuits and acquirements. Let it be rendered
                            intelligible, attractive, and practical. Let it win their affections, command their
                            reverence, and ensure their obedience. Children of any class whatever, may be taught in a
                            great compass and liberality of knowledge; not only without apprehension, but with assiduity
                            and encouragement; but let them above all things, be "taught of the Lord." And what follows?
                            When all thy children shall be taught of the Lord, what is the promise, the reward and the
                            consumation? "Great shall be the peace of thy children." All the blessings, signified by
                            that word peace, shall be the lot of those who are thus wisely instructed, and these shall
                            descend on the community, in proportion as it has exerted itself to diffuse light and
                            religion throughout its whole mass. Knowledge of itself is power, and when the knowledge of
                            the Lord is united with it, it is happiness and real pros- perity. Order reigns—the best
                            order—that which is produced, not so much by the operations of authority and law, as by the
                            independent righteousness of each individual, who bears about with him his own law : freedom
                            finds its congenial habitation and home; for general intelligence inspires mutual respect,
                            and self respect; and "where the spirit of the Lord is there is liberty." Benevolence is
                            ever active and zealous ; for knowledge is the enemy of selfishness. Religion warms and
                            expands, the heart and the discipline of Christ is assured that the best service of God, is
                            the service of mankind. In short, there cannot be other than a sense of security, and a
                            composed countenance of peace, felt and experienced throughout society, when those
                            principles of religious knowledge are generally and practically received, which hold up to
                            the face of every man, his duty to his Maker, to his neighbor, and to his own soul. Then
                            there is that separate individual peace, which takes up its dwelling in the minds and hearts
                            of all those who have been taught of the Lord, a peace holy, heavenly, profound, which the
                            world cannot give because it is above the world and independent of it; the peace of a quiet
                            conscience, of a regulated mind, of innocent hopes, of calm desires, of the love which
                            embraces humanity, and the trust which reposes on heaven; a gentle river running through the
                            life, imparting beauty, pouring out refreshment, and lending its grateful moisture to the
                            most hidden and attenuated roots and threads of sen- iment and feeling, clothing the sands
                            with verdure, and sprinkling the lonely places with sweet flowers. Add this peace of each
                            single bosom to that general peace which pervades the community, and how truly may it e
                            called great! I deny not that a nation may become powrful, victorious, renowned, wealthy,
                            and full <pb n="60" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> of great men, even though it should neglect the education of
                            the humbler classes of its population; but I do deny, that it can ever become a happy or
                            truly prosperous nation till all its children are taught of the Lord. To say nothing of the
                            despotisms of the east, look at the kingdoms of Europe, with their battles and their
                            alliances, and their pompous and gaudy ceremonies ; their imposing clusters of high titles
                            and celebrated names; and after this showy phantasmagoria has passed away, mark the
                            condition of the majority, observe their superstition, their slavishness, their sensual
                            enjoyments, their limited range of thought, their almost brutalized existence ; mark this,
                            and say, whether a heavenly peace is among them ! Alas, they know not the things which
                            belong to their peace; nor are their rulers desirous that they should know; but they rather
                            prefer that these should live on in submissive ignorance, that they may be at all times
                            ready to swell trains of their master's pride, and be sacrificed by hecatombs to their
                            master's ambition. South Union, Ky.$$ </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 10" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN CULTURE. No. 10</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName">WM. H. BUSSELL </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Patience: This is usually styled a passive virtue, in contradistinction to those called
                            active. But, strictly speaking, none of the virtues requires more constant exercise than
                            this. It presupposes a life demanding hardihood of character, the very opposite of luxury
                            and indolence. The apostle Paul represents the Christian life as a warfare, and
                            exhorts,—"Endure hardness as a good soldier." Also, as a race—*"Let us run with patience the
                            race that is set before us." The poet Longfellow beautifully combines the idea of endurance
                            with that of activity, making them the complements of each-other. "Let us then be up and
                            doing, With a heart for any fate ; Still achieving, still pursuing, Learn to labor and to
                            wait." Nature does not do every thing for man. She requires that he shall supplement her
                            work. Indeed, it sometimes seems as though she were acting in direct opposition to his best
                            interests. He is often led to ask, why these countless enemies to success, when he is doing
                            his utmost to succeed. Why these frosts and droughts that cut off' his means of subsistence.
                            These tempests and tornadoes, these fires and earthquakes that destroy in a moment the
                            labors of many years, and involve man and his works in one common ruin. To the materialist
                            these things are inexplicable ; not so to the Christian. By these he learns patience and to
                            be a co-worker with God. His hold language is—"Though he slay me, yet will I trust in him."
                            Patience has a far-extending vista, reaching to the very throne of God himself, being
                            co-ordinate with wisdom, love and power. The common adage, "The world was not made in a
                            day," has its application both to man and the earth on which he dwells. Man's life is still
                            only in its incipient stages. As yet he is but brother to the beasts that roam the earth,
                            devouring one another; though here and there are found a few that partake of "angels' food"
                            and hence are beginning to live the life of angels, "unvexed with all the cares of gain,"
                            and free, in a measure" from the beastly passions that are the cause of wars and their
                            unnumbered ills. Genuine, Christian patience is not an unreasoning thing, it is consistent
                            with the highest reason. It looks with the utmost confidence to results of the most
                            gratifying nature, for it perceives an infinite Cause in operations. The impatient mind does
                            not study the Divine operation, and hence the world is a problem it cannot solve. Let the
                            divine inspirations touch it, it can then see "the Hand that moves the world," and trace its
                            various manipulations all along from the feeble beginning to the glorious end. These
                            inspirations are indispensable. The life of Christ within the soul is the life of God there.
                            This not only gives the power of overcoming the spirit of the world within, but imparts the
                            assurance that all tilings will work together for the good of those who love God and
                            ultimately effect the supreme welfare of all men. The patience of God imparts its own
                            MAJSTCFESTO. <pb n="61" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE! SHAKER 61 character to those who are the possessors
                            of it, just as the love of God within changes the sensual, hating, vindictive earthly being
                            to the spiritually kind, gentle and all-loving being. Groveland, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to be accepted" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO BE ACCEPTED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, Jacob" TEIform="persName">JACOB  KULP </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> What shall I do to be of use Unto my fellow-man? How best serve God in spirit, truth, And do
                            the good I can ? I will confess, repent, forsake, And keep my heart from guile ; Perchance
                            my God will then accept And on my offering smile. He asks : "My son give me thine heart,"
                            And can I this refuse ? Nay ! consecration to thy work Is just the life I choose. I give
                            whate'er I claim of earth,— My wealth, my talents,—all, What e'er the gifts I might possess,
                            The offering would be small. The carnal life, the selfish will Must both be crucifiedi; No
                            flesh may glory in thy sight, Nor prosper in its pride. The creeds and forms which progress
                            check, By truth shall be consumed; Then shall thy will on earth be done, And here thy
                            Kingdom come. Thus all who hope to reign with Christ The cross he bore, must bear, Denying
                            all ungodliness And in his sufferings share. The promise is "He shall receive An hundred
                            fold in time ;" Most humbly I acknowledge, Lord, This measure now is mine. Pleasant Hill,
                            Ky. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you suffer your people to be ill educated..." TEIform="index"/>If you suffer your people to be ill educated...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> If you suffer your people to be ill educated, and their manners to be corrupted from their
                            infancy, and then punish them for those crimes to which their first education disposed them,
                            what else is to be concluded from this but that you first make thieves and then punish
                            them?—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="More, Thomas" TEIform="persName">Sir Thomas More </persName></byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blessed sabbath" TEIform="index"/>BLESSED SABBATH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, Ann" TEIform="persName">ANN BUCKINGHAM </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Blessings on the day ! It is now, we feel, unusually, regenerating gifts from God ; and it
                            is a golden interval of time ; new rays of light descend ; the bow of promise shines
                            resplendently upon the changeful life of earth's poor, toiling millions, whose daily
                            hurrying lives are spent in cares. Thanks, one day in seven, a newer blessing reaches their
                            inner hearts, and man's better nature feels the Sabbath holy, and his thoughts rest more on
                            heavenly things. Thanks, yet again ; for is not it a gift divine ? At every periodical
                            recurrence, still greater thanks ; for rich and podfr, bond and free, now lift their souls
                            in prayerful oneness, above all selfish clangor ; a foretaste of the heavenly future, of
                            equal gifts for equal lives of goodness, is seen and realized more truly and fully on the
                            beautiful, blissful season of this holier day— because more devoted to holiness—the Sabbath.
                            Shakers, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Proposed additions to the Rochester platform" TEIform="index"/>PROPOSED ADDITIONS TO THE
                            ROCHESTER PLATFORM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">ELDER F. W. EVANS </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The planks in the National League bridge, that is to pass us safely from the old to the new
                            earth government, are good as far as they go. But there are not enough of them; we shall
                            fall through, unless more are added. To make it safe, I propose to add :— 1. A distinct
                            recognition of women as citizens, equal with men in all the processes of framing and
                            executing the laws. IVLAJSTTF^STO. <pb n="62" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 2. A warrantee deed of all the land
                            in the United States to all the citizens of the United States. 3. A land limitation law,
                            denning the quantity of land that any citizen may purchase, or inherit and hold, after the
                            year 1878. Heirs to inherit, but be compelled, by the limitation laws to sell all land above
                            the legally limited number of acres. The government to legislate poverty out of existence,
                            and each citizen into possession of a portion of land, from which to produce his daily bread
                            by his honest labor. In the "wilderness," all owned the land, and each citizen gathered the
                            "manna" with his and her own hands. This land legislation should respect existing vested
                            rights of individuals and corporations, as is done in making highways, railroads and canals,
                            and as is done in times of intestine and national wars. 4. The abolition of laws for the
                            collection of debts. It is stated that the collection of debts costs more money than the
                            amount collected will pay, and that the lawyers and courts are thereby defrauded of their
                            just or legal dues. Now that the National Liberal League is formed, I feel comforted in my
                            spirit. The Inquisition, with its fires and fagots, its racks and screws, its horrible
                            tortures and dislocations of the human form di- vine, seem further off in the coming future.
                            Cause and effect are no more indissoluble, than it is that any religionist, who believes in
                            war under any circumstances, will advocate the union of Church and State. When Church and
                            State are united, and they have legislative power, they will think they are doing God, and
                            Christ, and the Holy Spirit good, and acceptable service in restraining heretics and
                            infidels, Quakers and Shakers, Freethinkers and Spiritualists. By the Constitutions of
                            several States, those who disbelieve in a personal God and devil, may not be witnesses in
                            law. As God liveth, and as human beings have inalienable right to life-elements— land, air,
                            and sunshine,—let there be no peace, nor rest, until the American gov- ernment is a joy in
                            the earth,—until Shaker communities, and all infidels to Babylon Church-and-State fighting,
                            monopolizing, persecuting theologies, are excluded and forever separated from the halls of
                            legislation and courts of justice, that are for all peoples, nations, and tongues on the
                            face of this earth. Let us all be known only as American citizens. Then shall those be
                            blessed who inherit the earth,—the land ; and wars shall cease to the ends of the earth, for
                            its causes will have been removed forever and ever. Those theologies that make people to be
                            hateful and hate one another, shall be supplanted by the love of God and the love of man,
                            that worketh no ill to its neighbor. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, second paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE Her
                            Work, her People, and their Critics Second Paper.</head><p TEIform="p"> The conjunction of Ann Lee with the revivalists Wardleys, proved to have been opportune for
                            the enhancement and enlargement of the little Society's interests. For by her uncommon
                            diligence in learning of the new life, and from her zeal in the promulgation of the faith,
                            she was instrumental in adding many to the faith, her husband being included among the
                            number. So zealous was Ann in the delivery of the testimony she had imbibed, and so full of
                            the administration of the power which accompanied the faithful, she C3 THE SHAKER
                            MAINTIPIESTO. <pb n="63" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 63 was unanimously chosen as the leader of
                            the little band, and from this time, hence, was called Mother Ann! We will see, as we
                            progress, how worthy she was of the title, and how mother-like she sustained it! It may be
                            well,, before dealing further with the administration of Mother Ann, to describe the movings
                            of the Spirit upon this little people, previous to her becoming their leader; that the
                            reader may realize what she found in progress at the Wardley's when she first visited them,
                            and attended their religious meetings. Let it be remembered, that the revival of the
                            beautiful spirit of Pentecost, began with the Wardley's in Bolton and Manchester, in 1747,
                            when Ann was only nine years of age, who of course was as ignorant of any such movement as
                            she was of her future. The testimony of these people was derived from vision, and a
                            revelation from some source that proclaimed verbally, through them : '' That the second
                            appearing of Christ was at hand, and that the church was rising in her full, transcendant
                            glory, which would effect the final down-fall of antichrist!" Their method of waiting on the
                            Spirit, was after the well-known manner of the Quakers. Sometimes, after assembling
                            together, and sitting a while in silent meditation, they were taken with a mighty trembling,
                            under which they would express the indignation of God against all sin. At other times, they
                            were affected, under the power of God, with a mighty shaking; and were occasionally
                            exercised in singing, shouting, or walking the floor, under the influence of spiritual
                            signs, swiftly passing and repassing each other, like clouds agitated by a mighty wind. Prom
                            these strange exercises the people received the name of Shakers, and by some were called
                            Shaking Quakers; but, from the time of James Wardley's ministration to the present day, they
                            have been most generally known and distinguished by the name of Shakers. Such was the
                            agitation of the religious elements when Ann joined and was baptized by the Shakers. Born
                            Feb. 29, 1736, she was at this time only 22 years of age when by her perfect obedience, she
                            had attained to all that was made manifest in the leading characters of the society, still
                            finding in herself the seed, or remains of human depravity, and a lack of the Divine nature,
                            which is eternal life abiding in the soul, she did not rest satisfied in that state, but
                            labored in continual watchings and fastings, in tears and incessant cries to God, day and
                            night, for deliverance. And, under the most severe tribulation, and violent temptations, as
                            great as she was able to resist and endure, such was, frequently, her extreme agony of soul,
                            that blood would issue through the pores of her skin. By such deep mortification and
                            suffering, her flesh wasted away, and she became like a skeleton, wholly incapable of
                            helping herself; and was fed and nourished like an infant, although, naturally, free from
                            bodily infirmities, and a person of strong and sound constitution, and invincible fortitude
                            of mind. In this manner she was more or less exer- cised in soul and body for about nine
                            years, previous to assuming the leadership, during which period the way of God, and the
                            nature of his work, were gradually opened from one thing to another, and the light and
                            understanding which she received, was gradually communicated to the society, until she
                            received that manifestation of God by which the man of sin was revealed, and through which
                            she discovered the transgression of the first woman—the root and foundation cause of human
                            depravity, whence all mankind were lost and separated from God; and by special and immediate
                            revelation, she received the Testimony of God against the whole corruption of man, in its
                            root and every branch; which is properly, the testimony against the flesh; or the testimony
                            against all sin. This testimony, in its fullness, she received in open vision from the Lord
                            Jesus Christ, who appeared plainly, and clearly revealed the true nature and work of the
                            everlasting Gospel of salvation to her. This was while she was in the public prison, where
                            she was put by the malice of her enemies, through false accusation, because of the searching
                            light and increasing power manifested through her. Thus she received her mission by the
                            heavenly dove, or Divine Anointing Spirit of Christ in the order of the female. Her
                            testimony was now increased in such mighty power of M^ISTZFIESTO. <pb n="64" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER God, attended with the word of prophecy, and such energy of the Spirit, as penetrated
                            into the secrets of the heart, and was irresistible, especially to those with whom she was
                            united Thus, we claim Ann Lee to have been the prepared and inspired woman, through whom
                            Christ's second manifestation was made evident to the world, in its true testimony against,
                            and power over sin. Known now to all as Mother, she refused all other titles, even of Madame
                            or Mrs. Entering upon the leadership in 1770, the order of religious exercises became more
                            governable ; but as full, and more so, of the revival spirit. Large numbers would come to
                            witness their devotions and to hear their testimony. They would sing, dance, shake and
                            shout; speak in new and unknown tongues, and prophesy understanding^ : they had all the
                            movings of the spirit, even to the healing of the sick, wounded, etc. that presented
                            themselves at the earlier Pentecostal church, when the Holy Ghost came ¦ down upon the early
                            believers in Jesus. While these spiritual demonstrations remained a novelty, and did not
                            interfere with any but themselves, they enjoyed the privileges dictated by the spirit. But
                            their testimony was for the world, and when, through public declarations, attacks were made
                            upon the sensual, idolatrous practices of the masses, in the lusts of the flesh and the
                            pride of life, then there rose tumultuous mobs, by whom she and her followers were most
                            shamefully abused, and she was particularly ill-used, being several times imprisoned. It was
                            while she was thus imprisoned— having been put there for the purpose of starving her to
                            death—that the door of her cell never turned on its hinges for fourteen days, nor did she
                            receive a visit from any, save one—a little boy, who being permitted to visit her once a
                            day, but not to see her, nor converse with her excepting through the key-hole, concealed a
                            bottle of milk and wine, which with a pipe-stem he fed to her. It was at this time she
                            claimed the spirit of Jesus Christ made its appearance to her, and also made to her the
                            grand annunciation of her mission! She was charged with blasphemy; and when after two weeks,
                            her keepers surprised at finding her alive, took her before a council of ministers, with a
                            demand by the mob that she should suffer the penalty for such an offence—that her tongue
                            should be bored, and her cheek branded with a B. Her judges heard her, questioned her, found
                            her to be most illiterate, yet wanted and demanded an exhibition of her speaking in unknown
                            tongues. The spirit moved her tongue to their more than satisfaction; for in speaking
                            several hours, she had delivered herself in more than seventy languages, much of which was
                            understood by her judges. These acquitted her, advising the people to let her and followers
                            go in peace; but they would not, and taking them apart from the city began stoning them, but
                            without harm, for dissensions arising among themselves, they scattered, leaving them alone!
                            Many such trials might be narrated of her and people while in England; and although rejected
                            by the people at large, the little company enjoyed in seclusion the benefits accruing from
                            their faith. For two years, while Mother Ann yet remained in England, the public testimony
                            ceased. She was now directed to repair to America, where she saw, in vision, the hand of God
                            preparing the way for the formation of a government, under which any and all could be as
                            good as they pleased, and testify of the inspirations of the spirit, as coming from
                            quickened and progressed consciences unhindered. * (continued.) </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thou art our God" TEIform="index"/>THOU ART OUR GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Huntington, Eunice" TEIform="persName">EUNICE HUNTINGTON </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> O Lord Thou rulest in the Heavens ; Thy footprints on the Earth are seen; Oft warnings from
                            Thy voice are given In mercy to the sons of men. Ah who Thy voice will recognize, Although
                            in thunder tones it sounds \ And who to Heaven send forth their cries, "While e'er thy mercy
                            still abounds ! The elements are in Thy hands, The watery depths move at Thy will; Thy laws
                            we may not understand, But of Thy mercies know full well. 64 MANIFESTO. <pb n="65" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER For Thou didst call by Thine own voice Our souls from Sodom's dark domain; By
                            inspiration, prompt our choice, O'er sin and death to rise and reign. May many thousands
                            hear the call And bravely struggle for the prize; Of earthly claims abandon all, Nor fail to
                            sever carnal ties. That in Thy kingdom they may stand, All clad in spotless robes of white;
                            With palms of victory in their hands And heads bedecked with crowns of light. Abundant
                            mercies of our God Are manifest in gifts of grace ;— Thy Son and Daughter, by Thy word, Have
                            brought redemption to our race. Forever hallowed be Thy name, Thou glorious Being all divine
                            ; All hail the Everlasting Twain, Whose brightness thro' the ransomed shine Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak unto me excellent things" TEIform="index"/>"Speak Unto Me Excellent Things"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName">Elder Otis Sawyer </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Speak not to me of sadness, Speak not to me of gloom, Speak not to me of darkness, Nor of
                            the silent tomb ; But tell me of the beauties rare, That in the pure heart bloom— 0, tell me
                            of the beauties rare, That in the pure heart bloom! Ah, tell me not of pleasures, A worldly
                            life can give ; And tell me not of treasures, Which death cannot retrieve; Nor of the deep,
                            heart-felt remorse, Of those who disbelieve— Alas, the deep, heart-felt remorse Of those who
                            disbelieve ! 0, tell me of the brightness, Of heaven all aglow; Where love, in all its
                            richness, From angel hearts o'erflow; And tell me of their golden crowns, And raiment white
                            as snow— 0, tell me of their golden crowns And raiment white as snow. I would be like the
                            Angels, Of purity and love; On earth I'd form a heaven, As formed in realms above; Where
                            flowers bloom, and music sweet Floats on the balmy air; And shouts of praise from the
                            redeemed, Proclaim the crowns they wear. West Gloucester, Maine. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Solomon Rankin, South Union, Ky My Dear Sir :—I have read all the papers you gave me..." TEIform="index"/>Solomon Rankin, South Union, Ky My Dear Sir :—I have read all the papers you gave me...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Illinois, Cairo, February 1, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Cairo, Ill. Feb. 1, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">Solomon Rankin, South Union, Ky My Dear Sir :—I have read all the papers you gave me,
                                relating to Shakerism, and I must say that I have derived much information and much
                                comfort. I say comfort designedly, because your religion aims at a close similitude to
                                perfection, and embraces a clear determination to follow the example of perfection. When
                                Christ said "Follow me, I am the way and the life," he said it with a full knowledge of
                                its import. That import was a separation from the world and its alluring follies ; and
                                if the followers of Christ remain in the practice of worldly and unchristian pursuits,
                                where is the "following" that Christ rec- ommends ? I am more than impressed with the
                                points of life as set forth in the pamphlet you gave me, and I wish to visit you again
                                and learn more of your people and their religion. I desire you to , treat me as a
                                novitiate, because I am in love with your holy lives and sublime truths. I am sick of
                                Sin ; I see my own shapeless deformity as a sinner: I want more light, more truth, more
                                rest <pb n="66" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MLAJSTHPESTO. from Sin under Confession and
                                Repentance. In spirit I am a Shaker. I will yet come to you. Your friend and pupil, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pryor, Charles R." TEIform="persName">Charles R. Pryor</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="G. A. Lomas, Beloved brother and Editor: Although a stranger to you personally..." TEIform="index"/>G. A. Lomas, Beloved brother and Editor: Although a stranger to you personally...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Although a stranger to you personally, I feel that' you are my brother in the bonds of
                                the gospel, the most endearing relationship on this earth. I feel emboldened by this
                                relationship to address to you a few lines, expressive of my admiration of the Little
                                Messenger edited by you, and called The Shaker Manifesto. A few 'thoughts have occurred
                                to me while contemplating the goodness and loving kindness of our heavenly parents, in
                                providing heavenly pasture for their sheep, in this wondrous gospel of peace and
                                good-will to man. I desire to lay before you my contribution for your disposal as you
                                think fit. Never having addressed you before, and never having written anything for
                                publication I know not that I can offer anything that will come up to your standard of
                                approval. If you should consider this worthy of being consigned to the waste basket I
                                shall not be displeased, but will still cherish for it and its editor the same love and
                                affection as heretofore. I consider it the repository of the highest and noblest
                                sentiments known to human nature, and capable of lifting up • the fallen race of man to
                                higher and loftier conditions, than are yet attained unto. Having been privileged with a
                                home among Believers at Mt. Lebanon for three years past I have been fed by your
                                writings and Elder Frederick's labors, so unselfishly bestowed upon our monthly visitor,
                                that I cannot allow you longer to remain in ignorance of the gratitude I feel, for so
                                noble a devotion to the cause of Zion—true missionary labor in God's vineyard, I
                                consider it is without a rival in purity and excellence and beauty of form; and I will
                                endeavor to tell you, in part what it has been to me during my three years' privilege.
                                It has been to me meat and drink, strength and consolation. My love and reverence for
                                Zion and her cause has been quickened and revived ; and by its aid 1 have been admitted
                                to the inner sanctuary of my brethren and sisters in Christ—the temples of those at
                                least who contribute to its columns—and I have thus in a measure been able to see what
                                was in their hearts for God. What a treasure I have found ! more precious to me than all
                                the wealth that earth can boast. Some months ago, Elder Henry C. Blinn commented in The
                                Shaker on the phrase used by the Shakers, "I kindly thank you." It reminded me of the
                                first time I heard it in New York. It had come directly from the Shakers, and I believed
                                it originated with them ; at any rate it kindled a love in my heart for those who drew
                                me towards them in spirit; and twenty years thereafter, principally by the influence of
                                those little words, I was drawn within their fold at Mt. Lebanon. And here I have found
                                fathers and mothers, sisters and brothers, who have returned to me a thousand fold for
                                all I have sacrificed, and have caused me a thousand times to shout for joy in the
                                spirit, that the privilege was given me to make my offering, and there to find myself
                                and family accepted. 66 <pb n="67" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 67 I found at Mt.
                                Lebanon, kind, gospel kindred, who were willing to care for me, minister the strength to
                                my weakness most adapted to my needs. At that time they nurtured and fed me, and bore
                                with me in my ignorance, folly and pride ; self-conceit and worldliness of heart and
                                mind that I brought with me, and planted me in this gospel, establishing me on the rock
                                of revelation. And now, beloved brother, I desire to "thank you kindly" for what you
                                have been to me through The Shaker ; and through you I would "kindly thank all" the
                                contributors to The Shaker Manifesto. I love you all; would that I could tell you how
                                much my prayer is, that our little messenger may prosper and continue its missionary
                                work, until its influence is appreciated wherever needy i man is found. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In for the blessing, and out at the slander" TEIform="index"/>In for the blessing, and out at the slander
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Can there be a better ire, or out, than this? We think not, and must congratulate
                                everyone ripon his wise choice, who joins us in the happy resolution. We are all
                                creatures of action, and incline daily to find outings and innings of some kind. How
                                brave and wise that we always seek these needed changes by true and noble principles. It
                                is more than meat and drink to live an earnest, free and happy life; but only such can
                                enjoy this boon, who are in for the blessing, and out at the slander. Canterbury, N. H.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer draws all Christian graces into its focus" TEIform="index"/>Prayer draws all Christian graces into its focus
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Prayer draws all Christian graces into its focus. It draws charity with her lovely train;
                                repentance, with her holy sorrows; faith, with her elevated eyes ; hope, with "her
                                grasped anchor; benevolence, with her opened hands ; zeal, looking far and wide to
                                bless; and humility, looking at home. —</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="More, Hannah" TEIform="persName">Hannah More </persName></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto:--Shakerism: the world's spiritual metre" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM: The
                            World's Spiritual Metre</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Societies are numerically populated, and strengthened physically and spiritually,
                            entirely by accessions from those once not of their peculiar faith and organizations. They
                            are ever thus nour- ished when genuine, religious revivals are visited upon the
                            people—whenever the real Christ makes its presence felt. Hence, in the absence of those
                            seasons of deep contrition upon the multitudes ; a want of real, soul conviction for sins ;
                            the quietude of the spiritual waters ; the cool indifference of the masses as "to whom shall
                            we go?" for "the faith once delivered to the saints," the aforesaid Societies keenly feel
                            the want of that valuable nourishment, and that invaluaole assistance which ever accompany a
                            genuine baptism of the people, by Christ's spirit. Our only hopes of the continuance and
                            permanence of the Societies, lie in our iaith that God loves the people ; will visit them
                            religiously ; ripen them fit for the spiritual harvest, "cut their lives off rom the
                            earthly," procreative plane, to ie angelic men and women in heavens, on earthbegun. Such has
                            been the promse of God to us as a people, and never las the promise failed us yet. To be
                            sure, we have seen dark, tryng seasons ; we have passed many deponding nights ; we have had
                            occasions when to doubt seemed justifiable, and j <pb n="68" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE when the
                            hand of Providence seemed shortened, its ear heavy and we left forgotten and forsaken ! We
                            have seen the flood tides of revivals filling our homes with individuals beyond our
                            conveniences, and had our hopes droop when the ebbing carried back to the seas of
                            worldliness as unfit material, the larger part of the accumulation netted therefrom, until
                            we have sighed from the depths of our hearts over the remnant: '' And will ye also go away?"
                            But God has been with us, and thus far the institution has been providentially
                            preserved—there has been too much good therein, for God to forsake it or its sustainers. It
                            still stands ! if not in all the exaltation of more spiritual conditions, yet sufficiently
                            permanent for the further salvation of the people, for whose spiritual baptism we sincerely,
                            earnestly pray, and for whose ensnarement into the gospel net, we as patiently and hopefully
                            wait. Waiting, we would work ; even as the heavenly Father "worketh hitherto," for the hopes
                            and happiness, the security of greater salvation for the people from besetting sins, over
                            which they really have no power of control! And our prayers and work avail something.
                            Finding insufficient power of salvation from the temptations and sins of unchristian lives,
                            many have asked, and will again ask : "To whom shall we go?" And while the seven-principled
                            tramp comes and goes—is cast back into the deep after having eaten of out five loaves and
                            two fishes—the really soul-hungering penitent, meets the Father and is received, "to go no
                            more out forever." Soon after the Shaker Churches at Mt. Lebanon N. Y. and Watervliet (now
                            Shakers N. Y.) were organized, all accessoins of a desirable kind ceased entirely ! Just
                            when the people so organized into churches had most hopes, that God would send hungering
                            souls for the bread of life in their keeping, all applications stopped! For eight or ten
                            years this stagnation continued; and some, grown weary of waiting, despondent and hopeless,
                            departed from the institution, to the exceeding sorrow of those remaining. In the year 1800,
                            Issachar Bates came to Watervliet as an inquirer ; and the whole settlement was roused to a
                            high pitch of excitement over the fact that the gospel had sufficiently opened to at- tract
                            a single individual who wanted more salvation than he could get elsewhere ! The news soon
                            reached Mt. Lebanon, and Asenath Clark, then a youth, (but afterward presiding Eldress of
                            the Societies,) ran from room to room, and from individual to individual, with the joyful
                            tidings : "The gospel has opened, for a man has come !" From this small opening, let us see
                            what followed, thank God, and take courage : Issachar Bates brought his family of nine ;
                            then came Benjamin Youngs with his family of seven ; then Seth Youngs with five ; then David
                            Train with nine ; followed by Jason Harwood with nine more ; then came the noble, royal,
                            Wells family of sixteen! then William Carter with seven ; Elizabeth Bowser with /our, and
                            Betsy Lovegrove with four more; another royal family followed, the Vedders, with seven;
                            Ralph Hodgson brought six with him ; Justus Brewster's family cotated seven; Frederick
                            Wicker's six, and Prime Lane's (colored) numbered seven. Ten more who came singly, without
                            families, complete the count of those who united at Watervliet, during the 68 MAJSTTEniESTO.
                                <pb n="69" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 69 ylars of 1800, 1801, 1802 and 1803— four
                            years ! Ujidthe beauty, brilliancy and best part to tell of these, is that nearly all
                            remained jto grow to advanced ages, pillars to the institution, having hundreds to rise up
                            and call them blessed, with many thousands yet to come, and to do praise to their
                            consecrations ! The times are dull, spiritually ; the heavens now seem unusually closed to
                            the impartation of heavenly gifts ; the special notices of the near, spiritual world, are
                            for a reason and for a season very measurably withdrawn ; the neces- sity of keeping our
                            conditions well ordered, with lamps trimmed and burning to meet some midnight cries, seems
                            hardly like a necessity, and greater conformity with worldliness seems almost desirable ;
                            but these trials of our faith, will prove the faithful worthy of the grand- est promotions.
                            Let us take heart, and fling doubt and despondency to the winds. Let us, and all the world
                            realize, that our maintenance as a spiritual organization entirely depends upon its genuine
                            religious revivals : that large faith in God is a necessity, to live in hopes of these
                            revivals ; and that our Shaker Societies will ever indicate by their fullness of active,
                            reliable members just how spiritually in- clined the world is, being the hope of its people
                            unto their greater and perfect salvation.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of the aged" TEIform="index"/>CARE OF THE AGED</head><p TEIform="p"> Do not let us forget those in the decline of life. We are very liable to fail of realizing
                            how soon people feel the effects of age, and thus need some especial considerations of the
                            young and strong. A hundred ways will open to mind whereby such can alleviate the cares
                            which declining years and strength always bring, and, without waiting for ambition to fail
                            those in life's decline, let the young do for them those hundreds of little kindnesses which
                            add so much comfort to them, and satisfaction to the givers, and almost make the aged forget
                            the pangs of growing old. Familiarity with their sufferings and trials, should be no excuse
                            for even a seeming neglect of the care they need from the young. Though they may inwardly
                            groan at their loss of youthful vivacity, let the young try to realize that they may be
                            left, by age and infirmities, to have just such feelings, and then may also need such kindly
                            considerations as those of activity and strength are now able to bestow. While the aged
                            should be kind to each other, may they be also patiently forbearing with the indiscretions
                            of those younger, who should be mindful, that, while the grinding misfortunes of sufferings
                            from infirmity and age unpleasantly burden the feelings of those upon whom they fall, yet,
                            no excuse can ever reasonably intrude for want of care for them, nor of casting them off,
                            with neglect of the bestowal of comforts according to their conditions. How dreadfully cold
                            to such, is even the apparent indifference of those, who should be staves upon whom they
                            might lean for support, as their children in the Gospel of Christ, having forsaken all
                            natural kin for the Gospel's sake, they are now reasonably looking for more kind care, and
                            sweeter comforts from their spiritual posterity. "How sharper than a serpent's tooth it is,
                            To have a thankless child." <pb n="70" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER M^TSTEEHESTO. Then let us see
                            to it that the G-ospel Providences are superior, and more plentiful in behalf of the aged,
                            than the best of care administered by the relatives of consanguinity. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Animadvertory" TEIform="index"/>ANIMADVERTORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We have been kindly apprehended, for certain allusions made in our last number,
                                unpleasantly reflecting on the apostle Paul. Our friends need have no fears, that Paul
                                will not be duly respected at this office. We have paid him the highest of compliments,
                                and still do so, when we say, that his life was Christian, his permissions were not, and
                                that he lived much better than he taught. These same friends admit, that Paul did grant
                                unchristian permissions for worldly, fleshly indulgences which Jesus never did, nor
                                would do to-day. They apologize for Paul however, offering as an excuse, the class and
                                character of the people he had to deal with. We admit all of this. We admit Paul thought
                                it best; believed it the only way to build up a church—believed he never would get a
                                church together unless he did so ; yet after all these admissions, we arraign Paul for
                                granting the permissions ; for intimating the futility of good works ; for making faith
                                more necessary than works ; for introducing the doctrine of the atonement, and for
                                various doctrines inimical to the life and gospel of Jesus, the Christ, to which, those
                                loving the pleasures of the world, and not the life of Christ, fly to, as Christian (?)
                                permissions to live unlike Jesus ; and will continue so to do while Paul is reverenced
                                as he is. He is not reverenced by the masses for the life that he lived—for his living
                                testimony—but for the permissions he has given those desiring them, of living in their
                                carnal lusts, thus evading the life of Christ, being consoled by Paul tfiat "Jesus paid
                                it all!" When the clergy shall leave Paul, and accept the life and living testimony of
                                Jesus, the Christ, as the guide of their lives and testimonies to the people ; then, and
                                not till then will evasion cease, and pure, unadulterated Christianity be preached.
                                Paul, little thought of the mischief he was handing down to future generations, where,
                                in excusing for the time only, some carnal, heathenish Corinthians, he was making the
                                foundations of so many modern churches, where the name of Christ is often heard, but
                                whose life does not mingle in the elements of their constitutions ; that the secret
                                lives of those who are the constituents of these churches, are as far from his life and
                                the life of the master—av_e, farther than the flesh-loving, self-seeking desires of
                                "foolish Galatians and carnal Corinthians !" Should Jesus come again to-day, would he
                                not rebuke us, for not more strongly rebuking these permissions of Paul, and protesting
                                against the ungodly use of his name? </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Abraham Stanley" TEIform="index"/>ABRAHAM STANLEY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We have received some admonition from some of our friends for the sympathy we extended
                                the above person in Feb. No. 'Tis true, he finally turned most bitterly against Mother
                                Ann ; but not until years after the time there spoken of. Mother Ann loved him ; spoke
                                often of his patient forbearance with her, when he did not know "why she acted as she
                                did when she was convicted of her sins, and as yet he was not; when she would turn from
                                them, and he was not yet convinced of their being sins; and yet was "kind, patient and
                                forbearing," we must repeat, that ufor this period of his life" we feel sorry for, and
                                in sympathy with him. Nor for him alone. Between married partners, one of whom embraced
                                faith in virgin purity while the other did not, it is easy to anticipate many incidents
                                calculated to of7O <pb n="71" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. fend the unbeliever,
                                causing such one to belless kind and patient than was Abraham Stanley, at this period of
                                his life. We are not done with Abraham Stanley ; but did he not act nobly so far ? We
                                presented him, and now hold him up, so far, as a model for husbands with wives, very
                                anxious to be and to live like the Shakers ! </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our hopes" TEIform="index"/>OUR HOPES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We do not expect to live to any great age ; but we do live in large hopes of hearing,
                                that through the gift of some benevolent person, having no better use for it, the sum of
                                at least ten thousands of dollars has been put out at interest in behalf of The Shaker
                                Manifesto ! We have ever been confident, of living to see this provision made for The
                                Shaker, either in propria personse, or springing from the posthumous relics of some one
                                or ones, who, sitting in the heavens, will thus everlastingly smile on us, or the work
                                being done by our modest Manifesto. Do you think, will it be so? </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Infidelity" TEIform="index"/>INFIDELITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Let none be surprised at the rapid increase of infidelity in the land. There are so many
                                professedly Christian people, with so very little practical Christianity, that the
                                wonder is, there are not more blatant infidels to indict them. Let it be as plainly as
                                it is reasonably understood, that professions often lie; that he or she is a Christian,
                                who lives as Jesus Christ did ; otherwise every pro- fessedly Christian family is, to be
                                very mild, a school of practical infidelity. Whoso wears the name of Christ, must depart
                                from all iniquity. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> We hereby give The Voice of Angels notice, that if a spirit said to it, that he was "the
                                Shaker, Jeremiah Lowe," he ought to be indicted for perjury. Jeremiah is not dead; and
                                if not as good as he ought to be, is yet very much too good to be so reported. Let those
                                spirits be tried. </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Can any one imagine our feelings, upon reading in Elder F. W. Evans' letter to the
                                editor of The American Socialist, that it was "the best conducted periodical of which he
                                had any knowledge I" He did not even except The Shaker Manifesto !! Have we not reason
                                to complain? </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two lives" TEIform="index"/>THE TWO LIVES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newhall, Cora M." TEIform="persName">CORA M. NEWHALL </persName></byline><p TEIform="p">I once knew of a little girl, who always wished she could become as good as some of the
                                friends with whom she lived. One day, when alone she said to herself: "Now there are two
                                ways of life, and I must choose one of these two. One is the Christian's life; and the
                                other is the worldly life. One tells me to obey the teachings of my father and mother,
                                take up my little cross against thinking of naughty things, and letting unkind words
                                fall from my lips. It teaches me to be kind to my mates and to heed the Golden Rule—"Do
                                unto others, as I would that others should do unto me." It teaches me to cultivate good
                                manners; to say "Good Morning," or to make some friendly greeting when meeting my
                                companions. It teaches me to trust in those who are older, and wiser than I am;
                                believing that what they say or do, is for my present and future good. It also teaches
                                me to correct my faults before retiring to rest at night; to resist temptation, shun bad
                                company, and to be honest, clean, and pure. Now the worldly life does not teach me these
                                good things. It allows me to disobey my parents, to be dishonest, to go where my
                                inclinations lead, and not to heed the voice of conscience when it says "You are doing
                                wrong!" I do not like this way of living so well because I will be unhappy. I think I'll
                                take the Christian's life, and become like those whom I love to look upon, for I know I
                                shall be happier in this life, at least. My young readers, how many of you have 71 <pb n="72" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKBE such thoughts in your hearts ? I have been acquainted
                                with this little girl, for twenty years; and not once has she regretted the choice she
                                made to live that life which would make her a noble woman; though she has failed many
                                times to do what was right—just as all little people are apt to do sometimes. Remember
                                therefore, that to choose a good thing, is a safe way, and is never to be regretted.
                                Canterbury, N. H. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speaking of salt..." TEIform="index"/>Speaking of salt...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Speaking of salt, brings to our mind an instance of its beneficial result, when applied
                                to trees. It will be nothing new to old fruit raisers, that Quince trees will bear but
                                little, unless salted annually. Where we now reside, previous to our possession of the
                                place, were two Quinces of good growth; but they had never borne a single specimen
                                previous to our occupation. We surmised the cause, and the first fall applied about a
                                pint of salt to each, scattering it about the tree, on the ground. The result the next
                                season was three fair specimens. The following fall we repeated the experiment, and
                                obtained, for our trouble, a fair yield of good fruit. We have applied salt every year
                                since, and have never failed of a crop. Salt your Quince trees annually by all means;
                                they require it even more than that best of vegetables, asparagus. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindness in handling horses" TEIform="index"/>Kindness in Handling Horses</head><p TEIform="p">One very bad habit or practice we observe both in the city and in the country is, that of
                                yelling at horses before cart, wagon, omnibus or buggy, with that of suddenly and
                                violently jerking the reins, supplementing it with sharp shrieks of the voice, provided
                                they make any untoward movement—a habit we deem no less reprehensible than detestable,
                                and one that should be at once corrected and abandoned torever. Gentleness and kindness
                                will be found not only the wiser and better, but the more humane and effective course in
                                accomplishing the end desired. </p></div3><div3 type="plant" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Introduction of the potato" TEIform="index"/>Introduction of the Potato</head><p TEIform="p">Sir Walter proved to be one of the greatest benefactors to his own country, and
                                eventually to the United States, by the introduction of the potato, in the year 1584.
                                The root was first planted on Raleigh's estate at Youghall, which was afterwards sold to
                                the Earl of Cork, and the person who had the management of the estate, mistook the
                                flower or fruit, as he called it, for the valuable part, and on tasting the potato ball
                                pronounced it a pernicious exotic. Sometime afterwards, on turning up the earth, it was
                                discovered that the root had spread largely.and in considerable quantities; and from
                                this source Great Britain's potato supply commenced and then gradually the cultivation
                                was extended through North America. The potato is supposed to have been a native of
                                Mexico. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The benefit which the manure pile receives..." TEIform="index"/>The benefit which the manure pile receives...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The benefit which the manure pile receives from the rich food fed, depends very much
                                upon the condition of the animal to which it is fed. In fact, the value of the manure
                                depends almost as much upon the condition of the animal as upon the quality of the food.
                            </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To brown butter" TEIform="index"/>To brown butter...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To Brown Butter : a simple recipe but a useful one. Put a lump of butter, as large as the
                                gravy demands, into a frying pan. When it is melted, dredge it with browned flour, and
                                stir to a smooth batter until it boils. Use this to color and flavor gravies. It makes a
                                nice sauce of itself. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lemon or orange butter" TEIform="index"/>Lemon or Orange Butter</head><p TEIform="p">Take one lemon, grate the rind, add the entire juice ; add two well beaten eggs, and one
                                cup of sugar; mix thoroughly, and use as an accompaniment to bread and butter, or
                                separately as a preserve. For Orange butter, use an orange instead of a lemon. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Housekeeper's table" TEIform="index"/>The Housekeeper's Table</head><p TEIform="p"> The following is a very valuable table, by which persons not having scales and weights
                                72 MANIFESTO. <pb n="73" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER •73 at hand may readily measure the
                                article wanted to form any recipe without the trouble of weighing. Allowance to be made
                                for an extraordinary dryness or moisture of the article weighed or measured. Weights and
                                Measures. Wheat flour, one pound is one quart. Indian meal, one lb. two oz. are one
                                quart. Butter, when soft, one lb. is one quart. Loaf sugar, broken, one lb. is one qt.
                                White sugar, powdered, one lb. one oz. are one qt. Ten eggs are one lb. Flour, eight
                                qts. are one peck. Flour, four pecks are one bushel. Liquids etc. Sixteen large
                                tablespoonfuls are half a pt, E'K"t " " " » one gin. Four " " " half a gill. Two gills
                                are one half pint. Two pints are one quart. Four quarts are one gallon. A common sized
                                tumbler holds one hall pt, A common sized wine-glass, half a gill. A tea-cup holds one
                                gill. A large wine glass is two ounces. A tablespoonful is half an ounce. Forty drops
                                equal one teaspoonful. Four teaspoonfuls equal one tablespoonful </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to bake meat" TEIform="index"/>How to Bake Meat</head><p TEIform="p">Place it on a grate, in the dripping pan. Sprinkle on ait sufficient to season half
                                through. Cover lightly with flour from the dredging box. The latter seals the pores,
                                thus preserving the juice. Add water about one half inch deep, to absorb the juices of
                                the meat, and prevent its drying or burning upon the pan. When browned on one side turn
                                over very carefully, aiming not to puncture it with knife or fork, thus letting the
                                juice escape. Season and flour on this side, and leave to brown. During the process of
                                baking, occasionally dip up the juice with a large spoon, and pour over the meat. Beef
                                should be cooked rare, other meats thoroughly The oven should be tempered to bake
                                quickly, but not hot enough to scorch. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Watervliet, (Shakers P. O.) N. Y.. Here live nearly two hundred professional Shakers ;
                                and for a long time past, even as at present, not one is sick, nor otherwise incapable
                                of some active physical service! This will strike the reader more peculiarly, when we
                                say that two are more than ninety years of age—Eleanor Vedder, and Phebe Lane,
                                (colored)—from among those who united about the year 1800. Two are above eighty years
                                old—Jeremiah Lowe ;—J. C. Buckingham and Eliza Wells—both connections of large families
                                coming early in this century. All of the above are very active—far from being on the
                                retired list. Then follow twenty-five, who are more than seventy years of age, some of
                                whom act as if in their prime; while fully as many more are within five years of
                                three-score and ten, yet none say: "/ am sick;" none that say : "I am old I" Elder F. W.
                                Evans may praise Mt. Lebanon, but as a place of health and perpetual youth, which one
                                will rise up to compare with youthful Watervliet? </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beyond the veil" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randolph, P. B." TEIform="persName"/>P. B. Randolph </byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of invention and manufacturer" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weekly commercial advertiser" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Beyond the Veil : By P. B. Eandolph. Published by D. M. Bennett, 141 Eighth St. New York.
                                A new arrival from the emerald soil, was once asked : "What is a posthumous work?" He
                                answered quickly: "It is the work a man does after he is dead!" Here we have a work
                                which is purported to have been done by its author since his death. It comes by his
                                inspirations through two venerable ladies, and is| most elegantly compiled. If the truth
                                of this volume could be as easily substantiated, as even we can vouch for its most
                                beautiful diction, then it would be most well for every body to get a copy and read it.
                                Whosoever does so, will suspend, every now and then, spell-bound. <pb n="74" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/>
                                74 THE SHAKER The Journal of Invention and Manufacturer : Henry Connett, Editor, copied
                                most kindly, with beautiful, almost flattering comments, the entire article on "Shaker
                                Inventions," for which we return thanks. It is only 25 cents a year and illustrated.
                                Burke and Fraser, 37 Park Eow, New York. The Weekly Commercial Advertiser : Largest and
                                cheapest newspaper published in New York city. It is full of good reading, and news of
                                markets etc. only 1.00 per. year. Address H. J. Hastings Nassau and Fulton sts. New
                                York. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A gentleman who circulates considerably in society..." TEIform="index"/>A gentleman who circulates considerably in society...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A gentleman who circulates considerably in society took it in his head to remark the
                                adjectives employed by the persons—outside, of course, of his own family— with whom he
                                came in contact. For a month he quietly noted, and a few months since he made up his
                                report. The favorite adjective among all classes he found to be "great" which he heard
                                pronounced within the time aforesaid 167 times, "Awful" and "splendid" ranked second and
                                third respectively,3 the former being repeated 142 and the latter 151 times;
                                "feai'ful"followed 150 times, and "frightful" 140 times. "Fine" he heard 138 times,
                                "gorgeous" 136 times, "grand" 134, "pretty'' 134, and "beautiful" 133. Among the]ladies
                                he found the word "lovely" to be an adjective held in high esteem, and which was applied
                                to everything. It fell on his ears 198 times, and four times he heard it expressed, by
                                men. In comparison, the superlative degree was employed the most, 218 times, the
                                comparative 143 and the positive 97 times. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things worth forgetting" TEIform="index"/>Things Worth Forgetting</head><p TEIform="p"> It is almost frightful and altogether humiliating, to think how much there is in the
                                common on-going of domestic and social life, which deserves nothing but to be instantly
                                forgotten. Yet it is equally amazing how large a class seem to have no other business
                                but to repeat and perpetuate these very things. That is the vocation of gossips, an
                                order of society that perpetrate more mischief than all the combined plagues of Egypt
                                together. You may have noticed how many speeches there are, which become mischievous
                                only by being heard a second time repeated, and what an army of both sexes are sworn to
                                see to it, that the fatal repetition shall be had. Blessed is that man or woman that can
                                let drop all the burrs, and thistles, instead of picking them up and fastening them on
                                to the next passenger. Would we only let 'the vexing and malicious sayings die, how fast
                                the lacerated and scandal-ridden world would get healed and tranquilized.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Huntington" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Despondency" TEIform="index"/>Despondency</head><p TEIform="p">The most perilous hour of a person's life is when he is tempted to despond. The man who
                                loses his courage loses all; there is no more hope of him than of a dead man; but it
                                matters not how poor he may be, how much pushed by circumstances, how much deserted by
                                friends, how much lost to the world; if he only keeps his courage, holds up his head,
                                works on with his hands and with unconquerable will determines to be and to do what
                                becomes a man, all will be well. It is nothing outside of him that kills, but what is
                                within, that makes or unmakes. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cost of war" TEIform="index"/>The Cost Of War</head><p TEIform="p">Give me the money that has been paid in war, and I will purchase every foot of land on
                                the globe. I will clothe every man, woman, and child in an attire that kings and queens
                                would be proud of. I will build a schoolhouse on every hillside and in every valley over
                                the whole habitable earth. I will build an academy in every town, and endow it; a
                                college in every State, and fill it with able professors. I will crown every hill with a
                                church, consecrated to the promulgation of the Gospel of peace. I will support in the
                                pulpit an able teacher of righteousness, so that every Sabbath morning the chime on one
                                hill should answer to the chime on another around the earth's broad circumference, and
                                the voice of prayer and song of praise should ascend like a universal holocaust to
                                heaven.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stebbing" TEIform="persName">Stebbing</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contention is contagious..." TEIform="index"/>Contention is contagious...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Contention is contagious, it spreads almost insensibly. Conceit is the high road to
                                shame.</p></div3></div2><pb n="75" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fowler, Edward" TEIform="index"/>Edward Fowler
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Jan. 31, aged 78 years, <persName reg="Fowler,                                     Edward" TEIform="persName">Edward Fowler</persName>.
                                Of this beautiful spirit, so long and faithfully known as Trustee of the Society, it may
                                most truly be said : "None knew him but to love him, "None named him, but to praise."
                                Though his departure was soon to be expected on account of^his age and infirmities, yet
                                his loss will be deeply felt, and his memory remain as an evergreen among the people.
                            </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meneeley Co. of West Troy New York..." TEIform="index"/>Meneeley Co. of West Troy New York...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Meneeley Co. of West Troy N. Y. are competing with the U. S. government in civilizing
                                the Indians! Government sending destructive, horror making cannons; Meneeley Co. sending
                                sweet sounding Chubch Bell ! Meneeley Co. were a long way ahead at last accounts. We are
                                using a number of Thb Biokford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory indeed,
                                Being among "the wonders in this age" of machinery, their utility and expedition in
                                business should be experienced by all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of wood
                                variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or rely on
                                the metal ones offered us by WASHBURN, MOEN Co. Please read advertisement of Wasson and
                                Martin several times. They form an enterprising and reliable firm. A Useful Apparatus :
                                JohnBunyan sai, that "an idle boy's or girl's head was the devil's workshop.'' Xet them
                                the "Keystone Self-Inker" with complement of type. See Adv. The Estey Organ scarcely
                                needs our praise. We have many of them in our Societies, and every one is a Utme
                                Delight." We further say, that Cluett has furnished us. We have been acquainted with F.
                                T. Van Patten for more than twenty years, and assure our friends, who need Broom
                                Machinery, or anything in his line of busi- ness, that they will receive the best of
                                satisfaction. Send for his Circular. Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that there are
                                un~ scrupulous persons, who, realizing the solid benefits of judicious advertising, will
                                use it most freely on some useless or worse, than useless articles, and soon retire with
                                fortunes of ill-earned gains. But we can still point to thousands who by a wholesome,
                                judicious judgment, have used advertising to their exceeding profit! and to the most
                                creditable advancement of useful materials. Such, we believe our patrons to be. We have
                                taken considerable and particular pains to acquaint ourself with Dr. Frazier's remedies,
                                and find from those using them, only a good report. His Bitters are purely medicinal,
                                and not an intoxicant beverage. For months, we have been witness of the workings of
                                Coolbv's Creamer, and we know of many who endorse what we have inserted as their
                                advertisement. We are confident dairy people will inquire into the arrangement, and send
                                for Circulars. It will pay to do The IT. S. Piano Co. enter a challenge to other
                                manufacturers and salesmen. We mean to make ourselves more acquainted with their
                                instruments. People will have Pianos, and they will look where to get them, in The
                                Shaker Manifesto. Every farmer will yet be his own Miller ; grindingout his "religious
                                bread" as Elder F. W. Evans would say; then they will send for one of Sedgebeer's
                                "Nonpareil." Send for a circular now. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the best
                                Water Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the firms of Leffel &amp; Co. and N.
                                F. Bumham, who enter into friendly competition in our columns, are both most honorable.
                                By reference to our Br. Philip Smith's advertisement, it will be seen that Farmers,
                                Gardeners, Amateurs, and "the rest of mankind" can get genuine Shaker Garden Seeds by
                                mail, at the very lowest cash prices. Try the seeds, coming immediately from the grower;
                                it will pay you. Van Deusen's Tree Label and "Business Cards" are a desiderata long
                                looked for. Send for a Circular and sample. The Hon. Clute Bros, of Schenectady, N. Y.
                                present most excellent encouragements for parties wishing Engines, Boilers, etc. We
                                know, also, of the "Clutk Plough" being the best plough yet created, for all kinds of
                                cross ploughing. Live honestly, purely, nobly, while on earth, and the Eternal Father
                                will care for your immortality. </p></div3></div2><pb n="76" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My savior" TEIform="index"/>MY SAVIOR</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. How exalted and how 2. Though uttered ages 8. My Savior, O, I
                            beautiful, the long ago, they love thy life. so sayings of our Lord! still retain the
                            power free from guile and stain; How To Thy clothed in grace and cheer the weary innocence and dignity, is each inspired word; They soul, and throw light o'er each adverse
                            hour; And purity my adoration claim. It 76 <pb n="77" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 77 are to me as golden fruit, in silver pictures countless millions, ages
                            hence, shall sing and speak the serves to elevate my mind to count thy virtues set, Like
                            music which the finite praise, Which fills the heart and moves the o'er, And prompts the
                            strife to pattern voice can never counterfeit lips of saints in latter days, thee,— to
                            "go and sin no more." <pb n="78" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/></p></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements removed] </p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>