<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0908" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18790801" TEIform="date">August 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> AUGUST, 1879. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editor. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        CANTERBURY, N. H. ' '' And they shall turn to you for a testimony. ''Go preach the Kingdom of God/" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISH" , 1879. ^ ¦¦ Vol. IX No. 8. 60 Cents
                        Per Annum. The Shaker </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="169" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exodus" TEIform="index"/>THE EXODUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DEVYR</byline><p TEIform="p"> When slavery laid an old man in the ground, The chorus rose, " His soul is marching on." Has
                            lie a refuge for the captive found, And to his olden home before them gone ? They silent
                            start, a dusky, tattered host, Without a warning, herald, word or sign ; Their boon of
                            freedom was Columbia's boast! Her deep disgrace, their solemn moving line. A cloud of
                            witnesses, they need not speak Of want and suffering, their dark eyes tell ; Their wretched
                            flight has proved the nation weak Her laws to vindicate, her foes to quell! Her laws ! what
                            are they in view of need ? What are they by the simple rule of right ? They stand as walls
                            around the realms of greed— They are as armor to the men of might. A land of millionaires, a
                            land of tramps ; A house divided that can never stand ; A flashing gleam from far centennial
                            camps, Reveals a structure built upon the sand. Would Pharaoh let the toiling people go—
                            Concede to slaves whate'er for them was asked ? Their stern oppressors mitigate their woe
                            Save by command, that they might more be tasked ? Ah, well! we read his folly and his fate;
                            That folly looming in the far away Must not attract from hardness just as great, From mad
                            perversity that reigns to-day. How blind we are to God's intended work ! How names, and
                            claims, suffice for substance true; What giant wrongs, all unmolested lurk Beneath the
                            little good the statesmen do ! They signed off slavery, and our hopes were high, While truth
                            bent low, these humbling words to carve: " It is not freedom! 'tis a burnished lie !
                            "Emancipation— liberty to starve! " A liberation, that absolves the care " That selfish
                            hands around their chattels threw ; " A legacy of tortures hard to bear, " A broader tyranny
                            than bondage knew," This verdict graven round the altar stone, Whereon the nation's
                            sacrifice was laid ; That great burnt offering which could not atone For half the wrongs
                            that slavery had made. And years pass on, dark years of pain and blight ; The North and
                            South, despair and anguish know ! Yet, hear they not upon the mountain's height— A voice
                            proclaiming " Let my people go I" Yea, let them go from poverty and fraud ; From malice,
                            hatred and from burning scorn! Let them go free to share the gifts of God, For to His bounty
                            all are equal born. Who owns the earth, the air, the sea ? They are the Lord's, and to His
                            children willed ; And never, never will the land be free, Till His behests are honestly
                            fulfilled ! Then, wherefore hold with subtle chain, and strong. Or strive to crush with
                            fierce barbaric hand! Awake to duty, overthrow the wrong, And give to freedom foothold on
                            the land. O ! North and South, ye partners in one sin Monopoly and slavery are one. Turn ye
                            to justice, life anew begin, And let this mottled servitude be gone ! Are not the toilers
                            white, as well as black ? These flying fugitives but swell the band Of wealth producers, who
                            are doomed to lack The fruits they heap profusely o'er the land. <pb n="170" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 170
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. O ! give them place upon the broad domain, And help them to secure
                            abiding home ! Then crowded industries no life will strain, And weary tramps no more will
                            hopeless roam. Nor will the freedman quit his quiet fields To seek for safety, or in quest
                            of food ; But all that freedom promises, and yields, Will fill the nation with undreamed of
                            And plotting monarchies — the curse of time— Will helpless sink into their waiting graves;
                            When God's Republic rises tjp sublime, to fell the system that produces SLAVES! Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Effects governed by law" TEIform="index"/>EFFECTS GOVERNED BY LAW</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p"> Probably there was never an age when the light of truth was greater, clearer, and more
                            extensively diffused in the earth, when genuine religious conviction was more freely
                            acknowledged, and yet, when compunctions of conscience for willful transgression were less
                            severe, and greater ease and apathy existed than at the present time. A universal spiritual
                            dearth pervades the earth, and mind seems paralyzed. Inhuman conditions there is a general
                            want of humility ; an absence of the element of love and desire for the principles of true
                            righteousness. Worldlineas in all its forms, independence and self-exaltation are the
                            popular sense. What then is to save us ? Are the judgments of Heaven the only alternative to
                            bring the quickening and force the realization that our situation is fearful ? that we stand
                            on the brink of a precipice, liable at any moment to be hurled into an abyss of misery and
                            woe ? The acts of our lives shape our destiny ; otherwise, we have no control of the laws
                            and principles that govern our being. There is no other destiny than that which we create.
                            Every condition is the result of fixed law. Every effect has a legitimate cause and every
                            cause produces an effect. This is a fixed eternal law. Reasoning from this fact, if our
                            conditions are to be changed, to produce the change, the character and tenor of our lives
                            must undergo a variation. This creates power. God has so ordained it. It is his law. If upon
                            earth we would have paradise, we must lay the foundation ; do the work that will produce the
                            elements of harmony. Heaven and hell are conditions self-made, the results of our doings.
                            God has so willed it. Here is where the free agency of man comes in j and without this
                            berth, he would not be man. Reason was given as a guide, being in its exercise subordinate
                            to the revealed will of God ; every part of creation, wheel within wheel, will work
                            harmoniously and the great desire of the human soul will be satisfied, its aspirations met
                            and its object attained in all that concerns us in every department in life. Then there will
                            exist no cause to cry the burden of the Lord ; no reason for the poverty of ministration of
                            strength ; for such condition can have no being. God helps all who help themselves. Hence,
                            as our better judgment dictates the use of every faculty of our being as creative power to
                            secure the riches, the benefits of higher life, we have every inducement, every
                            encouragement and every facility to work together for the heaven we so much desire to
                            attain. Enfield, N. H</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consumption" TEIform="index"/>CONSUMPTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRAZER</byline><p TEIform="p"> I. All diseases are traceable to violations of hygienic laws. II. Personal violations give
                            rise to hereditary diseases; violations of them by society as a body, also originate
                            diseases transmissible in the form of epidemics. III. Scrofula is the mother of consumption
                            ; both have their origin in false dietetic and other bad habits, and especially in breathing
                            re-breathed air. IV. When good air is constantly inhaled and all other habits are correct,
                            scrofula cannot exist, hence consumption cannot be induced. V. All diseases originated by
                            society or by individuals can be controlled, and their causes abolished. Consumption quietly
                            carries off its vie- <pb n="171" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 171 tims year after year.
                            Has any public effort concentrating the hygienic light of our day been applied to arrest,
                            and finally abolish consumption so destructive of life and of cherished hopes ? It has been
                            thought that consumption causes a greater destruction of life in Boston in ten years, than
                            yellow fever does in the same time in New Orleans. In the crescent city the enemy comes down
                            in a moment, exciting the notice and sympathy of the whole land. In the space of a few weeks
                            it fulfills its awful mission, mysteriously disappears and remains absent sometimes for
                            years. Yellow fever is one of the protests against the existence of large cities; they are
                            necessarily unclean. Suppose in countries visited by this scourge, that every dwelling shall
                            have at least one acre of land attached to it, and every unclean thing of the city burnt up
                            or buried, and hygienic law, lovingly, and of course faithfully obeyed, dietetically and
                            procreatively by every [one, would any epidemic be able successfully to assail the people?
                            Plenty of fresh air is the best disinfectant, and plenty of good earth the best deodorizer.
                            Suppose we at the north should go as energetically to arrest consumption, as no doubt the
                            people of the south will this summer, to prevent the approach of yellow fever; is not the
                            road to success clearer to us than it is to those of the south to effect their object ? They
                            can only act on general principles and hope for good results. We can understanding^ apply
                            them, to effect a specific purpose. If breathing re-breathed air induces consumption, let us
                            begin with the fact, that man, as with other animals, was created in reference to having
                            free access to an ocean of air, forty or fifty miles deep ; and that it is a contravention
                            of the order of things, for several persons to shut themselves up during the night, or at
                            any time, without securing ample ventilation. That doing so, shows not only a want of
                            culture, but also some ignorance of the nature of air and of the uses of breathing. Air is
                            changed chemically at a most astonishing rate by being breathed only once ; the oxygen or
                            vital air is greatly diminished, and the carbonic acid gas greatly increased, and if
                            breathed twice or thrice, the gas of death becomes still more abundant, while the oxygen as
                            rapidly disappears. We have in our close sleeping and sitting rooms a powerfully exciting
                            cause of con sumption. Bring about a change in the matter of air, so as to accord with the
                            nature of things, and correct other habits, and in two generations the possibilities are
                            that a case of consumption would be rare. Ventilation can be secured to every apartment by
                            having flues built in the walls, extending from the floors to the top of the house. The
                            halls, and especially the cellars, should be so ventilated, keeping the whole house supplied
                            with fresh air. Chimneys that have not a good draught should be rebuilt ; much better to
                            have a tall chimney than a long doctor's bill. Trees should not be allowed to overtop a
                            building, nor in any way to obstruct the air nor sunshine, more especially the morning rays.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear blessed now" TEIform="index"/>THE DEAR BLESSED NOW</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Overton, C. M." TEIform="persName"/>C. M. OVERTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> There's a land that is fairer than day, Nor by faith do we see it afar, For the Father has
                            shown us the way, To prepare us a dwelling place here. Cuo.: In the dear blessed now, We
                            have met on the beautiful shore. Let us drink of the sweetness that's here, Let us bask in
                            the warmth of to-day ; Let us joy in the heaven that's near, Nor sigh for a heaven far away.
                            To live with the friends that we love, From sorrow and sin set apart, 0, what could we ask
                            from above, To add to this heaven of the heart! Let us cherish our friends on the earth, Nor
                            wait till they vanish away ; For how shall we measure the worth Of the angels enveloped in
                            clay. N. Union, 0.</p></div2><pb n="172" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts of life" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WHEELER</byline><p TEIform="p"> "I would not give my free thoughts for a throne." I have thought sometimes that those feel,
                            ings which enter the chambers of the imagination, and in the face of all obstacles clothe
                            themselves in language pure and beautiful must certainly emanate from a source higher than
                            the purely physical plane. Come they from dust? and must they to dust return ? What good is
                            attained by their birth, if they pass in and out of the imagination and leave no record upon
                            the register of immortality. Beautiful flowers refresh and renew the pulse of earth life;
                            the soft sunbeams which pass like a dream of peace warm and revivify with strength and
                            beauty the varied forms of mortality. The silent dew that steals out of the soft
                            night-skies, leaves its sweetened breath upon fair nature. Every thing in the universe works
                            its message in living, glowing lights and shades. Yet the spirit of man that weds the earth,
                            leaves its higher destiny to grovel with the things beneath it. Matter should be subservient
                            to mind, not mind to matter. Does the angel of intelligence and divine beauty bring thee
                            messages of peace and love ? Visions of the grand possibilities of the inner consciousness ?
                            Does he walk with thee by the briery pathway and pluck for thee the fragrant flowers ? Cast
                            them not aside. Trifle not with these whispers of poetry! Pay thy tithes to earth, but save
                            thy immortality for heaven. When memories of the flowery springtime of life steal over thee,
                            before thy faith and trust in human truth had been fully tested, shut these not entirely
                            from thy mind for when the clouds are dense and dark, and shadows lurk along the hidden
                            way&gt; sweet memory tells thee what the sunshine is, and gives thee hope to feed the
                            heart. The sunshine of thy faith and trust will yet illumine the most intricate windings of
                            life's pathway, and if we walk with wisdom we will never walk alone. Earth to earth, but not
                            soul to earth. When thoughts of beauty, truth and brightness steal in like sunbeams upon thy
                            silent hours give them room and form. A few moments to transfer them to paper will not be
                            missed at the dropping of the curtain. They may be to some one a light in darkness. Imprison
                            the sunlight of heaven if ye may. Give not the pearls of wisdom to the swine because they
                            are not diamonds. The golden gates are not reached by walking a silent, solemn unresponsive
                            line, but by exchanging sympathies and affections with humanity, by giving and receiving the
                            golden grains of wisdom and truth. Isolation leads away from the city of love to the bleak
                            hills of desolation. It is said that no soul is desolate as long as there is a human being
                            for whom it can feel trust and reverence. So should we wear the beauty of the soul as an
                            every day garb, that the face may be bright with human love and confidence. The world should
                            never grow dark to a sorrowing sister ; the sunshine of pleasantness should inspire trust
                            and reverence which steals away the shadows " ere we are aware." When we walk by faith and
                            not by sight, if by the exercise of all our energies we can keep alive the flame of
                            unselfish emotions, we may still make them hours of active love which will write a glory
                            over our name in the immortal world. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interest" TEIform="index"/>INTEREST</head><p TEIform="p">No blister draws sharper than interest does. Of all industries, none is comparable to that of
                            interest. It works day and night, in rain or shine. It has no sound in its footsteps, but
                            travels fast. It gnaws at a man's substance with invisible teeth. It binds industry with its
                            film, as a fly is bound in a spider's web. Debts roll a man over and over, bind hand and
                            foot, letting him hang upon the fatal mesh until long-legged interest devours him. There is
                            but one thing on a farm like it, and that is the Canada thistle, which swarms new plants
                            every time you break roots, whose blossoms are prolific, and every flower the father of a
                            thousand seeds; every leaf is an awl, every branch a spear, and every flower like a platoon
                            of bayonets, and a field of them like an armed <pb n="173" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            173 host. The whole plant is a tormenting curse ; yet a farmer would do better to make his
                            bed of Canada thistles than attempt to be at ease at interest. In this Age of debt, with
                            government, states, counties, cities, towns, corporations, churches and individuals all
                            hopelessly bankrupt, nothing but a speedy return to a ready cash-on the-spot system can save
                            Christianity itself from going to protest. For it is a fair question, how much this
                            universal depravity and misery of debt has been brought about by false notions on religion,
                            such as salvation in sin, Jesus paying all our dues to God. Debt is a dangerous stimulation,
                            as sinful as other forms of excess, and in the end, a bolster of dried nettles is like a
                            downy pillow by the side of debt's sting. The principle is wrong, whether in business or
                            morals, and must suffer the fate of all weeds.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One character" TEIform="index"/>ONE CHARACTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> A modern writer says: " Each individual has two characters or reputations ; one which the
                            world recognizes, and another, veiled, that they do not know. We are all living —more or
                            less—under a mask. The bubble reputations that we are seeking are too often a cloak for
                            hypocrisy ! " If this is true which few will gainsay—why is it thus ? What the cause, and
                            what the remedy ? We do not suppose that God, the arch-angels, nor the redeemed saints who
                            surround his throne, are masked in a false garb. God is Light, Love, Wisdom, all that is
                            true and good. If we dwell in him, and walk in loving obedience to his commands, and have no
                            fellowship with the " unfruitful works of darkness," then we have nothing to conceal; have
                            no use for false drapery to cover and hide deformities ; but shall wear garments of
                            innocence and diffuse love, and radiate light wherever we are, at home or abroad, whether on
                            this or that side the river, which is called the dividing stream between life and death—the
                            mortal, and immortal. Humanity at the present time finds itself in a marked degree far below
                            the medium round of the ladder of truth, that leads from the earthly, animal condition, up
                            to the heavenly state, where the Christ angels dwell, and the victorious songs of overcomers
                            resound through the arches of the glorious " house not made with hands ;" yet the sounds
                            reverberate and fall sweetly upon the ears of those in mortal form who have listening ears,
                            and who stand upon the watch towers of Zion, earnestly looking for the appearance of
                            message-bearers who scale the ladder that is accessible to mortals and angels, and connects
                            the spheres—the human and divine. It would seem scarcely necessary to ask the cause of the
                            false colors under which men and women sail, and the great dissembling to conceal the real
                            character formed and maintained in private life in contrast with the one, painted, polished,
                            and fashionable to meet the public eye. Those who have eyes to see, know that the cause lies
                            in a departure from the just laws of nature and grace decreed by the universal lawgiver, for
                            the well-being and happiness of all creatures and things which he has formed and caused to
                            exist. Inordinate desires and uncontrolled passions have for centuries borne the masses down
                            into a vortex where they toss widely upon its up-heaving billows, without power to extricate
                            themselves. Priests and people have fallen into the ditch of sin together ; and while they
                            strive to maintain their popular standing in society, fearfulness takes hold of their
                            consciences when they remember that they are under the power of sensuality, intemperance and
                            monopoly, and are in reality the servants of sin while professing to hold the truth that
                            makes souls free. Sin, in any form, is a scourge ; it creates malaria, corrodes the heart,
                            destroys the moral sensibilities, and despoils the beauties of the soul-temple, which should
                            ever be in readiness for the reception of pure and exalted spirits to enter and hold
                            communion, as divine teachers, indicating present duty, and pointing to the high lands of
                            progression in spirit spheres, which are rendered more beautiful and lovely as souls ascend
                            and unfold, and become more and more refined and God-like, reflecting the <pb n="174" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. dual likeness of the Eternal Parents— Father and
                            Mother God. Multitudes of human beings are willing slaves to evil passions. Others sin
                            ignorantly, and carelessly plod their way along life's toilsome journey, and reason that if
                            they follow in the footsteps of their sires and grandsires, they will come out all right in
                            the end. There is another class to whom sin is repugnant; and they deplore their captivity
                            and long to be free from the oppressor's yoke; but the bonds are strong and they are held by
                            them ; yet they struggle and pray for deliverance. They remember that one of the ancient
                            prophets said : " The Lord will suddenly come to his temple;" and they are looking for
                            relief to come in some miraculous way : when, by super-human agency, they will be uplifted
                            from low earthly conditions, be disenthralled and triumph in victory. The same prophet asked
                            the question : " Who may abide his coming '? and who shall stand when he appeareth ? for he
                            is like refiner's fire and like fuller's soap ? " Let us suggest to our pilgrim brother and
                            sister, that we strive to hasten the coming of the Lord, by making a willing sacrifice of
                            all our idols; mnd use all means within our reach to break down barriers that sin has formed
                            between our souls and God. Let the inebriate hurl the intoxicating cup from his lips, and
                            the warrior lay by his life-destroying weapons, and turn his energies to battle internal
                            foes, those of his own heart. Let those who have stolen, steal no more. Let the sensualist
                            renounce all iniquitous practices, and learn to be pure in thought, desire and action. Form
                            our character— that of an honest man or woman—and then see if God is not already near ; and
                            that he is coming nearer all the time, ready to dispense grace and truth as far and as fast
                            as we are willing to receive it. God, through his mediators, will come to us, if we will
                            make room for them by renouncing sinful deeds which we have power to do, if we so will it;
                            and thus be practically saved. Other than this, salvation is a meaningless term. If we would
                            rea,p well, we must soic well; be strictly honest; no longer be heard to say : " Monopoly is
                            wrong; but if others over-reach, T must do the same, else I cannot live." But let us prove
                            whether the ear that hears the ravens' cry, and the hand that feeds them, will not also hear
                            our petitions and supply our needs.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>THE CROSS NO. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> When a person undertakes to perform any task, the supposition is that he is competent to its
                            performance. The architect is familiar with the rules of architecture, and hence is capable
                            of giving directions in constructing an edifice. So with every kind of secular business ; it
                            is no less true in spiritual things. There is this difference, however, in constructing the
                            "house eternal in the heavens," the Christian may begin to build at the same time that he
                            begins to learn the principles of divine architecture. In the school of Christ it is said :
                            " If any one lack wisdom, let him ask of God, who gives to all liberally." This doctrine is
                            fundamental, essential not only when the disciple first takes the cross, but through his
                            whole course of selfdenial, until the merely sensual or carnal life is outgrown and only the
                            heavenly life bears sway in the entire being. This is prominent in all the teachings of
                            Jesus and the apostles. " The spirit of truth dwells with you an'd shall be in you." " It is
                            God that works in you," this makes bearing the cross effectual; in fact, self-denial without
                            this is not the cross of Christ who taught the necessity of growth into the life of God,
                            which is effected only by the inspiration and indwelling of the Divine Spirit, " I am in the
                            Father and the Father in me," " if a man love me my Father will love him,and we will come to
                            him and make our abode with him." These words of Jesus declare the ability to bear his cross
                            of those who purpose to become his disciples as well as the essential character of all such.
                            " God is love," " Gtod so loved the world that he gave his only begotten Son." Divine love,
                            then, must dwell in all those who bear the cross of Christ. This is the sole and
                            all-sufficient test of discipleship. Divine love is essen- <pb n="175" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 175 tially the same in God and in man. " Love thinks or devises no evil," it can
                            never, then, exercise itself in vengeance ; " love works no ill to one's neighbor." This
                            must determine the character not only of the individual, but of all bodies of people who
                            claim to bear the cross of Christ. The essential nature of divine love is to unite those in
                            whom it dwells ; " I and my Father are one," is the declaration of Jesus, this is His prayer
                            for His disciples, " that they all may be one as thou, Father, art in me and I in Thee." The
                            terms of discipleship, and the only terms in the words of the great teacher, are taking the
                            cross and following Him, and the results of this are the in-dwelling of divine love in the
                            hearts of the disciples transforming them into the very life of love, so that in their
                            aspirations, their hopes and their efforts, they become one. Has any other cross, any other
                            faith than this proclaimed by Jesus to the few who were in daily communion with Him, ever
                            effected this ? Let historv decide.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Growth" TEIform="index"/>GROWTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burgur, Martha Ann" TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA ANN BURGUR</byline><p TEIform="p"> While the natural creation is so beautifully and gloriously constructed as to flood the home
                            and heart of humanity with light, peace and happiness, should not the height and goal of
                            'Christian perfection be earnestly sought ? that each life may speak of attainment in
                            spirituality ? All things in nature are evolving, changing ; every plant and shrub touched
                            and in. vigorated by the power of creative forces, and the breath of the universe, make
                            their impress—write their history. The rock in its home of earth, the pebble resting beneath
                            the crested wave, until the beating tide bears it to the sunlight, each tells of growth and
                            change, beauty and glory ; all are in harmony and join in one universal song of progress and
                            fill the earth with joy and praise. As each, act of life stamps its record upon the
                            character, serious thought should be given in this direction, particularly with the young,
                            that life's enfoldment and advancement be for honor and not for shame. In ages past when
                            truths were brought forth, persecution marked their course ; the prophets and saints were
                            stoned to death ; burnt at the stake with many other horrible devices inflicted by enemies
                            of the truth; but, rather than abandon their principles they were sacrificed upon the altar
                            of tyranny. History reveals volumes of persecution, filling the soul with compassion toward
                            the one, and indignation toward the ignorance and cruelty practiced by the other. Time and
                            growth have effected changes, and we enjoy, void of the persecution, what martyrs in past
                            ages labored to unfold and uphold. As years revolve and new truths open, greater changes
                            will mark the course of the pilgrim traveler ; but, if the mind is exercised aright, upon a
                            growth of goodness, that will develop the spiritual being, we may meet the era which will
                            soon dawn with joy and not with grief. As the natural creation stamps its record upon each
                            leaf and blade of grass, so may we be employed in writing the record of virgin purity upon
                            the thoughts and deeds which combine to form the true, the higher life of Divine Revelation.
                            Mt. Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's morning" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S MORNING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA STEPHENS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Life's morning hours soon pass away, Like hues of sunset light : No vain regrets, no
                            mournful tears, Can stay their arrowy flight, As clouds before the summer wind— With naught
                            their course to stay— So morning years with youthful dreams, Glide to eternity. But will
                            they pass like summer's clouds Upon the balmy air ; No good thing sought, no good deed done,
                            No treasure gained with care ? 0, what is youth but life's fair spring, Its growth and
                            blossom hours ? The time to sow the precious seeds, With earnest, spirit powers. The wheat
                            we sow will surely grow, This law will never sleep ; And if our hopes are true or false,
                            Their harvest we must reap. <pb n="176" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. But, if through
                            life's fair spring-tide years We till the mellow soil; And do our work with willing hands,
                            Through summer hours of toil. Autumn will yield a precious store, To fill our granary ; And
                            we can sing a joyful song, In harvest jubilee. The evil days will never come— No future
                            shall we fear— But fruits of everlasting peace, Will in our lives appear. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God in the constitution" TEIform="index"/>GOD IN THE CONSTITUTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barclay, Chas. G." TEIform="persName"/>CHAS. G. BARCLAY</byline><p TEIform="p"> The history of the Christian church from the day of its ascendancy is replete with
                            persecutions, atrocities and barbarities committed and resorted to for its propagation. The
                            gloomy past shows clearly that the church cannot be trusted with civil powers. Among the
                            many instances we might cite, we select from the blood-stained record of the church the
                            following examples of Christian love, mercy and tolerance : " The famous image controversy"
                            cost 50,000 lives during the persecutions instigated in the ninth century against the
                            Manichsens. There fell in Greece 100,000 persons. The loss of life by the " crusades," was
                            not less than 4,500,000 including all the expeditions, seven in number. The extermination of
                            the Moorish nation from Spain; the persecution of the Jews in the middle ages, and the final
                            expulsion from Spain and Portugal. The famous schism which preceded the burning of Huss and
                            Jerome of Sprague, and the war on the Hussites that followed (costing 200,000 lives); the
                            destruction of 12,000,000 unoffending aborigines, by Cortez and Pizarro, and their priestly
                            abettors. The massacre of St. Bartholomew costing 40,000 lives. The killing of 50,003
                            persons in the Netherlands, in the reign of Charles V, and thousands more under the reign of
                            his heartless son. The burning of 81.000 and the killing or torturing of 290,000 more by the
                            Inquisition of Spain ; the burning, hanging and otherwise destroying of hundreds of
                            thousands beside these. The persecution in England, Scotland and Ireland, and the murders in
                            this free country, are as we have said comparatively few of the enormities that can be
                            appealed to, in illustration of the intolerance which has followed the ascendancy of
                            Christianity wherever it has gained a foothold, and has prevailed unchecked by opposing
                            influences. Here we have at a very low estimate the loss of 18,100,000 human lives caused by
                            the church in disseminating the doctrines of love and peace ; and in the face of this record
                            of their own making, they ask us to allow them to amend the Constitution of the United
                            States by inserting the word God in it. Thus at once making the government sectarian in its
                            character and opening the road to future, further and still more grievous encroachments upon
                            the already too limited religious liberty of the country. The past, so full of useful
                            lessons, should be our guide for the future. The past teaches us that the clergy cannot be
                            trusted; and with this salutary fact fully impressed upon us by the lives and blood of over
                            eighteen millions of beings, why should we say, Let bygones be bygones, and let us hope for
                            the best. No, no, my friends ; be not deceived by these hypocritical canting parsons. Truly
                            are they wolves in sheep's clothing. The movement (the Amendment) was proposed by a few
                            fanatical and a good many designing leaders of the sect—principally U. P. at the outset.
                            Those who inaugurated it have quietly withdrawn from the public gaze, that they may prepare
                            the racks and torture for us when they succeed in their undertaking, which they hope to do
                            by (without giving time for reflection) forcing it upon the people, and carry it from the
                            very fact that the masses do not see its tendncy. " Put not off until to-morrow what you can
                            do to-day." To-morrow they may launch their amendment upon us, and with long 'aces they will
                            go among the people and cry, " The country that recognizes not God cannot stand ; " :' It is
                            an insult to God that our Constitution does not recognize him," etc. Therefore go to work at
                            once and show the real object of the incarnate fiends; for t is only that in a few years
                            they may have the satisfaction of putting upon the rack the <pb n="177" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 177 Spiritualists, the Unitarians, the Deists, the Materialists, and all
                            other liberalists. Now is the time to fight the battle, by showing them to the world in
                            their true light. But should they succeed by fraud in securing the amendment, through the
                            ballotbox, then let the liberalists of the world unite and meet them with their own
                            weapon—the sword ; and may we die rather than lose what little religious liberty they have
                            seen fit to give us. And if it must come to the rifle and the sword, let the battle be waged
                            so that they may beware of us. The object" of omitting the word God from the Constitution
                            was clearly to guard against the despotism of the clergy. So, in addition to the fact that
                            "No religious test should ever be required as a qualification to office," and that "
                            Congress should make no law respecting the establishment of religion or the free exercise
                            thereof," the framers, as a special guard against the encroachments of the church, omitted
                            the word, so that neither the spirit nor the letter of the law could be infringed upon or
                            evaded. Moreover, God is omnipotent and omnipresent, and being so, cannot be, either by
                            legislation put in the Constitution, or by lack of it kept out. What is most wanted is more
                            of the love of God in the hearts of men, and less hypocrisy in the hearts of the clergy. But
                            this say to your congregation, beloved clergy: The liberalists will never be slaves of a
                            bigoted or intolerant church, but will rather die in defense of their natural liberty and
                            rights, given by God himself.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Expedience of a veteran sister" TEIform="index"/>EXPERIENCE OF A VETERAN SISTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sharp, Eliza" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZA SHARP</byline><p TEIform="p"> Nearing the borders of time, which fact a ripened age promises all, I wish to bless a work
                            which has been such a solace in my declining years. I have been an interested reader of "
                            The Manifesto " from its earliest publication, and could I contribute any thing that would
                            benefit its readers, would, as the widow of old, cast in my mite. Though age has given me a
                            quiet seat in the old arm chair, to witness the proceedings of several generations around
                            me, I still partake of their interests, resolving to bless while life remaineth. In this
                            spirit I present a little of my experience to the readers of The Manifesto. My parents,
                            though not companions of Daniel Boone, were among the early settlers of Kentucky, where I
                            was born, and lived, until five years old ; at which time we removed to the State of Ohio.
                            In the year 1801 there was a religious awakening in my native State, called the "Kentucky
                            Revival." My father with many others took an active part in the work. Many of the awakened
                            subjects prophesied concerning the Second Appearing of Christ. The day when people would be
                            saved from their sins, instead of in their sins. In one of the meetings an elderly lady
                            exclaimed : " We shall soon praise the Lord in music and dancing, and Christ himself will be
                            the fiddler." This was soon verified to their minds, although it was not personified in the
                            Jewish garb. The mighty power of conviction swept all human pride before it, the manliest
                            hearts becoming like dependent children, seeking to be led in preference to directing
                            others. They prayed for Christ to make his appearance, in man, woman, or child ; they were
                            ready to receive him with thankful hearts in whatsoever form it pleased heaven for him to
                            appear. Many prophesied that messengers were coming from the east, with glad tidings of
                            peace and salvation to all. Their teaching would be to confess and forsake all sin, living a
                            pure, holy life, and their worship would consist of music and dancing; though not in the
                            dances in which the wicked revel. These prophecies were uttered under the divine influence
                            of the truth, and the people were anxiously awaiting the fulfillment thereof. In the year
                            1805 the reality of these prophecies was experienced, as there were three missionaries sent
                            from the society of Shakers at New Lebanon, N. Y., as leaders to these people; viz. : John
                            Meacham, Benjamin Youngs, Issachar Bates. They preached the " Second Coming of Christ " in
                            the female through Ann Lee. My parents, who were among the subjects <pb n="178" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/>
                            178 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. of this great revival, not finding peace of mind, trusting to the
                            merits of Jesus as their former theology taught, readily accepted the gospel of " Christ's
                            Second Appearing," confessing and forsaking their sins, and living the repentance which only
                            existed in word before. Though but a child, the change in my parents made a deep impression
                            upon my little mind, and when they taught me to confess all my transgressions of honesty and
                            purity, I was glad to confess to them every little wrong, according to my understanding, and
                            feared to commit the same evils again. I grew up under the teaching of this peculiar
                            doctrine, and for many years have proved the efficacy of selfdenial to all those human
                            passions which link mankind in the generative order; and can testify of the possibility of
                            living in the present, world a pure, holy life. I feel thankful at every recollection that
                            in early childhood I received that conviction for sin, which would not permit me to retire
                            at night with a fault concealed. Yet I would not wish to overdraw the picture of real life,
                            or cause any to think I was instantly lifted from the human into the divine life. It has
                            been a gradual unfolding of the angelic nature in accordance with the practice of true
                            self-denial, and in early life I found much in my mind that was tempted by the elements of
                            inferior human nature, and was still more deeply tested when I have witnessed harsh
                            persecutions and infringements from those who did not accept the doctrines of these people.
                            Mobs frequented our premises by day and night, and being very secret in their designs needed
                            close watching. They burned our place of worship, cut down fruit trees, destroyed gardens,
                            and burned barns, with all their stock of fall and winter provisions; and even poisoned a
                            number of horses to death. The brethren were waylaid and cruelly whipped. At one time a
                            companyof about fifteen thousand men were raised, many of whom were in military array ;
                            others came as spectators, though nearly all were full of rage and malice, declaring they
                            would force the Shakers to renounce their faith and flee the country. Their chief object
                            seemed to be to liberate the young people from the bondage and servitude in which they
                            understood they were held. They asked to see them, and their request being granted, they
                            freely conversed with a number of the young brothers and sisters, searching every apartment
                            of the house and interrogating each one present. These critics finding none held in bondage
                            declared themselves satisfied and peacefully withdrew. When I was about seventeen years old,
                            a band of marauders, about thirty in number, came in the morning immediately after the
                            brethren had repaired to the fields to their labor, leaving only two or three at home. The
                            ruffians, though forbidden by the brethren entering the yard, broke through the gate and
                            demanded an entrance to the house. The sisters (as is usual for women to do on such
                            occasions) hastened to bar the door, and I was one of the number that ran to hold it. They
                            finally broke through a strong door, bent a large iron bar, entered the house, broke the
                            balustrades of the stairs almost entirely to pieces, and injured the lower part of the house
                            very much. They would have searched the entire building, mutilating all the furniture, had
                            not the sisters so filled the stairs it seemed impossible for them to ascend. After a while
                            the brethren, hearing the alarm, came to our rescue, but the ruffians handled them harshly
                            and wounded some severely. The number of ruffians increased to nearly three hundred until we
                            were obliged to apply to the civil authorities to quell the riot and dispel the mob. The
                            officer was an uncle of mine, Judge Harlow, who dispersed them about sunset. This he did
                            riding around the house three times on a large horse swinging a closed umbrella saying, " I
                            command you in the power and authority of the United States to leave this place or you will
                            be confined." The trouble did not, however, cease here, for several nights we did not go to
                            rest at all, for the threats of our enemies were so violent as to jeopardize our lives, burn
                            our buildings, and destroy other property, so we <pb n="179" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 179 were necessitated to secrete our furniture and our clothing, and keep a
                            continued watch day and night. Thus I spent my early life in what was then the western land
                            passing through some outward afflictions for my religious belief, yet enjoying inward peace
                            and consolation. In the year 1835 I came to Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., where I have since resided. A
                            short time after my arrival here our people were.visited by an extraordinary spiritual
                            manifestation, when tests of this power were experienced, fully equaling any of the more
                            modern spiritual manifestations. I have been an eye and ear witness of many displays of
                            divine revelation and inspiration whicii were both striking to my view and interesting to my
                            mind. These manifestations were beyond the skill of man to invent, and I here add my
                            testimony to the spiritualism I have seen manifested among our people, where it was
                            predicted this ism would spread through the land. I have myself, though of a very sanguine
                            temperament, felt invisible control to that degree that I was moved as a leaf in the wind
                            without the least effort of my own strength. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Root out of dry ground" TEIform="index"/>ROOT OUT OF DRY GROUND</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p"> Had the earth been prepared this root to conceive, And Moses and Jesus had both been
                            believed. Nor sought to uproot, this dear plant from above, Instead of the sword we'd have
                            brotherly love. This root being dual must wait for the plan— Heaven and earth to develop —
                            the counterpart man. Now the earth helps the woman in her extreme need, While the heavens
                            are peopled with her righteous seed; The true heirs of heaven rejoice in glad song, While
                            these joyful tidings are telegraphed on ; This root has found soil and more commonly
                            appears, As branches expand in the cycles of years. " Why wert thou here, O rival of the
                            rose ? I never thought to ask, I never knew ; But in my simple ignorance supposed The self
                            same power that brought me here, brought you." Let the arrogant and bigoted, the foes of
                            free thought, reflect on the application and exchange despotism for human, brotherly
                        love.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pentecost" TEIform="index"/>PENTECOST</head><p TEIform="p">(Tribune.) Our clergymen need not be in any doubt of a subject to-morrow. It has been the
                                day on which for eighteen centuries many Christians have celebrated the anniversary of
                                one of the most incredible events told us in the bible; and even those church-going
                                people who do not keep these Christian fasts and feasts would do well to look into the
                                matter a little. We, practical New Yorkers, are asked to believe that once, centuries
                                ago, on a spring day, a body of ordinary men, just such as we meet in our daily
                                business—tax gatherers, fishermen and inn-keepers — being assembled in an upper room,
                                the little house was suddenly shaken as by a mighty, rushing wind, and these men,who,
                                until then had been uncultured and common place, with no genius or special gift of mind
                                or body, were instantly filled with the Divine Spirit and became to a degree as gods,
                                inspired to speak the highest truths to every man in his nativetongue. Now the question
                                which comes into every man's mind when he hears this story is, why is not this thing
                                done now? The world surely needs the truth just as much as then. There is as much
                                drunkenness, and fraud, and unchastity in New York this morning as in Jerusalem under
                                Pilate. The men and women in Broadway are no whit different in nature from those who
                                crowded up to the great Oriental mart. Their God was really our God. Why does not the
                                rushing wind come to us, and the tongues of fire ? Our clergymen could make good use of
                                to-morrow in considering this question. We suggest this in all earnestness, and it is
                                entirely within our province to suggest it. A secular newspaper is not the index to the
                                popular mind ; it is simply a mass of facts— a record of the stock market, of the
                                hunting down of the Nihilists, of police reports and party policy. But under all these
                                flow the great currents of right and wrong, up to civilization or down to brutality—that
                                is the meaning of it all. Every small item of daily (ttaxmsponftzntt. <pb n="180" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. news hints at the progress of a man or a nation
                                toward God or away from Him. That is the gist of the whole thing, and we all know it,
                                though only the preachers talk of it. We venture, therefore, to urge our readers to look
                                at the questions to-morrow which this story of the Pentecost suggests, in a plain
                                practical way, and in the light of these daily happenings. Is there no power at work
                                now, influencing men and nations, which is neither intellect, nor reason, nor emotional
                                passion ? Is there no such thing to-day as a supernatural force, like a mighty, rushing
                                wind blowing through great masses of people, or the mind, perhaps, of our common place
                                neighbors, changing instantly and without rational cause their motives, lifting them
                                suddenly to new planes of thought and action ? Did we never know anybody on whom, this
                                tongue of ,fire had rested ; who spoke the absolute truth to us—truth that had nothing
                                to do with expediency or moneymaking, or getting on in the world '! It might be a great
                                orator, or a black laborer, or a patient, obscure woman ; it spoke in their lives and
                                actions much oftener than in words; we called it as it happened, honesty or charity or
                                religion. But we knew in our hearts that it was the .immortal fire, and that God himself
                                gave it to them ; and we knew just as certainly that it was something which would
                                outlast money and business, and every thing else in the world, and was worth them all.
                                If our readers carefully think over these things to-morrow, they will, we are sure, be
                                able to give to the old story of the Pentecost a modern meaning, and will read, too, the
                                daily record which we shall bring to them on Monday morning from a clearer and higher
                                point of view.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New pentecost" TEIform="index"/>A NEW PENTECOST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">ELDER EVANS TELLS WHAT HE SHOULD EXPECT TO SEE IF THE TRIBUNE'S IDEAS WERE CARRIED OUT.
                                To the Editor of the Tribune : Friend : Saturday's editorial—Pentecost indeed ! "
                                Incredible events " ! ! What were they ? The iconoclastic Tribune tells us to our face,
                                and is it not to our shame ? Was not the editor inspired to preach to the preachers 1
                                God will speak, and will be heard, even if " these stones " have to be the mouthpiece,
                                and a universe the auditor. If, as Professor Mapes claimed, it is by evolutionary
                                processes that God moves the material world from primates to ultimates, is the mental
                                and spiritual world in humanity to be alone fixed, stationary, until it is not the head,
                                but the tail, of human motive forces ? Until the spiritual—religious—element, instead of
                                being the life of God in human souls, becomes a myth, a snperstition, a bundle and
                                jumble of effete priestly nothingarianism, a la Beecher and Talmage trials, a World's
                                Protestant Evangelical Alliance, a prophetic conference about the second coming,
                                logically ending in a Pocasset tragedy, by simple, sincere believing Second Adventists ?
                                Freeman-was just what the Tribune urges the preachers to become —like Catholic
                                Inquisitors, Protestant, Quaker and Witchcraft persecutors, religious warriors of all
                                false systems—doers of their theology. Grant said : " Put a bad law into practical
                                operation—enforce it, or repeal it." This is what the Tribune is at with the
                                theologies—do them, or change them. Let the old Pentecost alone, or let us have a modern
                                Pentecost, and the faithful Tribune will record the results. That is right—the editor is
                                right. Let God speak through the secular press, through Infidel Communists, or through
                                the Shakers, to test what is, and establish what should be. Any thing is better than
                                this body of death. Let us all, as you suggest, " look into the matter a little," if we
                                dare to do it. An upper room, filled with ordinary people—tax gatherers, fishermen,
                                inn-keepers —fanatics all, who were sure to act out what they fully believed—hence how
                                important that they believe right. The little house (a la Kiddle) suddenly shaken by a
                                mighty rushing wind, and these men, with no cultivation, genius, or special gift of mind
                                or body, instantly filled with the Divine Spirit—whatever that may be—but it is
                                something that caused these common people to become, in a degree, as God's inspired to
                                speak to every man in his own language, or tongue. Is it fanaticism, enthusiasm, or
                                inspiration that asks the question, " Why is not this thing done now ? " The world
                                surely needs the truth just as much as then. Drunkenness, fraud and unchastity, in the
                                men and women of our Broadway, are as rife as in those who crowded up the Oriental mart.
                                Terrible truths these to set before the clergy, the Wall street brokers, the Fifth
                                Avenue dwell- <pb n="181" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 181 ers, and common people. "
                                Their God was really our God — why does not the mighty rushing wind come to us, and the
                                tongues of fire?" These questions are put by the secular press, cognizant of the fact
                                that beneath the shell of our modern hollow civilization there do flow on forever,
                                irresistibly, the great currents of right and wrong, up to a true civilization that will
                                secure, to the greatest number, the greatest possible good —or down to (Russian)
                                brutality. Now, my dear Tribune, I ask, in the name of my old friend Horace, who often
                                stands at your elbow, what would happen in New York if all your readers should fall into
                                line and look at the Pentecost in that practical common sense way? If these internal
                                fires —eternal, abstract truths—which do exist, as you declare, in the very souls of the
                                population of the great city and its suburban villages, being merely crusted over with
                                the conventionalism of society as it now exists, should burst up, as Mt. iEtna is doing,
                                and overflow, would it not sink the whole system in a moment, like a great mill-stone
                                dropped by an angel into the sea? If, in the next morning's issue, the Tribune should
                                announce, with Divine authority—"Henceforth, all things are common, and let no man nor
                                woman say, of aught they have possessed, it is mine, but ours," would not the priests,
                                if a great company of them were willingly obedient to the new faith, rise up in a body,
                                as the heart of one man, and declare, in these words: "It is a Spiritual force, and has
                                come, like a mighty, rushing wind blowing through great masses of people, or the mind,
                                perhaps, of our commonplace neighbors, changing instantly, and without apparent rational
                                cause, their motives, lifting them suddenly to new planes of thought and action?" Are
                                not many hungering souls ready for such food, or has the Tribune ceased to plead the
                                cause, and give voice to the wants and desires of its constituents—the People ?</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, June 2, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, June
                            2,1879.</dateline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Governmental inquisition" TEIform="index"/>GOVERNMENTAL INQUISITION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">From the N. Y. Tribune. Is not the conviction and imprisonment of D. M. Bennett a church
                                and State persecution ? If not, will the Tribune please enlighten the country cousins ?
                                In the circle of my acquaintances, I have never known the people, male and female, more
                                thoroughly aroused than at the present time. What will the end of ecclesiastical
                                governmental interference be ? The approaches of military siege works to capture a
                                citadel were never more systematic and to the point than are the successive moves of the
                                clergy toward theologizing the American government—a union of church and State. Indeed,
                                is it not already virtually accomplished? The world's exposition for every people, creed
                                and theology, was closed by clerical influence upon one of the seven sabbath days of the
                                week, except to a few favorite sinners of whom several thousands were always admitted.
                                The clergy have possessed themselves of the American government. Its mails, the most
                                sacred of all trusts by the people, are broken open, overhauled, and inspected by the Y.
                                M. C. association agents, in the name of the United States. Its courts are turned into
                                inquisitorial engines of physical and mental torture and affliction. Honest American
                                citizens are incarcerated and their business broken up by these merciless
                                God-in-the-Constitution advocates. What an outrage upon the rights of man and the
                                liberty of American citizens to be sanctioned by a government founded by infidels, like
                                Thomas Paine and Thomas Jefferson, and fought for by Washington, father of the Republic,
                                who, when making a treaty with Tripoli, declared before all church and State
                                governments, that the United States did not constitute a Christian nation, and that,
                                constitutionally, it was a purely secular government, under which the Atheist, Deist,
                                Mormon, or the clergy of any theology upon earth, possessed equal civil rights and
                                nothing more. Is not the stealthy passage of Comstock laws and the appointment of an
                                irresponsible individual, publicly charged with grossly immoral and obscene practices,
                                clad in Russian arbitrary power to rob the mails of 30,000,000 inhabitants, an
                                unparalleled inconsistency to common-sense people, who flattered themselves that they
                                were the sovereigns and that the American government was their agent to execute their
                                legally ex _ <pb n="182" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. pressed will'? Not a few,
                                honest, modest people regard the whole Comstock concern as an unmitigated American
                                obscenity. The possibility that such may be true should insure the repeal of all
                                Comstock laws. Can President Hayes, or the editorial corps, fail to see that placing in
                                the hands of any one man or woman, such unlimited and terrible power over the
                                confidential correspondence of a nation, as Comstock is intrusted with, is un-American ?
                                Would the English people endure for a week, the operation of such church and State
                                espionage over their private communications with each other ? I do not believe it. Nor
                                will the American people, when they come to a knowledge of the facts and the issues
                                involved. I would a thousand times prefer leaving the morals of the nation in the hands
                                of parents, school teachers, pastors and logical infidels, than to demoralize American
                                citizens by first tempting them to do evil, then instituting unconstitutional legal
                                proceedings, that rogues may pocket the informer's wages of iniquity after having thus
                                put the cup to their neighbor's lips. Hoping thatD. M, Bennett, and all convicted under
                                Comstock laws, may be at once pardoned, or the agent placed with them in the
                                penitentiary, I, in the name of the liberty loving, law abiding Shaker Order, remain
                                your sincere friend and well wisher.</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Frederick : Respected Sir.—Although it is about two years since I left your family..." TEIform="index"/>Elder Frederick : Respected Sir.—Although it is about two years since I left your family...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, New York, July 5, 1879" TEIform="index"/>New York City, July 5th, 1879</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., G." TEIform="persName"/>G. B.</byline><p TEIform="p">Elder Frederick : Respected Sir.—Although it is about two years since I left your family,
                                after a short experience, I have never changed my Shaker faith. I feel assured if you
                                had understood my motives you would never have written me such a severe letter to
                                Oneida. I had known nothing of Oneida or her community until informed by one of your
                                family. He told me he did not know the principles, but heard they were a good people. As
                                I had felt that your separating me from my wife was more than was actually necessary, I
                                determined, while settling my affairs, to investigate Oneida. I did so, and found
                                principles to which I would never desire to be reconciled. Before I could see you and
                                endeavor to pray you to allow me some concessions, you wrote me to take away my wife. I
                                have conversed with many Shakers since, who all gave me words of consolation and wisdom.
                                They tell me, with my belief and convictions, there is no reason why my wife Frances and
                                myself should not become * members of a Shaker community. I understood from them, that a
                                family, man and wife, professing Shakerism, could be taken by a community without
                                separating them— allowing them to live in the same house together, providing they
                                abstain from carnal pleasures, or sexual gratification. Dear Elder Frederick, Frances
                                and myself view each other with a pure unsullied love. We are willing to abstain from
                                sexual and other indulgences. We think we have the energy and ability to make ourselves
                                good Shakers. Frances staid with you long enough to prove her willingness to work. We
                                believe in Shakerism. We respect you as a father. Why will you not save us from the
                                temptations and vileness of this world ? Two years ago I was disgusted with the
                                wickedness of the world's people, and my disgust increases as I live. Frances and myself
                                have now been united for some years. We agree that we are a happy couple, and do not
                                feel justified at present in separating. We want to live a pure, good life together, and
                                the only place to do so, that I know of, is a Shaker community. Dear Elder, I never felt
                                in my life as I did when you placed your hand on my head, and said : " George, we will
                                endeavor to live a just and good life together." Frances and myself want to do what is
                                right. In our opinion, that means to be Shakers, but we fail to interpret the bible
                                requiring us to separate ourselves from each other. I cannot write just what I mean, but
                                would be happy to come to Mt. Lebanon and see you, providing you might give me some
                                encouragement that we might become members of community without separating. Knowing your
                                boundless virtue, I hope you will write me a favorable letter of advice and consolation.
                                Yours, respectfully,</p></div3><pb n="183" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friend G. B.—Your letter of the 5th inst. is at hand..." TEIform="index"/>Friend G. B.—Your letter of the 5th inst. is at hand...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, July 13th, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, July I7th, 1879</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">Friend G. B.—Your letter of the 5th inst. is at hand. We have no wish to separate man and
                                wife. You can live together so long as you desire so to do in the outside world. Or, if
                                you contemplate becoming Shakers sometime in the future, as a preliminary step—a
                                preparation—you can provide yourselves with a small house near the society, and by
                                attending its meetings, visiting, etc., gradually gather with, or away from the order
                                and people. That you request to be admitted into a society, the fundamental principle of
                                which is celibacy, making a proviso that you room with a woman, evidences your
                                destitution of the simplest element of Shaker faith. We thought—still think, Oneida
                                would exactly meet your wishes—just suit you. There you could maintain a social magnetic
                                relation with each other and yet abstain from sensuality to the extent that you choose
                                or its regulations demanded. What more do you want? They have no law against a man
                                touching a woman. We think it not good. Why ask us to violate our own rules ? Should you
                                at any time hereafter desire to become full Christians—to forsake father, mother, wife,
                                children, lands and little houses to live together in, write me. At present, we can
                                neither walk together nor live together, because we are not agreed. Without the faith of
                                the Shakers, we can neither please God nor the Shakers by living with them. Your letter
                                is well written and applies to a whole class who are seeking union with our order
                                without separating themselves from the generative order ; therefore, do I publish it. If
                                God be God, serve him ; if generation be the God of this World, cleave to it. His
                                servants ye are whom ye obey. Respectfully,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Elder Frederick—I wish to thank you for your excellent letter in to-day's Tribune..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Elder Frederick—I wish to thank you for your excellent letter in to-day's Tribune...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Ludlow Street Jail, July 2, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Ludlow St. Jail, N. Y., July
                                2, 1879</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bennett, D. M." TEIform="persName"/>D. M. Bennett</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Frederick—I wish to thank you for your excellent letter in to-day's Tribune.
                                It is most excellent, indeed. I have seen nothing better. It is exactly to the point.
                                Every sentence is replete with wisdom. I am very glad you wrote it, for they will let
                                you into The Tribune when they will not let my friends here in the city have a chance to
                                say a word. I have written to them since I have been here, and my personal friends have
                                called there and tried hard to get a little space to correct their own
                                misrepresentations; but they would not open their columns on any conditions. The
                                Christian bigots had doubtless bulldozed them. The press of this city have acted very
                                cowardly and mean since my sentence. They seem to be afraid to say their souls are their
                                own. The Christian tyrants seem to own them. I feel sure your letter will do much good.
                                I would be so glad if you would write a similar one to the Sun. I think Dana would print
                                one from you. I shall copy your letter in my next paper, and also incorporate it in the
                                book, I am making up of my "Behind the Bars." I have enough now for 150 pages already
                                stereotyped, and will have 800 or 400 in all. I have great hopes that Hayes will pardon
                                or release me in a week or so. Nearly 50,000 names have been sent on, and thousands come
                                in daily. Gratefully yours,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Starved to death" TEIform="index"/>STARVED TO DEATH</head><p TEIform="p">In an attic, cold and dreary, Lay a mother and her child, Helpless, hopeless, weak and weary,
                            And with craving hunger wild. Husband, father, toil-enduring, Working hard for pittance pay—
                            In a week, enough procuring For his family for a day. Neighbors learn their sad condition ;
                            Gather in to render aid ; Husband goes for a physician— Cannot come, unless he's paid. Tries
                            another and another, Until one consents to come, But too late to save the mother— She in
                            Death's cold arms is numb. Millions spent in church-adorning— Millions wasted, making laws;
                            Millions of the people mourning, While the demon hunger gnaws. Oh, ye paid and trusted
                            leaders! Listen, while ye hold your breath : In this land of Bible-readers, Wives and
                            mothers starve to death !</p></div2><pb n="184" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grand evolution" TEIform="index"/>THE GRAND EVOLUTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The poetical allusion that "his creed cannot be wrong whose life is in the right,"
                                obtains a more general acquiescence than ever; and with such liberal admission,
                                creed-bondage grows beautifully less, while the religion of reason assumes its
                                G-od-giyen position of being right director of the soul. Once, " Tell us what you
                                believe, and we will know if your religion is the right one." Now, "We judge the tree by
                                what it bears," is the pretty general criterion of which theology is the true one. " The
                                good time coming " — come — does away with religious controversies—"the gates of hell"
                                and what manner of life is lived, decides the right or the wrong, the efficiency or
                                deficiency of an adopted faith. The old-time tenacity for the maintenance of dead and
                                dying creeds is scarcely anywhere to be seen or heard, excepting among those whose minds
                                have been abused and strained by erroneous educations, and in whom evidences of lunacy
                                are clearly apparent. The change — the evolvement — the rolling out of a more liberal
                                and progressive religion, has been marvelously rapid, and the grand, most remarkable
                                feature of our day is that it found such a general desire for it—such a universal
                                acceptance of the religion of reason. Millions to-day look back one score years in
                                wonder, and are unable to account for their great change of views; nor when the
                                transformation took place that gave them broader and more loving humanity, that in
                                opening the gates of heaven to all whose lives are right, whose fruits are good, whose
                                works are best, dispels the narrow selfishness of their old theological spheres. The new
                                Earth and Heavens have labored, and the children are born, almost unconsciously forced
                                into superior life. The theologies of a century since are being washed by the
                                intelligence of this age, and the gold remains, while the dross and dust are being
                                carried by the stream of time into oblivion. Let none fear the loss of any good thing.
                                Errors must die, and let us let them go to burial. Truths will supplant them, and let us
                                hail their advent. Amid the tests of theologies,, their washings by reason, and their
                                crucial tests by the fires of truth, there looms up more brightly than ever to the
                                visions of the universal brotherhood the beautiful image of the Christ, undisturbedby
                                vanishing errors. To all the excellencies of his right character, pure aims in life,
                                advanced love for all humanity and exceeding admiration of resurrected humanity are
                                clearly apparent. To this conclusion we are all hastening—that as yet no better model
                                than Jesus, the Christ, has made its appearance on earth. Never has there been a more
                                brilliant consecration of self for humanity's good; no greater renunciation of both the
                                good and bad of the worldly to obtain possession of the more superior and heavenly. His
                                radical positions upon and in favor of purity of life, while admired by the churches
                                more than ever, are yet too radical for the majority. The admiration is on the road to
                                acceptance. Even the correction of the perversions of worldly life to its purest and
                                proper action, is a progress gtfiimriat. <pb n="185" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> toward Christ's life.
                                The multiplied testimonies from the people toward the correction of unnatural, fleshly
                                lusts is very cheering. War, personal and national strifes, were never so unpopular, and
                                a tendency is distinctly seen toward universal peace and good will. The large-hearted
                                works of philanthropists speak many and stirring testimonies against personal
                                accumulations and in favor of the universal interests of brotherly equality. "Advance,"
                                then, all along the line, is our captain's command. To the end that our lives will yet
                                reflect the Master's, and, forsaking the love of the worldly, experiencing a complete
                                renunciation as He did, a union of churches will consequently be established upon the
                                incomparable basis of Christ's life, from which the most beautiful fruits will spring,
                                indicatingits radical features best. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Queries—answers" TEIform="index"/>QUERIES-ANSWERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">" Do tlie Shakers believe Jesus was divine from birth ? " The Shakers are a body of
                                people made up largely from adhesions by those previously belonging to other
                                denominations, whose early educations were from the more popular creeds; hence some
                                Shakers do believe so, but the majority of our people believe Jesus was pretty perfectly
                                " made under the law," " not of the nature of angels, but the seed of humanity;'1
                                "learned obedience by sufferings," was tempted in all points, as are other men and
                                women. The belief. pro or con, possessses no essential to salvation. We make all welcome
                                to believe on such matters as they please, but require of members a purely celibate,
                                peaceable, unworldly life. We, personally, believe Jesus to have been a good Jew, who
                                was converted or progressed to the higher laws and life of Christianity. " Do you
                                believe Joseph was the father of Jesus ?" It is quite immaterial who was the father of
                                Jesus, so that Jesus is a good and more excellent example for humanity, who would be
                                genuine Christians, and not merely nominal Christians, to follow after. If God made
                                Jesus other and better than the rest of humanity, He broke His own laws, and was thus
                                unjust in giving superior advantages to one sent as a pattern for us to follow. If God
                                broke His laws then, we are confident He never will again; and we are just as confident
                                that those who believe He did break His own laws then would not believe the repetition
                                of the circumstance if occurring to-day. " Do you believe Jesus Christ and the God of
                                heaven are one person ? " We do not so believe. Christ is an honorary appendage,
                                indicating that Jesus was anointed for the work He was called to do. To any exact
                                follower of Jesus the. appellation is equally applicable, whether to Daniel, Frederick,
                                Polly or Antoinette. We believe Jesus conformed His mind and life to God's will, and
                                thus He and His Father were (of) one mind. Let us do likewise.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Doing Good.—We were pleased to read in a late number of The Harbinger of Light,
                                Melbourne, Australia, two articles, copied from The Manifesto, from the pens of Elder
                                Evans, and Wm. H. Bussell. and that <pb n="186" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> must be a very noble and
                                liberal oniversalist paper. The Her aid, oi Notasulga, Ala.,which contained three
                                articles credited to The Manifesto, from the pens of Isabel E. Patrick, Daniel Orcutt,
                                and Hortency (1. Hooser. Brethren, we are doing- good—even more than we are aware of—and
                                so let our lights continue to shine, for God is magnified in other souls thereby.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wooden swearing" TEIform="index"/>WOODEN SWEARING</head><p TEIform="p">The Sabbath School in Rockville was assembled for their monthly concert. The lesson was
                                about swearing, and when the children had repeated their verses, the minister rose to
                                talk to them. " I hope, dear children," he said, that you will never let your lips speak
                                profane words. But now I want to tell you about a kind of swearing which I heard a good
                                woman speak about not long ago. She called it wooden swearing. It's a kind of swearing
                                that many people beside children are given to, when they are angry. Instead of giving
                                vent to their feelings in oaths, they slam the doors, kick the chairs, stamp on the
                                floor* throw the furniture about, and make all the noiso they possibly can. 'Isn't this
                                just the same as swearing T said she. ' It's just the same kind of feeling, exactly,
                                only they do not like to say those awful words ; but they force the furniture to make
                                the noise, and so I call it wooden swearing,' I hope, dear children, that you will not
                                do any of this kind of swearing either." It is better to let alone wooden swearing, and
                                all other kinds of swearing.—The Little Christian.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grumbler" TEIform="index"/>THE GRUMBLER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Goodale, Dora" TEIform="persName"/>Dora Goodale</byline><p TEIform="p">My dear children : — Bless your dear young hearts! While making characters for yourselves
                                be determined not to be grumblers. Look just as much as you can on the bright side of
                                life ; of course you do not know of any who are like the following, if so, may you know
                                of less, should there be any among your acquaintances who are in any way related to The
                                Grumbler : His Youth. His coat was too thick and his cap was too thin, He couldn't be
                                quiet, he hated a din ; He hated to write, and he hated to read, He was certainly very
                                much injured indeed ; He must study and work over books he detested, His parents were
                                strict, and he never was rested; He knew he was wretched as wretched could be, There was
                                no one so wretchedly wretched as he. His Maturity. His farm was too small and his taxes
                                too big, He was selfish and lazy, and cross as a pig; His wife was too silly, his
                                children too rude ; And just because he was uncommonly good, He never had money, enough
                                or to spare, He had nothing at all fit to eat or to wear ; He knew he was wretched as
                                wretched could be, There was no one so wretchedly wretched as he. His Old Age. He finds
                                he has sorrows more deep than his fears, He grumbles to think he has grumbled for years;
                                He grumbles to think he has grumbled away His home and his fortune, his life's little
                                day. But, alas ! 'tis too late — it is no use to say That his eyes are too dim. and his
                                hair is too gray. He knows he is wretched as wretched can be, There is no one more
                                wretchedly wretched than he., —[ (ten years old), St. Nicholas.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Papa knows" TEIform="index"/>Papa knows</head><p TEIform="p">It was Saturday evening, and we were returning from New York on the floating palace, Dean
                                Richmond, under the command of Capt. Thos. Christopher. The captain's two bright and
                                beautiful little daughters were on board for a sail to Albany, and sojourn there until
                                Monday, then to return home to New York. After some very interesting conversation with
                                my little friends, I inquired : " Where are you going to stop, and who will take care of
                                you while you are away from mamma t" The <pb n="187" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                187 eldest, leaning her head, most trustingly to one side answered : " I'm sure, I don't
                                know, but papa knows !" Is it not wisdom, that when we find ourselves unable to care for
                                ourselves, there is still left us the thoughts of, and care by our provident, heavenly
                                Father 1 And does not the trust inspired by " Papa knows " ever comfort us ?</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society Record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We clip from The Public Spirit the following interesting items of Harvard and Shirley..." TEIform="index"/>We clip from The Public Spirit the following interesting items of Harvard and Shirley...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We clip from The Public Spirit the following interesting items of Harvard and Shirley : —
                                There is an aged man with the Church family of Harvard Shakers who is worthy of
                                particular mention. Grove Blanchard, who is in his eighty-second year, is still enjoying
                                tolerably good health for one so far advanced in life. He is a native of Petersham, in
                                this State, and commenced the goodly life of a Shaker when fourteen years of age. When
                                he first joined this community the first minister was Eleazer Ran, and after him came
                                John Warner, who was released, and then followed the subject of this sketch, Grove
                                Blanchard, who filled the arduous duties of his office with the greatest satisfac tion.
                                For fifty years he has ministered to his people, and well do they know what a useful
                                life he has spent among them. He was the perfect type of all that was good and lovable,
                                and his stately mien was the cause of many a kindly and deserving re mark from not a few
                                outside of the fold. Even now with tottering limbs, he carries the marks that have so
                                distinguished him in earlier life. May he still have a longer lease of life is the
                                earnest wish of the writer. He was released from the ministry nearly eight years ago,
                                and John Whiteley of the north family of Shirley Shakers, hag taken his place. Thomas
                                Hammond, another Harvard Shaker, if he lives till next August, will be eighty-eight
                                years of age. He was born in Newton, in this State. He too has been a very useful member
                                of the society and wa nineteen when he made his home with the Shakers. Though some years
                                the elder o1 Brother Blanchard, he enjoys very gooc liealth, and is likely to live to a
                                very advanced age. Abraham Whitney, a [member of the Shirley Shakers, was ninety-three
                                last April, and is in the enjoyment of good health. He works a little every day, and his
                                mind is as clear as it ever was. He was born in Bolton, and has been a member of the
                                Shaker family of this town for sixty-three years and over.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morse, Mary Rose" TEIform="index"/>Mary Rose Morse</head><p TEIform="p">Death. — died of consumption, at the Shirley Village, Thursday, July 3, and will be
                                buried Saturday at two o'clock in the afternoon. She was thirty years of age the 28th of
                                May last. Reared from a child in the community at Shirley, she became a prominent
                                member, and for several years had taught the Shaker district school very efficiently and
                                acceptably to the town's committees, as well as the officers and members of the society.
                                She was much beloved by her associates and highly esteemed by a wide circle of friends.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="shaker-reportt" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, New York
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. — Improvement is the order of the day. The Church family have
                                erected a barn 40 by 120 feet, located one mile west of their dwelling. Other new
                                buildings are in course of completion here. Gravel roofs have had their day, and the
                                North family are dismantling one on barn on Rice farm. The most convenient and perfect
                                of laundries has lately been completed here. Very sorry to hear of dangerous illness of
                                Brother Thos. Smith. Sister Dolly Saxton has completed her round of 104 years, and is
                                happy and as " lively as a cricket." Her memory is good.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision of Echard" TEIform="index"/>The Vision of Echard</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier" TEIform="persName"/>Whittier</byline><p TEIform="p">'s last poem-, " ," has this bit of Quakerism, and 'tis all the better for it : Ye bow to
                                ghastly symbols, To cross and scourge and thorns; Ye seek his Syrian manger Who in the
                                heart was born. For the dead Christ, not the living, Ye watch the empty grave, Whose
                                life alone within you Has power to bless and save. 0 blind ones, outward groping The
                                idle quest forego ; Who listens to his inward voice Alone of him shall know.</p></div3></div2><pb n="188" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Camphor balls" TEIform="index"/>Camphor Balls</head><p TEIform="p">Clarify a pound of mutton suet, and add to it three pounds of spermaceti, two of white
                                wax, and one of gum camphor cut into very small pieces. Melt these together with gentle
                                heat, and stir until the camphor is dissolved, then pour it into molds. Frequent
                                applications of this emollient will prevent disagreeable roughness of the hands. Should
                                they become chapped, a most effectual but slightly inconvenient way of healing them is
                                to wrap them in wet cloths with an outside bandage of flannel, first making a free
                                application of the camphor balls. This treatment will soften and whiten the roughest
                                skin, and it is also an excellent application in chronic rheumatism.—Banner of
                            Light.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ingrowing nails" TEIform="index"/>Ingrowing Nails</head><p TEIform="p">Our much valued eldress at So. family, Mt. Lebanon, has had an experience in dealing with
                                these very sore pests ; and.says that a notch-cut in the end of the nail at the center,
                                and as deeply as possi. ble without pain, will effect the desideratum. There are many
                                painful suggestions for relief going the rounds ; but here is one, simple, painless and
                                effective, and the informer has our thanks.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fly banishment" TEIform="index"/>Fly BANISHMENT</head><p TEIform="p">It is again freely circulated, that the combined odors of a geranium and calceolaria in
                                any room, will effectually banish flies. We hope, if any of our trustworthy friends End
                                this a fact, they will report.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Valuable recipe" TEIform="index"/>A Valuable Recipe</head><p TEIform="p">The following is the prescription for what is known throughout the country as " The Sun
                                Cholera Mixture," and is almost identical with the preparation known as " Shaker Pain
                                King." For immediate need it should be always on hand. That paper has published it every
                                summer for the last twenty-five years. It is highly recommended by the medical faculty
                                as being one of the best, if not the best remedy extant for colic, diarrhoea and
                                dysentery. It is advisable to preserve it for future reference : " Take equal parts of
                                the tincture of cayenne pepper, tincture of opium, tincture of rhubarb, essence of
                                peppermint and spirits of camphor. Mix well, t Dose, 15 to 30 drops in a little cold
                                water, according to age and violence of symptoms, repeated every 15 or 20 minutes until
                                relief is obtained."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rest" TEIform="index"/>REST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ryan, [Father]" TEIform="persName"/>Father Ryan</byline><p TEIform="p"> My feet are wearied, and my hands are tired— My soul oppressed ; And with desire have I long
                            desired Rest—only rest. 'Tis hard to toil, when toil is almost vain, In barren ways ; 'Tis
                            hard to sow, and never garner grain In harvest days. The burden of my days is hard to bear.
                            But God knows best ; And I have prayed—but vain has been my prayer For rest, sweet rest.
                            'Tis hard to plant in spring, and never reap The autumn yield ; 'Tis hard to till, and when
                            'tis tilled to weep O'er fruitless field. And so I cry, a weak and human cry, So
                            heart-oppressed ; And so I sigh, a weak and human sigh, For rest—for rest. My way has wound
                            across the desert years And cares infest My path, and through the flowing of hot tears I
                            pine for rest. 'Twas always so, when still a child I laid On mother's breast My wearied
                            little head ; e'en then I prayed, As now, for rest. And I was restless still. 'Twill soon be
                            o'er For, down the West, Life's sun is setting, and I see the shore Where I shall rest.</p></div2><div2 type="book-notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religiophilosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>Religiophilosophical journal
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is with pleasure that we observe the great enterprise exhibited by The
                            ReligioPhilosophical Journal, of Chicago, 111. It is very ably conducted ; increases in
                            interest and good material, and must go to the front with a very multiplied subscription
                            list by its late reduction of price from $3.15 to $2.50. Send for sample copy, free.</p></div2><pb n="189" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's love" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hillsgrove, M. R." TEIform="persName"/>M. R. HILLSGROVE</byline><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. O the love of God how precious, Filling all immensity, 2. By this love
                            we're led to serve Him, And to bear the chastening rod, 3. Gracious Father, we surrender,
                            Time and talents all we claim,—And His mercy O how boundless! Lasting as eternity. By this
                            love we hope to triumph, In obedience to his word. Asking to be worthy ever, These to offer
                            in Thy name. Guiding us to perfect heaven, Where no evil can intrude, Bless us with that
                            holy fervor. That shall quicken us to be May Thy love preserve and hold us To a life
                            divinely pure, May this love so freely given, Fill our hearts with gratitude. Sons and
                            daughters of his likeness, By the truth made wholly free. Light the darkest night O Father,
                            With thy love a passport sure.</p></div2><pb n="190" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let aristocracy think" TEIform="index"/>LET ARISTOCRACY THINK</head><p TEIform="p">Who shall judge man from his manners? Who shall know him by his dress ? Paupers may be fit
                            for princes, Princes fit for something less. Crumpled shirt and dirty jacket May beclothe
                            the golden ore Of the deepest thoughts and feelings— Satin vest can do no more. There are
                            streams of crystal nectat Ever flowing out of stone ; There are purple beds and golden,
                            Hidden, crushed and overthrown. God, who counts by souls, not dresses, Loves and prospers
                            you and me ; While he values thrones the highest, But as pebbles in the sea. Man upraised
                            above his fellows, Oft forgets his fellows then ; Masters—rulers—lords, remember That your
                            meanest minds are men ! Men of labor, men of feeling, Men of thought and men of fame,
                            Claiming equal rights to sunshine In a man's ennobling name. There are foam-embroidered
                            oceans, There are little wood clad rills ; There are feeble inch-high saplings, There are
                            cedars on the hills. God, who counts by souls, not stations, Loves and prospers you and me ;
                            For to him all vain distinctions Are as pebbles in the sea. Toiling hands, alone are
                            builders Of a nation's wealth and fame, Titled laziness is pensioned, Fed and fattened on
                            the same ; By the sweat of others' foreheads, Living only to rejoice, While the poor man's
                            outraged freedom Vainly lifts its feeble voice. Truth and justice are eternal, Born with
                            loveliness and light ; Secret wrongs shall never prosper While there is a sunny right. God,
                            whose world-wide voice is singing Boundless love to you and me, Links oppression with his
                            titles But as pebbles in the sea.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two ladies, both of them a little dull in the hearing..." TEIform="index"/>Two ladies, both of them a little dull in the hearing...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Two ladies, both of them a little dull in the hearing, were in church one day when the
                            minister had for his text, " Except you repent ye shall all likewise perish." They listened
                            patiently enough, but when they got out the one said to the other; "Janet, wasna yon an
                            awfu' text the minister had the day ?—' Except we pay our rent we're a' to be putten out o'
                            the parish.' "</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True strength" TEIform="index"/>TRUE STRENGTH</head><p TEIform="p">We must measure a man's strength by the power of the feelings he subdues, not by the power of
                            those who subdue him. And hence, composure is often the highest result of strength. Did we
                            ever see a man receive a flagrant injury, and then reply calmly? That is a man spiritually
                            strong. Or, did we ever see a man in anguish, stand as if carved out of solid rock, as if
                            mastering himself ? Or, one bearing a hopeless, daily trial, remain silent and never tell
                            the world what cankered his home peace ? That is strength. We too often mistake strong
                            feelings for strong character. A man, who bears all before him, before whose frown domestics
                            tremble, and whose bursts of fury make the children of the household quake, because he has
                            his way in all things, we call him a strong man. The truth is, that he is a weak man; it is
                            his passions that are strong — he, mastered by them, is weak.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ready for death" TEIform="index"/>READY FOR DEATH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Feltham, Owen" TEIform="persName"/>Owen Feltham</byline><p TEIform="p">He that always waits upon God is ready whensoever He calls. I will labor to set my accounts
                            even, and endeavor to find God such to me in my life, as I would in death should he appear.
                            If I cannot put off humanity wholly, let me put off as much as I can; and that which I must
                            wear let me but loosely carry. When the affections are glued to the world, death makes not a
                            dissolution but a fraction, and not only separates the soul, but tears it away. So the pain
                            and the hazard are more. He is a happy man that lives so, as death at all times may find at
                            leisure to die.— </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This is the way the Japanese put facts..." TEIform="index"/>This is the way the Japanese put facts...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">This is the way the Japanese put facts : " A hawk and a crow, you know, can fly away when
                            they have two wings. And if one wing be maimed or shot off, the bird flutters to the ground
                            and cannot fly. We also have two wings on which we fly to heaven ; the one is faith and the
                            other works. But we can only fly thither with two, and if we try with one we fall to the
                            ground, and flutter and crawl there like a maimed bird."</p></div2><pb n="191" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco habit" TEIform="index"/>THE TOBACCO HABIT</head><p TEIform="p">A man in our neighborhood having of late become convinced on the tobacco question, was led to
                            make a calculation how much his tobacco habit had cost him in forty years, computing at
                            compound interest. He was so astounded at the result that he engaged another, more skillful
                            than himself in the use of figures, to correct or supervise his work. The outlay was found
                            to amount to no less than thirteen thousand three hundred dollars. He is a poor man, and no
                            wonder. Thirteen thousand three hundred dollars in the course of forty years, spit and
                            smoked away. Think of this, gentle reader, when you smoke tobacco. It is often pleaded on
                            behalf of the tobacco user : But may not the poor man, after the toil of the day is done, be
                            allowed the comfort of a quiet smoke in his own chimney corner or by his own fireside ? We
                            ask, would not the stimulus to be derived from the evening paper which the money puffed away
                            in smoke would buy, or from some good book, or from the thought that he was doing something
                            better for his children than he would otherwise be able to do, or that he was laying up
                            something for a wet day, prove quite as comforting, and far more civilizing and ennobling,
                            than that drawn from a stinking pipe in the chimney corner ?</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Birds must die and children starve" TEIform="index"/>BIRDS MUST DIE AND CHILDREN STARVE</head><p TEIform="p">London Letter to New York Times.</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The other day I came upon a new store in the city..." TEIform="index"/>The other day I came upon a new store in the city...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The other day I came upon a new store in the city. The windows were fairly dazzling with
                                color. A stray sunbeam falling v upon them, the shop front flashed back a rainbow of
                                blue and green and red and yellow, indigo and vermilion, amber and black and white. I
                                paused to gaze. It was a store devoted to the modern fashion of adorning ladies' hats,
                                bonnets, and dresses with birds and butterflies. All the corners of the earth had been
                                ransacked to satisfy this new craze. Whole birds' wings, tails, breasts, were here by
                                the thousand. Butterflies and humming-birds vied with each other in wealth of color and
                                beauty of arrangement. It is true there are lots of stores in London devoted to
                                specimens of " natural history," where these things may be purchased ; but here is a
                                shop full of them, not as studies or specimens, but as articles of adornment. Travelers
                                and others tell me that bird slaughter as a trade has now reached proportions which
                                threaten the very extinguishment of some of the rarest, as well as gayest, species. One
                                can understand this when stated on authority that a German dealer in this city recently
                                received a consignment of 32,000 dead humming birds, 80,000 aquatic birds of several
                                varieties, and 800,000 pairs of wings. This to one dealer alone ; while at the same time
                                all the other traders are increasing their orders to foreign shippers. There is
                                something very sad in these figures. Surely our women cannot think about the subject, or
                                they would never promote this sacrifice of bird life for a mere freak of fashion. The
                                rage for feather trimmings has almost annihilated the ribbon trade jai Coventry. Men,
                                women, and children in that once busy city are starving because fashion has produced a
                                new style of ornament. So that to please the whim birds must die and children must
                                starve. You may stand " on the bridge at Coventry" now and see scores of people
                                loitering there who, but for the supersedure of ribbons by feathers, would be busily at
                                work in the locked up mills.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hallelujah idols" TEIform="index"/>HALLELUJAH IDOLS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The self-renunciation of the ladies of Florence, when, under the preaching of
                                    Savonarola, they cast their jewels and false hair into the bonfire in the Piazza
                                    delta Signoria, is paralleled by the recent converts of the " Hallelujah Lasses" at
                                    Blyth, England. " On Tuesday night," says the local paper, " an interesting and
                                    novel sale took, place at Blyth, Mr. Fynes, auctioneer, having offered at public
                                    auction (for the benefit of whom it may concern) a large collection of Hallelujah
                                    Idols, comprising poultry, canaries, parrots, bird cages, dress rings, meerschaum
                                    pipes, a variety of gentlemen's and ladies' dress ornaments, and a miscellaneous
                                    group of other articles, which had been given up by parties in this district on
                                    their conversion by the' Hallelujah Lasses.'" There was a numerous attendance at the
                                    sale.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian nion" TEIform="index"/>Christian Union</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="192" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Effects of Love" TEIform="index"/>The Effects of Love</head><p TEIform="p"> When Rev. Dr. Alexander Clark s death was announced, the Albany Express stated that he was
                            the only known orthodox minister who ever took a friendly interest in the skeptic and spoke
                            good words for him. And that Col. Ingersoll appreciated the man and his great-heartedness
                            read these feeling extracts from his tribute to the late Pittsburg editor ¦ Upon the grave
                            of the Rev. Alexander Clark I wish to place one flower. Utterly destitute of cold dogmatic
                            pride that often passes for the love Of God, without the arrogance of the " elect" — simple,
                            free and kind — this earnest man made me his friend by being mine. I forgot that he was a
                            Christian, and he seemed to forget that I was not, while each remembered that the other was
                            a man. He believed in the power of kindness, and spanned with divine sympathy the hideous
                            gulf that separated the fallen from the pure. Giving freely to others the rights that he
                            claimed for himself, it never occurred to him that his God hated a brave and honest
                            unbeliever. With the generosity of an honest man, he accorded to all the fullest liberty of
                            thought, knowing, as he did, that in the realm of thought, a chain is but a curse. For this
                            man I entertained the profoundest respect. In spite of the taunts and jeers of his brethren,
                            he publicly proclaimed that he would treat infidels with fairness and respect; that he would
                            endeavor to convince them by argument and win them with love. He insisted that the God he
                            worshipped loved the wellbeing of even an atheist. In this grand position he stood almost
                            alone. Tender, just and loving where others were harsh, vindictive and cruel, he challenged
                            the respect and admiration of every honest man. He admitted that I had not lost and could
                            not lose a single right by the expression of my honest thought. Neither did he believe that
                            a servant could win the respect of a generous master by persecuting and maligning those whom
                            the master would willingly forgive. His sympathies were not confined within the prison of a
                            creed, but ran out and over the walls like vines, hiding the cruel rocks and rusted bars
                            with leaf and flower. He could not echo with his heart the fiendish sentence of eternal
                            fire. In spite of book and creed, he " read between the lines " the words of tenderness and
                            love, with promises for all the world. Above, beyond the dogmas of the church — humane even
                            to the verge of heresy — causing some to doubt his love of God because he failed to hate his
                            unbelieving fellowmen, he labored for the welfare of mankind, and to his work give up his
                            life with all his heart.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oh, Enfield!" TEIform="index"/>Oh, Enfield!</head><p TEIform="p">—The New York Sun is responsible for the statement that the Shakers of Enfield, Conn., are
                            losing some of their primitive simplicity. It says: "Their new buildings, equipped with
                            almost every convenience, show that one by one the luxuries of social life are getting a
                            foothold. Books, newspapers, instruments of music, carpets, cushioned chairs, and steam for
                            heating, washing and cooking are in their habitations." To which the courteous Am. Socialist
                            make rejoinder: "Well, why shouldn't the saints enjoy the good things of this life as well
                            as the sinners ? Can that luminary which ' shines for all' tell us."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words to us" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words to us</head><p TEIform="p">We have received the J uly number of the Shaker Manifesto, edited by G. A. Lomas, and
                            published by the United Societies. Coming from such a source, it is of curious interest and
                            not without literary ability, truth and common-sense. Among the subjects treated are
                            "Respiration," by Martha Anderson ; " Freeman's Faith," a letter from the deluded wife of
                            the fanatical Pocasset murderer, with Elder Evans' logical comments ; " Philosophy of
                            Shakerism," by C. M. Overton ; " Catholicism," a reply to a Catholic priest, by H. L. Eads ;
                            " For the Intemperate," etc. Shakers, New York.—Boston Commonwealth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is reported that Dr. Gumming, of London, in a recent lecture, announced to..." TEIform="index"/>It is reported that Dr. Gumming, of London, in a recent lecture, announced to...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is reported that Dr. Gumming, of London, in a recent lecture, announced to his
                            congregation that he firmly believed that many of his hearers would live to witness Christ's
                            second coming. The rapid fulfilling of prophecy indicates the near approach of the great
                            millennium, and it would be a source of much happiness if we could be permitted to realize
                            that the grand event shall take place during the present generation.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good philosophy" TEIform="index"/>Good Philosophy</head><p TEIform="p">A little girl of five years, when on a visit, refused to take a hot roll at the tea table. "
                            Why not, my dear ? " asked the hostess. " Don't you like rolls ?" " Yes ma'am," she said, "
                            but when I eat them at night, I always dream of black cats, and I had rather go without
                            rolls than to be so frightened." Here was an embryo philosopher! Well would it be if every
                            person who is troubled with bad dreams would both study out and avoid the cause of them.</p></div2><!--
   				<pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>