<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2505" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18950501" TEIform="date">May 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
MAY.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
" Cast tht bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.	
	Page.
Truth and Fiction,	97
Gleams,          -.- -..	')*<
Thy Will be Done,	100
Self Control,.....	"
Life's Foundation,	10-2
They Ministered,	
Sowing and Reaping,	104
Obedience,            .....	    105
Which Choose Ye,	107
Bight Living,                ....	108
Music,Courage,	110
Notes About Home,	111
Look Upward,	in;
Spring Cleaning          ....	"
Thoughts.          .....	117
Acrostic,......	"
What was his Creed,	
Letter,1). Orcutt,	118
The Bright Side,	
Exchanges.           .....	Hi)
Denunciation,	
Deaths,            ......	1-20
Books & Papers,	
WANTED
RELIABLE MEN to sell
our choice and complete
line of Nursery Stock.
'Highest salary and commission paid weekly, paying permanent position
guaranteed and biiccess assured to good men.
Special inducements to beginners, experience
not necessary. Exclusive territory and your
own choice of same given.   Do not delay.
app.,.0  ALLEN NURSERY CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
THE mill COVENANT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all in"
quiring minds.    Price 5  cts. each,   postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the hd without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond  belief.
Practical and artistic'.   Sond for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY=PA1NB MFQ. CO., Phila., Pa.
This is a good CliunjEd.
WANTED!
Agent to sell our new book, Dictionary of
United States History, by Prof. J. Franklin Jameson. Needed by every teacher, pupil, and family; indorsed. Agents selling fifty books per week. Successful agents will
be made general agents.   Big* pay.
1 UHITAN PUBLISHING CO., Boston. Mass.
CAN I OBTATN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN fc CO., who have had nearlyfifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A IIamlbnok of Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.  S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, tiS cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New Yohk, 361 BROADWAY.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
= IUUSTBATES HOME JOUKITAi =
BO Cts. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
thomas a. xnsvruLAur ft son,
CHICAGO, ILL.--><pb n="97" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth and fiction" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH AND FICTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">A RECENT writer has said; Man may be defined as an animal that readily believes a lie.
                            Ancient wisdom says, In vain the net is spread in sight of any bird. "But man not only waits
                            patiently to have the snare woven around him, but will turn and aid its completion." He
                            reads or listens to fiction assuming it to be real, or quasi-real, till it takes the place
                            of the real to him, and the real seems fancied or imaginary. We toil hard, early and late,
                            to gain earthly pelf for the support and shelter of our bodies. Why spend those painfully
                            coined life drops for gin, hock and whiskey, which poison the blood, or to encourage the
                            makers of fiction to feed the mind on lies, husks and trash as a substitute for the true and
                            the real which is ever spread out around and within us in abundance. If the latter costs
                            more exertion and self-denial to acquire, being real and permanent, it is of a thousand-fold
                            more value than the tissues of fiction that lazy people weave from their disordered fancies
                            and perverted talents, to gain the means of subsistence from careless dawdlers, whose
                            leisure is not prized as opportunity for spiritual culture, and whose labor is wasted on
                            trifles. There is no healthy mental nourishment in fiction. It forms an element in which the
                            good seed of the gospel will not grow. People feed their own spiritual craving and the minds
                            of children, on tales of ogres, brownies, elves and pixies that have no existence outside of
                            a delusive fancy, rather than receive instruction upon the mode of spiritual existence, the
                            laws which govern our conditions hereafter, put in operation by our own free moral agency,
                            and the knowledge which our departed friends MAY, <pb n="98" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 98 THE MANIFESTO. are
                            able to give us through spiritual communication. Thus they feed on delusion till they are
                            led to believe that all spirit manifestations me pretended and unreal, and having but slight
                            experience of any other kind they seem to have an utter disrelish and disbelief of the true.
                            Exciting fiction has an effect upon a sensitive, nervous temperament which may be compared
                            to that of intoxicating beverages upon the body. It tends to pervert the reason, stimulate
                            imagination to excess and to unbalance the judgment, substituting false criterions and false
                            concepts for original and true. A good rule to follow for those who are cur.-ed with the
                            habit, or who have temptations in this line, is to refuse to read any work known to be
                            fictitious, be it long or short, and no matter how great or little the genius or fame of the
                            writer. If you desire to reap the most satisfactory harvest, let fiction alone till you have
                            exhausted all other sources of knowledge and you will lose nothing of value by so doing.
                            This condemnation does not apply to moral allegories, similitudes and parables used by
                            sages, philosophers and prophets to convey religious and spiritual truths to their hearers.
                            These invariably appeal to, stimulate aud feed those superior faculties of mind which the
                            fictions of the lower life narcotize and benumb. Whoever by the truth is made wholly free,
                            will have no use for the delusive shadow called fiction. Chaff is more than fiction because
                            it serves a need, a use, while the good seed is growing, but even that must be burned with
                            unquenchable fire. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gleams from the divine inmost" TEIform="index"/>GLEAMS FROM THE DIVINE INMOST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">/^ORGANIZATION is the primal energy of pure being. It is even beV_y hind all Evolution.
                            Again, systematic arrangement underlies all esoteric existences and phenomena. All things
                            visible and invisible are one; therefore the law of differentiation is only in degrees, not
                            in variety of substance for there is none. The greater the energy the greater the results :
                            the less, the less and no matter what directions they take. A greater amount of energy plus
                            a lesser, will produce a greater result than either separately. If God's love and wisdom are
                            greater than mine and he imparts a measure to me I am blessed and bettered thereby. If I
                            have more than another and impart to him, the same result follows. If an inmate of the slums
                            of New York or London has, and imparts, more love and wisdom than a scullion the latter will
                            be blessed and bettered. This seems to be a comforting confirmation of St. Paul's remarkable
                            saying "Without ah1 contradiction the less is blessed of the better." This sublime law of
                            the universe when brought into practical requisition and systematic arrangement of Ministry,
                            Elders, Trustees, Deacons and all members in the Church does work wonders. One of these <pb n="99" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 99 is, that it gives room for the faculties and talents
                            of the members in all directions of usefulness. No one can appreciate nor even calculate the
                            immense value of this sublime arrangement only by an actual experience of long duration in
                            obedience to its dictates. The results of this obedience are the gradual expansion of that
                            little spark of the Kingdom of Heaven in each one of us into a genial fire and which Jesus
                            declared consisted of righteousness, peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. What greater Heaven
                            than this can be found here or hereafter? At the risk of being thought a fool (albeit for
                            Christ's sake,) I will point out one of the paths of evolution I have found through the
                            instrumentality of this systematic arrangement. I discovered man in his rudimental condition
                            to be not much better than an animal. The secretions of his blood, his animal energies and
                            lower impulses led him directly to a life of generation: but when I confessed my sins I
                            became convinced that these secretions were capable of re-absorption and of being carried to
                            the front and top brain there to give amazing energy to pure sweet and holy impulses to
                            higher intellectual energy to higher aspiiations for love and good will to others. This was
                            a regeneration of all the animal instincts into a vastly higher type of energy. Then came
                            the tug of war, for "Greek had met Greek." I was confronted with the solemn alternative,
                            "Choose ye this day whom ye will serve" the inexorable demands of generation or the higher
                            call for regeneration? My own will and choice must arbitrate this awful question. I must
                            choose for myself. Jesus had not come unto me for it was now dark and he was asleep in the
                            hinder part of the ship, and so after much wrestling I decided once and forever for a life
                            of regeneration ; to lay down and abandon forever the world, the flesh and all negative
                            issues. O what immortal glories I receive glimpses of, as I progress in this sublime
                            evolution from flesh to spirit or from lower to higher existence. I sometimes exclaim with
                            the poet "In thy goodness O God what a victory is this Over all evil passions to reign, With
                            a Heaven here on Earth and the bright fields of bliss, And sin can not come with its pain.
                            As the green waving tree or the still autumn sky Is the Holy serene of the souls Who have
                            fought the good fight and ascended on High Where the river of Love ever rolls." In more and
                            more love and better and better wishes for The Manifesto and all its managers and
                            manipulators I close. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="After the conflict that has stirred our very soul-depths..." TEIform="index"/>
                            After the conflict that has stirred our very soul-depths...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">After the conflict that has stirred our very soul-depths, and hatred and pride have been
                            defeated ; then in the triumph of the noblest and best that is in us, we can say with the
                            great Julius Caesar, "I have no enemies to forgive, because I recognize no enemy." </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="100" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thy will be done" TEIform="index"/>THY WILL BE DONE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah J. Burger.</byline><p TEIform="p">O Lord unto Thine altar pure I bring Some cherished idol for an offering, That through Thy
                            love my soul may chastened be, And though the sacrifice be hard for me, I'll pray, Thy will
                            be done. Though bitter waters oft my cup may fill, In resignation I will do Thy will, Endure
                            the cioss and trial, for at length I know will come the love, the power and strength To say,
                            Thy will be done. Though roses crushed lie withering at my feet, There yet remains a perfume
                            pure and sweet; And though life's joys sometimes may clouded be, A sincere prayer ascends O
                            Lord to Thee To let Thy will be done. O may I gain that holiness of life That sanctities the
                            soul and saves from strife, And in the spirit of pure love divine On bended knee at truth's
                            most sacred shrine Pray that Thy will be done. And whatsoever I must feel or do, I know Thy
                            holy power will help me through, Make light my burdens and relieve my care, And clothe with
                            graces true my soul would wear So let Thy will be done. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-control" TEIform="index"/>SELF-CONTROL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sevester, Edwin P." TEIform="persName"/>By Edwin P. Sevester.</byline><p TEIform="p">"TT^ITHER we must master ourselves, and rule our passions and temper, or JLjJelse they will
                            rule us. It is strength of character to live to our principles, to have the moral courage to
                            live out our convictions of right and truth, to stand up against adversity, to be calm and
                            self-contained even when the arrows of malice pierce us most cruelly. It is strength to
                            perform our whole duty to man without hope or any prospect of reward. The man or woman of
                            unbending moral principle is a real hero. The one who stands erect with his heel on the
                            demon of temptation, is nobler and stronger than the most gifted statesman or the conquering
                            chief. The taint of sin gives all of us <pb n="101" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 101 passions
                            and opens a hundred avenues to the tempter. To close them all, and live true to ourselves,
                            and to the right, is to exalt our most divine life and be a blessing to mankind. Our
                            choracter is to be built like a dam in a river. While being compacted and solidified, the
                            restrained waters, like evil passions and wicked impulses, seek to break through; a single
                            breach and it widens, and at last the torrent destroys the whole dam. Guard against the
                            smalk st fracture, and it is safe and strengthens year by year, until at last, firm as the
                            anchored rock it breasts the mightiest floods or freshets unharmed. Without this unyielding
                            self-control, our life is like a ship without a rudder or compass, blown about hither and
                            thither by every wind and at last wrecked. But with it, it is like the same ship, with a
                            safe and strong arm at the helm, that holds her to her course, when the storm-clouds lower
                            or the angry gales seek to drive her toward the breakers ; that avoids the hidden rocks and
                            shoals, bringing her safely into port. In this endeavor, we fail not to war against vice in
                            all its myriad forms. Evil is often robed in splendor, but however dazzling the outer,
                            within is but corruption and decay. "Whited sepulchers which indeed appear beautiful
                            outward, but within are full of dead men's bones and all uncleanness." If the canker worm is
                            at the core of an apple, it is destined to decay and no earthly power can avert its fate. It
                            is the first encroaches which should be most sternly repulsed. Each temptation, which moral
                            rectitude enables us to resist, leaves us stronger for the next encounter. But woe to him
                            who yields to the tempter; at each successive attack the moral stamina grows weaker and
                            weaker for the walls of even a Sebastopol lose their protective value, whenever a single
                            breach is made in them. How truthfully a gifted poet has declared : "We are not bad at once.
                            The course of evil Begins so slowly, and from such slight source An infant's hand could stem
                            its breach with clay. But let the stream grow deeper, and Philosophy, Aye and Eeligion too
                            will strive in vain To stem the head-long torrent." . Religion is fully able .to "stem the
                            head-long torrent" of sin if only the wicked will be released from his wickedness, because
                            man is a free agent, able to accept or refuse at his own free choice the means God has
                            offered him in the gospel to be redeemed from sin. We are born into this world, with good
                            and evil mysteriously combined within us. The soul is the immortal, divine, and we are
                            created in the image of God. But after a little time, comparatively, the child's passions
                            develop ; self-will, defiance, anger and revenge in a greater or less degree, and this
                            compels that parental restraint, so valuable and necessary in every household, be exercised.
                            Thus the Spirit of good and the spirit of evil struggle for the mastery in every heart. With
                            every <pb n="102" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE MANIFESTO. good impulse drawing us toward the right, and
                            with every evil impulse drawing us toward the wrong we commence the endless, ceaseless
                            battle of life. Our birth is but a starting place, Life is the running of the race. Properly
                            trained and conscientiously directed, the child grows up an affectionate, enlightened,
                            energetic, self-denying man, an honor and a blessing to the community where he resides,
                            beloved while living and when life is ended, remembered and regretted by many hearts.
                            Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life's foundation" TEIform="index"/>LIFE'S FOUNDATION.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Sarah Ann Collins.] 
                                    THE foundation of life is truth. It is the foundation of home life, business
                                    life, Church life and of society. Without it there is no stability because there is
                                    no confidence. Even careless thinkers admit this, and those who least regard it in
                                    practice, sometimes in their innermost souls value it most highly. The value of
                                    truth as a basis of living is acknowledged, "Buy ihe truth and sell it not." With
                                    upright, straightforward dealing comes a good conscience. It is a strange and solemn
                                    power which conscience wields. Jn secret a wrong is committed, one feels guilty and
                                    wretched and is in his own eyes degraded. This feeling does not pass away ; at times
                                    it revives. Conscience speaks most forcibly in lonely hours. It awakens one at night
                                    by the side of the bed, and says wake up, listen to me, and holds with a remorseless
                                    eye. Wrong-doing comes from the grave of the past and marches by in melancholy
                                    procession, in terror one looks at it and goes forth to business, trying to smile,
                                    but conscience has its revenge. It pays to be upright in small as well as great
                                    matters.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="They ministered of holy things" TEIform="index"/>THEY MINISTERED OF HOLY THINGS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens. </byline><p TEIform="p">Do ye not know that they which minister about holy things, live of the things of the temple?
                            and they which wait at the altar are partakers with the altar? 1 Cor. ix., 13. WHAT a broad
                            vista of thought this beautiful passage of Scripture opens up to the mind ! Right here I am
                            impressed with this idea ; how much we are indebted to the Jews as a race of people; no one
                            can read the Bible understandingly without perceiving much that is noble and grand in their
                            history; superior in many respects to our present system of civili- <pb n="103" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 103 zation ; but many with ardent hopes and faces turned toward the sunrise
                            of the coining day, are apt to discard everything of the past as worthless, in comparison
                            with present developments. But not so; God's truth is eternal, no matter in what age of the
                            world it was first revealed. It is well for us to perceive the good of the past, as well as
                            the present and future. We Lave many records of this peculiar people that are truly
                            wonderful. Moses was ordained of God as their law-giver; Aaron, his brother, their
                            High-priest, who ministered to their spiritual necessities. They believed in one invisible
                            God, with whom Moses held communion at various times. It is statc-d that the Lord commanded
                            that the chief of the twelve tribes of Israel should bring a branch of almond tree to Moses,
                            who was to write every man's name on the branch and deposit it in the Tabernacle, for the
                            Lord would show them by a miracle which tribe should hold the office of the priesthood. In
                            the morning, the branch that Aaron deposited had budded, blossomed and borne fruit. Thus the
                            family of Aaron and his descendants became the hereditary priesthood, and this was the most
                            honored office that a Jew could hold. In the sanctuary of the Temple was a secret place,the
                            Sanctum Sanctorium, or Holy of Holies. Here was placed the Ark of the Covenant, whose golden
                            cover was the Mercy Seat; over this the cherubim, with outstretched wings called the Throne
                            of God; above this a visible cloud, the Sheckinah or Divine Presence, in which Jehovah was
                            supposed to be actually present, to hear and answer prayer and make known his holy will. The
                            High-priest alone was allowed to come into the Holy of Holies; he stood in God's presence as
                            a "day's-man between heaven and earth," and communicated the law of God to tiie, people.
                            This most sacred office required great sanctification of soul and body, for if they
                            ministered of holy things, they must live the spiritual life of the Temple, and if they
                            wrait at the altar they must be partakers of the Divine grace that rests over the altar. All
                            forms, ceremonies and symbols in the lapse of ages lose their life and are destined to be
                            succeeded by others, but the spiritual ideas that they represented, all that made them a
                            thought of God will last forever, as Emerson so beautifully expresses it, "The heedless
                            world hath never lost One accent of the Holy Ghost." We, as members of the Virgin Church of
                            Christ, are called to be "Priests and Priestesses unto God." Ancient forms have passed away,
                            but to us is revealed their deeper meaning. We have found the altar of sacrifice, so
                            beautifully typified in the Jewish religion, whereon we sacrifice the lower life of self to
                            gain the life of the Spirit,the eternal life. We have found the Mercy Seat covered with the
                            overshadowing wings of a heavenly Father and Mother, where we may feel their divine
                            benedictions; to us is revealed the Holy Presence, the light of Revelation that shows where
                            our feet must walk <pb n="104" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE MANIFESTO. in paths of purity, self-denial
                            aud integrity, proving by our devotion our loyalty to the cause. "They which minister about
                            holy things, live of the tilings of the temple, and they which wait at the altar are partak
                            rs with the altar." Ours is a holy faith, an exalted calling; we are to be light bearers to
                            the world. With this sacred mission upon us, our duty is imperative to be trui' to our
                            profession, and if we minister of holy things we must also live of holy things for "faith
                            without works is dead." To render every sacrifice of self willingly, that the Truth may have
                            its perfect work, developing the immortal faculties of the mind and uniolding that purity of
                            soul by which alone we see God and gain eternal life, should be our life long aim. Only
                            through obedience to divine light, and loyalty to our high principles can we bear aloft the
                            banner of holiness and prove our heaven-sent commission. Let the fires of Truth be rekindled
                            upon the altars of our hearts, then indeed, can we be the ministers of the holy things of
                            the temple of which we have been made partakers. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing and reaping" TEIform="index"/>SOWING AND REAPING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bodine, Sarah F." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah F. Bodine.</byline><p TEIform="p">T I ^HE natural or physical world is only an external manifestation of the JL spiritual,
                            which is the archetype ;"it is the effect of which God is the cause." All life develops from
                            within outward. The spirit or life is eternal therefore existed before it found expression
                            in physical organisms ; but how and when is a problem which many philosophical and
                            scientific minds have endeavored to solve and have arrived at the conclusion that their
                            powers of investigation and comprehension were too weak to vie with the Almighty or to
                            measure the Infinite. That life is the vitalizing spark, burning in the heart of creation,
                            and that it is of God we are certain ; that there are many degrees of its development we
                            readily perceive. No manifestation of life is despicable ; go search out the ways of the
                            Almighty; the lowest unfoldment is important and holds a relationship to the Creator
                            according to its rank. So we are encouraged to cherish the spark that lives in humanity to
                            toil for it and even anticipate its perfection. The sowing and reaping periods are
                            momentous, as is also the time of cultivation. Before each of us lies a fieldthe field of
                            destiny. The parable of the sower perfectly represents the conditions in life of every
                            individual. We are all sowers. In this field are places as sterile as the steppes of Siberia
                            ; spots where the refreshing dews of Divine love, and the plenteous showers of heaven's
                            blessing never descend to moisten the parched soil, but <pb n="105" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 105 there are places fertile and beautiful where all that is virtuous and lovely
                            grows. With the knowledge which we possess concerning the field wherein we are called to
                            labor, should we not strive to understand fully the responsibility that rests upon us? We
                            sow in the field of another as well as in our own. The sterile place must be cultivated and
                            seeds of love, trust and purity sown therein; but the soil that yields the rose also
                            produces the thorn, and in the ground where the wheat matures we find also the tares. The
                            wheat we liken to that which is good, while the tares represent the evil, "evil is the abuse
                            of good," the result of ignorance in the misdirection of the life forces. The great secret
                            of our happiness lies, in directing these forces aright, in other words, sowing the seeds
                            that will yield fruits of joy and peace. The enemy that sows tares is within ; he that heeds
                            and watches closely every manifestation of growth, will easily discern by their formation
                            whether they will develop into the precious and graceful wheat that bends and sways in the
                            sunshine of God's free blessing, or into tares which are certain to yield a harvest of
                            disappointment. "Sow in faith, Sow the good seed, another after thee Shall reap." We may
                            wait long and late for the harvest of our soul efforts ; the sun may shine and the dew fall
                            over and over again before we realize the harvest. Some thought germs may well be compared
                            to the century plant, others to biennials, annuals etc; but as surely as the sun rises and
                            sets in each successive day, when the harvest time comes, we shall reap that which we have
                            sown. The law of retribution is just, and is the great power that governs life; "whatsoever
                            a man soweth that shall he also reap." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience" TEIform="index"/>OBEDIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kirkley, George H." TEIform="persName"/>By George H. Kirkley.</byline><p TEIform="p">If ye love me keep my commandments.John, xiv., 15. OUR whole duty to God is built upon a
                            foundation of obedience to his laws. The whole creation is based upon laws which can not be
                            disobeyed without bringing destruction to the portion that is in disobedience. We know that
                            a disregard of the laws of hygiene is sure to be followed with consequences, that none of us
                            are pleased to experience, and just as surely as punishmemt follows the transgression of the
                            law of physics, just so surely will it follow a disregard of the moral laws that have been
                            framed for the good of society, or the higher spiritual laws governing our relations to each
                            other as religious beings. The question naturally arises, Whom and what are we to obey? Is
                            it <pb n="106" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 106 THE MANIFESTO. our duty to obey every person who may have a
                            seeming authority over us? Are we obliged to obey any and every rule or regulation drawn up
                            by such authority, regardless of our personal feelings in the matter? The Declaration of
                            Independence asserts that "all men are created free and equal," and this no one can deny. We
                            all enter this world as free and independent beings, each with a distinct individuality.
                            What we may become, depends in a measure on our early instructions, what we may wish to be,
                            on the way we direct our youthtul ambitions, and what we are in after life, ' depends on the
                            obedience we render to the laws of God, that have come to our knowledge, both by instruction
                            and observation. As a Society, or as individual members of Society, our success depends, on
                            the obedience we render to the vital piinciples involved in our "Church Covenant," as well
                            as to the less important rules and precepts that govern each famity. All of us who are old
                            enough to choose for ourselves, understand, that our presence in Society is the strongest
                            profession we can make of obedience to its rules and regulations. The fact of our church
                            membership is a guarantee that we are honestly professing an obedience to the laws of God as
                            interpreted in the tenets of the Church, and an acceptance of the principles upon which the
                            law and order of the Church are based. There is no obligation that compels one to become
                            united with any church, or to believe in any form of worship ; but every person whose mind
                            is developed, arrives at certain fixed ideas, wh'ch at last form a belief in the mind, which
                            can not be doubted. Whether the belief is Christianity, Mohamedism or Atheism, it is only by
                            living strictly to what we profess, that will bring satisfaction. It is a love for the
                            principles that we wish to demonstrate, that gives us our greatest inspiration to obedience.
                            Jesus said, "He that hath my commandments and keepeth them, he it is that loveth me; and he
                            that loveth me, shall be loved of my Father, and I will love him, and will manifest myself
                            unto him." Jesus has given us an example of this spirit of obedience. We read of his
                            suffering in the garden of G-ethsemane, on the night before his crucifixion and how with the
                            dread of his agony before him, he prayed,"O my Father, if this cup may not pass away from me
                            except I drink it, Thy will be done." Yet the next day, he betrayed no sign of fear, as he
                            was led to the cross. He rendered unquestioning obedience to his Father's will, hence he is
                            able to exhort his followers to keep his commandments; not fearingly, but with a loving
                            cheerfulness, evidences that we have perfect love in our hearts that casteth out fear. Thus
                            while our obedience should be inspired by a love for the principles and spirit of the work
                            which we have undertaken, we should bear in mind, that, "No half way work, no vain pretense,
                            can satisfy the soul." Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="107" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which choose ye?" TEIform="index"/>WHICH CHOOSE YE?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Earnest" TEIform="persName"/>By Earnest Pick.</byline><p TEIform="p">AS followers of Christ, true servants of God, we have no time to be idle, morose nor
                            unchristian, nor can we pass our time in silly gossip or poisonous slander; neither in
                            slighting nor being slighted, but it behooves us to be awake to the use we make of each
                            moment of our life ; to know but one thing ;the Christ spirit; to have and keep but one aim
                            before our eyes : that justice and equality be established in the earth. Count not our
                            labors, burdens and crosses; think not of ourselves, our ease and comfort, but have our
                            faces set like a flint heavenward, toward the sun of everlasting righteousness. Neither
                            consider whether or not we derive any benefit or reward for our labor, immediately, for the
                            reward will be with us. There are two powers at work in this world of ours. One is like unto
                            a man who came into the possession of a fertile valley and wooded hillside and forthwith he
                            begins to cut down the inhabitants of the foi'ests and woods , and sells them, thinking in
                            his mind, that he will have profit enough as long as he liveth. After all the trees are cut
                            down, the rains of the summer and the snows of the winter find no more impediment to check
                            their course and absorb their moisture and they wash the hillsides bare and carry off the
                            fertile soil of the valley within their course. Time passes, a few years roll by and they
                            find the hillsides barren and naked, the valley dry and sterile ; desolation is written on
                            the face of the plane, desolation is echoed back from the mountains. The other power is like
                            unto a man who comes into this same valley and resolves to make the wilderness blossom like
                            a rose. He, too, engages in hard work ; for every tree that the first man spnt down the
                            valley he sends one up the hill, for each tree that has been rooted up, he planteth one. He
                            never grows weary in his up-hill work, spending all his means, strength and all the days of
                            his life. A shrewd man passes by saying : "He is a fool." But time passes ; a few years roll
                            by and they find the hill-side clothed with verdure and shade, the valley blooming in the
                            pride of its gardens and fields. Prosperity is written on the face of the valley, prosperity
                            is echoed back from the mountains. In which of these two powers are we moving? In the one
                            which looks at immediate profit and gain and after all labor, anxiety and planning leaves
                            but a curse to posterity ? or in the one that cares naught for immediate reward and after
                            all labor, anxiety and planning leaves a blessing to posterity and generations after ? Which
                            work are you engaged in, brother, pray, which is your choice, sister? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memory is the urn..." TEIform="index"/>Memory is the urn...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Memory is the urn that holds the ashes of experience.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. S.</byline></div2><pb n="108" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Right living" TEIform="index"/>RIGHT LIVING. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">IN a Christian church, it would seem that the principle of righteousness should stand
                            foremost, and that the general influence of the body of the church should stimulate a
                            pleasant action in that direction. The Teacher was very emphatic in his remarks on this
                            subject, and gave it a conspicuous place in all his lessons of instruction. The most simple
                            and satisfactory definition of this talismanic word is, right living, and this includes
                            right thinking, right speaking and right acting. Those who attempt to mystify the word as
                            something almost unattainable in the ordinary course of life, that may or may not be
                            received by imputation according to theological rules, do a great harm to the upward
                            progress of the Christian world. The whole journey of life is a wonderful lesson, and this
                            may include , experiences of still more wonderful variations. The advantages or
                            disadvantages that may come through birth, through education and through association, will
                            tell upon the mind with the most powerful effect as the pilgrim moves along from degree to
                            degree, over the King's highway. Moses was very decided in saying that these conditions of
                            the mind and body would be visited upon the children down to the third and fourth
                            generation. In this example of retribution we might well say that "the way of the
                            transgressor is hard," as his unrighteousness after enforcing a severe penalty upon the
                            violator of God's law, inflicts a corresponding penalty upon others through several
                            generations. The same law of God holds good even to the present time and the errors of one
                            generation, or family, or church are seriously visited upon those that are to come forward
                            on the stage of action at a much later date. A clearer insight into the workings of this
                            peculiar law might be the means of saving many persons from suffering, from disease and even
                            from death. Sins of every degree and of every shade are found to be more or less actively
                            developing in the minds of those who neglect the opportunities of doing good. Jesus did not
                            hesitate to credit the Scribes and Pharisees with the works of righteousness, and he
                            evidently found many among them who were honorable and honest men,faithful in the
                            performance of every obligation, and in this they were sure of their reward as was promised
                            to the righteous man. But they were not Christians and had not accepted the more advanced
                            light. "Learn of me," said the divine Teacher, and then, "except your righteousness shall
                            exceed the righteousness of the Scribes and Pharisees ye shall in no wise enter into the
                            kingdom of heaven." As the light of God <pb n="109" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 10l increases
                            the light in man must increase in corresponding ratio. This must continue, whatever the
                            length of time may be, till that crucial test has been reached "when the prince of this
                            world cometh and hath nothing in me," as said Jesus. In this arises a demand for spiritual
                            inspection. Unrighteousness can not lead to God, ncr protect the soul in the light. Every
                            deviation from a right course must culminate in a corresponding state of darkness. This is
                            as unchnnging as is the scripture testimony through the inspiration of the
                            apostle,"Whatsoever a man soweth, that shall he also reap." In his reaping his reward for
                            ill doing, he may force many others to suffer' innocently through his transgression. He has
                            sown to the wind and is now reaping the whirlwind. As this law so thoroughly follows
                            individuals and inflicts upon them the penalty of their transgressions, it also follows as
                            directly the lives of a family or a church or a community, and they suffer from every
                            violation of right, in exact proportion to the transgression and in accordance with the law
                            which also might read with equal propriety,Whatsoever a community soweth that also shall it
                            reap. If we are not reaping the fruits of an active Christian righteousness, then there is
                            great need of a more careful investigation that we may discover the source of our
                            declension. O.ir hope of salvation for either soul or body must be in a life that is
                            vitalized with living truth. Righteousness must be laid to the plummet with the same
                            exactness as it was by our divine Teacher, and as thoroughly as it was by Mother Ann Lee and
                            the Elders. Our prosperity can only be revived by rraking tiie gospel work of the first
                            importance. "Seek first the Kingdom of God and its righteousness,"and when this begins to
                            stand first in our thoughts and words and in our whole life, then will spring up a spiritual
                            prosperity filled with life from God. "For the Lord shall comfort Zion, he will comfort all
                            her waste places, and he will make her wilderness like Eden, and her desert like the garden
                            of the Lord; joy and gladness shall be found therein ; and the voice of thanksgiving and
                            melody. Therefore the redeemed of the Lord shall return, and come with singing to Zion, and
                            everlasting joy shall be upon their heads, they shall obtain gladness and joy, and sorrow
                            and mourning shall flee away." Isaiah, Ji., 3, 11. A faithful continuance in well-doing will
                            insure for us the prosperity of everything over which we may exercise a care. "God is no
                            respector of persons." The righteous man will receive the righteous man's reward.</p></div2><pb n="110" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Courage" TEIform="index"/>COURAGE.</head><p TEIform="p">"Ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make you free."John, viii., 32. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y. 1. We see it! oh we see it! The dawning red and gold, The promise of the 2. We see it! oh
                            we see it! The gates of sunlight ope, And morning writes with altar flame that coming clays
                            enfold,Tho' throbbing darkness circles the rainbow tints new messages of hope, Wide floats
                            the snowy banner for tempest's mighty form, Tho light of Revelation will dissipate the
                            storm, all the earth unfurled,Truth lifts her standard heavenward that will redeem the
                            world. We see it! oh we see it! As harbingers of light, We lift our voices to proclaim, That
                            God will speed the right.</p></div2><pb n="111" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MAY, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society op1 Believp;rs" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Okdek and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Meb, Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year,
                            postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. March. Thermometer. Itain. Snow. 1894. 39 20 1 in. 5
                                in. 1895. 24.87 % " 19 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 52 above 0 Lowest " " " " 6 " "
                                Number of rainy days " " 2 " " snowy " " " 8 " " clear " " " 12 " " cloudy " " " 9 C. G.
                                Reed. Center Family. April, 1895. The April number of The Manifesto reached us this
                                evening, well filled with choice reading matter from the various contributors in our
                                sister Societies. It does us good to see so many able and busy brains working to help
                                the cause nearest to our hearts. I am sorry we can not report an ingathering to our Zion
                                home; those who abide the work are loyal and what are numbers compared to invincible
                                integrity? The idea comes that with the starting of a new colony some may be led to
                                inquire what it means. If there be vitality enough in the body to send out missionaries
                                the Church is not dead and while there is life there is hope; we live not only for
                                ourselves but for mankind; our mission is to preach the gospel to the ends of the earth.
                                We are or used to be called the United Society of Believers; I think could we make that
                                title a little more or a good deal more practical it would redound to our glory. Spring
                                time has come again, the harbinger of another busy season. We are making preparations
                                for another winter, by storing fire wood. We hear encouraging news from the Brethren in
                                Florida. May the Lord bless and prosper the good work being done in that far away land
                                of promise. I have been thinking about the Bible story concerning the children of
                                Israel, how before entering the Promised Land, the Leaders of the people sent out twelve
                                spies to view the land they were to inherit, and only two of that number brought back a
                                goodly report, bearing with them the fruits of the land; great clusters of grapes. So
                                much for the story, whether true or false, and it serves to illustrate human nature. We
                                hear many conflicting stories of the sunny south and out of the drift we sometimes see a
                                gem of real worth. Timothy Raynon. North Family. April, 1895. Home Notes are not
                                necessarily a rehearsal of external occurrences, while things of much greater importance
                                seem to present themselvesnamely, our mental and spiritual status. "The life is more
                                than meat and the body is more than raiment." True goodness never contracts the mind and
                                soul, but ever tends to broaden thought and action. They whose lives are wholly absorbed
                                in doing good are, as TERMS. <pb n="112" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 112 THE MANIFESTO. a happy result
                                saved from evil, having risen above it. He who "maketh his sun to rise on the evil and
                                the good and sendetli rain on the just and on the unjust" would not have us an exclusive
                                people. Let us not hide our light under a bushel and think we shall be benefited thereby
                                or we shall find ourselves narrower than those we look upon as belonging to the lower
                                grade of society. Let us aim to act in accordance with the principles we profess to
                                embody in our lives; aim to advance wisely while so doing, not permit our exalted
                                position to become lowered, or our sacred principles to become desecrated by those who
                                would for selfish and pernicious purposes use our name, or caricature us to our
                                detriment. The Christ spirit which has been made manifest through many personalities as
                                far back in history as we have any record, is as fully alive as ever, and is inspiring
                                the hearts and lives of many to-day. The pessimist, if he will, may enjoy his own dark
                                forebodings; but the optimist, God's own instrument for good, hears amidst the clamor of
                                mental distraction, a voice, telling of better things in the near future) and sees
                                through the smoke of false ideas' grand and ennobling thoughts finding birth all around
                                him. One of the many encouraging signs which we particularly notice is, that minds on
                                the higher strata of life are deeply interested to know more of a true Christian life
                                and to seek more ardently to investigate the principles that govern our Church. This
                                gives opportunity for the distribution of pamphlets and tracts treating upon various
                                subjects pertaining to our faith. Last year we spent over two hundred dollars for
                                missionary purposes, and we look upon it as money well spent. Our good Sister Ann
                                Offord, who has for more than twenty years filled the office of Deaconess, resigns on
                                account of physical indisposition. She is at present, with Sister Louisa Bell,
                                sojourning with kind and loving friends at Enfield, Conn. To heal the soul is one thing,
                                to heal the body is quite another; they both belong together and together they are
                                destined to rise out of old into new conditions. This all important law of healing which
                                Jesus and Mother Ann recognized and practiced upon the people in their time, is working
                                like leaven among a certain class and will be made more manifest as minds are prepared
                                to receive it. Sister Martha J. Anderson resigns Imposition as assistant Eldress and
                                fills the vacancy in the Order of Deaconesses. Sister Sarah Jane Burger is called to the
                                Eldership. We rely upon a spiritual gift and trust all is wisely done. We shall soon
                                plough and plant and believe that God will give the increase. Health of family generally
                                good; having a grip on hygiene, La Gripp finds us fully equipped against him. Love and
                                good-will to our dear friends everywhere. Grace S. Bowers.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1895. "Home sweet home, there is no place like home" with the virtuous and true.
                                How many different homes Believers represent, and yet, there is a spirit of union and
                                love existing among the members of each Society, that unites them in the bonds of the
                                gospel, "for we are members one of another." How blessed it is to feel that we are under
                                the care of One "who doeth all things well." We delight to think on God's promises to
                                those who obey Him. Let us cling to Him who is our refuge and strength, and by the cross
                                make our lives full of brightness and joy and an honor and glory to Him who has enabled
                                us to be heirs to a kingdom that is eternal in the heavens. Love lightens labor, and as
                                we help others, a well-spring of joy and happiness springs up to cheer and encourage,
                                even though our burdens seem heavy. To admire a virtuous life, yet not live it, is sad.
                                Steady growth in the right direction is the growth that tells. ******* <pb n="113" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 113 Buying seed requires greater confidence in the
                                integrity of the seller than any other article of merchandise. 'Chicago has twenty-five
                                buildings that are more than twelve stories high." The whole basis of winter laying hens
                                may be summed up as follows: supply the hens in winter with what they can pick up during
                                summer months. A hen at large, supplies herself with grit in the shape of sharp flinty
                                substance. It is proper care and food that hastens early laying. Hens should have all
                                the milk they can readily drink; no kind of ood is better adapted to egg production.
                                Daniel Orcutt. South Family. April, 1895. Home Notes are again in demand, and the time
                                seems unusually short since the last issue. The return of spring, with its mud and
                                almost impassable roads, is here. We have but little rain, although April is the month
                                for frequent showers, and the cold winds of March have not disappeared, still
                                preparations for gardening are being made. The tomatoes started in boxes are doing well
                                and will be in readiness for transplanting when the time arrives. The bluebirds and
                                robins have come and receive a welcome greeting as we love to hear their musical voices.
                                The past week the fruit trees have received the second application of the spraying
                                apparatus which will prevent the blight that would otherwise spoil the fruit. Some seven
                                hundred trees of different varieties are very soon to be set out, also a new strawberry
                                bed. This is the time of year to find plenty of occupation both in the house and out.
                                Housecleaning is progressing in our home, removing all objectionable objects which have
                                accumulated through a long cold winter. When duties are well performed in their season,
                                peace and rest will follow. A comparatively good degree of health is enjoyed in our
                                family at present, and is the cause of deep thankfulness to the giver of every good and
                                perfect gift. We had a short though pleasant visit the past week with two Sisters from
                                the North family at Mt. Lebanon. These interviews help to strengthen the bond of union
                                between the Societies and so are very profitable. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1895. With the beautiful month of May just dawning, we are glad to greet the-
                                readers of The Manifesto with the cheery salutation, "God bless you all;" while we
                                chronicle the good news of general good health and prosperity. The bleak winds of winter
                                have dealt fairly with us, having made no inroads on our physical organizations causing
                                lingering illness, which so wrecks human happiness. On March 22nd Br. Simeon Childs took
                                his transition to the Celestial City. "Where kinilreil ami .-u;: niians are joyful To
                                wi.len the spiritual boni." Sixty-two years of his life were devoted to the work of
                                regeneration, and no other man more effectually won the palm of victory over self and
                                sin. It may well be said that those loved him most who knew him best. He needs no
                                monument of honor but the one already erected in the hearts of his home relations.
                                Gospel kindred, as one by one our friends ascend, what are we doing to fill the
                                vacancies made? We are in the midst of mr sugar liarvest having tapped 1800 tries. As
                                compared with last season we are having rather a late spring, but acting upon the advice
                                of a very wise philosopher who declared it was always best to let the weather take its
                                course, we are waiting the arrival of summer when we shall exchange the snow shovel for
                                the hoe and rake and toil for those things which though perishable are indispensable to
                                all alike while inhabiting this mundane sphere. On the evening of April 2nd twenty-five
                                members of the Enfield Christian Endeavor <pb n="114" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 114 THE MANIFESTO. 
                                society, spent over two hours at our sugar-camp, enjoying its fruits and in singing
                                hymns and conversing upon profitable subjrcs. As is well known, they are a growing
                                society. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1895. March has gone. With us it was a cold disagreeable month, and on leaving
                                roared like a lion. It came in like a lamb but the lamb was soon frozen. Now April comes
                                with its sunshine and showers, making muddy roads and walks. Soon the waters of the lake
                                will yield to the sun's hot rays and come forth sparkling as brightly as ever. These are
                                fine days for the maple trees which are giving us an abundant harvest. It is a pleasure
                                to the young people to be out early, these bright mornings, gathering the sap which is
                                brought to the evaporator in barrels. Our dearly loved Eldress Lizzie Noyes oversees the
                                whole business. The hum of the wood-saw has been heard for the past fortnight. That job
                                is over now. Our portable engine has done its part of the work very faithfully. The
                                banks of the mill pond are piled with logs waiting to be sawed into lumber for the
                                Lewiston market. Many a noble tree lies there whose beauty has been destroyed by the
                                woodman's ax. We manage to get along from year to year by united and consecrated
                                efforts, and have not yet thought of migrating to Florida, but Believers can not be
                                separated in spirit, though their homes may be far apart. Ada S. dimmings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1895. Beloved Elder Henry:I always read The Manifesto with great interest and am
                                glad we have this exponent of our faith and of the glorious salvation from sin we have
                                found in obedience to the teachings of Christ. I am sure all who have tasted of the joys
                                of the world to come and realized the satisfaction of a selfish life laid down to take
                                up the burden of the Lord, would willingly proclaim to the whole world that "now is come
                                salvation and the kingdom of our God." Of the many children for whom we care, it seems
                                that many are led to love the life of Christ, but when the test is applied, "Except a
                                man forsake all that he hath he can not be my disciple," many prove moral cowards and
                                are slaves to the passions which rule the heart of the natural man. Yet, how many are
                                thankful they were educated with the Shakers and when stricken with poverty or death,
                                their first thought is that their children be placed with the Shakers to receive a like
                                education. All we can do is to offer to those who come among us, the gospel of love and
                                purity in all its attractiveness, and some good fish will remain while the others go
                                back into the sea from whence they came. May the Lord bless and unite his people and
                                send faithful workers into his vineyard. Lucinda M. Reynolds.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. April, 1895. As the cold weather has abated and the warm sun is spreading
                                its rays over our beautiful White Water valley, I thought a few home items might be of
                                interest to our Gospel friends, both east and west. We are at the present time, planting
                                our potatoes. Expect to plant about five acres. The cold weather has not injured our
                                fruit crops as badly as we expected. I presume if we have no more heavy frosts, we may
                                be blest with some fruit, which has been a failure for the past three years. Our good
                                Sisters are very busy at our home cleaning house. The Bible teach- <pb n="115" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. llo es, "Cleanliness is next to Godliness," and we believe it. What a
                                blessing it is to the Brethren that they have kind and willing Sisters ever ready to
                                beautify our gospel home and we know from past experience, that they are glad that there
                                are good and faithful Brethren to help as this season of renovating and repairing comes
                                round. Brother Charles Dixon, our herdsman is very active with the whitewash brush, and
                                I presume when he gets through, we will hardly know our old place. May God bless every
                                soul who is willing to help beautify and build up our gospel homes, both temporally and
                                spiritually. On the 23rd of March we opened a pit of potatoes and found enough new ones
                                there for a dinner for fifteen gi'own persons. I do not know whether our Florida
                                Brethren can excel this or not. We of White Water extend our prayers and love to our
                                gospel friends in Florida. Recently, I had the privilege of visiting at Union Village
                                and enjoyed it very much. La Fayette Parker.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. April, 1895. While pursuing the even tenor of our way, we have with us the
                                blessings of God and it is of very great importance to the mind as we view life from an
                                external point of view. "The Kingdom of heaven is within you." There should be laid the
                                foundation on which to build the superstructure in which shall be the dwellingplace of
                                that spiritualized being who has attained the mastery over the rudimentary life; not
                                through the "conflict with carnal weapons attaining power over fellow mortals and
                                compelling States and Empires to do homage to their will. Spring is very backward
                                comparing it with past seasons. At present writing there are large snow-drifts to be
                                found in the woods though the cleared land is generally free. March showed very little
                                indications of balmy spring, but was typical of the month in maintaining boisterous
                                weather. As far as health is concerned there has been a favorable state with the
                                exception of colds and a few cases of the grip. By the time of the appearance of these
                                Notes your humble correspondent will be busily engaged in the garden. We feel thankful
                                for the privilege to commune with gospel Brethren and Sisters either thivugh The
                                Manifesto or in daily communion. They quicken the spirit and make one feel that "Life is
                                more than meat and the body than raiment." Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">April, 1895. The long tedious winter has finally left us, after holding us in its icy
                                embrace till the last of the month. Not a spring note was heard during the month, save
                                on one sunny day a bluebird uttered one feeble song, and then disappeared not to come
                                again till it could hail tl.-e month of showers. The farmers have the wo;id securely
                                housed, and are now busily engaged making preparations for seed time. It has been
                                arranged for our South family to remove from their present home to live in our Church
                                family. The removal takes place about the 18th of April. 'ihey will be heartily
                                welcomed. In concentrating our forces ti-ere is strength. Our aged ones have endured the
                                severity of the season remarkably well and all have been free irom illness, with tLe
                                exception of an epidemic of colds which soon left us. Our centenarian, Br. Ezra Newton
                                is very feeble and needs constant care. He has been growing more feeble since the
                                celebration of his one hundredth birthday. In these troublous times we have much cause
                                to offer oblations of praise to the Father of mercy and justice. By living by the
                                revelation of his spirit we have a peace that the world can not give neither can it take
                                it away. Marcia M. Mallard.</p></div3></div2><pb n="116" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look upward" TEIform="index"/>LOOK UPWARD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>By Ada S. Cummings.</byline><p TEIform="p">Look upward, is the call to thee, When thou art sore oppressed; 'Tis from above, thou'lt find
                            a balm Which calms the troubled breast. Look upward, O thou biuised tiowers! The storm hath
                            ceased, awhile, The sun is shining on thy bower Lift up thy head and smile. Look upward,
                            send thy fragrance forth To cheer some wearier heart. Though thou art bruised, arise again,
                            And bid thy grief depart. Remember that thy petals pure Though crushed upon the ground, Can
                            shed abroad a perfume rare In sweetness all around. Look upward, then for joys will be Along
                            thy journey here; It is God's hand that's leading thee, Therefore thou need'st not fear.
                            Then look aloft, whate'er betide, Though rough may be the way, If thou would'st reach the
                            brighter side Above, 'tis always day. Look upward: there is still a work For each and all to
                            do, Thy faith will show the silver cloud, The sun is shining through. What tho' thy journey
                            seemeth long! Thy goal seems yet afar; "Look upward," still should be thy song Thy bright
                            and guiding star. Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spring cleaning" TEIform="index"/>SPRING CLEANING.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Genevieve DeGraw.] Yes clean your house and clean your shed And clean your barn in every part; But
                                    brush the cobwebs from your head And sweep the snow-banks from your heart Just when
                                    spring cleaning comes around Bring forth the duster and the broom, But rake your
                                    fogy notions down And sweep your dusty soul of gloom. Sweep old ideas out with the
                                    dust And dress your soul in newer style, Scrape from your mind its worn-out crust
                                    And dump it in the rubbish pile. Sweep out the hates that burn and smart Bring in
                                    new loves serene and pure, Around the hearth-stone of the heart Place modern styles
                                    of furniture. Clean out your moral cubby-holes, Sweep out the dirt, scrape off the
                                    scum; 'Tis cleaning time for healthy souls Get up and dust! The spring has come!
                                    Clean out the corners of the brain, Bear down with scrubbing brush and soap, And
                                    dump old Fear into the rain, And dust a cozy chair for Hope. Clean out the brain's
                                    deep rubbish hole, Soak ev'ry cranny great and small, And in the front room of the
                                    soul Hang prettier pictures on the wall. Scrub up the windows of the mind, Clean up
                                    and let the spring begin; Spring open wide, the dusty blind And let the April
                                    sunshine in. Plant flowers in the soul's front yard, Set out new shade and blossom
                                    trees, And let the soil once frozen hard Sprout crocuses of new ideas. Yes, clean
                                    your house and clean your shed And clean your barn in every part; But brush the
                                    cobwebs from your head And sweep the snow-banks from your [heart. No need to go to
                                    Florida To keep your house in good repair; No need to leave a sunny home To breathe
                                    the southern sultry air. The Northern climate is the best, Most healthful too for
                                    soul and mind. Its fruits,none better can be found For all the ills of human kind.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The missionaries do not always have the daintiest menu..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The missionaries do not always have the daintiest menu...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The missionaries do not always have the daintiest menu as they sit down to dine.
                                    Missionary Walker describing his bill of fare in Central Africa says he occasionally
                                    has white ants as a delicacy, and likes <pb n="117" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 117
                                    them very much, though it takes some time to get over the feeling of repugnance
                                    which ants at first excite as an article of diet. There is nothing like getting used
                                    to things. Dr. Junker found that, after a while, he could eat fried ants with as
                                    much relish as any of the natives, and the explorers on the Congo have not objected
                                    to an occasional hippopotamus steak when stowed goat and boiled chicken have failed
                                    to give sufficient variety to the canned meat of civilization. An orchid collector
                                    who has enriched the hot-houses of Erastus Corning and other horticulturists, avers
                                    that stewed monkey isn't so very bad, at least on the upper Amazon. One dish
                                    however, was set before an eminent explorer awhile ago, that was too much for him,
                                    and he unconditionally surrendered. It was De Brazza, and he sat down very hungry
                                    one day to eat a native dinner on the banks of the Ogowe. He thought he was eating
                                    fish and a very palatable dish it seemed, until he was told by the delighted lady
                                    cook whom he was complimenting, that it was snake. The information ruined his
                                    appetite. The missionary by the way, has abundant cause for thanksgiving, and no
                                    doubt has his Thanksgiving dinner. But what foreign missionary dines off roast
                                    turkey? Their number can be written by a 0.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian at Work" TEIform="index"/>The Christian at Work.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hicks, Willie C." TEIform="persName"/>By Willie C. Hicks.</byline><p TEIform="p">(12yrs. old.) 1. Do good for evil. When any one kicks you do not kick him, but do good to him
                            for evil. 2. You know that if you help a sinner, you are laying up treasures in heaven; help
                            a sinner as much as you can. 3. Do not be afraid of a sinner but take him and talk kindly to
                            him and be done with him. 4. Be loving to every one, do not say "go away" or "leave me
                            alone," that is not "brotherly love." 5. The Lord is with you wherever you go, but if you do
                            not keep his commandments you will not enter the kingdom of heaven. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morgan, Henrietta" TEIform="persName"/>Henrietta Morgan.</byline><p TEIform="p">Consecration, precious virtue, Over all take full control; Not one talent for reserving,
                            Sacrifice to God the whole. Every thought, word and action, Consecrate anew each day; Reward
                            will crown the effort, And the right will bear sway: Teach us then, oh Consecration, In thy
                            service to remain; Over every wrong we'll triumph, Never to retract again. West Pitt afield,
                            Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What was his creed?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT WAS HIS CREED?</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He left a load of anthracite In front of a poor woman's door, When the deep snow,
                                    frozen and white, Wrapped street and square, mountain and moor. That was his deed;
                                    He did it well; "What was his creed?" I cannot tell. Blessed "in his basket and in
                                    his store," In sitting down and rising up; When more he got he gave the more,
                                    Withholding not the crust and cup. He took the lead In each good task. "What was his
                                    creed?" I did not ask. His charity was like the snow Soft, light and silent in its
                                    fall! Not like the noisy winds that blow From shivering trees the leaves; a pall For
                                    flowers and weed, Drooping below. <pb n="118" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 118 THE MANIFESTO. "What
                                    was his creed?" The poor may know. He had great faith in loaves of bread For hungry
                                    people, young and old, And hope inspired, kind words he said To those he sheltered
                                    from the cold. For we must feed As well as pray. "What was his creed?" I can not
                                    say. In words he did not put his trust; His faith in words he never writ; He loved
                                    to share his cup and crust With all mankind who needed it. In time of need A friend
                                    was he. "What was his creed?" He told not me. He put his trust in Heaven, and he
                                    Worked well with hand and head; And what he gave in charity Sweetened his sleep and
                                    daily bread. Let us take heed, For life is brief. "What was his creed?" "What his
                                    belief?"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>�Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright side" TEIform="index"/>THE BRIGHT SIDE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Lookin' on the bright side That's the way to go; All the time the right side,
                                    Summer time or snow! Clouds is got a light side All the bells will chime! Lookin' on
                                    the bright side Gits there every time! W'hen the weather's hazy Light the lamps an'
                                    still Think you see a daisy Hear a whippoorwill! When you're out o' money, Smile an'
                                    take your ease! Think about the honey That's a-comin, with the bees!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Atlanta Constitution" TEIform="index"/>Atlanta Constitution.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Youth;--'Blessed are the meek'..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Youth;--'Blessed are the meek'...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, April 1895" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct. April,
                            1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Youth;"Blessed are the meek." Meekness is one of the characteristics o God's people. You
                            are exhorted by precept and example to have a submissive, meek and resigned spirit. How much
                            happier you might be if you would learn more Christian patience, and receive with meekness
                            and humility all chastening necessary for your purification as coming from your heavenly
                            Father for your eternal good. Jesus was patient, pure, submissive and meek. Walk in his
                            footsteps. Humility and meekness are beautiful ornaments of refinement and culture; it is a
                            mistaken idea of refinement or a false culture that ignores either. One of the fruits of the
                            Spirt is meekness, and you are encouraged to walk in the heavenly pathway "with all
                            lowliness and meekness" and to "put on mercy, kindness, humbleness of mind, and to follow
                            after righteousness, love and patience." You can not be too humble and meek. Clothe your
                            soul with humility. Those who are humble are like Jesus, in that respect. Increase in every
                            virtue that will fit you for heaven. Purity is a lovely ornament and very much you need it.
                            Scorn improper conduct. Be guided by truth and keep clean within. "Blest are they who seek
                            in their youth, With spirit meek the way of truth."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">the writers of The Manifesto can not all think alike, any more than they can all look alike,
                            they may be consulted in regard to their special views, on the subjects of which they write.
                            One thinks that every thing is spirit and that all tangible things are only a coarser
                            quality of spirit. Another thinks that matter stands first and every thing is matter, and
                            that the invisible things of God, and even God himself is matter, only a little more
                            refined. This is called the one substance theory. As <pb n="119" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            119 One person thinks he lives on the outside of the earth, another thinks the earth is
                            hollow and he lives on the inside, while a third, thinks the earth a plane surface and we
                            can neither go into it nor around it. So long as all this makes ignorance to be bliss, it is
                            folly to be wise. who write for "Home Notes" should not forget the order of that department,
                            and write an essay on either religion or domestic duties. An article of 350 words will do
                            quite well. Write your article on sheets of NOTE SIZE.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progressive thought" TEIform="index"/>Progressive Thought
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Progressive Thought is published in Olathe Kansas "in the interest of Progress and
                                Humanity." E. Z. Ernst, Editor of Progressive Thought is an earnest advocate for
                                reformatory measures, in the interest of the workingman. It believes that a better day
                                is dawning nnd urges its readers "not to be blind to their own interests." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal
                                of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal
                                of Hygeio-Therapy Edited by Dr. T. V. Gifford is a welcome messenger. Lessons in life
                                are among the most valuable, and when they are so clearly presented to the reader, most
                                certainly should they be appreciated. Most of us who have seen one half of the journey
                                of life could tell a wonderful story of our experience in the "Wilderness of pills and
                                powders." This subject can never have too much light thrown upon it. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our animal friends" TEIform="index"/>Our Animal Friends
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Our Animal Friends
                                is a beautiful periodical sent out by the "American Society for the Prevention of
                                Cruelty to Animals." This great kindness that is extended to the animal creation is a
                                strong evidence of the upward march of the human race. "Blessed are the merciful," was
                                not spoken in vain, and the merciful man rests assured that in his care over these
                                animal friends he is approved of God. This beautiful work is published each month at 10
                                East 22nd St., New York City, at $1.00 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fire brand" TEIform="index"/>The Fire Brand
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Fire Brand is from Shenandoah, Iowa.
                                C. S. Hanley, Editor. It is a religious journal and admits no advertisements to its
                                columns The Editor says, "The firm name is God, the Father, Son and Holy Ghost. We are
                                responsible to God for what we put in this paper, on "which our readers are to feed
                                their never dying souls." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Altruist" TEIform="index"/>The Altruist
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Altruist is published in St. Louis, Mo, and is the
                                exponent of the principles held by the Society. Alcander Longley is the Editor and also
                                the President of the organization. It allows equal rights and privileges to all its
                                members and makes no interference with the marriage relations, nox- with religious or
                                political opinions. We hope Br. Longley will soon be able to register the onehumlred men
                                and women that he wishes to enter his Community. Every such effort is doing good in the
                                world and we wish for it great success. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humane journal" TEIform="index"/>The Humane Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Humane Journal is published in Chicago, 111,
                                by Albeit W. Landon. The mission of the Journal is to promulgate the law of kindness and
                                certainly that mission must be from God. Literature of an elevated order like that found
                                in the Humane Journal, must have a beneiicial and moulding influence on all who are
                                privileged to read it. The paper is beautifully illustrate:! anl will be sent to any
                                address for $1.00 a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Denunciation" TEIform="index"/>DENUNCIATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cotton, Walter" TEIform="persName"/>By Rev. Walter Cotton.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Ann Cumings.] Denunciation never yet protected the innocent, confirmed the wavering, or recovered the
                            fallen. That spirit of ferocity which breaks the bruised reed, partakes more of relentless
                            pride than virtuous disapprobation. Many sever themselves from all sympathy with the erring,
                            from the mistaken apprehension that the wider the chasm, the more advantageous the light in
                            which they will appear. The chasm which seems so wide to them, narrows to a faint line in
                            the Eye of Omniscience. Forgiveness is our duty; not that forgiveness which scorns and
                            forsakes the object on which it is bestowed, but which seeks to reclaim the erring, and
                            re-instate the fallen in merited confidence and esteem. When repentant guilt trembled and
                            blushed in the presence of Him whose divine example is our guide, no frown darkened his
                            brow, no malediction fell from his lips; his absolving injunction was, "Go and sin no more."
                            The brightest stars are they which have emerged from a horizon of darkness. Those</p></div2><pb n="120" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health lor April leads with a character study
                                of the Hon. Thomas C. Platt, the eminent political manager. It is from a personal
                                examination by the editor, Dr. Beall, and is commendable for its cool impartiality and
                                close analysis. Two portraits are given which clearly illustrate the qualities
                                described. "Education for Every Day," by Caroline BLeRow, -will be appreciated by
                                practical people; and "Temperament and Faculty," by W. P. Underwood, will interest
                                students of Phrenology. "My&amp;terie^ of To-day," by Anna Olcott Commelin is a
                                story of experience in occultism. Dr. H. S. Drayton contributes a valuable paper on the
                                scientific standing ofGall and SpurzIieim. Mrs. Wells gives a fine sketch of William
                                Walton, with illustrated extracts from his writings on the English poets, eomparingheads
                                with their literary productions. Professor Sizer presents a galaxy of "young hopefuls"
                                in the Child Culture Department, with numerous handsome illustrations of special value
                                to parents. Under Science of Health are a number of excellent articles on Magnetism,
                                Elements of Blood, and other hygienic questions of importance. The Editor has an
                                illustrated physiognomical study of the mouths of Archbishop Satolli and Mary Anderson,
                                and an earnest, eloquent protest against the whipping post in the light of phrenological
                                philosophy, etc., etc. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Current events" TEIform="index"/>Current Events
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Current Events, the new magazine printed at Rockville, Conn.,
                                gives a complete review of the important news of the world every month, with timely
                                illustrations, for 30 cents a year. It tells of the progress of the world in an
                                accurate, interesting way, and it is therefore used by many teachers as a supplementary
                                reader for school use. The publishers send sample copies free on receipt of postal. A
                                feature of the April number is an up-to-date review of the China-.]apan war. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work of Albert Lynch" TEIform="index"/>THE WORK OF
                                ALBERT LYNCH
                            </head><p TEIform="p">THE WORK OF
                                ALBERT LYNCH. A lbert Lynch, whose work is becoming so much more generally known to
                                Americans through his drawings in Scribner's Magazine and his cover designs for The
                                Ladies' Home Journal is Peruvian by birth, but of English parentage. He is only
                                thirty-three years of age, and of extremely retiring disposition. He is unmarried and
                                lives in Paris. The young artist commands the highest prices for his work, his smallest
                                water-color paintings read ily selling for $600 to $900 each. In 1893 he received the
                                Salon's first prize for his beautiful panel of "Spring," showing a single figure. This
                                picture won the admiration of the French art critics and the public to such an unusual
                                degree that the painting was sold for a fabulous sum to a private Paris buyer. Recently
                                The Ladies' Home Journal acquired all publication rights to this painting, and it will
                                serve as one of the cover designs for that magazine. The next issue of the Journal will
                                also have a design by Lynch, portraying his. conception of a woman's ideal costume. A
                                succession of other cover designs by Lynch will follow these two. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of
                                Hygeio-Therapy. April. Contents. Primary Facts for Doctors; How to live Properly;
                                Testimonies against Tobacco; Cancer and Vaccination; The Garden; Phrenology; A Sermon by
                                a Layman: Substitutes for Flesh Moats, etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp; Co.,
                                Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible rhymes and bible lessons" TEIform="index"/>
                                Bible Rhymes and Bible Lessons
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bible Rhymes and Bible Lessons, by Anna Bell, is published by H. L.
                                Hastings, 49 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. This interesting and illustrated little work has
                                for its object the stimulating of the minds of all, old and young, in the more careful
                                study of the Bible. It is a work of some eighty pages, of excellent paper and beautiful
                                type. The largest part is devoted to questions and answers on subjects of special
                                interest to be found in the Scriptures, as"The Books of the Bible." "The Angels." "The
                                Manna." The "Wisdom." "The Food, Clothing and Hair." "The Bible Children." "The Bible
                                Mountains," etc., etc. Sunday Schools and families would find in these carefully
                                prepared lessons a Book of extended information, and one which would on examination be
                                appreciated. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian arbitrator" TEIform="index"/>The Christian Arbitrator
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Christian Arbitrator and Messenger of Peace has entered upon its
                                twenty-fifth year, and removed from Richmond, Indiana, to Philadelphia, Pa. It is a
                                bright monthly, handling the subject of peace and arbitration from a Christian
                                standpoint. A leading article, "War in the Old Testament," by the late London banker,
                                George Gillette, puts a new light upon the subject, and is worthy of study by all
                                pastors and Christian professionals. It has a resume of the peace work being done by the
                                W.C.T.U. and other peace societies, both in America and abroad, and much to interest
                                these workers. Takes great interest in the labor movements and should be read by working
                                men, especially Christian working men. It will be the organ of the Christian Arbitration
                                and Peace Society, and is published at the extremely low price of twenty-five cents per
                                annum, education rather than^rofit being its purpose. 209 Cooper St., Camden, N. J.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Childs, Simeon" TEIform="index"/>Simeon Childs
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Simeon Childs, at Enfield, N. H. Mar. 22, 1895. Age 83 years, 2 mo. and 10 dajs.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains  130 pages ;md has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75  cts;   in boards oO cts.
Address    H. C. Bjuxn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY.
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on fie principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
T-iis should rule the life of the  Individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
(.Established 1S61 )
IS Oldest, Larsesi. ]>.-t,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Be<-Paper in all
America.  32 pngre. $1.00
a ypar. ., Send for Frco Simple.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK F~
,. W. Y0EK & CO., 199 Raudolph St., Chicar        >.,
SHAKERS1
CONCENTRATED
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. IlYDKIODATK OF POTASSA to 12 Bottles.
PREPARED AT
Shaker Willage, Werrimach So., T&. )$.
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
TO THE OFT REPEATED QUESTION,
"What   will   become   of   the
World, if all become Shakers?"
Price, 10 cts.
#     This medicine has proved to be most
fc valuable in the following diseases :      *
t     Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive *
#  Organs; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion; Weak- $
 ness and Sourness of the Stomach; liheu- fc
|; matism ; Salt liheum ; Secondary Syphilis; g
 Functional Disorders of the Liver ; Chronic %
^ Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous *
^ diseases and disorders arising from im- ^
 purities of the blood.    It is also an excel- <*
^      ;   i'emody for the Erysipelas, Asthma, 
| Dropsy,  Dysentery,  and Diarrhoea,   and $
g for the complicated diseases of females, &
p so apt to end in consumption.                    
\, Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful $
 four or live times a day, with or without &
% a little water, which may be increased to ^
$ a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient. %
$ To guard against counterfeits, observe ^
S the signature of the inventor on each 5
 label and on each wrapper.
is an iliusii'jdd! MonHily, now only ">0 cts.
per    year,    dented   to   PHRENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY-   HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOORL B.IF0EM.
Would inm like it co\>y?
Send 5 cts. for Sample  to Prof. Haddock.
Phrenologist,  lok; Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
HUMAN NATURE
American Bee Jonrnal,
T
H
E
A
COMPOUND
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A crea.n of   tartar   baking   powder
H'ghest of  all in   leavening strength.
Latest   United  States   Government
Food Report.
Royal Baking Powder Co.,
106 Wall St., N.  Y.
The Self-Pouring Pot looks like any
other and is made of various materials
and patterns. Its peculiarity is that it
stands all the while in its place on the
tray and is neither lifted nor tipped. The
handle is only to carry it to the table.
How then?
The cover is made so it can slide up
and down a few inches within the body of
the pot, and has on its top a small knob
of non-conducting material, with a small
hole through the center. Take the knob
by the thumb and second finger and lift
the cover, close the small hole with the
forefinger, then press down and the liquor
is forced by pneumatic action through the
spout into the cup. The spout is turned
downward, always pointing to the bottom
of the cup. The instant the fingers relax
their downward pressure on the knob the
flow stops. The pressure regulates the
flow; there is neither slopping nor dripping.        (See "ad." on another page.)
HOW I CAME
TO    BE
A  SHAKER
Price 5 cts.
This is a genuine American Watch.
It is made for service and is the Best low
priced Watch for the rich man or poor
man, or for their sons or for any one who
wants a
Good Time Keeper.
It is a work day as well as a Sunday
watch. It has a patent winding attachment and weighs 4> oz.
It is open face, with heavy,
For $1.50  we will send the Watch, and
also a copy of The Manifesto  for one
year, to any address in the U. S.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury, N. H.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
2 N. Fourth St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>