<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2801" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18980101" TEIform="date">January 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    [Advertizements deleted]
                    <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type=
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. VOL. XXVIII. Prepare ye the way of the Lord, make straight in
                            the desert a highway for our God.."—Isaiah, xl., 3. East Canterbury,N. H., 1898.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
                    [blank page]
                    <pb n="3" id="p5"/>
                    [title of page deleted]
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress of shakerism, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>THE PROGRESS OF SHAKERISM. NO. 1</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Henry C. Blinn</byline><p TEIform="p">IT is now quite universally admitted that the unfoldment of the human mind has been very
                            gradual and yet of continuous growth. The animal man does not change in the twinkling of an
                            eye, from low to high estates. Even the most radical Biblical students who were positive
                            that the days of creation, as recorded in Genesis, were periods of time, of only twenty-four
                            hours each, now admit that the morning and evening which formed the day, may as well have
                            been one thousand, ten thousand or forty thousand years each, as to have been only
                            twenty-four hours. Figuier says,—"The mind recoils dismayed when it undertakes the com-
                            putation of the thousands of years which have elapst since the creation of man." This being
                            the case, even admitting that prehistoric man was made nearly on a level with the brute
                            creation, we wonder that so many thousands of years could have past away, and brought to the
                            race no higher moral standard than is represented in the book of Genesis. That there was a
                            gradual development of the mind, altho it may have been at a snail's pace, is generally
                            conceded, as a writer of the Sacred Book, places man in advance of the animal race and
                            denominates him when standing upright, to be a "son of God." Isolated individuals may have
                            been found no doubt who were equally as far advanced as was the one we call Adam, but the
                            race, as a whole, was very far from being what we should consider, either sons of God or
                            even an ordinary standard for humanity. The historian in illustrating the condition of some
                            orders of society, at that date, says ;—"every imagination of the heart was evil
                            continually." JANUARY <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4 THE MANIFESTO. Such a condition would be hard to
                            conceive, and still more difficult to accept into the mind, even tho we should bring forward
                            the most uncivilized races that exist at the present time. If the development of man before
                            the advent of Adam was twenty thousand or even ten thousand years, and the time from Adam to
                            the present date has been only some six or seven thousand years, then we should readily
                            admit that the advancement of humanity for the last term has been wonderful. But the six
                            thousand years of man's existence may be no more exact than was the minister who said that
                            the three holy children were not in the fiery furnace, but just near enough to be
                            comfortable. The eagle-eyed commentators have found some one hundred and forty opinions of
                            the date of the creation "and that between the varying, extremes there is a difference of
                            three thousand one hundred and ninety-four years; a difference which only applies to the
                            period between the commencement of the world or birth of Adam and the birth of Jesus." A
                            slight acquaintance with the Phrenological chart will perhaps show us how easily the good or
                            bad conditions may predominate in the mind. How the moral and intellectual faculties may
                            rise through many degrees to a higher and better form of humanity, while a departure from
                            right or from goodness will as certainly lead to brutality and to a sensual existence.
                            Having this thought in mind it is not strange that the family of man should have been formed
                            into classes, and one should have been designated as the "sons of God, and the other as the
                            sons of Belial." Then as now it was a matter of discipline that made an honorable state of
                            society or through lack of discipline made those of low conditions, that were a disgrace to
                            humanity. From the days of Adam to the present time; from the first religious and murderous
                            quarrel of the two brothers, and these were sons of God, down through all the races of men,
                            whether savage or civilized, the same contest has been going on, and yet we have this
                            assurance, that the better quality of the human mind has predominated, and the great family
                            of man has moved forward in everything that makes life of more value upon the earth. It has
                            also as steadily moved upward toward a higher ideal of man's duty toward man, and no less
                            toward the kingdom of God, the consummation of our greatest hope. That there should be some
                            nations or tribes that should be savage and sensual, and of a degraded type, is no more
                            strange than that there should be found in some well-ordered families, one or more of the
                            children who become a sorrow and a disgrace to their parents. At the advent of Shakerism, so
                            early as the year 1770, there were wars and rumors of wars. The thirst for conquest and the
                            thirst for gold were quite closely conjoined and aroused all the passions of the mind to do
                            and to dare, even to the utmost cruelty and savagery of their animal natures, and yet many
                            of those most warlike demonstrations were led by men who be<pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 5 lieved in the name of the Prince of Peace and in the advancement of the human
                            race. Four thousand years of selfishness, of wars and of slavery, had made indelible
                            impressions upon the mind. Out of this great body, a few individuals may have been found who
                            gave their lives for the good of humanity as did the man of Galilee. Obscured as this may
                            have been, it sometimes found willing advocates whose testimony was as the sword of the God
                            of Peace. From this Babylonian mass came the first Shakers and the voice of the spirit was
                            the same to them as it was to the primitive Christians,—"Repent, for the kingdom of God is
                            at hand." Shakerism, is by no means an instantaneous conversion. Those who have been
                            traveling many years from right toward wrong, may be as many years in travsling from wrong
                            toward right. It was a wonderful power that could enter into the mind of a selfish man and
                            take him while so filled with the war spirit, with the love of money, with the love of
                            honor, and a great name in the earth, and lead him to love God, as a Heavenly Father, and
                            then to pray for his persecutors. To place men and women in a Christian community, after
                            they had been developing all the variations of self-love for twenty or forty years, was a
                            test of Christianity, that but few have experienced. A fair illustration of the disciples
                            who entered into Christian fellowship, would be to visit the service held by the evangelists
                            of the present day. If the word of God should reach such a class, it would take them as it
                            found them, and it would find them as it found Cain and Abel; as it found the people in the
                            days of Noah; as it found the inhabitants of Sodom, or as Jonah found the people of Nineveh.
                            If the cross prevailed it would take them as St. Paul took them into his church. Did he
                            accept those who pilfered? Indeed, he did. He said to his brethren; "Let him that stole,
                            steal no more." Did he accept the selfish and overbearing? He says, "Wherein thou judgest
                            another, thpu condemnest thyself." Did he accept those who were weak in the faith? "Him that
                            is weak in the faith receive ye," and yet there were some who would put stumbling-blocks in
                            the way of others. They were carnal and indulged in strife. Some of his members were less
                            reputable in their characters than were the sensual Corinthians. This may be quite like the
                            promiscuous gatherings of the men and women of even this year of grace. Paul says the
                            brethren went to law against their own brethren, and the Christian churches of to-day do the
                            same thing. Some were so covetous that they neglected to eat at home, that they might
                            consume the more at the communion table. This is a sad picture of unregenerate man in the
                            early Gentile Christian church, before the advent of the Shakers, and yet it was quite the
                            same when the Shakers formed their communities. (To be continued.)</p></div2><pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science vs. the Christ" TEIform="index"/>SCIENCE v. s. THE CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Maclaughlin, Charles Jay" TEIform="persName"/>Charles Jay Maclaughlin</byline><p TEIform="p">~TT"T~HEN schism crept into the primitive church, causing it to fall, men VV came under the
                            bondage of creed. The original faith and practice of the church of Christ as taught by our
                            Savior and reiterated by his apostles gradually disappeared. The doctrine, "-Work out}7our
                            own salvation with fear and trembling; for it is God which worketh in you both to will and
                            to do of his good pleasure" was set aside. Practically, men were told to allow the
                            individual understanding to decay and listen only to the voice of the priest and prelate.
                            This state of affairs brought with it the dark ages and the notorious corruption of the
                            Roman clergy against which Savanarola hurled his anathemas, Melancthon penned his
                            disquisitions and Luther thundered his denunciations, opening anew the scriptures to
                            individual inquiry. While the Reformation broke the power of Rome it signally failed to lift
                            the people from the bondage of dogma hence orthodoxy has not given forth that light which it
                            claims. In the original gospel there was no dogma, no creed, no system of theology, but a
                            living faith and practice. Martin Luther, however, began the work of individual thought
                            carried forward by such men as Jacob Brehme, Emanuel Swedenborg and the whole host of names
                            which have givtn lustre to the pages of modern literature. But the difference between the
                            work of Brehme, Swedenborg and Ann Lee lies in the fact that their minds were illuminated
                            while others brought forth the inspiration of natural genius. Herein lies the distinction
                            between science aud the Christ. Dante, Schiller, Goethe, Kant, Shakespeare, Mohere,
                            Montague, Rorscean, Carlysle, Browning, Emerson and the rest belong to the realm of natural
                            inquiry properly denominated science (from scire, to know;) but to know a thing from the
                            standpoint of the natural mind is very different from perceiving it by illumination. In the
                            efforts of mankind to break away from creed there have come forth in these latter days with
                            the running to and fro, divers doctrines which while an aid to the development of the
                            natural intellect are no part of that mind which was in Christ Jesus our Lord and which
                            carries with it the only genuine power for soul healing from which all sin, sickness and
                            death emanate. Theosophy, Ethical Culture and the vaiious forms of mental science belong to
                            this class. They are neither substitutes for the Christ nor effective panaceas for the ills
                            of humanity. All things springing from the natural mind today are tainted with the spirit of
                            the prince of this world. Jesus said to the Pharisees; "Ye are of this world; I am not of
                            this world.'* This doctrine of the Christ is just as true to-day and ever must be. We have
                            reacht a time when the old serpent through the natural powers of man will be able to
                            counterfeit everything from Heaven but the saving of the soul. It will be remembered that
                            Moses threw down his rod and it became a serpent; the <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 7
                            Egyptian magicians then threw down their rods and they also became serpents but Moses took
                            up his rod again as a rod while the rods of the magicians remained serpents. Pantheism of
                            which all these new doctrines are a part, teaches, but has never demonstrated the
                            proposition that the human mind is without limitation in the possibility of its
                            achievements. Aristotle and Plato, Cuvier, Kant, Shakespeare, Darwin, Spencer and Agassiz to
                            say nothing of Buddha or the Hindoo adepts have never proven it. "There is no new thing
                            under the sun." Why? God alone, as exprest by Emerson, is the eternal child, the bound-
                            less, the limitless, unchanging mind. As Job expresses it; "Canst thou by searching find out
                            God? canst thou find out the Almighty unto perfection? It is as high as heaven; what canst
                            thou do? deeper than hell; what canst thou know? The measure thereof is longer than the
                            earth, broader than the sea. For vain man would be wise, tho man be born like a wild ass's
                            colt." Even the human in Jesus cried out at the last; "My God ! My God! Why hast thou
                            forsaken me." This new school of .mentality which is rising would set at naught the Mosaic
                            law and declare that sins committed in violation of that law are simply mistakes. It works
                            itself up into a state of ecstacy wherein it imagines that everything is divine and that
                            there is no evil to be overcome, which idea it uses as the source of its healing power. Such
                            repeated affirmations as the following are said to bring strength to this purpose; "I am
                            pure !" "I am divine!" "I am healed!" "There is no evil!" Many cases of healing are re-
                            ported to have been effected by this means. The healing is not accomplisht instantaneously
                            as in the times of Christ and his apostles, but gradually. • We are glad for all benefited
                            by these mental, not spiritual means, but is the benefit lasting? We do not believe it
                            because the remedy applied is of a mesmeric character as are all intellectual persuasions.
                            Jesus healed through the law of sympathy. He was touched with the feelings of our in-
                            firmities because he was the at-one-ment with God. He taught the doctrine of the angel life
                            and community of goods as the only method of developing those divine forces in men and women
                            which make the whole world akin. If persons living in the natural life with its mine and
                            thine, who have never come to any deep conviction of the lost condition of mankind through
                            sin as did Ann Lee, can create a system of healing that is all-sufficient for the soul then
                            we are unavoidably forced to one conclusion, to wit: that the mission of Christ is at an
                            end. It is only by the principles of bear and forbear in the communistic life and of the
                            daily cross against evil that deep love and sympathy of the soul can be brought forth which
                            really bears the stamp of the divine. "All souls are mine" saith the Lord. If this statement
                            be true as well as the one that all weakness arises from a diseased condition of the soul,
                            then only from the house of the Lord can go forth that cleansing power to lift mankind from
                            the crawling serpent. <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 8 THE MANIFESTO. This is a matter of vital
                            importance to Zion. Let no man take thy crown. All else in this world is antichrist but an
                            obedience to that great summary of the law as enunciated by Jesus of love to God and the
                            neighbor. That law was repeated and emphasized by the Christ spirit in Ann Lee, and through
                            the work which she inaugurated, tho but in its infancy, there has been made more definite
                            progress toward the settlement of the one great question—that of sex-—than has been made by
                            all other movements of the times. In Zion there is to be found an inner way partaking not of
                            the form but of the spirit which will yield salvation, and to her has been committed the
                            task of consummating that one great declaration of supernal truth, —There is neither male
                            nor female in Christ. Movements springing from the earth may train the natural mind to think
                            and teach self-control and thus far are valuable, but in the daily, practical, spiritual
                            life personal experience with the difficulties to be met and overcome sets aside all theory
                            and calls for an application of those Christian principles which alone can develop the real
                            man and woman. A complete sacrifice of self and self-interest to the spirit of truth is the
                            only way of attainment. To all filled with the afflatus of pantheism to the effect that men
                            can rise "of their dead selves to higher things" let the example of the Nazarene suffice,
                            made perfect by Christ through suffering. The natural precocity of Jesus as a boy was
                            evident from the fact of his having confounded the doctors and lawyers in the temple with
                            his questions. His intuitive genius and comprehensiveness of mind derived from his lineage
                            were made manifest while the knowledge he had acquired previous to his conjunction with John
                            must have been a treasure to him, yet he knew that of himself he could do nothing for by the
                            God power alone with which he had been anointed through the descent of the dove was he
                            enabled to raise the dead, heal the sick and preach the gospel to the poor. The complete
                            earthliness and limitation of the natural mind with all its philosophy and science, valuable
                            enough in their sphere, were thus clearly demonstrated. The revelation of God in Jesus
                            through the witness, John, is an unanswerable testimony against pantheism with its
                            inadequate individualistic development. Let vain-glorious man with all his researches and
                            philosophies remember that while he may write books and add proposition to proposition that
                            the childlike simplicity possest by our Great Examplar who said his doctrine was not his but
                            his Father's who sent him, is a resignation of the human to the divine which the spirit of
                            truth demands. The difficulty in regard to the teachings of Christ with the majority of
                            people lies in the fact that they have not grown to them and therefore conclude that some
                            new ideas, so-called, claiming to point to the higher life are an ? improvement upon them.
                            This delusion arises from sheer ignorance. No production in all literature is comparable
                            with Christ's Sermon on the Mount. He spake the eternal truth as never man spake it.
                                Notwithstand<pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> TL.E MANIFESTO. 9 ing all the evolutions of thought by
                            the mind of man it will be discovered at the Last that the everlasting gospel which John the
                            Kevelator saw the angel standing in the sun (divine illumination) proclaiming to all
                            peoples, nations and tongues possesses the only power to fulfill that prayer indicted by our
                            Lord; "Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in earth as it is in Heaven." Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Ezekiel Morrill" TEIform="index"/>TESTIMONY OF EZEKIEL MORRILL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morrill, Ezekiel" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The following was written at Enfield, N.
                            H., June 30, 1826.] MY native place was South Hampton, in New Hampshire. I was born November 15, 1747. In my
                            childhood, my father moved with his family to Canterbury, where I lived till I was forty
                            years of age and then removed to Enfield, N. H. My parents were Calvinists, and I was
                            brought up under the influence of their principles. In my youthful days, I had religious
                            impressions, and felt some concern for my soul; but having little hope that I was one of
                            that small number who were elected to salvation, I resolved to pursue the course of the
                            world to the extent of my abilities; but determined, at the same time, that if I should ever
                            feel any call of God, by the movings of his Spirit upon me, I would embrace it. In this
                            situation I past my time, till I was about thirty-one years of age, when I was struck with a
                            deep conviction of my loss from Grod, which put an end to all my worldly pursuits and carnal
                            pleasures. About this time, a great light broke out in the vicinity, attended with a great
                            outpouring of the Spirit, which was evidently the spirit and power of Elias, and might be
                            compared to the work of John the Baptist, to make ready a people prepai'ed for the Lord.
                            Under my conviction, I united with this body of people, who were afterwards called Free-will
                            Baptists, and I endeavored to live to the light manifested in it. My conviction led me to
                            seek salvation from sin, fully believing that the Church of Christ must be a pure Church,
                            and that there could not be a pure head and a corrupt body; and I well knew that Christ was
                            generally acknowledged as the head of his body the Church. It was therefore clearly evident
                            to me, that there had been a falling away from the primitive purity of the gospel; and that
                            the power of the holy people was lost. But having in myself an inward corruption, which was
                            not removed, and which brought me into captivity to the spirit of darkness, I was unable to
                            live up to the light of my conviction ; nor was I able to find the cause by the light which
                            I possest, or by that which was in the body to which I was joined. This led me to believe it
                            could not be found short of a new revelation. My faith led me to believe there must be a
                            travel in the regeneration, but this I could not find. I also believed that a cross was
                            required; but what <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. this cross was, or in what it
                            consisted, was still unrevealed : for notwithstanding all my exertions to bear this cross,
                            or to find it, my soul was yet in bondage to sin. While laboring under this distress of
                            soul, I had several visions, in which I saw the pure Church, and received some bright and
                            encouraging manifestations of God, that I should see it establisht in my day. I continued in
                            this situation of mind about four years, laboring and struggling in deep tribulation. And I
                            believe it would have terminated my existence, had I not found deliverance through two
                            messengers of Christ, commissioned by Mother Ann Lee, to preach the gospel of salvation.
                            These messengers came to Canterbury in the latter part of the year 1782, with the testimony
                            of the everlasting gospel. When I first saw them, I knew them, having a number of times seen
                            them in vision, during the time of my labor and tribulation to find the way out of sin. When
                            they came to open the gospel, in its purity, they showed what the real cross of Christ was;—
                            that the lust of the flesh was the vail that darkened the soul; and that living in the
                            gratification of it, was the reason why we could not travel in the regeneration, nor find
                            the way out of sin. They had spoken but a few words before the prison doors of darkness were
                            set wide open, and I saw and knew that the lust of the flesh was the man of sin. They
                            testified that we must confess our sins, and bring our deeds to the light. Their testimony
                            was accompanied with such convincing evidence, that I was constrained, by my conscience, to
                            confess my sins in the presence of God and before his wit- nesses. I then set out to forsake
                            them forever, and to bear my daily cross, by which I felt my soul releast from its burden,
                            and brought into a new element of life. Shortly after this, I went to see Mother and the
                            Elders, who were then at Ashfield; and i found them to be just such a people as I had been
                            seeking after. I saw and felt the evidence that Christ, by his Spirit, had commenced his
                            second appearance in Mother Ann. I afterwards visited them often, and had many opportunities
                            of seeing them, and hearing their testimony, the whole object and tendency of which was, to
                            make an end of sin, to purge out and subdue all its evil propensities, and to bring in
                            everlasting righteousness. I can testify, from long experience, that in obedience to
                            Mother's testimony through the Elders and leaders, I have found an increasing victory over
                            every propensity to evil, and have received the baptism of the "Holy Ghost and fire." —Matt,
                            iii., 2. And in proportion as I have gained victory over the nature of sin, so have I felt
                            my soul rise in the resurrection power of life. And I can bear witness to all mankind, that
                            I have proved the truth of all that I have been taught from the beginning, by those who have
                            stood in Mother Ann's gift, and kept her testimony. And in obedience thereto, I now live in
                            the elements of spiritual life, as sensibly as I ever felt the elements of natural life.
                           Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto, January, 1898. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO.
                            JANUARY, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION.</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is publisht by the "United Society of Believees" on the first of each month,
                            and is the only work issued regularly by the Shakee Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain
                            and simple statement of the religious views of the Obdee and to inculcate the spirit of
                            righteousness. Address all communications to Heney C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N.
                            H. TEHMS. .50 One copy one year, postage paid. A cross in the margin will show that your
                            subscription has closed. Remittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post
                            Office at Concord, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">November. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. Snow. 1896. 42.67 2.125
                                in. 4in. 1897. 38.13 7.25 " 8 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 64 above 0 Lowest " " " "
                                12 " " Number of rainy days " " 11 " snowy " " " 3 " clear " " " 3 " " cloudy" " " 13
                                Nov. 1897. Novembee has been a stormy month. It has spread its gloom over more than the
                                weather and this has been dismal enough for the most somber mind. Yet when it enters our
                                household and strikes the vital fountain with the death of those who are a consolation
                                in our cherisht domain; taking from our ranks such needed ability as Sister Martha J.
                                Anderson in the prime of life, it is enough to make angels weep. When life has been
                                perfected with fullness of years and crowned with virtue and usefulness, fully ripe for
                                the harvest we can have a joy in seeing them borne by Angel bands to the beautiful
                                mansion of the redeemed as on the 28th day of this month they conducted our noble,
                                angelic mother, Eldress Eliza Ann Taylor. Her funeral was attended by representatives
                                from Watervliet, Enfield, Conn., and Hancock in connection with the Brethren and Sisters
                                at the Mount. It was a season that will be remembered by those who were in attendance.
                                We are trying to repair the dilapidated places in our possessions. November has brought
                                its modicum of cold and chilliness, requiring artificial heat to enable us to sustain
                                the vital warmth of our physical systems. Among our many temporal failures this year,
                                the failure of our heating apparatus in our dwelling-house is added. We are taking out
                                the old sectional boiler, that is rusted out and shall put in a new tubular boiler,
                                which we trust will give us more heat with less expense for fuel. The fire fiends are at
                                work again. Soon after this year's section of the state road between Lebanon and Hancock
                                was completed, the barn that had been used for lodging of the hands, was burned to the
                                ground. A few weeks ago the barn (owned by Simmons of Pittsfield.) located in the the
                                valley of New Lebanon, was also burned. In the evening at about 10 o'clock, Nov. 28th
                                the old Shapley barn above the South family was fired. This was evidently the work of an
                                incendiary as the rail fence enclosing the yard in which young stock were herded was
                                opened and the rails were turned and laid straight, which could not have occurred if the
                                cattle had thrown it down. The wicked will do wickedly! Those of us who still remain in
                                time, bid fair to tread the earth a while longer, and feed on tangible food to
                                recuperate our depleted energies.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>Calvin G. Reed</byline></div3><pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South family" TEIform="index"/>South Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1807. November has been the bearer of tidings glad and sad. On the 19th we were made
                                glad by an interesting visit from our brother, Hamilton DeGraw, a life member of the
                                Sonyea Society. He gave us a pleasing account of his recent return trip to the dear old
                                home, of the markt renovations perfected there since our departure, but we shall ever
                                love best its homelike plainness, Nov. 21st (to-day) we go to the North family to attend
                                the "Welcome Home Meeting" of our loved Sister Martha J. Anderson, the noted hymnologist
                                of the age, and inspired singer of Mt. Lebanon. Now that she still lives, we trust she
                                will have time to visit us. Sister Martha was one of God's noble women, possessing in a
                                markt degree, the qualities that constitute the Christian virtues. Nov. 25th we observed
                                as a special day of thanks-rendering, recounting the many blessings, spiritual and
                                temporal that are ours to enjoy, remembering that in the year 1621 the first
                                Thanksgiving hymn was sung, by the noble band who crost the sea for freedom's land. Nov.
                                28th records one of the sad scenes of 1897 a barn containing thirty tons of hay went up
                                in smoke. The structure was an ancient landmark erected during the days when Mother Ann
                                Lee traveled through this section. We pray that a protecting power may surround our Zion
                                homes and "keep them from flood, from flame and famine and in God's goodness may we
                                share, thus we implore thee heavenly Father for thy protecting hand of care." Dec. 1st
                                we are invited to be present at the memorial services of our angel mother, Eldress Ann
                                Taylor, beautiful and prophetic were the tributes rendered in honor of her long and
                                useful life, her parting blessing "love to all" was given to the assembly, by Sister Ann
                                Maria Graves, to whom she made known her last wish. May this be our motto "Love to all."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Genevieve" TEIform="persName">Genevieve DeGraw</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1897. Ix seeking for riches, honor and fame we many times have to suffer disappoint-
                                ment; but in attaining the gifts of the spirit there are no false calculations. In that
                                realm, the instruction, "seek and ye shall rind," is without variableness or shadow of
                                turning. We spent a week in the month of November with our gospel kindred of Mt. Lebanon
                                and West Pittstield, and we found a goodly band of those who have given all they
                                have to the cause; who were of that number who do not worship Baal nor do homage to his
                                image. We enjoyed a beautiful visit with our beloved Mot'.ier Eldress Ann Taylor, and
                                tho feeble in body her spirit is full of zeal. She said, "give my love to all of the
                                Brethren and Sisters," and in receiving that beautiful benediction we thought, "these
                                are they who have come up through tribulation and have made their garments white." May
                                we keep in union, with those blessed saints so that from out the destruction of our
                                rudimental life may be evolved a glorious destiny. Our national Thanksgiving was
                                observed and what imprest us in the Elder's address was the reminder of what we owe to
                                the labors of those old pioneers, the Pilgrim Fathers whose efforts on the line of
                                political and religious freedom made it possible for coming generations to worship God
                                according to the dictates of their consciences unmolested. For every advance made either
                                by nations or individuals towards that goal, the universal brotherhood of man, there has
                                had to be the wormwood and the gall. Some souls have had to suffer, be a for- tress
                                behind which the coming time could prepare more advanced conditions of life. Those
                                to-day who are the human representatives of that mighty power which is shaping human
                                destiny for its weal whose thoughts even are as ministering angels pointing to a better
                                way, come from the humbler walks of life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline></div3><pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1897. North Family. "I turn a page whereon to write, On which in future I must
                                dwell; I find it spotless, clean and white, No shades of blight thereon hath fell. Oh in
                                the light of love serene. How would my heart this fair page fill; How wonld 1 that no
                                deeds be seen My soul to blight, my heart to chill. Oh that the pen of time may stamp
                                Thereon the beautiful and true; Ah how in earnestness I plead, As I these stainless
                                pages view." The coming New Year! Oh that we may have garnered all that is precious from
                                the days that are past. May the experiences of the faded year teach us to live better
                                for God and humanity. Brethren and Sisters are still making improvements as fast as time
                                and means will allow. We have succeeded in arrang. ing a chapel in the new building, and
                                the former place of worship will be occupied as a school-room. Two large heaters in the
                                basement moderate the cold air in the halls to an agreeable temperature. In a short
                                time, our bath-rooms will be completed and we shall once more enjoy the blessings
                                afforded by such facilities.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shufelt, Edith" TEIform="persName"/>Edith Shufelt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1897. "We are living, we are dwelling In a grand, eventful time, In an age on ages
                                telling, To be living is sublime." The truth of this poetical declaration, is realized
                                as we think of the great inventions man has made in the halls of art, music and
                                mechanism. Life is only sublime, as we live in thoughts and acts that are stampt with
                                the sublimity of the Christ spirit. A spirit that keeps itself unspotted from every de-
                                filing element and is devoted to God, of whom, every product of nature, not created by
                                finite powers, and the stars radiant in their golden silence, constantly remind us.
                                "There is a way that seemeth right unto a man, but the end thereof is death." Narrow or
                                sin-diseased must be the mind that can not distinguish right from wrong. No one need to
                                master all isms, sciences and philosophy to work out a sublime immortality, it is only
                                to "cease to do evil and learn to do well." The doctrine of Christ does not appall or
                                enchant, but instructs to right living, and the life of the Christian, is not a, sol-
                                emn drama, of masquerading of seem-tobe Christianness, but a life as open and as pure as
                                the heavens; full of good fruits, without partiality and without hypocrisy." We had a
                                very profitable Thanksgiving service and entertainment, both of which added comfort to
                                the aged and cheer to the young people. We lately had the pleasure of entertaining
                                Misses Gould and Davis of Lebanon, N. H. who gave us a recital of their visit to the
                                convention of Christian Endeavor, held at California, also, of listening t.) an
                                excellent discourse on missionary work among the fallen and poor of New York, by Mr.
                                Fred Partington of Mt. Kisco, N. Y. For all our blessings, we render thanks to God and
                                associates and hope at the end of the corning year we may be able to report greater
                                advancement in spiritual and material growth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baxter, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Baxter</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoosee, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossee, Fla</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1897. Dear Editor ;—Through your paper, we thank our dear friends in the north, for
                                their kindness extended to us. During the past few weeks we have been the recipients of
                                many excellent letters, especially from our own dear home and from the dear friends at
                                Canterbury. These have been letters, both of joy and sorrow. The death of our gospel
                                sister, Martha Anderson, awakened our sympathy. A noble soul has fallen in the bat- tle
                                of life, while clad in full armor. The outlook for this state seems more propitious than
                                ever. The orange crop is <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. greater than was
                                estimated, and the fruit is commanding fancy prices. The vast herds of cattle that are
                                raised for the market, is also a great source of income to the state. Spain's doubloons
                                are sure to find their way into the pockets of the people. War is a tenible thinjr, and
                                the follower of the meek and lowly Jesus will never lend an influence for its
                                advancement. But sometimes out of evil come blessings of recompense. Thousands of cattle
                                are being shipt to Cuba for the Spanisli soldiers. We have been selling some of our beef
                                stock to these same parties, and the demand will hold good for months to come. It has
                                been said that the best poor man's country is Florida. Everything except wheat and
                                coffee can be grown here. Our pinery has grown to double its former size, and is now
                                filled with young plants. In twelve months from this date we may write of results. A
                                Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year to all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Barrett</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1897. The summer is past with all its beauty, and the falling leaves remind us that
                                winter is drawing near, and that we must be prepared. We are trying to carry out the
                                principle of godliness in our home. As cleanliness is next to godliness, we have been
                                putting our home in order. A new coat of paint on our kitchen and dining-rooms will add
                                much to the pleasantness of these places. We have also removed some old buildings that
                                were not in use. We have been blest with an abundant hay crop and the late rains have
                                brought forward our wheat crop, so that we have great reason to be thankful. The
                                interest on good roads has given us employment for several weeks and as it was by order
                                of the County, it proved to us a double blessing. The cutting down of some old trees
                                near the buildings has been to the village, a decided improvement. Spiritually, let us
                                strive to lead a pure and holy life; forgetting the past, let our lives be in peace and
                                harmony. "Let us not be weary in well doing, for in due time we shall reap if we faint
                                not." Have thankfulness for our present home, however small our inheritance on the
                                earth. If faithful we shall realize more than the poet's dream and more than the
                                prophet's expectation. These are my expressions of love and gratitude to God, and may
                                The Manifesto spread the glad tidings of truth, throughout the whole earth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Westwood, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Westwood</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1897. "In duty enduring, in bearing believe, Forgiving if any my spirit should
                                grieve; Rememb'ring at all times, as Mother did say, To set out anew and begin every
                                day." How anxiously we have desired that a voice from the unseen might speak a few
                                words,—only a few words, that we might believe. It is in the above quotation that we
                                hear the spirit of our worthy Elder Issachar Bates, and even at this date it gives forth
                                no uncertain sound. It is the voice of the Christ, "Forgive, and ye shall be forgiven."
                                Accepting this voice of loving inspiration, let us begin the New Year with a clean
                                record. Abundant cares confront us on every hand. The affairs that pertain to the hap-
                                piness and prosperity of this life are imperative in their demands, and we must "Provide
                                things honest in the sight of all men," during our pilgrimage on the earth. Nearly seven
                                hundred cords of firewood must be provided for this Community from year to year. When
                                Br. Andrew sees this statement he will evidently, rejoice in his Florida home. Our
                                potato crop was a failure, but of apples we had a good supply. By and by "seed-time and
                                harvest" will come again, and then we may have reason to rejoice more fully.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn</byline></div3></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Condiments" TEIform="index"/>CONDIMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">The powerful inflaming influence of rich, highly-seasoned foods is well known as a fact
                                of observation. It may be well, however, to consider briefly the physiological facts
                                upon which this influence depends. The effects of mustard, pepper, and other condiments
                                upon the sexual organs are so well recognized by physicians that they are always
                                prescribed in all cases of acute disease of these organs, as in gonorrhea in men, and
                                they enormously increase the flow of blood to these parts. The reason is very evident.
                                The irritating oils to which the special properties of these condiments are due are
                                eliminated by the kidneys, and hence, being concentrated in the urine, affect
                                particularly the genito-urinary organs. In the case of capsicum, cayenne pepper,
                                mustard, and similar condiments, the indigestable particles which contain the acrid oils
                                are carried along down with the food and deposited in the rectum, where they produce
                                congestion, irritation, and resulting catarrh and hemorrhoids, as well as increast
                                sexual excitability.—Temple of Health.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the political world..." TEIform="index"/>In the political world...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">lsr the political world the last stronghold of prejudices, the rights of women are being
                            recognized. We have to-day a President and Congress elected in part by the votes of women.
                            The constitutions of Wyoming, Colorado, Utah and Idaho secure to women the full
                            suffrage.—The Woman's Tribune. new commandment by F. S. W. "Employ thy mind and thy body
                            about thine own business and avoid insanity." Humanity. Mexico it is the custom to eat a
                            dish of raw ants at the close of the dinner. It is called the honey ant.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Holy life" TEIform="index"/>A HOLY LIFE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A holy life is made up of a number of small things. Little words, not eloquent
                                    speeches or sermons; little deeds, not one great heroic act of martyrdom, make up
                                    the true Christian life. The little constant sunbeam, not the lightning; the waters
                                    of Siloam, "that go softly" in the meek mission of refreshment, not the "waters of
                                    the river great and many," rushing down in noisy torrents, are the true symbols of a
                                    holy life. The avoidance of little evils, little sins, little inconsistencies,
                                    little weaknesses, little follies, indiscretions and imprudences, little foibles,
                                    little indulgences of the flesh, go far to make up, at least, the negative beauty of
                                    a holy life.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="index"/>Martha J. Anderson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName">Martha J. Anderson</persName>, at North family, Mt.
                                Lebanon, N. Y. Nov. IP, 1897. Age 53 years and 10 months. Nov. 19th Sister Martha J.
                                Anderson past beyond our sight and touch, but never beyond our deepest, highest love.
                                She has been in failing health for some time, a nervous trouble which at one time
                                threatened blindness. When our friends go over the Border Land so near, and yet in
                                health and strength seeming so far, their faults are forgotten and their virtues
                                heightened; the very faults of our dear sister leaned to virtue's side, being unjust to
                                herself in her unselfish care for all others. Her sweetness and utter foi-getfulness of
                                self made her life among us from eleven to fifty-four years of age, like the golden path
                                thrown by the setting sun, all brightness and beauty, in whose light others might walk
                                and ever grow better and stronger.—Anna White.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Taylor, Ann" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Ann Taylor
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Taylor, Ann" TEIform="persName">Eldress Ann Taylor</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Nov.
                                28, 1897. A memorial will be publisht, in which an extended account will be given of the
                                life work of Eldress Ann.</p></div3></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books &amp; Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Outlook" TEIform="index"/>   The Outlook
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Not a little favorable comment lias been made by the press on the special announcement by
                                The Outlook that its chief feature for the coming year (in the Magazine Numbers) will be
                                a series of papers by Edward Everett Hale on "Lowell and His Friends." The general
                                interest exprest assures a particularly cordial welcome to this series of articles. ($3
                                a year. The Outlook Company, 13 Astor Place, New Y.ork.) </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humanity" TEIform="index"/>Humanity
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Humanity for Oct. mid Nov. has
                                a discourse by Dr. J. E. Roberts who is denominated a minister of this world. This
                                article is "Con- cerning Prayer" and to read it is to be made better. Among the many
                                good things that are said is this "Religion is to live well, to do justice, to love
                                mercy and to be fraternal and kind." "Is he a Good Man," can be read very profitably
                                several times. Other nice articles may be found in this same number, which may require a
                                careful study, and a thoughtful consideration. Publisht at Kansas City, Mo. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Frank Leslie's popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Christinas number of Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly is brimful of attractive articles
                                and entertaining stories for the festal season. The number opens with a Christmas story
                                by Frank R. Stockton, entitled Old Applejoy's Ghost; which contains a particularly
                                clever idea workt out in Mr. Stockton's wellknown pleasing manner. It is illustrated
                                with three full page drawings by George Wright. This is followed by the second paper in
                                the magazine's important series on Andrew Jackson, and his times and compatriots, taking
                                up this month Andrew Jackson as a Mili- tary Commander, written by A. Oakey Hall, and
                                containing portraits and views and an excellent picture of Jackson spending Christmas
                                Day, in 1814, by H. M. Eaton. Hunter MacCulloch contributes an entertaining paper on The
                                Music of Christmas time, which is made particularly interesting by the insertion in the
                                text of reproductions of the music of some of the old time songs and carols. Famous
                                Ranchos of the San Gabriel Valley, writ ten by Beatrice Bellido de Luna, has many fine
                                illustrations. Perhaps the most important article in the number is one on The Baptists,
                                in which General T. J. Morgan, Corresponding Secretary of the American Baptist Home
                                Mission Society, describes the history, growth and creed of that religious body in this
                                country. It is the first of a series of articles on the Religious Denominations of Amer
                                ica. There are other interesting articles; sev eral short stories in addition to the one
                                by Frank R. Stockson, contributed by Amelia E. Barr and Margaret E. Sangster; poems by
                                Ella Wheeler Wilcox and Minna Irving; an attractive department for the boys and girls,
                                etc., etc.—Frank Leslie's Publishing House, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy for
                                Oct. and Nov. contains a large amount of useful information in regard to the treatment
                                of the sick . "A successful system of treating the sick -without the use of Drugs," is
                                certainly a great boon to those who are deprived of health. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp;
                                Co. Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for Dec. is largely the
                                Messenger of sorrow which will reach the homes of a large class of the readers of the
                                Journal. The first mentioned, is the death of Prof. Nelson Sizer, the President of the
                                American Institute of Phrenology. It is said of him "So remarkably tender, subtle and
                                electric were his feelings that he could call forth a tear or a smile in quick
                                succession. He will be missed in all lands by all classes. The untimely death of Henry
                                George has been the sorrow of thousands of his friends. "Pure in motive, high minded,
                                absolutely devoted to the service of his fellowrnen, he has fallen battling against the
                                tyranny and corruption of one-man power." The great Journalist, Charles A. Dana has also
                                past beyond time. His whole life has been in the interest of humanity and he is said to
                                be "the greatest all around newspaper man America has ever produced." The duchess of
                                Teck or Princess Mary endeared herself to the hearts of the English people and few have
                                workt so hard so indef atigably and unselfishly as this noble woman has done for years.
                                An article bearingjthe name of Mrs. Henry Ward Beecher, is also found in this number.
                                These several notices are all illustrated with portraits of the individuals which will
                                make the Journal one of special interest. Much other valuable reading will also be found
                                in the Dec. number. Fowler &amp; Wells Co. 27 East 21st St. New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies'
                                Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Ladies'
                                Home Journal has secured what promises to be the great magazine feature of 1898. It is
                                entitled The Inner Experiences of a Cabinet Member's Wife. In a series of letters
                                written by the wife of a Cabinet member to her sister at home, are detailed her actual
                                experiences in Washington, frankly and freely given. The letters were written without
                                any intention of publication. They give intimate peeps behind the curtain of high
                                official and social life. They are absolutely fearless, they study Washington life under
                                the search-light as it has never been before presented. The President and the highest
                                officials of the land, with the most brilliant men and women of the Capital, are seen in
                                the most familiar way. As these are all actual experiences the name of the writer is
                                withheld. The letters will doubtless excite much shrewd guessing by readers and study of
                                internal evidence to discover the secret. The "Experiences," which will be beautifully
                                illustrated, begin in the December number and will continue for several months. <pb id="p19" TEIform="pb"/></p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to grow flowers" TEIform="index"/>How To Grow Flowers
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The December number of How To Gicow Flowers is a very attractive one. The leading
                                articles are devoted to "The Parks of Pitts burg" and "Flowers at the Nashville
                                Exposition"—both beautifull5r illustrated. Other departments and contributions are up to
                                the usual high standard of this publication, and announcements of next year's features
                                foreshadow continued improvement. Five cents a copy at newsdealers or fifty cents a
                                year, with splendid plant premium, of the publisher, Miss Ella V. Bain.es, the Woman
                                Florist, Springfield, Ohio. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks on the mistakes of Moses" TEIform="index"/>Remarks on the Mistakes of Moses
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, H. L." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Remarks on the Mistakes of Moses, by H. L. Hastings. This is
                                an enlarged and beauti. fully illustrated work and is well worthy of an extended
                                circulation. To say the least, it does not seem to be very kind to be talking of a
                                persons mistakes for three thousand years, especially when it is so hard to find them.
                                Br. Hastings, however, comes forward as an able advocate for the world renowned prophet,
                                and thousands of readers will be interested in this little work. H. L. Hastings, 47
                                Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loretto Order" TEIform="index"/>The Loretto Order
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, Eleanor M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Loretto Order. Bv Eleanor M. Parker, in Donahue's. Self
                                sacrifice so heroic must necessarily bear abundant fruit, and today throughout the great
                                West the Society counts many noble institutions. Historic Loretto Academy at Florisant,
                                Mo., which this year celebrated its golden jubilee, lias sent forth many distinguisht
                                pupils; like- wise the school of the same name in St. Louis. In the city of Denver is
                                St. Mary's Academy and, crowning Loretto Heights in the suburbs of the same city, is the
                                superb new Loretto Academy, built of red granite. Houses have also been establisht at
                                Las (Ji-uces, Soeorro and Bernalillo, N. M.; Pueblo, Col.; El Paso, Texas, and many
                                other points. The school at Bernalillo is a government contract school for the education
                                of Indians. This institution was recently made prominent by Morgan's infamous attack. By
                                impartial judges this school is conceded to have done much toward civilizing the
                                Indians. The most interesting of the Kentucky branches are Betnlehem Academy in Hardin
                                County and Mt. St. Benedict's, Louisville. On the grounds of the latter stands a small
                                building known as the ¦'Bishop's House," in which Archbishop Spalding wrote the greater
                                number of his valuable works. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Newspaper advertising in the United States" TEIform="index"/>Newspaper Advertising in the United States
                            </head><p TEIform="p">• Newspaper Advertising in the United States. A book of
                                two hundred pages, containing a catalogue of about six thousand newspapers, being all
                                that are credited by the American Newspaper Directory (December edition for 1897.) with
                                having regular issues of 2 000 copies or more. Also separate State maps of each and
                                every State of the American Union, naming those towns only in which there are
                                issuedjnewspapers having more than 1,000 circulation. This book (issued December 15,
                                1867) will be sent, postage paid, to any address, on receipt of one dollar. Address The
                                Gto. P. Rowell Advertising Co., 10 Spruce St., New York. For the thirteenth year the
                                Columbia Pad Calendar makes its ai pearance promptly on tiine for 1898, and while its
                                general style is of the same familiar character, the many bright thoughts it contains,
                                contributed by its friends in many parts of the country, as well as abroad, are new, and
                                will be appreciated by all who take an interest in bicycling, healthful exercise and
                                good roads. The 1898 Columbia Pad Calendar contains a convenient arrangement of dates
                                that will prove useful to busy men, and as plenty of space is reserved for memoranda,
                                the: pud may be used as a diary and a-s a reminder for business appointments and
                                obligations. It is neat in appearance, takes u,i but little room and is both ornamental
                                and useful for the desk, while its stand is of such character that it may be used either
                                upon the de k or hung upon the wall. • The moon's phases are indicated in the Culendar
                                for the benefit of those who wish to have this information. The Calen iar is ready lor
                                distribution and all orders for it will be filled upon the day of receipt. It can be
                                obtained by mail pre-paid for five two-cent stamps by addressing the Calendar Department
                                of the Pope Manufacturing Company, Hartford, Conn.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>