<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0401" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18740101" TEIform="date">January 1874</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-8</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <p>Vol. IV. No. 1. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. ^ , _, __ __. _. -iory^ Fifty Cents ^aQJ Mt. Lebanon, Ool. Co. N.
                        Y. January, 1874:. PER ANNUM></p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New heaven" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW HEAVEN</head><p TEIform="p">The Shaker and Shakeress sends kindlygreetings, and would fain waft joyous influences of
                            love, and all-inspiring hope, over the whole "Household of Faith;" not omitting its host of
                            other friends, in the Natural Order, for the year 1874. We commence the new volume with
                            thoughts upon the new heaven ; and we bless those who " let patience have its perfect work "
                            while they are creating it. And, through suffering, may the Shaker and Shakeress be made
                            more perfect. A glorious hope inspires us on, To bear the burthens of our day ; A living
                            faith bids us be strong To reign o'er wrong undauntedly. For lo, we see the heavens bend,
                            The Angels come with choicest things; And to their home we would ascend — Mount upward, as
                            on eagles' wings. To the " new earth" we have given a " place " to be, when truth-loving
                            souls in the outer order shall have created it. But we would now sing of the " new heaven "
                            in its purity and spiritual beauty, as distinct therefrom as is the sun from the moon. "
                            Come hither," said the Angel, " and I will show thee the Bride, the Lamb's wife." Marriage
                            in the " new earth " will be between one man and one woman; but, in the language of the
                            Christ Spirit, it is a union between the Male (or Jewish Pentecostal) Church, and the Female
                            (or G-entile Pentecostal) Church. They were betrothed 1840 years ago (" He that hath the
                            Bride is the Bridegroom), and have now just grown to " the measure of the stature of man "
                            and woman—Two Orders— in Christ." Jesus and the twelve Apostles of the Father Church, as
                            representatives of the spiritual principles which should be revealed to and in the Mother
                            (or Gentile Pentecostal) Church, were the " corner stone " and foundation of the Jewish
                            Pentecostal Church, which had the Mosaic Law as a basis, but did not possess the revelation
                            of the Mother Spirit in Deity, or in Christ. The Gentile Pentecostal Church, however, does
                            possess that inestimable treasure— the revelation of the Mother Spirit; but, being " without
                            the Law " of Moses, it cannot, at present, sing the song of Moses, the servant of G-od — all
                            of those beautiful natural truths which will constitute the glory of the " new earth," as
                            set forth in our preceding article, in 1873. During the 1260 years' reign of Antichrist
                            ending in 1792 or 3,* these two systems, or* In this, Cumming, Snimeal, and the Shakers,
                            respectively (in their critical calculations) agree. ders, and peoples existed, one on
                            earth, the other in the spirit world, and acted upon each other for the progress of the
                            race. The holy Jerusalem, or city of the Jews — the first Pentecostal Church — " was caught
                            up to God," away from the persecuting spirit of heathen Rome, and was his throne in the
                            spirit world; and was also the source and fountain of inspiration to the " two witnesses,"
                            who were continually delivering their testimony, and being slain by the " beast and its
                            image " — Catholicism and Protestantism ; first physically, then spiritually; until the
                            kingdom of Antichrist has become full of their " dead bodies " — " names " — sects. When, in
                            the fullness of time, the Christ Spirit began, through female in England, to be revealed, as
                            it had been revealed through a male in Judea, the Church had to flee from the face of the
                            English Lion, as it had " fled from the face of the Roman Dragon; " for, at that time, there
                            was "no place" of refuge for it upon earth. Therefore " it was caught up " to the land of
                            souls. Persecution had " destroyed the body" but could not destroy the spiritual
                            organization. But, in 1774, the Church " fled into the wilderness of this "new world," from
                            the face of the English Lion, and it came to the help of the American Eagle. For Mother Ann
                            proclaimed the Independence of the United States Government that should be finally and
                            successfully established ; as also liberty of conscience, through its agency. John
                            continues: " He (the Angel) carried me away, in spirit, to a great and high mountain, and
                            showed me (in the spirit world) that great city, the holy Jerusalem " — the Jewish Christian
                            Church (in which there had been a war between the saints and the Dragon and his angels —
                            Roman heathens in the spirit world — until they were cast out), " descending out of heaven
                            from G-od ; " see Rev. xxi. It had a " wall" of separation from the "new earth," "great and
                            high; twelve gates, and twelve Angels " guarding them ; " and names written thereon, which
                            are the names of the twelve tribes of Israel. For in the spirit world, as on the earth,
                            Jesus was sent to its "lost sheep." The city was four-square, and, when measured, it " was a
                            hundred and forty-four cubits, the measure of a man, that is, of the Angel; " the number
                            twelve denoting the natural, or generating man ; twelve times twelve, the celibate or
                            resurrected angelic man. And the many " precious stones " bear to the earthly man and woman
                            — the " new earth"—the same relation that resurrection spiritual principles bear to the
                            heavenly man and woman, or "new heaven." There was seen no physical "temple, and neither sun
                            nor moon; for the glory of G-od did lighten it; and the Lamb"—the Christ Spirit—"is the
                            light thereof." It was spiritual to that degree, that neither John nor his inspiring Angel,
                            who was one of the ancient "Prophets," could comprehend it. Nor has any generative man or
                            woman ever been able to look into this Apocalyptic book without becoming blind; and " any
                            such person attempting to explain this book is crazy, or will become so."—Emerson. Yet the
                            natural man and woman in the " new earth " may " walk in the light of it," as of a spiritual
                            sun; for the Law of Moses shall go forth from Zion, and the word of revelation shall come up
                            from Jerusalem. And " the kings "— leaders in the earthly order — "shall bring their honor
                            and glory into it." "And the gates thereof shall not be shut at all by day; for there shall
                            be no night there." But there will be a continual ascension of individuals from the "new
                            earth " into the "new heaven." Yet " there shall in nowise enter into it any thing that
                            defileth, or that worketh abomination, or that maketh or loveth a lie; " but only those
                            whose virgin characters are "written in the Lamb's book of life." "Blessed," in the "new
                            earth," ''are they who do his commandments, that they may finally have a right to the tree
                            of life"—of spirituality; and may enter, through the gate of confession, into the city of
                            God — the " new heaven"—while yet in the body. "They sing a new song before the throne," or
                            Church, which none but the twelve times twelve can learn; these being "virgins," who were
                            "redeemed from the earth, and are not defiled " with generative men or women. The first
                            Gospel Church had its representative men; the second, its representative women. These two
                            are the " angels who neither marry nor give in marriage." " I looked, and behold a white
                            cloud, and upon the cloud one sat, like unto the son of man"—a woman — "having on her head a
                            golden crown, and in her hand a sharp sickle. And to her an Angel said: Thrust in thy
                            sickle, and reap; for the time has come for thee to reap; for the harvest of the earth is
                            ripe ; and she thrust in her sickle, and the earth was reaped." Does not Shaker celibacy
                            reap a man or woman from the earthly order, and bring it to an end in them ? But "the
                            plowman may overtake the reaper," and the sower may soon follow; and thus the Two Orders — "
                            the new heaven and the new earth"—may run parallel forever; <pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEE AND
                            or until this planet is exhausted of its vitality, and falls back into the sun, from whence
                            (some say) it was originally projected. It is a well-known fact, that the Churchand-State
                            theologians utterly ignore the Mosaic Law; and that, from the days of Constantine to those
                            of President Edwards, they have waged against it an unrelenting war. Gentile Christianity
                            rests upon the Justinian Code and the Roman Pandects, exactly as Jewish Christianity rested
                            upon the Law and the Prophets. Blackstone refers, not 1o Jewish, but to Roman Law as
                            authority. In the relation of the sexes, and of property, "an English woman," says Dixon,
                            "is far worse off than any of her swarthy sisters of Egypt, or Bengal." " We get our
                            marriage laws from the Roman Pandects; the Moslems get theirs from the Koran. In this
                            difference of origin lies the secret of their difference in tone and spirit. Our laws have a
                            civil and commercial source; theirs a moral and religious source. Primarily, theirs are
                            Mosaic, as Mahomet was a lineal descendant of Abraham, through Ishmael, his son." (P. 294.)
                            " Here, indeed, an inquirer strikes his ax upon the root of our " Babylon " system. Our life
                            is a divided duty : a moral life based upon the G-ospel; a family life based upon Civil Law.
                            Thus, while our morals have their life in Christianity, our statutes have their root in
                            Paganism." '' The truth is, we English and Americans have hardly yet embraced Christianity
                            as a scheme of life. We find our religion at church ; and, when we have sung our psalms, and
                            breathed our prayers, we go back into the streets, to be governed for another week by our
                            Pagan Law."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meetings of shakers and spiritualists in New York" TEIform="index"/>MEETINGS OF SHAKERS AND
                            SPIRITUALISTS IN NEW YORK</head><p TEIform="p">That the Metropolis needs a baptism of salvation, equal to the supply of water that sur-
                            rounds it, some will hardly deny. If this salvation should ever reach any of its denizens,
                            it will be through the instrumentality of those who are saved from the sins with which this
                            and other cities are notoriously afflicted. They need " Saviours." Upon the appeal of a
                            lover of truth — J. M. Peebles — that " Zion must have a hearing in New York," ten of us
                            girded ourselves for the mission, and were hailed by the beautiful morning of Nov. 22d,
                            1873. We quartered at the hospitable "New Hygienic Home " — clean, quiet, and restful — at
                            whose head stands Dr. Miller, who finds it more difficult to relieve his patients of the
                            effects of other doctors' medicines than to effect permanent relief from disease. As a "
                            Home," or " Cure," we recommend travelers to 41, West Twenty-sixth street. On Sabbath
                            morning, we repaired to Robinson Hall, which was soon comfortably filled by a thoughtful and
                            respectful audience. J. M. Peebles welcomed and introduced us in (as we felt) very
                            flattering terms, which we are laboring to feel may some day be deservedly bestowed.
                            Singing, by the excellent choir of the "North," followed, with much interest. The writer was
                            next introduced; and, though our efforts were very well received, we proved only a kind of
                            John Baptist to the speaker of the evening, which we were contented and duly prepared to be.
                            Eldress A. Doolittle followed in a few well-timed remarks upon the increased facilities for
                            obtaining knowledge of the truth, and the necessity of obedience thereto. Her words were
                            received with evident satisfaction, and much outward approval. A few more songs, and then
                            our Morning Meeting closed. In the Afternoon, we attended the Lyceum, spoke to, and sang
                            for, the children, and witnessed the movements of the Spirit upon some individuals, who lost
                            all control of themselves. In the Evening, we reached the Hall early, yet found it nearly
                            filled with impatient auditors of seemingly select minds, who were conscious of their needs,
                            and appeared to realize that they were soon to receive satisfaction. A few songs opened the
                            meeting. Elder F. W. Evans came forward, and taking for his theme the Leaders of the
                            December and January Nos. of the " Shaker and Shaker ess," spoke, for more than two hours,
                            as we never, upon any occasion, heard him or any other man speak. Thus to hold an audience,
                            as crowded as was that, for so long a period, required both talent and the power of truth to
                            accomplish. Several Reporters for the City Press occupied places on the platform ; and,
                            although beginning with the speaker, they soon became too interested to continue reporting.
                            We followed him for an hour and a half, reporting sufficient to fill six columns of this our
                            Monthly, when we too became enchained by seeing and hearing. Such indeed was the discourse,
                            that we should require six times its period of delivery to report the whole of it. There
                            were laid down the most thoroughly radical premises in truthful systematic theology ; and
                            upon these were built up the beautiful structures of a new earth and a new heaven. Arts,
                            sciences, history, orthodoxy, infidelity, land re- forms, land limitations, social life with
                            sectarian proclivities, lawyer-craft, priestcraft, and doctor-craft, all came in for their
                            share of elucidation and justice at his hand. The utter abandon with which he scathed the
                            rottenness of man-made creeds, and hypocritical professions, surprised me; and the thought
                            that we were " bearding the lions in their den," led to reflections upon what might be the
                            consequences. Jesus said far less to the Jews, for which they crucified him. And the fact
                            that round upon round of applause greeted the speaker, evidenced the highly-liberal
                            preparation of the people for truth, and their appreciation of the spirit no less than the
                            letter of the Constitution of our country. Time was, and that not long since, when a safe
                            conduct would have been necessary, after such a delivery in this same city. One man, of fine
                            intellect, said to me: " No one but a Shaker would have been permitted to speak like that,
                            without a tragical ending." So we thought, so think we now. But of one thing we are assured
                            : Just such facts and undeniable logic, carried into effect in that most wicked of cities,
                            would prove the salvation of thou- sands. The sister of R. D. Owen remarked: "If this nation
                            is ever saved, it must be through the Shakers." Other women returned heartfelt thanks for
                            the clear, lucid advocacy of their rights and interests by the speaker. One remarked : "
                            This city needs just such salting, at least once a year, to keep its rottenness from
                            reaching the nostrils of an avenging heaven." And that noble-hearted, eccentric, but honest,
                            infidel — George Francis Train —who says that he does not believe in a God, or in a Jesus,
                            or in a hereafter, but does believe in Elder Evans and the Shakers, after reaching the
                            Institute, sent up the following note: " Dear Elder Evans, Congratulations on your
                            magnificent lecture. It should have been taken down in short hand, and published all over
                            the world. You should write it out, and print it in the " Shaker and Shakeress." " Many
                            thanks for so handsomely shutting off the call of the audience, as I requested before you
                            went down. My speaking days are over. The time for action is now at hand." "George Francis
                            Train." The evening proved rainy ; but this was for- tunate ; for the Hall would not have
                            held a third of the number who undoubtedly would have made the attempt at an entrance, but
                            were prevented by the unfavorable weather. This Meeting will prove but a forerunner ; and
                            then we move : Ho ! for the Cooper Institute !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder G. A. Lomas, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, September 25th, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Sept. 25th, 1873</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elders, &amp; Brethren &amp; Sisters of the Gathering Order : I was agreeably
                            surprised to find the " Social Gathering " in our dwelling-room, when I came in for meeting
                            on Tuesday evening, and am delighted with it, containing, as it does, many excellent hints
                            for our guidance and travel all along the way. It was a real casket, handsomely and
                            tastefully prepared without and within, ornamented with buds of promise, blooming flowers,
                            and ripened fruitage, the products of a self-denying life Those offerings, proceeding from
                            the heart and life of the contributors, reminds one of the pellucid waters of life, which
                            rise beneath the Altar of Self sacrifice, and flow from under the threshold of the Temple
                            down into the great Sea of human nature, to heal its muddy waters, that the fish therein may
                            live in preparation for the Gospel net. Beloved friends, it brings your spirits very near,
                            aa they often are ; and I hope the life of every one whose name is there recorded,, and all
                            others who have entered the Gospel field, may ever continue under the Altar as a well of "
                            living waters springing up unto everlasting life;" and that they may glow as stars of di-
                            vine light and beauty, beneath the graduallyextending canopy of the New and Spiritual
                            Creation. Surely there can be nothing so beautiful and glorious on this earth, as the clean,
                            consecrated, subject sons and daughters of our Heavenly Parentage. O may I never mar this
                            beautiful relation, which is really worth tenfold the sacrifice required to gain it — yea, a
                            hundred-fold! My feelings were with you all that day. If I had been in need of rest from
                            toil, and were allowed my choice as to how to take it, I would have been with you bodily,
                            without the least desire or temptation to be anywhere else. I am thankful for what you have
                            given us. It is indeed seldom that such a clean messenger, so free from mixture of earth, or
                            taint of error, goes forth in a visible form to enlighten the denizens of this benighted
                            planet. And, if it should be but little heeded now, it will inevitably sow seed that will
                            spring up in some soils, and extend with a widening influence, as the ages roll on, and the
                            actors grow strong by increasing toil and sacrifice. 2 <pb n="3" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> Reformers, and
                            even anti-christians, having little else than moon or starlight, though they sometimes hit
                            upon real gems of truth, yet are they so embedded in earth, or surrounded by darkness, as to
                            be often like a torch in a cavern: bring them out to the sun, and their light ceases to
                            appear. Hence their fire, brought down from heaven in the sight of men, only enlightens
                            those who are in a like degree of darkness. And so far as they hold the truth in
                            unrighteousness, like those who hear the sayings of Christ and do them not, their impure
                            affections and desires, which are the windows of the soul, are like stained or colored
                            glass, adjusting the light to their pleasures or fancy. The light of mere natural reason,
                            unaided by the wisdom that comes from above, is both adjustable and movable from place to
                            place, and allows its possessor, like one carrying a lantern, to wander in the wilderness of
                            the natural life, as far and as long as he pleases. Not so with the revealed light that
                            shines in Zion, which proceeds from the primal Source of unchangeable principles, in a
                            direct line through an orderly channel, inviting the wanderer to return thither, and to
                            dwell in a fixed place of abode, in a quiet resting-place, and peaceful habitation, which
                            shall never be taken down, nor one of the stakes thereof be removed forever. Here our God
                            has become unto us a place of broad rivers and confluent streams, wherein shall go no galley
                            (labored system or creed) with oars, neither shall gallant ship (of human invented schemes)
                            pass thereby. Therefore have we received garments of praise for the spirit of heaviness, and
                            the oil of joy for mourning; for, in the Orders of the Gospel, the Law of Mount Zion, we
                            have a fixed light which will not veer to human caprice and folly, nor accommodate the
                            worldly-wise and carnally-minded; and, if we find we are getting on colored glasses, we can
                            have them removed, if we desire it, by dipping in Jordan, which is but coming into the light
                            of the true and faithful witnesses, who are appointed as watchmen to guard our city, whose
                            walls are salvation, and her gates praise. By thus doing, we renew vital contact with that
                            word of Truth, which is the light of the heavenly and only true life. All such have access
                            to the sanctuary of holiness, where God has promised to meet and commune with us. Beloved
                            Elder Frederick, Eldress Antoinette, and co-laborers, your lives of devotion are known. We
                            bless your lives of consecration ; and may we imitate your righteous example, by obedience
                            and faithfulness in the trust committed to us, to prove our sincerity by good works. In much
                            love, from your brother, who is deeply interested in all efforts to hasten the work which
                            shall cause the knowledge of the goodness and glory of God to cover the earth as the waters
                            cover the seas. PS. Our Elders unite in sending their love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Long speeches, long letters, long communications, are out of place..." TEIform="index"/>Long speeches, long letters, long communications, are out of place...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Long speeches, long letters, long communications, are out of place these stirring
                                    times. We have a whole world's news to look after and put in order for our readers
                                    over night. Remember that, kind correspondents and contributors. Avoid parentheses.
                                    Drop the semi-colons altogether. Make the spaces between your periods as brief as
                                    possible. Shake out the adjectives without remorse. Sacrifice the pet metaphors. Be
                                    not led away by the lovers of antithesis, or alliteration. Be clear and crisp,
                                    pertinent alike in your invectives, eulogies, and recommendations. Think of the
                                    Lord's prayer, and then of the awkward sub- stitute served up by sensation-mongers
                                    in too many pulpits. That flights of tawdry rhetoric, and volleys of expletives;
                                    what endless repetitions of tedious details weary and disgust the hearer. It is
                                    frightful to think of the time wasted by these self-parading petitioners and
                                    long-winded inditers of many-headed sermons. Life is too short, too full of cares
                                    and duties, to be thrown away thus. The best advice, the brightest wit, the deepest
                                    wisdom, come over in small packages.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston globe" TEIform="index"/>Boston Globe</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth for youth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH FOR YOUTH</head><p TEIform="p">To all the youthful readers of the " Shaker and Shakeress " in Zion. None of you can lift the
                            curtain that conceals the events of 1874 ; but if you will commence with the purpose, as
                            well as the wish, that the year shall be to you all a fruitful one in spiritual progress,
                            then you need not fear what coming time will bring. Eesolve from this day that your be-
                            loved Elders and caretakers, who love you " with that love which God does bless," shall have
                            nothing from you but truthful words, and ready obedience. For nothing is beautiful but
                            truth. This sentiment, though true, has been deplorably neglected. But truth does not need
                            untruth to bring out its beauty. The object of uttering an untruth is generally to conceal a
                            fault; but, as this end is seldom attained, the one who utters it adds another to it. In
                            point of prudence, even, an honest confession will always serve you better. Truth is all
                            important. It alone, more than all other qualities put together, will give character to
                            youth, and is of itself a rich inheritance, of greater worth than mines of silver or gold.
                            It is related of one of the ancient kings, that, when asked what was the first thing he
                            learned, he replied, " To tell the truth." He was fortunate in having good instructors. Had
                            he lived in this day, many would have instructed him differently. Remember, then, if you
                            wish to be loved and respected, you must be known; but you cannot be known unless you speak
                            the truth from your heart, and act the truth in your life. Again : The mariner who should
                            put to sea without chart or compass, trusting to his own knowledge, would, without doubt, on
                            the first stormy night, bitterly repent of his folly. How much greater is the folly of those
                            who, trusting to their own ways, refuse to be guided by the " Spirit of Truth," which would
                            lead them to perfect happiness. There is a way that seemeth right, but the end there- of is
                            death. Prov. 16 : 25. Here, then, is the conclusion: Imminent perils surround the youth ;
                            but the greatest of all perils is the danger of trusting to your own heart. Youth, beware !
                            lean not to your own understanding; own God in the appointed Lead, and all will be well.
                            Though you are weak and unwise, yet God is wise and strong, able to guide and protect all
                            who trust in Him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I thank God for our little paper..." TEIform="index"/>I thank God for our little paper...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"I thank God for our little paper, the " Shaker and Shakeress " ; I greatly bless its editor
                            and editress. Much have I learned by perusing it. How thankful I was to have you come and
                            visit us; please to come again as soon as you can. I have now entered into quite a labor of
                            mind against all mental and physical disease. Be so kind as to help me all you can. A great
                            day this is, surely. I want to be a Progressionist, like yourself. I am longing for the time
                            to come when all animals will be in their own climate ; when the lower orders will not have
                            to be slain — yea, more—when they will not have to work to support poor, lazy man. Be so
                            kind as to explain about the " new heavens and the new earth," whether those in the latter
                            are to have " all things common," the same as the former. Please accept an abundance of love
                            from us all. Your Gospel son,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davidson, Henry L." TEIform="persName"/>Henry L. Davidson, West Gloucester, Me.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberal offer" TEIform="index"/>LIBERAL OFFER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">All persons who will remit fifty cents for this number shall receive, free, eleven more
                            numbers.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dissatisfaction" TEIform="index"/>DISSATISFACTION</head><p TEIform="p">The more contented people are in any state short of the resurrection, the more desperate is
                            their condition. Stagnant water is proverbially unhealthf ul. The more men are absorbed, and
                            find enjoyment, in the pursuits of earth for selfish purposes, the less probable is it that
                            they will be quickened by the Spirit of Truth. As long as men are contented with the
                            pleasure which indulgence of their passions brings, and with the comfort which wealth and
                            the present false organization of society bring, so long will they be out of reach of the
                            pure pleasures of self-denial. Indeed, they can have no conception of the fact that there
                            are delights therein, which immeasurably surpass every earthly satisfaction. To them every
                            thing which cuts off any selfish gratification is loathsome. Those who live lives of virgin
                            purity, consecrated to holiness and truth, are to them ignorant bigots. Cut off from all
                            living hope in the future, they cannot realize the welling up of eternal life in the souls
                            of those despised ones. Yet happiness can be found through an awakened and justified
                            conscience alone. But the more we reconcile ourselves to worldly pursuits, with the
                            inevitable consequences — deception, the greed of gain, worldly pride, with more or less of
                            sinking into the mire of sensuality—the more will the conscience become deadened, the
                            farther off will become the prospect of eternal life, the harder will it be to shake off the
                            bondage of the world when truth strikes irresistibly on us. Dissatisfaction alone with
                            existing circumstances, on the part of those who are on Nature's plane, will lead to that
                            yearning after something that can satisfy the soul, which is the best preparation for
                            enlightenment into divine truth. Nothing ought to satisfy a rational being short of the
                            possession of principles which can redeem the soul from the power of evil, and that can
                            bring it into a state of justified relation to the Deity — the only state in which continual
                            progress in Christian qualities is possible. It is not those who are satisfied with an easy,
                            good-natured life, who do any thing to exalt their race. Though they may do but little
                            active harm, they are utterly incapable of making the sacrifice and effort which spiritual
                            progress demands. As the testimony of the First Christian Church was "Awake from the death
                            of sin," with a foreshadowing of the resurrection ; so the more vital testimony of the
                            Second Christian Church is "Awake from the death of Nature," with the full proclamation of
                            the resurrection for humanity while in time.. Tims, those who cannot be satisfied with
                            natural affections and interests, and with sin, who restlessly and eagerly seek to know and
                            realize divine blessings, such have been the witnesses of God in all ages of the world; such
                            were those who founded the Second Kingdom of Christ on earth; and such are those who are
                            building up that kingdom in this day. But, while the only hope of salvation for man lies in
                            dissatisfaction with a life of nature, sin, and earthly pursuits, he ought not to be
                            ungrateful to God for the blessings wh ch he receives in his present condition. He should be
                            thankful for his existence; for the prospect or the possession of a sphere of usefulness ;
                            for the numberless pure blessings which all men receive unasked from their Creator ; but no
                            man or woman should be satisfied with a state of life in which they are obliged to violate
                            their consciences, in which they are conscious that they are cut off from the life in God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, T. J." TEIform="persName"/>T. J. Stroud, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man who yields to anger..." TEIform="index"/>The man who yields to anger...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The man who yields to anger, and seeks to appease his disturbed temper by inflicting upon his
                            horse, or other domestic animal, an unmerited punishment, is injuring himself in a great
                            degree. Such a man will, in a short time, become morally depraved, and incapable of
                            rendering any true sympathy for man or beast. It will destroy those beautiful traits of
                            character that make a man manly, and should be the distinctive marks of his affinity with
                            God, as a son of the Most High.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., E. C." TEIform="persName"/>E. C. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The life of an honest man is a beautiful poem; and every human being who reads it feels better,                                 stronger, more                                 hopeful for it" TEIform="index"/>The life of an honest man is a beautiful poem...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The life of an honest man is a beautiful poem; and every human being who reads it feels
                            better, stronger, more hopeful for it.</p></div2><pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New York, November 24,1873" TEIform="index"/>New York, November 24,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans, Messenger of the Lord — the Female in Deity: Accept the warmest thanks in
                            behalf of the Shaker sisters of New York City, whose sentiments you so bravely and admirably
                            expressed in Robinson Hall last Sunday evening. Not in the whole city of New York, or
                            Brooklyn, do we know of a platform where Woman is invited to advocate the grand truths which
                            for years have inspired her, from what you would doubtless term the seventh or Christ
                            Heaven. Man is the great red dragon who has usurped every place of honor and trust, and who
                            faces her in the wilderness travail of her soul. Does she want a church ? a man owns and
                            controls it. A public hall ? she must apply to a man. Even the deciding power of who shall
                            supply the rostrum of the liberal Spiritualists is a man, or a woman whom man places in
                            power. The qualifications in Woman for pre-eminence and preferment demanded by man are not
                            Shakerism, but they are those that will pander to his lusts either under the cloak of " Free
                            Love " or beneath the darker mantle of hypocrisy. Who are the women that can support a pa-
                            per in New York city ? Those who advocate and practise " Free Love." Who are the women whose
                            lectures are reported in the newspapers and who can get a " respectable " man to introduce
                            them to a public audience 1 Those whose bodies and souls are under the psychological
                            influence of man. Would woman build or hire a hall for herself, she has no money, no
                            strength — nothing. Every place of business is run by man, and he dolefully stints her wages
                            even ; she often compromising virtue to hold any place. Is she the wife of a millionaire,
                            she is no less a slave. He carries the purse, and will lavish its contents only upon doll
                            faces who will gratify his passions. Intellectual and inspired women have no foothold upon
                            earth ; and, while the Shaker brothers brought along an equal number of their sisters to
                            occupy the Spiritual rostrum, they were welcomed by the Spiritual brothers, but the
                            Soul-women of this movement were not even notified of their coming, or given the liberty to
                            express their glad welcome before the public. And the only place among the Spiritualists,
                            even where they can possibly obtain a hearing is at the " Spiritual Conference." Here, each
                            person (every Sunday) who first commands the floor, has the privilege of ten minutes free
                            speech ; and, if a woman is spry and bold enough, she can push her way, in spite of tonguey
                            and aggressive men that j ump the moment the last speaker is seated. Woman, subjugated by
                            man, has brought forth monstrosities, great red dragons, whose horns of power have hemmed
                            her up in this Great City of Babylon, from which she has apparently no avenue of escape;
                            (but she hails in Elder F. W. Evans a sign and promis of future deliverance ;) that is the
                            reason the country is on the verge of ruin ; that is the rea son licentiousness prevails;
                            therein is the cause of "great expectoration," and why the tormenting smoke of tobacco
                            ascends upwarc forever and ever. The country is flooded by the dragon, anc Woman is
                            suppressed in her birth-pangs for the nation. And this is her only opportunity of stealing a
                            chance to offer the right hand of fellow ship to our dear Shaker brothers and sisters</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Travailing daughters of Zion in New York City" TEIform="persName"/>The travailing Daughters of
                            Zion in New York City</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rise and fall of empires" TEIform="index"/>THE RISE AND FALL OF EMPIRES</head><p TEIform="p">All that has been said, or may be said of Dmpires, may, without much stretching, be said of
                            races, generations, and individuals. All have their culminating point, their ascendng and
                            descending grades. By fidelity to nature, by stern self disci)line, especially as respects
                            diet and the use of the reproductive functions, through successive generations, the
                            culminating point of that !amily stock is achieved, to wit: the producion of a choice type
                            of the race homo — a lappy combination of the intellectual and moral elements in the human
                            make-up. Now, let us go back on the record. Do we, in any case, find that high attainment
                            transmissible by ordinary generations ? Does it not appear that liberal, intellectual
                            endowment, and high moral culture, lift their possessor above the reproducing plane ? Where,
                            in lineal descent, do we find the Moseses, the Solomons, the Jesnses, the Wash- ingtons, the
                            Jeffersons, or the Paines ? The individuals aforesaid, were the culminating point of that
                            family stock. The reproducing of God's image and likeness is a highly responsible office.
                            Such high official functionaries should, in no case, be cumbered with serving the
                            commonwealth in any other official capacity. Pater-familias should have undivided use of his
                            capabilities to provide ways and means. Mater-familias should have full liberty to care for
                            the little ones, unencumbered with other official serving. In the coming new earth it must
                            be so. Another, an intellectual class — celibates —must run the Government machine, wholly
                            unencumbered with domestic cares and responsibilities. When the new earth is fully
                            actualized, all departments, each in its own order, working harmoniously — don't you think
                            the morning stars may sing together, and the daughters and sons of God shout for joy ? Then
                            will the new heaven be replenished with material not marred in the hands of the potter.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Prentiss, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>A PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">O Lord, thou who seest all things, and orderest aright the way of the sincere, enlarge the
                            scope of our understanding, that we may comprehend the truthful import of thy require- ments
                            to us. O God, unlock the prison doors, so strongly barred by our own transgressions
                            perverted habits, and sensual hankerings foi unnatural stimulation. Make us, 0 Lord, to feel
                            satisfied with, and thankful for, thy in struction, plainly showing us how to escape from
                            the present quagmire of disease anc premature deaths, mainly induced by our own
                            transgressions. Distil, O Lord, the bright shining rays of thy truthfulness into our souls,
                            to understand that there is no transgression of thy law, either in mind or body, without its
                            attached penalty according to the greatness of its duration amount, and number. O God, open
                            our hearts to understand that thy primitive natural laws are all truthfulness, reflecting
                            thine own image of beauty, perfection, and health ; and that al the misery and trouble comes
                            from the many soughtout inventions of man, perverting thy natural law, in both his doings,
                            habits, tastes and inclinations, thus unhinging thy whole economy for his true comfort and
                            happiness 0 God, open our eyes to see and obey the truth, and gird us with thy armour of
                            strengtl so sufficiently that we may no longer hanker after the flesh-pots of Egypt, or
                            unnatura" poisons and narcotics, or thirst for stimulants in this our day. And thus, O Lord,
                            shall we be enabled, b] degrees, to travel into the full perfection of thy present
                            requirements — freedom from sickness, disease, and premature deaths, satis fied with the
                            real needfuls of life, instead of their fancies. And all the praise, honor, anc glory shall
                            forevermore be thine. Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts, September 21,1873" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass. Sept. 21,1873</head><p TEIform="p">MUCH-BELOVED ELDER FREDERICK : Will you please have tlie kindness to send me one hundred
                            copies of the " Shaker and Shakeress," containing the " Social Gatherng " the modern "
                            Jacob's Ladder ; " for, of a truth, on that day, " the angels of God ascended and descended
                            on it," and the rest of the vision (though it seems to tarry) is sure of fulfillment in
                            spiritual Israel. See Gen. 28: 12 to 15 inclusive. Though I was not apprised of the time of
                            the gathering, yet, not far from that time, I prepared the inclosed poem, Truly the Lion and
                            the Lamb have commenced their state of quiescence, and the Lamb is outside of the Lion ; not
                            forced, but protected by the secular arm. I was both edified and inspired in reading the
                            record of that heaven-blessed day; I found there no finality-pins to mark the place where
                            aspiration perished, to rob the more blessed future. If one-half of man has not been an
                            entire failure, what may we expect of a whole man ? for, when woman holds her station, man
                            alone can never fall. Then blessed, thrice blessed, are the virgins! Heaven ever recognizes
                            the white-robed passport. Your article on " Judgment " came with divine unction to my
                            spirit; it has seemed for years that we were experiencing the judgment of our time, for our
                            idolatrous veneration of the past, of persons and mediums, in place of vital advancing
                            principles of truth. There seems to be a prevailing disease of looking back to something
                            great and grand (well nigh final), and stretching the imagination forward to something still
                            grander; in the distant future ; almost forgetting that we live to-day, and that our work is
                            ever before us. To assert such truths, insures an unwelcome and undeserved appellation. God
                            bless you, Elder Frederick. Gratefully thine, unqualified love to all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worcester, Massachusetts, October 6,1873" TEIform="index"/>Worcester, Mass. Oct. 6,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. Evans. Dear Sir : You will perceive by this, that I have settled down here in
                            Worcester, and shall be obliged, if you will change my address on your books, as I am seldom
                            at Fitchburg. I was up there last week, and found two Nos. of the " Shaker and Shakeress."
                            In the multitude of cares, in establishing our office, advertising, mailing circulars, etc.,
                            I quite forgot to order my paper sent here. I take great pleasure in perusing the contents
                            of the " Monthly," and perhaps may find much profit. It is a spicy, earnest, readable sheet,
                            attacking boldly, and with a trenchant blade, some of the worst plague spots that are
                            festering and corrupting the morals of the nation. We need just such a fearless exponent of
                            truth and purity in every family in the land. May its influence extend, and take deep hold,
                            until the people in and out of the churches shall see and feel how far short the present
                            teachings of so-called Christian ministers are of the Christ model, as exemplified by him
                            they profess to represent; and until they realize how imChristlike is much that is called
                            Christianity. With earnest wishes for your success in your reformatory efforts, I am, sir,
                            respectfully yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barto, B. G." TEIform="persName"/>B. G. Barto</byline></div2><pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">To the Friends and Supporters of the Shaker and Shakerbss, Greeting : Twelve months have
                            passed since we sought aid from our Gospel kindred in a new field of labor. As we then
                            stated, it was by the earnest solicitations of many friends and inquirers outside of our
                            community, who seemed to think that duty demanded a greater effort on our part to make known
                            the fundamental principles of our institution, religious belief, etc., to the world at large
                            (as far as we could gain access), and to frankly " give our reasons for the hope" and faith
                            " that is in us" (and which has hitherto been our chief burden to actualize in daily life),
                            that we were induced to engage our services in bearing to those who had ears to hear what
                            the Sisterhood of the Shaker Societies had to offer in defense of our religious faith and
                            the reasons for reducing that faith to practice. Our efforts in this direction have been
                            sincere, our services freely rendered, and our deep and earnest prayers have been that God
                            might be honored, our GospeJ kindred comforted, and that humanity, through this humble
                            agency, might receive some new thoughts and new aspirations for the higher life; and, with
                            us, be led to the conclusion that holiness of character is profitable to all in this life,
                            as preparatory to entering upon the great future in the unseen world. We have made our
                            record for the year 1873, and time must decide for or against its value. Journalism has
                            become a great institution in all civilized countries ; but America is a receptacle, not
                            only from the " father land" and " mother country," but all nations and peoples find a home
                            in this " broad land of liberty ;" and hence the press is brought into requisition, and
                            wields a greater power than in any other nation. It is (speaking after the manner of men) "
                            the lever that moves the world," and moulds society in secular matters, and in a religious
                            point of view; but there is a " Providence "—a power behind— " that shapes our destinies,"
                            will it as we may. Amid such a variety of periodicals and newspapers which fly through the
                            land, containing advertisements for commercial departments, crimes and casualties for lovers
                            of the marvelous, and politics for office seekers we cannot reasonably expect that a smal] "
                            Monthly," containing none of the foregoing but which condemns the ungodly practices o\ the
                            age in which we live, and would seek to reason dispassionately of cause and effect would
                            receive a large amount of patronage Yet we rejoice to acknowledge that there are many candid
                            and thoughtful persons who de sire an increase of physical, moral, and spirit ual truth in
                            what is called Christendom to-day and who feel deeply for the welfare of our race ; and they
                            cry, " Lord, what shall we do to be saved! Give us the bread of life through thine own
                            instrumentality, and we will bless the means." " Only save us from the destructive elements
                            which are sweeping through the land, the effect of raging, unsub dued passions in human
                            souls ; that is all we ask." Such persons are glad to receive the " Shaker and Shakeress,"
                            and make it a wel come messenger to their family circles, anc eel that they are benefited by
                            its moral tone, and are made better by its religious teachings, and heavenly inspirational
                            influence. Many who have sung of the beautiful star hat arose in the eastern hemisphere,
                            which ndicated where the young child might be 'ound, who was to be the medium of the Christ
                            Spirit that was about to visit the earth, now look upon the Shaker and Shakeress as another
                            star, that has appeared in the spiritual lorizon, pointing those who have studied the
                            prophetic periods, and are watching the signs of the times, to the place where the second
                            appearing of the Christ Spirit may be found in a ' cloud of witnessing saints," who testify
                            that " now has come new life and strength," by the power of the Christ manifested through
                            both male and female, and that the gathering of the saints has begun. Such say to us, " Do
                            not let the light of that star go out! by all means let it continue to shine !" Now that we
                            have concluded to extend the publication of the dual sheet through 1874 (if life and
                            strength should be preserved), we solicit contributions from the Sisterhood in every
                            Society, and we ask you to seek, through faith, humility, and prayer, for Divine assistance.
                            We need aid from resurrected spirits, that we may receive inspiration from on high, to
                            enable us to " give meat in due season " to all who are prepared to receive. If we keep our
                            eyes turned toward the Fountain of light and love, we shall receive new supplies of living
                            inspiration, and our understandings will open to new truth, and our spirits will yearn for a
                            growth in an endless life ; and thus we shall be prepared to leave the dead past, and drink
                            of the pure waters of divine revelation, which makes the work of God an ever-living, present
                            work. Let us, my dear Gospel Sisters, rise above selfhood, and, through pure love to truth,
                            and love to human kind, arm ourselves anew for another race. The heavens are full of truth;
                            let us wrestle in spirit to attain thereunto, open our hearts to receive, and stretch forth
                            our hands to grasp the hands of the angels, and they will delight to fill them with pearly
                            gems which are found on the banks of the beautiful river which flows through and gladdens
                            the celestial city, where nothing can enter that is impure, defiling or deceiving Thither
                            let us wend our way, dear Gospe' friends, and by diligence and self-sacrifice, in duce
                            others to join our ranks, and with us journey homeward to the rest of God. We would now
                            speak peace in well-doing to the whole " Household of Faith," and wish all " a happy new
                            year."</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Eldress Antoinette" TEIform="index"/>Dear Eldress Antoinette</head><p TEIform="p">We would say a word to you concerning the " SJmker and ShaJceress." It is a blessing to the
                            woz-ld, and we want it continued ; for it is among the brightest stars that ever shone in
                            the New Heavens, or lighted the New Earth May no dark cloud ever obscure its brilliancy or
                            dim its lustre! Though it was small in its beginning, yet it has thrown great light upon
                            inquiring minds. Believers need it, to guide their feet up the high hills of Truth, and
                            through the greei fields of progression. When the toils of the day are over, we can look
                            upon its pages and find inspiring thoughts and glorious hopes, and are lifted in spirit
                            above the perishable things of time, and feel joy anc rest. It is a comforting Angel! Gospel
                            Truth s written upon its wings of snowy whiteness. '.t is like a beautiful banner of purity
                            waving n the soft breezes of love, which blow from ;he summer land, which lies just beyond.
                            It nust not, shall not fade away ! I send a few thoughts upon " Woman ;" and if you think
                            proper, please give it a little corner in the " Shakeress."</p><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of Woman" TEIform="index"/>THE VOICE OF WOMAN</head><p TEIform="p">In this age of progress, when the sunlight of heaven is shedding its golden rays of
                                divine revelation upon us, and a deep and holy inspiration, from the Eternal Fountain of
                                Goodness and Love, kindles anew the fires of truth in many prepared souls, there is
                                still a voice of lamentation heard in our land. Whence does it proceed ? from the virgin
                                daughters of Zion 1 Ah, nay ! " These are they upon whom the ends of the world have come
                                "— the end of the generative life. It comes from those who have been oppressed by the
                                iron rule of fashion, and public opinion, and held in bondage by old theologies and
                                commands, such as Paul gave in his time : that " women should submit themselves unto
                                their husbands in every tiling — keep silence in the churches,"—and if they really
                                wanted to know any thing, they might "ask their husbands at home." That part of the
                                Scripture text has been remarkably well remembered ; but " Husbands, love your wives as
                                Christ loved the Church, has been little thought of, and less understood and acted upon.
                                Many enlightened females, in this day, are becoming restive under the yoke thus imposed;
                                and are seeking for newly-inspired Apostles, who will give new commandments that will
                                meet the demands of the present age, and give woman power over her own body, and an
                                equal right with man, to think, speak, and act according to the dictates of her own
                                reason and conscience! Error darkens the windows of the soul; and is ever blind to its
                                own weakness and deformity. We now hear the cry " Let there be light!" and let Truth
                                sweep error away, and triumph over every form of evil! Now, the question arises," What
                                is the duty of the daughters of Zion who have fled the house of bondage, and, through
                                the Christ baptism, have found liberty, being no longer ser- vants to sin ? Is it not
                                our duty to hold that liberty sacred, and to use it to help others of our sex to attain
                                to the same condition of freedom ? Let us arise, and, like the good Samaritan of whom we
                                read, reach out the helping hand to aid in the glorious work of emancipating Woman from
                                her present condition of servitude to the lower instincts of her natureLet us proclaim
                                aloud, " There is redemption, for Woman ! " Let us seek, by precept and example, to draw
                                souls away from the paths of sin, which lead down to destruction. Within the past few
                                years, much has been said, and written, concerning the Bights of Woman ; and a variety
                                of opinions exist to-day upon this important subject. I well remember a few remarks that
                                were made by Eldress A. Doolittle, in a Convention held by the Shakers in the city of
                                Boston, in the year 1869, which, in substance, were as follows : " Much is said at the
                                present time about Woman's Eights. There is another question which is to my mind of
                                equal importance, i.e. What are Woman's Duties? According to Bible history, Woman was
                                first in transgression! This, the old story, has been handed down from generation to
                                generation, through the past centuries, until we have become weary of it; and we propose
                                a change. If Woman was the medium, in the beginning, of leading man into sin, let her
                                now become a redemptive agent to lead him out of his fallen condition, up to the higher
                                plane of spiritual life ; and, by our good example, and purifying influence, let us blot
                                out the censure that has so long rested upon our sex." To which we heartily respond,
                                Yea, we have a duty to perform! Let Woman come forth, and act in her proper sphere — the
                                sphere of usefulness, purity, and love — and be what God designed she should be. Let her
                                strip off the garment of pride that she has worn so long, and 5 <pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 6
                                8HAKEE A.ND testify against the evils that are spread broadcast over the land; against
                                the fashions and follies which are so closely interwoven with her existence. Then, she
                                will be able to look with the eye of pity and sympathy upon the erring of her own sex ;
                                and, instead of treating them with coldness and indifference, she will be ready to lift
                                up the fallen,and to remove their worn and tattered garments of ignorance and
                                unrighteousness, and guide them into the straight way, by the cross, which leads to
                                immortal life beyond the shores of time. This is Woman's work ! It is our work, noio,
                                to-day. My Gospel sisters, let us toil early and late, and not be afraid of soiling our
                                hands, if by any means we may win souls to Christ, and help them to find a heavenly
                                parentage, that they may feel a Father's strength and a Mother's love. It is said of
                                Jesus (who was the first to receive the Christ baptism), that lie was tempted in all
                                points like others of our race, Rad was able to succor those who were tempted as he was.
                                And Ann, who was the first baptized daughter of Zion, gained her redemption through
                                tribulation, fasting, prayer,and watch- ing. Let us follow them, and work as they
                                worked; and, like them, depart from all ini- quity. Let us sow the seed of true
                                conviction, and if need be, water it with our tears. Let us enter into the secret
                                chambers of our own hearts, and see that they are clean and pure, fit temples for the
                                indwelling of the Holy Spirit Then we may with confidence pray for suffering humanity,
                                while our feelings are drawn out toward them in sympathy and love. The Gospel of
                                salvation is God's Gift to us ; it is our treasure ; may we keep it pure. Then we shall
                                be ministers of strength to the brotherhood of the " Household of Faith," and be as
                                angels of love to one another. We need the united effort of both brethren and sisters,
                                to carry on the great work that is committed to our keeping. We cannot work alone ; we
                                want the aid of men of God, who are strong in the power of truth; those who are honest,
                                pure, and just ; who are able to defend the right, and bless our earnest efforts. Thank
                                God, we have such in our beautiful Zion, and we claim them as our spiritual fathers and
                                brothers in the glorious work of redemption.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Mary A. Gillespie, Alfred, Me.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shining page of history" TEIform="index"/>A SHINING PAGE OF HISTORY</head><p TEIform="p">I saw a page of history written in words of gold — Truth — and gleaming with the light of the
                            sun — Revelation. Other pages were turned, but none were so lustrous ; some bore the stain
                            of blood — war; some had dark spots—spiritual sins; others were wreathed in chains, implying
                            tyranny and oppression, on others, again, there was light in the beginning, while a cloud
                            overshadowed the close; signifying a commencement in the Spirit, and an ending in the works
                            of darkness. I could not clearly define the reading on the shining page, because of its
                            brightness ; but, was impressed thus. The history of all religions is stamped on the ages,
                            and on humanity. Behold what God hath wrought in this latter day. The organization of
                            Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, purely spiritual, and founded in revelation which
                            arose cotemporary with the free infidel American Government, has stood a century in the
                            rectitude of the undying principles of righteousness and practical religion. Its history is
                            untarnished by any of the unhallowed deeds of vain ambition, gross superstition, or
                            sanctified lust, which have dimmed the lustre of goodness, and set the " mark of the beast"
                            in the forehead of religion, in times past; stifling the sources of inspiration, and binding
                            the consciences of men with priestly power. " The wisdom that cometli from above " has
                            confounded the wise of this world, and brought to naught the understanding of the savants of
                            earth, through the mediumship of an unlettered woman, whose soul drank in the inspiration of
                            the heavens, until it was divinely illumined, whose spirit was uplifted to the Christ
                            sphere, where she was imbued with a baptism of God's love, which is fire to evil, and which
                            led her to confess and forsake sin, regenerating her life through the agony of death ; thus
                            preparing her to come forth, clad in the armor of righteousness, with the breastplate of
                            truth, to bear a testimony so powerful that it has shaken the foundations of the old heavens
                            — false theology, the pompous mockery of religion ; and the old earth — the Adamic life in
                            man and woman ; supplanting these with the foundations of a new Order — with virgin purity
                            (the Christ life) as the basic principle, on which shall be reared the glorious structure of
                            the Second Christian Temple. Behold the consummating work of God's perfective plan for the
                            redemption of mankind, turning the powers of mind and soul into channels of divine thought
                            and lofty aspiration. Thus is His Spirit (through His appointed mediatorial agencies) acting
                            on the souls of honest men and women, who drink in the Christ testimony, in its second
                            unfoldment, " as the thirsty ox drinketh water." Such are the virgins, standing on a sea of
                            glass," the white " cloud of witnesses " who testify of the efficacy of the work of God in
                            the " latter day." They worship neither man nor woman, but the attributive principles which
                            constitute Deity — the Eternal Father and Mother of all intelligences. Their toil is
                            worship, because consecrated to the good of the greatest number, and performed in the
                            high-toned spirit of Christian love, which redounds with blessing to the Giver. Their altar
                            of prayer is the hallowed sanctum of the heart, where faith supplicates, hope inspires, and
                            conscience rules. Their strength in unity is goodness. Their pledge of honor, truthfulness
                            of word and action. In daily duty, Progress is the watchword. No formal creed, with bolts
                            and bars, confine the soul within the narrow limits of sectarian dogmatism ; but broad as
                            the universe of our beneficent Creator, so lie the unexplored fields of scientific and
                            spiritual truth, which stand in harmonious relation one with the other. Search for the
                            diamonds and gold ; bring hither the sparkling gems of wisdom and knowledge; for the Lord's
                            Temple shall be the conservatory of all good, and His people shall be a praise in the earth,
                            because of the righteousness and purity maintained in their lives.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gratitude" TEIform="index"/>GRATITUDE</head><p TEIform="p">We thank Thee, Holy Father, Thou Source of love divine, For all Thy Gospel givings, Which
                            worldly joys outshine ;— Our Fathers and our Mothers, * Who kindly for us care ; Good
                            Sisters and good Brothers, Whose sympathy we share ; Pure bonds of Christian friendship,
                            Which ne'er can broken be, Deep wells of pure affection, And sweets of liberty ; A blessed
                            home of beauty, Where peace and plenty reign — A hundred fold of substance — Industry's
                            honest gain; A golden cross to carry, In mercy handed down From Christ, through Ann and
                            Jesus, By which to win the crown ; The fires celestial kindled, To burn within our breast,
                            Till, through Thine own appointment, We find supernal rest; TJntil we reach the fountain Of
                            Thy redeeming love, Which floweth down the mountain, From out Thy throne above. For all Thy
                            gracious givings, While here in time we live, In fullest consecration Our hearts to Thee we
                            give.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The social evil, as a public question..." TEIform="index"/>The social evil, as a public question...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Social Evil, as a public question, has submitted itself to legal adjudication in St.
                            Louis. The decision contains the following correct sentiments by Judge Calvin: "The judge
                            says further, it is a special law in its application to but one sex and not to both sexes.
                            In this it is against the spirit of the Bill of Rights. The law should operate uniformly.
                            The offense charged in the information cpuld not be, if the other sex were not participants
                            in it. It is unjust and unfair that of the parties to the offense one should be required to
                            conform to multitudinous and grievous and burdensome regulations, while the oth er party
                            does not even receive a tacit recognition."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman clothed with the sun" TEIform="index"/>"A WOMAN CLOTHED WITH THE SUN." (Kev. xii.)</head><p TEIform="p">As my eye glances eagerly over the precious outbreathings of the last S. and S. how grate-
                            ful I feel for the truthful thoughts on " Sunlight." Truthful, because they commend
                            themselves to our reason, our knowledge of science, our experience, our intuitions, and
                            last, but not least, to our own inspirations, as well as those of the Scriptures. For it
                            would seem that the Prophets and Apostles of the past, from their oft-repeated allusions,
                            understood and acknowledged the powerfully-curative influences of sun-light. The truths of
                            religion are compared to light, sun-rising ; and one of the Prophets foretells, " But unto
                            you that fear my name (or that dare not violate my natural laws) shall the Sun of
                            Righteousness arise with healing in his beams; and ye shall grow up as calves of the stall."
                            As the light of the natural sun pierces into the dark and chilly abodes of earth, it cheers,
                            invigorates, and tones up the circulation, making even the desponding feel that life is not
                            so bad after all; and one more effort must be made. Even so, when the rays from " the Sun of
                            Righteousness" begin to penetrate the crust of worldliness and sin, which, like a damp vapor
                            or chill, has kept the eyes from seeing, and the heart from feeling, the warm and salutary
                            influences from the spiritual Sun ; then each dormant germ of love and goodness responds to
                            the quickening and vivifying influences, and, starting in the spiritual life, begins to put
                            on conditions of growth. And, when they become awakened to see and feel the love from that
                            blessed Mother who is represented as " the woman clothed with" the warmth and glory of " the
                            Sun," and that when like her the moon (and works of darkness) are under their feet, they too
                            can become conquerors, and have dominion over themselves ; and their crowns will manifest
                            the progress they have attained in the Christian virtues. And, as their victory becomes more
                            complete, and these twelve stars shine more brightly, they find that this power with which
                            they become clothed, heals them from their earth wounds, and gives them "joy for the spirit
                            of heaviness;" and they would fain live and bathe in the invigorating influences of not only
                            the spiritual Sun, but its most fitting representative in the natural heavens. As the aches
                            and pains of the body vanish away under its rays, and life becomes healthy, labor ceases to
                            be a burden, self-denial seems easy, cares and burdens vanish, and, with the Psalmist, we
                            exclaim, truly, " Light is sown for the righteous, and gladness for the upright in heart! "
                            While no forces in Nature are so potent for growth in use and beauty, so are none so sweet,
                            so silent, and withal so powerful, as those represented by the loving, feminine attributes
                            of Deity, as unveiled in the Revelator's thrilling vision of the maternity of the two
                            manifestations of the Christ Spirit,through " the woman clothed with the sun." And that
                            through her painful travail, and repeated persecutions, the Christ manifestations have found
                            access to mortals, we will ever rejoice; for " now is come salvation, and strength, and the
                            kingdom of our God, and the power of his Christ;" and " whosoever will" may take of these
                            saving influences freely. Thanks, then, for the blessed sunlight, with its healing and
                            consoling magnetisms, so significant of the powers of good, in banishing the sins and wrongs
                            of the past, and the darkness of superstition, with the gloom of ignorance and oppression.
                            And may it never be said of any of us, that " this is our condemnation that light has come
                            into the world, but we chose darkness rather than light, because our deeds were evil," and
                            would not bear the searching light of the full-orbed Sun of day. May we ever be " children
                            of the light," walking and toiling, speaking and breathing, in the light, that the image of
                            our heavenly Parents may shine in us, even the " Sun of Righteousness," and his purified
                            Bride, all " glorious within."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>SELF SACRIFICE</head><p TEIform="p">I love to reflect upon the deeds of noble selfsacrificing souls, both in the past, and at the
                            present time ; those who have not counted, and who do not count, their lives dear unto them,
                            nor fear the bitter envy, scorn, and contempt of the masses, if by any means they can uplift
                            humanity in the scale of moral purity, and spiritual truth. Such see many evils afar off,
                            and seek to evade, or fend off their direful influence ; and they give their minds to search
                            out the causes which create unhappy conditions, and strive to remove them, that the effects
                            may cease ; and they willingly endure hardship and toil while they keep the one object in
                            view. Although war is unchristian, and belongs to savage tribes (if anywhere), yet I often
                            think of those who struggled to free America from British rule, that there might be one
                            place on this broad earth sacred to liberty, where all nations, kindreds, and colors, might
                            worship God, after this or that manner, as seemed right to them; and I bless the motives
                            which prompted them to action; while conscience, and all the better feelings of my nature,
                            recoil at the means used to accomplish so desirable a result. I love to think of our pilgrim
                            fathers who endured persecution even unto death, rather than violate the truths which were
                            committed to their charge in that day ; how they wandered from mountain to mountain, through
                            dark forests, footsore and weary, the cold clods of earth their couch, the starry heavens
                            their canopy, and the wild beasts their watchers. I honor the Menonites, the Quakers, and
                            the early Methodists, for their self-sacrifice and devotion to principle ; for it was the
                            love of God in their souls which prompted them to hold the truth more sacred than their
                            physical lives, or creaturely comforts. They were once known by plainness of dress and
                            manners, and trueness of life. Where shall we look to find them now 1 Where are the
                            suffering martyrs of to-day, who count the truth of more value than worldly honor, riches,
                            carnal pleasure, and self-indulgence ? Is the martyr spirit dead ? or does it only sleep, to
                            awaken again with renewed energy ? As we come down to the Believers in Christ's Second
                            Appearing, what a noble band of self-sacrificing souls were the pioneers in this work ! and
                            what mental labor and soul struggles they passed through! In tears and strong supplication,
                            they sought for wisdom from on high, to aid them in laying a foundation for the Second
                            Christian Temple, so deep and strong, that neither the winds of false the- ologies, nor the
                            vile passions of men, could ever undermine and overthrow it; and, at the same time, to have
                            it broad enough to admit of an endless increase of all that is true and good. They endured
                            physical, mental, and spiritual suffering, that God might be honored, Truth progressed, and
                            human souls uplifted from moral degradation, and spiritual death, caused by transgression.
                            They did the work of their day nobly, and have gone to their reward in the heavens. Angels
                            bless their labors, and many honest truth-loving souls, who have built upon the foundation
                            of Gospel law and order, which they laid, by the assistance of Divine Wisdom and Love from
                            the high heavens, honor them, and praise their good deeds, while they give glory to God,
                            with hearts abounding in love and thanks. Are we as prepared to give our strength, time, and
                            talents, as freely in our day, and to do and suffer, according to our ability, as they were
                            ? This is a question that all should earnestly put to their own consciences. Shall we be
                            willing to subsist upon the labors of others, without striving to render an equivalent
                            therefor, and to put forth our strongest and best efforts to do something for others ? If
                            so, we shall prove ourselves unworthy, and unprofitable servants in the Lord's vineyard.
                            They who seek to occupy an easy chair to-day, expose themselves to be driven by the winds of
                            adversity to-morrow. If we would wear the laurels of immortal renown, such as purified
                            spirits in the heavenly spheres are constantly weaving into glorious crowns that will not
                            fade or tarnish, then, let us work ; work with the Angels, and with all the good and true in
                            the earth sphere. Let us bless every true reform, and encourage every sincere worker in that
                            field, while we ourselves remain careful to keep the clear line of demarkation and
                            separation between the generative order and life, and the angelic life, which belongs to the
                            resurrection order.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pattison, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/>Margaret Pattison, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the 'Shakeress'" TEIform="index"/>FOR THE "SHAKERESS."</head><p TEIform="p">When I was a child of but eleven years of age, I was taken from the outside world and placed
                            with Believers (or Shakers), where I found spiritual parents and guides, and I learned to
                            understand the meaning of the Apostle's words, " Children, obey your parents in the Lord,
                            for this is right." When I was wayward, my good mothers reproved me kindly, and told me " to
                            go and sin no more ;" and I obeyed through love, not through fear. They faithfully
                            instructed me to resist all temptation to seek pleasure through sensual appetites, and
                            warned me not to set my affections upon the perishable riches of this world, but to seek the
                            durable riches of the kingdom of Christ, and to lay up treasures in heaven, and seek those
                            joys that are found at God's right hand, which will never fail. They taught the necessity of
                            imitating the example of our Saviour, and to remember his words, " I am the light of the
                            world : he that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of life."
                            Although I was placed under the guardianship of kind friends, and received much good
                            instruction, yet I was left to be tried, and to feel what there was in my own heart. My
                            youthful mind (as I became older) was tempted, through passion for worldly plea- sure, to
                            look for a more pliant way than the one marked out by Jesus of Nazareth. I turned my
                            thoughts toward the broad road of sinful pleasure and looked to see what was to be found and
                            enjoyed there ; and I saw that all that could be obtained from that source was but
                            momentary, and ended in disappointment. And God (through the medium of my conscience)
                            forbade that I should renounce a life of virgin purity, and leave " an hundred-fold of
                            fathers and mothers, and brothers and sisters, and numerous other blessings, for a dish of
                            pottage." I reflected upon the superior advantages for physical health, and the comforts to
                            be derived therefrom ; also of the kind care bestowed in sickness, and of the beautiful
                            surroundings in my Gospel home — of living in companionship with kind loving brethren and
                            sisters, ever forbearing and forgiving, and who were cleanly in their habits of life. It is
                            said that " cleanliness is next to godliness," and I think we may add that there is very
                            little true godliness without it. " O! then I gazed upon my peaceful cot, Where the clement
                            bowers entwine ; The land of the strangers tempted me not— O nay ! nor could their home be
                            mine." Then I turned my eyes and thoughts, and came to the conclusion, that the most excel-
                            lent and honorable character that any one can form, is by resisting temptation to evil,
                            practising virtue, and shunning vice, and by consecrating all his or her powers to honor
                            God, by living honestly, justly, and truly. Those who seek to be shielded from temptation,
                            and for protection from sin, feel that it is a privilege and blessing to be retired from the
                            multitude who throng the broad road, and from the society of those who seek pleasure in
                            unrighteousness. A truly religious life is not fraught with gloom and sadness ; nor does it
                            deprive us of enjoyment in this present state of existence. If we learn to use the things of
                            this world, and not abuse them, we shall find that " pure and undefiled religion" will
                            enhance, not diminish, our happiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lyman, Amelia" TEIform="persName"/>Amelia Lyman, Enfield, Conn. </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us, like Moses, choose the wiser part..." TEIform="index"/>Let us, like Moses, choose the wiser part...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Let us, like Moses, choose the wiser part, Willing to suffer with the good and pure, Rather
                            than sin, and thus corrupt the heart, By grasping pleasures which cannot endure.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Calver, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poor" TEIform="index"/>THE POOR</head><p TEIform="p">" The poor ye have always with you," said Jesus. As the cold, bleak winds of winter are
                            howling about our dwellings, and we gather into our comfortable apartments, made so by the
                            consecrated labors of our predecessors in the Gospel work, coupled with the toils of many
                            who are still with us, how appropriate it is for us to reflect upon the condition of
                            thousands of our fellow-beings who are as good by nature, and perhaps as sincerely desiring
                            to please God (according to their conception of right) as ourselves, and who are filled with
                            dismay at the prospect before them of not being able to meet the inclemency of the winter
                            that has opened upon us with such severity. There are strong forebodings of suffering among
                            the poorer classes, in consequence of the recent financial crisis, which has thrown many
                            honest laborers out of employment, and which is, more or less, affecting all departments of
                            business. What an opportunity is now offered for the exercise of Christian charity, that
                            most precious of all Gospel virtues. Many are destitute of suitable clothing, and are
                            without the means to procure fuel to make them comfortable, while others are not even
                            sheltered from the piercing blasts so keenly felt by the homeless wanderer. How sad the
                            reflection that so many human beings (who are brought into existence without their own
                            volition), who are forced by circumstances over which they have no control, to eke out a
                            miserable life of suffering and want, only now and then receiving temporary alleviation. Nor
                            is this all; degradation and crime frequently follow in the wake of those who are destitute
                            of the means of subsistence ; for it has been said truly, that " hunger is a sharp thorn ; "
                            and, under such circumstances, temptation to sin is very great. The prayer of Agur, recorded
                            in Scripture, was dictated in wisdom : " Give me neither riches nor poverty, but feed me
                            with food convenient for me, lest I be full, and deny thee, and say,' Who is the Lord ?' or
                            I become poor, and steal, and take the name of God in vain." Would it not be well for those
                            who are rolling in affluence and luxury to pause, amid their lavish expenditures, and
                            remember the words of the Saviour : " The poor ye have always with you." And again, "
                            Inasmuch as ye have ministered unto the necessities of the least of these little ones, ye
                            have ministered unto me."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda R." TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda R. Hollister, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reward of sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>THE REWARD OF SACRIFICE</head><p TEIform="p">God will lead forth to fountains pure, And robe in love divine, The souls that follow Christ
                            in truth And all to Him resign. He will uphold the constant mind, Through envy's fiery
                            darts, And spread before the valiant soul The rest that faith imparts. He will uproot the
                            strange, wild vine, And sow the precious seed, That Christ may keep, and angels bless In
                            truth and very deed. And He will raise an ensign high Above the false and vain, And call the
                            honest and sincere Its glory to sustain. For them a house He will create, With treasures
                            rich and rare, Which shall have power to elevate And bless each loyal heir. And, when they
                            pass from death to life, New prospects shall appear; And they shall walk the golden streets
                            With kindred spirits dear. And He will place within each breast The snow-white dove of
                            peace, And safe shall be their heritage Whose joys shall never cease. He'll cause them there
                            in strength to grow. And bloom in endless light, Where seraphs and bright angels meet With
                            anthems of delight.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Maynard, Betsy F." TEIform="persName"/>Betsy F. Maynard, Harvard, Mass. </byline></div2><pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Glad new year" TEIform="index"/>THE GLAD NEW YEAR!</head><p TEIform="p">mp 1. A long the shadowy aisles of time, there floats a murmur soft and low, Now swelling in
                            harmonious chime, sweet notes in measured numbers flow. With joy we catch the glad some
                            strain, which fills our hearts with loving cheer, 2. 4. Our hopes on starry pinions rise.
                            High aspiration thrills our soul, We tread the vale of time and sense, Amid its phantom
                            fleeting dreams, A nobler life to realize, Ascending to perfection's goal. Still longing,
                            with a hope intense. For something that enduring seems; The past with joy and sorrow
                            fraught, Shall from our vision disappear; Yet duty's path we will pursue, Without a doubt or
                            cringing fear; The present claims our earnest thought: All hail the bright, the Glad New
                            Year! With lofty aim and purpose true, We'll toil throughout the Glad New Year ! 3. 5. Like
                            angels from the realms unseen, Light-wing'd the moments come and go, The tender cords of
                            purest love, With peace entwined, shall stronger grow; The shining links of life, between
                            Ethereal spheres and earth below; We'll bear the spirit of the dove. And kindness to the
                            erring show. They bear a record of the deeds That cloud, or make our pathway clear : With
                            gentle words, and Christ-like deeds, A monument of good we'll rear; Broadcast they sow
                            time's precious seeds, And usher in the Glad New Year! While bliss, that fills our spirit
                            needs, Awaits us in the Glad New Year</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><p TEIform="p">With magic key, he comes to ope Another realm for us to tread ; He bears the shining lamp of
                            hope ; A crown of stars is on his head. All silently the crystal gate Swings forward on the
                            field of snow; We enter, as by power of fate, And list its closing, soft and low. The bridge
                            of ice that spann'd the moat Is drawn up on the other side ; For us there is no ferrying
                            boat, No backward wave on which to glide; But footprints even now are seen ; Time waits not
                            for the tardy feet, But onward speed*, to valleys green, To bloom of spring, and summer's
                            heat. Then to the rainbow of the land — The season born of sun and frost — Whose
                            half-bewild'ring glories stand Like sunset clouds on nature toss'd. But nought alluring can
                            prevail; Though flaming leaves his pathway strew, He presses for the snowy vale, Where once
                            again his life is new. And, as we contemplate his round, And view the miracles that rise,
                            Rich lessons by our souls are found, That we may keep, to make us wise. The year expires
                            upon the snow, And on the snow its life begins ; And, when we leave the life below, How
                            slight the change the transit wins. It is for us to work, and bear Against the curse that
                            bringeth death ; It is for us to gain and share The pow'r of the Almighty's breath. That
                            pow'r that made a living soul Of him who was a mass of clay, Is needed, like the winds, to
                            roll Upon humanity to-day. By revelation's light we read The grand old myths, and draw their
                            worth See God hath sown the spirit-seed Through all the nations of the earth. O that each
                            heart might but unfold, And let its hidden good appear: The treasured joy, all unforetold,
                            Would crown and bless this true New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon </byline></div2><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">NOVITIATE ELDERS AND ELDRESSES. Elder F. W. Evans................ " Q. A. Lnmas..............
                            " C. O. Reed ................ " Simon Mahee ............. " H.S.Kellogg.............. " A.
                            J. Battles............... " Wm. Leonard ............. " H. Taber.................. " Henry
                            Cummings.......... " B.H. Smith................ " J. B. Vance.............. " Nehemiah
                            Trull............ " J. S. Prescott .............. " Isaac Beats......... ...... " Jacob
                            Kulp............... " John B. Cooper............. " Ezra Sherman.............. " Stephen
                            Ball............... Post-office Address. Mt. Lebanon, Columbia county, N. Y Shakers, Albany
                            county, N. Y........, Sonyea, Livingston county, N. Y...... West Pittsfield,
                            Mass.................., Thompsonville, Conn................. South Lee,
                            Mass....................., Aver, Mass............................. Shirley Village,
                            Mass.................. Enfield, N. H............................ Shaker Village, N.
                            H................... Alfred, Me............................ West Gloucester,
                            Me.................. Cleveland (Shakers), O.............. Lebanon (Shakers),
                            O.................. Pleasant Hill, Ky..................... South Union,
                            Ky...................... Preston, Hamilton county, O........ Dayton (Shakers),
                            O................... Eldresses. Eldress Antoinette Doolittle. " Harriet M. Bullard. "
                            Abigail Crosman. Betsey Sneydon. Anna Ervin. Harriet Storer. Nancy Fairbanks. Lucretia
                            Godfrey. Hannah Taylor. Harriet March. Eliza Smith. Hannah Davis. Prudence Sawyer. Susannah
                            Farnham. Betsy Spalding. Sarah Small. Betsy Q. Gass. Adaline Wills. The Evangelical Alliance
                            was formed in London in 1846. It has held five conferences previous to the present gathering
                            at New York, the last being at Amsterdam, in 1867. The following nine propositions
                            constitute its platform, which would be simply absurd, or worse, for any Unitarian or
                            Universalist to pretend to accept: — "1. The divine inspiration, authority, and suffi-
                            ciency of the Holy Scriptures. " 2. The right and duty of private judgment in the
                            interpretation of the Holy Scriptures. " 3. The unity of the Godhead and the trinity of the
                            persons therein. " 4. The utter depravity of human nature in consequence of the fall. "5.
                            The incarnation of the Son of God, his work of atonement for the sins of mankind, and his
                            mediatorial intercession and reign. "6. The justification of the sinner by faith alone. " 7.
                            The work of the Holy Spirit in the conversion and sanctification of the sinner. "8. The
                            immortality of the soul, the resurrection of the body, the judgment of the world by our Lord
                            Jesus Christ, with the eternal blessedness of the righteous, and the eternal punishment of
                            the wicked. "9. The divine institution of the Christian ministry, and the obligation and
                            perpetuity of the ordinances of Baptism and the Lord's Supper. There was a quiet little
                            election in the town of Bushnell, 111., a few days ago, to obtain an expression of the
                            wishes of the citizens for or against licenses for the sale of intoxicating liquor, and the
                            Judges decided that as it was desirable to obtain the general sentiment, they would receive
                            the votes of the women also. This being made known, 125 ladies assembled at the Methodist
                            Episcopal Church, and thence marched to the polls and deposited their ballots unanimously
                            against license. The vote of the town was strong the same way.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curtis, George" TEIform="index"/>George Curtis
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Curtis, George" TEIform="persName">George Curtis</persName>, aged 67, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                                Nov. 23d.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Howell, Lucy Landon" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Landon Howell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Howell, Lucy Landon" TEIform="persName">Lucy Landon Howell</persName>, aged 97, at Alfred,
                                Me. Nov. 28th. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salisbury, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Salisbury
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Salisbury, Olive" TEIform="persName">Olive Salisbury</persName>, aged 79, at Mt. Lebanon, N.
                                Y. Dec. 5th. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Offord, Rhoda" TEIform="index"/>Rhoda Offord
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Offord, Rhoda" TEIform="persName">Rhoda Offord</persName>, aged 34, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                                Dec. 10th. Elders. </p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>