<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1008" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18800801" TEIform="date">August 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">165-192</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
	                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> AUGUST; 1880. MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY.
                        "And they shall turn to you for a testimony. '"Go fir each the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The
                        Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880. The Shaker Vol. X. No. 8. 60 Cents Per Annum </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>--><pb n="169" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                   <div2 type="note">
                        <p> THE Shaker Manifesto. CONTENTS. page. ¦ page. Spiritual Communications, - - - - 169 Book Notices, - - 185
                            Recipes for Making and Keeping Friends, - 170 Society Record, - - - - - - 186 The Condition of Europe, - - -
                            -172 Agricultural, - - - - - 188 The Lamp of Experience, - ... 174 Lend a Hand,......187 Vision.—No. I, - - - -
                            - - 175 Our Elder Brother, - - 187 Who Holds the Keys ? - - 176 Success in Life, - 188 Truth, - - - - - - -
                            178 Rulings or " The Golden Rule," 188 The Iconoclast, - - - - ¦ - 178 Music: Eulogy upon a Shaker, - - - - -
                            179 The Bright Hope Star. - - - ' - 189 A Philosopher's Religion, 179 The Children's Grotto, • - - - - 190
                            Correspondence, - - - - - - 181 Home Topics, - - - - - 191 Editorial: The Theology of the Heart, - - 192 What
                            was He? - 183 Let these Things be Corrected, - - - 192 Editorial Notes, - - - - - - 184 Vol. X. AUGUST,
                            1880. No. 8. </p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual communications, their character, quality, what governs them" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL COMMUNICATIONS. Their Character — Quality — What Governs Them.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/> GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Disappointments and astonishments often occur with those who consult spiritual media, or
                            listen to their communications, because of a lack of knowledge relative to the manner in
                            which media are impressed or inspired, and the sources of their information and inspiration.
                            Media are sensitive spirits, whether in the mortal or immortal form, and those in mortal
                            form are, oft times, as really inspired by those in the body as those in spirit realms. As
                            there is a scent transmitted from the living animal to the soil on which it treads, which is
                            sufficiently manifest to be recognized by the acute olfactory nerves in the dog, even so
                            there is a magnetism,a spiritual aura transmitted by every intelligent being, to every thing
                            with which they contact, and this, is sufficiently powerful that very sensitive
                            intelligences, as many spiritual media are, can and do realize it, and thereby read not only
                            the character and condition of the being transmitting the magnetism and aura, but oft times,
                            their thoughts, desires, convictions and spiritual vitality or inertness ; their power for
                            either good or evil. It is by this avenue of communication and this acute sense of
                            perception that media derive and receive inspirations, and in accordance with the quality of
                            which the character of their communications is manifest. It is thus that, spiritual media
                            (who by the mass of mankind believing in them at all) are supposed to be always inspired by
                            spirits in the spirit world, are yet often simply inspired by persons in this world, and
                            those especially with whom they are in association, communication; whether by simple
                            presence, by verbal or witten correspondence, or by sympathetic spiritual affinity of
                            condition. It is thus, through the exercise and culture of this wonderful sensibility to
                            magnetic and spirit aura (the culture of which is attained by giving minute attention to its
                            tenderest manifestations), that media, like A. J. Davis, Mansfield, Denton, and hosts of
                            others, read the questions propounded to them in sealed envelopes, without ever breaking
                            their seals; read books thousands of miles distani, never seen by their mortal eyes, of
                            which there are thousands of well authenticated instances, as demonstrable facts,
                            notwithstanding the incredulity of unbelievers and the inexperienced. <pb n="170" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            170 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. And, often, the answers to those questions are simply the
                            opinions, and according to the desires of the persons presenting the questions, as their
                            spirit aura, or impress, is the strongest upon the medium. Again, the idea entertained by
                            the myriads of China, Asia, India and Hindostan, that every person in this world is attended
                            by a special guardian spirit finds a vast support in modern revelation. Pythagoras and
                            Socrates both claimed to have a, heavenly guide, to whom they owed their safety. The Shakers
                            have been conscious of this guardianship for very pany years. Hence, media for spiritual
                            communications at times supposed themselves to be influenced by a particular spirit, who has
                            been their control of influence, and with whom they are most familiar in a state of
                            impressibility, when, occasionally, the fact is, such media are at times inspired and
                            controlled simply by some one or more of the persons surrounding them in the body, or the
                            one who wrote the sealed communication they hold in their hands, presented for rejoinder.
                            The sense of touch in the fingers of the human frame in very sensitive media is so very
                            delicate that it receives the magnetism or spirit aura transmitted by the writer to the
                            paper on which a communication is written, or by the grasp of the hand of the person
                            present, and communicates it to the brain of the medium, thus revealing to him the thoughts
                            and feelings of the communicant as really as the eye transmits ideas and spiritual
                            impressions by the sense of sight, or the ear by the sense of hearing. There are, also,
                            other senses possessed by human beings more subtle than the five, ordinarily ascribed to
                            humanity; senses answering to the use of sight without physical eyes ; hearing without
                            material ears, and feeling without animal nerves. These are the senses which, when highly
                            developed, detect the subtle aura transmitted from living beings even to inanimate
                            substances with which they come in contact, as really as animate creation, though not as
                            abundantly. It is by the use of these senses that media can read the incidents in the life's
                            history of persons whom they never knew ; tell of incidents in human history transpiring in
                            distant countries and climes at the moment of their advent, and prophesy of the future by
                            vivid perception of a chain of unavoida" ble causes and consequences, though beyond the
                            recognition of ordinary sensibilities. These characteristic qualifications constitute the
                            real ipseity of humanity ; they are soul faculties, deeper than sense, and are the auditors
                            of voices from beyond this world. They constitute the ever living man, the conscious
                            possessor, user and conservator of most real sensibilities unknown to the gross materialists
                            ; they open a highway to worlds where truth is the path of progress to wisdom, unclogged by
                            material obstacles, and where the good and true of humanity have an eternal home of glory,
                            and drink from ceaselessly flowing fountains of inspiration, the union and intelligence of
                            kindred spirits in spheres above earth. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Recipes, for making and keeping friends" TEIform="index"/> RECIPES, For Making and Keeping
                            Friends</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/> AMELIA J. CALVER</byline><p TEIform="p">What is the end and aim of life? What is the earliest thought of childhood, the chief
                            aspiration of mature years, and the clinging hope of enfeebled age ? Is it not happiness ?
                            and in all the world where do we look for such a treasure, in its truest deepest colors,
                            other than in the claims of true friendship. Has it not been proved that real friends can be
                            substituted for almost every blessing in life ? Has not the loss of health, wealth, and
                            freedom, been cheerfully endured, by the presence of this inestimable boon ? Then with what
                            eager watchfulness should we study, first to gather and then to 'hold in possession such
                            priceless treasure. In almost every book and periodical, we find in particular detail,
                            recipes for making nearly every thing, from a piece of toast, to the most intricate mixture
                            in alchemy's list; and yet how surprisingly few, are the real valuable receipts, on the art
                            of making and keeping friends. <pb n="171" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 171 We often hear
                            the remark that a friend without fault cannot be found; thus consoled we sit passively,
                            claiming the excuse for ourselves, each one admitting that since we cannot be perfect in
                            this world, if people wish to love us they must take us as we are ; and thus the rough spots
                            are suffered to remain. There is so much of the present tense flattery, so much policy
                            friendship in this world of selfishness and fashion, that to the, real sensitive mind it
                            seems hardly safe to trust any ; while if the subject was given a thoughtful study, all
                            would have in possession ingredients for making themselves the richest boon of earth life.
                            It has always been deemed unsafe for intimate friends to make the study of one another
                            openly ; for it is so natural to enshrine " self," in a sanctum sanctorum, and to look upon
                            every one treading there as an intruder ; and of so trifling account are our disagreable
                            ways (to ourselves) that it seems petty to discuss them. Yet these very little foxes are the
                            greatest spoilers of the entwining" vine of friendship. How then are we to find these little
                            foxes, if we do not wish even our dearest friends to tread in our vineyard; and as a reply
                            comes in a most valuable command : " study thyself." It is certainly one of the greatest
                            evidences of the efficacy and perfection of virtue, to be aware of its lack so quickly in
                            others. "It happens I know not how," said Cicero, " but whenever a thing is wrong, we see it
                            much sooner in others than in ourselves." The child reproved for a fault, which reproof it
                            ardently resents, will turn in a few moments and chide another for the same fault, as though
                            it was itself the embodiment of perfection. In making receipts for puddings and pies, we
                            generally name the necessary ingredients ; here we reverse, as we find it far easier to tell
                            what to avoid ; therefore, (1) Never attempt to catch a friend by flattery, the cord is
                            entirely too slippery. (2) It is dangerous to endeavor to win favor, or climb into
                            estimation on the wreck and ruin of character which you have destroyed by slander; for time
                            will soon crumble you with the ruins on which you build. Those who sacrifice principle to
                            party will sooner or later find themselves minus of both. (3) "If you wish a true friend be
                            one yourself." (4) Be very careful to avoid in yourself what you dislike in others;
                            remembering " If each one would mend one, all would soon be mended." (5) It is impossible in
                            this world of differences, to prefer all alike, therefore if you have a circle of choice
                            friends, it ought to be the means of ameliorating your conduct toward every one ;
                            remembering that all are somebody's friends, who wish them well treated. (6) Be very careful
                            in your conversation ; for an agreeable talker has a good 'foundation for making many
                            friends. Watch a friend closely to see if your talk pleases ; " if you should tire him once
                            he will ever afterward be afraid to listen to you. (7) Avoid both extremes; that of prying
                            into others business, or engrossing the wholeconversation, in talking of yourself ; remember
                            " If you your ears would save from jeers, Five tnings keep wisely hid ; Myself and 1, and
                            mine and my, And what 1 said and did." (8) Never interrupt a person while speaking ;¦ but
                            let each one have an opportunity of finishing their sentence, before you break in upon
                            them.. This is not only essential to friendship but good manners also. (9) Endeavor to tax
                            your memory enough not to repeat the same story in the same company many times. (10) Always
                            try to be interested in whatever pleases another ; this you will find to be the beautiful
                            charm of agreeable people, while to treat with scorn or indifference the enthusiasm of a
                            friend is a most bitter insult. (11) Never try to make your friend a reservoir for the
                            disagreeable feelings you hold against others ; lest they, finding themselves forced into
                            unpleasantness, choose to keep aloof. <pb n="172" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 172 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. True
                            friendship can only be preserved by sweetness ; that which it takes a pickle to preserve is
                            neither salutary nor pleasant. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Condition of Europe" TEIform="index"/>THE CONDITION OF EUROPE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer" TEIform="persName"/> DANIEL FRAZER</byline><p TEIform="p">During the Feudal era, Europe was covered with petty principalities ; their chieftains
                            assumed almost absolute power. When that system broke up, the chieftains confederated
                            —forming the present governments of Europe ; they had no idea of admitting the people to
                            participate in forming laws, etc. Hence the governments of Europe to-day are but
                            conglomerates of nobles, representing but themselves. The representation of the whole people
                            is being driven very slowly into their compacts. Nevertheless, as long as these nobles (so
                            called) are great land-holders, they will continue to hold the resources and forces of their
                            respective governments. The Queen of England represents but the interests of great
                            land-holders. Hence the state of Europe can be best shown by illustrating an integral part
                            of any of these governments For this purpose the Duke of Argyle is selected. He is accepted
                            as a very respectable man and as the descendant of the chiefs of a clan — tribe of Scotch
                            Highlanders — called "the Campbells." He lives at Inverara, about fifty miles from the city
                            of Glasgow. His son, as Viceroy, represents,on this continent, these confederated
                            land-holders. Like our Indian tribes, " the Campbells " were warriors and made raids on
                            their neighbors and took their lands. Hence the Duke is a great land-holder. As the Feudal
                            system disappeared, he secured to himself the possession of the tribal lands. And so secure
                            is he, that should a descendant of the people of his tribe go and take possession of a
                            needful portion of the land of his fathers, and build a cottage in one of the cozy dells of
                            Inverara, pasture a few sheep, and do a little fishing, the Duke would drive him off. And if
                            not strong enough,he has only to tell the Queen and her Christian majesty would promptly
                            send him all the fixed bayonets he may want. The Duke has got matters nicely arranged, lie
                            goes to London to support her Majesty's government—to support himself in holding all the
                            tribal lands. And when in office, yets paid for doing Jiis own work; and the landless
                            children of all the tribes are taxed to pay the Duke's salary ; and, also, the soldiers who
                            keep him in possession of said lands, fishing grounds, minerals and social position. These
                            confederate governments are true to their integral forces ; the Duke acquired property by
                            predatory incursions ; the Queen by the same means has acquired an empire in India, and she
                            is now fighting for more land there. During a serious up-rising in that empire, even the
                            Duke's battle cry was heard, "The Campbells are coming! 0! ho ! 0 ! ho !" and a sad " 0 ! ho
                            ! " it was to the people of India. As the Feudal form of the social gave way, the people
                            continued their pastoral and fishing industries ; as the chiefs had been supported, the
                            people continued to do so. By and by these great land-holders found that sheep were more
                            desirable than the presence of men having as much right to the land as themselves had.
                            Thereupon wholesale evictions took place; extensive tracts of land have been thus
                            depopulated, and the dwellings of the people leveled to the ground. The poor, warm-hearted
                            high landers as they left their homes and were losing sight forever of the mountain tops of
                            the land of their nativity would raise a mournful dirge, " Loughaber no more," as did the
                            Israelites of old when despoiled of their lands and driven into captivity. To support these
                            European governments in their oppressions, to make incursive wars and to protect themselves
                            against the assaults of the landless multitudes, huge armies are employed. This has been
                            carried to such a length, that now the whole fabric of European social life rests on bayonet
                            points — on a bed of moral nitro-glycerine. To prevent explosions, these governments, during
                            1879, spent for military purposes nearly eight hundred millions of dollars ! Their standing
                            armies, including reserves, <pb n="173" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 173 number more than
                            eight millions of men. And if France increases her forces Germany does so too. The debts of
                            Europe, mainly war debts, aggregate more than twenty billions ! The shoulders of the
                            laboring populations have to bear this ; also, the costs of criminal institutions, public
                            works and buildings; pensions, annuities and also the enormous sums paid as interest for
                            private and municipal indebtedness. Again, there are more than fifteen millions of
                            non-producers in Europe to-day in addition to the said eight millions. In private families
                            if one or more do not provide for themselves, they must be supported; in a kingdom the case
                            is the same. And if there are families who live in style they are burdens, more so than
                            paupers are. The difference between a tramp and a genteel idler is, the former does not know
                            where he may sleep and gets a morsel when he can ; the other lives in a mansion and has his
                            food brought to him in abundance. If onehalf of the people contrive to live on government
                            securities, on rents, on profits and on the interest of money, the other half will be ground
                            to the dust, as are the farm laborers of Europe. War and other debts may run along for
                            generations, and be paid over and over. Should the burden-bearers in their agony try to
                            throw off their oppressors, their taskmasters, in the name of law and order, crush them down
                            with the bullet; and when they ask for an equitable share of the food, etc., they have
                            produced, they are met with the bayonet. Land monopoly and financial iniquities are at the
                            botton of the social troubles of Europe. The existence of privileged classes, their
                            patronage, influence and demoralizingextravagance rests there; pauperism and crime have
                            their issues there. Physical, mental and moral degradation, unrest, and the anguish of the
                            millions are due to these causes. During the past one hundred years, twenty millions of
                            persons have met with untimely deaths under Brittish rule; not on the battle-field, but by
                            famine, destitution,, and over-work; mainly by the hands of dukes and their fellows. In view
                            of such moral obliquity — such stupendous frauds — such awful deeds of wrong, we may well
                            stand aghast, and inquire, do these European confederates belong to the genus-homo- ? Are we
                            capable of doing what they and their fathers have done ? Perpetrate, continue and enforce
                            such wrongs, by enormous armies and powerful fleets ? The answer is, the members of the
                            human family are essentially alike. Do not all those who are under the power of their lower
                            self-hoods want to be dukes, to have social position above their fellows, and property to
                            correspond ? Is it not very agreeable to live on the interest of money and have the
                            principal increase ? Is it not very easy for us to use power in favor of ourselves ? We may
                            flatter ourselves that in this country we are not burdened with a titled class of men,
                            controlling legislation in their own favor, and securing execution of the laws in the same
                            direction ; and filling all the important offices. Halt ! the nobles of England confine
                            themselves mainly to their estates and governmental affairs. The industries of the country
                            and finances are in the hands of other parties, and serve as checks. Are not all our
                            legislatures controlled by parties, who are at once landmonopolists, financiers ; and in
                            whose hands are all the leading industries ? A combination terrible in power, and utterly at
                            variance with the logic—-the existence of the Republic. The laws these parties frame are of
                            course in favor of themselves, and unfavorable to the bone and sinew — the stay of the
                            Republic. Even the National Legislature is composed of just such men ¦— eighty to ten ! Is
                            not a confederacy of hydra-headed corporations more to be dreaded than a nest of noblest The
                            former has many votes, a duke has but one. Have not these corporations already voted to
                            themselves two hundred millions acres of land ? And did not their committee on lands, but a
                            few weeks ago (April, 1880), recommend voting to themselves a tract of land eighty miles
                            long and sixty wide, between the Rio Grande and Colorado rivers ? Is not the statement of H.
                            B. Wrright, M. C.; of Pennsylvania, <pb n="174" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. almost
                            incredible—"that two hundred millions of the public money has gone into the hands of these
                            corporations." And that when he introduced into Congress a land and loan bill (the loan to
                            be refunded), it was thrown out by a vote of 212 to 22. To poor families the public lands
                            are inaccessible ; without help they must remain wagesslave — commodities. Did Southern
                            slavery, " the sum of all villainies," do more than make men, women and children commodities
                            ? Is not the monopoly of land, of the industries of the country and of making the laws, that
                            sum? Are not the financial iniquities of bankers and speculators, inducing over-production
                            and creating panics, throwing hundreds of thousands out of employment, an aggravation that
                            the African slave never felt 1 Thinking men view us with alarm ; they see breakers ahead !
                            they see that the great and growing inequalities of social conditions are destructive of
                            unity of interests, and are not compatible with republican or Christian sentiments ; and
                            also destructive of all ideals of human elevation. Again, they see that educated men, even
                            under our institutions, have not yet learned the first lessons of social life : "That
                            justice to all is the foundation of peace, and that beneficence is cheaper and more
                            efficient than standing armies." In conclusion : " Land being the source of human
                            sustenance, of social and judicial equality, and a regulator of the exchange, and values of
                            commercial equivalents; therefore every person of age should have access to it at all
                            times." Those whose eyes have been opened, see that standing in the lower self-hoods they
                            can but bring forth the order of the world as above shadowed forth. Such will also be able
                            to see that the foundations of our Shaker order of life are the foundations of Heaven — not
                            given to be changed nor modified to suit the worldly minded, but to be built upon. Some may
                            build with wood, hay or stubble ; others with hygienic, moral and divine truths,
                            crystallized into living forms. These foundations are barred to all uncleanness of flesh or
                            spirit, but open to the pure in heart. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lamp of experience" TEIform="index"/>THE LAMP OF EXPERIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Among many other salutary helps to young persons, and indeed to any who have had but a short
                            privilege among the Shakers the experience of those of long standing and sincere effort,
                            might be made a solid means of encouragement. When I , was young, nothing was more
                            interesting and encouraging to me than to find some one to converse with, who could detail a
                            series of trials, temptations, and conflicts parallel with my own, but which the narrator
                            had passed successfully through, and was able to speak of, from a standpoint of victory and
                            triumph. Indeed, thought I, during such interviews, " There's a home, sweet home for the
                            weary pilgrim — The traveller when his journey is o'er; His rest is complete, eternal his
                            joy, And his sorrows will come no more." " Then I'll mourn no more though sorrows roll, At
                            the cross be never murm'ring; For a passport to that happy shore, I know that I am gaining."
                            All this I could read in the serene and peaceful countenances of those loving and
                            sympathizing brethren and sisters—substantial veterans in the gospel — when they spoke
                            together, and to me (as.they often did in those days), of their previous experiences. God
                            forbid that I should be guilty of any egotism, for I long since discovered that the gospel
                            necessarily and absolutely " excludes all boasting." Nevertheless I feel confident that none
                            will be injured and some may be comforted] and encouraged by an offering of the best of my
                            experiences practically illustrated, or at least one or two of them. When about fifteen
                            years old my occupation was weaving, in a solitary shop with no company, day after day and
                            week after week. Now perhaps nothing in the catalogue of afflictions and trials was severer
                            in their effect upon me (and I have no doubt many if not all other young people) than the
                            weary wear and tear of almost unbroken monotony and sameness with which life among the
                            Shakers was at <pb n="175" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 175 that time surrounded. I used
                            to sit and cry over my work with very ennui, and disgust of life. One day I asked my good
                            old elder (who was about one of the best men I ever knew), if he kept me thus tediously
                            confined in solitary loneliness just for the sake of the suffering there was in it? "Oh, by
                            no means," said he, "but just because we can do no better ;" or words to that effect. I
                            noticed, however, that shortly afterward he told me to take the afternoon on Saturdays and
                            go with the other boys into the woods after nuts and in other diversions. His explanation
                            and his after charitable policy, to some considerable extent, bridged over this scene of
                            trial, and in the course of time, change of circumstances, self-discipline, etc., brought
                            about an endurable and at times a pleasant condition of life. But again : When about
                            twenty-two years old, I was seized with an almost uncontrollable desire for change ; and for
                            what then appeared to me as liberty, to do exactly as I pleased and go precisely when and
                            where I pleased. I cannot say that I was free from this temptation a single day from four to
                            six months. But one calm afternoon I was standing alone in a kind of reverie and praying to
                            be guided by God's good presence and wisdom and love through this dreadful scene of
                            self-sacrifice of my will and my whole self, to the behests of that divine cause He had
                            called me to espouse, and in obedience to that order and organization through which such
                            desirable triumph was alone to be reached, instantly God's presence and love were made so
                            astonishingly manifest to me that I was altogether released from every sign or sensation of
                            rebellion and restiveness, and fairly rejoiced with joy unspeakable and full of glory.
                            Indeed I fairly wept with joy and was filled full of peace and remained so for quite a long
                            time. Since that day (now more than 40 years) I do not recollect of ever having the least
                            trial nor temptation to go into and over the world to enjoy its liberties, its shows nor its
                            scenes. So if any one is under similar conditions of restlessness and monotonous agony, I am
                            sure, if he or she perseveres in patience and can only afford to hold on in integrity,
                            deliverance in God's good time, in complete and final triumph, will be abundantly
                        bestowed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision, no. I" TEIform="index"/> VISION. No. I.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/> WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The primitive meaning of this word is sight. A secondary meaning is what the Scotch call
                            second sight, or the ability of persons living upon the earth to see beings who live in the
                            spirit world, as used by Jesus after the appearing of Moses and Elijah to Himself and His
                            disciples—" tell the vision to no man.'' Like many other words, also, it has its various
                            accommodated or figurative and symbolic meanings. There can be no question in the minds of
                            those who have carefully studied the subject, that what is called second sight is simply a
                            more than ordinary development of the natural vision, just as some persons haye an unusual
                            development of the calculating faculty, or an extraordinary ability to excel in some one
                            pursuit. Very young children have given sometimes unmistakable evidence of this power of
                            sight. There are, however, very many, even persons of great mental acumen, not only such as
                            deny the existence of human beings after the death of the body, but also of those who
                            profess the utmost faith in man's immortality, who utterly reject the idea of beings upon
                            the earth seeing those in the spirit life, except as a mark of Divine favor, as in the cases
                            recorded in the Scriptures, or to confirm the truth of God's revelation to man. According to
                            them, it is all hallucination, a dream, a fancy, unworthy the acceptance of a rational
                            being. A remarkable instance of this is recorded by the celebrated Lord Chancellor Brougham,
                            in his autobiography. He and a very intimate friend were members of the University of
                            Edinburgh. In their walks together, they were accustomed to discuss many subjects of
                            interest, among others, the immortality of the soul and a future state. To use his own words
                            : " This question and the possibility of the dead appearing to the living were subjects of
                            much speculation, and we actually committed the folly of drawing an agreement, written with
                            our own-blood, to the effect, that <pb n="176" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO.
                            whichever of us died the first should appear to the other and thus solve any doubts we had
                            entertained of the life after death. After we had finished our classes at the college, my
                            friend Gr-----went to India, having got an appointment there in the civil service. He seldom
                            wrote to me, and after the lapse of a few years I had almost forgotten him." In the year
                            1799 Brougham was traveling in Sweden, and on the 19th of December took a warm bath. He says
                            : " While lying in it and enjoying the comfort of the heat, I turned my head round, looking
                            toward the chair on which I had deposited my clothes, as I was about to get up out of the
                            bath. On the chair sat my friend Gr-----, looking calmly at me. How I got out of the bath I
                            know not, but on recovering my senses I found myself sprawling on the floor. The apparition,
                            or whatever it was that had taken the likeness of G-----, had disappeared. The vision
                            produced such a shock that I had no inclination to talk about it; but the impression it made
                            upon me was too vivid to be easily forgotten, and so strongly was I affected by it that I
                            have written down the whole history with the date, 19th December, and all the particulars as
                            they are now fresh before me. Soon after my return to Edinburgh, there arrived a letter from
                            India announcing G-----'s death and stating that he had died on the 19th of December.
                            Singular coincidence !" And yet, singular as it was, Brougham says : "No doubt I had fallen
                            asleep, and that the appearance presented so distinctly to ray eyes was a dream I cannot for
                            a moment doubt; yet for years I had had no communication with Q-----, nor had there been any
                            thing to recall him to my recollection ; nothing had taken place during our Swedish travels
                            .neither connected with Gr----- nor with India, nor with any thing relating to him nor any
                            member of his family." He further says: " I believe every such seeming miracle is like every
                            ghost story, capable of explanation." No doubt! The explanation in his case is very similar
                            to that of the appearance to the apostles when they were with Jesus on the Mount. Brougham
                            says: "On recovering my senses I found myself sprawling on the floor!" In the New Testament
                            record it is said ; " Peter and they that were with him were heavy with sleep, and when they
                            were awake they saw His glory and the two men that stood with Him." Very likely the shock,
                            that affected Brougham opened his eyes to see his friend before fear prostrated him on the
                            floor. Brougham had a great fondness for what is called natural science. Had he gone a few
                            steps farther, on the borders of the Spiritual Realm, he might have found a ready
                            explanation of the occurrence, without the supposition of an ordinary dream to account for
                            the vision of his friend. Sonyea, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who holds the keys?" TEIform="index"/>WHO HOLDS THE KEYS?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Jesus, when he was about to leave his little flock that he bad gathered around him during his
                            ministry, gave the keys of the kingdom to Peter. We do not suppose that Jesus meant to be
                            understood that Peter was a Rock, or that as a man he designed to build his church upon him.
                            But he perceived that Peter was blest with the gift of Revelation when he said, " Thou art
                            the Christ." And Jesus, knowing that the time of his departure was at hand, was anxious to
                            find one upon whose brow he could place the signet of Leadership, and baptize, as himself
                            had been baptized ; one who would be able to lead, direct and protect t'.ie lambs of his
                            fold after he had passed from their sight. He felt that Peter was the fittest representative
                            of Christian principles, and the ablest expounder of the doctrines which he himself had
                            taught that he could find for the time being. Peter also passed away in due time, and also a
                            long line of his successors down through the ages. Did they retain or lose the keys, or who
                            holds the keys of the kingdom now ? Innovation and transformation of turning and overturning
                            seems to be the ruling spirit of the present age. We have commotion and strife in all
                            departments, our standing armies in military array on the lands, and fleets upon the seas.
                            Also an <pb n="177" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 177 army of politicians in secret
                            conclave and in open combat, as numerous as were the locusts of Egypt. And in the highest
                            offices and tribunals of the civil government, all is not sunshine and peace. True, without
                            agitation of thought, there would be no progress; but when the time conies, if ever, that
                            diversity of thought and opinion, by comparison and analysis, can be brought into orderly
                            arrangement, so as to produce harmony and growth instead of discord and strife, we shall be
                            apt to think that the millennial period has come to stay. In the ecclesiastic
                            department—Christian churches under clerical rule—we find divisions and subdivisions upon
                            minor points of doctrine, until churches are multiplied and have become so complex that it
                            is difficult to numerate them. The reason for this diversity does not appear to be so much
                            to excel in practical virtue, in goodness and truth, as to gain the mastery and become the
                            most popular. It is apparent to every close observer of the signs of the times, and listener
                            to the murmuring winds that come from the orthodox churches heavily freighted with doubts,
                            and wails of dissatisfaction, that Luther and Calvin doctrines are destined to pass away;
                            that orthodoxy and heterodoxy must meet face to face, each to plead their cause and bring
                            forth their reasons for be lieving, or disbelieving thus, and so, and if this could be done
                            in a right spirit, truth would be advanced thereby. Those who have been honestly linked to
                            the creedal faiths of their forefathers and have conscientiously guarded them, would
                            certainly lose nothing by liberal investigation. But bigoted controversy and theological
                            strife, merely to uphold some pet dogma, and prepossessed opinion, always go to form dark
                            clouds, that obscure the rays of light from the sun of divine revelation, that are so much
                            needed to warm and enliven human hearts and promote spiritual growth, and convert from
                            practical wrongdoing, and bring faith and good works into co-operation and harmonious
                            relations. Modern Spiritualism has come to earth as an evangel of light ; and tens of
                            thousands have been more or less developed as mediums, and millions have been converted to a
                            belief in spirit communion with mortals in divers manners. They also are divided into many
                            classes ; and the question arises : " Who has been made essentially better in their life
                            deeds by such belief ? The effusions of the brain without the co-operation of heart-felt
                            emotions, well directed convictions, culminating in practical works, will avail little.
                            Dissenters from orthodox churches, called Spiritualists, are as much at variance in
                            religious opinions as are those who remain. The human mind is ever active, reasoning and
                            making comparisons, and trying to solve knotty problems, and to arrive at just conclusions,
                            but many times, while seeking to extricate the mind from the net work of erroneous ideas,
                            and superstitions of the growth of centuries, they surround themselves with still greater
                            difficulties and add mystery to mystery, until they are enshrouded in greater uncertainty
                            and doubt than when they commenced. The cry, " Lo here and lo there," is now heard with
                            great distinctness from many quarters, till the atmosphere is pregnant with the sound. What
                            is to be the final outcome? Who will give the certain and who the uncertain sound ? The
                            conclusion still remains ; " Judge the tree by its product—the fruit it bears." When the
                            national civil rulers enact more just laws, bearing equally upon all citizens, irrespective
                            of sex or color, deepening and broadening the basic foundation of American government, which
                            professes and should be non-partisan, and will give a strong guarantee that all its subjects
                            shall be fully protected in civil and religious liberty, leaving each and all free (while
                            law-abiding) to worship God in accordance with their own convictions of right and duty,
                            irresponsible of any earthly tribunal, then the new earth will be formed, abounding in
                            fruitful fields. Wars will cease, and fraternal relations between nations be established to
                            the ends of the earth. Thus purified, the national banner will be uplifted, and never more
                            be left to trail in the dust of low selfish aims and political intrigues. Then the new
                            heavens will <pb n="178" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 178 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. have a permanent foundation to
                            rest upon, and divine revelation will illume the spiritual pathway and open the doors to the
                            inner spheres of the resurrection heavens, and harmony will prevail. Leading minds will
                            fraternize, and the " Watchman in Zion will see eye to eye." This unity will only be
                            accomplished by a heavenly baptism that will purify the heart and quicken the g-erni of
                            immortality planted by God in all human souls. When that good time comes we shall no longer
                            ask, " Who holds the keys?" that will unlock the doors of Christ's kingdom. We shall find
                            the " Seal broken, and the mystery finished." There will be " an open door that no man can
                            shut; and that all may know the Lord for himself or herself, from the least to the
                            greatest." We shall always have need of spiritual, heavenly guides and teachers, more
                            advanced than ourselves, to go before us ; but all may hold the keys of revelation within
                            their own grasp. If truth be our motto, and we resolve to make it our nearest friend and
                            companion, we shall find neither bondage, mystery, darkness nor death in it. All hail the
                            coming day ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">Truth gives character to youth more than all other qualities combined, and it is of greater
                            worth than mountains of gold. " Better die for the truth, than live to uphold error." To be
                            thought truthful is not sufficient, act the truth, for truth alone will stand." If you obey
                            the spirit of truth, it will lead you to perfect happiness. No one ever regretted being true
                            and pure in early life. A true life wears the best. The pare and true are ever attracted to
                            those who live unsullied lives —" like gathers to like." Truth is as necessary to the soul
                            as health to the body. " Stand for truth whate'er betide." Truth is the basis of all manly
                            character; it is the foundation of all goodness. A person may have faults, but confidence
                            can be placed in him if he is truthful; but when veracity is gone, all is lost, unless he is
                            soon won back to truth. A fault concealed will be very troublesome ; it will set one's
                            invention on the rack to add other faults thereto; even in point of prudence, an honest
                            confession is always better, always the best. All heaven is on the side of truth. Truth is
                            beautiful, it is consistent, and near at hand, and does not need untruth to bring out its
                            beauty. Some youths vow to be true, and raise many pleasant expectations which they never
                            seem to think of again they practice a thousand deceits, when straight forward truth is just
                            the thing required. Too often they are " chips of the old block." Be true. Truth and
                            simplicity are beautiful ornaments of culture and refinement; it is a mistaken idea of
                            refinement, or a false culture that ignore either. Open your hearts to the sunlight of truth
                            ; brush out the " cobwebs of sin " by confession, and make room for that which is prized by
                            the honest and pure. How beautiful is truth ! Write it down on your memories, and let it
                            stand as a title page of your whole lives. A fig for all your endeavors, if truth is
                            wanting! Seek the ornaments of truth, of purity; these will clothe you with un fading glory,
                            and they will last in eternity. "Buy the truth and sell it not." Be bold for truth, fear
                            God, and you have nothing else to fear. If you would make your mark in life for all that is
                            noble and good, have an unbending regard for truth, and my word for it, you will succeed.
                            Watch ! gather to the stronghold of truth, and from it may you never depart. Enfield, Ct.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Iconoclast" TEIform="index"/>THE ICONOCLAST</head><p TEIform="p">As humanity has been, is, and will be on the ascending grade, early imbibed theologies—
                            mental snubbing posts—must be left behind. Theologies, though behind the age, are in some
                            cases so enshrined in the pious affections, as to require the services of the iconoclast.
                            Who shall be the iconoclast ? What motive must prompt him? What his reward 1 <pb n="179" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 179 The " saved," who have attained a clearer vision of
                            the true dignity of manhood, who with the beloved disciple have made the sublime discovery
                            that " God is love," and like the fair shepherdess, that''love must govern the world," 'tis
                            theirs to give practical demonstration of the better way, the theology of love. They have
                            neither the time nor the disposition to perform the drudgery of the iconoclast. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss." TEIform="persName"/>Prentiss </byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eulogy upon a Shaker" TEIform="index"/>EULOGY UPON A SHAKER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">(Lines written upon the occasion of the decease of our worthy brother, Hiram Irish, who
                            departed this life, Enfield, N. H., June 18th, 1880. Read at his funeral, June 20.) He
                            passed the stream without a sigh or tear, As beautiful as sets the orb of day ; He's left
                            the scenes of earthly turmoil here, And into spirit life has passed away. O ! faithful
                            brother, happy is thy lot! Thou hast no cause to grieve thy exit here; Life's fearful battle
                            thou hast nobly fought, And joys await thee in thy spirit sphere. Go reap the blessings of
                            thy earthly life, A crown of glory brighter far than gold; A piece that knows no bitterness
                            of strife, And heavenly gifts unceasingly unfold. A bright example for the rising age ! May
                            we as children of the blest deceased; Come forth a bright and living heritage, Fit subjects
                            for the heavenly marriage feast. Let us as youthful aiders in the cause Bear well in mind
                            while now in early days, That those who bear the cross without a pause, Become assured, the
                            gospel life well pays. And we who've passed the buoyant hours of youth, And feel the
                            burdened cares of riper years; Remember that our Savior's words are truth, And will be
                            verified, as slavish fears. And self-indulgences are done away, And we accept the gospel as
                            it is; Withholding nothing that would mar or stay Our progress in the work. And this was
                            his. Our brother's faith through life, and nobly too Has he accomplished this most glorious
                            end; Whatever work his hands they found to do, Was faithfully performed; he knew no bend To
                            any selfish feeling or desire; The blessed gospel was his all in all ; His soul is purified
                            by furnace fire, ' And now with joy he hears the welcome call: [The following beautiful
                            dirge was harmoniously sung as continuation and conclusion of the eulogy. —£d.) Come home,
                            thou faithful servant of the Lord, Thou hast well done, thy mansion waits for thee; Accept
                            the promised, glorious reward, And blest forever thou shalt surely be. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philosopher's religion" TEIform="index"/>A PHILOSOPHER'S RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline">A Letter, from <persName reg="Franklin, Benjamin" TEIform="persName"/>Benjamin Franklin</byline><p TEIform="p">to George Whitefield. To this Editor of The Sun— Sir: I send you for publication the
                            following letler of Dr. Franklin, addressed to the great and eloquent Methodist and revival
                            preacher of the last century, George Whitefield, who addressed and electrified audiences of
                            from 10,000 to 60,000 people. This letter seems to be applicable at the present time of
                            revival preaching and praying. The kindness alluded to in the letter as done by Franklin to
                            Whitefield, referred to the fact that Franklin had relieved Whitefield in a paralytic case
                            by the application of electricity. The prayer of Dr. Franklin, which I send, I find is
                            hardly known at all and I think a republication of it might be welcome to many: FRANKLIN'S
                            letter. Philadelphia, June 6', 1753. Sir ; I received your kind letter of the second inst.,
                            and am glad to hear that you increase in strength. I hope you will continue mending till you
                            recover your former health and firmness. Let me know whether you still use the cold bath,
                            and what effect it has. As to the kindness you mention, I wish it could have been of greater
                            service to you. But if it had, the only thanks I should desire is, that you would always be
                            equally ready to serve any other person that <pb n="180" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE SHAKEfl
                            MANIFESTO. may need your assistance, and so let good offices go round, for mankind are all
                            of a family. For my own part, when T am employed in serving others, I do not look upon
                            myself as conferring favors, but as paying debts. In my travels and since my settlement, I
                            have received much kindness from men, to whom I shall never have any opportunity of making
                            the least direct return, and numberless mercies from Qod,who is infinitely above being
                            benefited by our services. Those kindnesses from men I can therefore only return on their
                            fellow men, and I can only show my gratitude for those mercies from God, by a readiness to
                            help his other child ren and my brethren. For I don't think that thanks and compliments,
                            though repeated weekly, can discharge our real obligation to each other, and much less those
                            to our Creator. You will see in this my notion of good works, that I am far from expecting
                            to merit heaven by them. By heaven we understand a state of happiness infinite in degree and
                            eternal in duration ; I can do nothing to merit such rewards. He that for giving a draught
                            of water to a thirsty person should expect to be paid with a good plantation, would be
                            modest in his demands, compared with those who think they deserve heaven for the little good
                            they do on earth. Even the mixed imperfect pleasures we enjoy in this world are rather from
                            God's goodness than our merit; how much more such happiness of heaven ! for my part, I have
                            not the vanity to think I deserve it, the folly to expect it, nor the ambition to desire it,
                            but content myself in submitting to the will and disposal of that God who made me, who has
                            hitherto preserved and blessed me, and in whose fatherly goodness I may well confide, that
                            he will nevermake me miserable, and that even the afflictions I may at any time suffer shall
                            tend to my benefit. The faith you mention has certainly its use in the world. I do not
                            desire to see it diminished, nor would I endeavor to lessen it in any man. But I wish, it
                            were more productive of good works than I have generally seen it. I mean real good works,
                            works of kindness, charity, mercy, and public spirit ; no holy-days keeping, sermon hunting
                            or hearing, performing church ceremonies, making long prayers, tilled with flatteries and
                            compliments, despised even by wise, men, and much less capable of pleasing the Deity. The
                            worship of God is a duty. The hearing and reading of sermons may be useful ; but if men rest
                            in hearing and praying, as too many do, it is as if a tree should value itself on being
                            watered and putting forth leaves, though it never produces fruit. Your great Master thought
                            much less of those outward appearances and professions than many of his modern disciples. He
                            preferred the doers of the word to the mere hearers ; the son that seemingly refused to obey
                            his father, and yet performed his commands, to him that professed his readiness but
                            neglected the wrork ; the heretical but charitable Samaritan to the uncharitable though
                            orthodox priest and sanctified Levite ; and those who gave food to the hungry, drink to the
                            thirsty, raiment to the naked, entertainment to the stranger, and relief to the sick, though
                            they never heard of his name, he declares shall in the last day be accepted, when those who
                            cry Lord, Lord, who value themselves upon their faith, though great enough to perform
                            miracles but have neglected good works, shall be rejected. He professed that he came not to
                            call the righteous, but sinners, to repentance, which implied his modest opinion that there
                            were some in his time who thought themselves so good that they did not hear even him for
                            improvement; but now a days we have scarce a little parson who thinks it the duty of every
                            man within his reach to set under his petty ministrations, and whoever omits them offends
                            God! I wTish to such more humility, and to you health and happiness, being your friend and
                            servant, B. Franklin. PRAYER OF DR. FRANKLIN. Merciful God! Wonderful Power! Increase in me
                            that wisdom which discovers my truest interest; strengthen my resolution to perform what
                            that wisdom dictates, and accept my kind offices to Thy other creatures, as the only return
                            in my power for Thy infinite goodness to me ! </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who does not participate..." TEIform="index"/>Who does not participate...</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Moltke, H. V." TEIform="persName"/> Count Moltke</byline><p TEIform="p"> the famous military strategist and commander-in-chief of the German army, lately sent the
                            following reply to a Saxon workman, who had written suggesting a decrease of military
                            burdens. " Who does not participate in the heartfelt wish to see lightened the iheavy
                            military burdens which Germany is obliged to bear, being, as she is, situated between
                            powerful neighbors 1 The princes and the government share in the same wish, but this happy
                            state of things cannot be hoped for until all nations acknowledge that every war, however
                            successful, is a general calamity. Even our emperor is not able to bring about this
                            desirable conviction, which can, in fact, only be produced by a better religious and moral
                            education of the populations, and this is the work of centuries. Neither you nor I will live
                            to see it.— Yours truly, H. V. Moltke."—Christian (London) Herald.</p></div2><pb n="181" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corresondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Veteran's testimory" TEIform="index"/>A VETERAN'S TESTIMONY</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Manifesto : I anxiously await your arrival eacli month, so that I may hear good
                                tidings from my friends north, south, east and west. I love to hear their plain
                                testimonies of truth, light, and peace of conscience, which they enjoy, after a long
                                life of travel in the straight and narrow path of self-denial; and through the dark
                                wilderness of temptation. What a cause of rejoicing to know they.have fought the good
                                fight, and kept the faith, and lived a life devoted unto God. What a blessing, yea, what
                                an assurance to know we can unite with the saints of the Most High, that we can bathe in
                                the flowing streams of pure gospel love and union. This assurance has kept my soul alive
                                and strengthened and encouraged me in times of trial, and temptation to wrong. Oh! What
                                a cause of rejoicing it should be, that we are called out of a world of sin and sorrow;
                                this is a source of joy to me to know how much I have escaped. I love the blessed
                                manifestations of love to God, good will to man, and the charity you extend to poor
                                down-trodden man. I am thankful I was called out of this world of vanity and fashion to
                                follow the Lamb. Here I have lived a pure virgin life, free from condemnation or guilt,
                                have tried to follow the great " Exampler," and to keep myself unspotted from the sins
                                that so easily beset us. I was born in 1791 ; there was a religious revival in Logan
                                county, Kentucky, under the ministration of John Rankin, which caused a great
                                excitement. The cry was: "The millennium is near at hand; Christ is to appear without
                                sin, unto salvation!" The call was to prepare to meet God, in judgment; this was a
                                solemn sound to souls that feared God ; this caused the people to bow low in humble
                                prayer, saying, " Lord come in whom thou wilt! " Others said : " He will come, and when
                                He comes we will go forth in the dances of them that make merry." Others said: " There
                                will be no husbands and wives, but brethren and sisters in the Lord ; that every dark
                                and secret thing should be revealed," Thus we waited and prayed for the fulfillment of
                                the prophecy. In the year 1805, three messengers came from the east, filled with the
                                power and spirit of Christ, testifying that Christ had come without sin unto salvation.
                                These tidings were hailed with joy and with sorrow. Our idols were swept away, but our
                                souls were filled with joy and comfort, in 1809, I confessed my sins, and began to take
                                up a cross against all the temptations of the world. My father, being- opposed to the
                                Shaker life, tried to induce me to remain with him, and threatened to disown and
                                disinherit me, which he did ; but I left my home at South Union and fled to Pleasant
                                Hill. I resolved to forego all the pleasures of the world and turn my face heavenward. I
                                have never looked back to Sodom, but have kept my first love, have passed through the
                                furnace ; but I feel amply repaid for all the self-denial 1 have practiced when my
                                worldly nature strove for the ascendancy. I feel a sweet peace of conscience now; and as
                                I near the dark river 1 have no fears to cross, knowing that I have received the hundred
                                fold and will receive life eternal in the world to come. May we all meet and rejoice
                                together. I will be eighty-nine years old in August, " the Lord willing."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carnahan, Prudence" TEIform="persName"/>Prudence Carnahan</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder G. A. Lomas: Kind Friend..." TEIform="index"/>Elder G. A. Lomas: Kind Friend...
                            </head><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Titusville, June 28, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Titusville, June 28, 1880</bibl><p TEIform="p"> Elder G. A. Lomas : Kind Friend :—On turning backward the leaves of memory, I find that
                                my subscription for the Shaker has expired, and I hasten to renew ; feeling that I
                                cannot be content to dispense with the monthly visits of that dear little pamphlet,
                                containing as it does so much of the " spirit of true religion ;" so much of ''peace on
                                earth, good will to man " and woman. This is the fourth year it has been a visitant in
                                our family and each number seems to be an improvement on the last. A good example of the
                                great '' law of eternal progress " which I as a spiritualist believe in. Every year for
                                the last five, since I read Charles Nordhoff's <pb n="182" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 182 THE SHAKES
                                MANIFESTO. book, I have had a desire to visit one of your societies and become better
                                acquainted with your mode of life. After meeting Elder Frederick Evans at the Lake last
                                September, andliearing him explain some of the points of Shaker belief, I have had a
                                still greater wish to know more of your social life by actual acquaintance, which is the
                                only reliable information those in the outside world can gain of you. I was in hopes
                                then to have visited you soon, but circumstances do not seem to favor me yet. " But we
                                know not what a day may bring forth." I wish to say here how much I was pleased to see
                                how grandly and nobly you and your societies also, stood by D. M. Bennett all through
                                his unjust imprisonment and persecution. I thank you all kindly for it in the name of
                                humanity and liberality. Enclosed please find subscription in stamps. Most respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Aikin, L. T. R." TEIform="index"/>Mrs. L. T. R. Aikin</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder G. A. Lomas: Kind Friend..." TEIform="index"/>Elder G. A. Lomas: Kind Friend...
                            </head><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Arkansas, Rich Mountain Unitary Home, Rich Mountain, June 29, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Arkansas, Rich Mountain Unitary Home, Rich Mountain, June 29, 1880
                                Rich Mountain Unitary Home, Rich Mountain, Ark., June 29, 1880</bibl><p TEIform="p"> Editor Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y.. : Through the kindness of unknown friends we are in
                                receipt of the Manifesto, from whose treasured pages I am beginning to learn that the
                                underlying principles of this faith have been treasured plants in the garden of my heart
                                since early boyhood. For notwithstanding the mental bias my early religious training
                                subjected me to, my parents being Baptists of the old school, I could never reconcile my
                                views of true inspirational teachings to such seeming inconsistencies of their faith as
                                that which when carefully investigated, made God Father and Son of Himself, as, also His
                                slayer, to redeem man from that depraved condition into which his Creator purposely
                                plunged him, that he might enjoy the honor of man's redemption. It seems quite clear to
                                my mind from the accounts given by Jesus of Himself, that He is represented under two
                                distinct characters, first, His individual character, as a natural man (the Son of Man),
                                and second, His official character as a physically sound man, who being free from the
                                contaminating and corrupting influence of disease was morally sound in His spiritual
                                character; 2 Cor. vii and 1. And hence a properly qualified representative of the
                                Christ. From a slavish fear of thi3 Jesus, prejudicial to the interests of the Rabinical
                                creeds, the people put the man Jesus to death. Nevertheless, as the mantle of Elijah
                                descended upon Elisha, even so the Christ, the Holy Ghost. The righteousness of the
                                children of light, even the Son of God, rested upon the true believers of the doctrines
                                taught by this Jesus, or all, who, like him, take up their cross, crucify self, and thus
                                follow Him in the resurrection to newness of life. But we see that creedists desiring to
                                make a scape-goat of-Him, to bear the sins and suffer the penalties which con science in
                                judgment daily imposes, desire to deify Him, that in His death, the stern sentence of
                                violated law in them might be revoked. They are willing to be borne away to the realms
                                of perfect bliss in some remote local region or the air, provided all necessary
                                sacrifices for sins can be made outside of self. This is that class of " believers,"
                                many of whom seek shelter from the bleak winds and pelting storms of the world's wintry
                                seasons, in Shaker families, receiving abundant sustenance from Shaker tables, but with
                                the return of spring, turn again to the fleshpots of Egypt." Your principles are new to
                                most people here, yet your papers are read with interest by those to whom we lend them.
                                We hope to see you expand in this direction until you reach us.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beauchamp, W. A. J." TEIform="persName"/>W. A. J. Beauchamp</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I desire no display at my funeral..." TEIform="index"/>I desire no display at my funeral...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Ames" TEIform="index"/>Ames
                        </byline><p TEIform="p">Several days before his death, Bishop Ames said to Gen. John S. Berry,'' I desire no display
                            at my funeral. I would have a plain coffin made of live oak and trimmed plainly with
                            trimmings of galvanized iron. Let there be no flowers on it. The tendency to extravagant and
                            useless parade at funerals in this country is getting to be a great and growing evil, and I
                            wish by my example, as far as possible, to inaugurate a different state of things." </p></div2><pb n="183" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What was He?" TEIform="index"/> WHAT WAS HE?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The controversies of the various religious sects are as unreasonable as they are
                                unnecessary. What matter can any make of an assertion that Jesus Christ was a Baptist.
                                Presbyterian, Roman Catholic or Quaker ? Or that did He live to-day He would advocate
                                the Methodist, Reform or Episcopalian formalities of the Christian profession ? In the
                                man Jesus we see grandeur personified. A Jew, who having " kept the law from his youth
                                up," was ready for an increasing evolution of life that would greatly supersede Judaism.
                                With a perfectly healthy body, none could wish for a superior earthly paternity than He
                                could have illustrated. Stalwart, brave, generous and just, He was fit for the crown of
                                any nationality. As a strategist, in peace or in war, He would have been unequaled by
                                any other Jew. With the masses He was popular, beyond Caesar. He was a born leader of
                                men. Judaism never presented to the earth a more perfect specimen of humanity. With
                                superexcellent health of body and mind, He felt and knew His superiority and power over
                                His fellows. Bubbling over with this superfluous health and human virtue, it would be
                                impossible to imagine a better instrumentality for God to introduce the most needed
                                radical reforms of reproduction— procreation upon the earth. Superior, physically, to
                                any of His predecessors, His condition would seem God's most favorable opportunity. But
                                with all His superfluous virtues as an earthly man, there beamed from Heaven upon this
                                man the progressive and superior gospel of Christianity, and its beaming was accompanied
                                by an irresistible conviction that duty to God demanded of Him a willing, living
                                sacrifice, as an example for all who would be more perfect than Judaism could or can
                                make them. With these convictions of duty resting heavily as a cross upon His earthly
                                nature, the temptations of resistance came upon Him. Upon the height of His ambitions "
                                the devil tempted Him " not to be a Christian. Duty to God conquered the exercise of His
                                selfish ambitions, and there and then Jesus became the synonym of self-denial, to all
                                engagements that would have made Him a representative of an earthly man. Denying to
                                Himself all the ambitious proclivities of a Jew, He began a new lite, which is genuine
                                Christianity. Whether this life represents the peculiar features of this or that sect we
                                have no need to argue. There stood, and still stands, the representative Christian,
                                crying: "I am the way, Mine is the life and My testimony the truth " of Christianity. If
                                any would be My disciple let him or her deny self as I have, and "follow Me." To that
                                religious% body who have chosen to pattern the most Christian life of Jesus, the Christ;
                                who have denied themselves as He denied Himself, that is the true church, regardless of
                                its sectarian title. Presuming Jesus to appear again, renewing the same call as of old
                                for volunteers as disciples, accompanied by the same conditions, enunciated at His first
                                appearance as credentials of discipleship, to what <pb n="184" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 184 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. sect could He come or go and find a people living as lived the converts at
                                His first appearing ? Renouncing the dearest ties of earthly relationship to accept the
                                relationships of His church life, husbands and wives became brethren and sisters in
                                Christ — the first, Adamic following, of reproduction was forsaken, and the life of "
                                the celibate for the Kingdom of Heaven's sake" was substituted. Relinquishment of
                                houses, lands, all personal property, followed, " and none possessed aught he called his
                                own.!" Where is the sect that is working on the line and in the life of Jesus? Desirous
                                of being Christians, because genuine Christianity is best, that sect consitutes our
                                church wherever it may be, or whatever its name may be. Let us not contend with wasting
                                and useless controversies. The simple, virgin pure life of Jesus; the unselfish, golden
                                rule practice of Jesus ; the unretaliating, peaceable career of Jesus ; the freedom from
                                worldly ambition, and the unspotted ness of Jesus—following these constitute the
                                evidences of who are his disciples to-day without a controversy, and these form His
                                church to-day, of what sect He was and would be of to-day. Let our emulations to be most
                                like Christ in our lives increase amazingly; and using Christ's life as an index of our
                                own, we may ask, of what sect is Christ Jesus ? but we can more profitably ask, " Is our
                                sect following Christ ? "</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Present number" TEIform="index"/>THE PRESENT NUMBER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Contains much that is very valuable for the students of religious literature. Without
                                specifying any one article, we ask close inspection of all, and all will be found
                                profitable unto increasing virtue and truth. The article by Elder G-. B. Avery will be
                                critically canvassed by many thinkers. Our music this month is very harmonious and
                                agreeable. There is no denomination but can use it with pleasure and profit. We are
                                sorry to record some departures from our midst of those whose years could not reasonably
                                demand a passport to spirit spheres, and that to " B. Good" we yet must die. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let England wince" TEIform="index"/>LET ENGLAND WINCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The seating of Bradlaugh, the English liberal, is a gain for freedom of conscience on
                                the other side of the waters. The fussy Tories, bound up with church al predelictions
                                must feel ashamed, when Bradlaugh refuses to take their unchristian oaths; but holding
                                the Bible aloft in Parliament, he refers them to the injunction: " Swear not at all! "
                                Those English bigots who sought to deprive him of his justly earned seat, because he
                                would not swear, must feel terribly, and yet properly mortified by this rebuke from a
                                so-called infidel. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those Letters" TEIform="index"/>Those Letters</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We hope the Correspondence department will not be neglected. Our precious sister,
                                Prudence Carnaiian gives a good lesson of grand experience ; our friend Aiken leans very
                                kindly toward the right; while we are very much pleased with our Arkansas correspondent,
                                W. A. J. Beauchamp, who speaks so lively in behalf of right principles, and against the
                                engagement of self-indulgence. This corres- <pb n="185" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                185 pondent hails from a newly established community; and the sentiments expressed give
                                hope that the western part of our country will be stirred by saviours. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aid the accomplishment" TEIform="index"/>AID THE ACCOMPLISHMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> For a few months, at least, politics will force themselves prominently upon willing and
                                unwilling ears and attention. We only care to have the best man elected, and believe the
                                country will not go to perdition if either candidate should be chosen to the presidency.
                                But we are glad of one feature in the canvass—that of selecting two high-minded men as
                                candidates—ones who have tried to do duty as they understood duty to be, and thereby
                                have been the means of shutting off any probability of those slanderous indulgences
                                which have so frequently been participated in by the contending parties. We hope editors
                                will readily seize upon the occasion to keep their issues free from such personal abuse,
                                as to make their periodicals the vehicles of respectability, and not corrupt the
                                sensitive minds of young and old in the families where they enter, with unnecessary and
                                unwholesome vulgarity. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Appreciated cross" TEIform="index"/>THE APPRECIATED CROSS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We are in receipt of some very beautiful communications from different sections of our
                                country and from Europe, and we appreciate their kind and encouraging contents. We are
                                sorry, however, to have some of these epistolary tributes, while acknowledging the
                                necessity of the cross, lamenting the fact that we use so much of it. This Shaker cross
                                of self-denial is not different in any respect from that of the Christian founder ; and
                                " must Jesus bear the cross alone?" But the simple acceptance of the fact, that there is
                                a necessity of some more cross by the people, is encouraging. Of one thing we have long
                                been assured—that as, and only as individuals season their lives with more and more of
                                the salt of the Shaker cross, can they with any reason expect more peace of mind, of
                                households, and greater advancement in spiritual experience. Add a little more of this
                                seasoning—add to life a great deal more of the cross and self-denials that ivere
                                Jesus'—and our word for it, the dawn of happier sensations in life will ensue, and much
                                greater satisfaction enjoyed. Try it; not necessarily calling the practice
                                Shakerism—call it living like Christ, and share the happiness of Christ as a result. Let
                                the world and its unchristian features alone ; let Christ and His Cross be uppermost and
                                only ; and all lamentations of " ,so much cross" will cease, and its fruits be
                                thoroughly appreciated. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="books" TEIform="index"/>Book Notices</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mister Horn and his friends ; or, givers and giving" TEIform="index"/>Mister Horn and his friends ; or, givers and giving
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mister Horn and His Friends ; or, Givers and Giving By Mark Guy Pearse author of " Daniel
                                Quorm," etc. This book is finely illustrated. The aim of the author is to teach and
                                enforce the lesson of systematic giving. The style is very attractive. It is a book well
                                calculated to do much good. This book is No. 32 of I. K. Funk &amp; Co.'s. Standard
                                Series. Price, 15 cents.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Orations of Demosthenes" TEIform="index"/>The Orations of Demosthenes, vol. 1</head><p TEIform="p">(translated by Thomas Leland issued in two volumes). This first volume contains some
                                twelve of the most famous orations of this great Athenian orator. No. 33, I. K. Funk
                                &amp; Co.'s Standard Series. Price, 20 cents. Published by I. K. Funk &amp; Co.,
                                10 and 12 Dey street, New York. </p></div3></div2><pb n="186" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>AWAY FROM EARTH</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hale, Nellie H." TEIform="index"/>NELLIE H. HALE</head><p TEIform="p">From Harvard, Mass., June 12, NELLIE H. HALE, aged 21 years. </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Floyd, Mary E." TEIform="index"/>"MARY E. FLOYD</head><p TEIform="p">Also, June 19ch, MARY E. FLOYD, aged 30 years. </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shepard, Lester G." TEIform="index"/>LESTER G. SHEPARD</head><p TEIform="p">From North Union, 0., June 15, LESTER G. SHEPARD, aged 83 years. </p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good, George B." TEIform="index"/>GEORGE B. GOOD</head><p TEIform="p">From Union Village, O., July 11, GEORGE B. GOOD, aged 71 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shannon, Olive" TEIform="index"/>OLIVE SHANNON</head><p TEIform="p">From South Union, Ky., June 2G, OLIVE SHANNON, aged 7G years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> RECEIVED. From C. Dibble, $17.40. From N. A. Briggs, $4.00. INTERESTING. It is now
                                thought necessity will demand a new edition of Elder H. L. Eads' " Shaker Theology." We
                                hope so. A large edition was struck off at first, and now new demands increase the
                                everlasting permanency of the noble monument. Those who had heard of our Bro. N. A.
                                Briggs losing the entree of his right hand, will learn with pleasure that the
                                penparalysis will hopefully be averted. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ages of sheep" TEIform="index"/> Ages of Sheep</head><p TEIform="p">The following is a pretty accurate direction to tell the age of sheep by their teeth :
                                The first year a sheep's front teeth are eight in number, and are all of equal size. The
                                second year the two middle ones shed out and are replaced by two much larger than the
                                others. The third year two very small teeth appear, one on either side of the eight. At
                                the end of the fourth year there are six large teeth. The fifth, year all the front
                                teeth are large. The sixth year all begin to show signs of wear.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture is the fundamental condition..." TEIform="index"/>Agriculture is the fundamental condition...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Agriculture is the fundamental condition of civilization, as its success is the measure
                                of all other industry. The very rudest agricultural has always produced much more than
                                is sufficient for the laborer and those dependent upon him. An agricultural people
                                always develop a leisure class, and as invariably render the state of things possible,
                                in which other laborers beside the agriculturist can obtain the means of
                                subsistence.—People and Patriot.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Luck in farming" TEIform="index"/>Luck in farming
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Luck in Farming.— There are few words oftener upon the lips of a certain
                                        class of farmers than "luck." Smith is a " lucky dog " because his corn never
                                        rots, his wheat never winter-kills, his sheep never get into his rye, and his
                                        cows never invade his meadows or orchards. His crops are better than his
                                        neighbors', his butter brings more in the market, and even his wife and children
                                        have a more contented look than other people. Everything he touches thrives.
                                        What a lucky man Smith is ! Now, the fact is, luck has nothing to do with
                                        Smith's success in life. If you watch the man you will find that every result he
                                        reaches is anticipated and planned for, and comes from his own wit and work. It
                                        is the legitimate reward of his labors, and it would have been bad luck had it
                                        turned out otherwise. His corn always comes up because he always selects the
                                        seed himself, and hangs it up by the husks in the garret, where it is thoroughly
                                        dried. lie does not plant until the sun has warmed the soil enough to give the
                                        germ an immediate start. His wheat fields he drains with tile, and the water
                                        that used to freeze and thaw on the surface, and throw the roots of the wheat
                                        out and kill them, now passes down into the drains and runs off. His fields are
                                        green and beautiful in the spring, when his neighbor's are russet, brown and
                                        desolate. His fences are in good repair, and his animals are not made breachy by
                                        continual temptation of dilapidated walls. His wife and children are comfortably
                                        clothed and fed, and are not kept in a continual fret and worry by a husband and
                                        father who has no system or energy in his business. "A time and place for
                                        everything " is his motto, carefully carried out. The shoemaker is always called
                                        in when his services are needed, and none of his household get wet feet, catch
                                        cold, have lung fever, and run up the doctor's bill of <pb n="187" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>
                                        THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 187 twenty dollars for want of a cent's worth of leather
                                        at the right time in the right place. Smith does not believe in luck. He knows
                                        that health in the family and thrift upon the farm depend upon a thousand little
                                        things that many of his neighbors are too lazy or careless to look after. So,
                                        while they are at the tavern, or loafing in the village, or running amuck in
                                        politics, he is looking after these things and laying his plans for next year.
                                        He has good corn in even the poorest year, because the soil has the extra manure
                                        it needs to bring out good, long, plump, well-capped ears. He meant to have
                                        eighty bushels to the acre, and he has it, good measure and running over. Talk
                                        about luck ; it's all nonsense. Bad luck is simply a man with his hands in his
                                        breeches' pockets and his pipe in his mouth, looking on and seeing how it will
                                        come out. Good luck is a man of pluck to meet difficulties, his sleeves rolled
                                        up, and working to make it come out right.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston cultivator" TEIform="index"/>Boston Cultivator</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lend a hand" TEIform="index"/> LEND A HAND</head><p TEIform="p">Life is made of ups and downs — Lend a hand; Life is made of thorns and crowns ; If you would
                            the latter wear, Lift some crushed heart from despairLend a hand. Crowns are not alone of
                            gold ! Lend a hand; Diadems are bought and sold ; But the crowns that good men own, Come
                            from noble deeds alone — Lend a hand. Many crowns that many wear — Lend a hand ; Never in
                            the sunlight glare; Diamonds never in them shine, Yet they hold a light divine — Lend a
                            hand. Hold a light that ne'er shall fade — Lend a hand; Beauty, art hath never made ; For
                            these crowns that good men wear, Everlasting are, as rare — Lend a hand. Would you own so
                            bright a crown ? Lend a hand; When you see a brother down, Lead him from the deep, dark
                            night, Place him in the morning light — Lend a hand. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our elder brother" TEIform="index"/> OUR ELDER BROTHER</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Jesus Christ, as the Father's " only begotten Son," is heir of the whole estate.
                                    The Father delighted in him, and "appointed him heir of all things." This is
                                    according to the law of primogeniture. But the Son will not enjoy the estate alone.
                                    Unlike many earthly sons, he is willing, yea anxious, to share it with as many as
                                    will accept it. He is willing his Father should adopt other children; and, though
                                    they be adopted, he will acknowledge them as " brethren." The peace and the joy were
                                    his ; but he said, " My joy 1 leave with you ; " My peace I give unto you." "
                                    Father, I will that they also, whom thou hast given me, be with me where I am ; that
                                    they may behold my glory, which thou hast given me." Behold the unselfish,
                                    disinterested love of Christ, our Elder Brother ! " For ye know the grace of our
                                    Lord Jesus Christ, that though he was rich, yet for our sakes he became poor, that
                                    ye through his poverty might be rich." " The corn of wheat" might have " abode
                                    alone," but it died that it might "bring forth much fruit." The Son was rich in
                                    life, but he descended to the poverty of death, that we might live. Risen from the
                                    dead, and exalted at the right hand of the Father, he has sent the Spirit to testify
                                    of his benevolence. "For ye have not received the spirit of bondage again to fear ;
                                    but ye have received the Spirit of adoption, whereby we cry, Abba, Father. The
                                    Spirit itself' beareth witness with our spirit, that we are the children of God ;
                                    and if children, then heirs ; heirs of God, and joint-heirs with Christ." " If so be
                                    that we suffer with him, that we may be also glorified together." Having shown the
                                    great exaltation of the " church of the firstborn " to joint-heir ship with him, the
                                    apostle names the necessary preparation. The suffering was first with the Lord ; so
                                    with the church. This is the divinely established path to perfection. But the
                                    sufferings are fora "moment;" the glory is eternal; therefore, we may " reckon that
                                    the sufferings of this present time are not worthy to be compared with the glory
                                    which shall be revealed in us."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="188" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Success in life" TEIform="index"/>SUCCESS IN LIFE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Benjamin Franklin attributed his success as a public man, not to his talents or
                                    his powers of speaking — for these were but moderate—but to his known integrity of
                                    character. " Hence it was that I was but a bad speaker, subject to much hesitation
                                    in my choice of words, hardly correct in language, yet I generally carried my
                                    point." Character creates confidence in men in high station as well as in humble
                                    life. It is said of the first Emperor Alexander, of Russia, that his personal
                                    character was equivalent to a constitution. During the wars of the French, Montaigne
                                    was the only man among the French gentry who kept his castle gates unbarred, and it
                                    was said of him his personal character was worth, more to him than a regiment of
                                    horse. That character is power, is true in a much higher sense than that knowledge
                                    is power. Mind, without heart, intelligence without conduct, cleverness, goodness,
                                    were power in their way, but, they may be powers only for mischief/ We may be
                                    instructed or amused by them, but it is -difficult, sometimes, to admire them, as it
                                    would be to admire the dexterity of a pickpocket, or the horsemanship of a
                                    highwayman. Truthfulness, integrity, and goodness, qualities that hang not on any
                                    man's breath, form the essence of manly character, or, as one of the old writers has
                                    it, that inbred loyalty unto Virtue, that can serve her without a livery. When
                                    Stephen of Coloma fell into the hands of base assailants, and they asked him in
                                    derision, Where now is your fortress ? Here, was his bold reply, placing his hand
                                    upon his heart ! It is in misfortune that the character of the upright man shines
                                    forth with the greatest lustre, and when all else fails, he takes a stand upon his
                                    integrity and courage. Virtue is a power in itself for good ; on the other hand,
                                    knowledge is power for good, only as it is allied to virtue. Unsanctified kuowledge
                                    is often a tower of strength in society. A character, in its nearest perfection,
                                    combines the three — virtue, religion and knowledge. These form the safeguard of a
                                    nation, and are objects of the highest importance in the state ! Young men should
                                    early lay the foundations of a good character, lay them deep in integrity and truth,
                                    s,o deep that the storms of life shall not prevail to overthrow them. Thus shall
                                    they find favor in the eyes of their fellow men.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dover Gazette" TEIform="index"/>The Dover Gazette</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rulings of 'The golden rule'" TEIform="index"/> RULINGS OF "THE GOLDEN RULE"</head><p TEIform="p"> For one to have the spirit and life of Christ is to be like Christ, and for one to be like
                            Christ is to secure all that heaven has for any man. We shall be free from temptation only
                            when we are free from sin. WTe shall be free from evil desires only when we are pure in
                            heart. The moment that any one rightly apprehends Christ in his life and death, in his
                            saving, teaching and grace5 he will gladly accept him as Saviour and Lord. " Christian union
                            is well," says Phillips Brooks, " but no courtesies between two regiments ever yet defeated
                            the other army." Have bickering, or jealousies, or exclusiveness ever done it, either? When
                            the apostle said " for me to live is Christ, to die is gain," he gave utterance to a
                            sentiment which has made the Christian world earnest in practical righteousness, and happy
                            in the thought of its reward. If we daily seek those things which are true, lovely and of
                            good report, the life beyond will be the fulfillment of our grandest plans, the realization
                            of our highest ambitions, the completion of all we desired and lived for here. Some people
                            talk about heaven as though it were located on some high bluff, so many feet wide and long,
                            walled in with a high, strong fence, and its mansions built with brown stone fronts. But it
                            is rather a blessed state of being; its security is its holiness, and its location is with
                            Christ, wherever that is, and no one will be kept out who is like Christ in spirit and life.
                        </p></div2><pb n="189" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright hope star" TEIform="index"/>THE BRIGHT HOPE STAR. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shultz, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Shults. Canaan, N. Y. </byline><p TEIform="p">1 Heavenly guid thro' the pilgrimage here, So long is the journey and dreary, 2. Heavenly
                            Pilot, far out on the sea, The billows are surging forever, 3. Heavenly Captain, the contest
                            of life Is raging in terror around me, I cannot walk thro' the valley alone, O give me thy
                            staff lest I weary! Launch my frail bark on the waters for me, And give me the oar of
                            endeavor; Give me thy faith lest I fail in the strife, And strength lest the tumult confound
                            me; And when the shadows of life close around, And coldly the night winds are blowing,
                            Struggling alone 'mid the darkness and gloom, All vainly I'm seemingly driven, I would not
                            fail in the battle today, Nor suffer my foes to defeat me, If I can see the bright hope-star
                            above, All cheerfully I will be going. But I will look to the light-house beyond, That
                            shines from the harbor of heaven. But in thy strength I will struggle and pray, That mine
                            might be triumph and vic'try. </p></div2><pb n="190" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto.</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boy Jesus" TEIform="index"/>Boy Jesus
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fox, Norman" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The infant Jesus has been a favorite subject in Christian art and Christian thought.
                                But the boy Jesus-the Jesus of eight or ten years' old - seldom comes into view. Nor is
                                it strange that it has been difficult to gain a satisfactory conception of Him. Religion
                                in its ancient and its medieval type was remarkably ascetic. And even in evangelical
                                circles in our own day, true piety is deemed - if not gloomy - yet not easily coalescing
                                with the fresher emotions of every-day life. It is stilJ too often conceived of as
                                something unearthly, something apart from ordinary human feelings. But the
                                characteristics of a genuine boy are animation, glee, an exuberance of animal spirit. We
                                find it not entirely easy, therefore, to combine the idea of deepest piety with what we
                                know of boy nature. And so it is difficult to form a clear conception of the boy Jesus.
                                But let us make the attempt. We may and probably should think of Him as a strong,
                                healthy boy. 'I'he Jews were a noteworthy people physica.lly as well as intellectually.
                                'I'heir soldiers were tough soldiers, and the toils which Jesus afterward went through
                                would indicate that He had a strong physical constitution. Nowif He had such a
                                constitution He must have had a boy's muscular restlessness and activity. We must think
                                of Him therefore as ever active ; as running when He might just as well walk; as
                                leaping and jumping and taking a thousand unnecessary steps simply to relieve His
                                muscles which are aching to be exercised, which are demanding in every fibre that they
                                be trained for what in aft1i" years they must do and endure. And so we must think of Him
                                as a joyful boy, as one to whom existence is a pleasure in itself, as the lamb frisking
                                on the hillside on a bright spring morning finds a joy in merely living. We must think
                                of Him as so thoroughly charged with animal spirits that merely to feel His own life
                                makes Him laugh and shout, with irrepressible glee. And if we would' gain an idea of His
                                personal appearance we' can gather it from the characteristics of any: group of good
                                looking little Jewish boys we: pass on the street, thinking of Him as a well: built lad:
                                handsome, at least with the pleasant look which always comes from a good heart; with
                                olive complexion, dark curling hair, dark eyes, and, to make this picture complete, we
                                must add a slightly prominent nose. And iutol lectual ly we must think of Him as a boy.
                                It would destroy the picture of His i nfuncy to imagine Him talking philosophy in His
                                cradle, to imagine Him as merely pretending to be an infant. And so to think of Him as a
                                real boy we must think of Him as possessing merely a boy's intellect. The', fact that He
                                "increased in wisdom" shows that in His human nature He did not have: all wisdom at the
                                first. The story of His, talking with the doctors in the temple pre. sents Him as an
                                unusually intelligent and thoughtful lad, but does not necessarily imply any thing
                                miraculous. Many a boy of twelve years of age has some very deep thoughts to pass
                                through his mind. Doubt-. less He often found it hard work to learn', His lessons-a fact
                                which may bring Him; nearer to many a boy who has trouble with his tasks. Jesus' mind,
                                like His body, had; to grow. It is not hard to picture to ourselves Il. Jew boy of
                                Nazareth. But can that boy bei' our Jesus? Can we add to this portrait the, idea of
                                Heavenly purity - of absolute sin-. lessneas, of perfect love to God? Why not'i May not
                                a boy be a true boy and yet be sin-; less? May he not laugh and shout and; romp and
                                play, and yet love his parents, and love his playmates - never inj uring:; their
                                feelings in any way, but doing every; duty to them? Certainly he can, and why: mav he
                                not also love God and do his whole duty to God? What sin - what shortcoms ing - what
                                evil of thought, word or act i~ necessary to the full idea of a genuine boy 1: None
                                whatever. 'l'herefore the boy 0 Nazareth may have been a true boy - ' thorough boy - and
                                yet the sinless One. The idea of the boy Jesus is one to be<pb n="191" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 191 studied by boys. If Jesus was once a true boy, why may not any boy
                                be a follower of Jesus? A boy needs religion as much as a man. The play-ground has its
                                temptations — it lias its trials and sorrows — it has its duties —the same as the scenes
                                of later life — and the boy, just the same as the man, needs the help of Jesus to meet
                                these trials and duties. The idea of the boy Jesus should be studied by parents, pastors
                                and teachers of boys. Nay, does not every man need to study this idea, as in some
                                respect the most perfect combination of the divine and the human—the intertwining of
                                deepest piety with the most active scenes of every-day life 1</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics.</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chester muffins" TEIform="index"/>Chester muffins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Chester Muffins. — Four quarts flour, teacup sugar, teacup butter, cup yeast, four eggs,
                                little salt, two quarts sweet milk. Let rise all night.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vermilion" TEIform="index"/>Vermilion
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Vermilion.— Vermilion is a mixture of sulphur and mercury, and is frequently found to
                                turn to a dark brown color if exposed to the atmosphere. A remedy for this is. said to
                                be to add one-eighth part flour of Sulphur to the paint when mixing. To detect
                                adulteration in vermilion, place a little on a red hot iron; if pure, it will evaporate
                                entirely; if not, there will be an earthy residue.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Excellent dentifrice" TEIform="index"/>Excellent dentifrice
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Excellent Dentifrice. — Dissolve two ounces of borax in three pints of hot rain water.
                                Add to it one tablespoonful of spirits of camphor, stirred into one tablespoonful of
                                pulverized sugar, to prevent it from curdling. Before quite cold, add ounce of tincture
                                of myrrh. One wineglassful,added to half a pint of water, and applied with a brush, and
                                as a gargle, will preserve and beautify the teeth, and prevent the adhesion of tartar
                                and the softening of the gums, arrest decay and keep the teeth in good condition.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To clean silk dresses" TEIform="index"/>To clean silk dresses
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To Clean Silk Dresses.—Scrape several large potatoes and put a pint of cold water over
                                them. When it has settled, pour it off; spread your silk upon the table, and wet with a
                                sponge a small part of the silk, and iron with a flat-iron just a little warmer than you
                                can handle with your hands bare. If it is too hot it will injure the silk. A
                                correspondent says: " I have just done over an old dress that I have had four years, and
                                it looks almost as well as new."</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make calicoes wash well" TEIform="index"/>To make calicoes wash well
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To Make Calicoes Wash Well.—Infuse three gills of salt in four quarts of boiling water;
                                put the calicoes in while hot, and leave them till cold ; in this way the colors are
                                rendered permanent, and will not fade by . subsequent washing. So says a lady who has
                                frequently made the experiment herself. Nothing can be cheaper and more quickly
                            done.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Raw cabbage" TEIform="index"/>Raw cabbage
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Raw Cabbage.— A nice way to prepare raw cabbage is as follows: Select a fine, good head
                                ; chop finely in a bowl what you think will be needed, and to every quart add one-half
                                teacupfulof thick sweet cream; two tablespoonsful of strong vinegar or lemon juice ; one
                                cupful of white sugar, and mix thoroughly.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cooked cabbage" TEIform="index"/>Cooked cabbage
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cooked Cabbage. — Cut fine as for raw ; put into a kettle and add water to cook until
                                tender; then add one-half cup of sweet cream ; one-half cup of vinegar, in which mix one
                                tablespoonful of flour; season with pepper and salt to suit the taste ; let it boil up
                                and serve.—Rural.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some, by nailing down their windows..." TEIform="index"/>Some, by nailing down their windows...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some, by nailing down their windows to keep out burglars, shut out their very best friend
                                — pure atmospheric air. By so fixing the windows that the upper sash can be dropped a
                                few inches only, the air can be admitted, while the burglar cannot enter, but by violent
                                means. It would be better to risk danger from burglars than to procure sure death by
                                shutting out the air.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washing floors" TEIform="index"/>Washing floors
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Washing Floors.—Floors should never be flooded with water, as is the too-common practice.
                                Use as little water as practicable. Avoid hot soap-suds — it softens the boards and
                                renders them rough ; disintegrates the grain of the wood, causing splinters. Oil (or if
                                desirable on old floors, paint) and wipe them with a wrung-out mop in warm water, and
                                your floor will be smooth and hard, and last longer than if drenched with water, or the
                                frequent use of soap. Save your floors, your soap, your muscles and your feelings.</p></div3></div2><pb n="192" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theology of the heart" TEIform="index"/>THE THEOLOGY OF THE HEART.</head><p TEIform="p">0 vet we trust that somehow good Will be the final goal of ill, To pangs of nature, sins of
                            will, Defects of doubt and taints of blood; That nothing walks with aimless feet; That not
                            one life shall be destroy'd, Or cast as rubbish to the void, When God hath made the pile
                            complete ; That uot a worm is cloven in vain ; That not a moth with vain desire Is shrivl'd
                            in a fruitless fire, Or but subserves another's gain. Behold, we know not any thing ; I can
                            but trust that good shall fall At last—far off—at last to all, And every winter change to
                            spring. So runs my dream ; but what am I? An infant crying in the night: An infant crying
                            for the light; And with no language but a cry. The wish, that of the living whole No life
                            may fall beyond the grave, Derives it not from what we have The likest God within the soul ?
                            Are God and nature then at strife, That nature lends such evil dreams ? So careful of the
                            type she seems, So careless of the single life; That I, considering everywhere Her secret
                            meaning in her deeds, And finding that of fifty seeds She often brings but one to bear, 1
                            falter where I firmly trod, And falling with my weight of cares Upon the great world's altar
                            vstairs That slope thro' darkness up to God, I stretch lame hands of faith, and grope, And
                            gather dust and chaff, and call To what I feel is Lord of all, And faintly trust the larger
                            hope. —B7rom Tennyson's "In Memoriarn:</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tennyson" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>LET THESE THINGS BE CORRECTED.</head><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge Choate recently ruled..." TEIform="index"/>Judge Choate recently ruled...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Judge Choate recently ruled that a Chinaman cannot be naturalized under the laws of the
                                United States. The application was made by a Chinaman known as Charles Miller, who has
                                lived in New York for twentyeight years. He was guided by the decision of Judge Sawyer,
                                of California, in the Ah Yup case, when thirteen hundred Chinamen petitioned that
                                schools might be provided for them, as for Indians and negroes, and showed that in San
                                Francisco alone they were paying $42,000 in school taxes. Judge Sawyer refused their
                                petition, though it asked only that he would carry out a provision of the Constitution
                                of the State.</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An interested party in the settlement..." TEIform="index"/>An interested party in the settlement...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">An interested party in the settlement of the Jay Cooke estate complains that two
                                attorneys have been employed by the receiver, whose fees amount to $75,000, and that a
                                committee of creditors who were expected to serve without pay have already received
                                $34,480. It is a well-known fact that the commissioners in bankruptcy all over the
                                country are growing rapidly rich out of the decay and dissipation of fortunes.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Learn wisdom by sufferings" TEIform="index"/>Learn wisdom by sufferings
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Learn Wisdom by Sufferings.— " The costume of the Persian women is the handsomest upon
                                the face of the earth. It consists of a loose waist, short skirt, and trousers not too
                                loose. I have made this costume beautifully and hung it up in Paris, but the women will
                                not wear it. I can do nothing more. They must suffer until they are willing to adopt
                                it." This is the testimony of Worth, the celebrated Parisian modiste.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rev. E. E. Hale, in his Easter sermon..." TEIform="index"/>Rev. E. E. Hale, in his Easter sermon...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Rev. E. E. Hale, in his Easter sermon, said that the formulation of the belief that "
                                Christianity is a life," which the world owes to Channing, has passed through the three
                                stages which Agassiz once wittily said every important scientific discovery experi enced
                                : " First it is said not to be true ; next that ' we have always taught it;' and last
                                that ' nobody ever doubted it.'"</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are many Christian people..." TEIform="index"/>There are many Christian people...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> " There are many Christian people who think that Christ is going to come to the earth
                                again, and reign personally. I am not ready to reject that theory; but if Christ does
                                come to our world again, I believe He will find a Mount Zion in this land, and will set
                                up His throne between the Alleghanies and the Rocky Monntains, and will walk the streets
                                of our American cities. In that millennial day there will be one denomination of
                                Christians far ahead of all others, if it have not swallowed them all up. Would you like
                                to know what denomination it will be? I will tell you. It will be that denomination
                                which has worked the hardest, trusted the fullest, loved the mightiest, and eclipsed all
                                others in the spirit of Christian toleration."</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>