<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0709" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18770901" TEIform="date">September 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER, OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " H** $rent\ the kingdom off
                        (§od! ** f^he testimony aft eternal truth. Yol. YI. \ G. A. LOMAS, Editor, J \ Shakers, N. Y. )
                        SEPTEMBER, 1877. ( N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher, ) I Shaker Village, N. H. ] No. 9.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH MARTIN</byline><p TEIform="p">How we love to meet a soul whose influence breathes peace, and such are they who cultivate in
                            their hearts the beautiful gift of universal love. When inexperience blinds our eyes, and
                            error leads us where we would not go, how truly then we appreciate that love whose gentle
                            acts speak thus: " I will sacrifice for thee ; thou art a portion of my sacred interest;
                            material trials cannot come between my soul and thine to mar nor divide ; but I will take
                            thee by the hand and pray for thee that thy strength fail not; till thine error is
                            conquered, and thou canst walk securely in the right-hand path, where virtue reigns. Purity
                            has paved the way; righteousness and peace illumine the .course ; strait as straitness, pure
                            as the heavens, thou canst not lose thy way." How it melts our souls ! How we love to clasp
                            so warm a hand, and find our reliance in so pure a heart! Surely, if before we felt
                            forsaken, now we feel the cloud of despondency lifted up, and one of God's messengers sent
                            to tell us of that love that " saves to the uttermost" that pure spirit of God dwelling in
                            the bosom of humanity ; and we voluntarily say we will sacrifice also. O, what a rich
                            treasure is pure, disinterested love ! How priceless the gem ! God created it. It is one of
                            the attributes of God. When he made man "in his own image," he infused this divine nature in
                            his being to bring forth fruits of righteousness and peace on earth, and make man truly only
                            a " little lower than the angels." But how has he perverted this Godgiven faculty of the
                            mind ! How has it become dimmed and cankered in the vortex of selfish passions! God calls
                            upon his children through the Christ spirit, to cultivate anew this heaven-born germ
                            implanted in the soul. He says: "Give me thy heart." Let us put forth thy hands in active
                            love,—be jealous over the interests of our brother and sister, through our own
                            self-sacrifice; "weep with those who weep"—let their sufferings touch our souls as our own
                            heart-griefs. We will " rejoice with those who do rejoice" in refined thanksgiving, for love
                            is harmony. Love is the greatest saving power,—'tis the "balm in Gilead " to soothe and make
                            whole. Love is selfdenying, and quickens the spirit in confidence toward its Creator, for
                            "Perfect 1 ove casteth out fear." What an Eden would this world be . bad man obeyed the
                            command, "Love . the Lord thy God with all thy heart," : and "thy neighbor as thyself." Love
                            ] lever slanders, never deceives, is not suspicious, not envious nor selfish. It delights to
                            speak well of its brother,— speak truthfully to him,—believes him sincere, and denies itself
                            for his happiless. Let us all cultivate love toward each other. We do not know the magnitude
                            of its holy influence on the minds of those around us. Let us speak in the tone of love, and
                            in the spirit of love, ind pray for a daily draught from the unfailing fountain of eternal
                            heavenly love, to cement us soul to soul. We must love ! We have sacrificed the carnal and
                            natural relations of this life, and our affections reach out to love. Let them be interwoven
                            in and through the pure Christian relationship. Let their roots be planted in that
                            foundation " pure as crystal," and their vines, entwining around the "oaks" in Zion. grow
                            strong and able to bring forth fruits of love unto the Lord,—a chastened spirit, a virgin
                            soul, the perfection of gospel graces. Let the aged feel th at we love and revere them ; for
                            they are needy and worthy of all we can bestow, and their blessing in return is a golden
                            link, joining us to the love of friends in the "better land." Let us love the middle-aged ;
                            on them devolve the burdens of this encumbered life, and love buoys and supports the soul.
                            Let us love the young. Ah, the young,— They need the love whose breath is prayer, To guide
                            their wayward steps—¦ To lead them to that anchor—where Their souls in God can rest. And let
                            us love the infant mind, yet ignorant of life's hidden snares and trying burdens. Amid our
                            hours of watching and weariness, let us not forget to love their souls, but gently lead
                            them, stamping the impress of love upon their tender hearts, ere they are seared by cold,
                            selfish neglect. How desolate would be the pathway of life, did not some sun of true, pure
                            love sometimes arise above the horizon of our vision, when our hope and faith seem eclipsed
                            with trial, to enliven and refresh with its bright anc glorious rays. A cheerful
                            countenance, a pure language, a gentle voice, a willing hand ¦ I are all notes of harmonyv
                            whose combined tones, vibrating on the chords of the soul, breathe the sweet music of Love,
                            lifting our thoughts to God and heaven. Let us all learn to "play these sweet keys," and
                            make our earth a paradise, and its inhabitants angels. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian charity" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN CHARITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">And now abideth Faith and Hope And Charity—these three ; The greatest one with which we cope,
                            Is Christian Charity. Do patiently and meekly bear The plain and wholesome truth,— The ills
                            of life, its wear and tear, And waywardness of youth, Requires that Christian charity, The
                            Christian only knows, Who cultivates among the three, The smiling, blooming rose. ?or though
                            we have the miner's wealth, His mass of glittering gold, And—greatest of earth's
                            blessings—health,— And gifts, a hundred fold, Yea, though we speak with tongues of men, In
                            eloquence most free, And wield the sage's magic pen, Yet, have not charity, We prove
                            ourselves as " sounding brass," Or " tinkling cvmbals " shoal; And when to spirit life we
                            pass, Remorse will fill the soul. Come, then, each fair professing saint. Let each our lives
                            review, And whatsoever proves a taint, We'll cleanse and start anew. But, deepest of all
                            sinful hues, Uncharity we find Discloses to our sight a bruise Upon the feeble mind, Too
                            deep and painful to behold, Without a shedding tear; The aching heart so void and cold, With
                            love we would not cheer! But let us now Love's healing balm, W ith constancy apply, And
                            every rising tempest calm, That clouds a sunny sky. The young and tender buds, that need The
                            nourishment of life, To cherish with parental heed, Shall be our future strife. Our blessed
                            Savior's words shall be Engraven with each thought, " Let little children come to me, And
                            none forbid them not." We'll draw each little trusting mind So closely to our own, That safe
                            protection they may find Within our walls of home. And though advancing days of youth
                            Increase each anxious care. And where we've sown the seeds of truth, We find the pois'nous
                            tare, We will not hopelessly repine, And in our weakness say, Behold the fruitless waste of
                            time, Our work all thrown away! But strive we will with Christian zeal, Each youthful heart
                            to bless, Although we may not always feel Returns of gratefulness, We ever will the right
                            maintain, And keep a spirit mild, With anxious feelings, to reclaim The wayward youth or
                            child. Thus like our Savior we may be, In Zion, saviors too; Promoting peace and purity, In
                            all we say and do. Uplifting in affliction's hour, The weary, fainting soul; Employing all
                            our time and power To strengthen young and old. Our blessed parents, who have trod The path
                            we now pursue, Have gathered many souls to God, And this now we may do. If we, with equal
                            charity, Forgive, and long forbear, With manifested parity, • Their gospel mantles wear; So
                            we, like them, may gather souls, From darkness, sin and loss; And as development unfolds,
                            Sustain them in the cross. Oh Charity, sweet Charity ! Thy sufferance is long! And " chief
                            among the blessed three," Thou conquerest all wrong. We'll wear thee as a garment fair,
                            Throughout our journey here, And let each word and act declare Thy presence ever near. And
                            in the good time yet to be, When from our toils we rest, Our grateful children we shall see
                            Rise up and call us blest.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Righteous vengeance" TEIform="index"/>Righteous vengeance
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Righteous vengeance.—Some one having urged Tasso to avenge himself upon a man who had done
                            him many injuries, he said: "I wish to take from him neither his property, nor his life, nor
                            his honor, but only his ill-will towards me."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession and absolution" TEIform="index"/>CONFESSION AND ABSOLUTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederick W." TEIform="persName"/>FREDERICK W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">In England, there is national excitement about the Eastern War; about the Bradlaugh and
                            Bessant book, how to check population, and also an ecclesiastical excitement about a new
                            book—"The Priest in Absolution." This book gives minute directions to the priests of the
                            high church party, to whom it is issued, how to question the penitent. As all the Protestant
                            priests, like their Catholic fathers, are of the " Lords of creation" order, this gives
                            unutterable offence to the anti-popery classes of the reformation. The ritualists are
                            lapsing back into the old mother of harlots' bosom. Confession and absolution are taught,
                            and Episcopal convents and nunneries are already established by ithe hundred, The mother and
                            her <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 THE SHAKER. harlot daughters are vitalized by the same "blood of
                            Jesus," and at their sacraments, eat his flesh—spiritual cannibalism. In war, monopoly and
                            marriage, they are one. Punch expresses the English mind thus: PUNCH TO THE PRIESTLY PAUL
                            PRYS. Bah ! 'Tis a loathsome task; a piece of work That Punch, as well as Redesdale, fain
                            would shirk; But, lest the pestfshould suck fresh life from doubt, " War to the knife ! "
                            the tocsin must ring out. Stand up, you priestly Prys! Sham Roman pranks, Mock-monkish
                            tricks we look for from your ranks— Matters of course, as ills familiar borne, Or
                            flagellated with half-careless scorn ; But when the gnats that pester, poison too, They must
                            be crushed—and so, Jack-priests, must you. What poison worse than the foul cankerworm's,
                            Dropped in the germ to blight the opening bud ? Nor casuistwrigglings, nor sophistic
                            squirms, Henceforth- can clear you ; it should stir the blood Even of Gallios, whom your
                            mummeries irk No more than puppet-posturings, to see The leaven of your impious piety In
                            black and white once more at its foul work. Hearts in these fevered days are not too clean,
                            Imaginations not too sweet. What then? You'd peep and pry into the souls of men, To scent
                            uncleanness out with snouts unclean ; You'd poke and pry upon e'en childhood's tracks For
                            the snake's trail. In maiden minds you'd wake Specters more easy raised than banished. Take
                            Your nostrums hence ! Sham spiritual quacks Must not be trusted with our household's health.
                            We dread your creep of super-subtle stealth, • Nor will we trust your fumbling hands to feel
                            About the roots of life. Let spirit deal With spirit frankly in free day-light. Learn That
                            still our English natures scorn and spurn This fleshly inquisition of the flesh, Whose
                            pryings serve no end but to enmesh Confessor and confessed in sense's snare. So stand aside,
                            let in the fresh Jun^air, With flowery breath to sweeten once again The place your presence
                            taints. ' Tis all in vain You'd burrow, mole-wise, in the dirt. Give o'er! We will not have
                            this bastard-birth of Rome— We'll guard from it the purity of home, Or crush it, like a
                            viper, at the door! "It is the old spirit of Henry the Eighth's time." " Hate the pope, the
                            man of sin, and the priests, his ministers," is the motto. Times are changed. The Protestant
                            priesthood have had their day and have now come to the day of judgment. Protestantism, in
                            England, will be displaced by the coming system, as it displaced popery. Church and state
                            will there be separated, as now in America. And, unless there is a better watch kept, church
                            and state will here be united. Either Protestant, or Catholic will gain the ascendency. To
                            liberty', it matters not which. Confession, of both sexes, to a male priesthood, is a source
                            of corruption, not purification. Such confession, and the sale of indulgences to sin, armed
                            Luther. " Priests with snouts unclean," reproving sin, is like Brooklyn churches reproving
                            filthy communications that have corrupted the good manners of the rising generations. Honest
                            John Bull hates shams. Can a solvent bank be bankrupted by counterfeits, unless itself is
                            deceived by them? Never! A true confession is good for the soul. Gold is not injured, even
                            in the crucible. When Spanish Catholics went to Mexico, they found a grand system, "with its
                            judiciary, military and priestlood, rivaling any western civilization. The priesthood was
                            dead—male and emale. Confession, as with the Shakers, was made in order. Each sex to ts own
                            priesthood. Nothing but good came of it. If a sin was repeated after confession, :here was
                            no expiation, no more forgiveness. The following is a Mexican jrayer, over a penitent: "O
                            merciful God, thou who knowest the secrets of all hearts, let thy forgiveness and favor low,
                            like the pure waters of heaven, to wash away the stain of this soul. Thou cnowest that this
                            poor man has not sinned of his own free will, but from the influence of the sign of the
                            zodiac mcler which he was born." In Mexico, the land was held by government, on )ehalf of
                            all the people. Each district supported its own inhabitants. No Door-houses. They had
                            hospitals, but the doctors did not protract cures to increase their revenues. Slavery
                            existed, )ut none were born slaves. Monasteries and nunneries were found in their great
                            temples. Temples existed by the mndred, in and around cities. Stairs wound round the pyramid
                            like structures, at each story. On the top was the great stone of sacrifice, whereon luman
                            beings were sacrificed, just as, under the Jewish priesthood, animals were killed on the
                            altars, for the same purpose—food. The Jew may eat no rlesh meat, except killed by the
                            priest. He is allowed to kill only five sorts of animals, oxen, sheep, goats, pigeons,
                            doves. Abram came near to the Mexicans when he purposed to sacrifice his own son Isaac. It
                            was in his heart to do it. "The hand of Jacob held fast the heel of Esau." The Mexicans
                            sacrificed from 20,000 to 100,000 yearly. The victims consisted of two classes, prisoners of
                            war and criminals. Occasionally, a notable victim, like Isaac, was called for. The victims
                            were generally well treated, even pampered and feted, by the aristocracy. The Spanish
                            priesthood sacrificed as many human beings—men, women and children, in their infernal
                            inquisitions, as the Mexicans offered in sacrifice. And they, as heretics, were tortured to
                            death, then sent into endless hell-fire. Whether the Spanish auto de fe, or the Mexican
                            procession, winding up, up, round and round, to the stone of sacrifice, was the most
                            debasing to the people, I leave for others to decide. The Mexican was awfully grand and
                            terrifically impressive, being plainly seen at a great distance. The Spanish was infernally
                            suggestive of an eternal state of devilish torment. May both be supplanted by a better
                            system. Is not the Protestant atoning sacrifice of Jesus, his blood to be drank and bathed
                            in as a fountain, the eating of his flesh, as in the Catholic and Greek churches, in
                            sacrament, a relic of a former state of Mexican cannibalism? Do not all these bloody systems
                            begin with the habit of killing and eating all sorts of animals? If marriage is legalized
                            licentiousness, private property, as now in operation, legalized robbery, war, legalized
                            nurder, modern cookery, a means of wandering to an abnormal, unregulated appetite, that
                            calls for legalized druggery, what had we better do about them ? Call the death roll, close
                            up our ranks, and read in the August number of The Shaker, under '¦'•Signs of the Times,"
                            the argument of a writer in the Boston Traveller, upon "Fruit Culture and Human
                        Progress."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hunting for the sunbeam" TEIform="index"/>HUNTING FOR THE SUNBEAM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">Of all life's recreations, There's none so dear to me As hunting for the sunbeam, Wherever I
                            may be. I find it often hidden Down in the mourner's eye, Or glistening from the cloud-bank
                            Beneath a winter's sky. It blushes in the rose-bud, And wakes it into bloom ; It gives the
                            heath its beauty, And violet its perfume ; It rouses Spring from dreaming Of fragrant buds
                            and bowers, And starts the harvest teeming With golden sheaves and flowers. Earth has no
                            grand specific For hearts that throb with pain, Like pouring in the sunbeams Till smiles
                            come back again. Oft when my heart is burdened Beyond what heart can bear, I gather in the
                            sunbeams, And all is happy there. Would all my j'oung companions Who list to me to-day, But
                            gather in the sunbeams And store them all away; They'd find this world so beautiful They'd
                            only wonder why So many seek for heaven Beneath a clouded sky.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers, no. 5" TEIform="index"/>Epitomic History of the
                            Watervliet Shakers, No. 5</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">EDUCATION. Previous to the year 1818, very little attention had been paid to literature.
                            There were no schools then established in the Society, and but little done in teaching the
                            young "idea how to shoot," as far as book knowledge was concerned. What had been done in the
                            line of instruction was performed, principally, in the separate families where the children
                            resided, in what is now termed " Private or Evening Schools." But, during the year 1823, a
                            brick school-house was erected, sufficiently large to accommodate twenty-five or thirty
                            pupils, and a regular day school was established, in which the common branches of education
                            were successfully taught, such as reading, writing, arithmetic, geography, grammar and
                            spelling. From that time to the present, our schoo' has been gradually advancing. The school
                            commissioners of our town and county, who have often inspected it, give it their approval,
                            and call it a wellorganized and a well-disciplined school. In addition to the
                            above-mentioned tranches of literature, we have since ntroduced others, viz : history,
                            astronomy, geometry, philosophy, physiology, drawing, algebra, and written composition. We
                            have adopted the free-school system of instruction ; in which the district urnishes all the
                            apparatus necessary— jooks, maps, charts, blackboards, &amp;c, and every child in the
                            district, if able, s required to attend ; males in the winter and spring, and females in the
                            summer and autumn. We have a district school library of over three hundred volumes of
                            selected 3ooks, including science, literature, history, biography, agriculture,
                            horticulture, chemistry, botany, philosophy, Dhysiology, morality, &amp;c, &amp;c,
                            in which is included sixteen volumes of the "New American Cyclopedia," a little world of
                            information within itself. This library las been in operation from the year 1846, to which
                            additions have been annually made. In order to establish a uniform method of instruction, in
                            which the different societies of Believers might all participate, Seth Y. Wells, of Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y., a well-educated, scientific man and brother, was duly authorized by the
                            leaders of our institution, to make a tour throughout the eastern societies of our people,
                            for the purpose of encouraging, regulating and establishing more permanently, the schools in
                            that vicinity. It was about this time that the Lancasterian mode of instruction was in
                            vogue, and he being in favor, and rather an advocate for that system, adopted it wherever he
                            taught. He Certainly did much in promoting the intellectual culture of the young in those
                            parts, even as he had done previously in the societies at Mt. Lebanon and Watervliet. It has
                            ever been, as it still is, the design of our institution, to train up the children which we
                            have taken and adopted, " in the way they should go," endeavoring to infuse into their young
                            and tender minds the genuine principles of truth and honesty. Children taken among us on
                            trial, if they wish to remain with us, although they have had no previous chance for
                            education, we endeavor to give them a fair opportunity, with others, as we sympathize-with
                            them greatly. Yet we find, where they have had no previous training, it is the more
                            difficult to raise them to an honorable standing by which they can accomplish the business
                            and common duties of life. Some children, on presenting themselves, or when being presented
                            by their parents and guardians, are hardly familiar with the letters of the alphabet, who
                            have arrived to the age of ten or twelve years. This should not have been so in any district
                            of our great state and country. The poor should be cared for ; and if the parents of such
                            children are too poor to educate <pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 67 them, some other means
                            should be provided by the district, town or county where they belong. The rich should help
                            the poor. In taking children among us, if we are pleased with them and they with us, by the
                            consent of their parents or guardians, we adopt them as our own ; and after having been
                            adopted, we feel that they are ours, and take special interest in their welfare and
                            protection ; as much so as though we were their natural parents, and were the immediate
                            cause of their coming into the world. Their sorrows become our sorrow, and their joys our
                            joy. We love them, sympathize with them, and are pleased with their innocence and
                            simplicity. But on the other hand, we are often grieved to see the vulgar traits—the base
                            conduct and conversation—of some children offered us, who have become acquainted with all
                            the vile trickery afloat in the world. Yet, even in this, we cast a cloak of charity over
                            them, and so sympathize with them that we would gladly raise them out of it, considering
                            that their parents, guardians or associates are quite as much to blame as themselves, in
                            very many cases. The example set them by those that are older, is, many times, very
                            demoralizing, and upon this class must rest much of the accountabilityIf parents and
                            guardians of children, after placing them among the Shakers would be satisfied to let them
                            alone, 01 remain with the people unmolested, i would be very much to the benefit o: the
                            children, as well as to the comfor of the people where such children are placed. By frequent
                            visits, with some few trifling presents, of little or no value parents often keep their
                            children in an unsettled state of mind, discontentec and unhappy, not being able to feel tha
                            they have really an abiding home any where. Children under such circum stances, are not able
                            to make their own choice as to the life they would prefer or be pleased to live—whether to
                            be a Shaker or not—for they have not beei left by their former friends and acquaint ances
                            long enough to feel and appreci ate the kind affections extended toward them by their
                            generous Shaker friends Children among us, when arrived a maturity, by our Church Covenant
                            have a right to choose for themselve what course they will take ; and if the} do not wish to
                            abide with us, and be come one of us, they are at liberty t leave. But we do not obligate
                            our selves to bring up or retain childre among us who are obstinate and rebel ious,
                            unwilling to yield to good mora discipline and religious instruction Neither do we take
                            children to educat or bring up for outside society merely with the understanding that we hav
                            no claim upon them whatever, whe their relatives or acquaintances ma please to demand them.
                            As befor stated, we take and adopt children fo the purpose of making Shakers of them if
                            possible. And if any are not willin their children should become^ Shakei n mature years,
                            they had better not jring them, nor seek to find a location :or them, as children, in our
                            Society.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical and spiritual harmony" TEIform="index"/>Physical and Spiritual Harmony</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>ANDREW BARRETT</byline><p TEIform="p">In perusing the well-filled columns four little Messenger, my eyes rested ipon the important
                            article, "How to ive, and live aright." Every agitation, or troubling of the waters on this
                            subect, meets my approbation ; and the ame of many more, who are trying to ive out the true
                            manner of life, physially, that in truth we may enjoy the Tuitions of the angel life. If we
                            have found the new life, and are approaching nearer the source of ife, do we not think less
                            of mere husks? ess of the exterior of things and more of the heart of things ? Do we not
                            beieve, more than heretofore, that the hings which are seen are temporal, and he things
                            which are not seen, eternal? If we care for our bodies, is it not that they may become
                            tabernacles other than for sensuous enjoyment? hat they may become the fittest possible
                            instruments for mental culture, moral and spiritual unfoldings? The spirit is the motive
                            power. Its operation upon our physical forms is similar to the steam upon the engine. And
                            how necessary it is to have every part of that engine in proper working order, if there is
                            to be a harmony of movements. But let a cog be broken, or a shaft misplaced, can it perform
                            its office ? So appears to me to be the case with the spirit and body. Can a diseased body
                            have a healthy spirit? Will they work together in harmony ? Can they enjoy the blessings
                            that the Creator has ordained them to enjoy? Is that body fulfilling God's purposes? Then
                            why not make it one of the great aims of life to know how to live ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 10" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way. No. 10</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">Just now I am somewhat interested in the demonstrations of light which I find circulating so
                            quietly, and yet so effectually, in the minds of men. Ii fact, I think the more interest we
                            take in any of the moral or religious phase of life, the more we shall see wherein the hand
                            of a kind Providence is gradu ally unfolding to the children of men more clearly and fully,
                            the "ways o pleasantness and the paths of peace. History informs us that there has been a
                            stone age, an iron age, and a golden age. Very well; if they proved satis factory to those
                            who lived amid thei especial influences, we should rejoic for their sakes. We have the
                            culmina tion of them all, and a manifestation o: light and life far exceeding. We hav heard
                            that those who dwell in splen did residences sometimes occupy fo years the rear apartments
                            of the builc ing, which are more or less obscurec by blinds or shutters, while they re serve
                            in darkness, the parlor or draw ing-room for an anticipated compan lat never arrives, thus
                            depriving themelves of the thousand and one blessings which the beautiful sunshine would
                            confer upon them. Possibly there may be men who, having exalted faculties of the mind, as
                            foolishly close their best apartments to the light, and hide themselves away to ponder over
                            some physiological, social, or theological problem, —the elucidation of which, to themselves
                            only, is the salvation of the world,—forgetting that the deprivation of either one may
                            render us very unhappy. He who teaches the imperative necessity of chastity of body may be
                            doing as much to establish the kingdom of God upon earth as the one who is singing psalms.
                            If the knowledge of the Lord, in this favored age, fails " to cover the land," it must be
                            admitted that it dwells largely among men. It is found up-springing on every side. A
                            prominent New England divine writes : " Woe to him who subtly brings evil upon;' another."
                            "In all your growth then, seek after goodness." " In your ambitions, in your way of talking,
                            in your style of doing business, in the expression of your religiousness, in your words and
                            feelings even, you are copied by others. The soul has its children as truly as the body. In
                            the judgment they will come to you and claim you as parents." From the author of "Man and
                            his Relations," we quote : "So intimate is the relation between the body and the mind, that
                            they act reciprocally and powerfully on each other. Especially does the mind exert a mighty
                            influence, for weal or woe, over the body. The mental and vital acting are so inseparable
                            that every silent emotion and unspoken thought leaves an image—dim and shadowy it may be—in
                            the organic structure. The vital fluids flow fast or slow, as the mind is excited, or is
                            permitted to repose." " Moral education, without which there is nothing of literature or of
                            science, but is liable to be perverted to the worst purposes, is to be begun in infancy. The
                            first step is to teach the child implicit obedience to parental authority, and then to rule
                            with such moderation and sweetness, that it shall en tirely trust and love the hand tha
                            guides it. Nor is it precept alone tha will suffice. Though precept upon pre cept be given,
                            and their memories be stored with moral and religious love o: the first kind, it will be of
                            little avai except a corresponding example b daily practiced before their eyes." It must be
                            a source of great satisfac tion to the philanthropic mind to fine such earnest co-workers
                            here. Throug] the persistent efforts of this, much tha is wrong is prevented from germi
                            nating. Infancy, youth and old age ar held by moral restraint from many o' the influences
                            which are on the border of perdition. Although called from th world as evangelists to
                            testify agains the sins of the world, our order "ha not whereof to boast." The scriptural
                            injunction meets us on every hand ' Freely ye have received, freely give." .t may be wise to
                            make an examination, nd see if we are not largely occupying tie rear apartments of the mind,
                            where he treasures of this world claim the xiost attention, or are quietly resting on
                            anticipated promises in the inner temple, with the blinds closed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? no. 6" TEIform="index"/>What shall I do to be a Shaker ? No.
                            6</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">As the religious and spiritual elements are increasing every year, running parallel with the
                            destructive element, the time is coming when the question, " Men and brethren, what shall we
                            do ?" will be asked with no unmeaning sound. When the angels of correction are sent forth,
                            as they surely will be, the cry of convicted souls will not be, "What shall I do to be a
                            Shaker?" nominally —this is too sectarian to the world— but what shall we do to be saved
                            from the violation of Christian law, from which we are now suffering? This will be their
                            language: "Men and brethren, what shall we do?"—Acts 2 : 37. This will be the burden of
                            their cry. Such are sinning with their eyes open ; living in constant and perpetual
                            violation of the laws of repix&gt;duction ; the fruits thereof are manifest, which are
                            death—moral and spiritual death. What shall we do that we may live— " to inherit eternal
                            life ? " A more important question was never asked. And the answer will be, not only believe
                            on the Lord Jesus Christ, but live his life. This is eating his flesh and drinking his
                            blood, in the very deed. Keep his commandments. "We shall be saved by his life."—Romans 5 :
                            10, and not by his death. This is being saved by the blood of Christ; for what a man eats or
                            drinks makes his blood. "The blood is the life thereof." Therefore all men should be careful
                            of what they eat, and of what kind of a life they are living on the earth; whether it is any
                            better than that which Adam lived, whom so many reproach for having committed the first and
                            great sin. WHO IS A SHAKER? A real and true Shaker is one who is living the life of Christ;
                            who is living in the development of the moral and spiritual faculties—the highest, crowning
                            glory of man and woman while in the form. This is the reason why he has stood before the
                            world for the last century and proclaimed his sentiments, and is still apparently unknown ;
                            " his life is hid with Christ in God;" he is an Essenean of the nineteenth century ; hence,
                            there is no affinity existing between him and those on that plane ; he lives in the future,
                            hence he is often misrepresented in the present; having outgrown the ruditnental, he " is
                            not of the world." Thousands are being developed on the animal plane, and as many in the
                            intellectual scale, who stand in great need of a higher moral and spir- <pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>
                            68 THE SHAKER. itual development. They lack these elements as much as did one of old, who
                            said he had kept the '•'•law" from his youth up. It was never designed that man and woman,
                            of noble intellects, should always remain slaves to their perverted appetites and passions.
                            There is a "higher law" for them to keep, and moral power is given in this day to enforce
                            that law. "For now is come salvation and strength, the kingdom of our God and the power of
                            his Christ." N. Union, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful things" TEIform="index"/>Beautiful Things</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WHEELER</byline><p TEIform="p">A spirit that harbors no malice, but forgives as it would be forgiven. A soft answer given
                            when the heart prompts a harsh one. It is a beautiful thing to frankly acknowledge an error
                            we are conscious of committing toward another ; and a more enjoyable thing to know we are
                            wiping away the tears of pain our thoughtless words have caused. The ready smile of a
                            cheerful spirit, and the encouraging words of a time-tried companion, are beautiful things
                            to the eyes of angels. A friend, who loveth at all times, through evil and through good
                            report; through sorrow unto joy ; through sin and suffering unto repentance, is more
                            beautiful than the stars in the firmament above ; more to be desired than all the wealth of
                            Golconda. A pure heart is the crown of all beautiful things. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Human elevation means animal extinction" TEIform="index"/>Human Elevation means Animal
                            Extinction</head><p TEIform="p">It is well known that since mankind's advent, many species and varieties of animals have
                            become extinct. Now, is it not as reasonable to believe that when the human race shall have
                            become sufficiently refined and spiritualized to no longer need nor feed upon animals, they
                            will all disappear from the globe? And may not internal parts of the human body likewise
                            disappear? Animals are to the erection and completion of the human kingdom what scaffoldings
                            are to the construction of a dwelling. When the structure is finished the builders remove
                            the instrumentalities, so that other and higher artisans may proceed with the finer works ;
                            and after the gardens are prepared, the decorations completed, and the furniture arranged,
                            it is then natural to expect and welcome the angel of the house. And if animals are man's
                            indispensable predecessors and subordinates, are they not fully entitled to human sympathy
                            and uniform kindness?</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Davis, A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A, J. Davis</byline></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Defamation of character" TEIform="index"/>Defamation of character.</head><p TEIform="p"> An excellent old deacon, who, having won a fine turkey at a charity raffle, didn't like to
                            tell his severe Orthodox wife how he came by it, quietly remarked, as he handed her the
                            turkey, that the "Shakers gave it to him." </p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waifs" TEIform="index"/>Waifs
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is said there is not now living a single male descendant of Chaucer,
                                    Shakespeare, Spenser, Milton, Cowley, Butler, Dryden, Pope, Cowper, Goldsmith,
                                    Scott, Byron, Moore, Sir Philip Sidney, Sir Walter Raleigh, Drake, Cromwell,
                                    Hampden, Monk, Marlborough,Peterborough, Nelson,Stafford, Orrnond, Clarendon,
                                    Addison, Swift, Johnson, Walpole, Bolingbroke, Chatham, Pitt, Fox, Burke, Grattan,
                                    Canning, Bacon.Locke, Newton, Davy, Hume, Gibbon, Macaulay, Hogarth, Sir Joshua
                                    Reynolds, David Garrick, John Kemble, or Edmund Kean. The Nashville Advocate adds to
                                    the list: Isaac Watts, John Wesley, Francis Asbury, Win. M'Kendree.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian advocate" TEIform="index"/>Christian Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War" TEIform="index"/>WAR</head><p TEIform="p">The beautiful working of war as a remedy for wrongs and a compensation for injustice is being
                            strikingly illustrated in the East. The war was undertaken by Russia to revenge the
                            Bulgarian atrocities, to improve the condition of the Bulgarians and other Turkish
                            Christians, and advance Christ's kingdom generally. Already some twenty thousand men, Turks
                            and Russians, have been killed, and twice as many mangled and maimed in Armenia, besides
                            thousands who have died of disease. Thousands of Moslem and Christian homes in the track of
                            the contending armies have been devastated and the families outraged or butchered. On the
                            Danube the losses of life have thus far been less, but will be tenfold greater. The
                            Bulgarians, whom the Russians came professedly to help, are being ground into fine powder
                            between the two armies, and their fertile country has been made a complete desert on which
                            the gaunt and famine-stricken people look down mournfully from the mountains in which the
                            remnant have taken refuge. The streets of Constantinople are filled with soldiers' starving
                            wives and children, of which the correspondents tell piteous stories, and all the other
                            cities are similarly thronged. Mothers are selling their children for bread, and brothers
                            their sisters. Famine will soon count its tens of thousands of victims.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discouraged" TEIform="index"/>DISCOURAGED</head><p TEIform="p">If you cannot pray as you would, nor as you should, pray as well as you can, One of the most
                            fatal things in the Christian life is discouragement. One of the most helpful is
                            cheerfulness. A very wise man once said that in overcoming temptations, cheerfulness was the
                            first thing, cheerfulness the second, and cheerfulness the third. We must expect to conquer.
                            When our hearts are faint, then temptation has power. Satan knows this well and he begins
                            his assaults by discouraging us. I once heard an allegory that illustrated this to me
                            wonderfully. Satan called together a council of his servants to consult how they might make
                            a good man sin. One evil spirit started up and said: "I will make him sin." "How will you do
                            it?" asked Satan. "I will set before him all the pleasures of sin," was the reply; "I will
                            tell him of its delights and the rich rewards it brings." "Ah," said Satan, "that will not
                            do; he has tried it and knows better than that." Then another spirit started up and said :
                            "I will make him sin." "What will you do?" asked Satan. -'I will tell him of the pains and
                            sorrows of virtue. I will show him that virtue has no delights and brings no rewards." "Ah,
                            no!" exclaimed Satan, "that will not do at all, for he has tried it and knows that wisdom's
                            ways are ways of pleasantness and all her paths are peace." "Well," said another imp,
                            starting up, "I will undertake to make him sin." "And what will you do?" asked Satan. "I
                            -willdiscourage his soul," was the short reply. "Ah, that will do !" cried Satan. "That wall
                            do ! We shall conquer him now!" And they did. An old writer says : "All discouragement is
                            from the devil." I wish every Christian would take this to heart, and never forget it. We
                            must fly from discouragement as we would from sin.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="S., H. W." TEIform="persName"/>H. W. S. in Words of\ Faith</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Was Jesus of Nazareth a shaker?" TEIform="index"/>Was Jesus of Nazareth a Shaker?</head><p TEIform="p">The question is a direct one, and upon its decision depends the validity of our claim to the
                            Christian qualification for our church ; and the same of every denomination using the
                            definitive christian. However ready or unready the world is, to consider Shakerism as being
                            genuine Christianity, we are positively satisfied that unwarped Christianity is radical
                            Shakerism. In these days of religious deterioration, when the substitution of man-made
                            theologies for the direct demands of primitive Christianity is so prevalent, the
                            reconsideration of what radical Christianity is, and who make its requisitions their right
                            to its name, are subjects that are opportune and very proper. That Christianity is more full
                            of salvation from sin and its consequences, and more pregnant with spiritual progressions
                            from that which wTas, and may be good, to that which is far better, are reasons which
                            comprise the acts of allegiance of every consistent Christian to it. Unless Christianity
                            makes us better to-day ; more free from bad habits ; more ample in the features that
                            represent the life in the heavens, than would Judaism or any other ism, let us relinquish it
                            at once. Does popularly-called Christianity save the world from as many sins of the
                            arch-enemy, selfishness, as did Judaism? We avow, it does not. Under the popular cognomen of
                            Christianity, mankind have too generally forsaken Moses and Judaism, and at the same time
                            have evaded the more restraining, saving, elevating and self-denying principles of Jesus,
                            the Christ. Jesus invariably magnified the efficacy of the law before the people. It was
                            good ; but he had something better. Its demands were earthly and moral ; his bequests were
                            from the heavens, spiritual. To every regulation of Moses, he gave the sanction of propriety
                            for all followers of Moses; and did he live to-day, would do the same. Thus, marriage was
                            good for Jews and heathens, but not for Christians, his followers ; and he invariably
                            demanded celibacy of his disciples, and would do so now, were he living on the earth. War
                            was and is good for those not yet converted to Christianity ; but for converts, peace is
                            better, and its practice positively required by the Christ. Private interests and selfsh
                            relations were necessarily concomitants under the old law ; and the moral extent which it
                            permitted them, finds no superior permission outside of radical Christianity. "Six days
                            shalt thou labor" for the interests o fMiNE ;"but on the seventh,thou shalt rest" from such
                            selfishness, and wait on the needy. The same of every seventh month, year, years. The moral
                            law was, and is, far superior in the curbing of selfishness, than the churchal rules of
                            popular theologies wearing the misnomer Christian. Every seventh year debtors were forgiven;
                            slaves made free; and that year the spontaneous productions of the lands belonged equally to
                            the poor as well as to the rich. "Seven times seven years " and there was witnessed, not
                            only all the preceding rebukes of selfishness, but the land itself was returned to its
                            original owners. How much better all this than the very contracted limits of unselfishness,
                            by what is called Christianity to-day. Truly, contrasted with the unselfishness of Judaism,
                            the present Christianity of the popular churches is a shame and disgrace in all but the
                            name. We wonder not that Jesus called the law good. Could he say the same of what is so
                            commonly called Christianity to-day ? The law regulated the marriages of the people ;
                            applied such Levitical restraints upon them as made abstinence from reproductive relations a
                            privilege ; forbade unfruitful works; and that which was reproduced was an "honor to father
                            and to mother ! " "Eye for an eye; tooth for tooth; life for life ; " was the established
                            perm ission—a retaliation only equal to the injury done. And so we might enlarge upon the
                            superior practices under the law , to the barbarous engagements in life, of those who have
                            so misapplied the name of Christian I What regulates their sexual conduct towards each
                            other, but the physical limits nature has fortunately placed there? And where, under these
                            circumstances, are children found wrho are an honor to their parents, compared with those "
                            made under the law?" Wh en do so-called Christians divide up their entire wTorldly goods
                            with the poor, or relinquish their claim to the very source of these? What regulates the
                            retaliation of such horrid Christians in their wars? Do they practice any equality of
                            retaliation when they can make the heavier, destructive annihilations? .Shame, shame, shame
                            on such Christianity ! Let us turn to Jesus, the Christian. Instead of marriage, he
                            introduced the brother and sister relations of the heavens; lived it; his immediate
                            disciples did so. Marriage is good, earthy ; virg in celibacy w7as a superiority, and was
                            distinctly featured in " the Lord from heaven." Instead of war, retaliation, etc., peace was
                            better; and "resist not evil;" " love your enemies ;" do good to those who do evil tc you,
                            evoke the improvements cl.iibtianity made on the good of Juui itiij ; and Jesus practiced
                            them ; rebuked his disciples if they ever thought of disregarding them ; and the Shakers
                            have adopted this as their rule. With the relinquishment of marriage for the superior,
                            unselfish relations of Christianity, the cessation of earth-families began ; and Jesus and
                            immediate disciples had neither husbands, wives, children, houses, lands, etc. Had they <pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 69 them? they relinquished them. " Lo," ( said Peter, " we
                            have forsaken all these 1 to follow thee ! " And Jesus knew no relations excepting " those
                            who did the will of his Father; the same is my mother, my sister and brother." And : the
                            Shakers, following after that model, primitive church, possess nought they call mine, just
                            as did Jesus. Instead of dividing the results of selfish gains once in weeks, months, years,
                            Jesus taught to divide with the brethren every day. Instead of periodically forgiving
                            debtors, Jesus and company "owed no man aught but love and good will"—contracted no other
                            debts. Instead of freeing slaves, had none to free. Instead of taking formal, selfish
                            possession of houses, lands, etc., only the preservation of the same for future brethren,
                            was inculcated by Jesus. And we ask the general world, whether in these, and other of the
                            general1 principles of Jesus, the Shakers have, or have not, been his copyists? If we, as
                            Shakers, have followed Jesus, then are we not Christians? If the Shakers, inasmuch as they
                            have followed Jesus, are Christians, then was not Jesus of Nazareth a Shaker ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Substitution" TEIform="index"/>Substitution</head><p TEIform="p">There can be but little doubt that all bad habits arise from a want of religious zeal. All
                            useful employment serves as an incentive to the denial of the useless, and worse than
                            useless ; but a practical, religious zeal, is the farthest removed from what are called bad
                            habits, and its cultivation and continuance are ardently to be desired. Merely periodical
                            fits of being converted will not do—we are almost inclined to say they are worse than
                            useless—for when the zeal has departed, the ardor of the soul for the better course of life
                            is permitted to cool, the substitution of the useless in life displaces what is right, and
                            then the worse than useless, the wicked follows, almost or quite invariably. If a
                            fashionable belle of Saratoga or Long Branch should feel the quickening of conviction, and
                            conversion to Christ, what would become of the silks, rings, diamonds ? Where is the man
                            that would think of meeting Jesus Christ, while smoking a cigar or meerschaum ? Yet having
                            doffed these in all ardor for the cause, how easily they are leavened back, when the zeal
                            for Christ is permitted to cool. It is not wise to permit discouragements, want of
                            appreciation, nor even a good many defeats, or cripple our endeavors in our own or others'
                            behalf, through retirement from the good race, and into the substitution of disfiguring
                            habits, which we so well know are self-pleasing, but not God-serving ! It is safe for us to
                            say, that all habits of intemperance in eating, drinking, dressing, etc., all engagements of
                            the merely sensual of humanity, however respectable; all ease, idleness and amusements, not
                            positively demanded for recreation and recuperation, are wrong in the sight and feelings of
                            any thoroughly awakened to the necessities of the Lord's work, and of their being the Lord's
                            helpers ! May none ever know what it is to feel crushed, nor experience sufficient
                            unchristian uncharity to feel discouraged from making further attempts at their own
                            elevation of souls, and for the assistance of others. It is a terrible condition ; and
                            awakens in the mind the barter of spiritual riches for merely earthly, temporary
                            indulgencies, by the substitution of indifference for earnestness ; diffidence for
                            confidence, corrupting atmospheres for divine afflata, and the corroding pleasures of self
                            and selfhood for the present and eternal blissfulness of self-denial. Let the weak and
                            weakening arouse ! All for Christ, and no substitutes! To backslide, is sure death finally ;
                            and to go forward, is life eternal, ever present. Have you bad or useless habits ? Go to
                            work with yourself, for Christ; and stick to Christ through thick and thin discouragements,
                            determinate for the crown of the overcomer ; and then see how, one by one, or many by many,
                            the substitutes for religious zeal will be abandoned, and a progress made in the path of
                            virtue and of Christ's life, to our greatest satisfaction. Discouraged one, you have the
                            sympathy of the heavens if to you your cause seems just. Accept this sympathy, and "grasp
                            the hands oi the angels." And though earth, and uncharitable earth-folk are indifferent,
                            work the harder and be the more selfdetermined. The sun will rise brighter, and never set in
                            a cloudy sky. Rise, brother, sister, shake off all hindrances —substitutes for religious
                            zeal—anc work for Christ, in the lowly valley oi self-denial.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-denials of Christianity" TEIform="index"/>The Self-Denials of Christianity</head><p TEIform="p">The Christian of to-day must, for his own spiritual good, beware of certain worldlj habits
                            and indulgencies, lest he go back to the world. It may not be easy to say where the harm of
                            theater-going, and horse-racing, and danc ing, and card-playing, and adherence to worldly
                            fashion, is; it can be argued, indeed with a good deal of-plausibility, that there is
                            nothing wrong in them at all; that a chris tian may indulge in them without fear o:
                            reproach; but if the tendency of those things is to dissipate seriousness, and to make the
                            soul worldly and careless of its religious duties, and so to throw it back and cause it to
                            retrograde in its devotion to Christ and love of his cause, then it had better deny itsel:
                            the use of them. It had better do so, both out of charity for others and regard for its own
                            highest welfare. "What doth it profi a man to gain the whole world and lose his own soul?"
                            Let the soul be kept sound and true to its purpose; let it be unwavering" and progressive in
                            its attachment to Christ, cost what r will. This is that pearl of great price which is worth
                            all one has to win and keep. Therefore, in regard to those matters which stanc on debatable
                            ground, the right or wrong o: which is not clearly discerned, be this the standard of
                            decision, namely, their effect on the soul. If they do not hinder it in the better life, use
                            them; but if they exert an injurious influence upon it, produce spiritua apathy, set the
                            soul back to that state o worldliness which it has professed to shake off, then they
                            doubtless belong to those hings "from which, if ye keep yourselves, re shall do well." We
                            copy the above paragraphs, from • Sermons by the Monday Club ;" and we are very much pleased
                            to acknowledge their goodly intent. There may De perceived therein, an earnestness to
                            oractice certain self-denials to some species of worldliness. It will, however, be easily
                            perceived, that the dearest idols of the world are unmentioned ; that, being made
                            respectable, and fostered by unchristian, fashionable Christianity, they are too dear to the
                            carnal mind, for many to rise with sufficient religious enthusiasm to testify against. For
                            instance: Marriage, that god of the world ; and another god with an / in it—gold ; and
                            another, that springs from "the lusts that war in your members," etc., etc. We would have
                            religiously-inclined people, adopt at first, without " beating round the bush" of evasion,
                            the radicals of Jesus' life. Read I. Cor. 7 : 32, 33. If we would be honest in serving the
                            Lord, instead of a great deal of the world, what shall we do with marriage? We think, it is
                            better to do with it as Jesus did—live above it. The only object of marriage is reproduction
                            ; any excess under its license, is beneath the practice of the brutes ! Reproduction is of
                            the world. The children of the resurrection, of Christ—" I am the resurrection,"—do not
                            marry, neither here nor hereafter. To rise with Christ, leaves marriage with the
                            unresurrected. Said Paul : " I would have you without worldly carefulness. He that is
                            married, careth for the things of the world—how he may please his wife, etc. He that is
                            unmarried, careth for the things that belong to the Lord, and how he may please the Lord."
                            Once again, we would repeat: We do not condemn marriage, individual possessions, war, etc.,
                            in their proper places. But we do object to their practice by those professing Christ.
                            Christianity, by its author, dissolved all marital relations and taught the superior, chaste
                            anc spiritual life of the heavens—brethren and sisters in Christ. We therefore with all
                            Christian respect, say to those who are married, etc., you are not following the Master;
                            have not •'¦left all and followed him," as did his immediate disciples; and inasmuch as you
                            have not done so, you are not Christians Jesus told of the unmarried occupying places of the
                            -'children of the resurrection ; " we all pray, or pretend to, foi that state of heaven or
                            earth. Jesus, his disciples, past and present, were virgins Paul wished all were virgins
                            like himself ; and " would present you as chaste virgins unto Christ." Strike more
                            radically, Monday Club. It is easy to pick holes in other people's work, but it is far more
                            profitable to do better yourself. Is there a fool in all this world that cannot criticise?
                            Those who can themselves do good services are but as one to a thousand compared with those
                            who can see faults in the labor of others,</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">The subject of Church Unions is exciting considerable attention now. We lear of LTnion Camp
                            Meetings, Union Sunday School Processions, etc. We are ever glad to hear of, or witness such
                            demonstrations. But why not come together, and speak right out in meeting, in testimony
                            against the causes of all dissensions in church matters, and je one people in Christ? The
                            main trouble causing so many Lords, faiths, Daptisms, etc., is a determination to save to
                            ourselves so much nve cannot find in Christ. Let Jesus, the Christ, be lifted up as the
                            model life of all church members; let each expunge from daily, life practice, what cannot be
                            found resembled in Christ-life, and the same of his immediate disciples, and their
                            unadulterated, primitive testimony, and let this copying of Christ-life in our lives, be the
                            basis of our union. Can we get a better basis? What will become of the riches, poverty,
                            marriages, wars, private interests, intemperances, lusts, salaried priests and medical
                            quacks? Passing, to the " Church Union," the above basis—Jesus Christ's life—as the proper
                            one for all Christians to agree upon, we hereby give notice that we, the Shakers, stand
                            ready to join the Union of Churches ! Who will accept the basis? There's many a truth said
                            in jest; and we advise serious consideration upon what "Punch" talks so funnily about in
                            another column. If it does not pay to live in health very long, it certainly will not pay to
                            live in a condition worse than death, ad infinitum. We may be the first to suggest the
                            mercy, but called on to witness so many heart-rending incidents, where persons caught in the
                            timbers of burning buildings, and doomed to cremation while alive ; we propose an addition
                            to the police or fire force, of a competent person to administer a sponge saturated with a
                            powerful anesthetic, to put beyond the power of feeling such persons, where escape from the
                            fiery element is decided to be impossible by the powers that command at such scenes. Were we
                            at such a fire as we lately read of, where a man begged to be killed outright, rather than
                            roast to death, we should unhesitatingly have used chloroform very freely, if we could have
                            rendered no further help. We, in his stead, would have more than desired the force of this
                            suggestion. A recent Presbyterian exchange asks The Shaker : "If the religion of the Shakers
                            is the right one, why are they so very few in number?" Thank you for that question. We will
                            answer you itwice: (1) "Broad is the way, etc., and many go in thereat; but strait is the
                            gate, and narrow is the way, and few there be that find it," or who want to find it. (2) Let
                            all Presbyterians attempt living just as the author of <pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 70 THE SHAKER.
                            Christianity lived, and then see how few Presbyterians there would be, and whether there
                            would be one left foolish ' enough to need an answer to such a ] question! If numbers count
                            for righteousness, the Shakers are not far behind the Presbyterians ! but do they ? --- |l
                            We. have large reasons for doubting the sincerity of those who say and sing so loudly their
                            love for Jesus, if they do not manifest their love by an increased nearness of their lives
                            to his. Whoever we express undue admiration and love for, we will invariably and
                            persistently strive to be like. Our love inevitably means a desire to be like the one or
                            ones we so ardently love. But there is a good deal of the spurious manifested, in songs and
                            else, about Jesus. Oh, for a good deal more genuineness in " Nearer, my God, to thee ! " One
                            of our old hymns, recently quoted in The Shaker, makes this truthful allusion : "This work
                            will make me kind and clever To all around me, yea, forever." We say, truthful allusion to
                            our gospel work. Our confidence in the efficacy of the gospel should begin at home, and in
                            its efficiency with ourselves. A sour, cross, ungoverned, uncomfortable Shaker, is a most
                            miserable representative of the system we are called to adopt. If we see or hear of one,
                            called to be a Shaker, whom any dread to meet because of their petulancy, scolding, fretful
                            and self-seeking, it matters not how good they have been in some respects, we must argue,
                            the gospel has really done but little for such, let his or her opportunity have been longer
                            or shorter. With the profession we make, and the boasting we enter into, and justly too,
                            regarding our Shaker faith, the presentation of a jealous, selfish, cross, peevish,
                            fault-finding individual as a representative, is a burning shame to the gospel of Ann Lee.
                            Such persons have certainly mistaken their profession— they should rather have embraced the
                            faith of those who deem salvation the work of a vicar ; who would make them pleasant without
                            their self-denial; but they are a disgrace to Shaker name and society. We would respectfully
                            ask any old or young Believers, who are periodically or generally afflicted with
                            crabbedness, often to look in the glass, and to manufacture an unchangeable smile for their
                            countenances, for the magnificence of the profession—" for the faith's sake." We recently
                            attempted a ruse, to draw out some answers from a novitiate elder of our church, as to "What
                            shall I do to be a Shaker?" Writing by proxy, and another's direction, we anticipated some
                            splendid reading for readers of The Shaker, and information to inquirers. Chagrin covered
                            our countenance all over when we received reply: "We are engaged harvestingno w ; no time to
                            write much. We send you a book." And then we had the pleasure of opening a copy of "Plain
                            Talks," a book which we, having written, were of course quite familiar with. We acknowledge
                            being outrused !</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear children: It seems a very long time..." TEIform="index"/>My dear children: It seems a very long time...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">My dear children : It seems a very long time since I had the pleasure of talking to you;
                                and it is nearly ;wo months. Now, let us converse upon the acuity of observation. It
                                will be interestng to you, I'm sure; and perhaps some of its simple ideas will surprise
                                you. Nearly all that we know, has been learned by observation ; aye, and ail we may
                                learn hereafter. 3e careful to observe small things; good grammar in small words; useful
                                knowledge n common every-day occurrences. There are very many who profess to be very
                                learned, who could not tell me how many spokes there are in a wagon wheel! Can you? And
                                how many more is it usual to find in the larger wheels than in the smaller, or front
                                wheels ? You have seen your friends pour hot tea into their saucers ; why is this? To
                                cool ? Well, that is right; but -why does it cool better so? fust so should we observe
                                the proper uses of small and abbreviated words. Never say 'them is," nor " there a'int,"
                                "you a'int," " they a'int," nor ask permission " to go out and get them things
                                "¦—whatever they may 3e. Yet how common to hear of these mistakes. Observe now: the
                                homely Avord ' a'int" is the short of "am not," and while admissible to say "I a'int,"
                                it is very wrong to say "he a'int;" for how would "he am not " sound to you ? Let us
                                think to say " we aren't," if we wish to, but do not say "we a'int," for one means " are
                                not," and the other "am not." You majr say "you aren't," " they aren't." By a little
                                observation now, concerning the proper uses of is, are and am, you will beautify your
                                style of language much. I would like to talk with you upon the adjectives and adverbs,
                                which seem so hard to be understood; and I will sometime. But let us look at some things
                                observation has done: All improvements in the sciences have been observed out. All
                                preventives and cures came from the same source. Some have used this faculty to
                                introduce valuable studies ; like phrenology, physiology, botany, geology, etc. Dr. Gall
                                was led to perfect his system of phrenology by first observing a marked j prominence
                                between the eyes of a boj' who invariably excelled him in spelling! Franklin observed
                                the identity of lightning and electricity, by means of a kite; and Morse observed its
                                ability to learn languages, by simpler means. Paley observed that the glow-worm is the
                                female of the species, and that the male is ayfy; and that her light was a necessity to
                                keep him from getting lost! Just think of what has resulted from Newton's thoughts upon
                                observing an apple fall! and the wonderful fruits of Kepler's observations, of which
                                your friends will tell you, and which caused Prof. Mitchell to say, "Thus the dawn of
                                modern science broke in beauty o'er the earth!" Never vise the expression "he don't" for
                                "he doesn't;" yet this is a very common mistake. When not abbreviated, we would laugh at
                                " he do not"! We may say "they don't," "I don't," "we dont;" but we should say " he
                                doesn't," which means, he does not. Observe for yourselves, children, and while you
                                observe, think. We are all too willing to let some one else do our observing for us, and
                                our thinking too. We could be situated so that we would believe this. If we were able to
                                make but one sound, and were the songsters of the groves restricted thus with us; did
                                all the flowers and clouds wear one appearance ; all the vegetables and fruits taste
                                alike; had we not variety in nearly everything, even of the same species, then, ah, then
                                we would think how blissful are our observations ! But these varieties are so much a
                                matter of expectancy, and so common, that we, having grand powers of observation, do not
                                use them as we should. But how we should miss the thousands of beautiful observations,
                                were we suddenly transferred to the desert of Sahara ! There we would find a waste of
                                drifting sand; enlivened by no stream's gentle murmur; cheered by no smiling verdure;
                                refreshed by no cooling breezes ; inspired by no gladdening showers, nor thrilled by the
                                music of the happy birds ! No trees, no flowers, no dew, no rain, no zephyrs, prairies
                                nor hills ! Now, we have all of these, let us observe them gratefully; for even these
                                need not yield to us the pleasures they now do,|in order to fulfill their various uses.
                                It is good to read what others think and write ; but this is only the reprint of others'
                                ideas—a picture of a picture. There is a pleasure in observing and thinking for
                                ourselves, that cannot be derived by relying upon others, which, my children, we are
                                all, too frequently, too content to do.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, New Hampshire, August 22, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H., Aug.
                            22, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker—Please read the inclosed scrap entitled "Soul Nurture," and see if you do not
                            think such a wellwritten truth, worthy to be copied on clean paper. The writer's name is not
                            appended, but as all truth emanates from God, we accept it regardless of the media employed
                            in portraying it. Perchance the writer never dreamed that he was penning facts upon which a
                            Shaker theology has rested for at least a hundred years. Thus : " The spiritual life thrives
                            only when cared for ! " What an axiom ! Should not all christians accept it? Faithfully,
                            your sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, A. C." TEIform="persName"/>A. C. Stickney</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul nurture" TEIform="index"/>SOUL NURTURE</head><p TEIform="p">The spiritual life thrives only when it is properly cared for. Whatever may be our theory of
                            regeneration and of its office, facts prove that the heart keeps and increases its vigor
                            only by attention to its necessities and the looking out for their supply. The impulse given
                            when God's Spirit starts us heavenward at the hour of conversion, does not itself provide
                            for our steady going onward in a straight line, and at a rapid rate of movement, to our
                            goal. The prayer, "Give us this day our daily bread," is meant to teach us the necessity for
                            constant and fresh supplies. The fuel which feeds the inward fire needs perpetual
                            replenishing. Hope will remain on the earth with weak and folded wings if it be not set
                            soaring frequently in prayer. God will seem to be moving farther and farther away unless we
                            keep him consciously near us by a free and steady communion. The Bible will no more glow
                            with heavenly luster if its lids are kept shut, and its blessed sentences are not allowed to
                            awaken and direct meditation. The atmosphere of the prayer-room is not breathed freely, it
                            parts with its magnetism and its fragrance, when we are willing strangers in the place. We
                            lose the yearning for others' salvation out of the heart when we neglect to point them to
                            the Lamb of God, and we fail to keep our power over worldly souls when we cease to gaze
                            longingly and with beaming eye toward the celestial city.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tachygraphy" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Touch me gently, Father Time" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clarke's outline of the structure of the pipe organ" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">We have received from the publishers, Otis Clapp &amp; Son, 3 Beacon street, Boston,
                                a strange little volume upon short-hand, entitled " Tachygraphy." The elements of this
                                system of writing are so extremely simple, that a child of ten years would learn them in
                                a few days. Every movement of the pen indites a letter, thus shortening common
                                chirography many fold. We have become so addicted to Pitman's Phonography, that it will
                                take us longer to adopt this unique system, than others who never studied shorthand. If
                                we are as successful in learning Tachygra-phy as we hope for, it may yet save us years
                                of labor. We would encourage young people to study Tachygra-phy, instead of " killing
                                time," by so many ways that there are of doing it unprofitably and foolishly. Besides,
                                the more who learn it, the greater its usefulness.</p><p TEIform="p">"Touch me Gently, Father Time :" A beautiful and appropriate song, for those on the
                                down-hill side of life. The music is very pretty, and is by the author of " He holds the
                                fort in heaven." Price 40 cents. Order of F. W. Helmick, 50 W. Fourth St., Cincinnati,
                                O.</p><p TEIform="p">Clarke's Outline of the Structure of the Pipe Organ. To organists, church committees, and
                                musical students, the above beautifully-printed work, replete with engravings, will be
                                invaluable. It is the work of one of the best-known and most-talented artists our
                                country has produced, and an organ builder of a reputation second to none in the world.
                                We speak for the excellent book a large sale. There is also manufactured by William H.
                                Clarke &amp; Co., Indianapolis, Ind., a chromatic tube, or pitch pipe,—:one of the
                                simplest, yet most convenient and useful accompaniaments of the singer and teacher ever
                                constructed.—Ourself, and several leading members of other societies of Shakers,
                                canvassed the entire city of New York to find such an article, and failed. It is about
                                eighteen inches long; in form like a monster whistle; and its price undoubtedly comes
                                within the compass of even the poor. Send a stamp, as above, for information.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head">Societies east of the central bishopric...</head><p TEIform="p">Societies east of the central bishopric have endured some heavy changes : At Enfield, N.
                                H., Elder Orville Dyer, retires full of honors; and Elder A. Perkins retires from the
                                ministry to assume the eldership of the Church Order. Elder Jas. S. Kaime, ascends
                                gracefully from Canterbury's novitiate.;,order to preside over the bishopric. Benjamin
                                H. Smith, whilom trustee, again assumes the eldership of Canterbury's junior order, and
                                will christianly wait on any, anxious to leave the world, and wishing for a privilege to
                                confess their sins. Present trustees of Canterbury, N. A. Briggs, Joseph Woods; Elder
                                John Cloutman of Harvard, Ayer, Mass., may be addressed by inquirers and correspondents.
                                The law of impenetrability does not work well at Harvard, for El. John is under
                                necessity of being in two places at the same time ! At Shirley, Shirley Village, Mass.,
                                Isaac Bailey assumes the novitiate eldership, relieving Daniel Eraser, who returns to
                                Mt. Lebanon. Hiram Baker, Enfield, N. H., assumes temporal charge of Second Family in
                                that place. ^gP*1 We would call particular attention to the change in P. O. address of
                                our people in Enfield, Conn. Many delays result in consequence of misdirection. It is:
                                "Shaker Station, Hartford Co., Conn."</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Allard, H. Chase" TEIform="index"/>Bro. H. Chase Allard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We were sorry to learn of the demise of<persName reg="Allard, H. Chase" TEIform="persName">Bro. H. Chase
                                    Allard</persName>, aged 71, at Enfield, N. H., on the 2d July. He was highly prized
                                by the people there. He was one who knew what the severity of extreme trials was, and
                                lived and died an honor to his people, and an example to all Christians. The most
                                beautiful of proceedings were enacted at his funeral, which want of space forbids
                                chronicling.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are also pained to observe..." TEIform="index"/>We are also pained to observe...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We are also pained to observe, an apparent infection, lately beginning at Shakers, N. Y.,
                                and extending east through several societies, and into Maine, by which at least four or
                                five <pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 71 of the sisterhood, advanced in years, within ,
                                the space of a month, fell, and either broke 1 their thighs, or seriously injured the os
                                femur. \ Such contagions are among the unaccounta- , bles. We hear, one of these sisters
                                has died, j At Shakers, N. Y., we lately had a short , visit from Islay Walden, one of
                                the two colored students studying in New Brunswick, N. J., for the ministry of the
                                Reform Church. We learn from Rev. Dr. DeBaun, that these are the first colored persons
                                their persuasion has educated for the pulpit. The pear trees at this place, during July,
                                were almost irreparably struck with blight, and while loaded with fruit. The central
                                ministry arrived at Shakers, N. Y., on August 2, to remain two or three weeks, before
                                returning to Mt. Lebanon.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Littlefield, Lydia" TEIform="index"/>Lydia Littlefield
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Littlefield, Lydia" TEIform="persName">Lydia Littlefield</persName> passed to the Evergreen
                                Shores from W. Gloucester, Me., June 11, aged 84 years.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How the French do" TEIform="index"/>How the French do
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> How the French do.—The French butcher separates the bones from his steaks, and
                                    places them where they will do the most good. The housewife orders just enough for
                                    each person and no more, even to the coffee. If a chance visitor drops in, somebody
                                    quietly retires and the extra cup is provided, but nothing extra by carefulness of
                                    intention, when the little range is extinguished, and waits for another time. No
                                    roaring cook-stoves and red-hot covers all day long for no purpose but waste. The
                                    egg laid to-day costs a little more than one laid last week. Values are nicely
                                    estimated, and the smallest surplus is carefully saved. A thousand little economies
                                    are practiced, and it is respectable to practice them. Cooking is an economical as
                                    well as sanitary and gustatory science. A French cook will make a franc go as far as
                                    an American housewife will make three, and how much further than the American
                                    Bridget nobody knows—we should probably be greatly astonished, could the computation
                                    be made, how much of the financial, recuperative powers of France is owing to her
                                    soups and cheap foods ; better living after all, than the heavy bread and greasy
                                    failures of our culinary ignorance.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Home and Farm" TEIform="index"/>—Home and Farm.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtuous energy" TEIform="index"/>VIRTUOUS ENERGY</head><p TEIform="p">The first thing to be attained to is to have it distinctly and explicitly graved into the
                            soul, that there is only one thing that can give significance and dignity to humanity, viz,
                            Virtuous energy; and that this energy is attainable only by energizing. If you imagine you
                            are to be much helped by books, and reasons, and speculations, and learned disputations, in
                            this matter, you are altogether mistaken. Books and discourses may awaken and arouse you,
                            and perhaps hold up the sign of a wise finger-post to prevent you from going astray at the
                            first start, but they cannot move you a single step on the road; it is your own legs that
                            can perform the journey; it is altogether a matter of doing. Finger-posts are all very well
                            where you find them; but the sooner you can learn to do without them the better; for you
                            will not travel long, depend upon it, before you come into regions of moor, and mist, and
                            bog, and far waste solitudes; and woe be to the wayfarer, in such case, who has taught
                            himself to travel only by finger-posts and mile-stones ! You must have a compass of sure
                            direction in your own soul, or you may be forced to depend for your salvation on some random
                            savior, who is only a little less bewildered than yourself. Gird up your loins, therefore,
                            and prove the all-important truth that as you learn to walk only by walking, to leap by
                            leaping, and to fence by fencing, so you can learn to live nobly only by acting nobly on
                            every occasion that presents itself. If you shirk the first trial of your manhood, you will
                            come so much the weaker on the second; and if the next occasion, and the next again, finds
                            you unprepared, you will infallibly sink into baseness. A swimmer becomes strong to , stem
                            the tide only by frequently breasting the , big waves. If you practice always in shallow
                            waters, your heart will assuredly fail you in the hour of high flood. General notions .
                            about sin and salvation can do no good in the blessed life. As in a journey, you must see
                            mile-stone after mile-stone fall into your rear, otherwise you remain stationary; so, in the
                            grand march of a noble life, one paltriness after another must disappear, or you have lost
                            your chance.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Blackie, [Prof.]" TEIform="persName"/>Prof. Blackie</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paralysis in peas" TEIform="index"/>PARALYSIS IN PEAS</head><p TEIform="p">The London Punch, alluding facetiously to the popular scare on poisonous canned peas, adds a
                            few lines of chemical fact worth remembering. Beware, says the writer, how you try the
                            effect of strychnine, prussic acid, or any other poison, on a rabbit or guinea pig. Have the
                            fear of the Anti-Vivisection Act before your eyes. If you want to try experiments with
                            poisons on a living animal, try them on yourself. Should you kill yourself, unintentionally,
                            the law will acquit you of suicide, as it does not forbid any donkey to experiment on a
                            donkey. Suppose, for instance, you want to know what is the effect of repeated small doses
                            of copper upon the human system, take a fraction of a grain of the sulphate of acetate of
                            that metal once a day continually till you discover. Ultimately you will find it produces
                            paralysis. You will ose the use of your hands or legs, or one ide, or more, of your body.
                            Salts of copper will paralyze you sooner than even salts of mercury. But you must take them
                            in minute quantities. In large doses they mostly rid you of themselves—copper acting like
                            antimony. In order to take your copper pleasantly, your best plan will be to swallow it at
                            dinner time, daily, along with green peas. This you can do all the year round, as peas are
                            always to be had preserved in tins. You can mix your copper with your peas if necessary. If
                            the peas are of a dull, grayish, faded, ugly color, there is probably no copper in them, and
                            you may have to put some. But when their tint is a beautiful bright green, then you may
                            suspect that there is plenty of copper in them to cause paralysis if persevered with
                            sufficiently long. The copper is mingled with the peas to make them look pretty; and few
                            people seem to be deterred by the fear of poison from preferring pretty-looking peas to
                            plain ones. It is possible, however, that it may become rather less easy than it has been
                            heretofore to procure tinned peas, which besides being tinned are also coppered. Several
                            foreign provision dealers have lately been summoned before Mr. Knox, and on medical
                            evidence, fined for selling tinned peas containing copper in dangerous quantities. As they
                            sold them in ignorance, they have been let off with nominal fines, but in future vend ers of
                            coppered peas may expect to incur a penalty of $250 for each offence—and have to pay. Of
                            course the multitude ignorantly eating peas greened with copper must be, all of them,
                            greener than any peas. Bright green tinned peas may always be suspected of containing
                            copper. If there is any question on that point, it may be summarily settled by pouring on
                            the peas a little strong liquid ammonia, which, if copper is present, will mak them turn
                            bluer than even their seller will loo when he is fined $250. So also with pickles, only the
                            vinegar of the pickles will require a large excess of ammonia. In case there is no ammonia
                            or other means at hand of determining whether the greenness of peas or pickles is owing to
                            copper or no, a philosopher would give copper the credit of the color, and himself the
                            benefit of the doubt.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature has many perfections to show that it is an image of the Deity; and it has defects to show                                 that it is but  an image" TEIform="index"/>Nature has many perfections to show that it is an image of the Deity...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Nature has many perfections to show that it is an image of the Deity; and it has defects to
                            show that it is but an image.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Pascal" TEIform="persName"/>Pascal</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR THINKERS</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We do not believe immortality because we have proved it..." TEIform="index"/>We do not believe immortality because we have proved it...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We do not believe immortality because we have proved it, but we forever try to prove it
                                because we believe it.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Martineau" TEIform="persName"/>Martineau</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good thoughts (though God accept them)..." TEIform="index"/>Good thoughts (though God accept them)...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Good thoughts (though God accept them) yet toward men are little better than good dreams,
                                except they be put in act.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Bacon" TEIform="persName"/>Bacon</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="None are too wise to be mistaken..." TEIform="index"/>None are too wise to be mistaken...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">None are too wise to be mistaken, but few are so wisely just as to acknowledge and
                                correct their mistakes ; and especially the mistakes of prejudice.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Barrow" TEIform="persName"/>Barrow</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith may sometimes exceed reason..." TEIform="index"/>Faith may sometimes exceed reason...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Faith may sometimes exceed reason, but not oppose it; and belief may be often above
                                sense, though not against it. Beware therefore, not only of an implicit faith, but of
                                being too closely tied up to reason, where faith is required. Do little helpful things
                                and speak helpful words whenever you can. They are better than pearls or diamonds to
                                strew along the roadside of life. They will yield a far more valuable harvest, as you
                                will find after many days.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An unsuspecting, unquestioning, unhesitating spirit..." TEIform="index"/>An unsuspecting, unquestioning, unhesitating spirit...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">An unsuspecting, unquestioning, unhesitating spirit, God delights to honor. He does not
                                delight in a credulous, weak, unstable mind. He gives us full evidence when He calls and
                                leads; but He expects to find in us what He Himself bestows—an open ear and a disposed
                                heart.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Cecil" TEIform="persName"/>Cecil</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The design of God in placing the soul within a material body..." TEIform="index"/>The design of God in placing the soul within a material body...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The design of God in placing the soul within a material body was, doubtless, to secure
                                for it a proper limitation. Both soul and body are endowed with matchless qualities.
                                They are both God's creation. They are both God's possession. Both suffered the curse of
                                sin; and both are redeemed by the life of the Lord Jesus, who came not to save the soul
                                alone from death, but also to ransom the body.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When a certain ambitious self-seeker once clutched at the dominion of all Europe..." TEIform="index"/>When a certain ambitious self-seeker once clutched at the dominion of all Europe...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When a certain ambitious self-seeker once clutched at the dominion of all Europe, stern
                            disappointment met him in his path of invasion, flung a Russian snow-storm in his face, and
                            out of the tiny snowfiakes wove a shroud to wrap the flower of French chivalry. The lesson
                            that the proud usurper would not learn at Aspern and Eylan was taught him in the agonies of
                            Borodino, and in ghastly blood-prints on the frozen banks of the Beresina. So, too, have we,
                            in the defeat of our humbler plans of selfseeking, been made to hear the sharp teacher say :
                            " Do not be selfish. Other people have rights as well as yourself." This lesson was worth
                            all it cost us.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cuyler, T. L." TEIform="persName"/>Rev. T. L. Cuyler</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To correspondents" TEIform="index"/>To correspondents.</head><p TEIform="p">We received from our compositors the reasonable suggestion given below. We have to copy a
                            good many articles sent us; and where we need not to do so, it is a pity that poor ink
                            should enter as an objection to our relief. Please take the hint : " Bro. Lomas : Wouldn't
                            it be a pious idea : to present--------with a bottle of black ink ; ¦ and thereby save the
                            poor printer from endangering his precious soul, by making use of naughty words? Your Poor
                            Printer.''</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Putting on Christ" TEIform="index"/>Putting on Christ</head><p TEIform="p">Do you put him on . when you undertake to copy some one or more of the virtues or characters
                            in him— , the gentleness, for example, the love, the i dignity—without being willing to
                            accept the ¦ sacrifice in him, to bear the world's contempt ¦ with him, to be singular, to
                            be hated, to go ¦ through your Gethsemane, and groan with ! him under the burdens of love ?
                            There can be or choosing out here of shreds and patches from his divine beauty; but you must
                            take t the whole suit, else you cannot put him on. s The garment is seamless, and cannot be
                            divided.</p><byline TEIform="byline"> —<persName reg="Bushnell, Horace" TEIform="persName"/>Horace Bushnell</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>AGRICULTURAL</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Green manuring" TEIform="index"/>GREEN MANURING</head><p TEIform="p">That green manures will improve our land and increase our crops is an established fact
                                which few will attempt to controvert. Experience and observation have proved it, but why
                                green manuring benefits soils and crops is not so generally known. There are very few
                                even of those who habitually sow, raise and plow under some vegetable crop while it is
                                yet green with a view to enrich the land and improve future crops, who know how the
                                process increases fertility, and what are the nature and properties of the fertilizing
                                elements added by the process. Agricultural chemistry has fully explained the mystery,
                                and shown how and why certain plants or grasses, plowed into the soil in a green state
                                are beneficial as a manure. It has shown that these fertilizing elements are 1, silica;
                                2, alumina; 3, lime; 4, magnesia; 5, oxide of iron; 6, oxide of magnesia; 7, potash; 8,
                                soda; 9, oxygen; 10, hydrogen; 11, nitrogen ; 12, carbonic acid ; 13, phosphoric acid;
                                14, sulphuric acid; 15, chlorine. When we know how much of these fertilizing elements,
                                and in what porportions, a particular green crop contains, and have ascertained what
                                elements we desire to restore to the soil for the benefit of a future crop, and in what
                                the soil is deficient, the process of supply is as easy as it is for a tailor to
                                purchase the exact quality and quantity of cloth needed, and then make a coat. It would
                                be hard to say which are the best crops for green manuring unless we knew exactly what
                                the farmer desired to raise on the land manured. Red clover is a number one manure ; cow
                                peas are good, and the same may be said of either rye or oats. Each of these contains
                                the fertilizing elements enumerated above, though in different porportions. According to
                                Prof. Way, red clover submitted to analysis foots up as follows : Silica 0.50 Lime 22.62
                                Magnesia 4.08 Oxide of Iron 0.26 Potash 36.45 Soda 00.00 Chloride of Potassium 2.39
                                Chloride of Sodium 1.53 Carbonic Acid 23-47 Phosphoric Acid 6.71 Sulphuric Acid 1.35
                                This clearly demonstrates why red clover ¦ plowed under, is so valuable as a manure. The
                                other crops named are not quite so rich . as clover, but are all very good. Some of the
                                advantages to be expected from green manuring may be summed up to numbers, thus : :
                                First. The manure crop gives back all the , mineral and alkaline elements which its 1
                                growth had drawn from the soil by absorption through its roots. Second. It gives back to
                                the soil those ' fertilizing gases which its growth had drawn : from the atmosphere,
                                thus, by one process, restoring" to the soil more fertilizing matter t than the crop
                                plowed under had taken from ; it, and if the process be repeated frequently, "
                                increasing the fertility of the soil to an almost ineefinite extent. Third. It decays
                                and ferments rapidly and produces an immediately beneficial effect on 1 the succeeding"
                                crop. Fourth. It loosens and mellows the soil, - making it porous and accessible to
                                heat, air ; and light. j Fifth. It elevates the temperature of the t soil by the
                                fermentation of a large amount of ) vegetable matter. 1 Sixth. It enriches the soil
                                further by shad; ing the ground by its thick and dense growth, 5 preventing the
                                evaporation of the moisture 2 of the soil, and holding the fertilizing gases . of the
                                atmosphere which decompose the veg- etable matter in and upon the soil. Seventh. Green
                                manuring is the cheapest <pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> possible mode of manuring, and it is
                                practicable upon the poorest land.—Journal of Progress.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small things" TEIform="index"/>Small things
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Small things.—Every farmer should have a small room, tight and warm, which he can lock
                                and where he can keep his small tools. Then he wants a good.solid work-bench,with an
                                iron vise on one side and a wooden one on the other. For iron working he wants a solid
                                piece of iron for an anvil, a seven-pound steel-face hammer, a riveting hammer, one
                                large and one small cold chisel, two or three punches from one-fourth to three-eighths
                                inch, a rimmer and countersink, to be used with bitstock, a screw plate that will cut a
                                screw from one-fourth to three-eighths inch; then with round iron of the various sizes,
                                and ready-made nuts he can make any bolt he wishes. For carpenter work, he wants a
                                square, a shaping horse, drawing knife, a set of planes, auger from one-half to two
                                inches, a fine hand-saw, with coarse cross-cut and rip saw, large cross-cut saw for
                                logs, and a grindstone. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cultivate frogs, toads, and lizards..." TEIform="index"/>Cultivate frogs, toads, and lizards...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cultivate frogs, toads, and lizards. Put them in your gardens, and as the evening
                                approaches they will hop from their hidingplaces and snuggle down in some convenient
                                spot near the gutter, or where fhey know their food will come plenty. The ants, roaches,
                                mosquitoes, etc., they consume in a night is marvelous, and thus they keep down the
                                insect pest. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A farmer of Goshen, N. Y...." TEIform="index"/>A farmer of Goshen, N. Y....
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A farmer of Goshen, N. Y., makes it easy for himself,uncomfortable for the potato-bugs
                                and fattening to the toads by employing the services of a large number of the latter in
                                his potato-patch. He has constructed a pit, into which the toads retire when not on
                                active duty, and at regular intervals they are let out to devour the bugs,which they do
                                very effectively.— Chatham Courier </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is usually thought..." TEIform="index"/>It is usually thought...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is usually thought that wheat is the most nutritious of all cereals; and this opinion
                                is current in all the works relating to food. Recent investigations by Prof. Wanklyn and
                                Mr. Cooper of England seem to show the contrary. They give the first place to rye,
                                stating that it contains one-third more gluten than wheat.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly guide" TEIform="index"/>HEAVENLY GUIDE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H 1. O who will guide my feeble barque, On life's ternpestuous sea? When e'er my
                            way seems drear and dark, My guide and helper be? Alone I ne'er can safely pass The dangers
                            of the way, The rocks, the shoals, the hidden mass, That in the ocean lay That in the ocean
                            lay. 2. Though for a while I calmly sail, Upon the waters fair, Rejoicing, as I breast the
                            gale, And breathe the balmy air.— Yet soon there comes a fearful change, Dark clouds obscure
                            the sky, And all around my vision's range, |j: The foaming waves dash high. : 4. But Oh !
                            what little faith is mine, I sink beneath the wave, And struggling, cry for help divine,— O
                            Lord, in mercy save. He takes me kindly by the hand, His power my soul doth thrill, The
                            elements at his command, ||: In tranquil peace are still. :|| 3. O who will then my pilot
                            be. My barque to safely guide, Through all the perils of the sea.— The storms, the winds,
                            and tide? I view him, coming o'er the main ;— He beckons unto me, :|| And Peter-like, my
                            feet would fain ||: Approach him on the sea. :| 5. Then he will be my Pilot true, My blest
                            and heavenly Guide, Whatever dangers now ensue, Securely I may ride. And as my barque he
                            safely steers, Toward that heavenly realm, My song shall be, I have no fears, ||: My
                            father's at the helm. :||</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>OUR SANITARIUM</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For dysentary" TEIform="index"/>For dysentary
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For dysentery.—Take leaves and root of blackberry plant. Boil to a deep color. One gill
                                before each meal time, and on going to bed. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cancer" TEIform="index"/>Cancer
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cancer.—Use tea made of red clover tops. Boil until strong. Use, as drink, a quart a day;
                                and use the same kind of tea, made stronger, for a wash, twice a dav. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consumption" TEIform="index"/>Consumption
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Consumption.—Let even the despairing, use strong mullein tea, freely, sweetened with
                                bro-wn sugar. In a week they will feel better; in a few months, they maybe ivell. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For burns and scalds" TEIform="index"/>For burns and scalds
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> For burns and scalds.—Apply common baking soda immediately. It will immediately cause a
                                cessation of pain. After a few hours or a day, wet the bandage. On removing the soda,
                                keep the wound moist with simply a wet cloth. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove berry stains" TEIform="index"/>To remove berry stains
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To remove berry stains.—-From the hands or clothes, let the stained parts be moistened,
                                and then treated to the fumes of sulphur. If the stains have been set by alkalies, apply
                                a little vinegar before applying the lumes. Tan can be removed by the same process, if
                                vinegar or sour milk have first been applied. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To destroy currant worms" TEIform="index"/>To destroy currant worms
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To DESTROY CURRANT WORMS.—Apply one ounce of copperas to a gallon of water; and after
                                dissolving apply with a wisp brush to the leaves, after the dew is gone. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freckles and sunburns" TEIform="index"/>Freckles and sunburns
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Freckles and sunburns.—i. Bruise and then squeeze the juice out of the common chickweed,
                                and to this juice add three times its quantity of soft water. Bathe the skin with this
                                for five or ten minutes, and wash afterwards with clean water night and morning. 2.
                                Elder-flowers treated and applied exactly in the same manner. When the flowers are not
                                to be had, the distilled water from them (which may be procured from any druggist) will
                                answer the purpose. 3. Honey, one ounce, mixed with one pint of lukewarm water; when
                                cold, it forms a good lotion. This is commonly called honey wash. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weak eyes" TEIform="index"/>Weak eyes
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Weak eyes.—A very simple remedy for weak or sore eyes is recommended,as follows : Get a
                                five-cent cake of elder-flowers at the druggist's, and steep in one gill of soft water
                                —it must be steeped in bright tin or earthenware; strain nicely, and then add three
                                drops of laudanum; bottle it tight and keep in a cool place; then use it as a wash,
                                letting some of it get in the eyes. Follow this, and -elief is certain. If the eyes are
                                painful or much sore, make small soft compresses, wet in the mixture, and bind over the
                                eyes at night. I can warrant the above as harmless and sure, having tried it in a number
                                of cases where other skill and remedies had utterly failed. If the eyes are badly
                                inflamed use it freely; and a tea made of elder-flowers, and drank, would help cleanse
                                the blood. Pure rock salt and water will strengthen your weak eyes if you bathe them
                                daily in it. I would earnestly advise you to avoid mixtures or washes containing mineral
                                or other poisons.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Styptic for bleeding wounds" TEIform="index"/>Styptic for bleeding wounds
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Styptic for bleeding wounds.—If puff balls are not convenient, apply dry flour of any
                                kind bound on with bandage. In absence of baking soda, (carbonate), flour is excellent
                                for burns or scalds. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A medical restaurant has lately been established..." TEIform="index"/>A medical restaurant has lately been established...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A medical restaurant has been lately established in London on the principle that diseases
                                can generally be cured by a special system of diet, and that they are caused chiefly by
                                improper food. On the entrance of a visitor a physician asks him regarding his ailments.
                                His meal is then prescribed, and he is allowed to eat no more than is presented to him.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every war involves a greater or less relapse..." TEIform="index"/>Every war involves a greater or less relapse...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every war involves a greater or less relapse into barbarism. War, indeed, in its details,
                                is the essence of inhumanity. It dehumanizes. It may save the state, but it destroys the
                                citizen.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>