<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2902" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">29</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18990201" TEIform="date">February 1899</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="29" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
MANIFESTO
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Puhlislied.      The  book is printed
with large type  and on  excellent  paper.
It  contains   130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Several SOCIETIES,  their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
Society of believers.
Price, 10 cts.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL,   CHURCH,
OH
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 cts.
THE ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling1, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and Avork together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. It now.has 5,000
acres of land in Southeast Missouri on
which it offers a home and employment
for life to all acceptable persons who may
wish  to  join  it.            50   cents  a  year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 19 28 Olive St. St. Louis, Mo.
S H A K E R I S M .
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
THE
FEBRUARY, 1899.
AND
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The Rev, Irl R. Hick's Almanac.     Pub. by
the Word and Works Pub. Co. St. Louis, Mo.
Price 25 cents.     The book contains more than
one hundred pages, and illustrates the "Ris
ing, Sytting and Meridian Passage of Planets.
Eclipses of Sun and Moon.     Chief Cities in
time belts.     Full exposition of Calendars.
Constellations and signs.     Sun slow and fast
explained.     Storm and weather forecasts.
Sun spots and w hat they prove," etc. etc,
The recent death of Senator.Justin S. Morrill
of Vermont, the oldest member of tire Senate,
gives a special timeliness to the publication
of an excellent portrait of Mr. Morrill which
is contained in an article on the methods and
character of the United States Senate printed
in the January Magazine Number of The Outlook, under the title "In the Seats of the
Mighty."    The article was written before Mr.
Morrill's death. It is evidently from the pen
of some one well acquainted with  Senatorial
precedents and political and social peculiarities, and is written in a light and even amusing vein.    ($3 a year.   The Outlook Co.   New
York.)
After Spain, it was natural to speak of the
markets in the ex-Spanish possessionsPorto
Rico and Cuba.   As I had just come from both
these places myself, I mentioned first the market life in Porto Rico. All burdens are carried
on their heads by the native women.   Saturday being tin; great market day throughout
the island, the roads leading to all the villages
on Friday evenings and Saturday mornings
are thronged with men, women and children,
leading donkeys loaded with fruit and vegetables, on their way to market.   The women,
old and young, march along straight arid erect
upon their heads loads varying in weight from
fifty or mdrefpounds, downward.   They travel
without shoes, many coming from long distances.   On arrival they seem as fresh as
when sighted miles away.   The same distance
has to be traversed at the close of the market
day.   All have a pleasant word for the traveler and generally a courtesy thrown in.   The
market is a large frame structure open on all
sides and on payment of a small fee a place
can be obtained wherein to display wares.
Bananas, oranges, yams, bread-fruit, cocoa,
plantain and other kinds of tropical fruits
and vegetables abound.    The greatest regularity and good behavior prevail among these
native women, and nine-tenths of their customers are of their own complexion.Gilson
Willette, in January Donahoe's.
The same supreme power that demanded
this war will demand the complete fulfillment
of its purpose.   It will demand intones which
none can misunderstand and which no power
or party can be strong enougli to disregard,
that the United States flag shall nevei be furled in any Spanish province when- it has been
planted by the heroism of our army and navy.
Call it Imperialism if you will; but it is not
the Imperialism that is inspired by the lu-t of
conquest.   It is the higher and nobler Imperialism that voices the sovereign power of  this
nation, and demands the extension of our flag
and authority over the provinces of Spain,
solely that "government of the people, by the
people, and for the people, shall not. perish
from the earth."   Such is the Imperialism that
has become interwoven with the destiny of
our great free government, and it will be welcomed by our people regardless of party lines?
and will command the commendation of the
enlightened powers of the old world, as it
real's for the guidance of all, the grandest
monuments of freedom as the proclaimed policy and purpose of the noblest government
ever reared by a man or blessed by Heaven.
Col. A. K. McCIure, in Frank Leslie's Popular
Monthly.
Number in Nature, by Edward White.   The
object of this Lecture is to present "an evidence of Creation Intelligence," in the use of
numbers.    That the creative plan has been
wrought out by a wise Master-builder, and is
not the work of chance or of a blind force.
Published by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.
We have before us a beautiful Calendar for
1809, just received from Hyde Park, Vt., the
home of Gov. Carroll S. Page.   It is printed in
bright colors of red and green, ami is on sheets
not less than 22x28 inches.   The figures are
nearly two inches and may be easily seen
across a large room.   A fine picture of the
Governor is on every sheet of the Calendar,
and those of a social mind can make him a
pleasant visit each montn of the year.   With
an eye to the interests of his special business,
not the least available space is wasted.    The
Calendar means business well worthy the attention of all who buy and sell.   For the Office
Shop or Store this will prove to be equally as
ornamental and more useful than many articles of much greater cost.   Send ten cents in
silver and obtain one of these beautiful Calendars and you will have a pleasant companion for the New Year.   Address,-U. S. Page,
Hyde Park, Vt.
The Christ Question Settled, or Jesus,
Man, Medium, Martyrs, by J. M. Peebles,
M. D.
This is a recent work from the pen of Dr.
Peebles.    It is written in the interest of that
Spiritualism which is the spirit of truth as
found in a Christian life.   The work is a powerful advocate of the existence and spiritual
mission of Jesus, the Christ, and must interest
that large class in every Christian denomination that would live in the light of the present,
day.   The Doctor calls to his aid witnesses
from many lands and from every shade of religious belief in order to prove the soundness
of his positive assertion.   His three journeys
around the world have afforded him a fund
of knowledge on this and kindred subjects--><pb n="17" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Disciples of Jesus, the christ, are not of this world" TEIform="index"/>THE DISCIPLES OF
                            JESUS. THE CHRIST, ARE NOT OF THIS WORLD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE above statement seems almost paradoxical, as the disciples were 1 taken from the walks of
                            life common to all other people. Most of them, probably, were poor fisherman living near the
                            sea of Galilee, and as their laborious work for a frugal living kept them so closely
                            confined, they gave but little thought to anything higher, or interested themselves in a
                            spiritual experience. They were in this world and had never thought otherwise. Suddenly, as
                            they were engaged in the mending of their fishing nets, a man salutes them in these
                            words."Follow me, and I will make you fishers of men." Such a remark no doubt, astonisht
                            them, as fishing for men must have been a novel idea, and a perplexing enigma. At this time
                            they were subjects of King Herod and living in the kingdom of Judea. So interested, however,
                            were they in this invitation of Jesus and expecting, withal, to find an increase of wealth,
                            they at once left their nets that they might accompany Jesus and secure the promist
                            treasures that he so liberally proffered. It must have been quite a sacrifice to these poor
                            fishermen to leave their boats and nets to engage in an enterprise so beclouded in their
                            minds, and which at this time they could not understand. Possibly, these Jewish laborers may
                            have the vague idea or rather the exalted thought that Jesus would be a new king, as he told
                            them that in return for every sacrifice that they made, they should receive an increase of
                            an nunFEBRUARY <pb n="18" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 18 THE MANIFESTO. dred-fold. If they gave up their one
                            house, with its acre of land, they would receive through him an hundred houses and an
                            hundred acres of land. Such an offer with its subsequent explanations was not to be
                            slighted, and there is evident reason to believe that they became deeply interested in the
                            new mission. This may have changed somewhat as days past on, and the lessons of a spiritual
                            life were unfolded to them. The hundred-fold of houses and lands, and boats and nets did not
                            materialize so fast as they had anticipated. At this anxious moment they must have
                            interrogated Jesus, as he soon makes this remark, while speaking of those who accompanied
                            him as disciples, "They are not of the world, even as I am not of the world."John xvii., 16.
                            Then he gave them to understand that his kingdom was spiritual, and altho his followers
                            might, by some, be considered as soldiers, they were harmless, as their warfare was wholly
                            spiritual and on this account his soldiers would not fight. Gradually, the disciples
                            accepted the ministration of Jesus and learned that their mission was to be one of peace and
                            not of war. That there was a higher life for man to live than the cruel and merciless
                            killing of each other, for an avaricious gain. It is generally conceded, however, altho in
                            very loose terms, that Christ's people or his church are not of this world, and that there
                            must be some sacrifices to ensure a fellowship in his company, .vhile very few may have a
                            fixt thought to bear any distinguishing mark to the mind. The first sacrifice of Peter and
                            Andrew, as they left their boats and fishing nets on the shore of the sea to follow Jesus
                            was more than many would care to make even at this present date, while assuming to
                            understand fully the whole mission of Jesus. When he informs his disciples of the different
                            relations that exist between his people and the world, and that to be a Christian they must
                            deny themselves and take up their cross daily and follow him, they soon find that he is
                            leading them where the children of this world can not go. As the world loveth its own, it
                            would not be expected to favor that which manifests an opposition to its worldly course. As
                            it was bitter and envious in its remarks about the divine Teacher, it could not be expected
                            to be otherwise in regard to those who accepted a communion in his life. Jesus understood
                            this so well that he informed his disciples that as the world hated him without a cause, it
                            would also hate them after the same unreasonable manner. There was no occasion for dislike
                            of him as an individual which so often culminated in persecution, as Jesus is said to have
                            increast in wisdom, and even grew in favor among men. But it was the doctrine of the cross,
                            and the system of self-denial which he taught that was so intensely hated. It was the
                            establishing of a new religious belief, and the preaching of righteousness that if they
                            would be the children of God they must accept the fatherhood of God and the brotherhood of
                            man. That his doctrine would establish peace on earth and good-will toward all. That wars
                            and rumors of wars would <pb n="19" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 c?ase, and that the vision
                            of the prophet would be gloriously fulfilled when men should beat their swords into
                            ploughshares and their spears into pruning hooks, and the nations should learn war no more.
                            We are well assured that the church of God must have a living testimony and that there must
                            be a discriminating line between that church and the people of the world. This will be so
                            distinct that all doubt will be obliterated as the faith and the works become manifest in
                            their presentation. It may not take much time for any class of examiners to determine the
                            position that is occupied by the church. Those who reject the first Adam with his Godgiven
                            works of generation, and have put on Christ, through the baptism of the holy spirit, will
                            according to promise, be raised from the dead by the glory of the Father and at the same
                            time be able to walk in newness of life. And if "'we have been planted together in the
                            likeness of his death, we shall be [raised] also in the likeness of his resurrection." It is
                            not at all singular that the world loves its own, or that it has a hatred to that testimony
                            which destroys its influence on the minds of men. Following the course of nature in which it
                            was estaVilisht, its life is the fulfilling of the desires of the flesh and of the mind. It
                            is the work of the first Adam and can not otherwise than lead the children of this world to
                            marry and to be given in marriage. This is quite different from the manner in which the
                            followers of Jesus are led. As they are with him in the resurrection, they neither marry nor
                            are given in marriage. These two classes are placed in sharp contrast with each other. One
                            is called "The children of this world," and they are engaged in the selfish work of mine and
                            thine. Their foundation is laid in a life of generation and they are married to sustain it.
                            The other class like Jesus have consecrated their lives and all they possess for the peace
                            and prosperity of their fellow-men. Their foundation is laid on the principle of
                            righteousness, and having put on the Lord Jesus Christ they make no provision for the flesh
                            to fulfill the lusts thereof. Many who through profession have renounced the first Adam and
                            entered into Christ, are still actively engaged in the interests of the world and can
                            manifest no discriminating line between the flesh and the spirit, and none between the
                            church of Christ and the world. "The Angel of Mercy flew over the church And whispered, 'I
                            know thy sin:' Then the church lookt back with a sigh and longed To gather her children in;
                            But some were off to the midnight ball, And,some were off to the play, And some were
                            drinking in gay saloons So she quietly went her way." We are quite well assured that the
                            separation of a man from the spirit of the world is in his acceptance of the cross of
                            Christ, and in the living of a <pb n="20" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. new life, free from
                            sin and from sinners. It would be as impossible now as it was in the days of Jesus for a man
                            to serve two masters especially if Christ is to be one, and the world is to be the other,
                            "for he will hate the one and love the other, or he will hold to the one and despise the
                            other." But a new day is dawning upon us and it comes as a precursor of light to lead us
                            into the beautiful pathway of righteousness and man will care for his brother man, as he
                            will by nature care for the interests of his own personal existence. East Canterbury, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Order of mediation" TEIform="index"/>THE ORDER OF MEDIATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lyon, John" TEIform="persName"/>By Elder John Lyon.</byline><p TEIform="p">f I ^HE order of the old creation was entirely different from that of the new. JL The second
                            dispensation of the old creation was one of types and shadows, while the mediatorial office
                            was the foundation of the new creation and established in the first appearance of the
                            Anointed. "If the foundation be destroyed, what can the righteous do? "Psalms, xi., 3. The
                            order and foundation of the old creation : Man was created a rational soul, and this made
                            him a free agent and lord of creation. How did God make known his will to man? Man was not
                            made to plan for himself what he should do, or what he should not do. Had he been made to be
                            his own director he could not have been an agent for another. That he was made for an agent,
                            under God, to rule the natural world, is evident. Not being endowed with omniscience, he was
                            provided with attendant spirits, to suggest to him how to act without controlling his free
                            agency. On the other hand man was more or less influenced by spirits from the opposite
                            source who were trying to seduce him from his dependence upon the Creator. Being placed
                            between these two agencies, gives man a fair opportunity to exercise his volition and free
                            agency in choosing which to follow. If he chooses to follow the good, the evil agents must
                            step aside, but if he chooses to follow the evil, the good agents will withdraw. Herein lies
                            the accountability of .man, and the freedom or his choice makes the action his own. Man was
                            made a free agent, but it does not appear that there was any visible order of mediation.
                            That patriarchal authority was established by the law of nature, is very true. It was
                            established in the law of nature, both in the human and brute creation, for the parents to
                            have dominion over their offspring. Jacob could no more expiate the sins of his sons before
                            God, for their murderous attempt upon Joseph, than could Isaac that of his son Jacob for <pb n="21" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 his deceit in relation to his brother Esau. God made
                            the vine of the earth to bring forth its fruit in clusters, and it was designed by the
                            Creator that man should leave father and mother, and cleave to his wife, and they should
                            becoine one fle-.li. As soon as the human race had borne children, under their parents, they
                            became parenis themselves, and the head of their respective cluster. This was, and still
                            stands as the order of nature for all the children of the old creation. When the time
                            arrived for the opening of the second dispensation, about 1491 years before that of the new
                            creation, God chose one people out of all the branches that sprang from Noah, and he made
                            them a type of this new civation. He appointed Moses a mediator to stand between himself and
                            the people, and to him the will of God was made known. Moses was anointed thp Messiah with
                            all the elements and principles of that day, so that there were no further requirements made
                            by God, nor by angels, nor by prophets. When the people had gone astray, they must return
                            again to the commandments. Moses was appointed the perpetual mediator as long as that
                            typical work should endure. Through this medium a soul could find access to God. Moses was
                            something more than a manhe was an anointed man. And God said to Aaron and Miriam; "Hear now
                            my words. If there be a prophet among you, I the Lord will make myself known unto him in a
                            vision, and will speak unto him in a dream. My servant Moses is not so, who is faithful in
                            all mine house. With him will 1 speak mouth to mouth, even apparently, and not in dark
                            speeches; and the similitude of the Lord shall he behold; wherefore, then were ye not afraid
                            to speak against my servant Moses?"Num. xii., 6, 7, 8. Aaron was the high priest, and Miriam
                            was a prophetess, the highest, visible officers that ever stood among the Jews after Joshua.
                            What was Moses that these two high functionaries could not claim an equality with him? Moses
                            was the Lord's anointed, God manifested in the flesh, to typify the great mediator, the
                            Author and Finisher of eternal salvation. God chose one people through whom to show, in a
                            figure, how he would lay the foundation of his work, to save man from his lost state and
                            raise him to an order above that which is earthly. All the rest of the human race were left
                            under the universal laws of creation or nature to be directed or influenced by spirits, to
                            regulate them according to the law of nature, or else to be influenced to an opposite
                            course. This typical nation was to be led by invisible spirits, but God placed his
                            requirements in an earthern vessel where they had his will continually before them. He
                            required them to adhere to the person he had appointed, and to obey the law given through
                            the human mediator. In doing this they were serving the one living and true God. They were
                            forbidden to turn from the order of God's appointment after other gods, angels, spirits or
                            their own ways for a director. But "were all under the cloud, and all passed through the
                            sea, and were all baptized unto <pb n="22" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MANIFESTO. Moses, in the cloud
                            and in the sea. And did all eat the same spiritual meat and drink the same spiritual drink,
                            for they drank of that spiritual rock that followed them, and that rock was the anointed."1
                            Cor. x., 1, 2, 3, 4. They were all baptized unto the anointed mediator to whom they were to
                            look if they would receive anything from God. This people were not left to set up for
                            themselves a god to serve, agreeably to their own inclinations, nor to seek after spirits to
                            direct them in a way congenial to their corrupted propensities. They were placed in a
                            situation where there was no alternative for them if they would enjoy the blessing of God.
                            If they turned from it they fell under his displeasure. After God had anointed a mediator in
                            whom he could deposit his requirements, he gave his laws and ordinances through this earthen
                            vessel which was calculated to curb their immoral desires. These laws typified a work that
                            could consume the element of the flesh, the fountain from whence all immoral desires and
                            actions proceed. The great desire of the people was to know whether it was God who required
                            obedience to these laws, or whether it was the man Moses. All they knewr of these laws and
                            requirements was, that it was the man Moses who required obedience, and while he was in the
                            mount receiving the law, the people began to show that opposition which reigns in man,
                            against submitting to God through a mediator. The people gathered themselves together unto
                            Aaron and said to him, "Up, make us gods which shall go before us; as for this Moses, the
                            man that brought us up out of Egypt, we know not what has become of him."Ex. xxiii. All that
                            had been done for them from the time that they left Egypt until that day, they ascribed to
                            the man Moses, not to God, because it came to them through a mediator in human form. They
                            could make for themselves a god of their jewels and through this acknowledge all the
                            benefits that they had received. "These be thy gods, O Israel, which brought thee up out of
                            the land of Egypt." There is nothing so repugnant to man's nature, as to acknowledge God in
                            his order of mediation. They could accept God in a piece of wood, in a stone, in gold,
                            silver, brass, and lastly in themselves, where there is no submission or reverence of any
                            kind required, but to acknowledge God in a mediator of his own appointment was too
                            humiliating and an opposition to the mediatorial order of God was the point at which all
                            their rebellious and derelictions from the order which God had appointed commenced and was
                            the source of all the misery and calamities which afterward befell them. (To be
                        continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Defend the character of the absent..." TEIform="index"/>Defend the character of the absent...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Defend the character of the absent, even of those that are bad, as truth will permit; the
                            rest conceal unless duty absolutely require its exposure.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><pb n="23" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Psyche" TEIform="index"/>PSYCHE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">O soil, in the smallest globule sent From the innermost soul's bright portal, With infinite
                            purpose and life intent When fledged are'thy wings immortal. No folding thy powers, when
                            once they have sprung From the chrysalis that confined thee, From life's first note is the
                            paean sung Of the ages that enshrined thee. Thy breath in the atom first is felt, Rock,
                            plant and tree enfold thee ; Dissolving matter may freeze and melt Yet its various forms all
                            hold thee, Progressing toward the destined height Through mineral, plant and creature, Till
                            man -appears as a God of light Perfect in form and feature. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress of the Harvard shakers" TEIform="index"/>ELDRESS OF THE HARVARD SHAKERS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[The Boston Sunday Globe of Oct. 30, 1898,
                            has publisht a very interesting article having reference to Eldress Eliza Babbitt, who is
                            now in the ninety-third year of her age.] 
                            In the several Shaker communities in the country, there is one venerable
                                    Shakeress who is especially well knownEldress Eliza Babbitt of the Harvard
                                    community. This particularly gifted woman is highly regarded by those of her faith
                                    for various reasons. She is appreciated because of her long association with the
                                    community, with which she has been identified nearly all her life, having been a
                                    member quite seventy-nine years. Eldress Babbitt is now in her ninety-third year,
                                    and retains in a remarkable degree those characteristics which have made her
                                    presence so unmistakably felt in the administrative and executive affairs of the
                                    Harvard Shakers. Eldress Babbitt received The Globe reporter with that graciousness
                                    which to those who know well the average Shakeress seems so much a part of their
                                    nature. She talked very entertainingly of her life in the community, evinced a deal
                                    of pleasure in tracing some of the humorous phases of affairs, and manifested a keen
                                    and witty disposition. A warm, sympathetic and conservative nature has made her a
                                    woman greatly admired by her associates, who have showered upon her such positions
                                    of trust and responsibility as were within their power to bestow. When it was
                                    intimated that in her prosaic life there could not have been much room for the
                                    romantic or the dramatic, she replied with energy that there had been both, and then
                                    referred in a very interesting manner to the rise and decline of the community, to
                                    the radical departure from the volume of business at one time carried on at the
                                    settlement to the comparative quietude of to-day to the change in the methods and
                                    customs of those of her faith, to the kaleidoscopic transitions which have taken
                                    place in the outside world, all of which, she remarked, must, to the keen observer,
                                    seem both romantic and dramatic. <pb n="24" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 24 THE MANIFESTO. She is said
                                    to be the oldest Shakeress living. When she was fourteen years old her mother, with
                                    six children, came to this community from Norton, where they had been living-. Her
                                    father died five years before. The eldress said that her mother, having visited in
                                    Harvard, learned much concerning the life of the Shakers, became greatly impressed
                                    with their ideas and mode of living, and so took up her abode with them. She
                                    volunteered the information that so far as the financial standing of the family was
                                    concerned there was no necessity for such a course, as there was sufficient to
                                    support her mother and her children comfortably, but her mother believed devoutly in
                                    the ideas of the Shakers and decided to cast her lot with them. In her early life
                                    Eliza Babbitt learned the tailor's trade, and for twenty-three years she cut and
                                    made all the clothing worn by the male members of the community, of which she was
                                    for m-my years one of the trustees. So ably did she discharge the duties of that
                                    position that she was chosen to fill a vacancy among the elders. Her success in that
                                    order so thoroughly stamped her as a woman of exceptional abilities that she was
                                    installed into the office of the ministry, a position which she has held for quite
                                    forty years. She became superior eldress in 1872. It is the duty of Eldress Babbitt
                                    to know all about the financial affairs of the community, which she does thoroughly,
                                    having received not a little of her business training during the seven years slip
                                    was in charge of the office of the community. It is a part of her duty as minister
                                    to decide questions relative to the conduct of affairs, and to determine who are
                                    eligible for admittance into the little settlement. She is the balance power of the
                                    community. Her sagacity and keen insight into business matters has made her an
                                    invaluable member of the little colony. With her it has been a cardinal principle
                                    never to venture an opinion upon any matter which involved differences of thought
                                    until she had fully heard all sides, and her decisions upon vital questions touching
                                    the community's welfare have ever been satisfactory. She has been retained in the
                                    ministry, as was frankly stated by her associates, because there is no one to equal
                                    her in judgment and in nice discrimination as to what is right and just and for the
                                    best interest of all. This venerable woman finds not a little pleasure in showing
                                    some of the results of her handiwork of the past three years. In that time she has
                                    made twenty-eight logcabin quilts, and because of severe trouble with her eyes much
                                    of the sewing was done by feeling the seam as the work progressed, but the quality
                                    of the labor does not indicate that it was performed under other than the most
                                    favorable circumstances. These quilts are to be left as legacies to her friends.
                                    Besides making these quilts she has done much in the line of crocheting. Aside from
                                    failing sight her faculties are as alert as ever. Eldress Babbitt talks very
                                    entertainingly of this Shaker community when it was at the height of its prosperity,
                                    a condition which she aided materially in creating. At that time a lively business
                                    was done in making brooms, while a great amount of milk was sent daily to the Boston
                                    market. Herbs in immense quantities were collected, pressed and packed for the
                                    retail trade,and that branch of work is still carried on to quite an extent. Here
                                    were raised for the market in great quantity garden seeds, while the Shaker apple
                                    sauce is still well known as the best of its kind. In those days cloth for the dress
                                    of both sexes was all of domestic manufacture. At that time there was a large saw
                                    mill, a tannery, a blacksmith shop, there was much done in fruit preserving,
                                    braiding of palm-leaf and straw, and in supplying the market with wool. There never
                                    was occasion to question the weight, measure or quality of the articles sent out
                                    from the community. The community prospered then, and as the result of that time it
                                    is highly prosperous to-day. <pb n="25" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 25 Scu'xh Babbitt,
                                    a cousin oF the eldress, gave to the world the benefit of several inventions evolved
                                    from her active brain which revolutionized some branches of labor. S.irah, with liar
                                    fither and sister, joined this community. She became known as sister Tabitha. To her
                                    genius is due the introduction of the cut nail. She got the idea from watching the
                                    operation of making wrought nails. She conceived the idea of cutting them from a
                                    sheet of iron when it should be rolled to the desired thickness. Her idea was put
                                    into practical operation and found to be a success, and the wrought nail became a
                                    thing of the past. One day while watching the men sawing wood, she noted that one
                                    half the motion was lost and she conceived the idea of the circular saw. She made a
                                    tin disk, and notching it around the edge, slipped it on the spindle of her spinning
                                    wheel, tried it on a piece of a shingle and found that her idea was a practical one,
                                    and from this crude beginning came the circular saw of to-day. .Sister Tabitha's
                                    first saw was made in sections and fastened to a board. A Lebanon Shaker later
                                    conceived the idea of making the saw out of a single piece of metal. One can hardly
                                    believe that the people who comprise this community, at the head of whom is Eldress
                                    Babbitt, with their quiet, peaceful, unobtrusive ways, are the successors of others
                                    of their faith who helped make for Harvard the most exciting and sensational pages
                                    of its history. Here was one of the places in the east where Mother Ann Lee made her
                                    appearance, and here her great power was very forcibly felt. When she came she said
                                    she had some time before seen the place an ; the people in a vision. Many of the
                                    people of the town knew Ler as the female C.'i v\st. She had many followers, and
                                    whole families became imbued with her ideas. So powerful was her hold upon a certain
                                    element in the town, and to such an ex tent were the ceremonials of the sect
                                    carried, that the devout enthusiasts of other religious faiths became alarmed at
                                    what they termed the fanaticism of Ann Lee and her converts. A town meeting was held
                                    in response to a petition "to determine on some means to remove the shaking
                                    Quakers." The town voted to prosecute them and appointed a committee to cany the
                                    vote into effect. The local military company marched to the Shaker rendezvous of
                                    that time and warned Ann Lee and her followers to leave before a certain hour.
                                    Mother Ann Lee left and returned several times. Upon one of her visits a day was set
                                    when the Shakers were to be driven out. Notices were posted in the villages bidding
                                    people to assemble on Harvard common for that purpose, and two barrels of cider were
                                    furnished those who responded to the call, to stimulate their zeal. Heeding wiser
                                    counsel, it was decided to waive any demonstrations at that time, but later the
                                    threat to drive out the non-resident followers of Ann Lee was carried out, and over
                                    a route of ten miles, the Shakers were subjected to many indignities and cruelties.
                                    Scourging formed a part of the persecution on this memorable day. After one offender
                                    had received half the number of blows to be administered, James Haskell, a highly
                                    respected citizen of Harvard of that time, rode to the scene of brutality,
                                    dismounted, took off his coat, and offered to receive the last ten blows. His action
                                    so filled the persecutors with shame that they released their victim, who had borne
                                    himself with great fortitude. The feeling toward the Shakers greatly changed as the
                                    years rolled on, as attested by the fact that the late elder, Elijah Myrick, was a
                                    member of Harvard's school board for ten years, besides being honored in many other
                                    ways. To-day, no one is more highly esteemed in the town than that bright, lovable
                                    leader of this community, Eliza Babbitt, whose beaming face is an index of her
                                    philanthropic nature.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston Sunday Globe" TEIform="index"/>, Oct. 30, 1898.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I seek not selfish ends..." TEIform="index"/>I seek not selfish ends...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">I seek not selfish ends, but greatly desire the end of self.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline></div2><pb n="26" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. FEBRUARY, 1899. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the
                            "United Society of Beijevers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Ordeb and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one
                            year, postage paid. .50 A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed.
                            Remittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">December. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Kain. Snow. 1897. 29.97 4 in. 2
                                ft. 9,', in. 1898. 30.2 .75 lV " Highest Temp, during this mo. 54 above 0. Lowest " " "
                                " 4 below" Number of rainy days " ". 1 " " snowy " " " 7 " " clear " " " 7 " " cloudy "
                                " " 16' Jan. 1899. The closing day of 1898 gave a farewell serenade to the exodus of the
                                expiring year. The incipient ceremonies opened with rain, which changed to sleet, and
                                then to snow which at New Year's dawn was a foot in depth, which has given us a
                                diversified storm as a farewell to the retiring year, and a pure white robe to adorn the
                                infant New Year. We willingly bid a long and eternal farewell to 1898 with its
                                tornadoes, whirlwinds, hurricanes, typhoons, volcanoes, floods, electric bolts,
                                sun-bursts, and all its destructive machinations of life and property of every kind on
                                land and by ocean's foaming, dashing billows. Columbia County has had its full share of
                                destruction by the angry elements and many thousands of dollars will fail to repair the
                                damages. The storm apparently spent its fury in prostrating S. J. Tilden &amp; Co's
                                new steel smoke-stack to their New Laboratory. The N. Y. State Road is less than one
                                half done. At the present time, preparation for putting an iron bridge across the gulley
                                east of our machine shop pond is being executed. The intention is to have it
                                accomplished before Spring opens. There is some physical inability among us, but no
                                death to record. I ran a narrow chance of passing the fatal ordeal but I feel at present
                                that lean stand quite a brush with the grim monster. Even so let it be. Calvin G. Heed.
                                North Family. Jan. 1899. Christmas has come and gone and standing on the ridge dividing
                                the Old from the New Year, we sniff some of the savor of saltness from the dawning
                                century just beyonda century of whose coming the poets and prophets have written. The
                                usual religious Services marked the morning and the usual festal entertainment the
                                afternoon and evening of Christmas Day. At 10 o'clock a. m. we met our friends of the
                                Church family in their pleasant chapel, spending about two hours in singing, reading and
                                speaking. All the services partook more or less of the spirit <pb n="27" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MA NIFES TO. 27 of the day. In the afternoon a number of the Church family made our
                                entertainment the more enjoyable by their presence and showed a cordial appreciation of
                                its program, with the usual Christmas features, singing, recitations, etc. At the close
                                of the exercises, a simple luncheon was served to all. We must not omit to mention that
                                our beloved Eldress Harriet and Eldress Augusta were among the welcome guests.
                                Altogether our Christmas day was full of Jesus, His life, His work and we trust His
                                spirit. G. Ada Brown. South Family. Jan. 1899. The Old Year 1898 was completely frozen
                                out, while the New Year of 1899, has become thoroughly frozen in, with the mercuiy
                                ranging from 10 to 12 deg. below zero. Our years they come amd go All too quickly here
                                below, But we wish they long might stay For the good they've sent our way. Leaving
                                blessings at our door Daily giving more and more, So the years they go and come
                                Benefitting ev'ry one. The holidays, as usual, were scenes of spiritual and social
                                communion, Santa Claus &amp; Co. made their annual tour of gift distributing; each
                                member was remembered by good old Santa and his honored staffSt. Nicholasnoted for
                                benevolence and a marvelous memory. By invitation from our Second family friends, a
                                delegation from this family were present at their Christmas festival on the afternoon of
                                that day. The chapel was decorated with evergreens. The vocal and instrumental music was
                                highly commendable. The reading and recitations were conducted most admirably. The
                                singing of a German Christmas song with an autoharp accompaniment was pleasingly
                                executed by Brother Albert, who not long ago hailed from that far away land of music and
                                song. At the close of the entertainment a bountiful repast was served in the family
                                dining-hall and all were merry as the Merry Christmas. The following is the program
                                given; "Words of Welcome," by the Elders. "Round the Christmas Fire." Song by the
                                Congregation." Recitations"Lo! I Am With You Always." by Lillian. "Know Thyself." by
                                Lena. "Fear Thou Not." Song by Congregation Recitations, "Family Greeting." by Henry.
                                Dialog, "Daily Hints." "Peace and Praise." Song by the Quartet. "Whispering Hope." Song
                                by Eugenia and Alma. Recitation, "Hope Why Mockest Thou." by Alma. "Evening at the
                                Farm." by Three Little Girls, "Four Little Sunbeams." by the Little Girls. "Any How." by
                                Earle. "Tale of a Sun." by Curtis. "Song of the Months." by William. "Christmas Bells."
                                Song by the Quartet. Recitations,"Man :md His Shoes." by Mabel. "Beiring Other's
                                Burdens." by Lena. "Natural Laughter." by Clarissi. "Little Nut People." by Bessie. "A
                                Little GiiTs Wish." by Flora "Babe of Bethlehem." by Jennie. Gmeviei e DeOvw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1899. The Christmas and New Year celebrations, in their active manifestation, have
                                past away, but their remembrance and the joy of their participation will last through
                                the year. Christinas evening we had an Entertainment of one and a half hour's duration
                                which was both instructive and entertaining; and as our beloved Editor and assistants
                                were not here to share in its pleasures, we will, if not crowding other members of the
                                home circle, present the program. [It would have given us all much pleasure to have been
                                present.Ed.] March."Coronet Band." Cantata. "Birth of Christ." Recitations"Gentle
                                Words." by Ethel. "The South Wind." by Byron. "Boy's Suggestion to Teachers." by Arthur.
                                "The Snow's Masquerade." by Lottie. "What Time is it?" by <pb n="28" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 28 THE
                                MANIFESTO. Chester. "Drum Corp's March." Music, by Lulu. March, "Coronet Band." by
                                Esther. "A Model School." by the Class." Recitations"Kittie Knew." by Nellie. "How the
                                Squirrel got his Stripes." by Fred. 'The Two Orphans." by Agnes. "It was Clucked
                                Before." by Ella. "Ring, Ring, Ring." Song by All. Recitations "The Sweetest Charity."
                                by Jennie. "Not So Easy." by Eddie. Dialog, by Arthur and Wright. Recitations"Patrick's
                                Colt." by Louise. "The Yankee Boy." by Robert. "Carve That Possum." Song by J. L. L. C.
                                Recitation"A Lost Type." by Daniel. DuetInstrumental Music, by J. and L. Recitations"A
                                Discourse on Apples." by Charlie. "How to Cure a Cough." by Luella. Dialog"A Minister's
                                Donation Party." Recitations "At Christmastide." by Mabel. "Always Some One Below." by
                                Samuel. Cantata."The Sister Graces." "Joy! Joy!" Closing Song by All. On the evening of
                                the 26th we met to receive the distributions from the Christmas tree, and hearts were
                                gladdened by the mementos from dear friends. Such seasons of pure enjoyment bring those
                                who are striving for the right into a oneness of spirit, and make them strong in their
                                efforts for good. While listening to the recitations of our Christmas party and
                                realizing the ability manifested, our thought in prayer was, Heavenly Father and Mother,
                                bless the rising generation! May their affections be inclined toward Thee, that they may
                                be the ministers of the new dispensation; for only a little while and they will be the
                                directors of that spiritual power which will be called upon to wrestle with the mighty
                                problems which the twentieth century will present for solution. Hamilton DeOraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1899. Leaf turning on New Tear's day is somewhat conducive to good habits. Doubtless
                                there are many to-day holding a rehearsal over their life's book. As page after page is
                                reviewed, and the blots and blemishes stand for account, new resolutions are made to be
                                more careful the coining year. To turn over a new leaf is not an easy task, when erratic
                                conduct has blotted many pages. Strong and determined resolutions and long and continued
                                efforts will help us to succeed. We may turn the pages of each Year book with pleasure.
                                On Christmas we sang a hymn in remembrance of our friends in the homes of our childhood.
                                We hoped that the same inspiration that overshadowed them would reach us in our
                                wilderness home. We would wish that it might help us, with them, to usher in the New
                                Year with such strong resolution of heart that the pages of life's book will not be
                                sullied by one blemish. On the 1st of January we dug our fall crop of northern potatoes,
                                and on the 6th we planted the same ground for another crop of the same kind. What a
                                contrast! Our friends who write us from the north, tell us of the snow banks that cover
                                the land, and of the task of keeping the paths open from house to house. Here we are
                                basking in the sunshine of summer weather. The thermometer ranges from 60 to 80 deg.
                                almost every day. We have had but one frost that has done any damage. Then the mercury
                                fell to 40 deg. These occasional frosts make winter gardens very uncertain, and for this
                                reason many do not plant after September. We send greetings to all. Anrfreiv
                            Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1899. New Yeab's day dawned bright, 16 deg. below zero, yet, despite the frosty air
                                our morning Service was well attended. With the new resolves given to be and to do what
                                duty demands the Service was more of a memorial, sacred to the memory of our arisen,
                                noble, gifted coworker, Eldress Joanna Kaime, who for <pb n="29" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES
                                TO. 29 about thirty years, was closely connected with our Society's welfare. To give
                                full recognition to so complete a life of righteousness, no poem or eulogy could tell
                                the half of her richness of character and worth to the cause of human regeneration. A
                                life, so fruitful of good virtues, qualities and thoughts, all forming a noble,
                                intellectual and strong individuality, can not be minimized to "Well done good and
                                faithful servant." Eldress Rosetta Cummings and Sister Nancy A. Morse, carried to our
                                sorrowing kindred at East Canterbury, our wreaths of respect, fastened with the bow of
                                fellowsympathy. Personally, I think that if articles were inserted in The Manifesto,
                                referring to the experiences, capabilities and graces, acquired and cultured by the
                                truths of the Christ spirit, of such souls as Eldress Joanna Kaime of East Canterbury
                                and Eldress Ann Taylor of Mt. Lebanon, and others who have honored our Church, they
                                would scintilate sparks of spiritual encouragement to the young people of our Societies.
                                We commenced Christmas festivity the evening before, with a social gathering, the
                                unlading of a well-stockt tree of gifts, for the young people, and a supper of fruit,
                                assorted cake, ice-cream and coffee. Sabbath morning's Service was rich with messages of
                                the Spirit of Christmas, telling of the beauty and benefit of the Christ spirit and
                                mission, also that spiritual and industrial action are the culturing forces of life, as
                                well as the means of spreading peace and good-will to man. In the evening, a concert,
                                appropriate for the day, afforded profit and pleasure to invited friends and home
                                relations. To all our friends who dwell In torrid or frigid sphere, We send a New Year's
                                message; May you have a glad New Year. . George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1899. Christmas cheer and good-will reigned in our home during the holidays, and the
                                good-will we hope to retain throughout all the days of the year before us. On the eve of
                                the 26 ult. the young people gave an entertainment which pleased all who attended, most
                                especially our good friends from Poland Springs who favored us with their presence.
                                Sister Aurelia is now in Farmingron, Me. where she is superintending the publication of
                                her book upon the life and light of Believers. We wish her every success as she has
                                always been earnest in her efforts to have the life of a Shaker better known. School is
                                in progress and the Singing Classes are working with untiring zea! to further the work
                                so nobly started last winter. We extend kind thoughts and loving sympathy to our dear
                                friends in Canterbury who are now suffering the loss of their good aud.faithf il
                                Leaders, E.dress Joanna and Eldress Dorothy. Ada S. Vmnni'ngn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1893. In hushed tones the New Year's gleetings past from lip to lip in our saddened
                                household, for the last moments of 1898 bade us lay to rest our beloved Eldress Joanna
                                J. Kaime. At the funeral service held in the afternoon of the 31st ult. Eldress Eosetta
                                Cummings and Sister Nancy A. Morse were present in behalf of the Society at Enfield; and
                                grateful tributes, written and unexpressed, rose from the hearts of all. But the current
                                of true appreciation for the beloved Mothers called from our midst, runs deep in the
                                hearts of their people, who hest understand the solemn burden of the withdrawal; yet we
                                feel the pulse of our Zion in sympathy and kinship. The old year passes on, its
                                foot-prints lie deep in our memories, yet we clasp hands with the New Year, realizing
                                that whatever the grief or burden, "underneath are the everlasting arms." ******* <pb n="30" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE MANIFESTO. The storm of Dec. 31 and Jan. 1 covered the line
                                of demarkation between the old and the new years, hut the newly printed calendars put
                                everything right; and by the 3rd inst. the ice harvest optned in cold earnest with m
                                irking and ploughing. Within the three days devoted to the bus- j iness, a January thaw
                                and a snow-storm crowded themselves in, but at the close of the 5th an ample bulk of
                                ice, tho not of A No. 1 quality, was in place of storage. With the mercury slipping down
                                to 10 deg. below zero, we do not feel the immediate need of King Winter's bounties, but
                                by Independence Day we can tell better whether we are really dependent or not upon these
                                wise provisions of nature. It is well that this is not the visiting season, for even the
                                horses turn a "cold shoulder" to us. School closed on the 11th inst., the winter term of
                                sixteen weeks having drawn to a successful close. Jessie Evans.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>From the Bible Classs.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wandering in the wilderness" TEIform="index"/>WANDERING IN THE WILDERNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Walcott, Eva" TEIform="persName"/>By Eva Walcott.</byline><p TEIform="p">It took the Children of Israel forty years to reach the land of Canaan. Some writers say
                                they might have reached it in much less time had they obeyed the commandments of God.
                                The journey of the Children of Israel is a type of the journey of the soul. Every soul
                                must take this journey in order to reach the land of Canaan, but it depends on the
                                obedience rendered to the landmarks given by the heavenly guide, as light and
                                understanding increase, that determines the length of time needed for the journey. When
                                a soul is convicted that living in Egypt, or being a slave to an earthly, sensuous life
                                does not bring him peace or satisfaction, the first words of comfort that he hears
                                are,"Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden and I will give you rest; take
                                my yoke upon you and learn of me, for I am meek and lowly in heart and ye shall find
                                rest unto your souls." When realizing the peace that is enjoyed in the Christ life,
                                which gives those who live it an eternal home in the land of Canaan, he longs for that
                                life more and more. Here the first guide appears, "The first, step of a Christian life
                                is obedience." After reading this he finds he must obey the convictions received and
                                leave Egypt, or the worldly life he is living, but he is still uncertain what to do. He
                                desires the enjoyment of the higher life, yet he is not reconciled to give up the
                                pleasures of the lower. He wants to enjoy both. Here the guide says,"Seek ye first the
                                kingdom of God and his righteousness and all these things shall be added unto you."
                                Having obeyed this counsel he receives strength to take the next step. Though he has
                                decided to serve God and seek the righteousness of the kingdom of Heaven, and has
                                started on his spiritual journey, yet when he sees the sins and passions, (his enemies)
                                to which he yielded in Egypt following him, he, like the Israelites of old, murmurs and
                                doubts, and longs for his former slavish life; yet warnings again appear,"Agree with
                                thine adversary quickly." "The way of the transgressor is hard." "Except a man forsake
                                all that he hath he can not be my disciple." By prayer to God he is able to cross the
                                Red Sea of doubt, and conquer his enemies. With new courage he presses forward with the
                                comforting assurance, "Lo I am with you always even unto the end of the world." To him,
                                this is the cloud by day and night. Happiness is insured to him when he continues to
                                watch and pray lest he be lost in the desert of sin. Feeling a loss of the support of
                                the eternal presence he may become hungry and thirsty; losing faith in the promised
                                help, he murmurs; but through divine mercy water is sent, reassuring him that God is
                                ever near. By lack of faith the water is bitter; not until he fully obeys do the waters
                                taste sweet, <pb n="31" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 31 for"Whosoever exalteth himself
                                shall be abased, and whosoever humbleth himself shall be exalted." Being careful to put
                                on the whole armor of God, with earnest prayer and supplication for mercy and strength,
                                he passes victoriously on his way, with the assurance that now, all is well. He takes
                                little thought lest he fall, and becoming weary in well-doing, returns to worshiping the
                                idol of selfish ambition, the golden calf of the Egyptians. For a time this gives him
                                the pleasure sought, but how bitterly he now understands the Savior's words; "Wide is
                                the gate and broad is the way that leadeth to destruction, and many there be which go in
                                thereat." Through the strength of temptations resisted and victories won, he is able to
                                advance more swiftlj to the Land of Canaan. By sending out the spits of Truth and Light
                                to view the land he sees the successes and failures to be met in the way, though lie
                                hears the report from Doubt and Fear who tell him that he will not be able to conquer
                                the land. Still, he hears the good report from the Caleb and Joshua of Light and Truth
                                who assure him that the land is equal unto the promises of God. Before he can reach that
                                land, however, he must cross the river Jordan. As the pure in heart only can enter, he
                                must first pass the Jordan and be cleansed from all impurity by an honest confession,
                                and through his humility the waters divide and he is led forth, forgiven. Before he can
                                gain a final victory he must become repentant. This means a conscientious walk in right
                                and duty until at last he will have "Come up out of gre^t tribulation," and will stand
                                crowned as a victor and rejoice in the presence of the Eternal Father, for "Him that
                                overcometh will I make a pillar in the temple of my God and he shall go no more out, and
                                I will write upon him the name of the city of my God which is New Jerusalem." East
                                Canterbury, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strive to do good..." TEIform="index"/>Strive to do good...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Strive to do good rather than to be too conspicuous.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A physician who is connected with an institution..." TEIform="index"/>A physician who is connected with an institution...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A. physician who is connected with an institution in which there are many children, says: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"There is nothing more irritable to a cough than coughing. For some tiine I
                                        had been so fully assured of this that I determined for one minute at least to
                                        lessen the number of coughs heard in a, certain ward in a hospital of the
                                        institution. By the promise of rewards and punishments I succeeded in inducing
                                        them simply to hold their breath when tempted to cough, and in a little while I
                                        was mys-elf surprised to see how some of the cliildren entirely recovered from
                                        the disease. Constant coughing is precis lv like scratching a wound on the
                                        oi.tside of the body; s long as it is done the wound will not heal. Let a person
                                        whin templed to cough draw a long breath and hold it until it warms and soothes
                                        every air cell, and some benefit will soon be received from this process. The
                                        nitrogen which is thus refined acts as an anodyne to the mucous membrane,
                                        allaying the desire to cough and giving the throat and lungs a chance to heal.
                                        At the same time a suitable medicine will aid nature in her effort to
                                        recuperate."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="San Francisco Examiner" TEIform="index"/>San Francisco Examiner.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nansen, the greatest living explorer..." TEIform="index"/>Nansen, the greatest living explorer...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Nansen, the greatest living explorer of the extreme North-land says: "My experience leads
                                me to take a decided stand against the use of stimulants and narcotics of all kinds,
                                from tea and coffee on the one hand, to tobacco and alcohol on the other. The idea that
                                one gains by stimulating body and mind by artificial means betrays, in my opinion, not
                                only ignorance of the simplest physiological laws, but also want of exp?rience or
                                perhaps want of capacity to learn from experience and observation."</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When overcome by bodily fatigue..." TEIform="index"/>When overcome by bodily fatigue...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When overcome by bodily fatigue or exhausted by brain labor no stimulant, so-
                                            <pb n="32" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE MANIFESTO. called, serves so well the purpose
                                        of refreshment and rest, both bodily and mentally, as milk. When heated as hot
                                        as one can readily take it, ib may be sipt slowly from a tumbler, and as it is
                                        easily digested one feels very soon its beneficial effect. Few persons realize
                                        the stimulating qualities of this simple beverage.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ladies' Home Journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Medical Record, an English Journal..." TEIform="index"/>The Medical Record, an English Journal...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The Medical Record, an English Journal, thus comments on the injurious
                                        effects of anger. Anger serves the unhappy mortal who indulges in it, much the
                                        same as intoxicants constantly taken do the inebriate. It grows into a sort of
                                        disease which has various and terrible results. Sir Richard Quain said, not long
                                        ago: "He is a man very rich indeed in physical power, who can afford to get
                                        angry." This is true. Every time a man becomes "white" or "red" with anger he is
                                        in danger of his life. The heart and brain are the organs mostly affected when
                                        fits of passion are indulged in. Not only does anger cause partial paralysis of
                                        the small blood vessels, but the heart's action becomes intermittent, that is,
                                        every now and then it drops a beatmuch the same thing as is experienced by
                                        excessive smokers. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We have pity for the Spanish youth..." TEIform="index"/>We have pity for the Spanish youth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> We have pity for the Spanish youth who have been compelled to fight and die
                                        in the Spanish army and navy, and we have had, with thousands of others, great
                                        sorrow for the sufferings inflicted on our own soldiers and on our army horses
                                        and mules, to large numbers of whom death has been a happy releaseand we wish
                                        there could be posted in every schoolroom of our land those words of James
                                        Russell Lowell:"War is Murder!" and these words of Gen. Sherman:"War is Hell!" </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Our Dumb Animals" TEIform="index"/>Our Dumb Animals.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Audubon Society of Mass..." TEIform="index"/>The Audubon Society of Mass...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Audubon Society of Mass, protests against the slaughter of little birds.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Over and over again..." TEIform="index"/>Over and over again...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Over and over again, No matter which way I turn, I always find in the Book of Life Some
                            lesson I have to learn. I must take my turn at the mill, I must grind out the golden gi\tin,
                            I must work at my task with resolute will, Over and over again.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pollard, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Pollard.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Johnson, William" TEIform="index"/>William Johnson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">William Johnson, at Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y. Dec. 18, 1898. Age 59 years and 6 mo. He
                                has been a member of the Community twenty-one years. We mourn the loss, but lie has gone
                                to reap the reward of his faithful labors. J. B. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bloomberg, Andrew" TEIform="index"/>Andrew Bloomberg
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Andrew Bloomberg, at Pleasant Hill, Ky.
                                Dec. 26, 1898. Age 80 years. Br. Andrew was born in Sweden, but has been a member of
                                this Community during forty-three years. He was a pure, true and honest man. J. W. S.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kaime, Joanna J." TEIform="index"/>Eldress Joanna J. Kaime
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eldress Joanna J. Kaime, at East Canterbury, N. H. Dec. 29, 1898. Age 72 years, 2 mo.
                                and 10 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McGaughey, Hulda" TEIform="index"/>Hulda McGaughey
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hulda McGaughey, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Jan. 11, 1899. Age 78 years and 4
                                months. Sister Hulda has been a member of the Community thirty-nine years, and a very
                                conscientious, good Sister. F. M. P. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Minor, Philinda" TEIform="index"/>Philinda Minor
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Philinda Minor, at East Canterbury, N. H. January
                                17, 1899. Age 81 y|ars, 2 mo. and 25 days. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lewis, Polly C." TEIform="index"/>Polly C. Lewis
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Polly C. Lewis, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Jan.
                                14, 1899. Age 83 years 2 mo. and 3 days. Sister Polly was brought to the Society at Mt.
                                Lebanon, from Savoy, when only two years of age. For many years she was the principal
                                business manager in the South family. She was the friend of all, old and young. S. A. C.
                                The</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MA NIFES TO.
which enables him to speak with authority.
A perusal of this work of 370 pages will assure
the reader that the Doctor is in earnest and
there need 1 e no doubt of the position he occupies on the question.  The Spiritualism that
he accepts, as given in his own words, "is
that it seeks the truth wherever found.    It
 strikes at the root of all things, demands the
genuineness of all phenomena, the reasonableness of all philosophy and the highest authority for its theories of the present or of the
elder ages."   Those who have read the former
works of Dr. Peebles need no words to induce,
them to become the possessor of this interest
ing volume.   Pub. by The Banner of  Light
Pub. Co.   !( Bosworth St. Boston, Mass.
Peasants in Exile. From the Polish of
Henry K. Sienkiewicz. Published by Rev.
D. K. Hudson, C. S. C. Notre Dame, Inrt.
This little book of nearly two hundred pages contains a wonderfully pathetic story.    It
pictures a forced  journey from Poland to
America and the unsympathizing spirit that
is met in this world among strangers.     It is
an elderly man and his daughter, a young
girl.   "What were they? Any one could tell at
a glancePolish Peasants."   The storm at sea
was a fearful experience,   "The gathering
tempest murmured round the ship like the
wind in a forest, and gaining force howled
like a pack of wolves."     They reach New
York, two strangers, without money, without
friends, and with no knowledge of the English
language, they find themselves, surrounded
by wealth.   They find a lodging room at last.
"The walls are covered with mould.   The
room has a worn-out stove and a three legged
stool.   In the corner is a little barley straw
that serve 1 as a bed .     The landlord, an old,
ragged mulatto with lowering brow had his
cheek plugged with tobsscco."   Even in this
hovel they could find no rest.     The landlord
pushed her into the street and threw her bundle of clothes after her.   This, in the Christian
city of New York      Obtain the book and read
the thrilling story of these exiles in America.
Address,   Tht Ave Maria, Notre Dame, lnd.
Price, 75 cents.
To have the men who have demonstrated
their organizing ability by great business successes tell their secrets of organization, is the
object of the editor of The Cosmopolitan.
That he is succeeding, is proved in the Jan.
issuqj^y the article from Chas. R. Flint, who
is regarded in New York as one of the three
or four ablest organizers in America.   He is
president of the Rubber Trust and the head of
the great mercantile house of Flint, Eddy &
Co., which has its ramifications in almost every port of the world.     Mr. Flint tells very
openly what makes, for success in the organi
zation of business." His article may be read
with interest by the Rockfellers, the Armours
and the Wanamakers, as well as by the humblest clerk seeking to fathom the secret of
business success.
In the same line is an article, also in the
JaD. Cosmopolitan, telling how Mr. Platt organizetl and conducted the campaign for the
election of Roosevelt.   It is by a gentleman
who was actively engaged at the Republican
headquarters during the campaign, and who
gives a vivid picture of the perfection to
which political organization has been carried
in New York State by the most astute of managers.   The wary old Senator who has been a
lifetime in politics and the youngest political
aspirant will alike tind food for reflection in
Mr. Blythe's article.
The Penny' Magazine, New York, which is
the lowest priced magazine in America ("20
cents a  year)  and  which  i   owned by Hon.
Chauncey M. Depew,  the eminent American
orator, wants a representative in this vicinity.    It is a good opportunity for one ot our
ambitious young men or young women.     Applications   should   be addressed  to the  Subscription Department, The Penny Magazine,
Temple Court, New York City.
Absolutely pure is the claim made in every
advertisement of the Royal Baking Pow.ier
and absolutely pure is the verdict of every
hou.-ekeeper iu the land using the Royal. It
is the standard among baking powders, worth
the price sold at, because of its purity, healthful bread-making qualities and the strength
that makes a small quantity go a long way.
No trouble about delicious biscuit and pastry
when the Royal is used.
POPULAR SCIENCE
Nature, Inventi >n,
Mril/CArchaeclog-y, Electricity lira I Til
NtllOChemistry, Mineral jgry.ntAU II
Health,  Hygien, Mdioine.
Formerly  Boston  Journal of Chemistry
ENLARGED and IMPROVED.
This popular, monthly contains a large uamber of Short, Easy. Practical, Interesting and
Popular, Scientific articles, that can be Appieciated and Enjoyed by any intelligent rea ier,
even though he knew'little or nothing of Science. It is intended to interest those who think
Profusely illustrated and Free
from Technicalities
Entirely Different from and much superior to
other papers  with a similar name.
Monthly,   $1.60 per year.    Newsdealers,   15   cts.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper.
LILLAED & CO.,
108 Fulton St., New Fork.
4=Mention this paper for a sample copy.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
ROYAL
Baking
Powder
Absolutely Pure
SHAKER HAMAMEIS
(WITCHKAZEL,)
50   YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
A. remedy for Cuts, Bui'iis, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, B!eeding of the
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Aiithuk Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
HOW TO MAKE MONEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, 'whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
HAVE YOU -'COMMON SENSE?"
If not, send at once for a free copy of this
liberal-minded  advocate of advanced
thought, which brings health and
success.    Address
"Common Sense," M. O. 55 State St.
,,             Chicago, 111.
>   Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention i* probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Tersest circulation of any scientific Journal. Terms, $.'i a
year: four months, SI.   Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNNXCo.361Broad^-New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE. SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the OiiDEK^iust
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Pric-, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>