<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2407" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">24</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">07</biblScope><date value="18940701" TEIform="date">July 1894</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">149-172</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="24" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="07" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
JULY.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXIV.
"Cast thy bread upon thk waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1894.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MAN I FES CO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
History of South Union, No. 0.        -       -       149
Columbian Liberty and Peace Bell, -           152
Celebration cf Our National Birthday, -      153
Zion,         -       -......       155
Letter;A. W. Dowe,      -                                   157
Take Thought,      -.....       159
The Dead Past,          .....           kjo
Christian Arithmetic,        ....       ](i2
Music,My Coining,        ....           163
Notes About Home,.....       I(i4
Deaths,.......           171
Books   &   Pap'is,        - - - - -       172
E, C, MORRIS, SAFE CO,
Successors to K. C. Moi-ris <te Co.
Capital, $250,000.
64 Sudbury St.,  Boston, Mass.
FIEE AND BIMLAfi-PROOF SAFES.
 >o,ioe>, Bank Vaults, Bank Vau.it
Doors, and Deposit Work of all kinds.
The Best Safe in the World.   130,000 in use.
Always preserve their content*.
150 sold in Lynn, Mass., since that great fire
where 50 of our safes were subject to intense
heat, preserving their content!-.
Champion Record also in the Great Chicago Fire in 1871, in the Cheat Boston Mr* in
1872, and in all the great fires since. Send
for circulars.        Agents Wanted.
PLAIN TALES
Being    Candid   Answers   for Earnest
Inquirers.
By  Geo.  A. Lomas.
Price, 10 cts.
THE   AJLTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. Tt is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Long ley.
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF1   BKLIEVKlv'S.
Price,  10 c.U.
WANTED.    Kf*le   me*   *
sell our choice and
],:ir<iy Mniseiy Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line.     Many varieties can  only be obtained through us.
Commission <>i   salary  paid weekly, and
promptly.    Exclusive and choice of  territory given.     Don't delay,    write  at mice
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
World's Parliament of Religions.
Dr. Harrow's Wonderful History of its proceeding's iit the World's Columbian Exposition. Published in two volumes on beautifully fine paper, an.I with large, clear, new type.
The work contains 230 illustrations executed
in the highest .style of art. Each volume contains some 812 pages, and contains a full, authentic report of the most Notable Congress
of Modern Times.
Price per set of two volumes.
Cloth stamped in Gold       $5.00
Leather   "        "     "        $7.50
Full Morocco,                  $10.00
Arrangements have been made with the Believers at Mt. Lebanon to receive subscriptions for the above Book, and all orders can
be addressed either to Thankful II. Hale, 206
E. Capitol St., Washington, D. C, or to
Anna White,
Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co., N. Y.
PRACTICAL RELIGION
ON--><pb n="149" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 9" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. No.
                            9.</head><p TEIform="p">JANUARY 15, 1862. John McLeon who left home on the 12th of Dec, fj returns to-day. He has
                            purchased thirteen hogsheads of sugar and a quantity of molasses. This merchandise was
                            obtained for Confederate notes at par value, in Tennesee, and the merchant agreed to forward
                            it immediately to South Union by R. R. As Br. John had other collections to make in
                            adjoining states, he attended to this business and then returned home expecting to find his
                            goods at the station in South Union. On reaching home he was surprised to find that the
                            sugar had not been received and no word in regard to it. Rumors were now afloat that no more
                            sugar nor molasses nor any produce should be brought into Kentucky by the Federals. Br. John
                            decided to return to Memphis and see for himself what had become of his sugar, and greatly
                            to his surprise he soon learned that it had not been moved. The merchant gave for an excuse,
                            that the cars had all been engaged in the transporting of soldiers and military stores and
                            he could not send it. Br. John bore a strong resemblance to Gen. Beauregard and many of the
                            soldiers would salute him with that title. While on his journey to the south he was met with
                            the greatest joy by many of his old customers, and saluted with,"My good old friend, how do
                            you do ? How did you get through the blockade ? How glad I am to see you. How are the
                            Shakers on this political strife ? " Br. John was a man of but few words and would say, "I
                            guess we are on the right side in our principles, yet we are neutral and take no part in the
                            strife. We are sorry, but hope it will come out all right." JULY, 1894. <pb n="150" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 150 THE MANIFESTO. When he was thrown into the company of those very much excited and
                            threatening what they would do with the Union men, he would remain silent, and not appear to
                            notice the conversation. In this way he managed to get along quietly and settled up his
                            business without difficulty. He now had his sugar casks packed in a car and it passed on to
                            Clarksville, Tenn. a distance of fifty miles where it was stopped by order of Gen. Floyd who
                            had forbidden anything of the kind to be taken out of Clarksville and brought into Kentucky.
                            It seemed that after all our efforts and all our help to the southern soldiers that we
                            should lose our sugar. Br. John returned to his home quite feeble, and unable to make
                            another attempt to get his property. Two of the Brethren offered to go and see what could be
                            done. It was a hazardous trip. They found the car on the side track in good order and
                            securely locked. The station agent was very friendly and said he would do all he could to
                            help them. On the arrival of the next freight train he ordered that car to be taken on for
                            Russellville. At Russellville it was placed in the freight station where the citizens and
                            soldiers were excitedly discussing the subject of burning the building. Not less than six
                            hundred soldiers surrounded tl e station at three different times during the day, but were
                            prevented by the urgent remonstrances of the citizens from firing the building and from
                            destroying the town. The soldiers were forcing noo only the property from the citizens, but
                            also from each other. Jan. 18. At two o'clock this a. m. three ox teams started for
                            Russellville. At daylight fourteen of our horses were fed; four wagons were made ready and
                            eight of these horses were put into their harnesses and soon on their way to Russellville.
                            They proceeded without disturbance till within three or four miles of the town. Br.
                            Jefferson Shannon, who was the director, ascertained that it would not be safe to enter the
                            town with the horses as the soldiers were pressing all the horse teams and their drivers
                            into the service of the army. This obliged us to hide the horses and wagons in the woods and
                            haul the sugar on the ox teams to a place of safety where we could transfer the loads to the
                            horse and mule teams. Br. Jefferson had found it necessary to hire six mule teams, but did
                            not venture to drive them to the station, through fear of the soldiers. No freight could be
                            moved from the place unless so ordered by the sheriff. Securing his aid, the hogsheads were
                            removed from the station, and the teams moved toward home. The Brethren, six in number,
                            concluded that their safety depended upon being near to each other, or they might lose, not
                            only their load, but also their oxen, as the lawless soldiers made free to claim all that
                            they could get. A careful watch was kept that night over the horses and sugar at the hiding
                            place in the woods, and so soon as day broke we started for home, where we arrived in
                            safety. <pb n="151" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 151 Jan. 19. Eighteen horsemen passed through
                            our village on their way to Bowling Green. We thought it w'as the same company that camped
                            near our village, a few nights since. Jan. 20. Six Cavalry passed on their way to Bowling
                            Green, and it was a remarkable feature that they made no demands on us. Indeed, it was quite
                            a surprise. Jan. 21. Four men with two armed soldiers called to see the machinery at the
                            woolen factory. " The soldiers said they came from Alabama. We were a little suspicious of
                            their movements, but they behaved well and left the place peaceably. Several in our family
                            are sick with the measles and this reduces our strength. Jan. 22. Ninety Confederate wagons
                            passed through the village and remained at Yost's tavern during the night. Two hundred
                            Artillery men and their horses were provided with supper. They then pitched their tents,
                            stole two bee-hives and made th ir tires with the rails around our lots. At the close of the
                            day Col. Scott's regiment of Cavalry of a thousand men called and said they would remain
                            with us one or two days, or till they received further orders from Bowling Green. We began
                            at once to make preparations for the cooking, but upon inquiry the Brethren ascertained that
                            the soldiers did not wish any food at present, and we hoped they would not until morning.
                            However, at nine o'clock an order came from the officers for six hundred pounds of bread.
                            The work began at once and the Sisters at the Center family baked four hundred and the North
                            family baked two hundred pounds. The soldiers were in groups in the highway and in the
                            fields. It was a strange sight. A large number of fires were blazing and the sparks were
                            carried in all directions, while the air was filled with the discordant voices of shouting
                            and cheering over incidents relating to the Rebellion. The Artillery had five cannons, and
                            every company had little Confederate flags fastened to the heads of the horses. Some fifteen
                            negro slaves were marching with the Infantry and were armed the same as the white soldiers.
                            Several slaves were also on horseback, and in readiness to obey any word from their masters.
                            The company was two and one half hours in passing our dwelling, and it was a great relief to
                            the mind when the end came. Nov. 22. A small company of eight Texas Rangers asked to be
                            sheltered during the night. They seemed to be very nervously excited. Their horses were
                            hitched before the house where they slept, but the saddles and bridles were not removed. Two
                            of the company were on guard all night. We furnished the men with supper and breakfast,
                            which they seemed to appreciate very much. (To be continued.)</p></div2><pb n="152" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Columbian liberty and peace bell" TEIform="index"/>COLUMBIAN LIBERTY AND PEACE BELL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeVere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>By Cecelia DeVere.</byline><p TEIform="p">Thou art the symbol of the inward bell That pleads and teaches with the still small voice,
                            But strikes the hour for action with a swell That wakes the spirit to heroic choice. Ring
                            out, 0 blessed bell a tocsin sound To call brave warriors to the Cause of Peace! To make all
                            earth for once, a battle ground Through whose triumphant victories wrong shall cease I Ring
                            loud, O ring the very wrath of God I Omniscient zeal, that naught of evil brooks, True as
                            the plummet, sure as measuring rod, Devoid of fancies, free from schemes and crooks. Bring
                            love baptismal, bring the vital strength That Michael and his angels had of old ! Till
                            clothed in her right mind the earth at length Shall know the fabled, dreamed of Age of Gold.
                            Ring fearless peals, to thunder far and wide With leveling force like horns of Jericho! Ring
                            out in earnest, heaven is on thy side, Till bastile, fort and citadel are low I Ring shame
                            upon the navies of the deep I Those monsters for iniquity, those floating hells, O'er which
                            the pitying angels pause and weep, "While demon pride each rivaling nation swells. Ring
                            shame that Carnage with its blood-red hand Presents the engines used in Christian might,
                            That would be spurned from darksome Horror-Land, As far too evil for plutonian night. Ring
                            till the Christian bells in steeple tower, O'er Legislative halls, and Learning's fane, O'er
                            mart, and mine, and factory own thy power, And vibrate with the justice of thy strain. Till
                            heathen lands their passion-rousing din, Shall silence for thy chimes so pure and blest,
                            When war retreats with legion hosts of sin, Thy music then, shall "charm the savage breast."
                                <pb n="153" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 153 Ring soft and low vsweet gratitude and prayer,
                            Ring "Peace on Earth," so sadly long delayed, God's joyful band again shall thrill the air,
                            Mid love-bought glory that shall never fade. As human hearts their angel-hood disclose, The
                            desert wastes in fruitfulness shall sing; The wildernesses blossom as the rose, And all the
                            bells of Heaven with thee shall ring. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celebration of our national birthday" TEIform="index"/>CELEBRATION OF OUR NATIONAL
                            BIRTHDAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">AMONG the most important and startling events of modern history, is that which is recorded of
                            the fourth of July, 1776, when, on the Western continent was born a new nation. On the
                            second of July of the same year, Congress met to consider the adoption of that immortal
                            document penned by Thomas Jefferson;the Declaration of Independence. It was generally
                            understood that a final decision was to be made on the fourth, and thousands eagerly waited
                            to hear the words of national destiny. When the welcome message, "/ has passed!" rung out,
                            it was caught up by an enthusiastic multitude ; and almost instantaneously, the ringing of
                            bells, the roar of cannon and illuminations from every house and hill-top bore witness to
                            the universal rejoicing. It was on this occasion of witnessing the peoples' outburst of joy,
                            that the grand patriot John Adams said: "1 am apt to believe that this, the greatest event
                            in American history will be celebrated by succeeding generations as the great anniversary
                            festival. It ought to be commemorated as the day of deliverance by solemn acts of devotion
                            to Almighty God. It ought to be solemnized by pomp and parade, with shows, games, guns,
                            sports, bells, bonfires and illuminations from one end of the continent to the other from
                            this time forth, forevermore !" From the lines quoted, we learn the origin of the present
                            mode of our national celebration, with some important omissions not at all creditable to the
                            people. The "solemn acts of devotion to Almighty God" seem to be entirely omitted, and in
                            the absence of religious sentiment, all the ceremonies of the occasion bear an aspect far
                            less noble than that conceived in the mind of him who proposed them. The excessive use of
                            tobacco, intoxicants and other low forms of indulgence would naturally be associated with
                            pleasure seeking and gaiety when <pb n="154" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 154 THE MANIFESTO. pursued as an
                            object, untempered by the restraints of religion, and in most cases undignified by any
                            intellectual efforts, even in calling to mind the occasion of celebration and the necessity
                            of vigilance in preserving those liberties which had been so dearly bought by the brave sons
                            of the Revolution. Could the fathers of our nation have made their voices heard, we think
                            they would long since have recommended some modes of celebration more befitting the
                            intelligence of a people who have had opportunities of development under free institutions.
                            Aside from the many accidents to life and property, and the useless expenditure connected
                            with the firing of cannon and pyrotechnical display, the moral influence is wrong,
                            (especially of guns,) and seems strangely out of place to mingle the booming which brings
                            the shudder of horror and memory of war's barbarism and hellishness, with the rejoicing of a
                            gala day, which commemorates so grand an event as the birth of a great nation, destined by
                            the providence of God to be a refuge for the oppressed of all lands where liberty and
                            equality should be the inalienable inheritance of all. The Declarations of Independence and
                            of Rights were the grandest documents pertaining to State affairs of which we have record.
                            In them were advocated those principles of justice and righteousness in whose fruition
                            should dawn the period of the Millennium. But how have these principles been carried out?
                            How much of that noble, self-sacrificing spirit which fired the hearts of Jefferson, Paine,
                            Franklin and their co-laborers, has descended to the present generation ? Alas ! where are
                            statesmen to whom the highest interests of the people are more precious than gold, than
                            reputation, than life itself? and how is it, that instead of being the freest and grandest
                            of nations, we are rapidly approaching a condition of slavery, not less to be dreaded than
                            that obtaining under the old monarchical governments? What of our public school system, our
                            colleges and universities, that send forth one generation after another to bear our nation's
                            burdens with so little knowledge of their duties as citizens, that they can neither
                            appreciate nor protect their liberties and rights? The effect of this ignorance is appalling
                            ; for to this must largely be attributed the development of those gigantic systems of wrong
                            which now threaten the destruction of our Republic. Unanimous has been the testimony of the
                            ages that degradation and slavery of the masses, and the final ruin of nations are the
                            inevitable result of land monopoly, yet this underlying cause of all other national wrongs,
                            has in the United States been allowed in proportion to the vastness of the country.
                            Encroachments have already been made upon our religious liberties, and the powerful hand of
                            Rome cunningly waits till all shall be ready, when she intends with one clutch to seize all
                            that remains of that glorious heritage bequeathed to us by those who struggled for the
                            blessing of "millions yet unborn." <pb n="155" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 155 These conditions
                            prove how grave has been the mistake in omitting a thorough education of the people into the
                            spirit and science of democratic principles and the forms of government best adapted to
                            their perpetuity. And what more fitting occasion than the annual celebration of the nation's
                            birthday to awakeu general interest and an intelligent understanding in these matters. If
                            down through the century the day had been observed by suitable recitations by the young, and
                            readings from the Declarations of Independence and Rights with lectures upon subjects of
                            national importance, these in themselves would have so enlightened the people that they
                            would not have stood by with folded hands and mute lips while pious hypocrites and shrewd
                            politicians forged link after link of the chain of their bondage. But, while we can not mend
                            the past, the present is ours in which to create a brighter future, and while we as a people
                            are called out from active connection with civil and political affairs, we should sustain an
                            interest therein, and keep ourselves intelligently informed concerning the movements of the
                            Ship of State, else how shall we hold that relation to the outside order in which its
                            leaders can receive the guidance of that higher "Law and Word that shall go forth from Zion
                            to the nations of earth?" Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zion" TEIform="index"/>ZION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>By Watson Andrews.</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following verses were given from or received from beyond the
                            veil. The name of the control was not given, and that of the medium is withheld by request.]
                            Lo! in wrapped silence, 'mid bright, rural scenes, Fair Zion sits, the virgin Queen of
                            queens. Lo ! from "the Mount" her living waters flow ; A thousand hearts, their healing
                            virtues know; A thousand souls, drink and are satisfied, And know, and love the risen Groom
                            and Bride; And know and love each other in the Lord, A dual Priesthood;Such the gift of God.
                            This holy union, male and female joined In gospel order, as of yore designed-, And
                            symbolized in Israel,chosen name, As seen by Moses, on the mount of flame, And wrought in
                            needle-work and beaten gold, And fine twined linen fabrics, fold on fold; A Tabernacle, type
                            of that to come, When Christ should bring again his Zion Home; When in the mighty power and
                            gift of God, <pb n="156" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 156 THE MANIFESTO. The Mother spirit, with the living
                            Word, Should mark and mortify the seat of sin, And with a holy zeal, should usher in The
                            Second Advent; Woman's virgin reign For lack of which, the ancient church in vain Essayed to
                            stand, but failed and fell away; The faithful waiting for the Latter Day. This latter day of
                            glory now begun, When not the Father only, and the Son ; But Mother and a Daughter, four in
                            One, Should be revealed, a family Divine, To such high lineage we trace our line, Whose
                            'image and whose likeness' since we bear, Their 'image and their likeness' we declare. 'The
                            things invisible, of Him,Paul said, Are seen and understood, by what is made.' The world of
                            nature, being God manifest. Thus proven this question should forever rest. Nor still
                            exclude, in sheer absurdity, The female nature from the Deity. But such the darkening power
                            of priestly art; And such the nature of the woman heart; She dreads to think the world is
                            all astray, On this, and kindred questions of the day. What she would have, offended nature
                            gave, And with that gift, the doom to be a slave, Until the light of gospel truth should
                            shine Into her servile heart, with power Divine; Until, in all the strength of Jachin, she
                            Should rise and slay her deadly enemy ; Should crucify original desire, Baptizing "with the
                            holy Ghost and fire." The Cross of Christ; the risen Savior's life ; The 'sacrifice of
                            husband, children, wife ;' 'Of lands and chattels, selfish will and way;' Such the baptism
                            of the woman's day. Away with cant; away with priestly guile; Away with subtle reasoning's
                            specious wile; Away with lukewarm folly, idle ease : The damp of death o'er Zion, comes of
                            these. Be not deceived, we reap whate'er we sow Whate'er we cultivate, we surely grow. If
                            light and life; a knowledge of the way; <pb n="157" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 157 A faith
                            unshaken in the Mother's day ; A faith unshaken in her precious word; In Ziou's Order as the
                            gift of God, We cultivate ; we've nothing then to fear ; Such consecration, brings the
                            kingdom near ; But if instead, we lend a willing ear To the seductive cry, Lo here ! Lo
                            there ! We're liable to drift, we know not where. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To Jennie H. Fish, East Canterbury, N. H...." TEIform="index"/>
                                To Jennie H. Fish, East Canterbury, N. H....
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="California, San Francisco, April 29, 1984" TEIform="index"/>San Francisco, Cal.,
                                April 29, 1894.</dateline><p TEIform="p">To Jennie H. Fish, East Canterbury, N. H. Dear Sister:Your gentle and loving letter came
                                in proper season and gave me a reminder that though far away, we of California are not
                                forgotten; and as to-day is Sunday I will improve the opportunity to drop you a few
                                lines of acknowledgement. I dare say the time of such Sisters as are consecrated to a
                                spiritual and heavenly life is very largely taken up during their spare moments in
                                writing to and answering inquiries of outside friends and seekers after truth. I fear I
                                have been too selfish in monopolizing so much of the time that might have been given to
                                others, and so I have determined not to do so any more and to be fully satisfied with
                                what the Lord may inspire any of you with from time to time. And as none of you seem to
                                be set apart for active and aggressive work in this Western Gospel field, I shall not
                                bother you with calls for aid or co-workers with me. I fully realize that you have
                                become so fixed and settled in your present mode of life and worship that it would take
                                more effort and labor to overcome the inertia and quietude you now enjoy, and get you
                                started into a spiritual avalanche, than would be needed in fully converting a society
                                which has no faith nor doctrine and setting it on its feet in the gospel road of
                                salvation. How much wasted effort there is in life. I can look back and see how had I
                                concentrated my work day by day, instead of scattering it here and there, I should ere
                                this have gathered many precious sheaves. Then, too, I have wasted much precious time
                                waiting for others to make up their minds what they would do as to co-operating, etc.
                                Situated as I am so far from the ruling and leading spirits of our movement it takes
                                much time waiting for advice, which often when it comes is not to the point nor does it
                                cover the question. Consequently another letter must be written and an answer awaited.
                                    <pb n="158" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 158 THE MANIFESTO. Since the present generation of Believers
                                have never been through a great revival and reformation of spiritual power, their own
                                experience does not fit them for the tremendous issues now before the world. In all the
                                great questions of the coming age, the majority of Believers have no practical knowledge
                                and consequently little practical sympathy. So to disturb their quiet sleep and rest and
                                their dreams of security would be of very little use, and would only provoke needless
                                discussion and friction. Prayers are good only when they proceed out from the life and
                                are backed by practical works. A man may pray for his crops to grow or for his clothes
                                to be made, but unless he puts his "hands to work" he will go hungry and naked. So it is
                                with any church society. They may moan and pray for an increase in numbers and power,
                                but unless backed up by active work out among the fields white with ripe blossoms, there
                                will be no response. But when a people become fixed and immovable like the "pillar of
                                salt" into which Lot's wife was changed, though once a live active woman and a power for
                                good. God is accustomed to raise up a new people and the former is left to wax old and
                                decay away. "He that will save his life shall lose it." What is needed is a new
                                demonstration of that love of man and God, which will convince unbelievers and skeptics
                                that Jesus Christ is alive, and as ever laying down that life for his enemies. Love is
                                the power that must break every yoke, and until you convince sinners that God;Man loves
                                them you can never convert them. You may bring them under the fear of the Law, but that
                                is all. And in that condition "all that they have will they give for their lives," but
                                there is no salvation in it. May the Lord grant unto us one and all the spirit and power
                                of the gentle, loving Jesus of Nazareth "who went about doing good and healing all those
                                oppressed of the devil." One thing is as certain as that God is true, and that is that
                                of the present form of Christian religion, no matter under what name, "Not one stone
                                shall be left standing upon another," God has spoken. In the meantime we must do our
                                duty, day by day just as though we were to continue a thousand years. What our hands
                                find to do let us do it with all our might. As to what the outcome will be of the
                                movement on this coast, God only knows. I have the names and addresses of about thirty
                                persons who are interested in "the way, the truth, and the life." I have circulated most
                                of the literature sent me, all of which went where asked for, and none was wasted. Have
                                held no meetings as I have not known what to depend upon from the East, and could give
                                no definite information to inquirers. Sister Cornelia Powers is in much the same
                                condition regarding her home family at Watervliet. They are in much the same state of
                                mind there as you are. As <pb n="159" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 159 St. Paul says in
                                Rom. vii., 18, "For to will is present with me but how to perform that which is good I
                                find not." There is but one way out of the difficulty, "I thank God through Jesus Christ
                                our Lord." The cross of self-denial and following him who laid down his life for us.
                                This is for the church as a whole. I have determined by the grace of God that hereafter
                                I shall take my cross as the Lord gives it to me, looking only to the Author and
                                finisher of my faith, Jesus Christ, that great Captain of my salvation. "Shaking" myself
                                free from the doctrines and commandments of men I shall cleave to him alone as he
                                reveals ,himself to me from heaven and in his Word. I shall let God "Shake everything
                                that can be shaken, and that which can not be shaken will remain" which is the "Word of
                                God." With kind love and a prayer for the spiritual and temporal welfare of you all who
                                love the Lord Jesus I remain as ever Your Brother in the Gospel,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dowe, Arthur W." TEIform="persName"/>Arthur W. Do we.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Take thought" TEIform="index"/>TAKE THOUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew D." TEIform="persName"/>By Andrew D. Barrett.</byline><p TEIform="p">IS there anything on earth that can equal a true friend? A true friend will never alienate
                            his friendship by hearing imaginary reports. Your grief will be his grief, your sorrow his
                            sorrow. Any other friend is not worth having. Let him go! A sterling character is one who
                            thinks for himself, and speaks what he thinks. He will never swerve from the truth for the
                            sake of keeping friends. I believe if there is any class of people that God will love better
                            than another it is the honest hearted. No doubt that truth and honesty, as Wm. Garrison
                            says, in many cases make enemies. Go straight on and not mind them. A man who has no enemies
                            is seldom good for anything. He is made of that material which is so easily worked that
                            every one has a hand in it. A celebrated character who was surrounded by enemies used to
                            remark, "They are sparks, if you do not blow they will go out themselves." Contention only
                            adds food to the flame. "The flying rumors gathered as they rolled, Scarce any tale is
                            sooner heard than told. And all who told, added something new, And all who heard it, made
                            enlargement too; On every ear it spread, on every tongue it grew." Such is the old saying
                            which has often been repeated. But ' 'let by-gones beby-gones." After the tempest comes the
                            calm. Let us brush away the clouds and hurry into the sunshine. Life is too short to be
                            worrying and fretting over the disagreeable past! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="160" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dead past" TEIform="index"/>THE DEAD PAST. </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">THE living present is, indeed, a wonderful age. It is a store-house yielding treasures which
                            have been accumulating for hundreds and thousands of years, and from this inexhaustible
                            repository men gather knowledge as they would gather fruit from a vineyard. Those who are
                            enjoying a privilege upon the. earth and sharing in its varied blessings of to-day, are most
                            fortunate, and may well be astonished at the wonders that have come down to them from the
                            heavens, and that spring up be-, fore them from the earth. No such privileges as those of
                            the present were ever known at an earlier date. From the whole world are gathered the many
                            treasures that are demanded for use, for comfort or for pleasure. Every day brings to the
                            front some wonderful invention through which knowledge is diffused, so that light and heat
                            and steam and electricity are made to act as faithful servants for the good of the whole
                            human race. Almost as by magic some simple machine is at once made to do the work of several
                            persons. Simplifying the order of manufacture, this reduces the cost and a greater number
                            receive the reward. This inventive faculty, however, so graciously given as a quality of the
                            mind, has fallen below other faculties of questionable value. The treasure that was hid in a
                            napkin, and has become such a remarkable lesson for reference in some special cases, finds a
                            valuable illustration in every department of the mind, and demands as forcible an
                            investigation of the use of God's gifts to man, as was represented in Bible story.
                            Contrasting the life of man of an earlier age with that cf the present, and some persons are
                            quick to denominate this as the "living present,*' forgetting that they are quite dependent
                            upon the work of the past for many things which they are now enjoying. Possibly this may
                            have been the condition of some minds in the primitive age. Jubal Cain in the manufacture of
                            harps and organs may have thought he was sharing the advantages of a "living present," and
                            was made happy in his wonderful achievements, very much as the same class of inventors are
                            made happy to-day. Without the organ of Jubal Cain it is questionable if we should see the
                            beautiful musical instruments that are around us or hear the harmony with which the land is
                            being filled. And had it not been for the work of the first evangelist, Seth, in that early
                            age of mankind, we might not have been blessed with the labors of faithful evangelists of
                            the present day. Everything is brought forward by degrees no less in the spiritual than in
                            the material. These <pb n="161" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 161 steps of growth are definitely
                            marked and a close dependence is maintained throughout the whole, for the good of every
                            developing phase. A first machine must be made, and a first lesson in morality must be
                            impressed upon the mind. It was life in and through God that awakened the thought for action
                            and that life can never become a "dead past." Men may have a wonderful idea of the value of
                            their own individual presence, and of their own individual thought. With them it is the
                            modern thought. The acme of all nice things is in this time, and to refer to an earlier age,
                            is to them of no especial value, and can be expressed in no clearer language than as the
                            '"dead past." Moses and Aaron, of course are of no account, only as magicians ; the prophets
                            and seers need not claim our attention and the work of the divine Teacher, of two thousand
                            years ago, may be laid aside, as of trifling value, as so much advancement has been made
                            since that date. Indeed, all that he may have said or done is now left quite in the shade.
                            That the gifts and blessings of the present time are wonderful is readily admitted, and
                            although there may be much ignoiance and wickedness in the world, there is, no doubt, more
                            kindness, more general humanity of man toward man, than was ever before known. With all the
                            reverse steps that may be taken by individuals, or families, or nations, as they fall into
                            themselves, or into an uncivilized state, the world, as a whole is, evidently, growing
                            better, and without the never dying work of living souls for the good of the race of
                            mankind, this present stage of wonderful development could never have been reached. Goodness
                            must be obtained and a search be made to obtain it, as one would search for precious
                            treasures that are hid in the earth. Excellent lessons may be drawn from every age of the
                            world, and these lessons of wisdom are as valuable for use at the present day as they were
                            when first uttered. What can be more to the point than this advice which Moses gave to his
                            brethren, as a guide in morality. "If a soul hear the voice of swearing, and is a witness
                            whether he hath seen or known of it; if he do not utter it, then he shall bear his
                            iniquity." Not less than three thousand years have passed since this was spoken to the
                            children of Israel, and its moral value is not in the least diminished. "Blessed is the man
                            that walketh not in the counsel of the ungodly, nor standeth in the way of sinners, nor
                            sitteth in the seat of the scornful." The living present can not bring forward anything that
                            will more directly lead the mind into the path of righteousness. <pb n="162" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 162
                            THE MANIFESTO. "Finally, brethren, whatsoever things are true, whatsoever things are honest,
                            whatsoever things are pure, whatsoever things are lovely, whatsoever things are of good
                            report; if there be any virtue, and if there be any praise, think on these things." A
                            healthy discipline of the mind could not be better reached than through the apostle's
                            beautiful admonition. It is one of the treasures that can never grow old, nor become of less
                            value. So long as the principle of righteousness can find access to the heart, so long will
                            a salutary influence follow this testimony of the good apostle.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian arithmetic" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN ARITHMETIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/>By Ernest Pick.</byline><p TEIform="p">I. Add faith to virtue to knowledge to temperance to patience to godliness to brotherly
                            kindness to charity. Amount. Entrance into the everlasting kingdom of our Lord and Savior
                            Jesus Christ. (1 Peter, I., 5, 6, 7, &amp; 11.) II. Subtract, from the works of the
                            Spirit, the works of the tlesh. Remainder. Salvation. (Gal. v., 19-24) III. Multiply, the
                            seed of the Spirit (which is the Word of God) by the bread of Life, (all the factors of
                            practical work.) Product. Righteousness. (1 Cor. ix., 10.) IV. Divide, all profane and vain
                            babblings by the word of Truth. Result. The sure foundation of God which is not mocked. (2
                            Tim. L, 15-19.) Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="163" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My coming" TEIform="index"/>MY COMING.</head><p TEIform="p">"Watch therefore, for ye know neither the day, nor the hour, wherein the Son of man cometh."
                            Matt, xxv., 13. Enfield, N. H. O Zion awake to thy interest so holy As a thief in the night
                            I may come unto you, And blessed are they who are waiting and watching For the will of my
                            Father in heaven I do. In the day of my coming my people shall triumph, The strongholds of
                            Satan I'll surely destroy, A beautiful morning already is dawning,Giving hope to the
                            fainting,to the sorrowing joy.</p></div2><pb n="164" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. JULY, 1894. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year,
                            postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. May. Thermometer. Bain. 1893. 55.52 5% in. 1894. 63.9
                                % " Highest Temp, during this mo. 80. above 0. Lowest " " " " 30. " " Number of rainy
                                days " " 11. " " clear " " " 7. " " cloudy" " " 13. C. G. Reed. June, 1894. And is this
                                June? Where are the "rare" days? No days yet comfortable without a little fire, while
                                rain seems to be a diurnal occurrence. Only once since the eighteenth of May, have
                                twenty-four consecutive hours passed without rain. A morning rainbow ushered in this
                                humid time, but we hope the beautiful arch seen this evening will be true to its trust
                                and prove to be the rear guard of the storm. We have thus far escaped injury by frost
                                though we can not tell yet how much the rains have blasted the abundant blossoms of May.
                                In these days of financial depression, in common with all interested members of our
                                Communal homes, we are thinking constantly how we can economize and save, since there is
                                so little opportunity to earn Ten months ago we put out the fire in the ovon.and bake
                                "between times" as best we can, in the cooking range, to save coal. Much wood collected
                                from the removal and repair of buildings, fences, etc. has been utilized in our furnace
                                the past winter for heating the house, in place of coal. The luxury of gas also we have
                                sacrificed, wherever we can possibly use lamps, as kerosene is cheaper than gasolene. It
                                can not be urged too strongly on every member of Community to "use the things of this
                                life as not abusing them." The financial burdens of our homes are heavy. It is said
                                those who "know nothing, fear nothing." Our experiences have taught us that those who
                                come with the least to offer for the common weal, are the most extravagant in their
                                demands. Children taken under reduced circumstances, prove the most ungrateful; and
                                parents whose children derive the greatest advantages, by our care, are apt to
                                appreciate it the least. Only those who know the value of hard earned wealth are fitted
                                to become interested and useful members of Community life. So let us all keep an
                                inventory of our possessions ever in mind, lest we selfishly accumulate for the "moth
                                and rust," because we can get it by the asking. This is the honest duty of all, not the
                                few. We were delighted to meet again our worthy editor, Elder Henry C. Blinn in Lebanon.
                                Though his tarry was short, we appreciate even the flying moments. The culmination of
                                his address in our TERMS. <pb n="165" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 165 morning service on
                                the Sabbath, was ''Do not prophesy evil of Community and if any one does, do not believe
                                it." And "so say we all." Life is what roe make it; not I. So let us work together arid
                                the salvation we earn we have the right to enjoy. Amelia ./. Calier. North Family. June,
                                1894. We must of course, say something about the weather. Everybody remarks about the
                                weather. During the last few weeks we have had so much of it, all over the country, and
                                of such an unexpected variety that people are naturally quite concerned about it. With
                                us it has been unusually wet, cold, almost sunless, with some frosts; had a slight frost
                                June 8th. We shall escape material damage if we get a change soon. Our sympat1 its go
                                out to others who have suffered loss, especially to our friends at Pleasant Hill, whose
                                crops we hear have been almost ruined by untimely frosts. Referring to your rect nt
                                visit to Mt. Lebanon, Elder Henry, and the little incident of your presence at the
                                meeting in one of the Pittsfield churches. We commend your custom to others similarly
                                situated. Your attendance at this particular meeting had quite a good effect. As you
                                explained to us, there was not much of it; still a kindly, fraternal spirit accompanied
                                with a simple, unassuming manner, is always appreciated and respected. In responding,
                                with others to the general call for a Scripture quotation and testimony for Jesus, you
                                spoke words in season which brought a blessing. We were encouraged by your breadth of
                                mind in stating your willingness to insert in the Manifesto contributions bearing upon
                                moral and social reforms, not inconsistent with principles of Believers. This is good.
                                We are all interested in the efforts being made to place the natural order of society on
                                a right, foundation, and we should inform ourselves of what is moving and contribute
                                what we can to the solution of the problem. Our love should be as universal as the love
                                of God. If we love God truly, we shall love fiat spark of the Divine that is in every
                                human soul, and yearn to see it and help it to unfold and develop. One of our valued
                                correspondents after reviewing the immoral social, and unjust industrial conditions asks
                                if we really think the world is growing bettor. Well, the social malady is reading a
                                climax. The prevailing discomfort is a sign. The present social system is the product of
                                man under the influence of his animal and material proclivities. Has developed the worst
                                elements of human character and is not conducive to spiritual growth or the higher
                                civilization. What we want is such a change as will give the honest, industrious and
                                conscientious a fair field, witli no favors to the strong and unscrupulous. Such changes
                                will be made. Man's redemption defends upon them. First redeem l.im naturally, then
                                spiritually. We believe that God designs his creatures to attain a condition of
                                righteousness, purity, peace and harmony. If we had not this faith in man's growth and
                                possibilities, how couid we Lave faith in God, his Creator and Inspirer. Believers1
                                faith is unbounded in the possibilities of man. Think of the faith of Mother Ann in
                                starting out in poverty, under persecution, tiie stite of society more gross and animal
                                than at present, to establish a standard of life more exalted than any in history. Our
                                faith is that the highest and best conceptions of the mind will yet be actualized both
                                in the natural and spiritual orders. Waller S. Shepherd. Center Family. June 1894. As we
                                were looking over our monthly messenger of June we noticed that the Center family did
                                not have any Home Notes, so thought we would send some this month, though ours may be a
                                small mite, compared with the many interesting Home Notes which are sent. The weather
                                has been very cloudy and <pb n="166" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 166 THE MANIFESTO. rainy for the past
                                two weeks nnd rather cool for this season of the year, but we hope it will be better, if
                                not we are afraid our harvest may prove a failure. Last Sunday being pleasant, we
                                enjoyed a very good meeting with our beloved Ministry, also Elder Henry C. Blinn from
                                Canterbury, and our friends of the Church family. It will ever be a pleasant
                                remembrance; the good gifts of the hour are treasures stored for future comfort and
                                sustenance. We have had a very agreeable visit with Eldress Ellen Greene, of Harvard. We
                                enjoy meeting our friends from different Societies: they always bring cheer and courage
                                with a blessing for the young. A short time since, Brother Andrew Barrett of Harvard,
                                returned to this, his former home and was gladly welcomed by his many friends who
                                remember with loving appreciation the faithful, consecrated service he has rendered to
                                the gospel cause, while residing in the Center family of Mt. Lebanon. Our fruit trees of
                                every variety look very promising and we hope to reap a bountiful harvest. The Brethren
                                have been spraying the apple orchards for the fourth time this season. This work
                                requires much time and strength and we hope may prove to be of enough benefit to repay
                                them for this special labor. Theresa Clutter buck.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, New York" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. The poem, "Watchman, What of the Night?" in June Manifesto is truly a
                                remarkable production. Its literary style is of a high order, and the spiritual insight
                                that it shows is indicative of the fact that the author was in close concord with those
                                powers that are revealing to human life the result of conditions that to the mass of
                                humanity are a sealed volume. - On the 26th of May, we were favored with a social call
                                from our beloved Sisters, Lucy A. Shepard and Emeline Hart of East Canterbury, and on
                                the following day the Sabbath, we enjoyed, in our Society Service, their blessed
                                ministration. The heavens opened and holy angels descended to hold communion with those
                                who weie striving for, and some who had attained unto sainthood here. It was truly a
                                communion of the saints, and we have naught but pity for any one who could not be
                                uplifted by these heavenly powers. The latter part of May gave us an exuberance of
                                moisture, while the me nth opened dry and cold. We have not suffered from devastating
                                floods, as many of our fellow mortals in different parts of the country have, for which
                                we are thankful; and extend to the afflicted our sympathy. If not able to assist in a
                                material sense, it is certainly right for us to sympathize with our fellow mortals, and
                                pray to God for our neighboi s as for ourselves. Success to the Manifesto. June number
                                full of excellent ideas. Editorial, splendid. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Mass" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. It is a beautiful day. The sun is shining brightly over the Bei'kshire hills,
                                filling the valley below with golden light. We are led to think with the writer, "O,
                                what is so rare as a day in June, then, if ever, come perfect days." We are very glad to
                                welcome these days for the last fortnight has been a succession of showers and cold
                                winds. We thought our fruit trees and gardens would yield an unusually early harvest,
                                but the recent cold weather has retarded their growth. It is feared that the corn
                                already in the ground is ruined and that it will be necessary to plant again. The old
                                drain pipes in our dwelling house have been removed and new and larger ones have taken
                                their places. Our large oven has been given a new lease of life, by undergoing a
                                thorough repairing. Our dairy has received a prominent share in the general improvement.
                                Last year an aqueduct was placed in the dairy, by means of which water is now obtained
                                for run- <pb n="167" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 167 ning the churn. We have purchased
                                Teed's "Maelstrom" water motor and with our present arrangement it can be used at any
                                time with but very little trouble. In the Church family we use the "Davis' Swing Churn,"
                                and those who manage it consider the churn a success. Our bird friends have taken their
                                permanent abode with us for the summer, and our groves and woods are filled with their
                                sweet melodies. The children have eagerly watched their appearance, and greatly admire
                                the orioles and scarlet tanager. They have made friends with many of the little birds
                                and listen with pleasure to the song of the bobolink. About three weeks ago, two little
                                robins were found on the ground by the side of an upturned nest. They were evidently
                                helpless and homeless, and apparently orphans. We took them to our room and fed them for
                                three weeks. One has flown away to its friends in the trees, but the other, though
                                several " times offered its freedom, always returns to us. The favorite wild flowers are
                                appearing, each in their season, and are being sought after, analyzed and pressed by the
                                school children. Our school opened the 23rd ult. with thirteen scholars in attendance.
                                Last Wednesday we enjoyed a brief, although pleasant visit with beloved Elder Henry
                                Blinn. We hope it will prove but a forerunner of a longer one in the near future. Rev.
                                Dr. Clymer, pastor of the Methodist Church of Pittsfield, called here a few days ago,
                                and spoke with much pleasure of the enjoyment he felt in the attendance of Elder Henry
                                at their prayer meeting on Friday, June 1st. Fidelia Esierbrooh.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. Our Pleasant Hill correspondent in April Manifesto says, "A word kindly
                                spoken, a smile, or a small act of charity or mercy has started many a poor wanderer on
                                the highway to true felicity, who otherwise might have sunk beneath a weight of sin and
                                discouragement." Very true, the happiness of life is made up of little things, little
                                courtesies, good deeds, good wishes, friendly letters, genial smiles, pleasant words,
                                and little kindnesses. The little things that make up life come each day and hour. If we
                                make the most of life and its possibilities for goodness then is the whole life
                                beautiful and good. In the little things the heart speaks from its fu'lncss. True
                                greatness consists in beinj gi-eat in little things. The pleasant interchange of good
                                deeds builds up happiness. It is the little moments well improved, the little deeds well
                                done that make up the sum of a virtuous life. The little things of everyday life have a
                                bearing on the endless life beyond. Let us think of that. One reason why some people
                                find it so hard to live a Christian life is because they devote so little time to it. It
                                is one of our golden opportunities to watch and pray. Nothing is more beautiful than
                                purity, it was this that made our Savior's character divine. Avoid all that leads to
                                sin. is a command of no small import. ******* Our new well, drilled 167 ft. in the s did
                                rock, affords a great supply of excellent water for all purposes. This is a blessing
                                that we can not too highly prize. A drilled well is perfectly reliable in dry weather,
                                as it does not depend upon rain to keep up the required amount of water. Our white
                                multiplier onions are a success and they are rightly named, for as many as fourteen fair
                                sized onions may be produced from a single bulb; very desirable for table use. Try them.
                                There are many little details connected with poultry growing, which if neglected, will
                                affect the profits decidedly. An important matter is thrift. Economy should be practiced
                                in feeding, giving only what will be eaten at each meal. The more the food of the laying
                                hen is varied the better will be its health. Daniel Orcutt.</p></div3><pb n="168" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Weather liecoid lor May, lfc!;4. Highest Temp, during the month, 82 Lowest ' " " " " 37
                                Mean " " " " 53.8 Amount of rain in inches, 5.09 No. of rainy days, 13 S. A. llriggs.
                                June, 1804. Foil central New Hampshire this is the one beautiful month of the year.
                                Everything is teeming with new life and there is a freshness and loveliness in the whole
                                scenery that just fills the mind. The rains that have fallen so abundantly upon the
                                fields and meadows, of the just and unjust, have brought forth a heavy crop of grass
                                which will be preserved as a great blessing for the coming winter. Very little hay is in
                                the barns at the present time and anxious minds are looking forward for the near future.
                                Br. Albert Evans is busily engaged in building a silo at our cow barn that will have a
                                capacity for holding a hundred tons of ensilage. In anticipation of this, Br. Arthur
                                Bruce has planted several acres of corn, and he too, is looking forward with an anxious
                                hope for the growing, and storing, and preserving and feeding of this new and wonderful
                                article for cattle. Br. Arthur has also several acres of potatoes in fine growing order,
                                and already in blossom. He thinks the potato bugs will be quite too late to do any harm
                                to these early plants. Br. William Briggs is busy with others in the sawing of lumber
                                that is to be used in the manufacture of chairs. A certain quantity is to be furnished
                                each month and the contract holds good during the year. After so many weeks of vacation
                                the machinery is again in operation for the knitting of Sweaters. The Sisters are now
                                furnishing two grades and they too, like others, are anxiously looking -for the
                                anticipated reward as well as for a more active growth in this line of business. During
                                the last week we have had the pleasure of entertaining Eldress Lizzie Noyes and Sister
                                Sirena Douglas of Gloucester, Me. This uni.m of social fellowship helps largely to make
                                the Believers one people, and to grow an interest and care in the temporal and spiritual
                                prosperity of each other. H.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. We are just emerging from a three weeks' season of almost perpetual rain. It
                                had been predicted that rain would fall every day for forty days, and we had almost
                                concluded that at last a reliable weather prophet had been discovered. Happily we are
                                disappointed, as the weather is again clear, though uncomfortably warm. Our crops are
                                all planted, and if the seed has not been injured we hope for bountiful harvests. The
                                summer season has commenced, and visitors are beginning to throng our Office. Could we
                                but gather one out of every hundred that comes, we should feel a degree of satisfaction.
                                As it is at present, people come to see the sights not even caring to learn our real
                                object in living the Community life. So long as curiosity is the prompting spirit, our
                                harvest will be light. Honest investigators are few and far between. However, few though
                                our number may be, we know the principles that underlie our faith, are built on a sure
                                foundation, and we take for our motto, the adage,"Be sure you are right; then go ahead."
                                O. H. Kirkley. North Family. June, 1894. When meditating upon the varied experiences
                                which have been effectual in educating our minds and ruling our lives to our ideal of
                                faith and life, how we are reminded of the wisdom of the law of cause and effect, the
                                great factor which gilds life with a halo of happiness or bedims it with the rust of
                                heart anguish. <pb n="169" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 169 Are not these visitations of
                                joy or sorrow the just reapings of our daily life? preventatives, that depraved nature
                                may not run rampant upon the broad way, aids to strengthen our better nature in being
                                able to pluck the fruits of the Spirit along the narrow way of Christian duty; ever
                                reminding us that the Christian life must emit spiritualizing and educating influences,
                                while the reverse plunges the soul into a chasm of moral darkness. While we do not
                                depend upon a Shakespeare to dramatize life's duties, or a Whittier to poetize life in
                                song, yet we do need a master mind of judicial discernment and appreciation of divine
                                and human realities, combined with true soul consistency, the sweet and rare life poem
                                of active goodness. As the late frequent rain visits give us hope of a good hay crop,
                                even so do all visits from gospel friends help to brighten our lives. Though short the
                                call of our esteemed Br. Benjamin Gates, (on business) yet the hand grasp and the
                                pleasant salutation (given to the writer, tarrying on the way-side from the pasture) was
                                cheering. The promise of a real visit in a not far distant day we record on memory's
                                page. Realizing a ready sale for butter, we dispense with our usual cheese industry this
                                season. All of our farm products give evidence of good crops. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. We have had sunshine for nearly two days, the first for a long, long time.
                                The robins still cry rain, rain, but the farmers' cry is "warm days and plenty of
                                sunshine." The peas that were in blossom three weeks ago, are still in bloom but the
                                pods fail to materialize. The sweet corn planted the first of May, has now to be
                                replanted and the potatoes are just coming into sight and the potato bugs are six to the
                                leaf. If an abundance of rain is productive of a large hay crop we ought to have an
                                abundance of that blessing this season. During the month of May, 18034 spaces of cream
                                were sold. Much credit is due Br. Franklin Butler who cares for the herd and also
                                carries on the vegetable garden, which is looking finely regardless of the wet weather
                                we have experienced. To our library of more than five hundred books has been added the
                                two valuable volumes of the "World's Parliament of Religions" which will afford to all
                                many hours of pleasant and useful study. What could be of more importance than the study
                                of religion? Is it not well for us to think often of the great profession we are making
                                and closely question "How near are we living to the wonderful profession that we make?
                                Fannie Casey.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. This is a most perfect Sabbath, and we are enjoying its restful influence. We
                                are also rejoicing that our dear Sisters Eldress Lizzie Noyes and Sirena Douglas are
                                visiting the Societies in N. H. It is a rest from home toil and burden which they very
                                much needed and their letters to us from Canterbury tell of their loving reception and
                                the happy hours which they are passing in that beautiful place. Our horse-chestnut shade
                                trees are unusually full of bloom, the white blossoms contrasting with the deep green
                                foliage. The little flower plants are fast coining along and will soon be ready to do
                                their part towards beautifying the earth. Poland Spring House opens this week. That
                                place is to have one more attraction. The Maine State Building from the World's Fair at
                                Chicago is now on its way to Poland Sprkigs the Ricker Bros, having purchased it and
                                chartered twenty cars for its transportation. It is to be fitted up for a Library and
                                Museum. <pb n="170" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 170 THE MANIFESTO. The gale of Dec. 12, 1893 blew down
                                over thirty large pine trees. During the past week the Brethren have been to the forest
                                to remove the bark aad secure them from injury, as they can not be drawn to the mil]
                                until next winter. Black flies and mosquitoes were so troublesome that the Brethren had
                                to wear netting drawn over their hats and fastened at the neck. In this way they found
                                they could work quite comfortably. We have had two promising Brethren added to our ranks
                                recently, which gives us courage to look forward to the harvest of souls for which we
                                hope to be prepared. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watervliet, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, O.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. We have been having very cool, wet weather through May, and had a slight
                                frost on the morning of the 31st. Well, we have been trying to make home cheerful,
                                inasmuch as white washing and repairing can do it. We are putting some new siding on our
                                wagon and carriage house. Also white washed some of the out buildings which makes them
                                look much better. We have taken down one old building that was used for storing tools.
                                Have put up a lath and wire fence at the south of the North family's garden which was
                                much needed and makes a better appearance. Our potato crop looks well and we shall have
                                new potatoes by the 10th or 15th of June. They are of the size of hens' eggs now. Garden
                                truck is coming on very slowly as the weather has been very unfavorable. Corn looks
                                well, also wheat and the harvest will be abundant if the frost will only keep away. We
                                hope that June will be warmer and the weather more pleasant, that the farmers may look
                                more cheerful. A company of Brethren went to Dayton to interview an army of Coxeyites
                                that were gathering together to start for Washington, but they got there one day too
                                late to see any of them. Wo had better take things as they come and learn to bear all
                                things patiently. We must not expect to have smooth waters to sail upon all the time. We
                                have sold some lambs that averaged 61 lbs. each. If any one can excel we would like to
                                hear from him. We herewith extend our kindest love and blessing to all Believers east,
                                west and south. We have nothing but good-will to extend all around. Flenrji W.
                            Fredrick.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. Our spring and summer so far have been uncommonly cold, with light, cold
                                rains quite frequently. Our wheat and barley will be good crops, so will corn and oats
                                if we have no more frosts. This is our third year without fruit of any kind but a few
                                strawberries. Garden vegetables are plentiful, so all things considered we are greatly
                                blessed and really ought to consider the poor; and we do give away, without money and
                                without price hundreds of suppers, lodgings and breakfasts, to poor and destitute
                                way-faring men. Our potato crop never looked better but hay will be scarce. This may be
                                remedied by cutting and shocking our corn. Three young Brethren paid us a short but very
                                agreeable visit lately viz. Augustus Fredrick, William Beckwith and Pernell Berry. They
                                came up on bicycles. On their return they made sixteen miles in one hour and forty-five
                                minutes. They expressed themselves highly pleased with their visit. We are always glad
                                whenever we are able to minister to the comfort and satisfaction of any of our good
                                friends of other Societies, ii The Nation appears to be struggling in the throes of a
                                revolution. But God runs the Universe, and I am sure He will manipulate the destiny of
                                the same in wisdom and in love. The whole trouble with the Nation in one word is
                                selfishness, and whether the Lord will give it rope enough and time enough to hang
                                itself, remains <pb n="171" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 171 to be seen. A happier
                                culmination than that however is to be devoutly hoped for. The policy at present like
                                that of the Allopathic Doctors is to treat the symptoms; not cure the disease. But
                                Mother Ann said, "Believers have nothing to do with it." Thank God for that. I was
                                delighted with that article written by a twelve year old girl. I was a great observer
                                and admirer of birds and even many insects when I was young. Also of the pretty gray
                                squirrels and the little striped fellows that lived in the ground. I also used to take
                                note of the periods, when different birds arrived. But O what a delightful time I had
                                when I studied Botany. To wander in the green woods and classify plants and flowers was
                                quite a little heaven for me. Let me tell all the girls and boys that these innocent
                                experiences and observations will be much better in later life than vanity and folly
                                which afterward give to memory no pleasant reminiscences, but a melancholy harvest of
                                vain regrets. O C. Hampton.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. We are enjoying good health, for which we return thanks, to the "Giver of all
                                good." Truly we do live in a chnnce world, for in the month of May we had chilling winds
                                and frosts to blight what little remained to us. A writer said "this is a Rose winter."
                                The rose, in all her queenly beauty, looked out of place when the mercury was at 38 and
                                41 deg. A snow 33^ inches deep fell on the twentieth of May. The wheat which was so
                                heavy and tall bent by the pressure and for days the grain crops were prostrate. The
                                wheat is doing fairly well, but the rye is injured, and will have to be cut by hand. The
                                beautiful days that we now have are suggestive of the wonderful power of the Creator,
                                who has made this beautiful earth for man. Then why not live to praise him with our
                                hearts' best gifts and with the brightjstars be found singing,"The Hand that made us is
                                divine." The June Man ifesto gave us much comfort and to all the writers we say "come
                                again." James W. Shelton.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1894. In consequence of the removal of our good Elder Andrew Barrett, whom we all
                                greatly miss, to his first beloved home at Mt. Lebanon, the Society at Harvard was not
                                represented in June Manifesto. Our beloved Eldress Ellen Greene is at Mt. Lebanon on a
                                visit to recuperate her health. The cold, wet May gives promise of a good hay crop. In
                                June we hope the weather will cease its erratic behavior and return to its accustomed
                                genial habits. Crops in general are looking finely, gardens flourishing and early peas
                                nearly ready for the table. Strawbenies begining to ripen. Milk, our present staple, has
                                increased very much since the return of good pasturage. Farm work progressing finely.
                                Some important improvements in the way of re-shinclinr, painting and repairing
                                generally, keeping all hands busy. In doing our part to make life pleasant, we can with
                                confidence look for a blessing. We are well pleased with the article in March and April
                                Manifestos on Agriculture. Hope to hear more on the subject. All boys should learn this
                                all important science and it would not hurt girls to understand gardening and fruit
                                culture. Mar Ma M. Bk'UitI.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clark, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Clark
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Clark, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. June, 10, 1894. Age 77 years. Sister Mary came to
                                Pleasant Hill in 1860, with a family of three brothers and a nephew. She was a quiet,
                                peaceable Sister; faithful at all times to her duty, and now that she has entered into
                                rest, we can say, "Give her of the fruit of her hands; and let her own works praise her
                                in the gates." J. W. S.</p></div3></div2><pb n="172" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Among the features that merit special consideration in the June number of The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health, is an article on the Faculty of Language,
                                illustrated; a plirenograph by the editor on Miss Susan B. Anthony, that will doubtless
                                be read by many who are now interested in the movement for Woman Suffrage; a sketch of
                                the characteristics of Ancient Man, with views of his skull form ; the Ethics of
                                Jealousy; Character Studies, including a brilliant plirenograph of Miss Florence
                                Rockwell, a young dramatic artist, by Professor Sizer, and How to Study Strangers. The
                                fresh installment of Phrenological Biography involves the late eminent writer John Neal
                                and Dr. B. A. Parnell. In Child Culture a pleasing sketch of certain phases of domestic
                                experience has the heading of "Three Visits." In the health department, Sir Andrew
                                Clark's Advice, Chinese Ladies' Feet and Effects of Quinine are very suggestive. The
                                editorials have a crisp, pertinent relation to the tlay as indicated by their titles,
                                Sir Walter Scott's Head, The Handwriting on the Wall, Ballot for Women. A variety of
                                other items and references is included in an admirable combination. 15 cents a number,
                                $1.50 a year. Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 25 East Twenty-first street, New York.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To make currant jelly" TEIform="index"/>To Make Currant Jelly.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When making currant jelly, select freshlygathered currants which are not
                                        over-ripe; mash and squeeze them through a jelly bag. Put the juice into a
                                        porcelain-lined kettle and stand over a brisk fire; let boil for twenty minutes;
                                        add a pound of sugar for every pint of juice, and stir until it dissolves. Skim;
                                        bring to a boil; take from the fire; put in glasses anil stand aside to jelly. A
                                        little of the liquid can be tried in a glass before taking up, and if it does
                                        not jelly it may be boiled a few minutes longer. A clear, lighter-colored jelly
                                        can be made by using white and red currants. To make English currant jelly, take
                                        ripe currants; do not pick from the stems; weigh, and allow half a pound of
                                        sugar to every pound of currants. Put the fruit into a preserve kettle; mash and
                                        stir over the fire for twenty-five minutes. Take up; strain through a flannel
                                        bag. Wash the kettle, put the juice in it, let come to a boil and add the sugar;
                                        stir until dissolved; take from the fire; pour in glasses; let cool and cover.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ladies' Home Journal" TEIform="index"/>June Ladies' Home Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Contents. June. Some Phrenological Characteristics of A.
                                J. Clausen; Diphtheria; Who are the Heathen; Anti-Vaccination; An Appeal for the
                                Protection of Children; The Pride of the Company, etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford &amp;
                                Co. Kokomo, Ind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Square talk to young men about the inspiration of the bible" TEIform="index"/>
                                A Square Talk to Young Men about the Inspiration of the Bible
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A Square Talk to Young Men about the Inspiration of the Bible. A book
                                bearing a title so singular as the above must attract the attention of an interested
                                reader. A Square talk about the Bible would signify thtit it is a straight forward and
                                fair illustration of the subject. The work contains about one hundred pages, and has
                                been written so simply that even the common people can read it with pleasure; and to
                                show the interest that has been taken in the little book the Publisher says that more
                                than two millions of copies have gone abroad into the world. We will now let the "Square
                                Talk" speak for itself and you will see how nicely it does it. "Suppose for example, all
                                the good people of this town should try the Bible, say for a single year. Suppose you
                                start to-night, and say, "We have heard about that book, and now we will begin and
                                practice its teachings just one year." "What would be the result? There would be no
                                lying, no stealing, no selling rum, no getting drunk, no Jtattling, no mischief making,
                                no gossipping, no vice, no debauchery. Every man would be a good man, and every woman a
                                good woman." After having been so extensively circulated through the world, the good
                                work of this little Book must be far beyond calculation. Read it and see for yourself.
                                Published by H. L. Hastings, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Interpreting prophecy and the appearing of christ" TEIform="index"/>
                                "INTERPRETING PROPHECY" AND THE "Appearing of Christ,"
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"INTERPRETING PROPHECY" AND THE "Appearing of
                                Christ," is the title of a neat little pamphlet of some forty pages, just sent out by A.
                                G. Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. The many at the present time who are interested in
                                the fulfillment of prophecy and in its mathematical calculation, will find themselves by
                                the side of the good old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ
                                so clearly that no occasion can arise for the least doubt. Price, 10 cts. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspirational Hymns and Songs" TEIform="index"/>Inspirational
                                Hymns and Songs
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Inspirational
                                Hymns and Songs, illustrative of the Besurrection Life and Testimony of the Shakers. 10
                                cts.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A   THOUSAND   TUNES
can be played on the Symphonion and the
Polyphon by merely inserting the proper
disc. A concert given your friends in your
own home, the programme changes each
evening.
No Years of Practice. No False Notes.
No Exertion.
Only listen and you hear any entrancing
valtz, beautiful symphony or funeral march,
played in the sweetest tone with perfect
time.
Our large (Jhjikuj of MUSICAL
NOVELTIES u icell forth your personal inspection.
Illustrated Catalogue Free.
K.   SANDER    MUSICAL    INSTRUMENT    CO.,
212 B0YL8T0N STJiEET, BOSTON, MASS.
you
CAN
HAVE
1000 Free Scholarships.
Cosmopolitan
pay your
SCHOOL OR COLLEGE
EXPENSES.
At leading Colleges of the country Vai/:, Vassac,
Harvard, Anx Arisor, Wellesley, Uxivkrsity
of Chicago, Georgetown; the great s-'hools of
Art, Medicine, Music, the
leading Conven's, schools
of Science or Agriculture
TTln'    Cosniopolitmi    ^lii^'azine    will    Kiy-aiilr./.i-    it*
First Edition o!' Lie.OiO C(i,iic for ,1 .lima i-.i,  a_.ii?S>3.
sent out from its own printing-house and bindjry, by
offering One Thousmd Scholarships at the leading colleges and schools of t'le country in consideration of
work which any ambitions young boy or girl can readily dowork at once honorable and cany of accomplhlnuenk.
If you Wish to educate yourselfto have yul" tuition, board, lodging an:l
washing paid at any leading school or college without putting the expense upon your
parents, and solely through your own effortssend for a pamphlet giving full particulars to The Cosmopolitan Magazine, Broadway, 5th Ave. & 25th St., N. Y.
THE
Magazine
All Are Open To You.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
JIbsoIately
Pure
A cream of tartar baking ;>o>vder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latest Unite I /States (jroverumon
Food Report.
Royal  Baking Powder Co.,
106 Wall St., N. Y.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Rip Van Winkle and ot'ier Skct -hes."
240 pages, 4x<>.                   '        10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. ox1}4. Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           $65.00
An. eight day brass time piece made in
1810   by Dr.   Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Spelling Book by Abner Kneeland.    .25
Second vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1725.                                  .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.    A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
CAX I  OBTAIN  A   PATENT?     lor a
prompt rnswer and an honest opini i'\ ^-li:, to
1VIUNN <&z CO., who have had nearly i.a'ty years'
experience in the patent business. Communicr.tions strictly confidential. A Handbook oi Information concerning Patents and how to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue Of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in tha
world.   S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New yoke, 31 Broadway.
.10
Address   H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
A    CONCISE    H1STOKY    OF    THE
SHAKERS.
Just published. The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains 130 pages and has illustrations of the Shakers and their
COMMUNAL HOMES.
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Sever:;! SOCIETIES,  thaiorganization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75  cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address.    H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
American Bee Journal,
IS Oldest, Laryesi. lit- t,
Cheapest, and the Only
weekly B<" -Paper in all
America.  .T2 p;>gv p. $1.00
a year.   Send for F.-ee dimple.
$1.00 BEE-BOOK FREE
it. W. YORK & CO.. 19!) Randolph St., Chicago, 111.
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
H
E
(Established l861 )
<pb n="" id="p29"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>