<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1110" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18811001" TEIform="date">October 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217- 240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>OCTOBER, 1881. 60 Cents Per Annum The Shaker MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United
                        Societies. OUR HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: "Go preach the Kingdom of God!"
                        ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XL No. 10.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="217" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavenly brideship" TEIform="index"/>THE HEAVENLY BRIDESHIP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>THOMAS SMITH</byline><p TEIform="p"> Deak Manifesto—Allow me to congratulate you on the article, in August number with above
                            title ; because it opens rather a new era, that is, one brother can express his thoughts as
                            to the correctness of points, taken by another, how otherwise can we grow ? History seems to
                            be full of strange facts, of which none are more striking than the constant failure of the
                            expectations of religious bodies ; supported by prophecy, embedded in tradition, confirmed
                            by reiteration, positive with bigotry, becoming chosen peoples of God ; they finally decay
                            and lose their hold upon the race, for good. The cause seems to be that they restrict their
                            ideas, beliefs and rewards to very narrow circles; a few are chosen, a few saved, one man
                            controls the salvation of the world ; or one set of men only possess authority to interpret
                            all truth, especially any new truth, or idea. Every era seems to demand change, new men, new
                            thoughts, and thre question of vital importance to us, as well as to all others is, how far
                            are we from the best light of our times ? The article "Heavenly Brideship" in August number
                            seems to be a brotherly criticism of "Circumcision and Beards" in July number, but are the
                            positions taken correct, is it not another skirmish in the continual struggle between those
                            on the one side, who believe that the Gospel of Christ, first and second, takes hold of
                            every act of our lives—Generation, Nutrition, Property and Government ; and all their
                            elaborations; and those who believe that when Jesus Christ came, then all these things
                            ceased to call for attention on the part of his followers; in other words, Jesus Christ came
                            to destroy, make null the Law, instead of fulfilling it. Which did He do ? The Law was a
                            schoolmaster to bring souls to the Gospel. No man upon entering college throws away the
                            rudiments of his early training; the alphabet forms the very foundations of his future
                            acquirements ; he ceases his former lessons only because they have become an incorporate
                            part of his being. No man erecting an edifice, after completion, tears out his foundations,
                            and throws them away ; else when storms come his building falls. Now why does not this law
                            hold good in the higher ethics of our latter-day life ? If Israel walked by law and statute
                            in all things pertaining to life here, for hundreds of years, and the net result was Jesus
                            Christ, why not continue the process, for further results ? Is it not <pb n="218" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                            218 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. just possible that we are suffering for the same processes ? "
                            Think not that I am come to destroy the Law or Prophets, I am not come to destroy, but to
                            fulfill ; for verily I say unto you, that heaven and earth pass, away, one jot or tittle
                            shall in no wise pass from the law, till all be fulfilled." If Jesus fulfilled the law, how
                            am I to escape fulfilling it, if I am His follower ?, And so with every one, it is only on a
                            par with the atonement, to say He fulfilled it for any one else. We sometimes hear, that
                            when Jesus Christ came the law ceased to be operative ; and there is a certain amount of
                            truth in the remark, but only because it is a play upon words. The Penal Law, the law of
                            punishment for breaking the higher law of God, was abrogated, simply, because the higher law
                            was obeyed. When the greater was fulfilled, the lesser ceased to exist ; the Jewish people
                            needed the Penal Law added, because of their transgressions of the original law of God and
                            Nature, relating to generation, food and property, no more than the people of Ann Lee's
                            time, and our own needed the same law for precisely the same transgressions. If the
                            restraints put upon the sexual relation by Moses, and in Christ's day in celibacy ; that the
                            restraints put upun property ended in community of goods, by what process of reasoning can
                            we escape the conclusion that the restraints put upon the use of animal food ended in its
                            entire rejection ? They must stand or fall together. The work of preparation was too vast,
                            too far reaching and elaborate, to find consummation in one man, or set of men ; it was
                            universal ultimately. So with the Bride and Bridegroom ; are they not terms, broad and
                            comprehensive enough to cover systems of thought reaching from the past to the present ?
                            merging the stability of the Jew with the broader and deeper light and knowledge of the
                            present Gentile ? And how does this detract in any wise from the dignity or kinship of Jesus
                            Christ or Mother Ann ? He was the first born of many brethren; she the first born of many
                            sisters; what either of them endured of physical suffering is of minor importance, as
                            compared with the great systems of thought which each headed in their time. Thousands of men
                            and women have borne equal physical pain and f©r righteousness sake. But Jesus and Ann led
                            the van. He represented the Fatherhood of God, she the Motherhood of God, but more than this
                            He represented the training and culture of ages, the stability and permanence of truth in
                            the Divine Man; while she was the protest of the agony and suppression of the Divine Woman
                            calling for recognition ; pressed down by government, social custom and blind ignorance. She
                            reached beyond her condition and claimed equality with her brother, Jesus. Why should her
                            system reject His culture ? Why should the basis of past progress be rejected by her
                            followers ? Is there no grandeur and beauty in the consummation of the Divine promise that "
                            all sickness and pain, all suffering and every thing that hurts or harms, in all God's holy
                            mountain shall be removed ?" Go with me throughout the quiet homes of our dear brethren and
                            sisters from Maine to Kentucky and what is there more needed than health? Ask your memory
                            how many of the bravest and truest have fallen by the fell hand of disease, when Zion most
                            needed them—irreparable losses ; and have we not grown in beauty as a people, as fast as
                            truth has regulated our lives in relation to this world ? • There exists a grave
                            inconsistency in our saying, " The way for the followers of Christ to do right about
                            generation is to let it entirely alone," and then say in relation to its fellow subjects, do
                            as the Gentiles do. Generation and its kindred subjects are all laid under the same
                            diseipline of the Law, viz., curtailment and restraint, and we say in relation to
                            generation, this restraint points to extinction, for a higher life, but its fellow subjects
                            are of no importance. Because the Law was first, does not necessitate the assumption that
                            the Gospel is subordinate, by any means ; the lesser always precedes the greater, the
                            greater conserves the lesser, not destroys it. " Because the law was weak through the flesh
                            " the gospel removed the flesh, and the law <pb n="219" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 219
                            became strong, not a nullity. Then when the truths of both dispensations are embodied in
                            human society, will we be able to sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the song
                            of the Lamb ; then differences of opinion will not constitute men heretics or lunatics, but
                            the Law having given us Truth and Justice, the Gospel will give us Love which melts and
                            merges differences of opinion into the Brotherhood and Sisterhood of Christ. Canaan, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sometime" TEIform="index"/>SOMETIME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schultz, Maria L." TEIform="persName"/>MARIA L. SCHULTZ</byline><p TEIform="p"> Sometime, when all my weary tasks are done, And life's hard lessons learned, When ceased the
                            tired walks from sun to sun,— When rest is fairly earned; — When all the crosses have been
                            carried through, Temptations met, and passed ; —I think there will be something sweet and
                            true. To bless me at the last. And if, through all the darkly-curtained days Of years which
                            follow Time, I can look up, and see the golden rays Of God's love-light sublime ; — If I can
                            drink life's bitter wine, and still Taste His sweet love divine, I think that I may know
                            that 'tis His will To test this faith of mine. But if my heart complains because its tasks
                            Do all so hard appear, And in unreconciled impatience asks Why life is so severe ; — And if
                            it murmurs that it cannot learn The lesson it most needs, I think there will be one for me,
                            more stern To translate into deeds. Then let me lowly live, and faithful, keep God's
                            counsels as I go, Rememb'ring there's a harvest yet to reap From seeds which now I sow. And
                            if, with holy courage, for Truth's sake, My soul through trial stands,— I think it will be
                            something sweet to take A blessing from God's hands. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wagan, Robert M." TEIform="persName"/>ROBERT M. WAGAN</byline><p TEIform="p">ELDER 0 Lord, we pray, remember us, a small, dependant, needy band. We ask for faith to bear
                            us on that we may wear the victor's crown. 0, grant us true humility that we may never stray
                            through pride and lust and our own ways; but help us always keep the straight and narrow
                            path of daily selfdenial. For Zion's sake may we be blest, and, by good works, an honor be
                            to her and Thee. 0, may Thy counsels gather us, and Thy great mercies cover us and help us
                            to stand a true devoted band, though tempests rage and billows roll. When in affliction's
                            dark hour trials come upon us, and tribulation doth oppress our souls, O, may we never doubt
                            nor faint, but ever keep in mind Thou art our comforter, a never-failing source of stength
                            and peace and joy forever. Give to them that ask in faith and prayer. Remember Thy lambs,
                            the children and youth, may they be dealt with tenderly, and, may the sweet rose of
                            innocence ever blossom and diffuse its fragrance throughout this Holy Mountain ; may they
                            repose in Thy love, which will reprove and chasten them for all their errors, plant them
                            firmly in Thy garden, that they may grow strong in the faith of Thy righteous saints.
                            Cultivate them in Thy holy fear and tender love, that they may see Thee at all times,
                            whether in joy and rejoicing, or in sorrow and affliction, whether in pleasant bowers and by
                            flowing streams, or tempest tossed on life's stormy sea, or left to scale ihe rugged
                            mountain — the pathway of burden-bearing souls. Bless all of Thy chosen ones, those
                            righteous aged souls, fathers and mothers in Israel who have kept Thy holy way, and been
                            ingtrumental in the salvation of other souls, weary and worn ; gather them to Thy sweet
                            haven of eternal peace and rest; may their mantle of strength rest upon other souls when
                            they depart this mortal life, that Zion may never lack a fullness of the power of salvation
                            from the nature of sin. Bless all Thy faithful workers; like bees in the hive, may they
                            gather in <pb n="220" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 220 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. heavenly bowers, and from fragrant
                            flowers in pleasant valleys, sip sweetness and richness of purest love and blessing. For
                            Zion's sake, fan, 0 fan, thresh and fan and separate the precious from the vile. Prune Thy
                            vines, lop from the tree of life the dead unfruitful branches, that Thy vineyard may be an
                            honor and joy to Thee forever. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Intellectual and spiritual progress" TEIform="index"/>INTELLECTUAL AND SPIRITUAL PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> The vast ocean of human thought and intelligence is deepening and broadening as time rolls
                            on. Truth, scientifically and spiritually, sends forth its darts, and its lances pierce old
                            and long-established forms and canons of the past, and mythology with its misty shades
                            disappear as vapory clouds vanish before the rising sun ; science, applied to the varied
                            departments of human life, progresses with such rapidity, it is with difficulty the common
                            mind keeps pace with the marvelous developments which time — as it moves on rapid wing—
                            reveals. A boundless storehouse seems to have opened in this nineteenth century from which
                            to draw all kinds of useful knowledge pertaining to the earth life ; also knowledge
                            concerning the spirit spheres is becoming almost universal throughout civilized nations, in
                            the cottage of the humble and lowly as well as in royal palaces. But without a right
                            application of such knowledge, how will it benefit humanity? " Ignorance is not bliss ; "
                            neither is knowledge bliss, unless turned into proper channels, and it be made to conserve
                            the good and true. Knowledge, unattended by wisdom and prudence, often culminates in folly.
                            Knowledge is easy to those who have enlightened consciences, and correct understanding, and
                            are willing that wisdom shall take precedence of knowledge; so that every great thought that
                            has been cradled in obscurity may be directed to useful ends and purposes, and prove a
                            benefactor to the race, when evolved from its hitherto covert resting place, and be made to
                            hasten the reign of universal love and peace, when truth shall triumph over error, and
                            right, instead of might, rule in the councils of nations, and conduct the affairs of men.
                            Spiritualism as it now^exists is undefinable and unreliable. While it indicates progress,
                            and is a nullifier of all creeds and dogmas, it fails to offer a better system of practical
                            Christianity. In many ways it points in a wrong direction and leads to latitudinarianisrn,
                            pleasing the senses and feeding the sensual appetites. Spiritualism, as far as it inculcates
                            purity of life and embodies the principles of love to God and man, bears witness that it is
                            a messenger sent from celestial spheres on an errand of love and mercy to the race of
                            mankind. We hope it will accomplish the work it was sent to perform, and not prove to be a
                            hydra-headed monster, unworthy the name it bears ; but prove to be a child of God,
                            commissioned by angels not onlv to enlighten the inhabitants of the earth sphere, but also
                            to quicken and vivify their consciences, and cause them to be more spiritual, and to bring
                            them into more just and harmonial relations with their brother man, and into closer union
                            and communion with God and His good angels. The phenomenal conspicuity of modern
                            spiritualism has arrested the attention, and attracted millions of people to it, and to
                            accept it as a theory, who in reality did not wish to be more self-denying in their life
                            practices, and to rise unto a higher plane' to live as do the angels, and be lifted up in
                            spirit and draw others unto them, as did the Judean prince and prototype. Hence,
                            spiritualism so named, in its present form, needs to be spiritualized. It lacks the
                            testimony of Jesus, the vital forces which can alone vivify and re-create the souls of men
                            and women, and cause them to expand and grow into the image of the heavenly. We are not
                            satisfied with a tree that only bios, soms well, however beautiful it may appear to the
                            external senses ; but in due time we look for the fruitage. The tree of modern spiritualism
                            blossomed well, and its aroma was borne by spiritual winds to distant lands. Now, it is time
                            to expect fruit. Religion is the essence of divine love. As <pb n="221" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 221 the soil of the earth would be cold and barren without the vivifying rays of
                            the sun, so is the human heart without faith in God, and the true love that inspires and
                            moves it to works of unselfish devotion for the good of humanity, as well as our own soul's
                            progress into higher realms of thought and action, where our motto shall ever be: " Blessed
                            are the pure in heart." Undefiled, unadulterated religion is what we need. Professions,
                            names and titles are of no account, if the heart is not right before God. If some who have
                            heard the call, " Come up hither," and have partly arisen with Christ onto the resurrection
                            plane of life and have " run well fora season," if they lay by their gospel armor and cease
                            the strife so that they lose their hold and standing, it will not change principle nor alter
                            truth. The higher they have risen the greater the fall. If angels fall, they must find their
                            place with fallen angels in a demoniac condition. God is not dependent upon mortals to
                            perform His work, but we are dependent upon Him for safe guidance and protection. And if we
                            keep His laws inviolate and bring forth fruit meet for repentance and the approval of good
                            angels, we have naught to fear. Gospel friends, let us take timely warning.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reformation" TEIform="index"/>REFORMATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> It was said by one a great while ago, " I once was young but now I am old, yet I have not
                            seen the righteous forsaken nor his seed begging bread." There are those in modern times who
                            might make the same declaration, for there are many who pass for righteous who would not
                            bear a very close scrutiny without disclosing some unrighteous acts. Tho' those acts be ever
                            so secret yet will they tell on the coming generation. So we are forced to the conclusion
                            that antenatal conditions have more to do in shaping the character and disposition of
                            children than would at first appear. The profligacy of ministers' children is so common that
                            it has become a proverb, that ministers have the worst children. But it does not follow that
                            because one looks after his neighbor's garden that his own is free from weeds. Besides there
                            may be some difference in preaching and practicing. Were those who are about to become
                            parents aware of the misery entailed upon children by antenatal conditions how earnestly
                            they would strive to make those conditions harmonious and agreeable. Many well-meaning
                            parents through ignorance entail lasting misery on their children. I once heard of a woman
                            who on her dying bed confessed to her husband that she had been in the habit of pilfering
                            frem him to eke out the allowance which he gave her for the use of the family. She mentioned
                            it, not that she thought that she had done wrong, but that her successor might not be
                            expected to do with the small allowance which was insufficient. We might at first think it a
                            small matter, but when we consider the disposition entailed upon the children by the
                            penurious miserly disposition of the father and the pilfering practices of the mother, who
                            can estimate the amount of misery visited on the children, it may be, to the third and
                            fourth generation. There is a great need ef reform. If we wish to improve the quality of our
                            fruit, we do not wait till the apples begin to grow, but commence in the fall with the tree.
                            Prune it thoroughly, attend to the condition of the soil and see that the tree is free from
                            every obnoxious influence and then under favorable cenditions we may look for superior
                            fruit. It has been said and that justly that there is more common sense used in every other
                            department of culture than that of the human species. " From whence come wars and fightings
                            among you ? come they not hence even lusts that war in your members ?" That is it, let lust
                            be subdued. Those who would bring about a reform in morals, temperance and peace had better
                            commence by teaching the present generation how to propagate their species in a pure,
                            orderly way. Then they may with confidence look for a reform in the next generation. Let
                            parents indulge in no act or disposition <pb n="222" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 222 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            that they would not entail upon thei children, then the coming generation wil show a great
                            improvement. Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="After many days" TEIform="index"/>AFTER MANY DAYS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcomb, Ola Leone" TEIform="persName"/>OLA LEONE WHITCOMB</byline><p TEIform="p"> Toward the hour of evening, the ships tha launched for me Will come sailing proudly in
                            across the hays, And the worried hopes and frettings which they bore out on the sea Will
                            come back as golden treasures, after many days. In the sober gray of Autumns, when the
                            leaves are falling down, All the seed I scattered in the smiling Mays, Shall their heavy
                            heads be bowing, till I bear them home at night, And my garners fill with riches, after many
                            days. Sometimes the morn will open with a drear and mourning dawn, And the sun will hidden
                            be, beneath its maze, But my heart shall never murmur, for I know it needs the rain, And the
                            light will smile upon me, after many days. While the winter winds are blowing, and the frost
                            is on the pane, While the blinding snow is piled along the ways, I remember June will
                            follow, in the path December trod, And the flowers will wait my coming, after many days. Oh!
                            the road I'm treading daily, seemeth weary and perplexed, Through a labyrinth of thorns and
                            stones it lays, But it will be brighter sometime, and my feet have stronger grown, And the
                            distance will be shorter, after many days. Ah! after many days will the yoke I've barely
                            borne Carry lighter, and reflect the golden rays Of the holy light of heaven, and my heavy
                            cross will be Transfigured to my shining crown, after many days. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentissiana" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA</head><p TEIform="p">"Great men are not always wise." Many mighty ones have essayed to give the biography and
                            whereabouts of deity. "I also will show mine opinion." To the inquiry, " Where shall I find
                            God?" a fair damsel, brought up in Shakerdom, responded: " 'Tis not for me to say where you
                            shall find God. 1 find God in all the works of creation, in mountains and valleys, in
                            oceans, rivers and rills, in birds, squirrels and wild flowers. I find God in my brother and
                            sisters, but most important of all, I find God in my own soul, a law to direct my every
                            action, word and thought." " Mine opinion is, the Shaker damsel was not so wide of the
                            mark."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Instinct, food and medicine" TEIform="index"/>INSTINCT, FOOD AND MEDICINE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p"> The object of food is to supply the natural waste of the system from day to day, and night
                            by night. Under natural conditions, food should be our medicine, as it is our
                            aliment.appetite is a safe guide to health as well as to satisfaction, eating and drinking
                            be for health and strength, to our best knowledge. This would honor God and glorify human
                            being, because it would be under the law of right, of use. Let us live and not die. Self
                            preservation is the first law of nature. Health is life, disease is death. The wicked shall
                            not live out half their days, nor do they. Dying, they die daily. They take pleasure in
                            unrighteousness, in things injurious to the body, and by sequence to the soul. What is
                            right, and what wrong, what healthy, and what unhealthy, are questions ever occurring, ever
                            to be replied unto. Individuals, having their senses exercised )y reason of use, would
                            forever be acquirng knowledge by their own observations and experience, and from the
                            observation and experience of other human beings. It is related of Father Joseph, that if he
                            lit his foot against a stone, he would re ¦ move it, or note it, holding that there were no
                            accidents in ^Christ. He ^was a wise, <pb n="223" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. 223
                            thinking, observing man, foreseing the evil afar off, where the foot would have passed on
                            and perished, in proportion to his folly. That man goeth astray from his mother's womb,
                            there can be no doubt. These physiological conditions of breathing, bathing, eating,
                            exercise and drinking, are not natural but artificial. Appetites and habits are thus
                            engendered that are lusts, producing disease and sickness, not continued health. The man, or
                            woman, who is under the leading of any lust of body or mind, is like a ship on the ocean,
                            whose captain and pilot are too drunk to manage the ship. The winds blow, the fires are kept
                            up by the engineer, the boiler generates power, and the ship moves, but it moves as
                            uncertain and never reaches the port of content and satisfaction. The fear of the Lord is
                            the beginning of wisdom, and to depart from* iniquity, from wrong doing, is understanding.
                            There is a blessedness in existence, when it is supported by law, by obedience to what we
                            know, or even to what we think is right, light being sown for the right-doer, and gladness
                            filling the heart, because love is created by truth. Truth, practiced in our necessities,
                            brings us near to God in nature, desire becomes a safe rrule of action. We become Godlike,
                            in that we are not even tempted, by false appetite, to abnormal action. When Anna Lee prayed
                            that God would give her good desires, she only prayed she might be as God, in her sphere of
                            existence, be happy. The sum of the whole matter is, a human being should be as susceptible
                            to constitutional craving (of which maternal longing and false appetite are but a
                            perversion), as are the wild animals, who are moved by natural instinct, to select from the
                            botanical variety of the country they inhabit, such articles as are both food and medicine.
                            The cook and the doctor should be all one. Then the pots in the kitchen to cook the food,
                            and the bells on the houses of agriculture to raise it, wouldall be holiness unto the Lord,
                            and sin and sickness go together into the hells on earth, to be forgotten by the saints in
                            Heaven.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep cool if you would succeed. It takes a cool hammer to bend hot iron" TEIform="index"/>Keep cool if you would succeed. It takes a cool hammer to bend hot iron
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Keep cool if you would succeed. It takes a cool hammer to bend hot iron.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True rest" TEIform="index"/>TRUE REST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard Pelham</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following is attributed to that re markably good man, of N. Union Society. If we mistake
                            let us be corrected. It is a remarkable poem, whoever wrote it.—Ed.] If thou should'st fail
                            to find true rest In earth, thou'lt find it not in heaven ; Here must it dwell within thy
                            breast, Or thou must tempest-tost be driven. For what is rest ? not indolence Of body, or of
                            mind, or soul ? Not in the loss of sight or sense, Not in the grave our earthly goal. It is
                            not freedom from the ills Which flesh is heir to—sickness, pain, Malice that wounds or Death
                            that kills, Temptation's lure or penury's chain. In vain in nature's solitude Tis fondly
                            sought—in hermit's cell, Where stranger footsteps ne'er intrude— On mountain top, in silent
                            dell ; It reigns not in the peasant's cot, Nor in the palace of the king. It is not found by
                            chance or lot; 'Tis not a partial, birthright thing. Gold cannot buy, nor valor win, Nor
                            power command, nor station gain it, Whatever bears the taint of sin, Unpurified cannot
                            obtain it. Thou mayest have beauty, wit and parts, That shall secure the vast acclaim, And
                            be the idol of all hearts, And gather universal fame ; And by the potentates of earth Be
                            honored as a chosen guest; And be exalted from thy birth—Yet never know ono hour of rest.
                            Thou mayest upon thy very knees Have gone on many a pilgrimage, And far excelled all
                            devotees That ever trod this mortal stage. In self-inflicted agonies, All sinful lusts to
                            crucify ; In vain thy tears, and groans, and cries, Rest by such acts thou canst not buy.
                            Thou mayest have joined some chosen sect And given thy sanction to a creed, And been
                            pronounced among the elect, And zealous been in word and deed— Most orthodox of proselytes
                            Strict in observing seasons, days, Church order, ceremonies, rites, Constant at church to
                            pray and praise ; Munificent in all good works, That with the gospel may be blest All
                            heathen tribes, Jews, Greeks and Turks, Yet still a stranger be to rest. For what is rest ?
                            'Tis not to be Half saint, half sinner, day by day ; Half saved, half lost, half bound, half
                            free ; Half in the fold and half astray ; <pb n="224" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 224 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO.
                            Faithless this hour, the next most true ; Just half alive, half crucified; Half washed and
                            half polluted too ; To Christ and Belial both allied ! Now trembling at Mount Sinai's base,
                            Anon on Calvary's summit shouting ; One instant boasting of free grace— The next God's
                            pardoning mercy doubting, Now sinning, now denouncing sin, Filled with alternate joy and
                            sorrow ; To-day feel all renewed within, But fear a sad relapse to-morrow ! All ardent now
                            and eloquent, Or bold for God with soul on fire, At once complete extinguishment Ensues, and
                            all thcsparks expire O, most unhappy of mankind, In thee what contradictions meet, Seeing
                            thy way yet groping blind ; Most conscientious, yet a cheat; Allowing what thou dost abhor,
                            And hating what thou dost allow. Dreaming of freedom by the law, Yet held in bondage until
                            now ! This is " the old man with his deeds," Striving to do his very best. 'Tis crucifixion
                            that he needs— Self-righteous, how can he know rest ? What then is rest ? It is to be
                            Perfect in love and holiness, From sin eternally made free ; Not under law but under grace.
                            Once cleansed from guilt, forever pure; Once pardoned, ever reconciled ; Once healed to find
                            a perfect cure, As Jesus, blameless, undefiled ; Once saved no more to go astray ; Once
                            crucified, then always dead ; Once in the new and living way, True ever to our living Head ;
                            Dwelling in God and God in us; From every spot and wrinkle clear, Safely delivered from the
                            curse ; Incapable of doubt or fear. It is to have eternal life ; To follow where the Saviour
                            trod; To be removed from earthly strife— Joint-heirs of Christ, and sons of God, Never from
                            rectitude to swerve, Though by the powers of hell pursued, To consecrate without reserve,
                            All we possess in doing good. It is to glory in the Cross, Endure reproach, despise the
                            shame, And wisely count as dung and dross All earthly grandeur, homage, fame, To know the
                            Shepherd of the sheep— Be gentle, harmless, meek and lowly ; All joy, all hope, all peace—to
                            keep, Not one in seven, but all days holy. It is to be all prayer and praise, Not in set
                            form or phrase expressed, But ceaseless as angelic lays— This, only this, is Christian Rest.
                            He who, believing, hath obtained This rest, shall ne'er be troubled more, Though round him
                            lions fierce, unchained, For his destruction rage and roar. He may be famishing for bread,
                            Or be of men the jest and mirth. And have nowhere to lay his head. No spot to call his own
                            on earth ; Temptation with its endless wiles May strive to turn his feet aside, And flattery
                            with its treacherous smiles May hope to flush some latent pride. He may be hunted as a
                            beast— As heretic dragged to the stake ; Placed on the rack, Revenge to feast, And Bigotry's
                            fierce wrath to slake ; Or whether death or hell assail It matters not; within his breast
                            Are joy and peace that cannot fail : This, only, is true Christian rest.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden picture" TEIform="index"/>A GOLDEN PICTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vance, John B." TEIform="persName"/>JOHN B. VANCE</byline><p TEIform="p">[The following beautiful tribute to The Manifesto, as well as " words fitly spoken " on vital
                            subjects, is fully appreciated by us. We would the world had, at least, twenty more such
                            admirable specimens of humanity — we mean just like him — as we know his whole soul to be.
                            We must be excused for withholding his closing remarks, as we feel unworthy of them, and,
                            therefore, unwilling to have them made public.— Ed.] Editor Manifesto — How often have I
                            exclaimed after reading The Manifesto : "Excellent!" "Splendid!" And now, after perusing the
                            September number, I am constrained to repeat it loud enough to reach your ears, so many
                            miles away. While the articles from the pens of such noted correspondents as " Giles B.
                            Avery," " F. W. Evans " and "Antoinette Doolittle " are always excellent, and in this number
                            show their usual ability, " Christian Progress," by Sister Marcia Bullard, claims my
                            particular admiration. It was replete with truth — and truths which we, as a people, need to
                            take home to our hearts, and heed well to-day. It would be the height of folly to forget
                            that we are human, and prone to err, sub* ject to the same worldly attractions, if we open
                            our hearts to them, as any people, our name giving us no additional protection. Sister
                            Marcia tells us that " when the <pb n="225" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 225 Quakers so
                            far forgot their union that they wrangled about doctrine, they sank into worldlings ; " and
                            " when the Methodists, tired of their plainness, ran after the fashions of the world, they
                            no longer had spiritual gifts, nor came under the influence of the power of God; and the
                            Shakers should profit by their example." And should they not ? What are we more than the
                            rest of erring humanity that we should not be equally affected by similar influences if we
                            take them home to our hearts and habitations ? Why ! While reading the above, I felt like
                            crying out as our English cousins do when a speaker pleases them : " Hear ! Hear'! " And I
                            would that every one of our little number could hear, and remember her warning, " the
                            Shakers should profit by their example." While so much is being said of the necessity of
                            cultivating the esthetic feelings, may we not be blind or deaf to the lessons taught by past
                            history. As is well said by Elder Giles, the workers in the Lord's cause, His witnesses in
                            every age, have been the Ascetics, and the path they traveled was the path of self-denial,
                            being willing to say " nay " to all of the importunities of the world. While the falling
                            away from every spiritual epoch has been marked by the ascendancy of the esthetics, if I may
                            so use the word. Shall we stand where others have fallen ? Not if we walk in the same path.
                            Some will say, " Oh, my religion does not consist in the dress I wear." Not more surely do
                            the various trees of the forest designate their kind by the foliage they put forth than do
                            the dress and surroundings indicate the spiritual travel of a people. May we not be
                            deceived—it is the world, whether we realize it or not, that is saying to us : " Your dress
                            is too simple to please my taste, I will give you pearls fo wear; Rich velvets and silks to
                            grace your form, And diamonds to deck your hair." And " Your house is too plain," said the
                            proud old world, " I'll build you one like mine ; Carpets from Brussells and curtains of
                            lace, And furniture ever so fine." While we would desire the beautiful, may we remember
                            there is a beauty peculiar to the flower, or generative period, and a beauty which belongs
                            to the ripened fruit and grain. If we really are of that number who are called the " first
                            fruits," preparing ourselves to be harvested from the earth, we shall best love the beauty
                            that is adapted to our condition. And our march up the hill of progression will be a
                            successful one if we are willing to accept the sister's test as to what really is
                            progression, and the spirit that goes with it. '' Every spirit that saith come up higher,
                            bear more crop, practice more self-denial, live more separate from worldly influences, is
                            safe to follow." Amen and amen. I notice that you advertise for an editor for the Manifesto,
                            and very kindly name the qualification desirable. I have my mind on one that will very
                            nearly fill the bill, having in a good degree all of the requirements called for. Perhaps I
                            had better say acquirements, for no small part have been acquired under the very severe
                            disciplinary conditions named in your article. He is none other than our dear friend and
                            brother who started with the very beginning of our little publication, by doing well, and
                            has gone with that into doing much better— growing, through the discipline named, into a
                            degree of excellence that is easy to bless and admire. * * * In bonds of sympathy and love,
                            I remain,</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday with the Shakers" TEIform="index"/>A SUNDAY WITH THE SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Some of our readers have seen the Shaker service. Many have not. For the benefit
                                    of both we give to-day a report of last Sunday's Shaker meeting at the little chapel
                                    on the border of Androscoggin county, some eleven miles from Lewiston. Shaker
                                    village is perched on one of the most arduous hills of the county. Miles away you
                                    can see the large, stone fortress-like building where one of the two Shaker families
                                    composing the community lives. The second family's home is in a weather-stained,
                                    old-fashioned building, almost one hundred years of age. It was built in 1795, and
                                    the elder said, after service last Sunday, " It's not fit for a Christian to live
                                    in. We're making preparations <pb n="226" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 226 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. now
                                    to build a new one." The Shakers in their dignified drab coat-tails, and Shakeresses
                                    in their neat, plain gowns, glistening white-pointed kerchiefs, and their
                                    scrupulously starched bonnets, were marching from the house to the chapel when the
                                    reporter arrived. In the church the Shakers formed, standing in two squares, the
                                    males in one and the females in the other. The two divisions stood facing each
                                    other, with their hands clasped in front of them. In the rear ranks of each body
                                    stood the young wards of the community. There were three little boys of eight to ten
                                    years, and half a dozen girls, apparently of four to fourteen years, whose long,
                                    braided hair formed a marked contrast with the closely concealed locks orf the
                                    Shaker women. The little boys' crowns were closely shaven, while the locks at the
                                    base of the head had been allowed to grow down their necks in imitation of the
                                    flowing, patriarchal hair of the aged Shakers. Standing in this position, one voice
                                    commenced a strain of quaint song, which ail took up. It was something between a
                                    hymn and a chant. The melody was strange but pleasing, and was sung by all the
                                    voices, male and female, in unison. An impressive effect was given the last chord by
                                    all the singers gradually softening the tone, and ending the diminuendo in barely a
                                    murmur, at the same time slowly lowering their hands from the clasped position to
                                    their sides in perfect harmony with the movement of the music. The elder then
                                    stepped forward to the space between the two sections of Shakers. The lines of his
                                    face indicate a man of remarkable firmness of character. The high, sloping forehead,
                                    the prominent Roman nose, the unrelaxed facial muscles, his stately demeanor, and
                                    the distinct solemn utterances of a deep, musical voice, all pointed to a mind of
                                    the most positive convictions, and ability of no mean order. The elder read the
                                    fourth chapter of St. John. The women and children then sang spiritedly a beautiful
                                    hymn. This and all the following hymns were given the same tremulous diminuendo,
                                    ending as before. In the next song one common spirit seemed to move the worshipers
                                    in a stately march backward and forward across the floor of the chapel. They kept
                                    perfect time with the tune they sang, and marched with the regularity of militia,
                                    making square heels, and accompanying their march with a swinging motion of the arms
                                    and hands, palms backward. There were several fine signers among the men, and all
                                    the women had excellent voices. The juvenile Shakers seemed to enter into the
                                    service with the same enthusiasm as the veterans. It was amusing to a spectator to
                                    watch the solemn faces and attitudes of the little fellows. Not a suggestion of a
                                    smile came over their features, and, to our mind, the staidest Shaker of them all
                                    was a lad of perhaps ten summers. He wore a loose, cherry-colored sacque and a
                                    high-buttoned velveteen waistcoat. He had a fair, untanned face, and pale blue eyes.
                                    The blue veins were seen through the delicate skin covering his temples, and he had
                                    a dreamy, far-away look. The neck-locks of light hair fell over his coat-collar. He
                                    seemed possessed of a most intense spirituality, and was as deeply ab sorbed in his
                                    devotions as the elder himself. The Shakers take these children by adoption, and
                                    have more requests to take and bring up orphan and uncared-for children than they
                                    can comply with. The wards are indentured to them until they are twentyone. Then
                                    they are at liberty to leave the community and go into the world if they wish. The
                                    Shakers educate them, and give them the best of home training. After several
                                    marching songs, the Shakers took seats. We had noticed among them one sandy-haired
                                    young man, apparently of not more than twenty-five yea.rs of age, who wore a
                                    plum-colored coat, and who sang with much unction. The young man stepped forward
                                    nervously, drank a little water from a glass, opened a Bible which lay on a window
                                    shelf, and after a nervous lifting of the shoulders and compression of the lips,
                                    read a text from the eighth verse of the third chapter of Second Peter: "But,
                                    beloved, be not ignorant of this one thing, that one day is with the Lord as a
                                    thousand years, and a thousand years as one day." He then spoke earnestly, for about
                                    fifteen <pb n="227" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 227 minutes, without notes, in
                                    a measured, distinct and cultured voice. The speaker's words were listened to with
                                    the most profound attention by the audience. He was William Paul, the eloquent young
                                    preacher of the Shakers. Mr. Paul has been with them about four years. He is older
                                    than he looks, having reached the age of thirty-five years. He was born in Scotland,
                                    and educated in Glasgow. There are few pulpit orators who have the power of clothing
                                    their ideas in such chaste and eloquent language, or addressing themselves directly
                                    to the hearts of their hearers to a greater degree than this young Shaker Scotchman.
                                    After he concluded, another song was sung. The preacher then arose again and said :
                                    "If any of our visiting friends desire to say a few words they have perfect
                                    liberty." One of the strangers present arose and explained the recently inaugurated
                                    custom of passing the contribution box. He said that it had not been originated by
                                    the Shakers themselves, but by the outsiders, who desired to see the chapel
                                    enlarged, in order that they might be accommodated more conveniently. He then passed
                                    the hat and got a liberal collection. The elder arose and said quietly: " Let us lay
                                    aside our seats and form a circle." The settees were placed beside the walls. A
                                    small circle of singers formed in the center of the chapel. Around this inner circle
                                    the other worshipers formed in double file, and marched, while all joined in the
                                    Shaker hymns, and kept up constantly a swinging motion of their arms and hands in
                                    concert with the rhythm. They took a very graceful promenade step, the women
                                    leading, and the small boys bringing up the rear. The queenly form and bearing of
                                    one woman, apparently one of the eldresses of the community, was noticed by every
                                    beholder. A handsome white silk handkerchief and the regal grace exhibited in her
                                    walk distinguished her from her sister Shakers. The sightless eyes of one very aged
                                    and infirm Shaker, who took part in the other exercises, prohibited him from
                                    participating in this. Four or five songs were sung and accompanied by this strange,
                                    sober walkaround. One of the scalp-locked lads was in the file with the elder, and
                                    the little fellow both lengthened his stride and drew down his face to equal
                                    proportions with the elder. The marching ceased, and the elder, after a few remarks,
                                    read an article from a publication called " The Shaker Manifesto," published by the
                                    United Societies. The reading was followed by testimonies by the brothers and
                                    sisters. One aged, gray-haired brother said : " I'm not ashamed of the Shaker life.
                                    I'm glad I have given up the life of self and given my life to God. I want to be a
                                    better Shaker." A sister said: "I think the angels have come near unto us in our
                                    devotions. I am glad I am a Shaker. At the age of sixteen I said to myself: "Shall I
                                    serve myself or the Lord? Shall I live a life of pleasure or a godly life? I said I
                                    would serve God, and I feel that I have done it. It has been a satisfaction to me to
                                    escape many trials, get out of the world, assume the plain dress and language, ani
                                    live a life of purity. I'm glad I did so. I know I would have been as liable as any
                                    woman in this world to succumb to temptations of the world if I hadn't placed myself
                                    beyond them." After more marching the venerable blind Shaker closed the exercises by
                                    speaking a few words and requesting the audience to remain seated while they passed
                                    out. This was done. The Shaker service was over, when the patriarch was reverently
                                    led out of the door by a young brother.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Lewiston journal (Maine)" TEIform="index"/>Lewiston (Me.) Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saving mother" TEIform="index"/>SAVING MOTHER</head><p TEIform="p">[The following poem we clip from The Banner of Light.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Those who can read between the lines will perceive a not uncommon case of
                                    neglect, not only of " saving mother," but of a too-common case of an unworthy
                                    cupidity, overbalancing the proper love of humanity from sheer selfish motives. The
                                    rebuke is an excellent one. Do any of our readers need it 1 — Ed.] The farmer sat in
                                    his easy chair Between the fire and the lamplight's glare, His face was ruddy and
                                    full and fair; His three small boys in the chimney nook Conned the lines of a
                                    picture-book; <pb n="228" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 228 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. His wife, the pride
                                    of his home and heart, Baked the biscuit and made the tart, Laid the table and
                                    steeped the tea, Deftly, swiftly, silently; Tired and weary, and weak and faint, She
                                    bore her trials without complaint, Like many another household saint — Content, all
                                    selfish bliss above, In the patient ministry of love. At last between the clouds of
                                    smoke That wreathed his lips the husband spoke: " There's taxes to raise, and
                                    int'rest to pay, And ef there should come a rainy day, 'T would be mighty handy, I
                                    'm bound to say, T' have somethin' put by. For folks die. An' tnere 's the funeral
                                    bills, and gravestones to buy — Enough to swamp a man, purty nigh ; Besides, there's
                                    Edward, Dick and Joe To be provided for when we go. So'f I was you, I'll tell ye
                                    what I'd du; I 'd be savin' of wood as ever I could — Extra fires don't du any good
                                    — I 'd be savin' of sope, an' savin' of ile, And run up some candles once in a while
                                    ; I 'd be rather sparin' of coffee an' tea, For sugar is high And all to buy, And
                                    cider is good enough drink for me. I 'd be kind o' careful about my clo'es, And look
                                    out sharp' how the money goes — Gewgaws is useless, nater knows ; Extry trimmin' 'S
                                    the bane of women. I 'd sell off the best of the cheese and honey, And eggs is as
                                    good, nigh about, 's the money; And as to the carpet you wanted new — I guess we can
                                    make the old one du. And as for the washer an' sewin' machine. Them smooth-tongued
                                    agents so pesky mean You 'd better get rid of 'em slick and clean. What du they know
                                    about woman's work? Du they calkilate women was born to shirk ?" Dick and Edward and
                                    little Joe Sat in the corner in a row. They saw the patient mother go On ceaseless
                                    errands to and fro; They saw that her form was bent and thin, Hertemples gray, her
                                    cheeks sunk in; They saw the quiver of lip and chin — And then, with a wrath he
                                    could not smother, Outspoke the youngest, frailest brother: " You talk of savin'
                                    wood and ile, An' tea and sugar all the while, But you never talk of savin' mother."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Banner of light" TEIform="index"/>The Banner of Light.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No books are so legible as the lives of men ; no characters so plain as their moral conduct" TEIform="index"/>No books are so legible as the lives of men; no characters so plain as their moral conduct...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">No books are so legible as the lives of men ; no characters so plain as their moral
                        conduct.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shoshone oath" TEIform="index"/>THE SHOSHONE OATH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline><p TEIform="p">How pitiful that man must anxious seek In every age some form of oath to find Which "may his
                            fellows terrify and bind! On holy book, by superstitions weak, With penalties the timid and
                            the meek He fetters, till poor honesty goes blind In many a soul whose birthright had been
                            signed To nobler things. Her vengeance truth will wreak On all such subterfuges, soon or
                            late. The savage knew her better when he said, Seeing the sun's great splendor overhead,
                            Seeing earth's beauty which doth lie in wait For all men's hearts, to give them ecstasy, " I
                            will not lie ! The sun and earth hear me!''* The only form of oath among the Shoshone
                            Indians is, " The earth hears me. The sun hears me. Shall I lie?"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Deep thoughts" TEIform="index"/>DEEP THOUGHTS</head><p TEIform="p">All principles will be judged by their results. All forms of society will be judged by their
                            results. " A large mould of men is what we want, and to get this, we must stop treating men
                            like a miscellaneous lot of hatchets and axes that are only waiting to be ground." " We are
                            enfeebled, we don't want new outlets for power when power itself is what we lack." "
                            Religion is perennial; religious instincts demand constant satisfaction, though the form of
                            the satisfaction varies from age to age:' " The nature of scientific doctrines is such as to
                            demand more rather than less development of the religious sentiments." " Living the great
                            truths of the spiritual world constitutes vital religion."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only the waters in the ship can sink the ship..." TEIform="index"/>Only the waters in the ship can sink the ship...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stanford, Charles" TEIform="persName"/>Charles Stanford</byline><p TEIform="p">Only the waters in the ship can sink the ship ; but while kept outside, all the heav. ing
                            deep waters thundering over three-fifths of the globe can work no shipwreck. So, while kept,
                            outside the church, the floods of ungodly influence can only help to float it on its voyage
                            to glory, or to lift it to its Ararat of rest.—</p></div2><pb n="229" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sermon" TEIform="index"/>A SERMON</head>A SERMON
                        <byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. BRIGGS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Know ye not that your body is the temple of the Holy Ghost which is in you, which ye have of
                            God, and ye glorify God in your body and in your spirit which are God's ? 1 Cor., vi, 19,
                            20. If indeed we would make our bodies temples for the Holy Ghost (Holy Spirit) how very
                            careful of them we should be ! What a purification we must have! With what exquisite pains
                            must we nourish, develop and educate these bodies; how solicitously guard them against
                            feverish and morbid conditions ! The Holy Spirit surely cannot dwell in a place of
                            defilement; its temple must be all garnished and clean. We are bought with a price. A full
                            healthy body and a pure spirit are obtained only by the sacrifice of every passional
                            indulgence. Intemperance in eating and drinking induces a grossness, a coarseness,
                            incompatible with spiritual life. A strict observance of physiological conditions, springing
                            from an intelligent education of the mind, will pave the way to holiness. " First that which
                            is natural, and afterward that which is spiritual." What good Christian does not take Christ
                            and Him crucified as his theory ? How few deny Him in practice ! The beautiful Christ life
                            is conspicuous for self-denial. It wages perpetual war against all worldly lusts, for these
                            destroy the life in the spirit. Unless, therefore, we deny ourselves, take up our crosses
                            and follow Christ in His life, in His example, we are not Christians. Let us tell the truth
                            in this matter, men and women, all of us. We recognize the beauty of self-denial, but our
                            passions are too strong for us, and so we try to find excuses which shall seem to justify
                            our excesses. Like the poor ostrich which when pursued by its enemies hides its head in the
                            sand, thinking because its own eyes are blinded and cannot see the danger it must therefore
                            be safe, we try to deceive ourselves by specious argument, hoping that if we can quiet our
                            own consciences we shall be safe. Vain hope. Our sophistries will fail us. Our
                            self-delusions will work great mischief, sorrow and disappointment for future life. Truth
                            will rend these fallacies like gossamer threads. We must have no half-way work in this
                            matter. It must be a war of extinction against the gross excesses which curse humanity. What
                            a baneful crop we are growing ! What a fearful harvest we must expect to reap ! Depraved and
                            unnatural appetites, abnormal and insatiable desires are being transmitted with increased
                            intensity from generation to generation, and what is to be the end of all this? Absurd is
                            our boasted advance of science when we evince so little sense in the care of the house we
                            live iu. Consistency thou art a jewel! We offer prizes for the discovery of a celestial
                            body, while wickedly ignorant of the cause of a mental or physical deformity in our child.
                            We hold fairs to encourage improvement in blooded stock, pay almost fabulous prices for
                            favorite animals, hold numerous and elaborate discussions upon the best methods to produce
                            best results with our domestic animals; yet the production of our own species is left to
                            chance! No more intelligence is here exhibited than was shown in barbarous ages. Science
                            does not aid in this most necessary feature of life. Thousands of human beings now eke out a
                            miserable existence who ought never to have been born. The instinct of the brute creation is
                            intelligence par excellence compared to the brutal grossness with which children are ushered
                            into the world. Poor things ! They must sufler for the ignorance and iniquity of their
                            parents. They are the heirs to a dreadful legacy of sin and sorrow. Parents have a fearful
                            responsibility, which although presently ignored cannot be escaped. Better learn the facts
                            and avoid trouble than remain willfully blinded to the truth and incur such heavy penalties
                            to ourselves and posterity. Eminent medical men tell us that six out of eight of the
                            children of this country violate their own bodies — desecrate those temples that should
                            entertain the Holy Spirit. Is not this dread- <pb n="230" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 230 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. ful ? And is there no remedy? Teach them hygiene; teach them the normal use of
                            each organ ; the care necessary to its healthfulness. Teach them the penalties affixed to a
                            violation of nature's laws. Reason with them, pray with them, labor with them untiringly,
                            until they learn intelligently to deal with their bodies as blessings loaned to them to be
                            improved, purified and sanctified, fit temples for the Holy Spirit.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Justice" TEIform="index"/>JUSTICE</head>JUSTICE
                        <byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hersey, D. M." TEIform="persName"/>D. M. HERSEY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Where are the men for this dark time, Strong men and women for the right ? Firm leaders in
                            the coming fight Of right and wrong in every clime. Where are the noble and the brave, Who
                            love their country, free from blame Who weep to see their country's shame, Nor stoop to be a
                            party slave ? O, give us men of honest deal, Who scorn a bribe, and hate a lie ? And
                            statesmen, who would rather die Than from their country's treasure steal. God grant that
                            those who rob the poor, When outraged Justice strikes the blow, May never sink in hells as
                            low As thousands of these slaves endure. O, man, how long wilt thou withold The help thy
                            brother sorely needs ? Go, bind the broken heart that bleeds, And give from out thy stores
                            of gold ! Oh ! shame upon a cringing press, That dares not brand Lthe wrong it sees, But,
                            pamper'd with the rich man's fees, Withholds a mighty power to bless. I know not, in the
                            coming strife, The ways that Justice will pursue; I only know, if we are true, We shall not
                            vainly give our life. Vineland, N. J.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who were they?" TEIform="index"/>Who Were They?</head><p TEIform="p">— Who was Samson? A man of great physical strength, whose beverage was water, and his food
                            vegetarian. Who was Daniel ? A wise and good man, whose drink was water, and his food
                            vegetarian. Who was John the Baptist? The mightiest man born of woman, whose drink was
                            water, and his food vegetarian." So says one of* our temperance journals.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing new" TEIform="index"/>NOTHING NEW</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> The universal circle marks Creation's perfect whole, From worlds ensphered in belted zones,
                            To life that crowns the soul. A wise man of the centuries past, In taking life's review,
                            Proclaimed that all earth's history Presented nothing new. And so we ask, is there a thought
                            Or word still unexpressed ? A fountain sealed that has not gushed Within some human breast ?
                            Is there a light or depth untouched ? Some secret hidden plan, To yet unfold within the
                            grasp Of ever reaching man '? The mines of knowledge still unsprung, Would seem but buried
                            lore, When brought to view the thing that's new Lo ! it was known before. The life we live
                            is but one grand Rehearsal of the past, The very motives of our souls In ancient mold were
                            cast. For human nature is the same To-day as yesterday ; The treadmill of old time moves to
                            The same dull roundelay. The mighty forces of the soul Well up and overflow, In streams
                            whose currents, swiftly on Through deepening channels go. The fevered tide of human life "•
                            Bears not upon its waves The power that lifts immortal souls — The strength that heals and
                            saves. The savage, though untutored still With gifts of nature blest, In his sublime
                            simplicity, Bears truth within his breast. While he who claims a fairer face. And broader
                            cultured mind, Will prostitute the noblest gifts That Heaven for good designed. And thus it
                            seems, that all our dreams Of progress we have made, When pressed to stern reality, Like
                            fitful fancies fade. For misery and crime increase, In ratio with the light, Where good is
                            found doeth sin abound, The wrong pursues the right. <pb n="231" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 231 Thus quickened mind inventive plies Its skill in many ways ; Devising schemes
                            in which to win The prize that self repays. How vain ambition crushes out The equal rights
                            of man; How bitter discord mars the peace Of nation, home and clan. And what we gain through
                            toil and pain, But trembles 'neath the power Usurped by those who sceptres wield, To triumph
                            but an hour. Religion, sovereign in the race, Still seeks expression free ; But cramped and
                            bound with fetters strong, Holds not its liberty. And the experience of the past, Though
                            changed the form it wears, Is but the cry of burdened toil, Through life's increasing cares.
                            Here generations come and go, Whose life seems but a day; Vast empires from the dust arise,
                            To perish and decay. Why boast of prestige, wealth or power? Why glory in a name ? For all
                            of earth to earth returns, Man goes from whence he came. And round and round the ages roll,
                            The seasons onward flow, Yet " vanity of vanities," Are all things here below. " 'Tis hope
                            eternal " that illumes And gladens all our strife. And righteousness alone can give The
                            bliss of higher life. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change of tune" TEIform="index"/>A Change of Tune</head><p TEIform="p">.— Deacon Hunt was naturally a high-tempered man, and used to beat his oxen over their heads,
                            as all his neighbors did. It was observed that when he became a Christian his cattle were
                            remarkably docile. A friend inquired into the secret. " Why," said the deacon, " formerly
                            when my oxen were a little contrary, I flew into a passion and beat them unmercifully; this
                            made the matter worse. Now, when they do not behave well, I go behind the load, sit clown
                            and sing ' Old Hundred.' I don't know how it is, but the psalm tune has a surprising effect
                            on my oxen."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak gently" TEIform="index"/>SPEAK GENTLY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., C." TEIform="persName"/>C. A.</byline><p TEIform="p"> If we would consider how much more grief and remorse we must suffer from unkind expressions
                            that we utter, than from those we bear, we would be more careful not to return ill for ill,
                            and more apt to remember, that " A soft answer turneth away wrath." Oh ! was there more love
                            divine on this broad earth below, 'Twould lume the gloomy haunts of sin with its celestial
                            glow, And many hearts now crushed by scorn, who to their fate were driven. Would be
                            reclaimed by love that breaths the blessed word " forgiven." As he whose bright example
                            gleamed adown the ages past, Asked those who knew no sin, to first the stone of judgment
                            cast; But, guilty hearts shrank from the deed as ne'er they shrank before, While to the
                            erring one he said, " arise, go sin no more." Grand words, so full of charity! so rich in
                            heavenly love! More potent far than human law the sinners heart to move ; This Christ,
                            indwelling in the heart, e'er prompts to noble deeds, And meets with truth's exalted power,
                            the spirit's inmost needs. 0 blessed is the heart! that tunes its heavenly minstrelsy, While
                            drawing inspiration deep, O fount of love from thee ! Depending on the power that guides
                            through bright and clouded days, At morn and eve it lifts the voice in hymns of grateful
                            praise. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflection" TEIform="index"/>REFLECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> Alas ! the precious hours of morn, how soon they vanish, never, never to be recalled.
                            Steadily the sun of advancing years courses its way onward toward the meridian sky. Every
                            day brings its duties to be performed, its burdens to bear; its lessons to be learned, and
                            its conflicts for the soul, in conquering <pb n="232" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 232 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO.
                            the ever present, strong and active forces of selfhood. Each day is fraught with
                            circumstances in which we may strengthen these forces by self indulgence, or subdue them by
                            self denial. The sun never rises in the orient sky, but, to our waking consciousness are
                            proffered new privileges for eternal gain ; new opportunities to sow in life's garden the
                            seeds of bitterness or peace ; and its golden beams never fade in the purpleing mists of
                            evening, as it sinks behind the hills, but our accountability to the Great Giver is
                            increased proportionate to the gift bestowed ; and an unerring impression of every passing
                            thought and inmost motive is photographed on memory's immortal tablet. O precious Time ! how
                            swift and sure the pinions that bear thee from our grasp! And with thy flight our ship keeps
                            pace, whose course with thee is onward to Eternity's vast shore. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="President Lincoln once saidthe best story he ever read in the papers about himself wa..." TEIform="index"/>President Lincoln once saidthe best story he ever read in the papers about himself wa...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">President Lincoln once said the best story he ever read in the papers about himself was this
                            : Two Quakeresses were trav eling on the railroad, and were heard discussing the probable
                            result of the war. " I think," said one, " that Jefferson will succeed." " Why does thee
                            think so ? " asked the other. " Because Jefferson is a praying man." " And so is Abraham a
                            praying man." " Yes, but the Lord will think Abraham is only joking," doubtfully replied the
                            first.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Chinese government for some reasons not stated, recently issued a decree..." TEIform="index"/>The Chinese government for some reasons not stated, recently issued a decree...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The Chinese government, for some reasons not stated, recently issued a decree commanding its
                            subjects to abstain from shaving the head for a period of one hundred days. Detected in the
                            act of disobeying this arbitrary regulation, between fifty and sixty persons in the city of
                            Foochow alone were on the 11th of June sentenced to receive castigation with bamboo rods,
                            and to pay each a fine of three thousand cash (about $6). It is stated by the local journals
                            that before liberation the heads of the offenders were, as a wholesome warning to others,
                            carefully painted and varnished.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ungodly persecution" TEIform="index"/>UNGODLY PERSECUTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">REMAINS OF THE INQUISITION. One of the most distressing and alarming propositions now
                                being considered by a certain theological court is the suspension, and perhaps
                                expulsion, of one of God's best mediums to the race, from the fellowship of the church ;
                                and this because of a godly growth, and the breaking of theological but unchristian
                                shackles; such is the case of one dear to our heart, the Rev. H. W. Thomas, of Chicago.
                                Outgrowing the narrowness of human creeds, and speaking from God in his soul, he has
                                dared presume and to teach a hope that in the future life there is yet a chance for a
                                change from evil ways to the better life, before the ultimatum of "go to Hades "' is
                                irrevocably pronounced. Still further, this champion for God and truth has dared to put
                                a reasonable construction upon the theory of the atonement, so that it will better mean
                                to be at one with goodness, that it may be of any beneficial effect. We have always
                                loved the Methodist church; and so do we all other churches for their every good
                                feature; but when any church rises up to punish, persecute and annihilate one of its own
                                best prophets, teachers and advancing leaders, because he presents a more loving and
                                adorable God than was ever worshiped in that church before, we rejoice that we know the
                                days of that church, in such narrowness, are numbered. It is a truth that the character
                                of God, as best known to the people, is <pb n="233" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 233
                                learned by the religious status of the people themselves. A vindictive man or woman
                                inclines to the opinion that their God is even more vindictive than themselves. It is
                                impossible to educate individuals with extreme benevolence and affectionate regard for
                                their species, that their God is worse than they are ; for " Education ne'er supplied
                                What ruling nature has denied." Therefore, Dr. Thomas, in the goodness of his heart,
                                rebels at the teachings of a,theology that would transfer the guilt of millions upon a
                                guiltless individual, and punish him with millions of stripes, for being so good as
                                never to have done any thing bad, while the bad go scot free ! We are aware of the
                                old-school theory that there is no chance for one's salvation from sin and its
                                punishments in the hereafter. But Bro. Thomas has in his nobler conception of God dared
                                to assert that a woman in Chicago, hurled into eternity by a murderous husband, would
                                find a probationary state there, and that because of any failure to participate in
                                certain churchal sacraments she should not therefore be numbered with the damned. For
                                this he is to be tried and condemned. We can only pity a church that can so enact, and
                                do more highly honor such an advocate ol mercy and charity, as Dr. Thomas, than we could
                                pay homage to the god of said church. Theodore Parkei was bitterly opposed to capital
                                punishments. Being ;isked by one who believed the God of the Old Testament to be the
                                unchangeable God o; the universe, what he would do if Goc should command him to go out
                                anc Tlang a man ? answered, very consistently : "I would hang up such a God, and let the
                                man go!" Bro. Thomas is a godly missionary to the Methodist chnrch to-day. If said,
                                church is ready to move toward a better God than she has conceived of heretofore, all
                                will be well. If she still confines her powers and petitions to a God which does not
                                comprehend as much goodness, mercy, charity and unselfish love as is found in some
                                mortal organisms, that church will become obsolete, Avhile her former adherents will
                                sail in another ship under the guidance of a better God. Our Methodist brethren, we
                                hope, Avill prove too noble to succumb longer to a theology that teaches of a God more
                                vindictive, cruel, and with less compassion than they are capable of exercising one
                                toward another. Let the result of the trial be what it may, we will pray for a firm
                                stand by Dr. Thomas. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs of the times" TEIform="index"/>SIGNS OF THE TIMES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> o every individual, given to fervent thought, the present status of the so-called
                                religious world is wearing a very different complexion than ever before, and withal, a
                                very improved complexion. Every denomination of the Christian profession has lost much
                                of that which formerly made ic a competitor for the laurels of infallibility, while a
                                liberal tone, and better — a humane, brotherly feeling — now pervades, where hatred for
                                any thing that differed from "our church " once prevailed. There are principles of
                                godliness that are infallible, invincible, all-con <pb n="234" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 234 THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. quering — principles, which in the progress of man, from the mere animal, up
                                to the angel, are irrevocably sealed as everlasting truths. The laws prior to those
                                given by Moses were undoubtedly the very best the world then ever knew ; and without
                                doubt the inhabitants thought them ne plus ultra, never to be improved upon. Moses came;
                                introduced an entirely new regime ; and improvement in human discipline, in general and
                                particular, was and is the acknowledged result. In the line of human progress, unto
                                everlasting elevation of humanity, Moses was, through the laws given by him, " a
                                schoolmaster " to bring the people into preparation for something even better than
                                Mosaim. Christ came. Acknowledging the laws of Moses as good, yet proclaiming His
                                mission to be even superior to the previous rule, the Jews treated with scorn any idea
                                that tended to thoughts that the laws of Moses could be improved upon, and they thought
                                they had nipped in the bud, and snuffed out both idea and attempt by the notable
                                crucifixion. Still the world moved; and with it the graduated class under Mosaic
                                discipline, and by the superior, Christian life of Jesus' followers, showed to the Jews,
                                by fruits, that which undermined the supposed infallibility of Judaism. Superiority is
                                destined to win. But there is no station of superiority where humanity can settle down
                                and proclaim no further progress. The amicable feelings prevailing among all
                                denominations evince the milk of human kindness that was not even dreamed could be, by
                                the best lovers of humanity, one hundred or even fifty years ago. How many of us can
                                realize how short the time has been when the direst denunciations for unbelief in the
                                peculiar tenets of this or that church were commonly and violently hurled, to '' Deal
                                damnation round the land, On each I judge thy foe ? " And yet the time has been so very
                                short since loving, Christian liberality and charity have displaced bigotry and deviltry
                                in theological matters, that while we reflect, we may well and reasonably stand happily
                                aghast at the swiftness of progress made! Admissions of the superior are invariably
                                accompanied by confessions of error in preconceived opinions. Admissions and confessions
                                are really good for the soul. Adjustments of differences in religious matters are being
                                rapidly made upon the principles of righteousness and charitable love, and these
                                principles will eventuate in a church universal — the millennium come. </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When a blessing comes to the church..." TEIform="index"/>When a blessing comes to the church...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">When a blessing comes to the church it will mean a surrender of old grudges,
                                        a forgiving of those who have wronged us, a wider Christian charity, a more
                                        patient endurance of sufferings for Christ's sake, a more self-sacrificing
                                        spirit of benevolence, a more complete separation from the world, a holier life
                                        and an intense service. And perhaps the revival is withheld until the church
                                        comes to the point where she shall seek it, not with a qualified, but an
                                        absolute surrender and a holy willingness to be and do all that the Spirit shall
                                        command. We want a blessing — the shallowest experience can say that; but
                                        whether we want a searching and withering, an unsettling, it may be, of hopes
                                        long unquestioned, and a renewal of life when it means agony for souls and
                                        cross-bearing for Christ — that is a deeper question.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Interior" TEIform="index"/>The Interior</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="235" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little children" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE CHILDREN</head><p TEIform="p">Keep guard of your words, my darlings, For words are wonderful things; They are sweet
                                like the bees' fresh honey, Like the bees they have terrible stings. They can bless like
                                the warm, glad sunshine, And brighten a lonely life, They can cut in the strife of
                                anger, Like an open, two-edged knife. Let them pass through your lips unchal lenged, If
                                their errand is true and kind ; If they come to support the weary, To comfort and help
                                the blind. If a bitter revengeful spirit Prompts the words, let them be said; They may
                                flash through a brain like lightning, Or fall on a heart like lead. Keep them back if
                                they're cold and cruel, Under bar, and lock and seal; The wounds they make, my darlings,
                                Are always slow to heal. May peace guard your lives and ever From this time of your
                                early youth; May the words that you daily utter Be the beautiful words of truth.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Killed for nothing" TEIform="index"/>KILLED FOR NOTHING</head><p TEIform="p">"Now tell us all about the war, And what they killed each other for," pleads little
                                Peterkin in Southey's poem of " The Battle of Blenheim." " And what good came of it at
                                last ! Said little Wilhelmine." These were questions that their grand father could not
                                answer. The cannibal's wonder when told about civilized warfare seems about as hard to
                                satisfy, though it is not quite so innocent. A missionary, in an address describing his
                                experience in New Guinea, gives some hard specimens of the questions he had to answer:
                                When I was talking to him about cannibalism, and wishing him to give it up, he said:
                                "But you know it is only our enemies; we never eat our friends. It is right to eat our
                                enemies. Have you got no enemies in your country ?" I was obliged to confess we had
                                people who were sometimes regarded as enemies. "Well," said he, "do you never fight!" I
                                was obliged to confess that we did. " And do you never kill any anybody?," I was very
                                glad he did not ask me how many, for 1 could not have told him. There would have been no
                                words in his language to tell him that. But when he found out that we did kill people,
                                he said: " Do you not eat them? " " No," I said, "we do not eat people in onr country.''
                                The man looked perfectly astonished. " Then what do you kill them for? " said he. " We
                                kill our enemies because we like them, but you kill them for nothing at all."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Verbrike, Dotia" TEIform="index"/>Dotia Verbrike</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Through some neglect the notice of our dear friend's decease, , aged 78 years, at
                                Pleasant Hill, Ky., has failed to appear.—Ed.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Todd, Mary Ellen" TEIform="index"/>Mary Ellen Todd</head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky., August 26, . one of the blessed rising stars, dropped her physical
                                and went to Heaven, aged only 37 years.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>Received</head><p TEIform="p">, B. B. Dunlavy, $82.50. M. Messner, Cleveland, O., sends us the gift of one dollar. And
                                yet our friends live.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the year 1848, James Shackleton, of Lawrence, Mass., found a man in..." TEIform="index"/>In the year 1848, James Shackleton, of Lawrence, Mass., found a man in...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In the year 1848, James Shackleton, of Lawrence, Mass., found a man in whom he thought
                                there was so little guile that he advised him to join the Shakers! That man so "jined,"
                                that in "all the east" no brighter star of Shakerdom shines to-day. We call him our "
                                beautiful eastern minister." This good friend, Shackleton, has been an unfailing
                                subscriber to the Manifesto from the start, and now he sends us $5 as a gift!</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That blessed goodie, Sister Mary Whitcher, has just sent us..." TEIform="index"/>That blessed goodie, Sister Mary Whitcher, has just sent us...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">That blessed goodie, Sister Mary WhitCHER, has just sent us two pairs of the most
                                beautiful and comfortable woolen socke. While looking at them we felt rebuked at having
                                said we work without pay.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain Talks" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The third edition of our little pamphlet, " Plain Talks," is wholly exhausted. We cannot
                                tell when we can raise $25 for a new edition.—Ed.</p></div3></div2><pb n="236" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A standing antidote for poison..." TEIform="index"/>A standing antidote for poison...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A standing antidote for poison by dew, poison oak, ivy, etc., is to take a handful of
                                quicklime ; dissolve in water ; let it stand half an hour, and then paint the poisoned
                                parts with it. Three or four applications will never fail to cure the most aggravated
                                cases.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pickling tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Pickling Tomatoes</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. P.</byline><p TEIform="p">.— J. H. S. would like to know how to put up green tomatoes in brine. The way I do is to
                                put them down with my cucumbers ; every time that I lay down a picking of cucumbers I
                                throw in a lot of tomatoes, every size. When I want to use them, I take them out of the
                                brine, cut them in two, and let them soak a, day or two; then I put them in more fresh
                                water and boil until tender; then drain them and put in good vinegar same as cucumbers,
                                with a few spices I also put ripe tomatoes down in vinegar. I put small red ones in a
                                glass can, all that will go in and not break the skin, with a little brown sugar, a few
                                cloves and cinnamon. I use the best cider vinegar — never acid vinegar, as it eats the
                                fruit and makes it soft. Tioga, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato catsup" TEIform="index"/>Tomato Catsup</head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Commerce gives the following directions as having been in use in the
                                editor's family for fifty years — which is going back to quite an early period in the
                                general introduction of the tomato for culinary purposes: "Take a bushel of tomatoes:
                                cut them in small pieces; boil until soft; then rub them through a wire sieve; add two
                                quarts of the best cider vinegar, one pint of salt, onequarter pound of whole cloves,
                                one-quarter pound of allspice, one tablespoonful of black pepper, one good-sized pod of
                                red pepper (whole), and five heads of garlic. Mix together and boil until reduced to
                                onehalf the quantity. When cold, strain through a colander, and bottle, sealing the
                                corks. It will keep two or three years as fresh as when first made."</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to tell a good potato" TEIform="index"/>How to Tell a Good Potato</head><p TEIform="p">.— Here is a good place in which to impart what is a secret to the vast majority of
                                people, and it is one well worth knowing. It is simply how to tell a good potato ; that
                                is, as well as it can be done without cooking it, for sometimes even experts are
                                deceived. Take a sound potato, and paying no attention to its outward appearance, divide
                                it into two pieces with your knife and examine the exposed surfaces. If there is so much
                                water or "juice" that seemingly a slight pressure would cause it to fall off in drops,
                                you may be sure it will be " soggy " after it is boiled. These are the requisite
                                qualities for a good potato, which must appear when one is cut in two : For color, a
                                yellowish white ; if it is a deep yellow the potato will not cook well; there must be a
                                considerable amount of moisture, though not too much ; rub the two pieces together and a
                                white froth will appear around the edges and upon the two surfaces; this signifies the
                                presence of starch, and the more starch, and consequently froth, the better the potato,
                                while the less there is the poorer it will cook. The strength of the starchy element can
                                be tested by releasing the hold upon one piece of the potato, and if it still clings to
                                the other, this in itself is a very good sign. These are the experiments generally made
                                by experts, and they are ordinarily willing to buy on the strength of their turning out
                                well, though, as stated above, these tests are by no means infallible.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtues of the lemon" TEIform="index"/>Virtues of the Lemon</head><p TEIform="p">. — A recent writer of note has the following to say regarding the virtues of the lemon:
                                " Lemon juice is the best anti-scorbutic remedy known. It not only cures the disease,
                                but prevents it. Sailors make a daily use of it for this purpose. I advise every one to
                                rub their gums daily with lemon juice, to keep them in health. The hands and nails are
                                also kept clean, white, soft and supple by the daily use of lemon instead of soap. It
                                also prevents chilblains. Lemon is used in intermittent fevers, mixed with strong, hot,
                                black coffee, without sugar. Neuralgia may be cured by rubbing the part affected with a
                                cut lemon. It is valuable also to cure warts, and to destroy dandruff on the head by
                                rubbing the roots of the hair with it. In fact, its uses are manifold, and the more we
                                employ it, externally, the better we shall <pb n="237" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                                237 find ourselves. Natural remedies are the best, and Nature is the best doctor, if we
                                would only listen to it. Decidedly rub your hands, head and gums with lemon, and drink
                                lemonade in preference to all other liquids.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We've all our angel side" TEIform="index"/>WE'VE ALL OUR ANGEL SIDE</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The huge rough stones from out the mine, Unsightly and unfair, Have veins of
                                    purest metal hid Beneath the surface there. Few rocks so bare but to their heights
                                    Some tiny moss-plant clings ; And round the peaks so desolate, The sea-bird sits and
                                    sings. Believe me, too, that rugged souls, Beneath their rudeness hide Much that is
                                    beautiful and good — We've all our angel side. In all there is an inner depth, A far
                                    off secret way, Where, through the windows of the soul, God sends His smiling ray.
                                    In every human heart there is A faithful, sounding chord That may be struck, unknown
                                    to us, By some sweet, loving word. The wayward will in man may try Its softer
                                    thoughts to hide — Some unexpected tone reveals It has an angel side. Despised, and
                                    lone, and trodden down, Dark with the shades of sin, Deciphering not those halo
                                    lights Which God has lit within ; Groping about in endless night, Poor, poisoned
                                    souls they are, Who guess not what life's meaning is, Nor dream of heaven afar. Oh,
                                    that some gentle hand of love Their gentle steps would guide, And show them that,
                                    amidst itall, Life has its angel side ! Brutal, and mean, and dark enough, God knows
                                    some natures are; But He, compassionate, comes near, And shall we stand afar ? Our
                                    cruse of oil will not grow less If shared with hearty hand ; For words of peace and
                                    looks of love Few natures can withstand. Love is the mighty conqueror, Love is the
                                    beauteous guide, Love, with her beaming eyes, can see We've all our angel side. '</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is easy to look down on other ; to look down on ourselves is the difficulty" TEIform="index"/>It is easy to look down on other ; to look down on ourselves is the difficulty
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is easy to look down on others ; to look down on ourselves is the difficulty.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No time for hating" TEIform="index"/>NO TIME FOR HATING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Duganne, A. J. H." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. H. Duganne</byline><p TEIform="p">Begone with feud! away with strife : Our human hearts unmating ! Let us be friends again!
                            This life Is all too short for hating! So dull the day, so dim the way, So rough the road
                            we're faring — Far better weal with faithful friend Than stalk alone uncaring. The barren
                            fig, the withered vine, Are types of selfish living; Bnt souls that give, like thine and
                            mine, Renew their life by giving. While cypress waves o'er early graves On all the way we're
                            going, Far better plant where seed is scant Than tread on fruit that's growing. Away with
                            scorn! Since die we must And rest on one low pillow ; There are no rivals in the dust — No
                            foes beneath the willow. So dry the bowers, so few the flowers, Our earthly way discloses,
                            Far better stoop where daisies droop Than tramp o'er broken roses! Of what are all the joys
                            we hold Compared to joys above us ? And what are rank and power and gold Compared to hearts
                            that love us? So fleet our years, so full of tears, So closely death is waiting ; God gives
                            us space for loving grace, But leaves no time for hating. — </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Service" TEIform="index"/>Service
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">SERVICE. ''Not all that is high is holy ; Not all that is sweet is good ;" Not
                                    every desire Toward which we aspire Pleases our God as it should. Sometimes the joy
                                    that we covet Is not a joy when possessed; And to labor right on Till our duties are
                                    done Is better, far better than rest. He who by pride is exalted, He who as monarch
                                    is known, Less honored may be By the Master than he Who stands at the foot of the
                                    throne. Far better it is to be humble, To serve in the lowliest place, To labor and
                                    plod With the veriest clod Than the likeness of God to efface. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Brethren's advocate" TEIform="index"/>Brethren's Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="238" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our father is dead" TEIform="index"/>OUR FATHER IS DEAD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcomb, O. L." TEIform="persName"/>O. L. WHITCOMB</byline><p TEIform="p">[In common with a united, sorrowing nation, our people felt the dreadful shock occasioned by
                            the transfer of our noble President from shores terrestrial to those celestial. We copy from
                            one beautiful season of respect, two tributes; one of these, from the peculiar condition of
                            its authoress, is, indeed, touching.— Ed.] Silent and deep at our common loss, The tears of
                            our common sorrow fall. He, high throned in our hearts, and crowned with our love, Lies
                            tranquil and cold beneath the dark pall. Over the land the flood of our grief Wipes out the
                            fire of our party strifes ; And prayerful and peaceful our hearts only beat, To the muffled
                            drums, and the whisp'ring fifes. Over the sea, in lands far away, There's tolling of bells,
                            and crape-hung doors, And the widowed Queen's hand in her widowed friend's heart The solace
                            divine sweet sympathy pours. Once before we have drained this cup's deep draught — Once
                            before, oh, our Father above, We have given to Thee at the lightning's flash The first of
                            our land, the first of our love Is there no strength in Thy hand to stay The power of might
                            over truth and right? Forgive us our murmurs, we are blinded in pain, And our questioning
                            eyes would be grateful for light. Peace to the name —the well-beloved name, Though our
                            heart's every fibre protests Against the dark deed that robbed us of him, Ever and aye shall
                            his memory be blest. Down 'neath the so'd we lay him to rest — He, who so bravely battled
                            above; His name on history's page will be bright, On our hearts, in letters of love. God,
                            take him home, but leave herewith us His mantle of courage and trust; Leave us his patience,
                            his meekness, to say "Ashes to ashes, dust unto dust! " Canaan, Sept. 26, 1381.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tendered to our president" TEIform="index"/>TENDERED TO OUR PRESIDENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Amy" TEIform="persName"/>AMY BOWERS</byline><p TEIform="p"> My head shall not refuse to bow, My knee shall not refuse to bend, My hand shall not be left
                            unraised, Nor shall my heart forget to send One little off'ring up. A prayer, as pure, as
                            white as these Fresh flowers from Nature's bosom culled. Oh Father! give me lips to breathe
                            ; And let all selfish thoughts be lulled, While from the Nation's cup I drink one little
                            drop, that mine With other hearts the thrill may feel Of perfect love and sympathy, Which
                            gives its wealth without appeal, To every human grief. Oh Memory ! keep thy leaves as green
                            As these, unfading in thy trust; Keep all the chastened grace which grows From out to-day's
                            tear-sprinkled dust. Nor let its life be brief. The above lines were written by a young
                            sister who has been confined to her room by sickness. Unable to attend the Family meeting,
                            in honor of our President, she wrote her offering and laid it across a bouquet of white
                            flowers and green leaves. Sympathy is the golden key to unlock the gates of Sorrow, showing
                            us the glory within. Canaan, Sept. 26, 1881.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What are a few years of what men call sorrow..." TEIform="index"/>What are a few years of what men call sorrow...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What are a few years of what men call sorrow and burden-bearing to an eternity of
                            blessedness.</p></div2><pb n="239" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gems" TEIform="index"/>GEMS</head><p TEIform="p">A good business — building a good character. An unprofitable business — tearing down other
                            people's characters. " No one," says Jerome, "loves to tell a scandal except to him who
                            loves to hear it." An angry man who suppresses his passion thinks worse than when he speaks;
                            an angry man that will chide speaks worse than he thinks. The hard, harsh world neither
                            sees, nor tries to see men's hearts; but wherever there is an opportunity for evil, supposes
                            that evil exists. There are men who no more grasp the truth they seem to hold than a sparrow
                            grasps the message passing through the electric wire on which it perches. Ruskin says that
                            the noblest building made with hands for spiritual ends must lack the perfection of grace
                            and beauty, unless lit from the lamp of sacrifice. Some men are always seeking for honors ;
                            trying to get higher positions. The better way is to walk faithfully in the path of duty and
                            the honors "will find them. Give not the tongue too great a liberty lest it take thee
                            prisoner. A word unspoken is like a sword in a scabbard, thine; if vented, the sword is in
                            another's hand. If thou desire to be held wise, be so wise as to hold thy tongue. An Indiana
                            woman has just killed twenty snakes which she found on one spot enjoying the warm sunshine.
                            If Adam had only had that kind of a wife ! But somehow the Garden of Eden had to be placed
                            on the wrong side of the Indiana line. The humble Nazarene knew the spiritual law so well
                            that he did not hesitate to tell the self-righteous of His day that their lack of charity to
                            the erring was a greater sin than the misdeeds of those they condemned. A few would-be
                            modern reformers of our day should bear this fact in mind and profit thereby,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Put down mourning" TEIform="index"/>PUT DOWN MOURNING</head><p TEIform="p">The wearing of mourning for departed friends is a terrible mistake. Our descendants will
                            smile at our infatuation, when it will be understood that the going away should be as
                            lovable as the coming. When our death will be a healthful passing, and ending, we shall look
                            eye into eye, grasping hand to hand to the last, and go with joy and cheerfulness. If it is
                            nature's law, it is nature's design ; if it is nature's design, it has a purpose in it, and
                            why should we be mournful at that ? Off with those poor, worldly, black clothes; put on
                            white and blue or rose and see that best beloved to the grave. There is no need to mourn ;
                            why ? Why go about quarreling with divine plan ? These black, heavy clothes on frail,
                            delicate women in our burning streets are really terrible indications of short-sightedness
                            and want of real love for the divine ordinances. They make one shudder to think of the poor
                            over-burdened body under them, and the weary soul that must be there too. When one has
                            passed away, let the other be up and doing, but not go about mourning and feeling as if he
                            or she had not gone, because go they must. The thought of death is lovelier than that of
                            birth. We never know what the latter may bring to that new-born child ; we are sure, quite
                            sure, that the former will bring us " time's completion."—Health and Home.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curious wish" TEIform="index"/>A Curious Wish</head><p TEIform="p">. — It was a recent wish of T. C. Leland that the good God would give him some neighbors,
                            whom he could love as well as he loved himself/ Does not such a wish express a too-common
                            frailty?</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No trust" TEIform="index"/>No Trust</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Greeley, Horace" TEIform="persName"/>Horace Greeley</byline><p TEIform="p">Abolish all laws for the collection of debts, and thus abolish the whole credit system; that
                            would relieve the poor working masses, and compel a cash-pay-asyou-go system, which is the
                            only safe, true basis; that would abolish most lawyers, all of the pawnbrokers' trade which
                            now controls the commerce of America. — </p></div2><pb n="240" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian love" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName"/>Elvah F. Collins</byline><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Leave some good behind you, 2. Leave some good behind you, 3. Leave
                            some good behind you, 4. Leave some good behind you, As you journey on, Tho' the seed be
                            small, God will bless your aim, Little it doth cost. Gentle act of mercy And along the
                            wayside And in love reward you, To bestow the sunshine Unto mortal It unseen may With a
                            righteous On a heart that's done, fall, name, lost, Christian deeds of kindness, It will
                            rise with vigor, Many souls will hail you, Tenderness of  feeling, Ne'er are wrought in
                            vain, And abundantly As a guiding star, Love to brother given, Only in our blindness, We
                            from these refrain. Bear the fruit of glad ness, In some future day. Fadeless in its
                            brightness, Shedding light afar. Is the balm of healing, Making home a heaven.\</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>