<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1009" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18800901" TEIform="date">September 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">193-216</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
	                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> SEPTEMBER, 1880. { 60 Cents Per Annum The Shaker MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the
                        United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony:'" "Go preach the Kingdom
                        of God ! " ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880. Vol.
                        X. No. 9. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="193" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who owneth America's soil?" TEIform="index"/>WHO OWNETH AMERICA'S SOIL?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Duganne, A. J. H." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. H. DUGANNE</byline><p TEIform="p">BY Who owneth America's soil? Is it he who graspeth the hard red gold; Whose glittering gains
                            are by millions told, Who bindeth his slaves to the woof and the loom ; And chaineth their
                            soul in living tomb— The tomb of hopeless toil ? Not he, not he — by Heaven ! Who shieldeth
                            America's land? Is it he who counteth his ships by scores ; Who plucketh his gain from a
                            thousand shores; Who buyeth and selleth and worketh not, And holdeth in pride what by fraud
                            he got— With hard and griping hand ? Not he, not he — by Heaven ! Who guardeth America's
                            right? Is it he who eateth the orphan's bread, Who crusheth the poor with his grinding tread
                            ; Who flingeth his bank-note lies abroad, And buildeth to worship a golden god, A shrine to
                            Mammon's might? Not he, not he —by Heaven ! Not these not these —¦ by Heaven ! But to those
                            who labor for God and man ; Who work their part in the world's great plan — Who plant good
                            seed in the desert's dearth, And bring forth treasures from brave old Earth ; To these the
                            soil is given — To these, to these — by Heaven ! To these must the soil belong; To the men
                            of all climes whose souls are true — Or Pagan, or Christian, or Turk, or Jew; To the men who
                            will hallow our glorious soil — The million who hope and the millions who toil For the Right
                            against the Wrong ; To these does the soil belong — To Guard, to work, and to own.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's church government—present and future" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S CHURCH GOVERNMENT -
                            PRESENT AND FUTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p"> From what we have been taught, and what appears in the administration of government in our
                            Pentecostal community, we infer that the ministry at the mother church, the subordinate
                            ministry of the several bishoprics, the elders, trustees, deacons, etc., constitute the
                            official administrative machinery of the community, or what is more generally called the
                            visible order of the church. Now unless we as individuals hope to undergo a great change in
                            our moral and spiritual nature at death (of which there is no reasonable evidence nor
                            likelihood), we may logically infer that this same order will be continued in the next state
                            of existence as in this; the same necessities attending us there which we find our- <pb n="194" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 194 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. selves under here. And doubtless this order
                            of things rests upon the great law of the universe, viz., that the less is blessed of the
                            better. This seems to me a mere instance of cause and effect. Leastwise, if our Pentecostal
                            church is not superposed upon this as well as other eternal principles, it is of small
                            moment, and of course must ultimately go to pieces for want of an eternal and impregnable
                            basis. To be sure, the sweet attractions of wisdom and love may in the course of one or two
                            hundred thousand years be substituted gradually for present sagacity, executive and
                            administrative energy and ability; but even then the modus operandi of conducting the
                            affairs of the church will be after all most likely, by and through the present beautiful
                            organization of ministry, elders, trustees, deacons, etc., including of course both sexes in
                            equal proportion and power. It seems to me logically, not to say mathematically, impossible
                            to conceive of a Pentecostal community or church outside of some such systematic
                            arrangement. What I wonder at, however, is that so many persons speak of Jesus Christ as the
                            only and the direct mediator between man and God, and yet say He was a mere man like all the
                            rest before and after Him. I believe myself that He was a man like unto the rest of us, and,
                            therefore, one of the millions of links of God's agency by which the great scheme of
                            progression from salvation to salvation is evolved from age to age, and that there is an
                            infinite concatenation of such spiritual intelligences or agencies ascending higher and
                            higher forever. Mother Ann, in whom I have quite as much faith as any others of the above
                            series, said: " There is no end to the heavens." When our blessed Saviour was bantered by
                            some of His enemies, to escape their persecution if He could, He mildly replied: " Know ye
                            not that I can pray the Father, and He will presently send me twelve legions of angels ? "
                            But what good could millions of angels do to a being who was the very next embodiment of
                            power and goodness to the Infinite, if indeed there can be any " very next ?'' Again, how
                            could they rescue Him or make Him able to endure that which was in store for Him "unless
                            they possessed a power and efficacy above His own ? Also, when He had fasted forty days in
                            the wilderness (I care not whether that wilderness was some big woods in Palestine or the
                            wilderness of His own lower instincts), and the angels came and ministered to Him, they must
                            have imported something over and above what He had himself, else it was lost time for both
                            parties. Likewise, in His unutterable agony in the garden of Gethsemane, " an angel
                            appeared, strengthening Him." To say that this mediate assistance was not really necessary,
                            but God merely wanted to discover whether or not Jesus was humble enough to receive help
                            from even inferior powers, which God for the time being could magnetize sufficiently for the
                            purpose, is relegating infinite to finite conditions, and, therefore, childish. It rather
                            seems to me that from regions of arch-angelic power, wisdom, love and intelligence, bands of
                            angels often descended to assist and strengthen "our Elder Brother," in agreement with the
                            sublime law of the universe, whose dictum is " the less are blessed of the better." O, but
                            you say: "At this rate, how do we know horn many Saviours the world may have, not heretofore
                            had, and what are you going to do with Kersey Graves' ' sixteen crucified Saviours ?'" To
                            the last question I would say, " simply nothing." To the first I answer, I cannot tell how
                            many Saviours Infinite Goodness may have sent to the world before Jesus, but I do certainly
                            know of one since, Ann Lee. There never was a Saviour if she was not one. Besides several
                            more at the same time, in the persons of Father James, Father William Lee, and four or five
                            hundred more, so that the Saviours have been all along " established on Mount Zion (the
                            Pentecostal church of the latter day), judging the Mount of Esau," even as it is this day.
                            Our earth being not less at least than about 66 million years old, what wonder if it should
                            be ascertained sooner or later that the Lord in his divine love and wisdom had not waited to
                            the ephemeral period of 1800 years ago, or even no longer or further back than the days of
                            Moses, to begin to send Saviours on the earth for the salvation of mankind, "and suited to
                            their different <pb n="195" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 195 stages of development and
                            capability for improvement? Finally, judging from my observation and experience, I am pretty
                            confident that the order, government and instrumentalities thereof of our Pentecostal
                            community are established on immutable and eternal principles, one of which is that " the
                            less is blessed of the better," and that in accordance with the inspired seer who was held a
                            captive by the rivers of Babylon, " In the days of these kings should the God of Heaven set
                            up a kingdom which should never have an end." This institution, I be lieve, is now set up in
                            this latter day, and the Shakers are the happy inmates thereof, and this I infer from the
                            fact that the fruits thereof agree in all particulars heretofore enumerated by sages, seers
                            and prophets referring to the same, but practically demonstrate in the lives of the votaries
                            thereol every spiritual principle and practice in sisted upon by Jesus Christ. Union
                            Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision no. 2" TEIform="index"/>VISION NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Coming events cast their shadows before." Prevision, like "second sight," is an unusual
                            development of the natural faculty of vision. Like "second sight," also, it is mostly
                            exercised under favorable conditions. John, the apocalyptic seer, tells us that he was '' en
                            pneumati " — in an exalted spiritual condition — when he beheld the various images he has
                            described in his wonderful book. It is the nearness of events that impress the
                            susceptibilities of the seer and open his internal vision. " Write," said the voice which
                            John heard, "what thou hast seen what is transpiring and what is about to transpire."
                            Others, also, in the infant church of Jesus, had foresight of things which were to affect
                            themselves as well as the people of aftertimes. So has it been among all peoples and all
                            ages. All are endowed with the same faculties, and these are exercised upon similar things
                            when similarly developed. Visions and previsions which are beyond the reach of the ordinary
                            or external sight are mainly intended to instruct us in regard to another life. Our outward
                            sight would be all sufficient if this were the whole of life. But because something better
                            is before us than this 'brief state of things, there is this occasional opening of the
                            internal vision. Doubtless it would be more than occasional were greater attention given it.
                            If there were less sensualism among men, less strife and contention for the things of this
                            transient life, "the night shade that waves round the skeptic's head" would be dispelled,
                            and his vision of the future life would be clear as the day. There needs to be far less of
                            mere pride of intellect and more of genuine intellectual culture. This includes the utmost
                            development and refine ment of the " inner man." " The pure in heart" — the single, the
                            sincere of heart — have the clearest visions of Divine character as well as of His
                            providential operations. The clearest vision in respect to the highest things of God
                            appertains to the purest heart.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Made perfect by sufferings" TEIform="index"/>MADE PERFECT BY SUFFERINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p"> Pity me not, when travel-worn Along the weary way, You mark my languid step and eye, As
                            wanes the toilsome day; Congratulate me, rather, dear, For know these travel-stains, Are
                            indications of success, Are marks of real gains. For travel is the thing we seek, Still in
                            the " narrow road ;" And travel causes weariness, Tho' leading home to God. Not weariness
                            alone, but death— The natural must die— In order that the soul may "live And reign with Him
                            on high." ¦ New creatures we are to become And leave the old behind ; And this transition
                            painful is, But we should be resigned. Then pity not, my sister, dear, But know, these marks
                            of pain, Are caused by what pain only cures, And hence are marks of gain. North Union,
                        0.</p></div2><pb n="196" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul of science" TEIform="index"/>SOUL OF SCIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>Catharine Allen</byline><p TEIform="p"> God is the centre of the universe. Religion is the soul of science. "In Christ are hid all
                            the treasures of wisdom and knowledge." Shakerism is not only in itself scientific, but
                            being progressive, comprehends every principle of science. Those who esteem and seek
                            goodness before any other attainment find the fountain source of all the streams of truth,
                            that course through the universe ; while those who seek external knowledge through the
                            outward senses,— at the expense of spiritual development, — may spend a life time in
                            following one stream to its source.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Needs of a new civilization" TEIform="index"/>NEEDS OF A NEW CIVILIZATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Frazer</byline><p TEIform="p"> In view of the awful crimes and human suffering consequent on modern civilization, and as a
                            step to a higher form of social life, could the All Beneficent Mind do better to equalize
                            human conditions, than to give each person a limited portion of land ? And as it is
                            impossible to obtain an organized form of society based on the fitness of things, without
                            rules of life, and that coming generations may be healthful, and not lacking in moral
                            integrity ; that He lay upon the people procreative restraints. To help in this direction,
                            and to insure a continuance of bodily health, He will give them a Dietic Law; curbing
                            sensuality in eating, and wasteful extravagance in cooking and in the presenta. tion of
                            food. Also, He would give them a Sanitary Law ; teaching the people to be cleanly, to have
                            clean air, clean every thing . and to cover up or burn every unclean thing. Then He would
                            give them a few brief rules of social manners— "the Moral Law." As some will incline to have
                            dollars grow, and mortgages to yield a crop, instead of grain and fruit, He will present
                            them with a Financial Ljaw. " Usury thou shalt not take." Usury has been declared to be a
                            damnable sin, the Christian world (so called) damns itself every day, and is so rotten as to
                            love to have it so. And to restore arjy lost social balance, He will give the people two
                            Revolutionary Laws, to operate at fixed periods, declaring debts cancelled, and alienated
                            lands restored. Finally, He would give them a Sabbatical Law. Giving rest to men and
                            animals, and opportunities for devotional and beneficent deeds. Visiting and helping the
                            needy, is religion, and true worship. Contemplating on the effect of the above codes, on
                            domestic, social and governmental life, I am lost in astonishment! In its conception it is
                            sublimely grand ! Again, when I reflect that this code was enforced on a whole nation, with
                            a power — an afflatus not yet spent, as every orderly Jewish family this day witnesseth, I
                            am struck with awe, the tremblings of Mount Sinai are before me ! the heavenly forces
                            conjoin with those of earth, to impress men, that violations of the fitness of things, is
                            disobedience to God. Is there to be found in the depths of Hindoo or Egyptian history, a
                            parallel of law and life that meets this standard ? Have the Greeks or Romans left on the
                            stream of time such remains as have Jewish law, life and manners ? Is there in modern
                            history a distinctive form of law and government fit to appear before it ? Bring together
                            the remains of ancient art, and let those of modern times appear. Let the pyramids preside
                            over them and what are they but the toys of kings, and the playthings of children of larger
                            growth ? Bring together the literature of the past and present; their poetry and laws, and
                            they dwindle into insignifi. cance before the efficiency of the Mosaic code ! Even a
                            Jewish^revolution (I allude to the restoration of lands, etc.), was gentle in its operation
                            as are the exhalations from a placid lake and full of individual and social blessings;
                            Revolutions in what are called Christian lands, are explosions, full of ruin, waste and war.
                            Such Christian cities, are cesspools, and farm yards, pestiferous nuisances, a disgrace to
                            science, and to any kind of religion. And land is cared for on the principle of killing the
                            goose that lays the golden eggs. And saint and sinner eat as if they were made to gobble
                            down all creation without law or'discrimination. The orderly Jew <pb n="197" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 197 of to-day refuses to eat of the products of the dairy, and animal food
                            at the same meal. A wise procedure — the experience of three thousand years, and the best
                            light of our day unite in declaring the law involved, hygienically correct. To bring about a
                            better state of things than now prevails, the following resolutions may be accepted:
                            Resolved, That a monopoly of land by individuals or corporations, is virtually instituting
                            slavery — Is a subversion of the foundations of morality; corrupts legislation; vitiates
                            courts of law and justice ; arrests human progress ; destroys identity of interests ; is a
                            fruitful source of crime, of dis content, and of bodily and mental sufferings unutterable.
                            Resolved, Therefore, that land shall be free to all, without money and without price.
                            Resolved, That this movement be inaugurated now — that now is the auspicious day_ May the
                            heavens of the Arctic Circle resound with the movement of its coming, and all the icebergs
                            of conserved wrongs and special privileges fall to pieces by the force of its
                            reverberations. Let the Temperate Zones clap their hands with joyful emotions; and the
                            Equatorial Belt, in all its wide circumference and grandeur, burst forth with rapturous
                            Hallelujahs of Glory to God, for the foundations of Justice are about to be laid, whereon a
                            higher civilization can rest, in which, " Bach shall care for other, And each to each shall
                            bend ; Then poverty shall cease to be, And wars will have an end. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great many mistake religious sentiment..." TEIform="index"/>Great many mistake religious sentiment...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A great many mistake religious sentiment for a religious life. Because they are
                                    touched by religious truth, they fancy they are religions. Because they are
                                    susceptible to religion they think they have it. An impression is to them the same
                                    as if they obeyed it ; to appreciate right is the same as though they did the right.
                                    Weeping over a book of martyrs, they almost think it as heroic as though they died
                                    at the stake themselves. They come to take what God has planted in them as a
                                    substitute for a practical Christian life.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jersey messenger" TEIform="index"/>N. J. Messenger </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sorrowful" TEIform="index"/>SORROWFUL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">[It was with an extreme sorrow, with scarcely any avenue of relief, that we learned on the
                            27th of July that one of the noblest of God's humanity lay at the point of departure from
                            earth. Every one sorrowed at this intelligence, for Elder Thomas Damon was not used up by
                            age, nor infirmity of lingering disease, but seemed a sudden call, an unseasonable collapse.
                            But the end of human endurance came, and a loved, upright and just man passed away, leaving
                            an innumerable company of mourning friends. We say innumerable, for as our nameless
                            correspondent truthfully closes a short obituary, "he had not an enemy."— Editok.] SKETCH OF
                            THE LIFE AND DEATH OF ELDER THOMAS DAMON. Thomas Damon was born December 26 1819, in the
                            town of Foster, R. I. When he was in his eighth year, his parents moved to the town of
                            Enfield, Conn., and joined their interests with the people called Shakers, giving their
                            children (whom they brought with them), their own life example of self-denial, and a daily
                            cross. In a religious revival which began among believers in the fall of 1837, the subject
                            of this sketch became deeply interested, and soon received through the washing of sincere
                            repentance a most genuine baptism of fire and the holy spirit, which worked crucifixion to
                            the nature of sin. For years he made the New Testament scriptures his chief study and
                            pleasure, carrying a copy constantly in his pocket, when about his work. Every spare minute
                            being devoted to its pages, and in all things he was accounted faithful and obedient, being
                            still a minor. He was soon placed in charge of a company of children and to school-teaching,
                            in which he acted a very creditable part, until he was chosen, raised and associated with
                            Elder Grove Wright in the ministry of the order, with whom he traveled and labored
                            faithfully and ardently for nearly fifteen years. In the autumn of 1860, Elder Grove, from
                            age and disability retired from the ministry, when Elder Thomas succeeded to the lead- <pb n="198" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 198 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. ing- gift and calling of that order, since
                            which he has toiled with his hands, his head and his whole heart for the good of souls,
                            sparing to himself no time for leisure nor pleasure, day nor night, that he did not labor
                            and bear and care for souls to such a degree that his physical health and strength were many
                            times seriously affected. Nevertheless, by the gracious hand of providence he was supported,
                            and continued active and laborious till (after a short illness) in the arms of death he
                            closed his earthly work July 28, 1880, deeply mourned and lamented by all who knew him We
                            think that it may be truly said that he had'nt an enemy in the world.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Government" TEIform="index"/>GOVERNMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline><p TEIform="p">" I will put my laws into their minds, and write them in their hearts. I will be to them a
                            God, and they shall be to Me a people." In the outside world, where sons of Belial roam at
                            large, an armed police is needful for the preservation of order. In Zion —in every branch of
                            Zion— it is the province of the chosen representatives of the divine law-givers, clothed in
                            mantles paternal and maternal, to call the attention of novitiates to the laws written in
                            their hearts. This involves no infringement of individual sovereignty. Every son and
                            daughter of Zion, seeing that the common good, and of course their own good, requires it,
                            sacredly and cheerfully observe the sacred law.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There goes the bell" TEIform="index"/>THERE GOES THE BELL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We wonder if any of our Shaker brethren ever have such thoughts and feelings about prayer
                            meeting time, as described by our poetical neighbor, in the following poem ? Nor will we
                            confine the query to our Shaker people ; for perhaps it photographs the soliloquies of a few
                            others besides. Perhaps also the rebuke will cause the practical repentance noted in the
                            last verses :</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer meeting bell" TEIform="index"/>THE PRAYER MEETING BELL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lent, Emma A." TEIform="persName"/>Emma A. Lent</byline><p TEIform="p">I cannot go to church to-night, The room is closed, the gas is bright, And then my head don't
                            feel just right, 'And I'm not very well. Perhaps 1 really ought to go, But then the brethren
                            vex me so, They pray so long, and speak so slow, Oh dear me ! there's the bell. I'm sure
                            they need not look to me, I have my work, as all must see, Besides, my friends were here to
                            tea, And they know that full well, And I have been out once to-day, And it is quite proper I
                            should stay At home to-night ; but, by the way, ilow long they ring that bell. I wish I knew
                            just who'll be there, And who will make the opening prayer, But then there's dampness in the
                            air, And I'm not over well. For just last week I had a cold, And looked quite faded I was
                            told, Oh well! I guess I am growing old, Is that the second bell ? Our pastor made an
                            earnest plea, That all would come ; but 1 can't see As that is any thing to me, When I'm not
                            feeling .well. By stitching now with all my might. These ruffles I may finish quite, For it
                            is too late to go to-night, That was the second bell I'm glad the bell is quiet now, It
                            troubled me I must allow, I wish I had not made that vow, To go when I was well. I promised
                            I would always aid, And do whatever conscience said, Ah me ! I wish I had obeyed The summons
                            of that bell. Oh Father ! on my bended knee In all my guilt without a plea For pardon now I
                            come to Thee, My heart Thou know'st well, Would feign disown the blessing sweet, Of health,
                            and strength, and try to cheat My soul in believing it were meet, Thus to ignore the bell.
                            My Lord, I know that Thou art there To bless Thy people bowed in prayer, My sin sick soul I
                            pray Thee spare, And make it pure and well. And then again 1 will not stray, Or from Thy
                            presence turn away, But with glad heart henceforth obey The calling of that bell. Bexford
                            Flats, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="199" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Say well and do well" TEIform="index"/>SAY WELL AND DO WELL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">In closing a sermon on " Good Works and Good Words," Dean Stanley of Westminster quoted the
                            following lines which some suppose were written by one of the earliest Deans of Westminster
                            . Say well is good, but do well is better; Do well seems the spirit, say well is the letter;
                            Say well is goodly, and helps to please ; But do well is godly, and gives the world ease ;
                            Sa}r well to silence sometimes is bound ; But do well is free on every ground. Say well has
                            friends, some here, some there, But do well is welcome everywhere, By say well many to God's
                            word cleave; But for lack of do well it often leave, If say well and do well were bound in
                            one frame Then all were done, all were one, and gotten were gain. Esteemed Brother Albert: I
                            send you the inclosed : " Sap well and Do well." And as good comes to us by littles, it may
                            do a little good. The ancient prophet said : "As the days of a tree are the days of my
                            people;" — seasons of growth and also seasons of seeming death— latent life. Our modern
                            prophetess predicted "days and nights," seed time, harvest and winter. Have we not witnessed
                            the spring time of hope, " signs and wonders," of seed sowing in receptive soil ? The summer
                            growth, the autumn harvest ? And shall we be dismayed at the silent winter? A season in
                            which all life seems extinct.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wesley on dress" TEIform="index"/>WESLEY ON DRESS</head><p TEIform="p">" I advise you ... (1) That your apparel be cheap, not expensive ; far cheaper than others in
                            your circumstances wear, and than you would wear if you knew not God. (2) That it be grave,
                            not airy or showy ; not in the point of fashion. And these easy rules may be applied both to
                            the materials whereof it is made and the manner wherein it is made, or put on. ... Wear
                            nothing, though you have it already, which is of a glaring color, or which is in any kind
                            gay, glistening or showy ; nothing made in the very height of the fashion; nothing apt to
                            attract the eyes of the by-standers. I do not advise women to wear rings, ear-rings,
                            necklaces, lace (of whatever kind or color), or ruffles, which, by little and little, may
                            easily shoot out from one to twelve inches deep."—Wesley's works, vol. 6, p. 547.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let bygones be bygones" TEIform="index"/>LET BYGONES BE BYGONES
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">LET BYGONES BE BYGONES. Let bygones be bygones; if bygones were clouded By aught
                                    that occasioned a pang of regret, Oh, let them in darkest oblivion be shrouded; 'Tie
                                    wise and 'tis kind to forgive and forget. Let bygones be bygones, and good be
                                    extracted From ill over which it is folly to fret; The wisest of mortals have
                                    foolishly acted,— The kindest are those who forgive and forget. Let bygones be
                                    bygones; oh, cherish no longer The thought that the sun of affection has set;
                                    Eclipsed for a moment, its rays will be stronger, If you, like a Christian, forgive
                                    and forget. Let bygones bo bygones ; your heart will be lighter, When kindness of
                                    yours with reception has met; The flame of your love will be purer and brighter, If,
                                    Godlike, you strive to forgive and forget. Let bygones be bygones; oh, purge out the
                                    leaven Of malice, and try an example to set To others, who, craving the mercy of
                                    heaven, Are sadly too slow to forgive and forget. Let bygones be bygones; remember
                                    how deeply To heaven's forbearance we all are in debt ; They value God's infinite
                                    goodness too cheaply Who heed not the precept, " Forgive and forget."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Chambers' journal" TEIform="index"/>Chambers' Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'I never turn out for scoundrels'" TEIform="index"/>'I never turn out for scoundrels
                        </head><p TEIform="p">'' I never turn out for scoundrels," said a bully, meeting a Quaker, and stepping up square
                            before him to inaugurate a quarrel. " I do," said the Quaker, and placidly took the other
                            side of the way.</p></div2><pb n="200" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto.— I received the letter forwarded by you from H. L. E...." TEIform="index"/>Editor Manifesto.— I received the letter forwarded by you from H. L. E....
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, August 1, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., Aug. 1, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor Manifesto.— I received the letter forwarded by you from H. L. E. I very much
                                regret when I tax the piety of any one over much. I do not, however, think that he and I
                                differ very much after all. Perhaps 1 had better define my idea of " Infidel more
                                clearly" : I do not care what people believe or doubt, if they conduct themselves well
                                in this world ; obeying all the moral and physical laws of nature, and adhering to the
                                Golden Rule. Such are prepared for the next place of existence ; and will feel at home
                                when they get there, just as much as if they always had been prating about heaven and
                                futurity to the neglect of earth life's duties. "The salt of the earth," are such as
                                save humanity from degradation and physical sins, either by precept or example, or by
                                both — whoever exercises the power to save, are saviours — why not ? Is it any robbery
                                of Jesus or his disciples, to declare others to be " the salt of the earth?" If I give
                                one man ten dollars, and another one dollar, does it necessarily follow that I have
                                robbed the first? Did Jesus secure letters patent on the means of salvation ? To the
                                contrary He rebuked His disciples for their arrogance, when they told Him that they "
                                forbade them to cast out devils in his name ! " If, as our mutual [friend, H. L. E.
                                would imply, that the Shakers alone are " the salt of the earth," then I must still
                                insist that the earth is none too well salted. In my opinion, the saviors on the moral
                                and physical planes are clearly entitled to the appellation of "salt."' In conclusion, I
                                really wish I could know, how some of the stern advocates for Jesus would agree with him
                                as a traveling companion or a room-mate ! I am, Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unitary home" TEIform="index"/>Unitary Home</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Arkansas, Rich Mountain " TEIform="index"/>,Rich Mountain, Polk Co., Ark., Aug. 21,
                                1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y.. The package of Manifestos sent us have been
                                distributed, mostly among preachers of various orthodox " persuasions." Your principles
                                seem to be little understood in this very " remote " section. God speed these little
                                messengers on their errand of mercy to poor, benighted creed-bound mortals hitherto
                                groping in darkness. To those who are disposed to class us with the Shakers, I have only
                                to say, would that we were worthy to be accounted Shakers. We read your papers with
                                profound interest and heartily indorse much that we read. We believe that Christ is the
                                only "begotten " Son of God, but that Jesus was begotten of mortal man, hence, He was as
                                He styles Himself, the Son of Man." We believe that His spiritual nature or " inner man"
                                was perfect only in proportion to his physical perfection and development, and subject
                                to the divine afflatus accordingly ; and that the whole human race may arrive at that
                                state of perfection through the process of " regenerating " the physical man, the tree
                                (Matt, vii, 18), and that as sin, evil, or disease and " death " came by " eating," so
                                regeneration must come through a knowledge of what and how to eat, and the propagation
                                of the race from that "stock" which "keeps my statutes." That the mental faculties are
                                subservient, in a greater or less degree, to physical conditions, we may cite among many
                                other evidences, the wretch who is under the influence of intoxicating liquors, the
                                various forms of lunacy, etc. We believe in a "trinity," i. e., that man is a threefold
                                being. First, the soul, immortality, life, is the spark of divine life which enlightens
                                and intensifies the animal nature ; second, a physical entity; and third, the "inner,"
                                or spiritual man, the " mediator " between mortality and immortality, in which the soul
                                moves in the celestial spheres, when mortality has been laid aside as an individual
                                identity, and that when man, through covetousness, neglects the " statutes and
                                commandments " of God, for the unnatural acquisition of worldly wealth, he impairs the
                                powers of physical development, impedes spiritual growth and progress, and either loses
                                his soul or right to individuality in the after-life, or must return again to the scenes
                                of earth and pass through other preparatory degrees. <pb n="201" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 201 " The soul that sins it shall die." Death, however, does not mean
                                extinction, but division, dissolution, parturition. The soul of man can never be
                                contaminated nor corrupted. It is not susceptible to tarnish in the slightest degree.
                                Neither can it suffer pain, hence it is above condemnation. It is not subject to the
                                creature, being part of the Creator who holds all things in subjection- The physical
                                structure is an aggregation of earth-matter, belonging to, and remaining with, the
                                earth. The spirit or " inner man" is an aggregation of more refined matter from the
                                ethereal realms, bearing a relation to the physical structure, similar to the relation
                                which the odor of an apple bears to the apple, both of which are tangible to certain
                                senses, while the principle of life that affinitizes infinitessimals, aggregating
                                structural compounds is the " hidden mystery." We believe that marriage, as we term a
                                certain relation of opposite sexes, is a divine institution and may be consummated quite
                                as legitimately by persons of the same sex, as by persons of the opposite sexes, being a
                                mutual compact designed to enlarge the scope of usefulness, enhance the interests of the
                                parties contracting, and intensify their enjoyments. As to how far the limits to the
                                privileges of these compacts extend, we have to be governed by the index by which nature
                                points to her interesting pages. It needs but a superficial glance of an unprejudiced
                                mind at these pages to convince us that no natural desire nor appetite should ever be
                                suffered to become a " lust." To foster the natural desire for the things of this world
                                engenders covetousness, lust; so, likewise, the indulgence of morbid greed in any
                                species of exclusiveness is to engender lust and lead our members into captivity to
                                evil. Under the present state of physical corruption and consequent social
                                demoralization our only hope of reformation seems to be in complete self-denial, that we
                                deny ourselves the right to any gratification which cannot in the nature of things be
                                mutually enjoyed by others without detriment to any. To secure these ends " marriage "
                                seems to be a necessity, inasmuch as our interests are naturally mutual, our relations
                                must be mutual also, and these relations, to afford the greatest mutual benefit, must be
                                complex, because " in union there is strength." The Shakers, with a hundred years'
                                experience " coming up out of tribulation " have proven this, and are to day enjoying
                                the blessings of perfect harmony when acting in a perfect unity of interests, and when
                                the world is ready to move in concert with this great work, Christ will come down in our
                                midst ushering in the millennium. Please accept the inclosed small remittance (00
                                cents). Very small indeed when offered as a tribute to the worth and merits of the
                                Manifesto. It is our mite. To appreciate the worldly value of that mite, you have only
                                to look back into your own past history when trials, hardships, privations and
                                persecution assailed you on every hand. Please accept our united and very sincere thanks
                                for the kind interest manifested in our behalf. I very much rejoice to see the
                                manifestations of interest with which our young of both sexes take up the Manifesto. To
                                us all it is an ever welcome visitor " brim full " of vital truths, uttered with a
                                spirit of impartiality everywhere characteristic of truth. Long may it continue to
                                arouse the deep lethargy into which the race has fallen, revealing new lights from old
                                truths which shall bring us nearer to each other in spiritual harmony and nearer in
                                happy anticipation to the eternal Father. The measure of our co-operation in the cause
                                shall be proportionate to our worthiness and consequent ability to labor. May God give
                                us light to direct us in the right way, and strength proportionate to labor in the
                                cause. Ever yours, etc. P. S. I have just read Elder Eads' Infidel Sophistry Rebuked "
                                and do not hesitate to pronounce it the best sermon I have heard since I came to the
                                State five years ago. This is religions science, and we consider religious science quite
                                as vital to the interests of immortals as is the science of agriculture, mechanics,
                                etc., to the interest of the mortal.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beauchamp, W. A. J." TEIform="persName"/>W. A. J. Beauchamp</byline></div3></div2><pb n="202" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Suppositions" TEIform="index"/>SUPPOSITIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">There can be no harm to suppose, as we in short purpose doing ; and there may be some
                                good done thereby; we hope so. Let us suppose the time arrived for the fulfillment of "
                                The Lord's Prayer," — " Thy Kingdom Come, Thy will be done on earth, etc." Let us
                                suppose the exultant spectacle of the descent of Jesus, and the beautiful repetition of
                                the original Christian testimony and call to individuals. Let us suppose some to be
                                fishermen to-day as in the days of yore ; and some shepherds; and farmers; and
                                merchants, mechanics, lawyers, scribes and pharisees. Let us suppose Jesus calling
                                individuals now, as then, from the various employments in selfishness, to enlist as did
                                his then immediate disciples under his banner, to march the march of life as they then
                                did ! Let us suppose what we should see: Neither " Fathers, mothers, wives, children,
                                houses nor lands " stood in the way as obstacles to the original discipleship, nor would
                                they now. Let us suppose that even a moiety of those now professing the name, and a love
                                for Jesus, as did his early disciples, should express that same profession , and give
                                evidence of that same love as did those of old. Let us suppose the little band of
                                thirteen now traveling in commonly called Christendom, and calling on the inhabitants to
                                become volunteers, to enlist in the faith as they had enlisted Let us suppose the day of
                                Pentecost again inaugurated, when they "were together, and none possessed aught he
                                called his own, but gave unto each as he had need." Let us suppose men and women as
                                anxious now, as then, to be Christ's disciples ; with the same credentials demanded ;
                                the same self-denials imposed ; the same life-examples of the master actualized and
                                exhibited : We would then see men and women forsaking the inferior conditions of
                                husbands and wives, fathers and mothers; forsaking the selfish obstacles of houses,
                                lands, property in every shape ; forsaking their selfish, carnal, Jewish unchristian
                                lives — loving the life of the master so well, as to permit nothing to enter as an
                                obstacle to an experience of the same. Even now, as in those days, there would be those
                                who loved the world better than they loved Christ ; they would be called now as Christ
                                called them then : " Children of the world, who married and were given in marriage;" but
                                there would be an immense congregation also, even if but a small part of those who
                                professed Christ would actually live Christ, who would represent *¦' the children of the
                                Resurrection "— (Christ's children — "I am the Resurrection," said He—) who neither
                                marry nor are given in marriage, but are as the angels in heaven !" Let us suppose that
                                we make personal wealth an objection to Christian discipleship as did Jesus; the use of
                                retaliations and carnal weapons positively unchristian ; the husband and wife relation —
                                marriage — a worldly, civil rite, but never a Christian insti <pb n="203" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 203 tution; that " the celibate for the kingdom's sake " was Jesus'
                                condition ; and let us suppose, finally, that Christians, like their leader, are solely
                                devoted to living unworldly lives, holding their church relations and government
                                positively separate from the worldly state : These suppositions lead to thoughts that
                                are simple Christianity, but the genuine gospel of Christ. We have supposed
                                sufficiently. N"ow let us hfiow who are the followers of Christ to-day ! Let us know
                                that Christ has come, and they are his followers who live as he lived; others are
                                "children of the world." vv</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Some kind Shaker has sent us several copies of the "Manifesto" a Shaker Magazine
                                published in New York. We like the spirit of it very much, but we cannot conscientiously
                                take any stock in Ann Lee as a leader. We prefer Christ the Son of God as a leader and
                                for our Saviour. We do not intend to caricature any person's belief, " fear God and keep
                                his commandments for this is the whole duty of men."—[Ed. The above we extract from a
                                very prettily printed periodical, but one tending to very gloomy considerations, called
                                "The Coming Struggle." In sympathy with Editor Chase, we, too, cannot "conscientiously
                                take any stock in Ann Lee," nor any other man nor woman "as a leader," unless Ann Lee or
                                such other man or woman followed and taught Christ most and best. If Ann Lee differed in
                                anywise from the purest teaching and life of Jesus, the Christ, we ask the attention of
                                no one to her gospel testimony. If her administration of the gospel of Christ left a
                                single loop hole through which carnal men and women could evade the full cross and
                                self-denials of Jesus, we do not know it. But we do know that the great objection of the
                                majority, concerning taking "stock in Ann Lee as a leader " or in her testimony as a
                                gospel, is that neither leaves any opportunity, nor gives any permission to engage in
                                fleshly indulgences even as Jesus did not. Leaving Ann Lee out as a leader; we ask those
                                who " prefer Christ as a leader," to be sure and follow where he led and leads ; and
                                then to considerately discriminate, if they can, how far from a Shaker life Christ has
                                led them.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union of churches" TEIform="index"/>UNION OF CHURCHES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We have often urged upon the various denominations or churches, professing Christ as
                                their Lord and Head, to try and come to some united opinion as to what constitutes
                                genuine Christianity ; and so to take action upon the subject as to have but one grand
                                church, one united brotherhood of faith and life. Although some wise heads of the "
                                Revs." have informed us that this " never can be done," we yet have an unbounded
                                confidence, that sooner than many are aware this scheme will be consummated. A very ably
                                edited paper in New York city has for years labored to this end, and has the encouraging
                                influences of very many of the most prominent clergy of our own and other countries.
                                This periodical is "The Church Union"." Amidst the most discouraging circumstances it
                                never has flagged, nor drooped its standard. And why should it ? Churches having by
                                profession one Lord, Christ Jesus, <pb n="204" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 204 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. and
                                the life of this head of the faith so explicitly and unerringly, delineated and
                                illustrated, why should there be any fears of a final union and a united Christ family
                                made up of all the churches professing love for the Christian life ? None whatever. The
                                Golden Rule, of Boston says : The Bishop of Manchester, Eng., in the course of a sermon
                                recently delivered at Rochdale, referred to the differences existing between various
                                religious bodies, and said he should like to see a conference of representatives of all
                                denominations for the purpose of seeing whether it was not possible even yet to adjust
                                their differences and place Christianity on a common basis, in order thatthey might have
                                a common Christianity running through the Sunday-schools of the land. Now, this feeler,
                                put forth by the anxious bishop, will work as a leaven among both clergy and laity ; and
                                but a few years can intervene, ere the popular demand of a humanity, with greatly
                                increased intelligence and human sympathies, will institute a conference for a union of
                                the now divided churches ; and the spirit, tenor, ruling characteristic of such
                                conference will be to settle the question : How did Jesus Christ live ? and the key that
                                will unlock the bar to a complete union, and dispel such bar, will be the conscientious
                                agreement of the representatives of such conference, that as Jesus, the Lord and Leader'
                                lived, so should his disciples,— those forming his church, live. And brethren of the
                                various Churches, Ecclesiastic denominations professing the Christian religion, we, your
                                friends, the Shakers, are ready and anxious to have the conference called and to meet
                                you there. Further, we issue the call, the same to be considered living and active,
                                until both conference and Universal Church are consummated.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sexual intemperance" TEIform="index"/>SEXUAL INTEMPERANCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Such is the title of a series of remarkable papers running through the current issues of
                                the liberal paper called The Truth Seeker, New York, and written by that indefatigable,
                                honest worker, (however infidel to popular Christianity), Elmina D. Slenker. We call the
                                series remarkable : for no such sound advice upon the subject is anywhere else given in
                                so concise, modest and intelligent a form. We wish everyone could read the wisdom, the
                                writer so humanely imparts and impresses upon all who can be so fortunate as to secure
                                the reading. Truly, the world has run mad in the intemperance of its sexual demands.
                                Nothing but a return to the normal use, by the children of the world, of the laws of
                                sexual engagements, for propagation only, can save the nations from a fate like Sodom
                                and Gromorrah's. From our standpoint we perceive the world mad in its fleshly lusts. One
                                of our correspondents, after reading the above mentioned series, called the writer a "
                                salt of the earth ; " and on being criticised therefor by another, writes usjan
                                explanatory epistle. While we cannot recommend the above series too highly, for those
                                living in and on the generative plane, we would not fail to impress upon all, that there
                                is something higher and better than generation of human beings; and this is found in
                                living Christ's life — ''the celibate for the kingdom of heaven's sake." And we at the
                                same time, knowing how needy the world is for a <pb n="205" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 205 testimony against its sexual intemperance join our correspondent in
                                callin E. D. Slenker, a great "salt of the earth."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unitary home" TEIform="index"/>unitary home</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A very appreciative and interesting letter will be found in our " Correspondence"
                                department, from a people who are determined to curtail human selfishness considerably,
                                by one of the many forms of community gatherings. Regardless of theological isms which
                                these communities enchain to their spirit of equality for all, of God's blessings, they
                                are worthy of extensive encouragement. We reciprocate the beautiful, almost affectionate
                                allusions of the writer for our people; and pray for the full dawn of the spirit of
                                truth, which will dispel all error from all associations bound Godward, and unite us in
                                a Unitary Home where Purity and Love and Truth will be the bonds of our Union.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trying to be a Christian!" TEIform="index"/>TRYING TO BE A CHRISTIAN!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">If there is any truth in the following story, it ought to put to the blush about
                                ninety-nine per cent of us who make Christianity a profession, but who love too well to
                                retaliate real or imaginary wrongs done us, that we retain scarcely the smell of a
                                Christian about us ! Can it be true ? " The history of modern missions tells us of a
                                negro in the West Indies who asked his master to buy an old, sickly man from a
                                slave-ship, carried him to his own hut, gave him his own bed, cooked his food and nursed
                                him till he died. When asked the reason of his conduct he said : ' I am trying to be a
                                Christian ; that was the man who stole me from my mother in Africa and sold me into
                                slavery.'"</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEPARTED THIS LIFE</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dewey, Oliver" TEIform="index"/>Oliver Dewey</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">From North Union, 0., July 80, , aged 58 years.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Promoted" TEIform="index"/>PROMOTED</head><p TEIform="p">A little form stood by my side, The eager look I noted— "0 teacher when vacation's o'er,
                                Say, shall I be promoted ? "Nay little one, you have been ill, The tasks would be
                                severe." Then coaxingly, " Would you not like To tarry longer here ? " " It is not you I
                                wish to leave, You're always good and kind, But when my mates are going on 'Tis hard to
                                stay behind." The blue eyes filled with sudden tears, I stroked the ringlets shining,
                                But well I knew the tired, feet Would stumble in the climbing. The weeks flew by, and
                                once again, In their accustomed places, I saw the children of my charge, With welcome in
                                their faces. But one I missed ; no earthly care May be to thee devoted : Thj' wish is
                                granted, happy child, And thou hast been promoted. O sad, reproachful eyes of blue, 0
                                tears that dimmed their shining! O tiny feet that struggled on, Nor faltered in the
                                climbing ! But one the Teacher great and wise Hath rightly gauged thy powers, O, may the
                                high and lofty place, Through grace at last be ours.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little girl described a parable" TEIform="index"/>A little girl described a parable
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little girl described a parable as "an earthly story with a heavenly meaning."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Susie,' said a teacher to one of her pupils..." TEIform="index"/>Susie,' said a teacher to one of her pupils...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">' Susie," said a teacher to one of her pupils, " you shouldn't make faces. You'll grow up
                                homely if you make faces." Susie looked thoughtfully in the teacher's face a moment, and
                                then innocently asked : " Did you make faces when you was a little girl ? "</p></div3><pb n="206" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reaping" TEIform="index"/>REAPING</head><p TEIform="p">Here's a beauty of a poem, which each of the dear children would profit by committing to
                                memory, and never forget while growing up, nor when grown to be men and women : . Every
                                one is sowing, both by word and deed ; All mankind are growing, either wheat or weed ?
                                Thoughtless ones are throwing any sort of seed. Serious ones are seeking seed already
                                sown ; Many eyes are weeping now the crop is grown ; Think upon the reaping — each one
                                reaps his own. Surely as the sowing shall the harvest be — See what you are throwing
                                over hill and lea ; Words and deeds are growing for eternity. There is one all knowing,
                                looking on alway ; Fruit to him is flowing, feeling for the day — Will your hearts be
                                glowing in the grand array ? Yea, that would be bringing sheaves of golden grain, Mind
                                what you are flinging both from hand and brain, Then 'mid glad songs singing, you shall
                                glean great gain.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little Allan's self-judgment" TEIform="index"/>LITTLE ALLAN'S SELF-JUDGMENT</head><p TEIform="p">"Allan ! Where is Allan V" A moment ago he was playing with his little cart in the yard,
                                hauling dirt to the currant bushes I cannot tell how many cartfuls he carried. He was as
                                busy as a little man. But Allan was gone ; there is his cart. "Allan! Allan!" " I'se
                                here," at last said a small voice from the back parlor. "What are you therefor?" asked
                                his mother, opening the door and looking in. Allan did not answer at first. He was
                                standing in the corner with a very sober look on his face " Come out to your little
                                cart," said his mother, " it is waiting for another run." " I'se not been here long
                                'nuff," said the little boy. " What are you here for at all?" asked his mother. " I
                                punishing my own self. I picked some green currants, and they went into my mouth," said
                                Allan. "Oh! when mother told you not to! Green currants will make my little boy sick,"
                                said his mother, in a sorry tone. " You needn't punish me," said Allen, " I punish my
                                own self." "His mother often put him in the back parlor alone when he had been a naughty
                                boy, and, you see, he took the same way himself. " Are you not sorry for disobeying
                                mother?" she asked Allan. " I sorry, but sorry is not 'nuff. I punish me. I stay here a
                                good while and thinks." Is not Allan right ? Sorry, if it is only sorry, is not enough.
                                How often children say they are sorry, and yet go and do the same thing again. That is a
                                very short, shallow sorrow. Allan felt this, so he was for making serious work of
                            it.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old merchant (to his son) 'John, do you remember what the first duty on tea was?'..." TEIform="index"/>Old merchant (to his son) 'John, do you remember what the first duty on tea was?'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Old merchant (to his son)—"John, do you remember what the first duty on tea was?" John—"
                                I should think, sir, that the first duty on T was to cross it."</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My! what a steep hill!..." TEIform="index"/>My! what a steep hill!...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">" My ! what a steep hill! And see those ten or eleven wretches packed in one wagon that
                                the poor, staggering horse can scarcely draw ! " " Wretches ! Them are all Christians,
                                mum, going to the camp-meetin' ?"</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Within some persons, some families..." TEIform="index"/>Within some persons, some families...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Within some persons, some families, some congregations, some communities, the leaven of
                                truth has been deposited for a long time, and yet they are not moved, they are not
                                changed. The. leaven remains as it came a stranger ; all around, notwithstanding its
                                presence, is still, is dead. It is when the Spirit is poured out as floods that the
                                leaven of the kingdom spreads with quickening, assimilating power. "I will pour out my
                                Spirit upon you, saith the Lord ; " the promise is sent to generate the prayer, as a
                                sound calls forth an echo. Behold, I come quickly, says Christ; even so, come, Lord
                                Jesus, respond Christians.</p></div3></div2><pb n="207" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Notices</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American newspaper directory" TEIform="index"/>American newspaper directory
                            </head><p TEIform="p">This immense work of more than a thousand pages will prove an invaluable companion to the
                                thousands of newspaper fraternity and millions of advertisers. Its contents are very
                                tastefully arranged, and no pains have apparently been spared to make it the most
                                complete work of its kind ever printed. It is the handiwork of that enterprising firm,
                                Geo. P. Rowell &amp; Co., New York, which firm has excited the unworthy envy and
                                malice of contemporaries, and yet which stands A 1 with all respectable business men. We
                                commend the same to the patron age of all advertisers.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Undiscovered country" TEIform="index"/>Undiscovered country
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Howells, W. H." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Undiscovered country has been sent us, and proves to be an unworthy novel of a very
                                talented man, W. H. Howells, editor of The Atlantic Monthly. The Undiscovered Country
                                has reference to the spirit world, and the theme is a mixture of love story and ridicule
                                of Spiritualism. If the writer does not find there is more truth in the simple,
                                scientific facts taught by Spiritualism "than he has dreamed of in his philosophy," then
                                we err in judgment. Just why this.unfriendly Howells must" drag in the Shakers into so
                                many of his stories, and placing them in so ridiculous a light before the world, we
                                cannot tell. But certain it is that in this story, as in " A House of Entertainment,"
                                Shakerism appears to be " a thorn in his flesh." Courtesy compels us to return some
                                kind'of a notice, but we cannot commend the propriety nor philosophy of the book.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Book of ensilage" TEIform="index"/>Book of ensilage
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bailey, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Bailey </byline><p TEIform="p">The Book of Ensilage, Billerica, Mass. In this work we have a treatise upon the newest
                                and grandest sensation in the agricultural world. The idea of being able, by regarding
                                the instructions of this handsome volume, to preserve in the green state for winter and
                                spring uses clover, corn fodder, peas, beans, etc., is simply wonderful to thiak of, and
                                by which we are enabled to produce milk for one cent per quart, butter for ten cents per
                                pound, beef for four cents per pound, and mutton for nothing, when wool is thirty cents
                                a pound ! We mean to try this Ensilage system by the construction of a small silo, and
                                would recommend to all farmers the reading of the book.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual harmonies" TEIform="index"/>Spiritual harmonies
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Spiritual Harmonies: Being nearly one hundred popular hymns and songs, with a summary of
                                the belief of Spiritualists, and a series of sensible and comforting readings for the
                                sick room and funerals. A glance through this little work confirms our opinions of the
                                necessity of such a book, and that a knowledge of the same will create an immediate and
                                immense demand. Its compilation and renderings are the work of our friend and brother J.
                                M. Peebles, and published and sold by Colby and Rich, Boston, Mass. Price 25 cents.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-love" TEIform="index"/>SELF-LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">Oh, I could go through all life's troubles singing, Turning earth's night to day, If self
                            were not so fast around me, clinging To all I do or say. My very thoughts are selfish,
                            always building Mean castles in the air ; I use my love for others for a gilding To make
                            myself look fair. I fancy all the world engrossed with judging My merit or my blame ; Its
                            warmest praise seems an ungracious grudging Of praise which I mightf claim. In youth, or age,
                            by city, wood, or mountain, Self is forgotten never ; Wlier'er we tread, it gushes like a
                            fountain, Its waters now forever. 0 miserable omnipresence, stretching Over all time and
                            space, How have I run from thee, yet found thee reaching The goal in every race. Inevitable
                            self ! vile imitation Of universal light,— Within our hearts a dreadful usurpation Of God's
                            exclusive right!</p></div2><pb n="208" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>TOMATOES</head><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stewed tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Stewed tomatoes
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Stewed Tomatoes. — To stew tomatoes properly they should be cooked at least two
                                    hours; pour boiling water over them and remove the skin ; then slice them into a
                                    stewpan — porcelain is the best, although new tin will answer ; allow them to boil
                                    briskly for twenty minutes, then remove to the back of the range to simmer slowly
                                    until required ; season liberally with butter, salt and pepper. They will then be
                                    cooked to a thick, creamy consistency with few lumps and a high, fine flavor, and
                                    will not, therefore, need flour or cracker crumbs, which to our taste are no
                                    improvement. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baked tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Baked tomatoes
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Baked Tomatoes. — Select large ones ; remove part of the inside, but do not skin ;
                                    make a stuffing of any kind of cold, cooked meat chopped fine, bread crumbs, green
                                    corn, minced onion or parsley, a well-beaten egg, butter, salt and pepper; fill the
                                    tomatoes with this dressing ; put a piece of butter on the top of each, and bake in
                                    a not very quick oven three-quarters of an hour. Baked Tomatoes and Corn. — Line a
                                    deep dish with slices of tomatoes, then cover with green corn cut from the cob;
                                    season with butter, salt and pepper; then another layer of tomatoes, corn and
                                    seasonings until the dish is full ; add one pint of good meat broth; sprinkle the
                                    top with bread-crumbs and bake one hour.</p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato figs" TEIform="index"/>Tomato figs
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Tomato Figs. — Remove the skins and allow one pound of white sugar for every pound
                                    of fruit; place them in a stone jar for twenty-four hours ; then pour off the syrup
                                    and boil, skimming until clear ; return the syrup to the fruit, letting it remain
                                    another twenty-four hours ; again boil and skim, pouring over as before. After the
                                    third time they are fit to dry ; place on earthen plates and set in the sun. When
                                    well dried pack them in small wooden boxes, with fine white sugar between each
                                    layer. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Broiled tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Broiled tomatoes
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Broiled Tomatoes. — Cut small tomatoes in halves and place upon a wire gridiron cut
                                    surface down ; when the surface is somewhat cooked, turn them with the skin toward
                                    the fire and finish cooking ; serve hot with butter, salt and pepper upon each half.
                                    These make a nice garnish for broiled steak. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fried tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Fried tomatoes
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Fried Tomatoes. — Dip thin slices of ripe tomatoes into flour, salt and pepper, and
                                    fry in boiling butter or lard until nicely browned. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiced tomatoes" TEIform="index"/>Spiced tomatoes
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Spiced Tomatoes. — To six pounds of fruit allow four pounds of white sugar, one
                                    quart of cider vinegar, not too strong, half an ounce each of ground cinnamon,
                                    cloves and allspice ; cook in a porcelain kettle one hour, then put in jars and
                                    cover tightly. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato catsup" TEIform="index"/>Tomato catsup
                                </head><p TEIform="p"> Tomato Catsup.—One bushel of tomatoes, three large teacupsful of salt, two
                                    tablespoonsful of cayenne pepper, four ounces of light black pepper, two ounces of
                                    whole allspice, two ounces of whole cloves, four ounces of grated nutmeg. Wash the
                                    tomatoes, put them into a kettle and mash as fine as possible; add the salt and
                                    spices and boil two hours, then strain through a sieve, carefully rubbing through
                                    the pulp; put back and boil; at the end of four hours remove; when cold bottle and
                                    seal ; keep in a cool dry place. When boiling it should be stirred almost constantly
                                    so that it may not burn. We also find it advisable to wire the corks. </p></div4><div4 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Delicate tomato salad" TEIform="index"/>Delicate tomato salad
                                </head><p TEIform="p">A Delicate Tomato Salad. — Many who like tomatoes prefer them most of all in a raw
                                    state, as salad, served with various combinations of vinegar, oil and mustard—some
                                    using only a little vinegar, others using no vinegar, but a combination of oil and
                                    mustard. A great improvement on any of these is made by using the juice of a lemon
                                    only. In this way good tomatoes, skinned by putting them in scalding water for a
                                    minute, allowed to cool, cut into slices and a good lemon squeezed over them, form
                                    one of the most grateful and wholesome dishes obtainable in summer. For salads we
                                    prefer skinning with a sharp knife without immersing in hot water. </p></div4></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When molasses is used in cooking..." TEIform="index"/>When molasses is used in cooking...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">When molasses is used in cooking it is an improvement to boil and skim it before you use
                                it. It takes out the unpleasant, raw taste, and makes it almost as good as sugar.</p></div3><pb n="209" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiced grapes" TEIform="index"/>Spiced Grapes</head><p TEIform="p">.—Eight quarts of seeded grapes, two ounces of ground cloves, two of cinnamon, three and
                                one-half pounds of sugar. Boil two hours.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A few pieces of horseradish..." TEIform="index"/>A few pieces of horseradish...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A PEW pieces of horseradish root placed among pickles will prevent scum from gathering on
                                the top of the vinegar.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Antitdote to poison" TEIform="index"/>Antidote to Poison</head><p TEIform="p">.—If a person swallows any poison whatever, or has fallen into convulsions from having
                                overloaded the stomach, an instantaneous remedy, most efficient and applicable in a
                                large number of cases, is a heaping teaspoonful of common salt, and as much ground
                                mustard, stirred rapidly in a teacupful of water, warm or cold, and swallowed instantly.
                                It is scarcely down before it begins to come up, bringing with it the remaining contents
                                of the stomach ; and lest there be any remnants of the poison, however small, let the
                                white of an egg or a teaspoonful of strong coffee be swallowed as soon as the stomach is
                                quiet, because these very common articles nullify a large number of virulent
                            poisons.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cheese pudding" TEIform="index"/>Cheese Pudding</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">This is a supper dish, and costs twelve cents. Into two quarts of boiling
                                        water, containing two tablespoonfuls of salt, stir one pound of yellow Indian
                                        meal and a quarter of a pound grated cheese (cost four cents); boil it for
                                        twenty minutes, stirring it occasionally to prevent burning, then put it in a
                                        greased baking-pan; sprinkle over the top a quarter of a pound of grated cheese,
                                        and brown in a quick oven. Serve hot. If any remains, slice it cold and fry
                                        brown.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="People" TEIform="index"/>The People</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To polish shirt fronts and wristbands" TEIform="index"/>To Polish Shirt Fronts and
                                Wristbands</head><p TEIform="p">. — Starch the fronts and wristbands as stiff as you can. Starch twice — that is, starch,
                                dry, then starch again. Iron your shirt with a box-iron, in the usual way, making the
                                linen nice and firm, but without any attempt at a good finish ; don't lift the plaits ;
                                your shirt is now ready for polishing ; but you ought to have a board same size as a
                                common shirt board, made of hard wood, and covered with only one ply of plain cotton
                                cloth. Put this board into the breast of your shirt, damp the front very lightly with a
                                wet sponge, then take the polishing iron, which is flat and beveled at one end — polish
                                gently with the beveled end, taking care not to drive the linen up into wave-like
                                blisters. Of course this requires a little practice, but if you are careful and
                                persevere, in a short time you will be able to give the enamel-like finish which is so
                                much wanted.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Killing rats" TEIform="index"/>Killing Rats</head><p TEIform="p">.—The following cheap and simple method is said to be in use in Germany: A mixture of two
                                parts of wellbruised common squills and three parts of finely-chopped bacon is made into
                                a stiff mass, with as much meal as may be required, and then baked into small cakes,
                                which are put down for the rats to eat. Several correspondents of the German
                                Agricultural Gazette write to announce the complete extirpation of rats and mice from
                                their cow-stalls and piggeries since the adoption of this simple plan.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use of powdered pumice stone on varnished work" TEIform="index"/>Use of Powdered Pumice
                                Stone on Varnished Work</head><p TEIform="p">. — Pulverized pumice stone is used to remove the gloss and imperfections on varnished
                                surfaces. It is applied by rubbing with woolen cloth and water. Rotten stone is used in
                                the same manner, but applied only on work that requires polishing.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tomato toast" TEIform="index"/>Tomato Toast</head><p TEIform="p">. — Take one dozen large, ripe tomatoes, pare and slice them , put in a stew pan over a
                                moderate fire. Add pepper and salt to taste. Toast two slices of bread, butter the toast
                                and lay it in the bottom of a deep dish, and pour the tomatoes over it.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nails" TEIform="index"/>Nails</head><p TEIform="p">--Many persons are puzzled to understand what the terms " fourpenny," " sixpenny," and "
                                tenpenny " mean, as applied to nails. "Fourpenny" means four pounds to the thousand
                                nails, and " sixpenny " means six pounds to the thousand, and so on. It is an English
                                term, and meant at first ''tenpound" nails (the thousand being understood), but the
                                English clipped it to " tenpun," and from that it degenerated until "' penny " was
                                substituted for pounds." When a thousand nails weigh less than a pound they are called
                                tacks, brads, etc., and reckoned by ounces.</p></div3><pb n="210" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To preserve carpets" TEIform="index"/>To Preserve Carpets</head><p TEIform="p">. — Carpets should be shaken often. The dirt that collects under them grinds out the
                                threads. But do not sweep them oft'jner than is absolutely necessary. Take a brush and
                                dusting-pan and remove the dirt in this way, and your carpets will wear enough longer to
                                pay for your trouble.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is a fact known to the philosophical instrument-makers..." TEIform="index"/>It is a fact known to the philosophical instrument-makers...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is a fact known to the philosophical instrument-makers, that if a metal wire be drawn
                                through a glass tube, a few hours afterward the tube will burst into fragments. This
                                will not happen if a piece of soft wood is employed. In these times, when glasslamp
                                chimneys are in such wide use, it is of no little importance that this fact should be
                                made known. Thousands of persons who have been in the habit of using wires, table forks,
                                and a variety of metallic articles in the washing of these chimneys, will, in the above
                                stated fact, find the reason of their chimneys so often snapping to pieces on the
                            lamp.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ox-gall" TEIform="index"/>Ox-Gall</head>Ox-gall
                            <p TEIform="p">. — An ox's gall will set any color — silk, cotton or woolen. One spoonful of gall put
                                into a gallon of warm water is sufficient for the above purpose. Gall is also excellent
                                for taking out spots from bombazines, and after being washed in it they look almost as
                                good as new. It must be thoroughly stirred into water, and not put on the clothes. It is
                                used without soap. After being washed in it, cloth which you want to clean should be
                                washed in warm suds, without using soap.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beef tea" TEIform="index"/>Beef Tea</head><p TEIform="p">.—Beef tea for the sick is made by boiling a tender steak nicely, seasoning it with
                                pepper and salt, cutting it up and pouring water over it, not quite boiling ; put in a
                                little water at a time and let it soak the goodness out ; then heat it hot</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Iron rust" TEIform="index"/>Iron rust</head><p TEIform="p"> , it is said, may be removed by tying a little cream of tartar in the stained spot
                                before putting the cloth to boil. If this does not succeed, thicken lemon juice with
                                equal parts of salt and starch, add some soft soap, apply the mixture to the cloth, and
                                lay it in the hot sun. Renew the application several times.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Way of the world" TEIform="index"/>THE WAY OF THE WORLD</head><p TEIform="p">Yes, stone the woman—let the man go free ! Draw back your skirts lest they perchance May
                            touch her garments as she passes ; But to him put forth a willing hand To clasp with his
                            that led her to destruction And disgrace. Shut up from her the sacred Ways of toil, that she
                            no more may win an Honest meal; but ope to him all honorable Paths, where he may win
                            distinction. Give to him fair, pressed down measures of Life's sweetest joys. Pass her, 0
                            maiden, With a pure proud face, if she puts out A poor, polluted palm ; but lay thy hand in
                            His on bridal day, and swear to cling to him With wifely love and tender reverence, Trust
                            him who led a sister woman To a fearful fate. Yes, stone the woman—let the man go free! Let
                            one soul suffer for the guilt of two— It is the doctrine of a hurried world, Too out of
                            breath for holding balances Where nice distinctions and injustices Are calmly weighted-.
                            But, ah, how will it be On that strange day of final fire and flame When men shall stand
                            before the one true Judge ? Shall sex make then a difference in Sin ? Shall He, the Searcher
                            of the hidden Heart, in His eternal and divine decree, Condemn the woman and forgive the man
                            ?</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pathographic dispatches" TEIform="index"/>PATHOGRAPHIC DISPATCHES</head><p TEIform="p">Office of the mouth—-at one end of the line. Office of the Stomach — at the other end of it.
                            DISPATCH. Inquiry — Mouth to the stomach. " Are you ready for breakfast ? " Stomach —¦ " Yes
                            ; what are you going to send ? " Mouth — " You will see. Prepare ! " The table bell rings.
                            Body hurries, drops into a chair. Mouth opens, and down goes as quickly as possible a cup of
                            coffee, at a temperature of 145 degrees of Fahrenheit. It burns the whole cesophagean track
                            as it passes it, and when it gets into the stomach burns it, and the stomach contracts, and
                            shrivels and cringes, and finally screeches, and the Mouth says, " Halloa ! what is the
                            matter ?" Stomach—¦" Matter! Enough I should think. Do you not know that I cannot ndure
                            slush at 140 to 160 degrees of heat ? " <pb n="211" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 211
                            Mouth — "Oh, never mind! Here comes some beefsteak with hot fried potatoes, hot rolls and
                            poor batter, some salad with vinegar, some buckwheat cakes and molasses. These will heal
                            it." Stomach — " Stop ! What earthly use is there in sending these down here all at one
                            time? They make a hodge-podge." Mouth — "Here comes some more coffee." Stomach—"Hold on!
                            wait! Give me some water ! " Mouth—"Water! when you can get coffee ! You must be crazy ;
                            water has no nourishment in it. One wants water only when one is dry." Stomach — "I am
                            thirsty ! Give me some water! " Mouth — " Cannot do it—they haven't any water up here. If
                            they have it is hot, and I doubt if they have any of that. Persons do not like water; and
                            you, oh, Stomach, are eccentric ; so stop complaining and get ready to take some food — '
                            take the good the gods provide you, and be content.' Are you ready ? 1 am in a hurry. JUp
                            here 'time is money.' I have to furnish you with material out of which strength is to be
                            gotten for the body's use to-day, and I have ten minutes allowed me for this purpose. Now
                            the afterpart is your look-out, not mine. Take notice ! Are you ready ? Here comes apple
                            pie, fried chicken, tripe, tomato catsup, boiled ham, minute pudding, corn bread and
                            cucumbers, pepper, salt, gravy, mince pie, another cup of coffee ; so look out! " Stomach—¦"
                            Look out! oh, murder ! what am I to do ? Do ? I must grind away at it ]ike a horse in a
                            bark-mill, till I am worn out. Under such a condition of things as this I shall break down
                            in the fourth part of the time which I might work. Then the mouth, and for that matter the
                            Heart, too, will be still, and I shall be at peace." —Laws of Life.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beating for recruits" TEIform="index"/>Beating for Recruits</head><p TEIform="p">.—The English Government offers five pound for each healthy boy of fourteen years old, from
                            the district schools, to be sent to the barra.cks to be trained as soldiers.— Voice, of
                            Peace,. Train up a child in the way he should go. Solomon.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Capital prescription" TEIform="index"/>A CAPITAL PRESCRIPTION.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A rather eccentric, yet eminent physician, was called upon to attend a middle
                                    aged rich lady who had imaginary ills, t fter many wise inquiries about her symptoms
                                    and manner of life, he asked for a piece of paper ^and wrote down the following
                                    prescription: " Do something for somebody." In the gravest manner he handed it to
                                    the patient and left. The doctor heard nothing from the lady for a long time. One
                                    Christmas morning he was hastily summoned to the cottage of his Irish washerwoman. "
                                    It's not meself, doctor, it's me wrist that's ailing. Ye sfee, I was after goin' out
                                    into the black darkness for a few bits of wood, whenmejfut struck this basket. It
                                    stood there like a big mercy, as it was, full of soft flannel from Mrs. Walker. She
                                    told me that your medicine cured her, doctor. So, if you plaz to put a little of
                                    that same on my wrist, I'll be none the worse for my nice present.' , " ' It's a
                                    powerful remedy,' said the doctor, gravely. And more than once in after years he
                                    wrote the prescription: 'Do something for somebody."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">[From the <index level1="Boston herald" TEIform="index"/>Boston Herald.]</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Late George Beckwith of New Haven" TEIform="index"/>THE LATE GEORGE BECKWITH OF NEW HAVEN.</head><p TEIform="p">H Mtkick.] ' He gave directions for the floral tributes at his funeral to be not profuse and
                            said: "Put my transit at the head of my coffin and point it up where I have gone. Take my
                            axe and twine it with flowers. Make a book of flowers and place trees in the room." These
                            directions were followed. Poor people came to the funeral in troops. There were drunkards
                            who had partly reformed and who trembled as they stood over the body of one who had been a
                            friend to them. There were poor women whose rent had been paid from his purse, and who had
                            frequently been restarted in life through his efforts. There were colored people whom he had
                            befriended when the action cost a person social ostracism. There were persons of nearly all
                            ranks. One woman in her <pb n="212" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 212 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. grief said: " Oh,
                            where can I go now for a friend ? There will be no one now to pay my rent." One man who had
                            been addictec to drink offered to watch with the corpse saying : " He done me good." It was
                            part of Mr. Beckwith's creed never to shake hands except with three classes : The col ored,
                            lest they should think he held them in contempt ; the drunken, because they knew no better
                            than to shake hands ; and olc persons, who might otherwise think he lacked respect. [This
                            man is " not far from the kingdom heaven." He has deposits thei'e — treasures secure from
                            moth, rust and thieves." Such " rich men," need not " enter the kingdom of heaven'' they
                            have it, "within."—</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Selections" TEIform="index"/>SELECTIONS</head><p TEIform="p">Science begins to whisper what revelation ages ago uttered in thunders, that there is a
                            spiritual body with glorious capacities. 9 V The success or failure to be a good and true
                            man depends largely upon one's obedience or disobedience to the convictions of duty which
                            every man at times feels. /? AWhen the standard, "By their fruits ye shall know them," is
                            the only one used to estimate a man's character and worth, the judgment of the world will be
                            more accurate and just. f( It is seldom wise to enter into a discus\ sion with a skeptical
                            man on the doctrines of religion. The best thing is to have such a life back of your words
                            that you can say " Come and see for yourself whether religion is not a blessed thing to
                            have." A 11 feel more and more deeply how un^ Christian and guilty the lives of the
                            prosperous classes are. How little genuine sympathy we have towards the masses of our
                            fellows. Society needs a revolution such as history nowhere records. To use our superiority
                            as a means of elevating those below us, is the spirit of Christianity, and were it to
                            prevail, would make a revolution more striking than any conquest has made.—[Channing. \No
                            man preaches well to others if he does not preach to his own heart. K. There are two easy
                            roads to heaven which shorten the distance immensely. For the .poor it is patience, for the
                            rich it is charity. /' Duty is the voice of God, and a man is neither worthy of a good home
                            nor a heaven, that is unwilling to be in peril for a good cause.—[John Brown. SsrHe who with
                            steadfast humility and patience endures tribulations for the fervent love of God, shall soon
                            attain to great graces and virtues. He shall be Lord of this world, and shall receive the
                            earnest of the world which is to come. "^^IJied, in" Laodicea, the prayer-meeting. Its
                            health was poor the last year. A few anxious friends kept it alive. Discouragement at last
                            prevailed, and it died from neglect. Not a Christian was present when it died. Over forty
                            professionals were living within a quarter of a mile, and not one was there. Had two been
                            there, its life might have been saved, for " where two or three arer gathered together,
                            etc." X Everything a man does, be it good or evil, he does unto himself. Therefore, be not
                            thou offended with him who injures thee, but rather in humble patience, sorrow only for his
                            sin, having compassion on him, and praying fervently to God for him. For, in as far as a man
                            is strong to suffer and endure injuries and tribulations patiently for the love of God, so
                            great, and no greater is he before God. And the weaker a man is to endure sufferings and
                            adversities for the love of God, the less he is in the sight of God. ¦h—-trTSaJority of the
                            rural parishes of Scotland the use of the manuscript in the julpit would, till a recent
                            period, have been ratal to the cordial acceptability of any presentee. " He's a graund
                            preacher! " whisaered an old spinster to her sister, on hearng a young minister for the
                            first time. 'Whist, Bell," was the reply; "he's readin'." " Readin' is he! " said the
                            eulojist, changing her tone ; " filthy fellow ! ¦ve'll gang hame, Jenny, and read our
                        jook."</p></div2><pb n="213" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration" TEIform="index"/>INSPIRATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G Russell</byline><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. 1 Blessed Inspiration That elevates the soul, That draweth 2. Waft, O waft me
                            onward, My vision would expand, I long to 3. When this life is over, And earth receives her
                            own, My spirit out from darkness, Away from earth's control, That leadeth range in spirit,
                            That blessed Summer Land; With angel then would enter My glorious heavenly home; No more a
                            to the fountain, Where crystal streamlets flow, Re— choirs to mingle, In music's sweetest
                            flow, On toiling stranger, Within this vale be low, I'll freshing life sustaining, O there I
                            long to go. wings of inspiration, O there I long to go. range the realms supernal, O there I
                            long to go. O there I long to go, Its heavenly joys to know, It is a haven of repose,— My
                            blest and heavenly home.</p></div2><pb n="214" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday with the Shakers" TEIform="index"/>A SUNDAY WITH THE SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">[The editor of The Granite State Free Press has been enjoying Shaker associations lately at
                            Enfield, N. H. Listen to his admirations and criticisms. His queries in regard to the
                            declination of Shakers to exercise the franchise of voting deserve elaborate replies, and
                            will receive due attention in The Manifesto in the near future. — Editor] " It is nineteen
                            years since we took up our abode within six miles of the Enfield Shakers, and last Sunday
                            was the first time that we ever attended church service there. It was not from want of a
                            wish or a standing invitation to do so ; but somehow the favorable opportunity never before
                            came. We arrived late. The scripture reading and the morning prayer were already past, and
                            the brethren and sisters were marching about the church by threes, keeping time with the
                            hands and feet to the hymns which they were singing, and which were such as any Christians
                            would sing in their devotional meetings. Now comes a halt. The worshipers remain standing. A
                            sister, evidently one of the most intelligent and devoted, in faultless language gives
                            utterance to her religious emotions, which seemed to be much the same as those of Christians
                            the world over. We should not have known that we were not in some social religious meeting
                            of almost any Protestant denomination. The leading thought was the consciousness of inward
                            joy in a life of crossbearing, and a wish to bring the life to be more and more like that of
                            Jesus. Subsequently, after all were seated, Elder Cummings stepped to the front. He had a
                            little slip of paper in his hands on which, as we suppose, a few leading thoughts were
                            noted, though we did not see him consult it. He took no text, but talked for half an hour —
                            a good common sense, rational discourse, as it seemed to us, covering a number of practical
                            points— a talk which evinced the fact that he is neither himself ignorant of, nor seeks to
                            conceal from those under his instruction, the conflict of ideas going on in the great
                            outside world, but rather that it is the aim of his sect to keep step with the progressive
                            ideas of a progressive age. The latter part of his discourse was largely a recognition of
                            the enlarged rights of women and a plea for their future enlargement, till man and woman
                            shall stand side by side, two equal parts of one grand whole. We do not recall a thought of
                            the speaker to which we could not respond amen. Just one query would arise in our mind. If
                            you are so strenuous for the right of women to vote, why do you, having that right,
                            habitually decline to exercise it ? The party of progress needs your votes as it does those
                            of women. If you, and all who think with you, (Shakers, Quakers, etc.) were to give it your
                            votes, some of these questions of human rights now at issue, would be settled, and the time
                            would then be ripe for still another advance. So it seems to a man of the world. The house
                            was full, as we understand it is nearly every Sunday, there being twice or three times as
                            many of the "world's people" as of the Shakers. Of the honesty and sincerity of this
                            peculiar people there seems to us no room to doubt. We are under obligations for many
                            courtesies extended duing our stay, subsequent to the meeting. We came away with the feeling
                            that there are many more objectionable ways of spending a Sabbath than in going to the
                            Shaker meeting, and that probably it will not be nineteen years ere we go again."</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why is it?" TEIform="index"/>WHY IS IT?</head><p TEIform="p">A FEW QUESTIONS ASKED — THE NEED OF OUR .COUNTRY TO-DAY. Notice was taken in a recent issue
                            of this paper of the experience of a large shoe manufacturer of this State, who advertised
                            in Boston and New York for twenty-five shoe fitters to work in his factory, offering fall
                            current rates and steady work. The advertisement brought one application. About the same
                            time a Boston firm advertised for a bookkeeper, and the next day's mail brought 347 answers.
                            During the same month an advertisement for a clerk in a Detroit paper brought 130
                            applications the first day and a greater <pb n="215" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 215 »_
                            number of letters and personal applications the next day. An advertisement for a week in the
                            same city, calling for four carpenters, brought only four replies. It is altogether probable
                            that in any considerable city in the land an advertisement for a bookkeeper or retail clerk
                            will bring fifty times as many replies as an advertisement for a workman in any trade. It is
                            also probable that in any and every city the average earnings of clerks are nowhere near so
                            large as the earnings of workmen of average skill in the various trades. Further, it is
                            fairly certain that, with equal capacity, industry and thrift, the young man who learns any
                            trade will achieve a reasonable competence sooner than the young man who sticks to clerking
                            ; while the chances for materially improving one's condition are more numerous in the trades
                            than behind the counter or at the desk. Why is it, then, that the boys all want to be clerks
                            ? Why is it then that intelligent parents encourage them in looking for a chance to " get
                            into business " and in looking down on mechanical employments — as though there could be any
                            calling more wretchedly mechanical than average clerking ? Why is it that teachers almost
                            invariably train their pupils to "look above" mechanical pursuits. What the country wants
                            now is workmen —intelligent, industrious, thrifty workmen ; men who can do skillfully the
                            work that waits for the doing—who can invent new means and better processes for developing
                            the crude resources of the land, and for converting crude matter into life-sustaining and
                            life-enriching wealth. Mere clerks and record keepers are at a discount. There are too many
                            of them. And the professions so called, are almost equally crowded with men who have nothing
                            to do. There never was a time when ability to do somethingreal and practical was worth so
                            much as now. Yet our young men swarm after clerkships. Why is it?— Yates Co. Chronicle.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alas! if the principles are not within us the height of station and worldly grandeur will..." TEIform="index"/>Alas! if the principles are not within us the height of station and worldly grandeur will...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Alas! if the principles are not within us the height of station and worldly grandeur will as
                            soon add a cubit to a man's stature as to his happiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sterne" TEIform="persName"/>Sterne.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beecher on church progress" TEIform="index"/>BEECHER ON CHURCH PROGRESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beecher" TEIform="persName"/>Beecher</byline><p TEIform="p">I have lived to see a great revolution. During my ministry I have seen the time when it would
                            have been preposterous to think of a woman speaking in our churches. But we have overcome
                            the barbarism of that notion. When I became the pastor of this church it would have required
                            all my influence to have prevented the expulsion of a colored man who came in and took a
                            seat here. I have lived to see the colored people not sitting in our churches, but they have
                            become our instructors, they hold office, they sit in Congress, they are admitted to juries
                            and they even ride by our side in the omnibus. It has become my privilege to give notice
                            that a colored sister would give instruction in the missions of this church, and that her
                            work is acknowledged of God and approved of men. This is a great revolution. To have lived
                            to see such a change in regard to the mission of a woman and of a race is to have lived in a
                            glorious day. It has been brought about through much struggle and not a little blood. It is
                            a harbinger and auspicious sign of greater victories in the future.— Tribune.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The danger which threatens the public..." TEIform="index"/>The danger which threatens the public...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The danger which threatens the public sohools — let us be just enough to own it—
                                    proceeds from Protestants more than from Catholics. It is not the Bible in the
                                    schools alone—though that is a specific source of mischief—but what goes with it,
                                    that works the most harm. Sectarianism percolates through school committees and
                                    teachers, and saturates text-books ; and the noisome mist is constantly enveloping
                                    young and plastic minds. It is far more fatal, because it insinuates itself in far
                                    more insidious forms, than Catholic sectarianism.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>The New Age</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pay in kind" TEIform="index"/>Pay in Kind</head><p TEIform="p">—- If thou hast wronged thy brother, in thought, reconcile thee to him in thought ; if thou
                            hast offended him in words, let thy reconciliation be in words ; if thou hast trespassed
                            against him in deeds, by deeds be reconciled to him; that reconciliation is most kindly
                            which*is most in kind. </p></div2><pb n="216" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Giving up evil habits" TEIform="index"/>GIVING UP EVIL HABITS</head><p TEIform="p">We commend the following sensible advice to the consideration of a very important subject.
                            Perhaps, reader, this is the great want of your manhood or womanhood. If applicable to your
                            cases, fail not to accept and to act upon its suggestions: A very thoughtful editorial in a
                            recent issue of the New York Sun calls attention to the high scientific opinion that can be
                            quoted in favor of reducing the passion for intoxicants by the use of vegetable diet instead
                            of meat, i. e., animal food. The experiment, we happen to know, has been made in a loose way
                            in a small institution in England, without any scientific knowledge, and only on general
                            principles, and from observation, and so far it sustains the opinion that vegetable food is
                            less fitted to excite the terrible craving than animal. ]STo country in the world is richer
                            in vegetables than ours. Why should not this point be tested in some of our asylums? The
                            evil is so crying as to render any remedy welcome. Who is willing to give up his evil habits
                            for the sake of preserving future generations from danger? Men toil to acquire property to
                            bequeath to their children, but they never think of restraining their selfish impulses or
                            intemperate desires, that their children may benefit by their restraint. It is a
                            well-understood truth that the children of an habitual drunkard will be inclined to
                            intemperance. Habit becomes second nature, and impresses the mind permanently ; and if a man
                            indulges freely in drinking he excites the hereditary love of liquor in himself, and
                            transmits it with accumulated force to his children. And were it not for the fact that most
                            children were born before their parents had indulged in the degrading appetite to a serious
                            extent, there would scarcely be a sober man found in the community.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth is rich in time..." TEIform="index"/>Truth is rich in time...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Truth is rich in time. It has all the measureless wealth of eternity to use so the multitudes
                            were fed on the the barren seashore, and the fragments gathered up ; little children were
                            blessed tenderly, and the blind beggars made glad with heaven's light in their darkened
                            eyes, while'sin lay like a great pall on the face of humanity and thousands were dying in
                            the darkness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="You cannot escape slander" TEIform="index"/>You Cannot Escape Slander</head><p TEIform="p">. — Let no one suppose that by acting a good part through life he will escape slander. There
                            will be those even who hate them for the very qualities that ought to procure esteem. There
                            are some folks in the world who are not willing that others should be better than
                            themselves.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sin of war" TEIform="index"/>Sin of War</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Diez, Abbie M." TEIform="persName"/>Abbie M. Diez</byline><p TEIform="p">. — We pity the heathen mother, who, ignorant of the gospel of Christ, and having no
                            knowledge of the plan of salvation, throws her child into the Ganges, or willingly sees its
                            young life crushed out beneath the wheels of the car of Juggernaut. And yet these same
                            Christians (?) who weep over her benighted condition, and send missionaries out to labor for
                            her conversion, are themselves bowing down to an idol equally heathenish, and worshiping at
                            a shrine equally bloody. May we not reasonably fear that it may be said of those who teach
                            this bloody religion : "It shall be more tolerable for Sodom and Gomorrah, in the day of
                            judgment, than for you The soldier who fights and dies is less criminal than his religious
                            instructors, who teach that war is in harmony with the gospel, and that death on the battle
                            field is a passport to heaven.— </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rich men" TEIform="index"/>Rich Men</head><p TEIform="p">.'—The following is from a recent sermon delivered by Dr. Beecher : " A man that has become
                            so rich that he don't want to associate any more with those he has been intimate with is in
                            a bad way. He thinks himself too cultured, but the proper way to spell that kind of culture
                            is c-o-n-c-e-i-t. Some men get too good to associate with their fellows. They are so good,
                            so confoundedly good—(laughter)—that they don't want to meet men that are not so ood. For
                            them, nobody prays as they ought, nobody preaches as they ought. They thank God that they
                            are not as other men are, and all the other men thank God that it is so too. (Laughter.)
                            There is a tendency in riches to pamper a man's pride, for with prosperity comes power and a
                            tendency of self will; of this the Scripture says: Seest thou a man wise in his own conceit
                            there is more hope (they didn't pay compliments in ^hose days)— more hope of a fool than of
                            him.' What a hopeless set there are about Brooklyn, and some of them are ere."</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>