<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0710" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18771001" TEIform="date">October 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">73-80</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="73" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. 44 §&gt;o $rencl\ the kin
                        #doin of (§od! *' §[he ttBiiniont) of efornnl h[uth. Vol. YII. G. A. LOMAS, Editor, Shakers, N.
                        Y. OCTOBER, 1877. i N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher, 1 Shaker Village, N. H. No. 10.</p><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boast not" TEIform="index"/>BOAST NOT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>OTIS SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p">Boast not thyself, vain man, oh boast not! For thy life's but a vapor, at best— As the dew of
                            the morning, 'twill vanish away, And thy vesture must lie in the dust. Then seek not for
                            glory—vain pleasure rejectBoast not of thy beauty nor strength ; For the hand of the Lord
                            thy career will detect, And will mete thee strict justice at length. Boast not, vain man, of
                            rank nor of birth— Of one blood are the children of men ! Boast not of thy talents, though
                            they're of great worth, Heaven gave them, they are not thine own. Boast not of thy life, nor
                            thy prospect of age ; Thy sun may go down at noonday; To secure life eternal thy mind should
                            engage, Time is precious, oh do not delay. Earth's boasted joys flit by as a dream, They no
                            lasting comforts afford; But the fiery baptism of Christ, will redeem, 'Twill abide, 'tis
                            Jehovah's own word! Oh boast not of wealth, for at best, 'tis but dross, E'en fine gold will
                            vanish away; But the Pearl of great -price that is gained by the cross, Will endure through
                            an eternal day. West Gloucester, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I'm glad I found the shakers" TEIform="index"/>"I'M GLAD I FOUND THE SHAKERS."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, Jacob" TEIform="persName"/>JACOB KULP</byline><p TEIform="p">When I am asked if the Shakers are the only people that will be saved, I am only able to
                            reply, that Jesus admitted but one door; and that none could come to the Father but by this
                            door—his life.' We cannot make the road of Christ's life any broader ; and he that climbs up
                            any other way, is (German text) "a thief and a murderer!" It was Jesus who warned : "Many
                            false Christs shall come, etc.," but we should be able to judge them by their fruits.
                            W'hatever society bears the best fruits ; whatever people enjoy most salvation, these are
                            the best—nearest to God. Although christened when a child in the Presbyterian church, I grew
                            up a free-thinker; but was anxious to be saved from sin and carnal imperfections I read the
                            good Book through ; becom ing alarmed at the sentence, "He tha sinneth is of the devil!" I
                            believec this, for naught but a wicked spiri would lead any to sin. I thought to join some
                            church. I found none bu admitted they were sinners ; and I hesi tated, because it was the
                            Christian lif —the saved life—that I wanted. And I found none living the life Jesus lived
                            —elders, deacons, ministers nor bishops. I thought I was living as moral a life as any ! Yet
                            I was not satisfied with my life ; nor could any of the pulpits give me relief; though I
                            believed many church people were living up to the best light they knew of. Soon, I found the
                            Shakers, who not only preached about salvation, but lived in it I Here was what I wanted. By
                            the confession and repentance of my sins; by entering into the self-denials of Jesus, and
                            striving to live pure as he was pure, I found saitsfaction to my soul—that "peace" which
                            Jesus said, "I leave with you ! " / am thankful, beyond expression, that I found the Shakers
                            ; and for my gospel call and companions. In the gospel of virgin purity, peace, equality,
                            and freedom from the flesh, I love to live. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great deliverance" TEIform="index"/>THE GREAT DELIVERANCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>WATSON ANDREWS</byline><p TEIform="p">Deep gratitude fills my soul, all my days now, for the precious relationship [ hold with my
                            dear brethren and sisters—whose hearts are warm to the core with a mighty love—filled with a
                            pure, unselfish love, which time changes not, and the long, glad years of eternity can
                            -&gt;ut make brighter and stronger. Unto my soul, in the soft, sweet hush of the
                            morning, comes a thrill of joy at my great deliverance. Once, "I was lost; now I am found ;
                            was dead indeed, but am alive again !" Twenty years of dissipation had plunged me in the "
                            gulf of woe," where I slept, but to dream of coiling serpents and frightful pitfalls; and
                            awakening only to realize a deeper, sadder sense of what I had lost! Then came repentance,
                            tears and cries to God for mercy. And mercy came. Not in that aid which crusaders against
                            the wine-cup can give ; for the pit of my loss was deeper. Not in the solace which pecuniary
                            success affords; for my want was not for gold ! Nor yet in the siren song of a vicarious
                            atonement could I find rest; for it wanted the power to break my chains and to bine my
                            enemy. But it did come in that small, still voice: "Cease to do evil; learn to do well." It
                            came in a knowledge of the followers of Jesus, the Christ, and in a privilege to follow whom
                            they followed. It came through the confession of my sins, accompanied by a power to forsake
                            my sinful ways. By practicing, in a good degree, for many years, the pure life and habits of
                            Christians, I have gained that peace and rest to ray soul which nothing earthly can give,
                            and nothing—but sin—take away. Having neither gold nor silver to offer, I present this, my
                            two-fold experience, to the needy ; hoping by these "footprints on the sands of time," they
                            " seeing, may take heart again," and to realize my great deliverance, " go and do likewise."
                            N. Union, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christianity, the end of the world" TEIform="index"/>Christianity, the End of the World</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">In its popular sense, and as commonly understood, Christianity embraces denominations of
                            professors numbering hundreds. Of these various sects, their theologies all contain some
                            essential Christian principles in common. These are of divine origin; and, since the falling
                            away of the primitive church, and an effort at the revival of Christianity commenced, it may
                            doubtless be truly said that each denomination has been of some benefit to our race, by
                            introducing some phase of Christian doctrines or elements of its principles, which were
                            needed by the human family, but wanting in other testimonies. It was doubtless a
                            consciousness of this need which gave rise to each sect, and its theology ; but we are
                            compelled to affirm that all denominational theologies which stop short of teaching
                            Christianity as the " end of the world," stop short of Christianity. It is universally known
                            that all the popular religions of the day hold the world, with a strong grasp, in the right
                            hand, and, indifferently, the Christian profession in the left; for they universally teach a
                            coalescence of the church and of the world. Yet, that theology alone is Christian which
                            teaches " the harvest of the world." Jesus, the first great Christian, taught "The law and
                            the prophets were until John, since then the kingdom of heaven is preached." "My kingdom is
                            not of this world." "And this gospel of the kingdom shall be preached in all the world, for
                            a witness to all nations, and then shall the end (of the world) come." "The harvest is the
                            end of the world, and the reapers are the angels." And, in answer to the Jews, who inquired
                            of him whose wife of the seven men the woman shall be who had been married to seven
                            husbands, he said: "Ye do err, not knowing the scriptures, nor the power of God, for in that
                            woi'ld (the kingdom of heaven,) they neither marry nor are given in marriage, but are (in
                            this present time,) as the angels of God in heaven." And again : "There are eunuchs who make
                            themselves eunuchs, for the kingdom of heaven's sake." He taught his disciples to pray :
                            "Thy kingdom (the kingdom of heaven,) come, thy will be done on earth as it is done in
                            heaven." If, then, Christ's kingdom —the kingdom of heaven — should ever be established on
                            earth, and, in it God's will should be done as it is done in heaven, and, to those in heaven
                            the end of the worldly life of marriage and its liberties has come, it follows that it must
                            cease in the kingdom-of-heaven order established upon earth. All the foregoing instructions
                            of Jesus synonymously teach "the harvest of the world" come unto all souls who enter into
                            "the kingdom of heaven," or Christ order upon earth. Jesus further taught: "I am the
                            resurrection,"—that is, my life-character is in, and is, the order of the resurrection. Of
                            course, the worldly order of marriage and generation is here at an end. The prophet Isaiah
                            said of Jesus, "Who shall declare his ge?ieration? for his life is cut off from the earth."
                            He had no generation to declare. No comment is needed to show that generation is essentially
                            and necessarily a worldly institution. As such, it cannot be Christian, since Christ's
                            kingdom is not of this world, though necessarily in this world. And the fact must be
                            manifest that all who make themselves eunuchs for the kingdom of heaven's sake, are
                            thenceforth incapable of generation ; their life is cut off from the earthly order. Hence,
                            all efforts to introduce reformed generation into the kingdom of Christ, when its subjects
                            shall have overcome the lusts of a generative life, must be unavailing; for, to these, the
                            end of the world, with all its passional pleasures, and emotional influences, is come, at
                            ence and forever. These constitute the kingdom of heaven. Were man merely an animal, no
                            doubt all his longings and aspirations would be satisfied with a fullness of the pleasures
                            of an animal life ; but human <pb n="74" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER,. history presents the fact,
                            that in all ages, among all classes of human beings, from the wildest natives to the most
                            refined and enlightened of our race, there is an intuition reaching beyond the shores of
                            time, to realms oi pleasure higher than the sensual. An angel nature, born for spirit life,
                            in heavenly spheres, crops out. and yearns for its native Eden ; and heaven, of some ideal
                            character, above earth's provisions, in all ages, has been the seer's vision ; the poet's
                            song ; the soothsayer's amulet; the resting place for the weary ; the sufferer's panacea,
                            and the pilgrim's home. For every field sown, there is an harvest. Generation is the
                            scu:i7ig of the world, regeneration the new birth into the kingdom of heaven ; the
                            resurrection ; are synonymously the elements of this heavenly order, and this order is the
                            harvest of the world. To souls in this order, "there is neither male nor female," in the
                            sexual sense of sensual pleasures, But, in the death such souls die to the worldly life,
                            they are resurrected in a new, angelic life, and, in their relations, increase an hundred
                            fold ; so that unto them is fulfilled the declaration of the prophet Isaiah : "More are the
                            children of the desolate, than of the married wife, saith the Lord." Also, the words of the
                            apostle : "Except a grain of wheat fall into the ground and die, it abideth alone ; but if
                            it die, it bringeth forth much fruit." "Ground" is the element in which the seed is
                            enveloped to die, and figuratively represents the christian's sufferings by the cross,
                            producing death to sinful nature, in order to bring forth fruit unto spiritual life eternal.
                            That is, if souls are baptized into Christ's death unto sin, and to a worldly generative
                            life, they will live in the angelic kingdom-of-heaven order, and spiritually have an
                            hundred-fold relation of fathers, mothers, brothers, sisters, etc. Thus " the harvest of the
                            world," that is, the cessation of generative life, and the institution of virgin celibacy,
                            with its laws of duty in angelic life, is a normal step of human evolution ; it is the
                            narrow gate opening into the kingdom of heaven. This kingdom is the goal to which all
                            religionists aspire ; the inspirational theme of their songs of devotion ; it is the
                            culminating fulfillment of all the prophecies pointing to the latter day; the realization of
                            man's hopes of happiness ; the highest round in the ladder of human progress ! The
                            pre-eminent work Christ came on earth to inaugurate, was to institute the kinsxlom-of-heaven
                            order—the harvest of the world. This work would have been necessary for the perfect
                            evolution of humanity's soul life, had mankind never sinned ; but, in that case, the
                            Christian's work would have been natural and easy ; instead of " the kingdom of heaven
                            suffering violence, and the violent taking it by force," it would have been taken normally,
                            as the succeeding step of man's evolution, pursuant to a legitimate fulfillment of nature's
                            law in generation. Human history reveals to us the fact that all nations and peoples, in all
                            past time, have had an order, or class, of virgin celibates, who have been revered as
                            superior beings, and sought unto as the oracles of divine wisdom and heavenly truth ; thus
                            demonstrating the fact that there is an intuitive perception of a higher life for humanity
                            than the animal, generative sphere ; a knowledge that this earthly order, even in its normal
                            and order!}' exercise, is not the element in which to develop soul life, and the
                            inspirations of the heavens. This requires the harvest of humanity from the worldly stalk ;
                            in other words, Christianity—Shaker ism ! Thus, all religions professing to be Christian,
                            whose theology and lifepractice stop short of virgin celibacy, and a total death to all the
                            passional impulses of a worldly, generative nature, stop short of the harvest of the
                            world—of genuine Christianity. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture. No. 6</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">INDIVIDUALISM.----SOCIALISM. It is not in human nature to ignore one's self. That is not to
                            be wondered at, seeing that in the divine economy so great provision has been made for the
                            individual. "See all things for my use ! " Pope gives as the exclamation of human pride. Yet
                            it contains a glorious truth. The Christian,—to use the language of Cowper, " Appropriates
                            nature as his Father's work; Calls the delightful scenery all his own; His are the
                            mountains, and the valleys his, And the resplendent rivers his to enjoy With a propriety
                            that none else can feel." If the unnumbered worlds in the universe are indicative of the
                            divine power and wisdom, no less so is the fact that the individual man is capable of
                            appropriating and enjoying, one after another, all things contained therein. Beginning with
                            the microcosm on which he dwells, prying into its history, whether of man, animal, rock or
                            vegetable, and developing whatever latent treasures it contains, he makes the whole
                            contribute to his own individual pleasures; partial, it may be, if he is wrapped entirely in
                            self; or unselfish and diffusive, if divine love controlshim in everything. Thence on to the
                            survey of other worlds, where nothing but the limitations of his yet undeveloped powers can
                            check him in his further researches. The individual contains within himself all the
                            faculties comprised by the entire community, and, when rightly and thoroughly developed,
                            these are capable of furnishing him the most exquisite enjoyment. Partial development makes
                            the partial and selfish person : complete development changes the narrow and exclusive
                            individual into the far-seeing and all-loving. There are manv in whom some one or a few
                            faculties are in excess. Such have an inclination to indulge in the excessive gratification
                            of these. To them this indulgence may not appear as it does to others. In their own
                            estimation, they are but gratifying propensities that nature has implanted within them. And,
                            in fact, there are those who maintain that this indulgence is all right. Selfdenial for the
                            sake of a greater good forms no part of their creed. It is enough for them to knowr that
                            nature has acted thus—the authorit}' of nature is all-sufficient. If that partial
                            development were the whole that nature has made known to us, then no reasonable answer could
                            be given. But she teaches many-sided development and growth as emphatically as anything
                            else. Indeed, what is human culture of any and every kind but the result of nature's work in
                            aid of the individual's effort? What could he do without her? If there were no progress of
                            the individual in every age, and of entire communities from age to age, then the grand
                            argument in favor of the Divine Existence and of man's immortality would be nothing. Nature
                            is but the method of working- of God himself, from the partial to the whole, from the lowest
                            to the highest. But the part implies the whole. If the individual has this tendency to
                            indulgence in partial gratification, then selfdenial becomes a paramount duty. Not entire
                            abstinence, but self-restraint. Nature will supplement her own work ii allowed to do so. "
                            Work out your own salvation, for it is God who works in you." This was the teaching of Jesus
                            Christ. "My Father worketh hitherto, and I work." And the grand result oi his self-denying
                            activity was the elevation of himself to the throne where the divine love forever reigns.
                            Christian culture, then, does not ignore the human self-hood, by any means; but it
                            discountenances exclusive devotion to a part, whatever that part may be, in derogation of
                            the whole. It is not sufficient to give heee to the maintenance of sound bodil} health and
                            vigor, to the neglect of the spirit ; nor to the improvement of the intellectual powers, in
                            disparagement of the moral or the afiectional ; noi solely to the cherishing of the
                            affections, because by means of these we are influenced to kindly regard for each other ;
                            nor to what is called the religious or spiritual nature, because that leads us to an
                            especial knowledge of God and heavenly things. Much has been written, and otherwise uttered,
                            in recent years, respecting individual sovereignty. If the individual man is sovereign, he
                            is so only over himself. He may rule over his own spirit, subordinating the inferior to the
                            superior, and seat himself upon the throne of intellectual and moral excellence, where he
                            may be " monarch of all he surveys." But that is a barren domain which consists of but a
                            single province, shut out from access to the thousand sources of wealth and enjoyment in
                            territories that lie all around. It is his right and duty to invade them all. Conquest in
                            such a case is justifiable. Subject them all to one uniform authority, whose government is
                            diviney constitutional.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Land limitation" TEIform="index"/>LAND LIMITATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Frederick W." TEIform="persName"/>FREDERICK W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">When we begin to pile up in cities, as in Europe, we shnll begin to devour one another is
                            they do in Europe.—Thomas Jefferson. Thomas Jefferson, one of the illustrious founders of
                            this Republic, laid it down as a fundamental truth,that land could not beheld as property
                            anymore than we can possess the stars of the firmament, or monopolize the air we breathe. We
                            can hold land only in usufruct. The reason for his position is : land was not created by
                            man—was not the result of his labor—that no individual could lay exclusive claim to any
                            portion of it, and that all men, by virtue of their birth, have an inherent right to the use
                            of it. In England we see to-day the evil results of the violaticn of this radical truth.
                            "When William of Normandy took possession of that country, he claimed sole ownership of the
                            land by right of conquest. He divided the land among his generals and barons, who held it by
                            feudal tenure. The common soldiers became tenants of the lords, and the original inhabitants
                            were reduced to a state of virtual slavery. The church and ecclesiastic owners became large
                            land-owners, many opulent persons upon their death-beds having bequeathed them their
                            property as expiation for their sins. In process of time, the Catholic church held one fifth
                            of the land in England. But, though the land was thus held by comparatively few persons, the
                            poor were not in very bad condition. The land was let on easy terms. Any one who called at
                            the castle of a lord, or at a religious house, was fed with bread and beer—at least all had
                            enough to eat. There were no taverns in those days— hospitality was the rule. The clergy,
                            not having children, used the proceeds of the property entrusted to .their care, to a lai"ge
                            extent, for the benefit of the poor. The reformation gave the Protestant clergy possession
                            of the property previously held by the Catholic church, and from that time common people
                            were debarred the enjoyment of any benefit resulting therefrom. The ecclesiastical revenues
                            were used for the aggrandizement of the upper classes of the English hierarchy. The income
                            which the lords of the church derive to-day from property thus unjustly held from the people
                            is simply enormous. Thousands if not hundreds of thousands are compelled to live under
                            ground, as miners, a life of incessant toil, barely earning subsistence—degraded,
                            down-trodden, abused, till life ceases to be desirable. I do not hold individuals
                            responsible for those things. It is the inevitable result of a vicious system. The Great
                            Napoleon, by confirming the acts of the Revolution, added three millions of | land-holders
                            to the population. The result of that enlightened policy, France, notwith| standing
                            tremendous drains upon her resources in consequence of unsuccessful, disastrous wars, is
                            to-day the most prosperous nation of Europe. When we look at the events of last week— |
                            strikes, riots, disturbances of the peace, reaching from the Atlantic to the Pacific,
                            resulting I in bloodshed and devastation, do we compreihend the cause? Let me tell you,
                            American ; citizens. There is wrong, national wrong, at the bottom. On one side we behold
                            the [strikers demanding bread or blood, indulging in riot and tumult, destroying millions of
                            property, violating law, resisting authority and endangering the peace of the country. On
                            the other side we see capital, enormous monopolies, vast interests controlled byfew men bent
                            upon extending their powers, ! enlarging their possessions, becoming richer at the expense
                            of the common people. That ; such a state of things should exist in Ameri <pb n="75" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 75 ca, among the first and most enlightened peo- c pie on the globe, is
                            surprising as well as de- J plorable. When Charles Bradlaug-h was here a and heard the
                            complaints of mechanics and la- i] borers, and beheld the dissatisfaction existing among the
                            common people, he was out oi ali a patience. "Why," said he, "you have every- c thing that
                            we are fighting for. You have the * ballot, universal suffrage, elect your own officers,
                            make your own laws. You have the x power in your own hands to remedy the evils : you
                            complain of." Are we to suppose that the strikers, who t acted so wildly and blindly for the
                            past week r or two, don't know enough to choose honest ^ legislatures to make just and
                            reasonable laws? Gen. Grant said, "The best way to secure the e repeal of an obnoxious law
                            is to enforce it," ( meaning, of course,that the sovereign people t would elect such
                            legislators as would frame r laws in accord with the wishes of their con- j stituents. The
                            deplorable occurrences of last c week are the natural result of disregard of , radical
                            truth. Unless people examine the cause of things and comprehend the relation ; in which they
                            stand to them, they will have trouble and discord and the wild wave of anarchy will roll
                            over them. Theodore Parker said, "If you indorse radical truths they will drop out at your
                            fingers'ends." When we see men like Stewart, Astor or Vanderbiit becoming so uselessly rich,
                            we will also see hundreds of thousands becoming uselessly poor. We will see strikes
                            convulsing the . country from one end to the other, tramps filling our streets, and hear the
                            dreaded cry oi . "bread or blood," the ominous cry that pre- . ceded the French Revolution.
                            It has been , heard in England—is now heard for the first , time in our country. What will
                            you do with a mass of men who cannot obtain work and , have no bread? Either you must get up
                            a national war, enlist these men and set them to killing each other, or they will kill you.
                            But I think there is a remedy for our present troubles. I mean Land Limitation. Let titles
                            remain as at present. Deprive no one of his rights, but pass a law that after 1878 no one
                            shall acquire more than a certain number of acres of land. And as the present owners of
                            exorbitant tracts die, let the surplus revert to the Government, subject to public sale, or
                            compel the heirs to sell to the legal limit. By this arrangement millions who now crowd the
                            cities would flock to the country and become small land-owners, the equilibrium would be
                            restored, a healthier tone would prevail in the land, and the cry for "blood or bread" would
                            be heard no more. Individuals are not responsible for the present unjust, abnormal state of
                            things. The glorious Declaration of Independence affirmed that "all men are born free and
                            equal, endowed with certain inalienable rights." The Constitutional Convention recognized
                            slavery. This was a compromise between ships and swamps. Massachusetts had ships and wanted
                            the carrying trade ; Carolina had swamps and must have slaves to work them. The sentiments
                            of the Declaration were the advanced ideas of a few men. Every Fourth of July spread-eagle
                            orators reiterated these ideas, until the people were educated up to the Emancipation Act,
                            and amended the Constitution in favor of human liberty. By peaceful and persistent
                            agitation, the public lands became free, the Homestead law passed and imprisonment for debt
                            abolished. I throw out to you the idea of land limitation. I desire you to take hold of it,
                            grasp it, reason, agitate, vote for it, until you incorporate it in your laws. Your wrongs
                            will be righted— there will be bread for all. It will be a move in the right direction. But
                            it should not be your only move. Truth should be yourj guide in every relation of life,
                            social, political and religious. Theological errors have more to do with present
                            complications than many are aware of. People should learn to pbey the truth—to receive truth
                            in the love j of it no matter from what source it comes, 'esus was the most sensational
                            preacher of f ill time. He produced a sensation whenever i ie spoke. He broke away from old
                            estabished customs and systems, and pointed out \ higher and better way. And though his
                            doctrine was revolutionary in the extreme, hie used no violent means to enforce it; on the
                            contrary, He preached and enjoined peace. When rioters give way to violent passions, esist
                            the law of the land and destroy millions of property, they pursue the wrong course to obtain
                            redress for their grievances. To gain the sympathy and respect of the people they must learn
                            peace—must show by their conduct that they are worthy of better conditions —that American
                            citizens are not law-breakers. We must remember that it is written, "There is no peace for
                            the wicked." This itrue of individuals and of nations. All wrongs must be righted until He
                            comes whose right it is to reign, because He shall seek to reign only in righteousness. He
                            that ruleth over man must be just, ruling in the fear of God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker church covenant in two numbers, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER CHURCH COVENANT. IN TWO
                            NUMBERS. NUMBER ONE</head><p TEIform="p">PREAMBLE. We, the Brethren and Sisters of the United Society of Believers (called Shakers),
                            residing in the county of--------, and state of --------, being connected together as a
                            religious and social community, distinguished by the name and title of the Church of the
                            United Society, in the town of--------, which for many years has been established and in
                            successful operation, under the charge of the Ministry and Eldership thereof, and, feeling
                            the importance not only of renewing and confirming our spiritual covenant with God and each
                            other, but also of renewing and improving our social compact, and amending the written form
                            thereof, do make, ordain, and declare the following articles of agreement as a summary of
                            the principles, rules and regulations established in the Church of the said United Society,
                            which are to be kept and maintained by us, both in our collective and individual capacities,
                            as a covenantor constitution, which shall stand as a lawful testimony of our religious and
                            social compact, before all men, and in all cases of question and lawrelating to the
                            possession and improvement of our united and consecrated interest, property, and estate :
                            .ARTICLE I. Of the Gospel Ministry. Section i. Their origin, call and institution : We
                            solemnly declare to each other and to all whom it may concern, that we have received, and do
                            hereby acknowledge as the foundation of our faith, order and government, the testimony or
                            Gospel of Christ, in his first ^nd second appearing, and we do hereby solemnly agree to
                            support and maintain the true primitive faith and Christain principles, the morals,rules and
                            manners pertaining to the said Gospel, as ministered by the founders of this Society, and
                            kept and conveyed through a regular order of ministration, down to the present day. And,
                            although, as a religious society, we are variously associated, with respect to the local
                            situations of our respective communities, yet we are known and distinguished as a peculiar
                            people, and consider and acknowl' edge ourselves as members of one general : community,
                            possessing one faith, and subject to one united, parental and ministerial ad| ministration,
                            which has been regularly sup' ported from the first foundation pillars of the ; Institution,
                            and which continues to operate for the support, protection and strength of ' t every part of
                            said community. ;i Section 2. Their order and office; We further acknowledge and declare
                            that a for the purpose of promoting and maintain- s ing union, order and harmony throughout
                            n he various branches of this community, the c primary administration of parental authority
                            b las been settled in the first established Ministry at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., there to rest
                            and s remain as the center of union to all who are a n Gospel relation and communion with
                            the Society. The established order of this Minstry includes four persons; two of each sex.
                            Section 3. Perpetuity of their office and low supplied : C We further acknowledge and
                            declare that he said primary administration of parental t luthority has been and is
                            perpetuated as fol- 1 ows : Namely, that the first in that office t and calling possesses
                            the right given by the f sanction of divine authority, through the first f bunders of this
                            Society, to prescribe or di- e ¦ect any regulation or appointment which "\ ;hey may judge
                            most proper and necessary t respecting the Ministry or any other import- j: ant matter which
                            may concern the welfare of c the Church, subsequent to their decease. I But in the case no
                            such regulation or ap- s pointment be so prescribed or directed, then t the right to direct
                            and authorize such regulation and appointment devolves upon the ( surviving members of the
                            Ministry, in council with the Elders of the Church, or others, ( as the nature of the case
                            in their judgment 1 may require. Such appointments being of- £ ficially communicated to all
                            concerned, and t receiving the general approbation of the Church, are confirmed and
                            supported in the Society. i This is agreeable to the example recorded i in the Scriptures,
                            and continued by the found- s ers of this Society, and is the order and man- t ner which has
                            been regularly practiced, ac- t knowledged, and maintained in the Commu- | nity from the
                            beginning. 1 Section 4. Of the ministerial office in the 1 several societies or communities
                            : t We further acknowledge and declare, cove- i nant and agree that the Ministerial office
                            and authority in any Society or Community of 1 our faith, which has emanated, or which may
                            emanate, in a regular line of order from 1 the center of union aforesaid, is, and shall be i
                            acknowledged, owned and respected, as the spiritual and primary authority of such Soci- ;
                            etv or Community, in all matters pertaining |: to the Ministerial office. And in case of the
                            : decease or removal of any individual of said Ministry, in any such Society, his or her lot
                            and place shall be filled by agreement of the surviving Ministers, in council with the
                            Elders and others, as the nature of the case may require, together with the knowledge and
                            approbation of the primary ministerial authority at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., aforesaid, to which
                            they are responsible. Section 5. Powers and duties of the Ministry : The Ministry being
                            appointed and established as aforesaid are vested with the primary authority of the Church
                            and its various branches. Hence, it becomes their special duty to guide and superintend the
                            spiritual concerns of the Society as a body of people under their care and government, and
                            in connection with the Elders in their respective families and departments, who shall act in
                            union with them, to give and establish such orders, rules and regulations as may be found
                            necessary for the government and protection of the Church and Society within the limits of
                            their jurisdiction, and also to counsel, advise ¦ and judge in all matters of importance, I
                            whether spiritual or temporal. The said t Ministry are also invested with authority in .
                            connection with the Elders as aforesaid, to . nominate and appoint to office Ministers, 1 ;
                            Elders, Deacons, and Trustees, and to assign i\offices of care and trust to such brethren
                            and j f!sisters as they, the said Ministry and Elders,! I shall judge to be best qualified
                            for the several offices to which they may be appointed; and we do hereby covenant and agree
                            that such nominations and appointments being nade and officially communicated to those
                            concerned, and receiving the general approoation of the Church, or of the families
                            concerned, shall thenceforth be confirmed and supported, until altered or revoked by the
                            authority aforesaid. ARTICLE II. Institution of the Church. Section i. The object and design
                            of Church relation : We further acknowledge and declare that the great object, purpose and
                            design of our uniting ourselves together as a church or body of people, in social and
                            religious compact, is faithfully and honestly to occupy, improve and diffuse the various
                            gifts and talents, both of a spiritual and temporal nature, with which Divine wisdom has
                            blest us, for the service of God, for the honor of the Gospel, and for the mutual
                            protection, support, comfort and happiness of each other as brethren and sisters in the
                            Gospel, and for such other pious and charitable purposes as the Gospel may require. Section
                            2. Who are not admissible into Church relation : As the unity, stability and purity of the
                            Church essentially depend on the character and qualifications of its members, and as it is a
                            matter of importance that it should not be encumbered with persons who are under any
                            involvement or incapacity, natural or moral: Theiefore, no member of any company or
                            association in business or civil concern, no co-partner in trade, no person under any legal
                            embarrassment or obligations of service, no minor, no slave nor bond servant, no insane
                            person, no profane person, nor any person who lives in the willful violation of the known
                            and acknowledged principles of moral conduct, shall be deemed qualified for admission into
                            the covenant relation and communion of the Church. Section 3. Preparation for admission into
                            Church relation : In order that believers may be prepared for entering into the sacred
                            privilege of Church relation, it is of primary importance that sufficient opportunity and
                            privilege should be afforded under the Ministry of the Gospel, I for them to acquire
                            suitable instruction in the genuine principles of righteousness, honesty, justice and true
                            holiness, and also that they should prove their faith and Christian morality by their
                            practical obedience to the precepts of the Gospel according to their instructions. It is
                            also indispensably necessa; ry for them to receive the one uniting spirit . of Christ, and
                            to become so far of one heart and one mind, that they are willing to sacrifice all other
                            relations for this sacred one. '. Another essential step, is to settle all just and
                            equitable claims of creditors and filial ¦ heirs, so that whatever property they may ¦
                            possess, shall be justly their own. When ; this is done, and they feel themselves
                            sufficiently prepared to make a deliberate and final choice, to devote themselves, with all
                            ; they possess, wholly to the service of God, - without reserve, and it shall be deemed
                            prop. er by the leading authority of the Church, after examination and due consideration, to
                            1 allow them to associate together in the ca5 pacity of a Church, or a branch thereof in I
                            Gospel order, they may then consecrate ; themselves and all they possess to the service f of
                            God forever, and confirm the same by ; signing and sealing a written covenant pred, icated
                            upon the principles herein contained, i and fulfilling, on their part, all its obligaI1
                            tions. ) Section 4. Admission of new members: As the door must be kept open for the adi|
                            mission of new members into the Church, i I when duly prepared, it is agreed that each , I
                            and every person who shall at any time after -the date and execution of the Church Cove; j
                            nant, in any branch of the Community, be <pb n="76" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 76 THE SHAKER. admitted into
                            the Church as a member thereof, shall previously have a fair opportunity to obtain a full,
                            clear and explicit understanding of the object and design of the Church Covenant, and of the
                            obligations it enjoins upon the members. For this purpose, he or she shall, in the presence
                            of two of the deacons or acting trustees of the Church, read, or hear the same distinctly
                            read, so as to be able freely to acknowledge his or her full approbation and acceptance
                            thereof, in all its parts. Then he, she or they (as the case may be), shall be at liberty to
                            sign the same; and having signed and sealed it, and being subject to all the obligations
                            required of the original signers shall thenceforth be entitled to all the benefits and
                            privileges thereunto appertaining; and the signature or signatures thus added shall be
                            certified by the said deacons or trustees, together with the date thereof. Section 5.
                            Concerning youth and children : Youth and children, being minors, cannot be received as
                            members of the Church possessing a concentrated interest in a united capacity, yet it is
                            agreed that they may be received under the immediate care and government of the Church, at
                            the desire or consent of such person or persons as have a lawful right to or control of such
                            minors, together with their own desire or consent. But no minor under the care of the Church
                            can be employed therein for wages of any kind. ARTICLE III. Of the Trusteeship. Section i.
                            Appointment, qualifications and powers of Trustees : It has been found necessary for the
                            establishment of order in the Society in its various branches, that superintending Deacons
                            and Deaconesses should be appointed and authorized to act as Trustees or agents of the
                            temporalities of the Church. They must be recommended by honesty and integrity, their
                            fidelity in trust and their capacity for the transaction of business; of these
                            qualifications the Ministry and Elders must be judges. The official Trustees of the Church
                            are generally known among us by the title of Office Deacons, of which there must be tzvo or
                            more; and being appointed by the authority aforesaid, they are invested with power to take
                            the general charge and oversight of all the property, estate and interest, dedicated,
                            devoted, consecrated and given up for the benefit of the Church ; to hold in trust the fee
                            of all the lands belonging to the Church; also all gifts, grants and donations which have
                            been, or may hereafter be dedicated, devoted, consecrated and given up as aforesaid; and the
                            said property, estate, interest, gifts, grants and donations shall constitute the united and
                            consecrated interest of the Cnurch, and shall be held in trust by the said Deacons, as
                            acting Trustees, in their official capacity, and by their successors in said office and
                            trust forever. Section 2. Duties of the Trustees : It is and shall be the duty of the said
                            Deacons or acting Trustees to improve, use and appropriate the said united interest for the
                            benefit of the church in ail its departments ; and for such other religious and charitable
                            purposes as the Gospel may require; and also to make all just and equitable defence in law
                            for the protection and security of the consecrated and united interest, rights and
                            privileges of the Church and Society, jointly and severally as an associated community, as
                            far as circumstances and the nature of the case may require ; Provided, nevertheless, that
                            all the transactions of the said Deacons oracting Trustees, in the use, management,
                            protection, defense and disposal of the aforesaid interest, shall be for the benefit and
                            -privilege and in behalf of the Church or Society as aforesaid ; and not for any private
                            interest, object or fnrfose tvhatevcr. Section 3. Trustees to give information and be
                            responsible to the Ministry and Elders : It shall also be the duty of the Trustees to give
                            information to the Ministry and Elders of the church of the general state of the temporal
                            concerns of the church and society committed to their charge; and also to report to the said
                            authority all losses sustained in the united interest thereof, which shall come under their
                            cognizance. And no- disposal of any real estate of the Church, nor any important contract
                            shall be considered valid without the previous approbation of the authority aforesaid, to
                            whom the said Deacons and Trustees are and shall, at all times., be held res$07isible in all
                            their transactions. Section 4. Books of account and record to be kept: It shall also be the
                            duty of the Deacons or acting Trustees to keep or cause to be kept, regular books of
                            account, in which shall be entered the debt and credit accounts of all mercantile operations
                            and business transactions between the Church and others; all receipts and expenditures,
                            bonds, notes and bills of account, and all other matters that concern the united interest of
                            the church ; and also a book or books of records, in which shall be recorded a true and
                            correct copy of this Covenant; also all appointments, removals and changes in office of
                            Ministries, Elders, Deacons and Trustees; all admissions, removals departure and decease of
                            members, together with all other matters and transactions of a public nature which are
                            necessary to be recorded for the benefit of the Church, and for the preservation and
                            security of the documents, papers and written instruments pertaining to the united interest
                            and concerns of the church, committed to their charge. And the said record shall be annually
                            inspected by the leading authority of the church, who. together with the Trustees, shall be
                            the official auditors of the same; and the signature of one or more of said auditors, with
                            the date of inspection and approval shall be deemed sufficient authority for the correctness
                            and validity of the facts and matters so recorded. Section 5. Trustees to execute a
                            declaration of trust: For the better security of the united and consecrated interest of the
                            Church to the proper uses and purposes stipulated in this covenant, it shall be the duty of
                            the Trustee or Trustees, who may be vested with the lawful title or claim to the real estate
                            of the Church, to make and execute a declaration of trust, in due form of law embracing all
                            and singular the lands, tenements and hereditaments, with every matter of interest
                            pertaining to the Church which at the time being" may be vested in him or them, or that may
                            in future come under his or their charge of office, during his or their said Trusteeship.
                            The said declaration shall state expressly that the said Trustee or Trustees hold all such
                            lands, tenements or hereditaments, and all the personal property of every description
                            belonging to the Church or Society, in trust for the uses and purposes expressed in and
                            subject to the rules, conditions and regulations prescribed by the covenant and constitution
                            of the said Church or Society, or any amendments thereto which shall hereafter be adopted by
                            the general approbation of the Church, and in conformity with the primitive faith and
                            acknowledged principles of the Society. And the said declaration shall be in writing, duljr
                            executed under his or their hands and seal;:, and shall be recorded in the Book of Records
                            provided for in the preceding section. # Section 6. Vacancies in certain cases; how supplied
                            : We further covenant and agree that in case it should at any time happen, in the course of
                            Divine Providence that the office of Trustees should become wholly vacant,'by the death or
                            defection of all the Trustees in whom may be vested the fee of the lands or real estate
                            belonging to said Church or Society, then, and in that case, one or more successors shall be
                            appointed by the constitutional authority recognized in this Covenant, according to the
                            rules and regulations prescribed by the same. And the said appointment, being duly recorded
                            in the Book of Records, provided for in this article, shall be deemed, and is hereby
                            declared to vest in such successor or successors all the rights, interest and authority of
                            their predecessors, in respect to all such lands,property or estate belonging to the Church
                            or Society as aforesaid.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>Epitomic History of the
                            Watervliet Shakers. No. 6</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">TEMPERANCE. Some time previous to the excitement created by the lectures of Sylvester Graham
                            and others concerning diet, or " Temperance in eating and drinking" especially in the use of
                            "ardent spirits," Believers, who had been in the habit of making more or less use of them,
                            had been very much awakened on the same subject, and had fully come to the conclusion that
                            it Was a useless habit, and unitedly resolved to abstain therefrom. Consequently, each and
                            every family and society of Believers east and west, rejected, totally, the use of ardent
                            (Shakers,) wholly and spirits, excepting as these might be used as medicine, under the
                            direction and control of physicians who had the immediate care of the same. This system of
                            strict temperance has been punctually carried out in the practical life of every genuine
                            Shaker for nearly forty years. All wines, and stimulating drinks of every name and nature,
                            were rejected ; even strong beer and cider, with tea and coffee, did not escape being
                            brought under stringent rules favorable to temperance. On this general ground of abstinence
                            from all kinds of ardent beverages, the Shakers have taken a prominent stand, setting an
                            example worthy of imitation. The increasing interest and labors manifest in the world,
                            respecting this very important subject, are highly commendable, and by us greatly
                            appreciated. We bless the earnest feelings— the very many trials and exertions that have
                            been, and still are being made by temperance men and women, who seem greatly engaged, using
                            their utynost influence to bring about a change—a radical change in the world, concerning
                            this matter. They are most worthy acts of true benevolence. Temperance meetings — individual
                            pledges—public lectures, and the many resolutions adopted in behalf of Reform throughout the
                            world, have done, and still are doing much good, especially among that class where poverty
                            and want have made their inroads, and dissipation and intemperance stamped their ruin. We
                            say, Lord speed the time when excesses of all kinds shall ceasecause they are not in
                            immediate fellowship with the world in all things, let us examine the matter a little, and
                            in addition to, as well as in connection with what we have already stated in past numbers of
                            The Shaker, respecting our institution, take the following: It is not so much in the
                            external or physical development of our being that we claim to be the most zealously
                            engaged—as the soul is much more important to us than the body—yet we have done something
                            for this even, and are daily doing what we are able for the further advancement of both soul
                            and body in the right direction, as we think. The Shakers have made one great sacrifice,
                            which the world of mankind in general have hardly attempted, further than to advocate the
                            idea, giving it a favorable recommendation. It is the total rejection of swine's flesh.
                            Believers—Shakersuse for nearly -have abstained from its thirty years ! and many when all
                            wrongs shall be righted—and slaves thereunto? truth and honesty bear universal sway. But as
                            some are inclined to think that individuals among us for a much longer time. We consider
                            ourselves far better without it than formerly with it. The salutary effects are visible. No
                            kinds of animal food are so profusely eaten by us now as formerly ; and the vegetable and
                            fruit kingdoms supply its place. We think we are less subject to fevers and consumptive
                            diseases; and therefore feel amply rewarded for the seeming great sacrifice. About forty
                            years ago, smoking and chewing tobacco were very much practiced among the members of our
                            community, especially by the aged. But light from the heavens illuminated the minds and
                            reached the understandings of many of us, to that degree, that being convinced of their
                            deleterious effects on the human system, they were almost unanimously rejected. Some persons
                            among us who had been in the habit of using tobacco for ten, twenty, and even fifty or more
                            years, resolutely set their faces against it evermore. And although there are some few who
                            still indulge in the foul habit, yet it is hoped the day is not far distant wThen it will be
                            wholly discarded and driven from our midst. Many that use" it, condemn it, and declare it to
                            be a useless and a very nasty practice, or habit; and yet they have not the manhood nor
                            selfcontrol requisite to its full renunciation. But such persons often talk largely about
                            reform and universal progression in other things, and sometimes even in this ! But let those
                            who favor reform in any point whatever, manifest it by example, and it wrill assuredly have
                            a better effect—being more graciously receivedPhysicians and others, who have written upon
                            the subject of tobacco and its use, call it a hurtful and poisonous weed—injurious to health
                            and life— from the use of which its votaries can derive little or no benefit. Then why so
                            many continue to be, as it were, We have found, by experience, that the better and more
                            ready way of breakthe Shakers are far behind the age, be-j ing loose from wrong or vile
                            habits of <pb n="77" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. any kind, is to summon them before us —look them
                            fairly and fully in the face —examine and cross-examine, and then resolve and re-resolve we
                            will no longer be slaves to our "baser passions" or depraved appetites, but that we will
                            conquer, whatever be the cost. Now let all who are in favor of reform in society, and wish
                            to make men and women better, consider that an example of temperance in all things is the
                            best and loudest preaching in the world, and that physical and moral rectitude are the very
                            step-stones to a religious life in Christ. "Let your light so shine before men that they may
                            see your good works and glorify your Father in heaven." Note.—I would here briefly remark
                            that, in the August number of The Shaker, Vol. VII., page 59, inan article on "Agricultural,
                            and other Improvements," in speaking of the "Improved Shaker Washing Machine," it was there
                            stated as being an invention of the Society at Shaker Village, N. H., which is a mistake. It
                            originated in the Society at Mount Lebanon, N. Y., and was used by them many years previous
                            to its being patented. The Society at Shaker Village, after having made considerable
                            improvements upon the original, in agreement with the originators thereof, got it patented
                            with their improvements. As I have only given in part the inventions of other Societies, I
                            hope by what I have stated on the subject of inventions, to call forth in The Shaker a true
                            statement from each Society for themselves.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming compunctions, confessions, and rependance" TEIform="index"/>The Coming Compunctions,
                            Confessions and Repentance</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">"At the time of the appearance of Christianity, a crisis took place in the development of
                            humanity, which may be described as the commencement of spiritual life. The change was not
                            abrupt, it had been preceded by the increasing spirituality of the Hebrew" faith through
                            prophetic teachings, and the genera! expectation of a Messiah. — Gold-win Smith. Two hundred
                            years preceding the second appearance of Christ, extraordinary preparations for that event
                            took place. First, the Reformation ; which broke the power of the Roman church. Second, the
                            appearance and power of the Puritans. Third, the spiritual life and influence of the
                            Quakers. Fourth, the prophetic teachings, life, and zeal of the French prophets. They
                            declared that the kingdom of heaven was at hand. Fifth, great activity of thought, and
                            extraordinary facilities for its expression and distribution. Compunction, Confession and
                            Repentance for sin, ushered in the first Christian dispensation, and brought forth a church
                            having all things in common. Compunction, operating in the same manner, ushered in the
                            second appearing of Christ, and brought forth a church wherein no man says that anything is
                            his. Churches made up of rich and poor are not Christian ; lacking in brotherly equality and
                            love. Compunction is inherent in our consciousness, and when moved upon by the holy spirit,
                            arrests man in his downward paths, elevates him above his animal selfhood, and unfolds the
                            divinity within him. Modifications of this force have in all ages been operative to prevent
                            society from sinking into degradation. And during human history, has been, and ever will be
                            operative, as a central force of elevation. The time is drawing on for compunction to begin
                            to operate on millions, as it did on Jesus, and on Ann Lee. He was touched so deeply, that
                            he solemnly declared and felt, that every idle word must be repented of. By the power of
                            compunction, he rose into a righteousness and life which the dispensation of Moses could not
                            give. He rose—was resurrected above his animal desires and emotions, into loves and a life
                            which the Father could love and own. So Ann Lee, under the same power, gave herself no rest
                            till she felt purged from the slightest animal emotion or desire. Every true child of hers
                            will do likewise. Even our eyes must be purged from lust, and sanctified. The experience of
                            our people has affirmed, that in the degree that individuals come under the power of
                            compunction, confession and repentance, they stand resurrected, as did Jesus, and become
                            Saviors, as he was. Wholesale confessions bring no deliverance ; the smallest faults must
                            all appear, and be repented of. The interior life of Jesus taught him, that which had been
                            done in secret must be brought to light. Mother Ann Lee, from her experience, also testified
                            in the most solemn manner, "that the smallest sin unconfessed, would shut the soul out from
                            God." There is a meaning in " Crucify the old man, ivitk all his affections, and all his
                            lusts. Be not conformed to the world, but transformed in the spirit of your minds." On the
                            tablet of our consciousness, is the record of our lives —a daybook, wherein deeds, words,
                            emotions and desires are impressed; and from time to time, there are interior calls to
                            settle accounts. The quickening of the higher life in man, with concurrent associations and
                            conditions, exalting and opening the spiritual faculties in humanity, has been the
                            foundation of all new dispensations of truth, and elevations of life. Doubtless the Mosaic
                            era was introduced at the right time and place. It is a system of life, law and government,
                            which, when stripped of all extraneous attachments, recommends itself now, and will through
                            the coming ages. Obedience to its requirements will ever be the law of all true progress.
                            "Heaven and earth may pass away, but not one jot of hygienic or moral law, shall pass, till
                            all shall : be fulfilled." The person who will keep ; these laws, will be called great in
                            the kingdom of heaven. But he or she, who may have a place in the second appearing of
                            Christ, who knowingly will break in any degree, or by their influence countenance vio¦
                            lators of hygienic or moral law, will be the least in that kingdom. For the darkness of ¦
                            night is past, and the day has come, to accomplish the prophecy : "I will put my law in
                            their inward parts, and write it on their hearts." This now, is with some, an accomplished
                            fact. The Mosaic system was but in part the law written on the heart, will have a wider
                            application than it had in Jewry. As the unfoldment of the spiritual in humanity opened, the
                            fullness of time came, when the revelation of the Christ became possible. Had there been no
                            preparation under John the Baptist, no quickening of the conscience, the materialist
                            Sadducee,the staid, pompous Pharisee, would not have come to John with feelings of
                            compunction. Their day of judgment, in part, had come; all souls will likewise be so
                            overtaken. So universal was the awakening in city and country, "that they of Jerusalem, all
                            Judea, and round about Jordan, went to John confessing their sins." This exaltation and
                            quickening was the foundation of the first Christian dispensation. Jesus felt, and honored
                            the general movement, and went also to John with those who came to be released from their
                            burdens of condemnation. Jesus, on opening his life, was by John refused baptism, on the
                            ground that his mission was not applicable—did not reach the condition of Jesus Christ.
                            Hence John honestly confessed, "I have need to be baptized of thee." Hereby testifying, that
                            in Jesus, a higher dispensation than the Mosaic had begun—a higher life and truths than were
                            cognizable by the Mosaic life or laws. So of the founder of our own order. The quickness of
                            her discernment of evil placed her before her teachers. A little band led by Jane and James
                            Wardley, had risen from the Quakers, and held to confessing all known sin, answered the
                            initiatory experience of Mother Ann ; but not resting there, the power of compunction led
                            her to a deeper examination of the workings and tendencies of human nature, and to a
                            corresponding cross, hourly, and momentarily to be borne against impure emotions,
                            selfishness and pride. Her sufferings of spirit were very great; she felt humbled in the
                            dust; so alive and intent was she to purify herself from the least contamination of evil,
                            that she in her abasement rose above her teachers, and ministered to them the elements of a
                            higher life than they had attained to. Although the ministrations of Mother Ann were keen
                            and cutting to severity against everything unclean ; yet her spirit was filled with love.
                            Even as the cleansing waters of compunction overflowed in her being, as do the waters of the
                            Jordan, so also in her, did the river of divine love overflow, while she baptized all
                            willing souls, with fire to burn up the old creation of Adam and Eve withir. them ; and with
                            the holy spirit, create them into sons and daughters of God. With Mother Ann this was not a
                            momentary effusion, but a continued life manifestation. Her everanxious and earnest desire
                            was, that others might have life in themselves, even as she had. So creative and heavenly
                            was her love. that "Mother" was the name spontaneously accorded her. Those who are baptized
                            into purity of life, abnegation of self, and into the newness of the higher life as she was,
                            delight now to call her Mother. Her natural brother, . a powerful young man, coming to her
                            baptism, exclaimed, " She is my Mother, yet she is my sister!" The brotherly equality of the
                            Pentecostal church has rarely been approached, never surpassed. The church of the second
                            appearing, after being in the crucible of time one hundred years, can be seen, quietly
                            "pursuing the even tenor of her way." A virgin life—circumcision of heart—her line of
                            separation from an unclean world; dispensing to all within her fold, the loves and blessings
                            of the higher life. The externals of which, are equality of condition, and the elevation oi
                            woman; placing her with man, as a component of government, judicial and executive. Ennobling
                            labor, and the laborer; freeing him from being a commodity—slave-like—in the market of
                            supply and demand. "I will make a man (not the procreative man) more precious than fine
                            gold." Ye men and women of mind, and of noble impulses; who seek the enfranchisement of
                            woman, the abolition of land monopoly, and of systems of finance as old as Egyptian
                            darkness, and as cruel as was its bondage. Look down the avenues of time. Gather up the
                            high-sounding constitutions, with preambles of "glittering generalities." Did not Solon the
                            first, embod3' slavery in his republic? Did not Plato dream of the same? Was he not
                            exclusive? "Let none enter here but geometers."' Have the modern Solons done any better? Are
                            not all hired men virtually slaves ? And, when worn out, or their labor not in demand, are
                            they not set aside as you would a handful of rags? Do not the inequalities of human
                            conditions to-day, rival those I of ancient heathen civilizations, while the productive
                            forces of our times are much greater? Are not the commandments of God. moral and hygienic,
                            set at naught when interest, appetite or passion present themselves? By compunction and
                            contrition, "Come out of her my people. Be not partakers of her sins, and that ye receive
                            not of her plagues."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Water baptism—is dancing as worship authorized by the scriptures?—marriage—was Ann Lee a divine teacher?" TEIform="index"/>WATER BAPTISM.—IS DANCING AS WORSHIP AUTHORIZED BY THE SCRIPTURES?—MARRIAGE.—WAS ANN
                                LEE A DIVINE TEACHER?</head><p TEIform="p">H-, Ind., Aug. 1st, 1877. George B. Amery : Kind Friend:—I promised to write to you, and
                                even if I had not, still I should have written, not only be; wanted a little more
                                information, but because I again must thank yon for your kindness. When I left your
                                happy home my feelings were akin to those of the poor traveler who has left the green
                                oasis far behind, and who wearily takes his way. He remembers, parched with thirst as he
                                is, the running streams of that green place; and while the sun beats dOAvn upon him, he
                                thinks of the shade of the palm trees left far behind. You remember, doubtless, how the
                                people of Israel, after toilsome inarches, came to Elam where grew " two and thirty "
                                palms; just so, my friend, ! came to your home. I was weary, and I rested. Friend
                                George, I do not suppose that you have been a wanderer such as I, and of course you
                                cannot know what heavy loads of grief oppress my laboring heart. I am one who has been a
                                wanderer all ray life, and while I have met many who pretended friendship, still I have
                                found hardly one whose words were proved to be true by their actions. I have been
                                looking with a hungry heart for true friends, and I fear I shall look a long time among
                                the people of the world. I would not have you set me down as a dealer in "mawkish
                                sentiments; " I am not. I do not believe in lovejis most people do. Love, I hold to be
                                lov ihould have not one graiu of self in it. If I loved a woman, and I knew or thought
                                that she would be happier as the wife of another man, I should endeavor to secure that
                                happiness for her. This is what the world "iils insanity, but what I with my smaller
                                views call love in the first degree. Now T am going to ask you several questions, and I
                                hope you will answer them. Most men are touchy on their doctrines, but I know you are
                                not, so here goes. 1. How do you get rid of water baptism, when Christ in his
                                conversation with Nicodemus said, "you must be born of water and of the Spirit?" 2. Did
                                Christ or God, or any one regarded as a readier. rncing as an act"of worship"? 3. Since
                                God said it was not good for man to be alone (meaning of course that it was not good for
                                a man to be without a wife), md si ce he commanded them to multiply and replenish the
                                earth, is it not going directly againstthe revealed will of God not to marry? Now,
                                friend George, I want clear answers, Biblical answers, if you please. And now, one more:
                                How will you prove, how do you prove, that Mother Ann was gifted with the Spirit of
                                Christ? If I can be satisfied that your people are living up to the law, there is iso
                                people on earth that I would prefer over you to be one of. Your females are innocent as
                                children; your men, men of honor. You are charitable, but are you in the right track?
                                Accept my thanks again for your kindness. I hope you Mill not leave this unanswered. It
                                is written in a hurry, without much thought. I pray you answer me, and the next time I
                                write I will do better. Until then, believe me, I am Yours kindly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., G. W." TEIform="persName"/>G. W. B—</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder G. W. B—, H—, Indiana:" TEIform="index"/>ELDER G. W. B-----, II-----, Indiana :</head><p TEIform="p">Esteemed Friend:—Your kind letter of Aug. 1st came safely to hand, and was read with
                                pleasure. I was really pleased to hear that you had been able to "feel the spirit" of
                                the people here. You but give expression to the feelings of tens of thousands of our
                                fellow-men, when you say your "heart is hungry for true friends." Your idea of love is a
                                very high type of natural love, which would bless humanity to realize. But that day is
                                yet afar off. Iain perforce compelled to be very brief with my notice of the first part
                                of your letter, in order to answer somewhat in detail the four questions you put. You
                                say, "Friend George, I want clear answers, Biblical answers." Let me tell you here a
                                story to the point in answer to your request for Biblical answers. Upon invitation 1
                                once attended a meeting of ¦ious sect called " soul sleepers, " or " annihilationists,"
                                who possessed bo great reverence for the literal scriptures, that they interrupted me
                                when I was answering one of their questions, and told me they wanted nothing
                                earthly—they wanted nothing but the clear, unperverted "Word of God." I took Paul's
                                Corinthian and other epistles, and plied so hot and heavy his denunciations of
                                uncleanness, and lowness of the "well," as compared with the "better state," that they
                                were soon t;o warm as to attempt to depart from the strict letter, and rise to explain;
                                but I stopped them by holding them with exasperating firmness and pertinacity to their
                                own request. Hold! nothing but the pure "Word of God." Probably you will ask, where is
                                the application? You left a work, one fourth or more of which is an argument of one of
                                your ablest reasoners on the subject of Baptism. Had lie confined himself to the un77
                                    <pb n="78" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 78 THE SHAKER. perverted "Word of God," all the scriptures
                                could have been written on quite a small sheet. Though my answers, to your mind, may not
                                seem Biblical, I do not at all fear making them plain and clear. Question 1: " How do
                                yon get rid of water baptism, when Christ in his conversation with Nicodemus says.
                                'Except a man be born of water and the Spirit he cannot enter into the kingdom of God.'
                                " Your quotation is from the 3d of John, in which, from the 1st to the 22d verse, the
                                interview and conversation are described. We think a careful reading of the text will
                                convince you that your application oi this to water baptism is quite a forced one. From
                                the 1st to the 22d verge not once does this word "baptism" occur in any shape or form.
                                Kead the 7th and 8th verses in the chapter following. In John iv: 14, a very striking
                                and beautiful definition of the water here spoken of is given as follows: "But whosoever
                                drinketh of the water that I shall give him shall never thirst; but the water that I
                                shall give him shall be in him, a well of water springing up into everlasting life." A
                                loveiy description of the process of being "born again," and its progressive
                                character—"a well of water springing up into everlasting life," causing individuals so
                                baptized to become like Whittier's "Cloud," which " Shall, with beams of fight from the
                                inner glory, Be stricken through." It is said that Jesus himself baptized not, but his
                                disciples. But that it will not do in every respect to follow the example of his
                                disciples, one circumstance alone will demonstrate sufficiently, i. e., thatof Paul's
                                circumcising Timothy. And further, even Jesus himself observed many of the Jewish
                                customs which he never enjoined upon his followers to keep. How true it is that people
                                "strain at gnats auu swallow camels." Matt. iii. 6, reads, speaking oj John, "and were
                                baptized of him in Jordan, confessing their sins." The people manifest a great deal oi
                                tenacity in holding on to the first part of this text at all essential, but they drop
                                the last and avoid it as they would fire, which it truly is if done honestly. If we turn
                                to the words of Jesus alone, we find thai in John x. 38, 30, he sends his disciples not
                                only tc teach and baptize all nations, but also to teach thest same nations to "observe
                                all things whatsoever lliavi commanded you." To give up all natural relations. for
                                instance, and last but not least "his own life also.1' Your champion, Elder Franklin, in
                                one of his discourses with his opponent, makes this strong jioint in contrasting
                                immersion with sprinkling or pouring. "My second argument is, that in departing from the
                                appointment of God, it is more probable that they departed from the more laborious,
                                inconvenient, and unpleasant, to the more easy, convenient, and pleasant," etc. A very
                                true remark, indeed, and one that is intensified a thousand fold in its applicability
                                when we use it in comparing your ceremonial baptism with ours, which buries us with
                                Christ. A burial, my deai friend, naturally suggests a corpse; so in Romans vi. 4 we
                                read: "Therefore ye are buried with him by baptism into death." You taKe your converts
                                down intc the water and bring them out alive and safe. We taki ours, ask them to
                                honestly confess their sins, andthei lead then) down deep into the waters of the Gospel
                                oi Jesus Christ, but instead of bringing them out we keep them under until ail selfish
                                ties, all selfish accumulative disposition, and in short all the connecting links which
                                bind them to the world, are broken, and they who went down alive are brought up dead,
                                completely buried to the world anil its life. They go dowr knowing (after the manner of
                                the world) father, mother, sisters, brothers by the flesh; they go down owning houses
                                and lands, wife and children: they ccftne up recognizing these no more, no matter how
                                loudly they may call. But in their places they find tin hundred fold promised; and in
                                place of wives thej know that, like the virgins, they have Christ! Now are not
                                Franklin's words forcibly applicable here? And last, but by no means the least reason
                                for our neglect of water baptism is the following: Every dispensation has had and must
                                continue to have its laws and ordinances. The Jewish law could not, nor would Jesus
                                suffer it to interpose any obstruction to the Gospel of Christ, which was superior to
                                the dead letter of the law and its ceremonies. Extracting the very soul and marrow of
                                the law, Jesus had still higher truths to urge, and when occasion required could make
                                people feel that he was master, not only of the Sabbath, but any other part of the
                                Jewish, dispensation. We claim that we are in a dispensation superior to that of the
                                apostles of Jesus, in that the truths and principles enunciated by Jesus are more fully
                                carried out now than in their day. Not but that they were faithful, but they could not
                                work before their time- And our dispensation being governed by laws given to it, as
                                Christ gave laws to his followers, and as he from time to time further taught them, we
                                are as firmly bound to observe the laws of our day and dispensation as the apostles
                                theirs. And in this new dispensation, as in the first dispensation of the Christian
                                church, there is a decrease of the ceremonial of the past era. but an increase of the
                                real and vital, and as a consequence a greater cross given to men t bear. And among
                                other ceremonials belonging to tl; first Christian dispensation, water baptism has beer
                                laid aside (by command) as aon-essential. Do not misunderstand us on this point. In the
                                dispensation past and gone it has had its uses. It served in ita time as "the answer of
                                a good conscience towards God," and to those who have received bo further light it will
                                still prove justifying, and, in a degree, comforting, ft is the baptism of John, and no
                                more. A baptism to repentance of an ungodly life. But we say, Christ offers more—a
                                better rite. We might proceed from text to text on this subject of baptism, but will
                                content ourselves by adding, that it is one of the misfortunes of humanity to almost
                                invariably elevate the ceremonial and mystical above the real—to prefer the shadow to
                                the substance—and while wrangling about hair-splitting differences between this or that
                                symbol, to lose sight of the allneedful, the true Christ life. So much for answer to
                                your first question—an answer long and still short—to you a question of great
                                importance, to us a mere side issue, serving to hide from view weightier truth, even the
                                baptism of the Lord Jesus Christ, which, redemptive in its very character and operation,
                                pales, by comparison, its faint symbol belonging to a dispensation to us past and gone.
                                Question1-!: "Did God, or any one regarded as a teacher, command dancing as an act of
                                worship? " Answer. My dear friend, there are some things, God lie praised, which mei and
                                women do without any commanding. Bowed down by sorrow, tears are wrung from oureyes;
                                moved by compassion, we weep over the sufferings of humanity. We have seen whole
                                assemblies carried away and crazed by glad tidings of an earthly character; there were
                                clapping of hands, stamping of feet, tossing of hats, laughter, and even shedding of
                                tears of joy, making a very babel of noise, :ind eve;1, ting such, an excitement that it
                                would have been dangerous for any one to have made manifest that he or she was not in
                                harmony with the all-pervading spirit of the hour. Could any one fully united in the
                                thankfulness of the occasion stand coolly by and criticise the various modes employed to
                                manifest emotion that would not be controlled? We tell you nay. The idea that after God
                                had bestowed upon us his richest blessings, filling us with joy unspeakable, he should
                                still find it necessary to say—"I positively command you to rejoice "—borders some
                                little on the absurd. The Israelites frequently employed dancing to show their rejoicing
                                for victories gained. The instances are so very numerous that we will only give you
                                references to the texts : Jeremiah xxxi. 13 etc.; Exodus xvi. 20: Judges xi. 34; 1st
                                Samuel xviii. 6. We believe that these prefigured the rejoicing of the latter day, when
                                people would rejoice in deliverance from their own sins. Read especially in connection
                                Math texts above referred to : Psalms xlvii. 1; and cxlix, 1st, 2d and 3d verses. And
                                now leaving the Old Testament let us turn to the New, and by way of Biblical answer, let
                                us consider the parable of the prodigal's return. He confesses his sins and begs his
                                father's forgiveness; he is stripped of his old garb and clothed with the new, a robe of
                                purity and righteousness, then "music and lancing." But the elder son is not pleased.
                                Why? Because these things had not been done for him. In brief, to modernize the
                                objection, " they did not do so in the apostles' day, hence it cannot be right." L«t as
                                be careful not to take the place of this elder brother, and lose our union with the
                                father by refusing to rejoice with those who are reclaimed. If it be pardonable in the
                                exuberant expression of earthly joy to forget self—and who can deny that this is
                                done—how much more excusable are those, who, being delivered from the bondage of a
                                fallen nature—having returned to their father—are led by His spirit " to go forth in the
                                dances of them that make merry." In conclusion, as I have before said, ours is a new
                                dispensation and this is one of the customs, one of the modes of giving expression of
                                joy unspeakable within, introduced by Ami Lee, and practiced as good by her followers.
                                Let us finally quote Franklin, and here say—that neither in tlua mode of worship have we
                                chosen "the wore easy, convenient and pleasant" worship in the eyes of the world. Can we
                                not ask ourselves which requires the greatest sacrifice of self to perform—the dead
                                formal worship of the world, or this in which hands, tongue and feet are all employed?
                                Question 3 : "Since God said it was not good for man to be alone (meaning, of course,
                                that it was not good to be without a wife), and since he commanded them to multiply and
                                replenish the earth, is it not going directly against the revealed will of God not to
                                marry?" Answer. God established Adam and his order. Gave him a law which he broke. Sent
                                messenger after messenger to his posterity. He also established the Jewish dispensation.
                                Then was Christ sent, and through Jesus (for a short time) the first Christian
                                dispensation was established; and finally this the last to date. In every dispensation
                                from Adam to Christ, there have been prophecies of increase or growth— and every new era
                                has found its bitterest antagonist in the one that gave it 1 irth. But still, in tones
                                of unmistakable clearness, to; : "ere seeker alter truth, the voice of God has called .
                                ; ( at the old, the new and living present; and well ver ¦¦¦¦'. . you are in the
                                Scriptures, we do not hesitate to nay, that Christ's words about the eunuchs, and his
                                testimony as to his disciples not belonging to the world, "who man \ and are given in
                                marriage," will be easily recalled. The world was not ready at that time for the first
                                ministration of the Christ spirit, for the testimony so foreign to it, and it was soon
                                driven from the face of the earth. The language of the world has ever been and will ever
                                continue to be: "Keep, if you will, ceremonies without number, but stay with me, abide
                                in my life, and I will protect you." But Christ calls, saying: " Come ye out from among
                                them and be ye not partakers of her iniquities." The first man (Adam) was of the earth,
                                earthy—the second man : (Jesus) the Lord from Heaven. The first married, the second did
                                not—neither do his followers. He came not to generate, but by his example and teaching
                                to regenerate—and "as he was in this world, so are we." Again let me say here, "we have
                                not chosen the . easier way." We will say in addition upon the subject of marriage, that
                                it was also discountenanced by Mother . Ann, as not belonging to the Christ Life. And we
                                know of no stronger evidence to the truth of this remark, than the united opposition
                                which both religious (?) and profane manifest to her pure testimony on this point. No
                                matter whether the objector belongs to the most refined and highly educated classes of
                                the land, or whether he comes from the lowest dregs oi humanity; no matter whether he be
                                married or unmarried ; no difference how much they may be separated by culture and
                                ignorance—here they are one, having one faith and one baptism, even the baptism of the
                                flesh! On this ground they meet as brothers; on this field they will battle valiantly
                                for their common cause, and on this plain, we say, "they die to the Christ Life which
                                cometh from above," and proves its divine origin by demanding of the soul that it leave
                                its old camping ground; that it pass through "the valley of the shadow of death" through
                                much suffering and tribulation into the land of purity beyond. II is souls who go
                                through this purifying work of whom it is truly said in Revelations xiv. 4 : "These are
                                they which were not defiled with women, for they are virgins. These are they which
                                follow the Lamb whithersoever he goeth"—not into marriage, for he never went there.
                                "Don't take up so much cross," says the world. "We are the children of Abraham," say the
                                Jews; but we reiterate the testimony to both Jew and Gentile, that in Christ Jesus, "the
                                resurrection and the life, there is neither marrying nor giving in marriage." Question
                                A: "How will you prove, how do you prove, that Mother Ann was gifted with the Spirit of
                                Christ?" Answer. By more positive and direct testimony than we can get with reference to
                                Jesus. We have conversed with those who have talked with others who have had her
                                personal acquaintance. Our informants we know to be people of unimpeachable
                                truthfulness, and they bore the same testimony with reference to the truthfulness of
                                their informants. These made her out a pattern of a Godly woman. But the Shaker
                                societies, with their treasures of precious souls, and their store-houses of heavenly
                                principles, afford to every diligent inquirer the most incontrovertible proofs of her
                                possession of the Chris' spirit. And we know, though young in experience, that the world
                                hates her and her testimony, as the\ hated, and as they still hate the testimony of
                                Chris! through Jesus. We know that she was gifted witli the Christ spirit, because, like
                                Him, she gave her lift to benefit humanity. She renounced the world to meet at its hfi
                                nds the most shameful abuse and persecutions, but with unflinching fortitude, she "kept
                                the faith" and ministered it to others. We know by personal experience that she was
                                gifted with the Christ spirit, because, she has left us laws and ordinances the
                                observance of which brings death to the very nature of sin and makes a clean, a perfect
                                separation from the life—the spirit—of the world. And still we say, we worship neither
                                Jesus, who said to "call him not master," nor Ann, who said "I am your fellow servant,''
                                but rather the spirit which governed them both, and which made them—the first man and
                                the first woman who received it—the leaders in this work. It is very seldom, indeed,
                                that, we enter into so long a review of passages of Scripture referring to ceremonies
                                belonging to past times and still practiced by the various sects of the land. Before we
                                accepted Sbakerism, we read, carefully, publications made by : the society in defence of
                                its faith; but we were not so attached as some seem to be, to the ceremonial part of
                                Jesus' testimony of eighteen hundred years ago. We will say finally, in concluding, that
                                in reading ¦ your commendatory testimony to the innocence of our sisters, the honor of
                                our brethren, and the charity of both, and your inquiry:—" But are you on the right
                                track?"—we are forcibly reminded of some, who after acknowledging that we were in
                                possession of almost ' every virtue under the sun, have also been most intensely fearful
                                that we were not "right after all." To ' all such we would say, we can much better
                                afford to ! be on the wrong track (?) with the virtues, than on ' the right one (?)
                                without them. And now, trusting that I have answered you fully, " and sincerely desiring
                                your eternal welfare, I Avill E close this long letter by sending you my love, and re'
                                turning you my thanks for yours. 11 I remain (paradoxical as it may seem after reading ;
                                this letter) a hater of theological discussions. 3 Most truly yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Amery, George B." TEIform="persName"/>GEO. B. AMERY 5 Whitewater Village, O., Sept.,
                            1877</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many new years, indeed, you may see..." TEIform="index"/>Many new years, indeed, you may see...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">M Many new years, indeed, you may see, but S happy ones you cannot see without deserving
                            them. These, virtue, honor, and knowledge f alone can merit, alone can produce. THE SHAKER.
                            Monthly—60 cents per an num. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Way, truth, and life" TEIform="index"/>THE WAY, TRUTH, AND LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">Would any know what these are to the people called Shakers? To come out from the world, by
                            the practice of unworldly habits and relationships; beginning with the confession of our
                            sins, accompanied by a repentance which ever means a departure from, and a cessation of sins
                            ; to do unto others all the good we can in the relationships of brethren and sisters in
                            Christ; to live purely, as we imagine the purity of Christ and angels to have been and now
                            is, and to live eonsecratedly, through hand labor, heart labor, and in incessant works of
                            mercy, charity and justice. These are " the way" unto every one who feels called to be a
                            Shaker! To unselfishly feel another's and others' woes; to administer testimony which speaks
                            of Christ and Christ crucified unto a sinful world ; to deem it duty to keep our life-lamps
                            trimmed and burning, and to let our lights so shine that others can see them, and safely
                            find a guide by them unto all Christian life ; to v'go preach the kingdom of God, and the
                            power of his Christ," through the word ; through The Shaker ; through every spare penny and
                            spare day oi devotion to its circulation ; and a determinate resolution that knows no such
                            word as surrender, until others know and experience salvation. These are "the TRUTH" to
                            every one who is a Shaker ! To count life as already " not of this world," but as belonging
                            in advance of death to the " kingdom of heaven" on earth; fulfilling the prayer of u Thy
                            will be done on earth as in heaven ;" to use life for others' good, and not selfishly ; to
                            realize life as saved from sin and condemnation, and to be saviors unto others who want
                            present salvation ; to love our neighbors as well, and better than ourselves; and with a
                            love, chaste, resurrected, unworldly, uncarnal and Christly in its every lineament ; to so
                            sorrow for the erring, that we will aid them at the expense of all selfishness ; and in
                            every other character imitate the meek, lowly, virgin, peaceable, self-denying Jesus. These
                            are "the life" unto every genuine, thoroughliving Shaker !</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Over-burdened shaker societies" TEIform="index"/>OVER-BURDENED SHAKER SOCIETIES</head><p TEIform="p">Many people make visits to our Shaker villages for the purposes of rest, change, recreation,
                            or from curiosity. While we frequently encourage people to inquire into our principles, and
                            ever are glad to extend hospitalities io the earnest, sincere seeker after truth ; we are
                            not glad, nor able to entertain all who drive out, seeking their own recreation, or for the
                            gratification of their friends' curiosity ; and we must not be expect- <pb n="79" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER. 79 ed to do so, only where there is a pre- tl vious and mutual understanding
                            that tl we are to do so. There are parties, u to whom we feel ourselves tinder con- if stant
                            and lasting obligations—toward d whom., propriety and justice demand \\ of us the best we
                            can do for them—but tl none should feel any demand upon us, because of a slight or even
                            intimate acquaintance, for an escort over our domains ; for meals and refreshments; ' when
                            he or they choose to take a day's e airing or ride. We cannot do it. Why? ' We have a large
                            property to look after s and keep in repair ; and while much of this occupies our whole
                            time, it does o not return to us any monetary remuneration. It is also well known that we t;
                            keep no house servants ; that our sisterhood is severely taxed with many house- f; hold
                            duties ; while those serving in the f culinary departments of our office build- t ings are
                            not only taxed to care for those a calling on legitimate business, but are unreasonably
                            expected to cook, and otherwise care for a small army of hire- t lings ! and when we say
                            unreasonably, a we mean that a due respect for the sis- v terhood of our faith would forbid
                            any I such use of gospel sisters ! There are ^ too many who deem it a nice affair "to drive
                            out to the Shakers and take din- r ner ;" who are very inconsiderate of the e tax they bring
                            to bear on those already over-burdened. ! Those wishing to visit us for pleasure or rest,
                            will find that we shall make , but few objections, provided these visits imply something
                            besides being enter- l tainedwith meals, etc. I We often utter the prayer of the af- !
                            flicted : li Deliver us from our friends ! " particularly from those friends who deem a
                            visit very incomplete without ] so much additional burden to us. While ; we would be
                            respectful and kind to all, . we want none to feel slighted when • i business or
                            circumstances prevent our inviting them to dine. Such a constant run of company do some
                            families in , some Societies have, desirous of full i and free entertainment, that tired and
                            jaded as the over-worked sisters are, this company becomes very tmwelcome ; and while duty
                            requires that we return gratitude for similar or superior favors, we hope the present, grand
                            majority will take our hint, be more considerate, and abstain from being bores upon us. Once
                            more : We are not inmates of public institutions—our Shaker villages being our own personal
                            homes. Parties, and particularly strangers, often commit a breach of decency by asking to be
                            shown through our buildings, offices, shops, domains, etc. We look upon such demands very
                            much as any private household in the land would ; and who would not feel insulted by such ?
                            We feel we are doing public duty by the issue of these palpable, but unpleasant remarks. We
                            have been forced to these reasonable considerations by actual, disagreeable experience. We
                            believe our genuine friends will be sufficiently considerate to acknowledge) leir propriety,
                            and to help us ; while!" lose sufficiently unfriendly to fail of Iri nderstanding us, must
                            not be surprised j 7 we are forced to tell them how very\disagreeable they are* in just so
                            manyjti words, as will assure us that we are b thoroughly understood. *i</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberal shaker sentiments" TEIform="index"/>LIBERAL SHAKER SENTIMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">The Albany Express recently sent its most i talented correspondent to attend our public j
                            services ; and a lengthy report follows in an j P early issue, giving complimentary
                            descrip-|" tions of the music, religious enthusiasm and j p order of the meeting. He also
                            paid us, per-j, sonally, some very flattering, and some doubt-1 ful compliments. We copy his
                            concise report jt' of our address, asking if it is at all "hazy" or &gt;r of doubtful
                            signification? He says : ' r After marching several songs, they stop, |c take their seats,
                            and the eloquently sedate j j speaker steps forward and preaches a short U sermon, full of
                            vigor and earnestness, and a j fair presentation of his belief. His text is!e from Romans
                            viii: 3-4, and he zealously la-L bored to show the distinction between Judaism j 1 and
                            Christianity, and the superiority of the!v latter. The following are the strong points L of
                            the discourse : L Under Judaism, much that genuine chris- L tianity abandoned was good, is
                            good to-day, | E as Judaism. Are there lovers of marriage, ;c war, private property and of
                            the world's pro-jr pensities generally, with us to-day? We have L only a liberal testimony
                            to impart to you. L You are right in such loves. Judaism claimedL these as good, and Jesus
                            ever sustained the L righteousness of the law. But Jesus present- , ed the better ways of
                            Christianity, and invited j as many as were able to accept of them. For , marriage, he
                            presented the superior doctrine , of life manifested by the celibate for the king- ( dom of
                            heaven's sake. And is it not strange ( that while the vast majority evade this in- ,
                            struction of Jesus, and the same, as lived and | ] taught by his immediate disciples, all
                            expect • to live just as we Shakers are living in the , not distant future? Marriage peoples
                            the ( earth ; celibacy populates the heavens, and as Christians, praying for heaven on
                            earth, how 't can we escape being insincere, unless we live here as we believe angels are
                            living there ? Are | you married? You are doing right therein, as , yews, and now let the
                            Levitical laws regulate . your passions, and we shall see a new earth,! blooming with
                            children, honors to their parents, having sound minds in healthy bodies. But while we
                            congratulate you on the righteousness of the laws of marriage and reproductions, we insist
                            the married are not, cannot be Christians. There never was, and never will be a child
                            conceived under the standard of Christianity. It is the right of a Tew to marry; it is the
                            duty of a Christian to be a celibate, even as was Jesus. Just so with private property : it
                            naturally and righteously succeeds marriage. It is a Jewish institution, but so regulated
                            that were it now in force as of old, there would be none inordinately rich nor poor, as now
                            found under bogus, but popular Christianity. The regular partition of goods as practiced by
                            the Jews puts to shame all the sham charities of to-day, though called Christian, and is
                            just the panacea demanded for the prevention of strikes, and the large increase of happiness
                            on the earth. But Jesus taught a progression upon the best forms of Jewish partition, by the
                            introduction y of an entire relinquishment of all and any • private property; and Peter
                            replied, "Behold, we have forsaken all," etc. Even the sweet ties of consanguinity were
                            severed, and Jesus, setting the example, acknowledged those only Y who lived as he lived, as
                            his mother, sisters, 1- brethren, etc. d "When Dr. Newman was the keeper of Gen. v Grant's
                            conscience he went to Utah, accompanied by the moral power of the government, to convince
                            the Mormons that polygamy was unbiblical, but Elder Pratt very e I quickly "floored" him, as
                            will every one be "floored" who attempts to dispute that marriages, either as polygamy or
                            monogamy, are not sanctioned by the God of the Jews. And who will say that war is not
                            righteous according to the same criterion ? Let none deny I the right of Jews to fight; but
                            who will be i brazen enough to say that there is any chrisjtianity about it! And yet there
                            are, Rev. Christians (?) too! We met one last evening \ on the boat from New York! This Rev.
                            i gentleman had two j'oung daughters. Alice, I running up to him, says, "Papa, Mary slapped
                            me!" "What, again?" says the father. I "Yes," says Alice. "Then," said the pious I parent,
                            "Alice, you go and slap Mary!" "And herein," said he, "was what Jesus meant by I turning the
                            other cheek!" And then this I minister went on to say that Toe Smith was I right when he
                            taught that, turning the other cheek, you were smitten, it was evidence of j intentional
                            insult, and you may "pitch into I the fellow !" Jesus overlapped war by destroying the
                            causes of war and teaching peace; even to "resist not evil," "do good to those who
                            despitefully use you," give the kiss for the I blow! WTe plead guilty equal to those of old
                            j who were charged with "turning the world 'upside down," for that is just what the Shakers
                            are doing. Christ being "lifted up" as our exampler we find in the following of him all the
                            results of the primitive Christian ! church manifested unto us. Those who were ! married,
                            became, as did the disciples, broth'; ers and sisters. We are forced, by the con\ victions
                            of duty, to lay our riches and pov' erty in one common treasury, and "nonepos; sesses.aught
                            he calls his own," only as sharing with brethren and sisters. Hence there is none rich, none
                            poor, but all very comfortable. We are constrained to ask our friends whether our position
                            is not that of the model church of old ? Can marriage, private prop' erty, wars of
                            households or of nations, or "selfish relationships be at all Christian? Let ! us present
                            the key to the mysterious problem : The God of marriage, of private property, " war, etc.,
                            was the God of the Tews. The God ' of celibacy, of communion of interests, of 5 peace and
                            Christian brotherhood is the God ' of the Christians. The God of the Jews is ' not God of
                            the Christians. There was aprog" ress for humanity, and Jesus, under the in' spiration of
                            the Christian's God, left Judaism " I to live Christianity. Hence we, the Shakers, &gt;
                            have done with Judaism just as Jesus did, and he lived above it! And inasmuch as we fol¦ low
                            Jesus are we not Christians? And inasmuch as Jesus practiced our life was not Jesus ¦ a
                            Shaker ? Commenting on the above, the correspondent says: "Here's richness for you," as s
                            Charles Dickens would say. Some of the as1 sertions, however, are startling, and though 3
                            the logic to an outsider is a trifle hazy, one 1 could not help admiring the frankness of
                            the y sermon. The discourse was delivered with a 1 polish and clearness, quite pleasing, and
                            s which could be emulated with profit by many 1 Christian clergymen.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="They wanted salvation" TEIform="index"/>THEY WANTED SALVATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Any one who is ever roused to any ;t religious ecstasy, will be able to appren ciate the
                                feelings of Bros. Andrews and }' Kulp, as expressed in their articles in '' this number.
                                We have not added to ' this number of Tup: Shaker the next additional answer to the
                                query : " What 5, shall 1 do to be a Shaker?''' but there may be found, teeming through
                                several '• of our contributors' articles, complete answers to the question. Whoever 1r_
                                will be a Christian, after the pattern of ¦y Jesus, finds an answer to the above
                                &gt;e question in their own experience. When 11 other systems shall fail to give the
                                Dower to live apart from sin—to expeience salvation in every-day life—then, f vou wrould
                                find satisfaction to the oul, call on the Shakers, who not only Dreach salvation, but
                                live in it! None eave the Shakers to find a greater sal-ation from sin than our church
                                gives.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retribution" TEIform="index"/>RETRIBUTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The strikes and strikers are taking a lap. Let no one deceive himself by he thoughts that
                                they are ended. They lever will end until a greater equality prevails among all classes.
                                The entire armies of states and nation will prove powerless to disarm the millions of
                                poor, crushed, over-worked, less than half-paid humanity. "God moves in a mysterious
                                wav;" and we see God's judgments visiting monopolists of the land in and through these
                                strikes. 1 he inordinate wrealth, extravagance, laziness and tyranny of the few ; and
                                the unearthly, squalid poverty of the multitudes, are things which ought not to
                                be—cannot be in the economy of God. Christianity teaches greater equality than Judaism ;
                                while millions of professed Christians do not practice half as much. We deprecate
                                strikes, and would prevent them, teaching by precept and example an exceeding equality.
                                Until we are willing to learn to practice equality—to ll love our neighbor as
                                ourself,"—we must reasonably expect such eruptions. The alternatives are before
                                us—either put away the causes of strikes, monopolies and monopolists ; giving the
                                laborer the worth of his toil: or anticipate and experience riots, destruction of life
                                and property—judgments of God on the rich robbers of humanity—with the very much worse
                                yet to come. Let there be none inordinately rich, and there will be none inordinately
                                poor; while all would be sufficiently wealthy to be very comfortable. It is useless to
                                ridicule communism ; it is God's arrangement; and we had better accept it through
                                merciful dealings with the poor, than be driven to it through the judgments of these
                                pitiless, unmerciful strikes and strikers !</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker covenant" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER COVENANT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">As wre promised, some time ago, we begin the publication of The Shaker Church Covenant.
                                It will be com Ipleted in the November number. We ask kind attention to it, by Believers
                                and "those not of our faith." It is the guardian of our rights and privileges ; our
                                duties and obligations, under Christ ¦ rule. It teaches, aye, demands, an ex1 ceeding
                                purity, self-denial, equal1 1TY, JUSTICE, PEACE, UNSPOTTEDNESS &gt; I from the
                                world! Wrho would truly t know this, let them try its discipline. t And yet, we do not
                                claim perfection for ; it. We know wherein it can be imlj proved by amendments ; for the
                                greater JI justice, comfort and satisfaction of its i" I subscribers. Such amendments
                                are f already under consideration by the 2 Central Bishopric. But we do claim 1 that
                                whoever lives up to its present re- <pb n="80" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 80 THE SHAKER. quirements, will
                                curb human nature from making a tyrant or usurper of any one ; and teach that he or she
                                that is greatest, must be so by becoming the servant of the brethren, at the expense of
                                personal selfishness. Brethren, it is sufficiently perfect to guard it with all possible
                                care, from even small breaches, which never of themselves incline to grow smaller ; and
                                as we would defend our homes, hearthstones, associations and faith, so let us engage in
                                all spiritual patriotism, and jealously watch the safety of our covenant.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Campellites attended to" TEIform="index"/>CAMPBELLITES ATTENDED TO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We yield large space to our Whitewater people and their Campbellite correspondent. The
                                letters are unusually able ; we feeling proud of our champion. By a careful perusal of
                                Bro. Amery's remarks, linked with those of Elders Avery, Evans, Fraser and others, we
                                are almost persuaded we present an unusually good number. Whitewater Village, O., may be
                                like "pent-up Utica," but there is large talent confined there, and we would like much
                                of it to rain on us—not pour however.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us go up and take the city" TEIform="index"/>LET US GO UP AND TAKE THE CITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. 1. Let us go up and take the City, Let not our zeal and courage wane, Nought
                            shall impede our 2. Let us go up and take the City, It is the strong in faith who win None
                            are entitled 3. Let us go up and take the City, We will sing praises as we go Bearing aloft
                            the progress upward, God will be with us to sustain. We will not flinch, tho' overcomers,
                            Bearing the stains of guilt and sin. Washed in the pool of gospel banner, Ensign of victory
                            o'er the foe. When we have passed the great the conflict, Knowing our cause is just and true
                            true repentance, Clothed in the virgin's blest attire, glorious ordeal, Proven our right to
                            joys of bliss, Victry is ours, if we are valiant, Every evil to subdue. Safely we'll pass
                            all scenes of dauger, Watery floods, or flames of fire. We will rejoice in our salvation,
                            Dwelling in peace and righteousness.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reciprocity" TEIform="index"/>RECIPROCITY</head><p TEIform="p">One of the famous (and justly, honorably so,) Smith Sisters of Glastonbury, Conn., kindly
                            sent us a Bible—translated literally from the original tongue, by herself—and it is a
                            wonderful performance by a very modest, but unusually talented woman. We feel honored by the
                            gift; and to the thousands of Bible readers whom The Shaker will greet with this
                            intelligence, we can safely predict a new-found pleasure by the procurement and delightful
                            pleasure of this valued novelty. One of the Harvard college Hebrew professors--Prof.
                            Young—has expressed himself in unmeasured terms of praise, that a woman, unaided by
                            masculine talents, should have been able to accomplish the task so literally and so
                            accurately. It certainly is a wonderful work, and is well worth the price—very cheap for so
                            neat and large a volume. Those interested may order through this office. Price, three
                            dollars. There is in Haifa, Syria, a missionary station, where those interested in its
                            sustenance have engaged in the manufacture of pure, olive oil, castile soap; hoping by the
                            sale of the genuine article to maintain the mission enterprise. Olive oil in Syria is of
                            small account, for reason of its abundance and cheapness. It has heretofore been extensively
                            used for illuminating purposes ; but petroleum has displaced it. Now, the purest soap
                            imaginable is being made of the olive oil—the genuine castile—and the samples sent us speak
                            very highly for it. The only agency for this excellent article is that of T. B. Nichols, 71
                            William street, New York. As the enterprise is a charitable one, let us help it.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY ITEMS</head><p TEIform="p">We get excellent reports of health from nearly all the societies. Mother Ann used to speak of
                            health as " the second greatest blessing" naming the spiritual work of the gospel first. In
                            our report of the curious contagion of injured hips, failure to correct proof, left an
                            unfortunate brother at Enfield, N. H., unmentioned. We hear gladly of improvement. Several
                            parties from Canterbury, N. H., are giving expression to their zeal, by visiting neighboring
                            towns, preaching the word, and getting additions to the subscription list of The Shaker.</p><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wilcox, Betsey" TEIform="index"/>Mother Betsey Wilcox
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wilcox, Betsey" TEIform="persName">Mother Betsey Wilcox</persName>, aged 81, left for
                                    the evergreen shores of the better land, from Enfield, Conn., August 6, 1877. She
                                    had celebrated her golden zvedding to the Shakers, before death came.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sparrow, Martha H." TEIform="index"/>Martha H. Sparrow
                                </head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Mass., Sept. 11, 1877, <persName reg="Sparrow, Martha H." TEIform="persName">Martha H.
                                        Sparrow</persName>, aged 63, left, after thirty years for the evergreen
                                shore.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Evans preached before an immense concourse..." TEIform="index"/>Elder Evans preached before an immense concourse...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Elder Evans preached before an immense concourse of intelligence at Shakers, N. Y., Sept.
                                2. Those present, give him excellent credit. Some of our neighbors—florists— proposed
                                crowning him with a beautiful wreath of immortelles; and they may have done so! Greeley
                                Mohawk Grapes, ripened here this year, August 25, ten days later than usual. Beautiful
                                flavor, large clusters, and no dropping from the stem. Trustees of Watervliet Society
                                (Shakers, N. Y.), at present: Chauncy Copley, Philip Smith, Henry George, Ruth A. Green,
                                Samantha Borvie, Adelaide Ingham. Erratum.—In September number, page 66, first paragraph
                                of second column, read "the priesthood was dual," instead of "dead." The meaning was
                                thereby destroyed.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>