<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0711" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18771101" TEIform="date">November 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="81" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">rpTTTji io JnL j^l J\_ Juj Jrv. OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " §a
                        $tre;tvf( the kingdom off (§od!" Jpu? htdhnoiiQ of eternnl hath. Yol. VII. i G. A. LOMAS,
                        Editor, ( \ Shakers, N. Y. ( NOVEMBER, 1877. l N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher, \ I Shaker Village, N.
                        H. 1 No. 11.</p><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We reap what we sow" TEIform="index"/>WE REAP WHAT WE SOW</head><p TEIform="p">For pleasure or pain, for weal or for woe, 'Tis the law of our being—we reap what we sow; We
                            may try to evade them—may do what we will— But our acts, like our shadows, will follow us
                            still. The world is a wonderful chemist, be sure, And detects in a moment the base or the
                            pure; We may boast of our claims to genius or birth, But the world takes a man for just what
                            he's worth. We start in the race for fortune or fame, And then when we fail the world bears
                            the blame; But nine times in ten 'tis plain to be seen, There's a "screw somewhere" loose in
                            the human machine. Are vou wearied and worn in this hard, earthly strife? Do you yearn for
                            affection to sweeten your life?" Remember this great truth has often been proved, We must
                            make ourselves loveable would we be loved. Though life may appear as a desolate track, Yet
                            the bread that we cast on the waters comes back; This law was enacted by Heaven above, That
                            like attracts like and love begets love. We are proud of our mansions of mortar and stone,
                            In its gardens are flowers from every zone : But the beautiful graces that blossom within,
                            Grow shriveled and die in the Upas of sin. We make ourselves heroes and martyrs for gold,
                            Till health becomes broken and youth becomes old; Ah ! did we the same for the beautiful
                            love, Our lives might be music for angels above. We reap -what we sozv—Oh, wonderful truth !
                            A truth hard to learn in the day of our youth ; But at last it shines out as "hand on the
                            wall," For the world has its debt and credit for all.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two sides of life" TEIform="index"/>TWO SIDES OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Life has two sides ; one is sunny, the other shady. Many persons, from moroseness of
                            disposition, or a wrong habit of thinking, dwell more or less within the shadows, and
                            incline to see every thing in a gloomy aspect. To such, the clearest sky is portentous of a
                            nearing storm ; the calmest sea has folded billows ; the serenest atmosphere envelops a
                            tempest; and the fairest morn is surely gathering mists of frowning clouds. Their brows are
                            dark with sullen thoughts of evil that may come. Few are the pleasant words they speak, till
                            the voice grows harsh, like some discordant instrument, and the whole being seems out of
                            tune with the sweetflowing harmonies of the material and spiritual universe. On the other
                            side dwell those who have the sunshine of cheer in their souls, t Dark foreboding shadows
                            flee at their presence. Although clouds, somber 1 and dense, lower upon the mountain i tops,
                            they know there is a "silver lin- \ ing," and that the glory beyond will ^ shift the darkest
                            scene. Anon the tern- t pestuous tide of time sweeps by, but ever leaves a calm sweetly
                            enjoyable. Fierce winds may mar and blight the perishable, yet tranquil the mind reposes
                            amid the wreck and ruin, while peace succeeds the war of adverse elements. Dense mists of
                            gathering vapors may obscure the mellow light of night's fair queen, and all the shining
                            hosts that silent tread the ether space ; yet still they gleam, and only hide awhile that we
                            may better appreciate their glorious beaming. This world is full of pleasant things, if we
                            would only keep on the sunny side. ''Light is sown for the righteous, and gladness for the
                            upright in heart." There are pleasant words to speak, genial smiles to give, kindly looks to
                            bestow, sweet notes to harmonize, pure gifts to mingle, loving deeds to perform, patience to
                            exercise, charities to scatter, and blessings to gather. Love is the sun of the soul ; let
                            its emanations radiate through heaven and earth, till the fullness of its blessing shall be
                            realized by all God's creation.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 11" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way. No. 11</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">152 GOOD AND DO GOOD. After a long pilgrimage on the journey of life, with a favored
                            opportunity to learn of the ways of man, and an : anxiety corresponding to the privilege, •
                            I am fully persuaded that to "be : good and do good," takes precedence of all creeds, forms
                            and ceremonies that may have originated in the mind of , either the passive or rigid devotee
                            of ¦ any religious order. There can be I nothing more potent than the word of ¦ God to Cain
                            : " If thou doest well, shalt &gt; thou not be accepted?" This same ad; dress may, with
                            all propriety, stand i first on the list of religious obligations . over which we may be
                            asking God's i blessing. ¦ To anticipate a process for goodness, i and to publish its
                            efficacy, is quite dif¦ ferent from the discipline which is de1 manded of those who would
                            walk faithfully in Christ Jesus. The imaginative &gt; principle in man's mind seems to
                            have been very prolific from the beginning. The sacred historian says: " Only this have I
                            found, that God made man right, and he hath entangled himself with an infinity of
                            questions." And we are further informed there was a time when all these imaginations of the
                            mind were from an evil source. Hence :he necessity of a flood ; but the gradual development
                            of the human family n the scale of moral and religious obigations, warrants us in believing
                            that he principle of goodness now stands in he ascendancy. Perhaps the mind in this age may
                            be nore prolific, and the imagination no less vivid, but we are learning that the deeper the
                            interest which is manifested in God and in his creature man, the stronger the incentive to
                            "be good and to do good." It is a wise provision of a kind providence that such is the fact;
                            and to all who are learners in the school of Christ, it opens a beautiful avenue for
                            spiritual progression. How like the prophetic Zion's army the children of light might move
                            on, if happily they could all accept the same revelations of goodness and of God. But the
                            slow process of trying the spirits, of analyzing the assumed progressive developments, and
                            the still slower process of disciplining the mind into a receptive state, obliges them to
                            move with measured tread on to the city of Peace. Our beloved Elder Frederic W. Evans would
                            inspire us with a knowledge of an increasing second cycle, heralded, as he says, by the
                            voice of thunder, which shall be to the Shaker order a deeper and more powerful shaking than
                            has ever been realized. To this declaration, evei'y Believer might well say Amen ! as it
                            awakens an inspiration corresponding so beautifully with the testimony of those sons and
                            daughters of God who were the pioneers of this gospel work. Whatever this voice may be, that
                            is to usher in a more advanced state of spiritual life, we feel well assured that it will
                            establish us more firmly in the principles of truth, and enable us to do more good. It is
                            well that here and there these witnesses have arisen and testified against the manifold sins
                            of the world. Others may arise and testify, for the better preservation of the church. If
                            their administration disciplines us to a more correct use of language, or opens to us a
                            deeper knowledge of dietetic laws, or ascends into the spiritual, and awakens in us a zeal
                            for good works, well may we recognize the hand of a special providence in the timely
                            monition.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 7" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture. No. 7</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">INDIVIDUALISM.----SOCIALISM. Nature has done much for man individually, but much more for him
                            as a social being. In the Christian economy, which is neither more nor less than nature
                            carrying her own work on to perfection, the individual is always regarded as forming part of
                            a united whole, but yet a necessary part of the whole, his individuality being as clearly
                            recognized as that of the link in the chain, or pillar, beam or brace in the building. The
                            individual may be complete in himself as such, but in his union to the whole by the spirit
                            of divine love, a far grander and more beautiful effect is produced than can be when
                            detached from it. The individual statues and spires of the Milan cathedral may each claim
                            the admiration of the beholder ; but only the entire view can charm both heart and eye. It
                            is this alone that makes the "thing of beauty a joy forever." It is just so with beautiful
                            landscapes. The poet Lamartine, after viewing one of these, might well exclaim, " If there
                            is so much to see, to admire and be delighted with in a single little corner of nature, what
                            will it be when the curtain of worlds shall be raised, and we shall contemplate forever the
                            admirable whole ?" In association—Christian association above all—there must be mutual
                            benefits and advantages, or else the association is valueless. The character of each member
                            must be so molded and formed that every other shall be benefited, and the whole body become
                            indissolubly united. This will ultimately be the state of the Christian church ; it must be
                            so measurably in the beginning of every association assuming that name. For the individual
                            disciple the Master has prescribed a rule that admits of no exceptions — " Deny thyself;
                            take thy cross and follow me." For the disciples as a whole—" Love one another." Christian
                            love is the necessary result of Christian self-denial; it flows from its divine source just
                            as readily and freely as water from the mountain when the way is opened for them to irrigate
                            the meadows of the valley. Mutual con- <pb n="82" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 82 THE SHAKER. cession is not
                            the Christian law, for there should be nothing to concede. The right eye is not to be
                            literally plucked out, nor the right hand to be cut off; but all disease, whether physical,
                            mental or moral, must be eradicated, or else the individual himself will suffer from it, and
                            the whole body, in its measure, be affected. This is the sacrifice to be laid on the altar
                            to be utterly consumed by fire ; but " every good gift and every perfect gift is from
                            above," and these are to constitute the Christian's life. There can be no concession of
                            right in any Christian association, as these are inalienable; no one having any liberty to
                            concede them, nor any one authority to demand or enjoin this concession. There cannot be a
                            right to what is evil —a vicious propensity, a passionate temper, indolence,
                            self-indulgence, envy, hatred, nor whatever is injurious to the individual nor the
                            community. These are to be abandoned forever by each one, as obstacles to all true
                            association, so that when a union is formed, all may enter upon a fuller enjoyment of their
                            natural rights than any state of isolation can possibly afford. There have been many
                            attempts at association, for the sake of a better life than ordinary society exhibits ; some
                            of them apparently successful for a while, but finally failing, for the sole lack of
                            harmony. This may arise from various causes—from stringent or despotic measures on the part
                            of those who seek a controlling influence, or from the selfindulgent habits of many or the
                            most of those who make up the community. An association of those who are governed by
                            Christian love will be permanent, though they may be destitute of wealth in the
                            commencement. This may be soon accumulated, both of the material and intellectual sort. But
                            of what avail are paper constitutions and by-laws where that is wanting? The person who is
                            destitute of it might as well sign his name to them with water; it would be no more
                            effectually null. It is not meant, of course, that in the formation and earlier years of a
                            Christian community everything works with the smoothness that is experienced when ripe
                            habits are fixed ; yet the Christian edifice will, from its very foundation, be Christian,
                            and nothing else, just so long as Christian principles form its life. And this is reasonably
                            to be expected ; for if a tree, a shrub, a plant, will grow when put into congenial soil,
                            and properly nurtured; if a building when placed upon a solid foundation, and all its parts
                            put together with the necessary care, will stand the requisite number of years, much more
                            will that which is established by the eternal Architect continue permanent, when everything
                            required by him is complied with by those who are the workers upon it. These workers are to
                            be a continuous body, not merely in the original establishment, but for all further
                            improvements. They may enlarge, strengthen and beatitify; whatever can add to its
                            convenience, elegance or splendor, they are at liberty to furnish; it is to be built up a
                            durable habitation of righteousness ; "a house eternal in the heavens."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="John's answer to William's question" TEIform="index"/>John's answer to William's question
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">JOHN'S ANSWER TO WILLIAM'S QUESTION. TO ALL WHOM IT MAY CONCERN. "Is the Church
                                    of England worth preserving?"— Mr. Gladstone. What is the church? Is it a place For
                                    holy antic and grimace? A sort of Sabbath opera-bouffe, Performed beneath a Gothic
                                    roof? Parade, with priest for fugleman ? Burlesque upon the latest plan Of things
                                    the most sublime and serious, Where mummery, veiling the mysterious, Yields
                                    mumbo-motley as result Of search for an "aesthetic cult?" Is this the church you
                                    tnean? If so, John's answer's an emphatic "No !" Is it a stage where bumptious boys
                                    May wrangle over gauds and toys, Fuming whene'er some scrap of flummery Is stript
                                    from their too florid mummery? May vent on Luther, or on Tait, Ecclesiastic
                                    Billingsgate ? Much like an angry housemaid, chidden For finery that is forbidden ;
                                    Who strikes an attitude as martyr Because her Sabbath rig's not smarter. Is this the
                                    church you mean? If so, John's answer is a ready "No!" Is it a "scene" where cleric
                                    pride May be supremely glorified ; And every petty priestling hope To play the part
                                    of petty pope, Shining in foolish virgin's eyes With sacerdotal sanctities; And
                                    gently dazzling, now and then, Some mooney and molluscous men ; Where, gaily decked
                                    in stolen plumes, 'Midst pompous rites and fragrant fumes The emptiest daw may
                                    masque and mum Ecclesiastic Fe-Faw-Fum ? Is this poor thing your "church?" If so,
                                    John's answer's an explosive "No!" Is it a word of life or death ? A sacerdotal
                                    shibboleth? A proud abstraction, vague and vast, Veiling the tyranny of caste? A
                                    verbal fetish, shaped to rule The flexile fancy of the fool? A web of forms,
                                    traditions, creeds, Stretched 'twixt the soul and the soul's needs? Is church the
                                    "priest's preserve?" If so, John's answer is—"Preserve it? No?"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London punch" TEIform="index"/>London Punch.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is God's word?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS GOD'S WORD?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chandler, Hewitt" TEIform="persName"/>HEWITT CHANDLER</byline><p TEIform="p">In a late number of The Shaker, I noticed an article entitled " God's Word," by Hervey L.
                            Eades, from which I would make a few quotations, and add a few criticisms : "
                            Notwithstanding the subject of what constitutes God's Word has perplexed the world for ages,
                            and been widely discussed and much befogged by writers, so that agreement has hitherto
                            seemed impossible, still, I think it can be made plain to the common mind. This is the task
                            I have now proposed for myself. It will first be necessary to state what we are to
                            understand by the term God." The explanation our venerable and learned elder gives may be
                            all clear to him, but to us it is a little foggy. Simple minds can comprehend only simple
                            ideas. "We understand by the term God in its highest sense to man, Infinite spirit
                            omniscient and omnipresent; then to speak of more than one Infinite God is childish, equal
                            to declaring there is no Infinite God, but being infinite in his presence, as well as his
                            power in all worlds and all places, in all humans and all things, at all times, makes all
                            works his own except that which is changed, obstructed or counteracted by free agents, and
                            for which the free agents are themselves accountable." If God is infinite in all respects,
                            wre cannot see how there can be any exceptions. 'All the anti-christian fuss about a fixed
                            throne, located in space somewhere ' 'twixt earth, sea and skies,' is pure fiction, chimera,
                            with no rational basis, as such notions destroy the idea of his infinity. This, however,
                            does not conflict with the idea of his kingdom in heaven, where Christ is the visible head,
                            who is still directed and controlled by the operation of the Divine Essence on his higher
                            consciousness, and to whom all must bow, angels or men." We would ask our teacher where "
                            his kingdom in heaven" is located? " If the affirmation that ' God cannot possibly be in any
                            evil work ' be construed to deny the eternal presence, then the affirmation is at fault,
                            because God is either omnipresent or he is not. If he is not, he is circumscribed. If he is
                            circumscribed, he is finite, and can be measured when infinity disappears. But God is ever
                            present in the cyclone, in the fire that warms, or that which reduces cities to ashes. He is
                            equally in the flint of the winged and quivering arrow of the wild Indians, on its errand of
                            death, as in the heart to coniemn or approve, or in that of angels or men on errands of
                            mercy and love." In following our teacher around the infinite circle, except where he varies
                            from it, we come back to the starting point; and using the term God to express the idea, we
                            say : God is everything, and everything is God ; and making the term God and spirit
                            synonymous, we say spirit is everything, and everything is spirit; hence, in using the term
                            God or spirit in this sense, we express only existence. Now, as we have a recess, let us, as
                            pupils, make a little trip inside this infinite circle. We know there is a force not always
                            visible to our senses, but only as we see its effects on what we call material things. This
                            force is motion, life. We will use the term God to represent this force ; and as we go
                            around the circuit, we see all kinds of vegetable, animal and mineral life forming and
                            dissolving again. Then we say, motion is life, life is God, and God is life. By this we
                            convey the idea of what appears to us to be an element, or a part of infinity. Now, we will
                            imagine a being in personal form, and call him God ; and, as our teacher says a throne
                            located " 'twixt earth, sea and skies is chimera," we will locate his throne above the
                            skies; and attribute to him the right and power to rule all things ; and whatever agrees
                            with our notions, we will call God's Word, and think it awful if any one slights this Deity.
                            We can, by using the term God, communicate our meaning to those who understand our ideas ;
                            but this being is only efficient to those who have the same fancied notions. Now, we will
                            combine the principle of goodness and love, and make of them God; not solely incorporated in
                            any particular personality,but acknowledged wherever these are found. We determine goodness
                            by what is beneficial to our being and our fellow-beings ; and love, in its highest sense,
                            by the desire to make others happy. This is the God whose voice we hear and can understand,
                            when our venerable fathers and mothers kindly exhort us to love God, do God's service, etc.
                            This is the God we will worship and pray to—pray that we may learn to live and act in such a
                            way as will best promote the welfare of our being, but not at the expense of others, and
                            that the happiness of all within our compass may be augmented by our efforts. The term God
                            is most commonly applied to the focus of religious worship, each sect respectively declaring
                            theirs the true and only God. Their God is true to all who are true to him ; but the
                            combined testimony of all annuls the term " only." We should judge, from the story recorded
                            in what is called Sacred Writ, that Moses wTould have others believe his object of
                            worship—or God, was the creator of all things, and that he was inspired to tell when all was
                            done. " That it has been his will to impart free agency to man, who may do evil or good at
                            pleasure, does not deny in the least degree the ever-existing Eternal Presence." All beings
                            are free agents in proportion to their power of action ; but none are independent, not even
                            the gods. The application of the term God to any compound of ideas, is a pun that does for
                            conceited theologians to quarrel over, but lovers of truth have no time to waste. " The
                            false but popular democratic cry of ' Vox populi vox Dei,' is at variance with the whole
                            genius, tenor, structure, and very existence of Christ's kingdom, which is a theocracy pure
                            and simple, and every iota of democracy that finds lodgment therein only has the tendency to
                            lower its status, and cause it to interblend with the kingdom and communities of the world,
                            and make it both 'common and unclean.' Ours is the antipode of democracy ; the one being the
                            government of God, the other of men; the heads of one being appointed by God above them, the
                            heads of the other by men below them." With highest regards for our veteran elder, but none
                            the less distaste for the sentiment. We cannot discover in what sense the phrase, " The
                            voice of the people is the voice of God," is false. According to our teacher's definition of
                            God, all voices must be God's voice. In a democratic form of government the heads are
                            appointed by the people for a definite space of time. In a theocratic form of government,
                            the head, or heads, are adopted by the people, with an admitted right to appoint their
                            successors. But of what avail is a theocracy, or its God, when the people fail to recognize
                            it? The real essence of theocracy is a desire to control others by declaring a Deity. The
                            essence of democracy is a desire to give others equal rights with themselves. The qualities
                            of our leaders are much higher appreciated when strcngly tinctured with the essence of
                            democracy, making them like unto the people they are called to serve ; and this element is a
                            counter-balance to aristocracy, to which theocracy is very closely allied. West Gloucester,
                            Me.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The gamester, if he die a martyr to his profession..." TEIform="index"/>The gamester, if he die a martyr to his profession...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The gamester, if he die a martyr to his pro fession, is doubly ruined. He adds his soul to
                            every other loss ; and by the act of suicide renounces earth to forfeit heaven.</p></div2><pb n="83" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith and hope in trial" TEIform="index"/>FAITH AND HOPE IN TRIAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smart, George W." TEIform="persName"/>GEO. W. SMART</byline><p TEIform="p">Now, for the heavenborn baptism of faith, I'm praying, When lifted up from common earthly
                            things. Assurance blest will come to me; my soul keeps saying— There's no true light but
                            what the gospel brings. I seek the blessed meed of faith; inspiring faith in all things, In
                            fellow man, as well as trust in heaven : And seeking, find in every human heart some
                            heavenly well-springs Of truth, and goodness, unto mortals given. The world's no desert, nor
                            is celestial love denied to all— The heart of man is not innately vile; Germs of the pure
                            living light in every mind, await God's call, As seeds in earth slumbers, till sunbeams
                            smile. In the rude, rocky waste where thorns and briars are, rich berries grow, Much wealth
                            of gold you'll find, mid sterile sands— Rich lustrous pearls lie deeply, where the cold,
                            cruel sea waves flow— Clouds hide the sun, that shines on other lands. On eastern plains,
                            where ruined temple walls are mouldering fast Mid dusts of age, the bright green mosses
                            blend-On Egypt's arid sands, round old crumbling pillars of the past, Frail tendrils of the
                            vine, heavenward ascend. So without worldly promise, and from the soul that seemeth vile,
                            Out-bursting freshly from the conscious mind, Unlooked for, radiant with glory, celestial
                            blossoms smile— Even here, flowerets of Eden, you may find. Striving for saving faith,
                            spirits bright, come guide and guard me ; And fan to flame .the spark divine within ; That I
                            may watch, and wait, and pray, until the end I see, Standing with God, emancipate from sin.
                            Guardian spirits hold their examples ever bright before me, Who gained salvation in the race
                            they ran ; Teach me, ever through trial, faith and purity. The life of Jesus and our Mother
                            Ann. Trials will surely come—for hearts have ached, and souls have hungered, Eyes have wept
                            blood, and brows with thorns been bound— Prophets, walking through fiery paths, have with
                            the dead been numbered, For martyrdom, some godly few have found. Assured that God's love
                            and tender mercy has no ending, His ear is ever open to my call; On His all bounteous
                            providence, I'm depending, Supported by His power I cannot fall. I shall yet rejoice—will he
                            my slumbering soul awake? Altho' salvation comes through toil anc pain, Should I but work,
                            and weep, heart of mine bat heave and break Beneath His yoke, my sufferings will be gain!
                            Knowing my labors will be blest, and mourning crowned with joy; Sad tears shed now, shall
                            bring me peace and rest; Our God breaketh down to build again, not to destroy; Patient labor
                            ever bringeth faith at last. Heart of mine by trials furrowed, toil sown, watered with soft
                            tears, Under God's sunshine, shall thy harvest come; Arfgels shall come and reap, and lay
                            their • burden at God's feet, so end my fears, Thy will, my Father, and not mine, be done.
                            Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="St. Paul's permissions" TEIform="index"/>ST. PAUL'S PERMISSIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Haskell, Russell" TEIform="persName"/>RUSSELL HASKELL</byline><p TEIform="p">The apostle Paul in some cases advised certain characters to marry, as a protection against
                            gross evils. His advice and permissions were in accordance with the decision of the apostles
                            and elders in Jerusalem, given when a distinction was made between Jewish and Gentile
                            believers ; which someyears afterwards was abolished ; but not till after the destruction of
                            the temple and city of Jerusalem. Soon after that event, many Gentiles, who were determined
                            on having eternal life, gathered in among the Jewish believers, and united with them in
                            following the good Shepherd's voice. As Jesus said. "•Other sheep I have, which are not oi
                            this fold. Them also I must bring, and they shall hear my voice, and there shall be one fold
                            and one Shepherd." If the apostle had intimated that living in certain unchristian
                            indulgences which he permitted, would make them heirs of eternal life, he would have
                            corrupted the gospel; but he did no such thing. For he said, " Be not deceived ; God is not
                            mocked ; for what a man soweth, that shall he also reap. He that soweth to the flesh, shall
                            of his flesh reap corruption : But he that soweth to the spirit, shall of the spirit reap
                            life everlasting." Sowing to the spirit is serving the spirit; bearing the cross, and
                            following Christ in the regeneration ; and the end is life and peace everlasting. But lest
                            some should make a mistake, thinking they might at the same time serve the spirit and the
                            flesh, he says, "They are contrary one to the other ; so that ye cannot do the things that
                            ye would." That ''the carnal mind is enmity against God." Had he stated that the carnal mind
                            is at enmity, the sense of the expression would have been obscure ; for in that case a
                            reconciliation might possibly take place ; but it is enmity itself; and of course never can
                            be reconciled. Yet, to be still more plain, and to put the matter, if possible, beyond all
                            dispute, Paul says, " They that are Christ's have crucified the flesh, wTith the affections
                            and lusts." His permissions of indulgence for the time being, were- not intended for those
                            who had received the faith of the Son of God, which was to walk as he walked. This faith he
                            did not permit them e to cast off"; but said, " Walk in the spirit, and ye will not fulfill
                            the lusts o t. the flesh." Nay, they were not intend ed for those who were looking heaven
                            vard, and seeking eternal life. A conirmation of this is not only found by a general and
                            connected view of the apostle's writings on the subject, but also by an amended translation
                            of the first and second verses of Cor. 7. The learned inform us that the word man in the
                            second verse is not the same word that is so translated in the first verse ; the former
                            signifying man looking upward, and the latter, man looking downward. Therefore the true
                            sense of the original may be expressed as follows : It is good for a man looking z^pward,
                            not to touch a wife. But because of the fornications among you. let every man looking
                            downward, have his own wife, and every woman of like character, her own husband. " I could
                            not write unto you as unto spiritual." Had he considered them as being Christians, those who
                            sowed to the spirit, following him as he followed Christ, he would have found no difficulty
                            in writing to them as unto spiritual ; even as unto those who were not in need of being fed
                            with milk. However, those who would give heed to the apostles' counsel and warning, even if
                            of the weaker class, experienced a degree of reformation ; being saved from fighting with
                            carnal weapons, from lewdness, from lying, from theft and robbery, or from those debasing,
                            heathenish practices which were contrary to the moral law, which would sink them far below
                            the uncorrupted order of nature. Such were held in a measure of relation to those who were
                            spiritual, and were permitted to unite with them in worship for a season. And all who in an
                            outward sense renounced idolatry, and professed to believe that Jesus was the true Messiah,
                            were, by their heathen neighbors, called christians, whether they w7ere deserving the name
                            or not. Soon after the days of the apostles, Cerdon and Marcion, who were considered leaders
                            among the people, formed societies that did not admit of marriage. They strove to adhere to
                            original Christianity by living a virgin life— a life of true self-denial. The apostle Paul,
                            after showing to his people the way of the cross, and also the opposite, with the results of
                            each, left them to choose for themselves. As if he hac said, Will you serve the spirit, and
                            reap life and peace everlasting? or will you serve the flesh, and reap corruption and death?
                            For if ye live after the flesh, ye will die to the spirit. Therefore choose life, I beseech
                            you, by following me even as I follow Christ. The profession of Christianity, in connection
                            with the life of a worldling, is indeed a great inconsistency. Therefore they who do not
                            forsake the earthly order, ought not, by any means, to call themselves Christians. Jesus did
                            not claim them as such, but styled them the children of this world. "All men cannot receive
                            this saying," (that it is not good to marry.) "save them to whom it is given. He that is
                            able to receive it, let him receive it," "Whoever there be of you that forsakes not all that
                            he hath, he cannot be my disciple." "The children of this world" (not Christians,) "marry
                            and are given in marriage:" but Christians " neither marry nor are given in marriage, but
                            are the children of God, being the childi'en of the resurrection." Here, the children of
                            this world are put in contrast with the children of the resurrection, who are in reality
                            Christians, or followers of Christ. In the first appearing of the Christ, which was the
                            third dispensation of God'.s grace, the waters of divine spirituality were only to the
                            loins, as represented in Ezekiel's vision. Accordingly, the weaker class among the Gentile
                            believers, who wTere not strong enough to swim in these waters, might wade ; living a
                            married life under certain restrictions ; abstaining from wantonness or the unfruitful works
                            of darkness. But the second appearance of the Christ was to a Gentile nation and in a female
                            Messiah. This was in order. For in all the works of God there is a unity of design, and
                            harmonious relationship, from beginning to end. First the Jews, who were God's covenant
                            people, were chosen to take the lead. Next in the order of his work were the Gentiles, who
                            were destined, in a subordinate capacity, to render assistance to the Jews. First the man,
                            and after that, the woman. And by this spiritual woman, prophetically styled the Queen, the
                            gospel was manifested in all its pristine purity. And the fullness of that redemption which
                            had been wrought in him, could be administered and take effect throughout the body of the
                            faithful; beginning on earth to be completed in eternity, or beginning in eternity with them
                            who had not previously been called. This could not be effected in the first gospel day ;
                            because the visible headship was incomplete, existing only in the line of the male. In the
                            fourth and last flowing of the holy waters, which Ezekiel saw, they had risen to an
                            unfordable river, "waters to swim in." Consequently, in this last dispensation of the
                            gospel, there must be a complete separation between the earthly and spiritual elements, and
                            souls must be borne up, by the holy waters of life, above the control of earthly
                            attractions; so that not even marriage under any restrictions can have place. For the life
                            of Christ in his people is to them the end of the world. And Jesus said, "This gospel of the
                            kingdom shall be preached in all the world, for a witness to all nations, and then shall the
                            end come." Although none are Christians, only s those who follow Christ in the regen-
                            crating life of the spirit, yet there are / others who may be denominatedFRiENDS 1 to the
                            Christian cause. All who are t seeking to honor God by fearing him aland doing his will in
                            the earthly or out-1 ward order, and who are not as yet t|called of God, by the operation of
                            his 1 spirit upon their souls, to enter into the e strait and narrow path that leads to life
                            e eternal; will experience the blessing of <pb n="84" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. divine
                            providence for their virtuous course, in obeying their highest light, and will not be far
                            from the kingdom of heaven. We, however, believe that the everlasting gospel of Christ,
                            which will finally redeem the soul, not only from all sin, but also from its nature and
                            effects, will, in God's own time, be preached to every human creature either in time or
                            eternity And every one will yet be convinced by the convicting power of the spirit, that it
                            is the true and saving gospel of Christ's second appearing. And all those who. will give
                            heed to its merciful call, by the confession and repentance of every known sin, and by
                            consecrating themselves to the service of God forever, will be secured in his heavenly
                            garner. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God" TEIform="index"/>GOD</head><byline TEIform="byline">[The following beautiful poem is from the Russian Anthology, and was written by the
                            celebrated <persName reg="Derzhavin" TEIform="persName"/>Derzhavin. This poem is said to have been translated
                            into Japanese, by order of the Emperor, and is hung up, embroidered in gold, in the temple
                            of Jeddo. It has also been translated into the Chinese and Tartar languages, written on a
                            piece of rich silk, and suspended in the Imperial Palace atPebin. It is a noble composition,
                            worthy of these honors.]</byline><p TEIform="p">O thou Eternal one ! whose presence bright All space doth occupy—all motions guide; Unchang'd
                            through Time's all devastating flight— Thou only God! There is no God beside— Being above
                            all beings ! Mighty one ! Whom none can comprehend and none explore: Who fillest existence
                            with Thyself alone, Embracing all—supporting—ruling o'er— Being whom we call God—and know no
                            more! In all its sublime research, Philosophy May measure out the ocean deep—may count The
                            sands, or the sun's rays—but God, for Thee There is no weight nor measure; none can mount Up
                            to thy mysteries. Reason's brightest spark, Though kindled by thy light, in vain would try
                            To trace thy counsels, infinite and dark; And thought is lost ere thought can soar so high,
                            Even like past moments in eternity. Thou from primeval nothingness didst call First, chaos;
                            then existence—Lord on Thee Eternity had its foundation ; all Sprung forth from Thee—of
                            light, joy, harmony, Sole origin—all, all beauty Thine ; Thy word created all, and doth
                            create; Thy splendor fills all space with rays divine, Thou art, thou wert, and shalt be
                            glorious ! great! Life-giving, life-sustaining Potentate! Thy chains the unmeasur'd universe
                            surround ; Upheld by Thee, by Thee inspired with breath! Thou the beginning with the end
                            hast bound, And beautifully mingled life with death ! As sparks mount upward from the fiery
                            blaze, So suns ai-e born, so worlds spring forth from Thee! And as the spangles in the sunny
                            rays Shine round the silver snow, the pageantry Of Heaven's bright army glitters in thy
                            praise. A million torches lighted by Thy hand, Wander unwearied through the blue abyss; They
                            own Thy power, accomplish Thy command, All gay with life, all eloquent with bliss. What
                            shall we call them? Piles of crystal light! A glorious company of golden streams! Lamps of
                            celestial ether burning bright? Suns lighting systems with their joyous beams? But Thou to
                            these art as the moon to night. Yes, as a drop of water in the sea; All this magnificence to
                            Thee is lost! What are ten thousand worlds compared to Thee? And what am I then? Heaven's
                            numbered host, Though multiplied by millions and arrayed In all the glory of sublimest
                            thought, Is but an atom in the balance; weighed Against thy greatness—is a cypher brought
                            Against infinity! WhatamI, then?—Naught. Naught!—but the efHuente of Thy light divine,
                            Pervading worlds, hath reached my bosom, too; Yes, in my spirit doth Thy spirit shine. So
                            shines the sun-beam in a drop of dew. Naught! but I live, and on hope's pinions % Eager
                            toward Thy presence; for in Thee I live, I breathe, I dwell; aspiring high, Even to the
                            throne of Thy divinity; I am, O God ! and surely Thou must be ! Thou art! directing, guiding
                            all, Thou art! Direct my understanding then to Thee; Control ray spirit, guide my wandering
                            heart Though but an atom 'midst immensity, Still I am something fashioned by Thy hand ! I
                            hold a middle rank 'twixt heaven and earth, On the last verge of mortal being stand, Close
                            to realms where angels have their birth, Just on the boundaries of the spirit land!</p></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communication from the spirit of Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNICATION FROM THE
                            SPIRIT OF MOTHER ANN LEE</head><p TEIform="p">G. A. LOMAS—My Dear Brother: Spiritual manifestations of all sorts and gradations, as Shaker
                            visionists and mediums prophesied many yeai'S before the Rochester rappings, have truly gone
                            forth into every nation, city, and hamlet, as witnesses of the immortality of the sou.].
                            Accordingly, I find spiritualists in all portions of the earth, and even the distant isles
                            of the ocean. Do you not remember Bishop Heber's hymn, commencing : "From Greenland's icy
                            mountains." And then, these lines : "What though the spicy breezes, Blow soft o'er Agean
                            isles; Though every prospect pleases, And only man is vile." Well, I am here on the Isle of
                            Ceylon, the land of cinnamon gardens, perpetual flowers, eternal summer, noxious insects and
                            huge, poisonous serpents. How true that: "Every pleasure hath its sting, And every sweet a
                            snare." I shall hurry away as soon as I accomplish my mission relative to looking up the
                            records of ancient Buddhism. Kanda, as every scholar knows, was the fountain-head of
                            Buddhism "250 15. C. Since leaving my native land I have met a medium encircled by three
                            grades of spirit intelligences, the higher of which were messengers between the world of
                            spirits, and the diviner realms of celestial life. I inquired of one of these usually
                            controlling spirits while entrancing the medium, if he knew Ann Lee in spirit life? "1 do
                            not personally," was the prompt reply. "She is far above me." Can you communicate with her?
                            "1 can probably so do by proxy—that is to say,—as she is much higher and holier than I am, I
                            can ask one of my teachers—a heavenly messenger, to bear to and receive from her a message,
                            if you so desire." I am anxious to have her answer me a series of questions. "It will be
                            best to prepare them in writing. Read them to me, and I will telegraph them on, by the law
                            of mediation ; and if she is disposed to trust me, I will boar back to you the responses as
                            best I can." Thus encouraged, I prepared the following : To ANN Lee, founder of that Order
                            of Believers known as Shakers : Pardon me for intruding upon one who has so long summered in
                            the heavenly land of promise. Let me assure you, however, that my object in propounding
                            these inquiries is neither curiosity, nor the selfish gain of knowledge; but, it is rather
                            to possess more of that "wisdom which cometh down from above," and which as an apostle said,
                            "is first pure, then peaceable, and full of good fruits and righteousness." In all sincerity
                            of heart then, permit me to ask : I. Do you continue to have a deep interest in Millennial
                            Believers—that body of people known as Shakers ? II. Do you still consider that your mission
                            was heaven-appointed, and that the "Second Coming"— the Christ spirit—was manifest in and
                            through you? III. Do you consider that the genius of true Shakerism, as manifest in and
                            taught by you, and by the pillars of the church, contained the "principles*of progress and
                            the law of unfolding cycles? IV. Is there in the higher heavens a Shaker church
                            triumphant—the New Jerusalem—of which the church*1 of Believers on earth is but a faint
                            reflection? V. Are not you, Jesus, John and other divinely inspired souls, now
                            Christ-angels—ministering to* the church of Believers on earth—to truth-loving aspirational
                            souls in all lands—and to the more receptive in the world of spirits ? VI. If truth is its
                            own authority, should not the teachers and leaders in the Shaker clmrch be governed more by
                            the spirit of truth—the spirit of a living inspiration—than the letter of the law, or the
                            customs of an antiquated past? VII. Do you from your present position see on earth an
                            increasing necessity for a governing celibate order—an order whose solid foundation is
                            purity, peace and all things in common t VIII. Are not the present wars, catastrophes,
                            excitements, struggles, and general unrest prophecies of a future increasing interest in
                            co-operation, communism, and that quickening of the spiritual nature which must ultimate in
                            a flocking to Zion—a vigorous ingathering of her vested souls? IX. Are you acquainted with
                            that distinguished celibate of earth, Giardino Bruno, who was martyred in Rome near the
                            close of the sixteenth century? He resides, I am told, in Pure-love city, and wields great
                            moral power in the world of spirits. X. Have you words of cheer and counsel for me to bear
                            to believers—to those, who, though not having seen, yet love and honor you as Mother? The
                            above questions having been read aloud, the controlling intelligence, putting the medium
                            into a still deeper trance, said "the chain of sympathy is now established; and I will
                            report to you what is given to me." ANN LEE'S RESPONSES. "Turning my mind to that land of
                            spiritual darkness, the earth, I respond through mediating messengers to our servant in the
                            field of reform—the one who calls upon me; and through him, if so desired, to those who
                            often speak of me, though yet dwelling in their tabernacle of clay. "To my dear sisters and
                            brothers upon earth, one and all;—the love of God, the peace of heaven, the patience of the
                            saints, and the purity of the angels be and abide with you, forever. "I. I continue to feel
                            the deepest interest in Believers, and trust that the stream of purity which has flown thus
                            far may continue to flow in every direction, till all souls are washed, and every heart is
                            cleansed m its heavenly waters. Remember, oh, my children, that purity is the key that
                            unlocks the inner gate of paradise. The pure in heart see God. "II. Most conscientiously do
                            I still believe, yea, I know, that my mission on earth was heaven-conceived and divinely
                            directed. And further, it was superintended, under God, by angels and arch-angels, and was,
                            among other things, for the purpose of revealing the Christ-principle in woman, thus
                            establishing the equality of the sexes. But in this I take no honor to myself. It is God
                            that worketh in us through his ministering angels, to will and to do. Accordingly, I humbly
                            bowed in submission to the divine decree that so ordained me to be a vessel, an humble
                            instrument for the divine manifestation. "III. The church of Believers on earth, found in
                            whatever land or clime, has its counterpart in heaven. And this spiritual church,
                            overshadowed by the Christ-spirit, and cared for by the messengers of God, certainly
                            contains the principles of all true spiritual progress. Much that is called progress on
                            earth is not true progress. Fire must try it all. Divine truth is from the heavens, and
                            certain mortals, as well as many in spirit-life, are vessels through which it is poured.
                            Therefore, it is with thanksgiving and with praise that I turn to God, and his holy angels
                            when reflecting upon the principles that I sought, and still seek, to engraft into you. "IV.
                            There is a Divine Church—holy assemblies of brothers and sisters arrayed in white—in heaven,
                            that the dragon cannot hurt! It is the church of purity and progress, and from its
                            life-bearing trees, drop leaves and fruits that tend to the healing of the nations. Many
                            full of the pride of life; many accounted rich and great on earth, have, upon entering the
                            world of spirits, suffered such torments and endured such fiery judgments, that they
                            earnestly, yet meekly and tearfully, cried to God for help, and at once sought the fold of
                            spiritual love and truth. Oh that the children of men would confess, repent of, and turn
                            away from their sins, before summoned to the suffering and discipline that otherwise await
                            them. God is not to be mocked, nor just penalties to be escaped. Those that sow to the flesh
                            reap corruption, while those, and those only, that sow to the spirit and live the calm, pure
                            spiritual life, reap life everlasting. "V. Jesus, and all Christ-angels, are engaged in the
                            blessed work of mediation and ministration. "VI. There is ever a necessit}* for reform in
                            all unclean habits; and for such progressive methods as shall give newness to, and vitalize
                            the past. The most useless things on earth are gravestones; for they neither grow
                            themselves, nor let the grass grow under them. Believers, as a body, may well be compared to
                            a city set upon a hill, a leading purpose of which is to illumine valley lands below. They
                            are also standardbearers ; and as such they should step into the spiritual waters in advance
                            of all others, that the healing waters of life may roll more freely. It is the spirit— the
                            spirit of truth—that giveth life, while the letter killeth. Believers, having been baptized
                            of Christ, and reposing upon the foundation of purity, peace, and a union of inheritance,
                            their principles must necessarily contain the very essence of progress, and will admit of
                            both growth and expansion of method. With the widening of thought, the deepening of wisdom,
                            and the expanding of truth-loving souls, religion, which may be summed up in love—love to
                            God and humanity—should keep pace. Conserve, then, all the good that the fathers and mothers
                            gave; but add ye more good thereto, and thus as the apostle commanded—'grow in grace.' "VII.
                            Looking down upon the world to-day, with its vices; its cloaked contaminations and its
                            polluting virus poisoning the infantile fountains of society, I see the greatest necessity
                            for the most rigid chastity— yea, more, for true celibacy, which is the equivalent of
                            positive purity. Virgin celibacy is as natural to the spiritual, as is polygamy to the
                            animal plane of life. I see pressing requirements for a complete change in the tide of human
                            nature—a change from profligacy, indulgence, and deep-seated worldliness, to the sternest
                            self-denial and virtue. So long as the marriage-beds of earth are the hot-beds of lust, so
                            long will prisons frown, nations fight, the earth mourn, and the ingathering to Zion be
                            stayed. Considering the weakness of human nature, it cannot rest safely half way. To taste
                            is to drain the cup—to drain the cup is to die. Therefore, my words to the world are, handle
                            not—touch not that which defileth; but practice chastity in its most godly sense, ye who are
                            of the world; and ye, oh ye, who have risen into Christ, practice virgin celibacy not only
                            in deed, but hi word and thought. The difference, between spirits and angels, is that the
                            latter are pure. We have here in our angel-world of peace a home—a Mothers' as well as a
                            Fathers' home, where we enjoy all things in common. And we thus enjoy, because we are
                            unselfish; because we love one another; because our life is pure, and because our souls are
                            united together in the spiritual bonds of fellowship and holy affection. 'VIII. There are
                            prophecies almost innumerable that foretell the coming brotherhood and sisterhood of
                            humanity. All pure ideals are ultimately attained; and, by the means of prayer, will-power
                            and work. From the most primitive conditions of the races to the present, the growth has
                            been towards this blessed consummation. Then work ye well; yea, labor diligently, for the
                            time shall come as the fruit of your labors, with the additional labors of heavenly teachers
                            when humanity shall have no despots, no kings, no rulers, no cities, no subjects; for it
                            shall have become one vast community, under the united government of wisdom and love. "IX.
                            Yea; I am aware of Bruno's existence; of the martyrdom he suffered in Rome, and the
                            extensive influence he exerts in his heavenly home of love. "X. There are many things that I
                            would like to say to the inhabitants of earth—and especially to the loving brothers and
                            sisters who in private and in public assemblies name my name. Let me admonish them to
                            perseverance—to patience under trials—to continue instant in prayer, and to give little heed
                            to familiar spirits, who while really of the world, stand behind a screen and delight in
                            much speaking. Though spirits, their spirit-world is the earth-plane of existence. And every
                            communication purporting to come from me that would loosen moral obligation, or lower the
                            standard of personal purity, is from the adversary. The beloved apostle well said—'believe
                            not every spirit; but try the spirits.' Permit me to further say, what has been often said,
                            yet too little heeded by the world—that freedom is the natural result of virtue, love and
                            harmony, guided and controlled by wisdom. All true finite freedom is within the limits of
                            divine law; and obedience to law must precede the ripening of the soul. God is infinitely
                            free because infinitely pure. That which worldly men call freedom, meaning the full exercise
                            of the propensities without restraint, is the deepest and most deadening form of slavery.
                            Such putrid waters drown the soul, and such teachings drag it to perdition. Envy, jealousy,
                            lust and kindred passions, are not to be modified and regulated, as some blind teachers have
                            taught; they are to be extirpated, annihilated! Freedom, based upon obedience, and practical
                            godliness, with the exercise of prayer) brings the soul into communion with the
                            Christ-angels. And these often draw near to you in your devotions, and shed upon you their
                            sweet and heavenly influences. The prayed-for increase will come—the invisible forces of
                            heaven are at work— there is a leavening power going on in the widespread field of
                            humanity—the darkness is breaking— and the long, tearful serving shall surely bring golden
                            sheaves to Zion. And then, the fullness of times having come, shall the church, humble in
                            victory, become the glory of our God. To the families, and all true, unselfish workers on
                            earth, I say, God bless you—let your light shine—continue faithful—be forgiving— love one
                            another with the love that angels know. And, oh, my children in Zion, think of the depths of
                            a mother's love—listen to her voice of admonition—pray in your times of labor for the
                            presence of heavenly hosts sing with the spirit and with the understanding—worship, in song
                            and speech, in march and dance, with enthusiasm. Shake away all vain worldliness, struggle
                            to conquer the apathy and selfishness of yourselves— 84: <pb n="85" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 85
                            strive to be living stones of crystal whiteness in the temple of God, and fruitful branches
                            upon that vine of which Christ is the root. I know your trials and your tribulations. They
                            are trifling compared to the sufferings and martyrdom of the 144,000 seen in the Revelator's
                            vision. Numbers do not constitute strength. Jesus trod the wine-press alone. Be patient,
                            then;—drink from the fountain that quenched the thirst of prophets and apostles—abide by the
                            law and the testimony—walk humbly, trustingly by the still waters—yea, walk and worship in
                            the beauty of holiness—walk, too, in the ways of simplicity, and keep the faith, till the
                            harvesters, the Christ-angels of the resurrection, put upon your heads crowns of life, into
                            your hands palms of victory, and upon your spiritual bodies robes of purity, preparatory to
                            a glorious and victorious entrance into the blessed and peaceful home of immortality." Thus
                            ends the message. If true in the past it is equally true in the present, that, "without a
                            vision the people perish." Visions, trances, prophecies, spiritual gifts and seasons of
                            worship are all helps to higher spiritual attainments. I believe this communication in the
                            form of answers to my questions, to have emanated mediately from Ann Lee, the blacksmith's
                            daughter, the Christ-appointed Mother! But the very fact of mediations, and fallible
                            channels, implies modification and non-infallibility. Accordingly all communications and
                            revelations necessarily partake of individual idiosyncracies. The Indian chief said of the
                            interpreter, "His much words no just give my meaning—blow through onion stalk, breath smell
                            onion 'tother end." Though the Indian's dialect was rough, and his illustration homely,
                            nevertheless it contained a very practical idea. In conclusion, I have to say that in this
                            matter I sought to be a faithful amanuensis, taking down the sentences as they dropped from
                            the medium's lips. Mother Ann's words to me personally, while piercing as a two-edged sword,
                            were both encouraging and beautiful. She is certainly an exalted and holy angel of love with
                            the Christ-principle of purity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/>J. M. Peebles. Point de Galle, Isle of Ceylon, August 2,
                            1877</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers, no. 7" TEIform="index"/>Epitomic History of the
                            Watervliet Shakers. No. 7</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">CONCERNING DRESS : WITH CLOSING REMARKS. Do people commonly change their costumes of dress
                            with a view of improving upon the past, making the new more convenient, plain and simple? We
                            could hardly judge this to be the case, when viewing their grotesque appearances. Novelty
                            and gorgeous display predominate over consistency—the rich seeking to outshine their
                            neighbors and the poorer classes, by appearing in garbs which none but they can well afford.
                            These changes are, manytimes, from bad to worse, and of a very extravagant nature. The
                            Shakers do not consider it wise, nor in any degree profitable, for them to compete with the
                            general world in this. They have no desire to make that gaudy appearance, nor outward
                            adornment of their persons, that many people seem to have. We choose to be clad decently,
                            comfortably, in a manner consistent with reason and good economy. Uniformity of appearance
                            in all things, is what is aimed at. None rich, and none poor; all fare and share alike,
                            consistent with needs and circumstances. The world of mankind everywhere needs more of this
                            leveling sys tern, to bring it right,—greater equality in all things needful, that the many,
                            as well as the few, may enjoy life. Man, in cultivating the soil economically, has recourse
                            to the leveling process, taking from the hills to raise the valleys, and both thereby become
                            improved. So, also, in the construction of railroads, canals, and other important
                            improvements for the country'sgood, it is found necessary to cut through or under mountains,
                            and in some way to cause the high lands to aid in the accomplishment of a level. Why not
                            then, the wealthy, in like manner, assist the needy, raise the destitute and degraded out of
                            their sloughs of woe ; and thereby lessen the evils that now exist in society? Cause the
                            naked to be clothed, the hungry to be fed, the homeless to be cared for, and the sick and
                            infirm to feel the sympathy of generous hands. If the people of this enlightened country and
                            Christian age are not prepared to adopt the apostolic mode of living—community of
                            interests,—holding all things in common let them approximate thereunto as near as
                            practicable. We, as Shakers, are enjoying, in a good measure, the benefits of the leveling
                            system of living; not yet attained to its fullness, but are progressing. We would be glad to
                            see thousands and tens of thousands engaged in the good cause, and thus bring on the earth "
                            peace and good will." When the Shakers have adopted any particular fashion of dress, and
                            have arriven at some suitable uniformity, they do not like to depart from that uniformity.
                            Nevertheless, when we have become convinced that a change is necessary, and that we should
                            be benefited by making it, and such change has the general approbation of the members of our
                            community, we then move cordially into it; not for display of outward appearance, but for
                            comfort and profit, all the members participating. In the first establishment of the Shaker
                            institution, they then adopted the same kind of dress made use of by the common people, and
                            have constantly adhered to the same, with some trifling deviations, until of late years. We
                            are now passing through a change, both in the color of our garments and the manner of
                            cutting and making them. Consequently, we do not appear at present so uniformly clad ; but
                            eventually shall become more so. We are not so superstitious in our notions, nor set in our
                            views, that we cannot alter when we have become sensible that such change will affect us for
                            good. Progression is one of the prominent points of our religious faith, and we endeavor to
                            make it manifest in things spiritual and temporal. In some things of a business nature, we
                            have been too anxious to move ahead, and have suffered loss by so doing. Some societies have
                            entered into the factory business, without very piT&gt;fitable results. The banking
                            business, so far as it was engaged in, proved a failure. Flouring mills, on any considerable
                            scale, instead of finding them adapted to our conditions, have generally proved the reverse.
                            It seems not proper for Believers to be over-anxious about the things of this life—" laying
                            up treasures on earth"—to the detriment of their spiritual travel ; but to let each have its
                            proper bearing, "seeking first of all the kingdom of heaven." This has been the counsel of
                            our worthy predecessors, and we must respond thereto in heart and hand. In closing this, the
                            last of a series of numbers which have appeared in The Shaker under the general head of
                            "Epitomic History of the Watervliet Shakers," the writer would here politely remark, by way
                            of apology, that he has been induced to give the brief statements of matters, in confutation
                            of many current reports of unfriendly persons, who seemed to take pleasure in
                            misrepresenting the people called "¦Shakers," as being " ignorant, superstitious and
                            unprogressive—far, far behind the age in which they live." From such remarks, to him seeming
                            so untrue, he was led to investigate more fully for himself, by comparing and contrasting
                            the present enterprising and flourishing condition of the Society, with that of the past,
                            even irom its commencement. Being in possession of records showing the early rise and
                            progress of the Watervliet Shakers, together with his own personal knowledge and experience
                            of nearly sixty years' membership thereof, he has been enabled to state, fairly and
                            truthfully, the facts presented. It is true, the Shakers have been under the necessity of
                            moving cautiously, guarding: on all sides against the evils of the world, both from without
                            and within ; temporally, morally and spiritually. Having fully tested the groimd over which
                            they have traveled, they are now ready and willing to declare to the world what the work has
                            done for them as a people ; and leave it for others to judge of what it may yet do for as
                            many of humanity as are willing, truly and sincerely, to progress therein. To accumulate
                            wealth has not been the prevailing motive and object of the Shaker institution ; but to work
                            out the great social and spiritual problems of "community life"—of people dwelling together
                            in peace and harmony, in united capacity, having all things in common. In taking this step,
                            Believers have found it necessary to do as did the original, apostolic Christian church,
                            —seeking to become clad in all heavenlv graces, that adorn the true Christian character, —
                            actually commencing the angel life while here on earth. Jesus, the Christ, taught his
                            disciples to pray : " Thv kingdom come. Thy will be done in earth, as it is in heaven." To
                            bring about this good state of things, we must not onty ftray, but work— work daily, and in
                            earnest. Cures for household pests.—Rats are said to have such a dislike to potash, that if
                            it is powdered and scattered around their haunts they will leave them. A piece of rag well
                            soaked in a strong solution of cavenne is a capital thing to put into rat or mice holes, as
                            they will not attempt to eat it. A plug oi wood covered with a piece of flannel so prepared
                            may be used to fill up the holes. Cockroaches and ants have a similar dislike to cayenne,
                            and a little strewed about the cellai will keep it clear of them. Abuse, like other poison,
                            when administered in too strong a dose is thrown off by the intended victims, and often
                            relieves where it was meant to destroy.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker church covenant in two numbers, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER CHURCH COVENANT. IN TWO
                            NUMBERS. NUMBER TWO</head><p TEIform="p">ARTICLE IV. Of the Eldership. Section i. Choice and appointment of Elders: The united
                            interests and objects of believers established in Gospel order, require that Elders should
                            be chosen and appointed for the spiritual protection of families, whose business it is to
                            take the lead in their several departments in the care and government of the concerns of the
                            Church and of the different families established in and pertaining to the Society. Their
                            number and order should correspond with that of the Ministry. They are required to be
                            persons of good understanding, of approved faithfulness and integrity, and gifted in
                            spiritual administration. They must be selected and appointed by the Ministry, who are to
                            judge of their qualifications. Section 2. Duties of the Elders: As faithful watchmen upon
                            the walls of Zion, it becomes the duty of the Elders to watch over their respective
                            families; to instruct the members in their respective duties ; to counsel, encourage,
                            admonish, exhort and reprove as occasion may require; to lead the worship ; to be examples
                            to the members, of obedience to the principles and orders of the Gospel, and to see that the
                            orders, rules and regulations pertaining to their respective families or departments are
                            properly kept. ARTICLE V. Of Fa.7nily Deacons and Deaconesses Section i. Their
                            qualifications and appointments : The office of family Deacons and Deaconesses has long been
                            established in the Church, and is essentially necessary for the care, management and
                            direction of the domestic concerns in each family, order or branch of the Church. They are
                            required to be persons of correct and well-grounded faith in the established principles of
                            the Gospel, faithful in duty, closely united to their Elders, and of sufficient capacity in
                            business. Of their qualifications, the Ministry and Elders by whom they are chosen and
                            appointed must be the judges. Their number in each family is generally two of each sex, but
                            may be more or less, according to the size of the family and the extent of their various
                            duties. Section 2. Their duties and obligations : The Deacons and Deaconesses of families
                            are intrusted with the care and over-sight of the domestic concerns of their respective
                            families. It is their duty to make proper arrangements in business; to maintain good order;
                            watch over, counsel and direct the members in their various occupations, as cccasion may
                            require; to make application to the office Deacons or Trustees for whatever supplies are
                            needed in the several departments of the family; to maintain union, harmonv and good
                            understanding with the said office Deacons ; and to report to their Elders, the state of
                            matters which fall under their cognizance and observation. But their power is restricted to
                            the domestic concerns of their respective families and departments, and does not extend to
                            any immediate or direct correspondence with those without the boundaries of the Church. They
                            have no immediate concern with trade and commerce, therefore it is not their business to buy
                            and sell, nor in any way to dispose of Jhe property under their care, except with the
                            counsel and approbation of the Trustees. ARTICLE VI. Privileges and Obligations of Members.
                            Section i. Benefits and privileges of members in church relation : The united interest of
                            the Church having been formed and established by the freewill offerings and pious donations
                            of the mem- <pb n="86" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE SHAKER,. bers respectively, from the commencement of
                            the institution for the object and purposes already stated, it cannot be considered either
                            as a joint tenancy or a tenancy in common, but as a consecrated whole, designed for and
                            devoted to the uses and purposes of the Gospel forever, agreeable to the established
                            principles of the Church : Therefore it shall be held, possessed and enjoyed by the Church,
                            in their united capacity, as a sacred and covenant right: That is to say, all and every
                            member thereof, while standing in Gospel union and maintaining the principles of this
                            Covenant, shall enjoy equal rights, betiejits and ^privileges, in the use of all things
                            pertaining to the Church, according to their several needs and circumstances ; and no
                            difference shall be made on account of what any one has contributed and devoted, or may
                            hereafter contribute and devote to the support and benefit of the institution. Section 2.
                            Proviso : It is nevertheless stipulated and agreed that the benefits, privileges and
                            enjoyments secured by this Covenant to the members of the Church, shall not be considered as
                            extending to any person who shall refuse to comply with the conditions of this association ;
                            or who shall refuse to submit to the admonition and discipline of the constituted authority
                            of the Church; or who shall willfully depart from the principles and practice of those
                            religious and moral obligations which have been established in the Church, agreeable to the
                            primitive faith and distinguished principles of this institution; of which refusal or
                            non-compliance the leading authority acknowledged in the first article of this Covenant
                            shall be the proper and constitutional judges. Section 3. Obligations of the members : As
                            subordination and obedience is the life and soul of every well-regulated community, so our
                            strength and protection,our happiness and prosperity, in our capacity of Church members,
                            must depend on our faithful obedience to the rules and orders established in the Church, and
                            to the instruction, counsel and advice of its leaders. Therefore, we do hereby covenant and
                            agree that we will receive and acknowledge, as our Elders in the Gospel, those members in
                            the Church who are or may be chosen and appointed for the time being to that office and
                            calling by the authority aforesaid; and also that we will, as faithful brethren and sisters
                            in Christ, conform and subject ourselves to the known and established faith and principles
                            of our community, and to the counsels and directions of the Elders, who shall act in union,
                            as aforesaid, and also to all the orders, rules and regulations which are or may be given
                            and established in the Church, according to the principles and by the authority aforesaid.
                            Section 4. Duties of the members : The faithful improvement of our time and talents in doing
                            good, is a duty which God requires of man, as a rational, social and accountable being, and
                            this duty is indispensable in the members of the Church of Christ. Therefore, it is and
                            shall be required of all and every member of this institution, unitedly and individually, to
                            occupy and improve their time and talents to support and maintain the interest of the
                            Society, to promote the objects of this Covenant, and discharge their duty to God and each
                            other according to their several abilities and callings, as members in union with one common
                            lead; so that the various gifts and talents of all may be improved for the mutual benefit of
                            each other and all concerned. Section 5. As we.esteem the mutual possession and enjoyment of
                            the consecrated interest and privileges of the Church a valuable consideration, fully
                            adequate to any amount of personal interest, labor or service, devoted or consecrated by any
                            individual; we, therefore, covenant and agree, in conformity with an established and
                            well-known principle of the Church, that no person whatever under its care and portection,
                            can be employed for wages of any kind, on his or her individual account, and that no ground
                            is or can be afforded for the recovery of any property or service devoted or consecrated as
                            aforesaid; and it is also agreed that in case of the removal of any member or members from
                            one family, society or branch of the Church to another, his, her or their previous signature
                            or signatures to the Church or Family Covenant from whence such member or members shall have
                            removed, shall forever bar all claims which are incompatible with the true intent and
                            meaning" of this Covenant, in the same manner as if such removal had not taken place. Yet
                            all Avho shall so remove, in union with the authority aforesaid, shall be entitled to all
                            the benefits and privileges of the Order in which they shall then be placed, so long as they
                            shall conform to the rules and regulations of the same. ARTICLE VII. Dedication and Release.
                            Section i. Dedication and consecration of persons, property and service : According to the
                            faith of the Gospel which we have received and agreeable to the uniform practice of the
                            Church of Christ from its first establishment in this Society, we covenant and agree to
                            dedicate, devote, consecrate and give up, and by this Covenant we do solemnly and
                            conscientiously dedicate, devote, consecrate and give up ourselves and ervices together with
                            all our temporal interest to the service of God and the support and benefit of the Church of
                            this community, and to such other pious and charitable purposes as the Gospel may require,
                            to be under the care and direction of such Elders, Deaccfns, and Trustees as are or may be
                            appointed and established in the Church by the authority aforesaid. Section 2. Dedication
                            and release of private claim : Whereas, in pursuance of the requirement of the Gospel, and
                            in the full exercise of our faith, reason and understanding, we have freely and voluntarily
                            sacrificed all self-interest, and consecrated and devoted our persons, services and
                            property, as aforesaid, to the pious and benevolent purposes of the Gospel: Therefore, we do
                            hereby solemnly and conscientiously, unitedly and individually for ourselves and our heirs,
                            release and quit claim to the Deacons, or acting Trustees of the Church for the time being,
                            for the uses and purposes aforesaid, all our private personal right, title, interest, claim
                            and demand of, in and to the estate, interest, property, and appurtenances so consecrated,
                            devoted and given up; and we hereby jointly and severally promise and declare in the
                            presence of God, and before these witnesses that we will never hereafter, neither directly
                            nor indirectly, under any circumstances whatever, contrary to the stipulations of this
                            Covenant, make nor require any account of any interest, property, labor nor service, nor
                            anjT division thereof which is, has been, or may bedevoted by us, or any of us to the uses
                            and purposes aforesaid, nor bring any charge of debt or damage, nor hold any claim, nor
                            demand whatever against the said Deacons nor Trustees, nor against the Church nor Society,
                            nor against any member thereof, on account of any property or service given, rendered,
                            devoted or consecrated to the aforesaid sacred and charitable purposes. In confirmation of
                            all the aforesaid statements, covenants, promises, and articles of agreement, we have
                            hereunto subscribed our names and affixed our seals, commencing on this--------day
                            of-------- in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and-----The transmutation of
                            meals is a small affair compared with changing shame to glory; reverses to success, sorrows
                            to pleasures ; yet true wisdom can do all this,</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our invitation" TEIform="index"/>OUR INVITATION</head><p TEIform="p">A short time since, we wrote of our willingness to cordially unite, in church and life
                            worship, with any other denomination, whose theological teachings would lead us into more
                            Christian love and self-denial; into a more practical work of the Christ spirit, as
                            manifested in and through the life of Jesus. As yet we have received no invitations ! We
                            therefore invite investigationsby the general churches—a most thorough analysis of Shaker
                            polity, principles and living results. We invite those who would be better than good
                            Methodists, Baptists, Presbyterians, Roman Catholics, etc., to engage in more of the
                            practical self-denials of Jesus; and while thereby showing a genuine love for him, they will
                            realize more of the baptism of his spirit. More self-denial is the desiderata. As Shakers,
                            we ask of all would-be Christians : A virgin celibacy in life, after the pattern of Jesus. A
                            universal love for all who do the will of the Father, by denying self, faring and sharing
                            all they possess equally and together. A peaceful, unwarlike, unworldly spirit, as
                            illustrated by that lowly, beautiful, Christian, Jesus. A separation from the world and its
                            sins, by confession and renunciation of its evils and its good I even as did Jesus. Such
                            life is to us genuine Christian life. Full of crosses, until these are worn into crowns of
                            glory ; but are there more crosses herein than Jesus bore, or more crowns than he wore? We
                            now send an invitation to those only who are able to be thus Christian, for the kingdom of
                            heaven's sake, on the earth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker inventions" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER INVENTIONS</head><p TEIform="p">In his history of Watervliet Shakers, our valued correspondent—Elder D. A. Buckingham—related
                            several valuable inventions that originated among our people. It seems to have attracted
                            considerable attention from the general Press; and led us to inquire whether the list of
                            inventions was complete. By a little inquiry, we have learned, that ten years before the
                            appliance of the screw propeller system of navigation, it was put into operation by one
                            Thomas Wells, of Watervliet, now Shakers, N. Y. That the first matching of boards and plank
                            by machinery in this country, was enacted at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., by Henry Bennett and Amos
                            Bishop, in 1S1 ^—they using vertical rollers to hold the lumber straight, and ropes and
                            windlass to propel the same over circular saws—first making the groove, then the tongue. In
                            1828, Woodworth invented the now common and improved system. Webster, in his Dictionary,
                            says that " Babbitt-metal was named after the inventor." This is untrue ; for it was the
                            invention of Daniel N. Baird, of North Union Shakers, Ohio. A few years since, certain
                            parties had suits in the courts ror infringements ; and we remember Bro. Daniel N. Baird to
                            have been subpoenaed as a witness, wherein his claim as the inventor of " Babbitt-metal" was
                            established. He was also the originator of the rotary, or revolving harrow, although it was
                            patented by another, after seeing the one of Baird's. At South Union, Ky., Sanford J.
                            Russell has invented and patented a sash balance, by which one sash is made to balance the
                            other, without the usual cords, pulleys, etc. Hie Scientific American says of it
                            additionally: "The best ventilator known, moved at the touch, and for fifteen cents
                            additional cost, may be locked at any desired point." M. B. Carter, formerly of Whitewater
                            Village, but now, we believe, of Union Village, O., invented a very ingenious governor for
                            over-shot water-wheels. And, if we mistake not, an improved wind-mill was invented by one of
                            the Canterbury brethren. A most beautiful folding stereoscope was, a few years ago,
                            invented, and, we believe, patent applied for, by Nelson Chase, of Enfield, N. H., Society.
                            By those who have seen this latter invention, it is pronounced unequaled for beauty and
                            convenience. We recall the skill of Bro. G. M. Wickersham, as applied to a summer covering
                            for a sad-iron stove, by which, the hotter the fire, the cooler the room ! We met Sewell G.
                            Thayer in New York, getting a patent on a stove-cover lifter, which lifter was kept always
                            on hand, always in one place when not being used, and finding and keeping its own place,
                            regardless of careless heads ! This was a North Union invention. The first one-horse wagon
                            was introduced to the world of travelers by Enfield. Conn., brethren. Let every one using
                            the single vehicle, render due credit. Previous to horse-collars, pads, under the hames of
                            harnesses, were used. These were invented by Henry Bennett, of Shakers, N. Y. And we will
                            close the list of special inventions by naming cut nails; they being the invention of a
                            party at Shakers, N. Y. ; which assertion we are abundantly able to justify, having some of
                            the original machinery on hand at present time. We might mention, with exceedingly large
                            credit, the valuable and indispensable machinery invented and manufactured by Elders D.
                            Boler and D. Crosman, for splint-making, basketworking, and box-cutting apparatus, at Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. And still the list is incomplete. Shaker minds tend to the inventive, moral
                            and spiritual. Other inventions will follow. Personal modesty forbids our saying much of a
                            prospective one, which may stir the entire world of letters. We will be patient. But we ask,
                            where, among a congregation of so few people, more needful inventions, or those more
                            valuable to humanity generally, have found an outlet?</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hard words mostly flow from soft heads" TEIform="index"/>Hard words mostly flow from soft heads
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Hard words mostly flow from soft heads.</p></div2><pb n="87" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War, not Christian, but barbarous" TEIform="index"/>WAR, NOT CHRISTIAN, BUT BARBAROUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We ought to learn an important lesson by the present European war; and this: That war is
                                all brutal, the antipode of Christianity. On which side is the greater brutality
                                manifested? We cannot decide. Both are as brutal as they well can be. Standing aloof
                                from this quarrel, so-called Christian America should view with a holy horror any
                                attachment of the name of Christian to any war whatever. We think it is far more
                                honorable to be a heathen Mohammedan in this fight, than to fight worse than a Turk—be a
                                greater brute, while wearing a very, very peaceable name ! Wars, of households or of
                                nations, are without the pale of Christianity ; and any nation keeping a standing army,
                                or a national guard of militia, has not even the smell of Christianity about it; but has
                                much of the odors of the hells ! Jesus was Prince of Peace ; all wars are of the
                            devil.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Polygamy—monagamy" TEIform="index"/>POLYGAMY—MONOGAMY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We must not forget the old adage about "people who live in glass houses should not throw
                                stones." Brigham Young is dead. To the majority of people, his greatest crime was
                                polygamy. If we find any fault with Brigham for this, we must also find the same fault
                                with very many scriptural characters. David, for instance, was a man after the God of
                                Polygamy's heart. Brigham had just as much right to'his many wives as David, Solomon,
                                etc. Many wives or one wife are all unchristian—find no sanction in the life of the
                                Christian exampler—Jesus. But we have some good thoughts of Brigham. He was,
                                undoubtedly, a man of extreme sensual passions. Dividing these passions among many
                                wives, fai less harm and brutality ware done than very many a so-ca41ed Christian enacts
                                with one miserable woman, called by his name. We sorrow for the woman who is subjected,
                                against her will, to the worse than brutal passions of hei anti-christian master ; and
                                if called on to decide the greater display of merciful morality, we would unhesitating!}
                                recommend polygamy. But while neither polygamy nor monogamy are in the least Christian,
                                monogamy, for the indulgence of libidinous passions only is less so than polygamy.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oral confession" TEIform="index"/>ORAL CONFESSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The excitement of the English churches over the proposed introduction of oral confession,
                                as a sacrament, into the demands of the Episcopal persuasion, does not die away yet. Why
                                should it? By what authority did the originators of that church do away with the
                                confession of sin? "Confess your sins, one to another!" The Baptists "baptize ;" but
                                they neglect the weightier matter of " confessing their sins." It may be Roman Catholic
                                to confess orally, but it is none the less Christian for that. In our opinion, while
                                acknowledging the prostitution of power by the priests, and much dead cere|mony of the
                                Roman church, yet the Episcopal must progress very much before they can present as many
                                Christian features as the Romans. Let them progress into oral confession—make
                                priestesses of women, and let each sex confess and be ministered to by its own sex. This
                                will excel the Romans !</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks" TEIform="index"/>PLAIN TALKS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Another edition of Plain Talks— our late pamphlet of 24 pp.—is called for from several
                                directions. We are happily disappointed, in that it proves not to be too ^plain. By
                                some, east and west, it is deemed an invaluable assistant, in answering very many
                                questions most likely to rise in an inquirer's mind. The second edition is entirely
                                exhausted — even novitiate elders we find are pretty close with the bait—and we have had
                                calls for two hundred and fifty copies which we could not supply. So soon as we can get
                                sufficient encouragement to pay for half an edition of one thousand copies, we will
                                trust providence for the means whereby the balance—twenty-five dollars—can be secured.
                                It will be comforting to any to add a missionary to aid in the spread of our gospel
                                work. Five cents each from one-half of the household of faith would print and circulate
                                a very large edition ! Who will take hold of the project?</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession of sins" TEIform="index"/>Confession of sins
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Confession of^sins.—The N.. T. Indefendent speaks very correctly on the subject in the
                            following quotations. We think that, " whatever is inconsistent with a pure Christian life,"
                            will include other practices and lusts not named herein by it.—Ed. " Confession of sin is a
                            chief test of repentance, and without repentance there is no religion. If we are sorry we
                            have done wrong, we will be likely to say so, and will be sure to sav so to th«se whom we
                            have wronged.1 The Bible very frequently insists on confession if we would be forgiven. "
                            Even better than confession is the evident putting away of the sins of an evil life,
                            especially where it is at some cost to us. There is not much magic practiced now; but those
                            who repent must put away their sins, of whatever sort. The Ephesian converts burned their
                            books of magic. Nowadays a convert will destroy his liquors, perhaps his cards and tobacco,
                            or whatever he thinks is inconsistent with a pure, Christian life. Thus he gives the best
                            evidence that he is in earnest. It is likely to be a genuine repentance that will conquer
                            our love of money, and will rule our pockets. "A confession and repentance that will do such
                            deeds as these done by the Ephesian converts will have power over the world. Such
                            self-denial attracts attention, and the conscience of everybody approves it. Here is a
                            suggestion to our churches to-day, ii they would be successful. Let them put away their sins
                            and be in earnest." Dear Editor—I do not know where I cut these lines from, but they are
                            suggestive that permanent peace must rest upon right. f. w. evans.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wait a while" TEIform="index"/>WAIT A WHILE</head><p TEIform="p">First, there are the poor, mark of every slaughter, Cesspools at their door, sewage in their
                            water; In each crowded dwelling poisoned air and vile, So you'll hear them telling, if
                            you'll only wait a while. Next, there is the drink, licensed source of ruin ; For
                            magistrates must wink at what their friends are brewing; Madness, murder, riot—on it all
                            they smile; But tho' men keep quiet, yet it's only for a while. ?hen, too, there's the land;
                            poor folk cannot get it; landlords understand too well how to let it; ?armers, once
                            contented, now begin to rile; Swear they're over-rented, and they'll show it in a while. And
                            is there no cure for wealth's distribution ? iere great riches, lucre! there great
                            destitution ! Can these camps divided nothing reconcile? So it seems decided, but it's only
                            for a while. Dnce I saw a ship on a calm sea swaying, The least finger-tip at its helm
                            obeying; n the distance heaving rose a cloudy pile, 3ut men unbelieving mocked it for
                            awhile,— 3ut 'twas only for a little, for a very little while.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Green, Ruth A." TEIform="index"/>Ruth A. Green
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., Sept. 23, 1877, aged 62 years, <persName reg="Green, Ruth A." TEIform="persName">Ruth A.
                                    Green</persName>. Beautiful by nature, and made more so by gospel graces, we
                                sorrowed to part with her.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Holt, John" TEIform="index"/>John Holt
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, Oct. 8, <persName reg="Holt, John" TEIform="persName">John Holt</persName>, aged 60.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turney, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Turney
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., Oct. 10, 1877, <persName reg="Turney, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly Turney</persName>,
                                aged 64. She turned her back to the world ; lived and died according to her first
                            faith.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Composition" TEIform="index"/>Composition
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Composition.—Here is a composition written by a boy of South Danvers, Mass. Let timid
                            contributors to The Shaker take courage. Let us hear from you. ''South Danvers is in the
                            United States. It js bounded by Salem and reaches to Middleton. Its principal river is
                            Goldthwaite's brook, which empties into Salem harbor. Its principal lake is the mill-pond,
                            which is dry in the summer. Its principal productions are leather, onions, the South Church
                            and George Peabody. South Danvers has many religious sects, among which are the Orthodox,
                            who worship their minister; the Spiritualists, who worship everything; and the Unitarians,
                            who worship nothing."</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How many pray thus?" TEIform="index"/>How many pray thus?
                        </head><p TEIform="p">*Io\v many ^ray thus'?—A work recently published in London, entitled " English
                            Eccentricities," contains the following prayer: " Lord, thou knowest that I possess nine
                            houses in the city of London, and that I have recently bought an estate in the county of
                            Essex. Preserve, therefore, I pray thee, the two counties of Middlesex and Essex from fires
                            and earthquakes. And, as I have an hypothecated estate in Hertfordshire, look also in
                            compassion on that county. As to the mher portions of the country, do as thou wilt. Lord,
                            consolidate the Royal Bank, that it may honor its notes. Let all my debtors be or become
                            honest men. Give a prosperous and speedy passage to the sloop Mermaid, for the insurance of
                            which I am responsible. Preserve me from robberies and brigands. Make all my servants
                            faithful and devoted, that they may watch over my interests and relax not their diligence by
                            day or by night."</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worth knowing" TEIform="index"/>WORTH KNOWING</head><p TEIform="p">Brimstone matches.—It will pay to save matches. Get a piece of pine plank two inches square,
                            and six inches long. Put one end in a vise—the lower end—and split first into thin slabs
                            across the top. Turn the block in the vise, and split the other way in to pieces as large as
                            matches. Turn again as before, in the vise, squeezing harder than before, and it will
                            separate the tops of the sticks. Sprinkle dry sand over the distendec tops, and take from
                            the vise. The sand wil keep each stick separate. Now, dip the ends, very slightly in melted
                            brimstone, and you have very good substitutes for matches wherever there are coals or flames
                            to ignite them. Besides, for one cent's worth of brim stone, you can thus manufacture
                            thousand of matches. We use them freely, for light ing lanterns, etc., from other lamps.
                            Shaving cuts.—Do you shave yourself If you do, you sometimes get a slight cut, o your beard
                            may pull out, so that blood wil come. We have seen, from slight cuts on some persons' faces,
                            the blood flow unusually free. As soon as cut, take a small piece oi he margin of a
                            newspaper—the poorer the quality the better—and stick on dry, holding t for a few seconds.
                            The cut will cease bleeding, and heal immediately. The first trial will surprise you. One
                            thousand shingles, laid four inches to the weather, will cover one hundred square feet of
                            surface, and five pounds of shingle nails will fasten them on. One fifth more siding and
                            flooring is needed than the number of square feet of surface to be covered, because of the
                            lap in the siding and matching of the floor. One thousand laths will cover seventy ya*"ds of
                            surface, and eleven pounds of lath nails will nail them on. Eight bushels of good lime,
                            sixteen bushels of sand, and one bushel of hair, will make enough good mortar to plaster one
                            hundred square yards. A cord of stone, three bushels of lime, and a cubic yard of sand, will
                            lay one hundred cubic feet of wall. Five courses of brick will lay one foot in height on a
                            chimney, six bricks in a course will make a flue four inches wide and twelve inches long,
                            and eight bricks in a course will make a flue eight inches wide and sixteen inches long.
                            True benevolence.—If it should ever be my fortune to discover or invent anything that can be
                            of lasting benefit to humanity, I am resolved never to turn it to a pecuniary, personal
                            profit. I believe it my duty, and the same of every individual, ever to perform sufficient
                            manual labor, to supply my physical necessities.—Levin Robbins, Whitewater,O.</p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Condensations" TEIform="index"/>CONDENSATIONS</head><p TEIform="p">Prof. Newcomb believes that the newly discovered moons of Mars, are of recent origin ; and
                            were undoubtedly supplied from an asfceroidal belt surrounding our planetary scheme. A
                            writer in Journal of Anatomy states that at every beat of the heart, the whole body is
                            projected a small, but perfectly observable motion in a direction of foot to head. Herr von
                            Hensen found that each acre of ground contains, on an average, 34,000 earth worms ; each
                            worm weighing but 46 grains, and producing in four hours nearly 8 grains of excrementitious
                            matter. The worms per acre weigh 224 pounds, producing a uniform mold of 37 pounds, every 24
                            hours ! Thus can their value be easily imagined. The Scientific American says that a good
                            cement for fork and knife handles may be made of one pound of rosin; half pound of powdered
                            sulphur; melt together; mix in twelve ounces of fine sand; use while warm. The handles of no
                            knives nor forks ever should be put into hot water. Tennessee lady named Ingram has
                            discovered that all the mosquitoes of a room may be killed by exploding a small amount of
                            gunpowder in the center of the room, by the force of concussion. Herein is a good use for
                            fire-crackers. There are many patent medicines bearing the name of some prominent root,
                            herb, etc., which do not contain any of said articles. For instances : "Schenck's Mandrake
                            Pills"— th^y contain no mandrake! and "Bishop's Citrate of Magnesia" contains neither citric
                            acid nor magnesia! Would not the cessation of building soldier's monuments be a fine idea,
                            at least, until the money could be better spared, by the almost innumerable widows and
                            children? Glue is damaged by frequent heating and boiling. The hotter it can be applied to
                            joints, the stronger it will hold,</p></div2><pb n="88" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beacon" TEIform="index"/>THE BEACON</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. Andante. 1. Far out upon Life's ocean, We see the coming sail—! Its waves
                            are in commotion As 2. Hold out the beacon clearly, Salvation's glorious ray ; Not in the
                            past, nor futlire, We 3. In vain we cry the blessing, Still waiting on the shore; Awake to
                            active service, And old traditions fail. Let present revelation Light up the darksome tide,
                            Until see its light to-day. Sail on brave ship of Progress, Contend with craft and creed,
                            Until ply the laboring oar. The nations thirst for knowledge, Where is the Savior found? Let
                            our needy comrades In harbor safely ride, the suffering millions By light and truth are
                            freed, virgins sing the advent,— With no uncertain sound. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A stable is not complete unless..." TEIform="index"/>A stable is not complete unless...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A stable is not complete unless ft) the a- imals may be safely fastened in a
                                        way not uncomfortable to them ; (2) unless the animals can be kept dry and
                                        clean; (3) unless it is light; and (4) unless one can pass through without
                                        coming in contact with the occupants and without soiling shoes and clothing—four
                                        important requisites, not expensive, but within the reach of every one who
                                        builds a stable.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Detroit tribune" TEIform="index"/>Detroit Tribune</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To insects we owe wax and honey, silks and precious dyes..." TEIform="index"/>To insects we owe wax and honey, silks and precious dyes...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To insects we owe wax and honey, silks and precious dyes, valuable medicines,
                                        food for birds and many other animals, the fertilization and increase of plants
                                        necessary for the subsistence of many creatures, and thus, indirectly, for the
                                        preservation of man. In short, the human species, wholly deprived of j the
                                        services of insects, would fade from the face of our planet. So the husbandman
                                        has only to make the best of it, by learning to distinguish between his friends
                                        and his foes, and how to assist the beneficent operations of Nature in
                                        encouraging the former and checking the latter.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal of chemistry" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal of Chemistry</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The toad as an insect destroyer is becoming quite popular in Europe..." TEIform="index"/>The toad as an insect destroyer is becoming quite popular in Europe...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> The toad as an insect destroyer is becoming quite popular in Europe. Once a week a "toad
                                market" is held regularly in Paris, to which these little animals are brought, carefully
                                assorted, according to their strength and size, and packed by the hundred in baskets of
                                damp moss. The market is never overstocked, and those of moderate size find ready
                                purchasers at prices ranging from seventy-five to eighty francs per hundred. The
                                majority of them are bought up for the use of English market gardens, and it is stated
                                that orders' are on hand for the purchase, at those rates. l of every basketful that
                                realities the market.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful white finish" TEIform="index"/>Beautiful white finish</head><p TEIform="p">A beautiful finish may be given to parlors or extra work ; in houses, by mixing zinc
                                white in white dammar varnish, of commerce. This forms the china gloss </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The secret of preserving eggs is..." TEIform="index"/>The secret of preserving eggs is...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The secret of preserving eggs is in excluding the air and sealing the pores of the shell.
                                This may be done by dipping the eggs in melted tallow and afterward packing them in
                                bran, layer upon layer, covering the uppermost well with bran. Or salt may be used
                                instead of bran ; or water saturated with lime and salt is also good. An English lady,
                                an experienced poultry breeder, has preserved eggs in this solution, keeping them for
                                several years, without a single failure.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why some people are poor" TEIform="index"/>WHY SOME PEOPLE ARE POOR.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Silver spoons are used to scrape kettles. Coffee, tea, pepper, and spices are
                                        left to stand open, and lose their strength. Potatoes in the cellar grow, and
                                        sprouts are not removed until the potatoes become worthless. Brooms are never
                                        hung up, and are soon spoiled. Nice handled knives are thrown into hot water.
                                        The flour is sifted in a wasteful manner, and the bread-pan is left with the
                                        dough stick-! object is to give a complete "review of what ing to it. Clothes
                                        are left on the line to whip to pieces in the wind. Tubs and barrels are left in
                                        the sun to dry and fall apart. Dried fruits are not taken care of in season, and
                                        become wormy. Rags, string, and paper are thrown into the fire. Bits of meat,
                                        vegetables, bread, and cold puddings are thrown away when they might be warmed,
                                        steamed, and served as good as new.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Milwaukee globe" TEIform="index"/>Milwaukee Globe</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>RECIPROCITY</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vital force: how waster and how preserved" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, E. P" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True citizen" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Women's words" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dancing as an amusement" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One thousand mistakes corrected" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Larrabee and Buttz" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Dr. E P. Miller is an author of very worthy us a work of over a Vital Force: Hoiv note.
                                We have before hundred pages upon " Wasted and hew Preserved." Also, two minor works;
                                one by the Dr. upon "A Father's Advice," a book for every boy ; and one by his lady, "A
                                Mother's Advice," a book for every girl. These are valuable treatises upon very
                                important subjects to the young and lovers of young people. Address the authors, 41 W.
                                26th street, New York. The True Citizen : is a monthly, published by The New York
                                Mercantile Journal Co., P. O. box 1919, New York. It is filled with a useful miscellany
                                of mercantile, political and domestic intelligence, and is conducted with excellent
                                ability. It is the largest, most replete monthly of general intelligence published for
                                one dollar. Woman's Words : A monthly, published at Philadelphia. Pa., No. 625 Walnut
                                street. Its the sex is doing," and is in all respects a woman's paper. It is neatly
                                printed, ably edited by Lady Juan Lewis, and will assuredly make its feminine influence
                                felt, in all the noble reforms of our day. One of the neatest pamphlets published,
                                giving cuts and explanations of The Improvei7 Shaker '.'Vashing MJchine, with most
                                worthy testimonials of its superior value over all others, is being circulated bv our
                                friends of Shaker Village, N. H. It is certainly the ncplus ultra in machinery. " </p><p TEIform="p">Dancing as an Amusement." Published by Tiballs &amp; Sons, New York.—The writer of
                                this little work is worthy of extensive praise for so reasonably bringing into disrepute
                                the common and popular rage of professing Christians for balls, dances at parties, etc.
                                That such dancing is detrimental to the morals of those who engage in them, stirring up
                                the sexual passions irreligiously, who can dispute? The writer calls the attention of
                                linguists to the translations of what is denominated "dancing" in the Bible. He seems to
                                admit the propriety of the religious dance ; and thinks each sex dancing by itself would
                                soon cure the passion for balls. Price only 50 cents. "</p><p TEIform="p">One Thousand Mistakes Corrected."—All our young people ought to have constant access to
                                the pages of this beautiful volume. Corrections of the commonest, every-day errors are
                                herein made, in such a pleasant, simple manner, that we find it a real friend indeed. It
                                is worth, to any one anxious to learn to speak and write correctly, many dollars; yet
                                its price is only one dollar! When we think, that with all the increase of schools,
                                there is an apparent increase of slang, vulgarisms, as well as badly-pronounced words,
                                we may all "rise up and call blessed" the two professors, Larrabee and Buttz, who have
                                prepared this work. Published by N. Tiballs &amp; Sons, 37 Park Row, New York.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>