<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2811" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">28</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18981101" TEIform="date">November 1898</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">161-176</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="28" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains 130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
MILLENNIAL,   CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of  Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price, 50 els.
THE ALTRUIST.
of the Shakers and their          Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common proper                                ty united labor, Community homes, and
HOMES      equal rights to all.     It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
The work gives quite an extended ac-  live and work together, and hold all their
property in common,  all the men   and
count of the Several SOCIETIES, their  women having equal rights in electing of.    ..         ,           ,                    .         ficers and deciding all business affairs by
organization and general management.        their  majority vote.     50 cents a year;
Price,  50 cts.         specimen copy free.    Address A. Longmt, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
or the
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of  Believers  in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price,  15 cts.
NOVEMBER,K   1898.
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
An inviting list of special articles of great
interest makes up the table of contents for
the October Magazine Number of The Outlook.   Prominent among these is that by
The Outlook's special correspondent at Amsterdam and The Hague, Dr. William Elliot
Griffls, "Queen Wilhelmina and Her Realm."
Equally timely in interest is that by Mr. Jaeob A. Riis, on "Roosevelt and His Men."   DrEdward Everett Hale's installment for the
month of "James Russell Lowell and His
Friends" deals with "Mr. Lowell in Spain,"
and throws alight on Spanish character which
has direct application to the present situation
between the United States and Spain.   These
three articles are all fully illustrated, as are
also the account of "Life at Willett's Point,"
by a private of the Twenty-second Regiment,
Mr. A. S. Cox; Mr. Clifton Johnson's description of "A Canal-Boat Voyage on the Hudson;1'
Mr. H. S. Houston's story of Bishop Hare's life
f "A Quarter-Century with the Sioux," and
Mr. Laurence Hutton's pleasant talk about
Charles Dickens.   The story of the number,
&y Mr. Joseph Conrad, the author of one of
the most successful novels of the year, "Children of the sea," is, like that novel, a strange
story of sea life; it is entitled "Youth; A Narrative." ($3 a year.   The Outlook Company,
287 Fourth Avenue, New York.)
Beginning with the next (November) numBer, Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly will
be changed in form and dress.   Its price will
Be reduced to ten cents per copy, one dollar
per annum.   Mrs. Frank Leslie, whose association with Frank Lfslie's Popular Monthly has been the chief factor in its success and
fame, now resumes direct editorial control of
the magazine, after three years' rest and sojourn abroad.   This congenial work will occupy Mrs. Leslie's exclusive attention. Under
her skilled and sympathetic guidance, the
changes inaugurated in the long-time favorite
illustrated family magazine will be in the line
ef development of the popular pictorial and
literary features which have characterized
it heretofore.   At the same time, various
novelties will be introduced.   The tone and
policy will be more than ever distinctively
American, in the new, broad "imperialistic"
sense.
Miss Mary E. Wilkins' new serial is the Jhumorous story of an up-to-date city woman
who attempts to reform a quiet village and
educate the people up to the latest fads of the
towa.   It is called "The Jamesons in the
Country," and its serial publication will be
commenced in the next issue of The Ladies'
Home Journal.    It will have Mrs. Alice Barber
Stephens as its illustator.
The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy for September has an article on Hysteria and its deplorable effects on Human Society.
It is from the pen of the Editor, and should
have a wide circulation, among the many
readers who would be benefited by this timely information.
Many other valuable articles treating on the
successful management of the sick, may be
found in the same number.
Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co.   Kokomo, Ind.
WITHOUT   DOUBT
THE BEST FAMILY PAPER PUBLISHED
IS   THE
NEW   YORK   WEEKLY   WITNESS.
16 Pages.   Only   $1 a year.
Has a very wide scope, comprising as it,
does the following departments:
Editorials,
Spirit of the Press,
Scientific and Instructive,
The Odd and Uncommon,
Our Country's Slope,
Foreign News,
A Talk With the Doctor,
Around the Hearth,
liittle men and Womn,
Weekly Articles by Gteorg-e R. Scott
Valniag*e's Sermon,
Monej and Business,
World-Wide Field.,
Our Family Story,
Farm and Crarden,
Market Reports,
SABBATH HEADING-.
16 Pages.   Only 50 cents a Year.
An Inter-denominational Weekly Paper.
Sabbath Reading is solely religious.
No news; no politics. A grand paper
for the truth-seeker.    It contains:
Editorial.
Christian Endeavor Topic,
Epwortb Iieag'ue Topic,
Sabbath-School Iiesson,
Choice I*oetry,
Good Stories,
Reports o iMZissions,
mother*' Sabbath Afternoon
With the Children,
And a mass of matter carefully selected.
Send for free sample copies of Witness
and Sabbath Reading. And send for
free sample pages of our Bagster's Bible.
Address
J 0 H H D 0 V a A L L & CO., 150 Nassau Street, New York.--><pb n="161" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN COMMUNISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Elder Henry G. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">WHOEVER becomes interested in the teachings of Jesus the Christ, becomes also interested in
                            all that is an outgrowth from that work. It is very true that Jesus never establisht a
                            permanent community, altho his life was wholly given to that end, and those who were called
                            to be with him were a kind of first-fruits of the kingdom of God. "All who believed were
                            together and had all things common. Neither was there any among them that lackt, for as many
                            as were possest of lands or houses, sold them and distribution was made to every man
                            according as he had need." A united inheritance in all things, spiritual and temporal is
                            founded in the unity of God in Christ. The family of Christ is one, one body and one head,
                            one Lord and one baptism. From the introduction of the Mosaic Law to the time of which we
                            are now speaking, there was an inspiration flowing through the prophetic spirit which
                            admitted and encouraged the dissemination of a love and care which might extend beyond the
                            borders of the private, selfish family interests. A remarkable lesson on this subject was
                            the gathering of the manna by the children of Israel. Every one gathered as he had need. All
                            shared alike. If through selfishness any one gathered more than his right, it spoiled in his
                            house so that he was in no better condition than his neighbor. During forty years that
                            people held their property in common and when they reacht the land of Canaan, "This land is
                            mine," saith the Lord. If they <pb n="162" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> .162 THE MANIFESTO. bought and sold for
                            me and mine, it was for a limited season and then all debts were cancelled and all the
                            bondsmen were made free. It is very readily seen that Jesus in the first of his ministration
                            left the selfish course of the world and accepted the principle of united inheritance. To be
                            a disciple of Jesus was peculiar in itself, and all men would know it by this one
                            expression,Their love one for another. Other religious leaders had their disciples and their
                            corresponding selfishness, but the family of Christ was to be one in its self-denial, in its
                            cultivation of peace and in its general life practice. Jesus was a Teacher and one of his
                            pupils was a rich young man. He ran to meet Jesus and kneeling before him, askt, "Good
                            Master what shall I do that I may have eternal life?"Matt, xix., 16. We suppose that the
                            young man had great love for Jesus and a strong faith in his testimony. He was anxious to
                            learn from this good master. The reply that Jesus made was that of a kind and hopeful
                            parent, "Thou knowest the commandments." It was as tho he had said, "If thou wilt enter into
                            life keep the commandments." This was not a prodigal son that had ruined himself through the
                            transgressions of the Law, and he replies,"All these things have I kept from my youth," and
                            yet with all this care and discipline he could not enter the community or family of Jesus.
                            He had done well so far, but said Jesus, "One thing thou lackest. If thou wilt be perfect,
                            go and sell that thou hast and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven."
                            Why should Jesus ask this young convert to sell all his possessions? Why should he be told
                            to give his property to the poor, unless it was to teach him a lesson in community interest?
                            In this unitary home there would be no rich, no poor, but all would be Brethren and Sisters.
                            The remark that was made to this upright, rich man so astonisht the disciples that they
                            began to enquire, "Who then can be saved?" It had never occurred to them that a little
                            personal property would prevent them from being disciples of the Lord. While the community
                            system was being discussed, Peter gave evidence that he was quite prepared for the work.
                            "Behold," said he, "we have forsaken all to follow thee." And yet there was a doubt in his
                            mind. He could not see clearly the advantage of forsaking his business relations and giving
                            his goods to the poor and running the risk of getting little or nothing in return. At this
                            same time Jesus was saying to the disciples, "I have not where to lay my head." I am not so
                            well off as the birds of the air. It was the representation of extreme poverty. "The king's
                            sons," said he, "can dress in purple and fine linen and fare sumptuously every day." It is
                            not strange that people of wealth should turn away sorrowfully, after they have learned that
                            they must sell their goods and give their money to the poor, before they can be accepted. If
                            the heavenly kingdom is to be estab- <pb n="163" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 163 lisht on
                            earth, the same condition that makes the heaven in the world to come will also make a heaven
                            in this present life. Here is the petition, "Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done in earth as
                            it is in heaven." And the kingdom is truth, justice, purity and God's love for man. How very
                            different is this from the present state of Christian society. Many who call themselves the
                            saints of God on earth, dwell in palaces and live like king's sons. They know no want, while
                            their Christian brethren may dwell in an ill-furnisht cottage or be provided for in the
                            almshouse. That this should be the condition of the children of this world does not seem
                            strange. "They have their reward." While the apostles were waiting in Jerusalem for the holy
                            spiiit to be poured upon them, the day of Pentecost arrives and Peter in his anxiety makes
                            this enquiry, "Men and Brethren what shall we do?" They could only do this,-^-inspire the
                            multitude with the testimony of Jesus, as they had been inspired at a former day. They could
                            teach only that which Jesus had taughtto forsake all and follow Christ in the regeneration.
                            The history of this first church informs us that the multitude were of one heart. Neither
                            said any of them that aught of the things which he possest was his own. Neither was there
                            any among them that lackt, for as many as were possessors of lands or houses, sold them and
                            brought the prices of the things sold to the apostles. Jesus and his disciples must have
                            maintained this same equality, and the same lessons were being carried forward at the feast
                            of Pentecost. Stepping out of their selfish interests, they were brought into fellowship so
                            that those who believed were together and had all things common. They sold their
                            possessions. "Go," said Jesus, "sell all thou hast." No such sacrifice of one's property for
                            the good of the whole could ever have been made unless the spirit of. God was manifest in
                            it. But the promise of God was sure. They received an hundredfold of houses and lands,
                            fathers and mothers in this worid and in the world to come, eternal life. This story of the
                            church is well worth studying by all professing Chris tians. The pretended consecration of
                            Ananias and Sapphira was met by a just retribution. Peter says, "While it remained, was it
                            not thine own, and after it was sold was it not in thine own power? Thou hast not lied unto
                            man, but unto God." The apostles were in no especial need of the property. He might have
                            kept the whole of it, and he knew this fact quite well. The poor man was double-minded. He
                            wanted to be received into the church, and still wanted to retain a part of his selfish
                            possessions. This man is a type of the many who have professedly consecrated themselves
                            before God, who have assumed a form of Godliness, while at the same time they have reserved
                            for themselves some of this world's goods, or some idol of the heart. It was a failure.
                            Failed to give up all, failed to bear a full cross, failed to be harvested from the world.
                            In the Christian church <pb n="164" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 164 THE MANIFESTO. the comforts of earth and
                            the blessings of heaven are equally alike. "Let the brother of low degree," said James,
                            "rejoice in that he is exalted, but the rich in that he is made low." The apostle was making
                            a contrast between the rich and the poor as referring to property. But in this day the
                            subject would create no interest in the Christian church. The poor man has no special
                            benefit over which he need rejoice, but in the Pentecostal community he would have been
                            exalted and would have shared equally with his rich brother. The rich man at the same time
                            could rejoice that he had the privilege of sharing with his poor brother. In accepting this
                            testimony of Jesus the Christ, we accept his life example which leads to a separation from
                            the world and to a universal brotherhood of peacemakers and thoughtful workers in practical
                            righteousness. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coming sail" TEIform="index"/>THE COMING SAIL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>By Jessie Evans.</byline><p TEIform="p">WE are upon the beach. Why we were so placed or how long we must remain we know not, we only
                            know that we are here within sight of the broad expanse of waters between us and the land
                            beyond. At first, we were satisfied with this life upon our vast island home, and found
                            pleasure and sorrow enough this side of the tides to absorb our attention from day to day.
                            At first we were happy in exploring the hidden wonders around us, content with the
                            friendships of the loved ones near us, and engrossed in the interests of our bright,
                            beautiful home ; but once, long ago, we caught sight of a sail which broke the human horizon
                            for the first time. On it came until it reacht the port of our loving welcome. Then the
                            angels at the helm whispered to our eager attentive minds tidings of that other shore just
                            across the waters, new sweet voices invited us over, and when they past away from us again
                            they left in our hearts newborn hopes, new ideas, new longings; for we realized that this
                            island home is not our native country, that by and by when the "coming sail" so commissioned
                            shall reach us, we shall take passage, one by one, for that Fatherland on the other side.
                            Since then, all the cares and joys here we view but as the flight of hours which draws us
                            nearer to the life whose cares are all joys. The idea of permanence has gone now. Our eye is
                            eagerly scanning the face of the waters to catch the next sail, for many have called this
                            way since that memorable day so long ago. As they came and went, we learned more and more of
                            that other home. Some of our companions were too busy on the sands to watch for the incoming
                            barques, but those who waited on the border line caught each time the precious whispers.
                            Sometimes they brought sad news perhaps that a beloved co-worker must take passage, and mid
                            our tears we said farewell. Still at all times, breath- <pb n="165" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            165 ings of a holier atmosphere reacht us, healing the wound and soothing our sorrows.
                            Through this medium our souls reacht out in their aspirations over the waters. Our prayers,
                            deep and fervent, found the .spiritual telegraph which spans the distance and now we talk as
                            of yore with the dear ones who seemingly left us. Across the deep, our ideals have touched
                            the diviner shore. Now, as we fulfill our lesser duties upon this nether beach from day to
                            day, we fail not to watch for the "coming sail" which keeps us in touch with the land from
                            which they comethe "heart's true home." Spiritual expectancy is a virtue to be encouraged.
                            Nothing is worse than an indifferent self-satisfied Christianity, if such can exist. If we
                            possess that type of so-called religion, which allays the continual hungering and thirsting
                            after righteousness ; if we are so good that we are satisfied to be no better, it is time to
                            question our status. A plant that ceases to grow commences to decay. There is no such state
                            as indifference in a Christian's mind. He is continually reaching after new themes for
                            thought, restful yet ever restless, satisfied yet dissatisfied, ever rich yet longing to be
                            richer toward God. A mind that is content with one type of happiness, one grade of
                            education, is not a mind worthy the name. Eternal progression, endless growth, is the law of
                            the mind. Growth is maintained by inspiration, physical and mental. The hope of a nation or
                            of an individual is its growth. As one has truly said, "It is not so much where we are, as
                            in what direction we are moving." Our nation encourages enterprise and invention in its
                            citizens by holding out strong inducements to the fittest, by denying its responsible
                            offices to the incapable. Hence we are bound to be a growing government. It is said of
                            Edison, that when one of his wonderful schemes is perfected, his interest holds it no more.
                            He relaxes his mental grasp upon it that he may attempt another and greater benefaction, is
                            pleased with one success only until the possibility of another is conceived. Thus should it
                            be with men in every vocation, attempt and attainment constantly alternating and ascending.
                            A nation bound by irrevocable laws; a church anchored to an iron creed, cold and
                            inspirationless ; a mind whose circle of vision is what has beenare crimes before the light
                            of present revelation which administers "strength according to thy day." The "coming sail"
                            toward which the gaze should ever be turned, means to us just what we need. God's
                            inspirations, so beautifully adapted to our shortcomings, are sent to answer our prayers, to
                            echo our praises and to suggest the new line of consecrated service. Into each horizon come
                            these blessed "sails." Are we too busy with our .tasks in the sands to note their approach
                            ere they have past? East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="166" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind sister;--We received your letter..." TEIform="index"/>Kind sister;--We received your letter...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="South Groton, May 20, 1861" TEIform="index"/>South Groton, May 20, 1861.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Kind Sister ;We received your letter and were all well pleased with its simplicity and
                                kindly spirit. In perusing the expressions of gospel faith, and the good determinations
                                you make to obey them, I conclude that I was particularly fortunate in my last contract,
                                for an addition to the number of my near and dear relation. I will attempt to explaiu
                                the portions of ancient Scripture to which you have so kindly called my attention. The
                                prophet Ezekiel lived and wrote in a remarkable period of Jewish history. He was a poor
                                suffering child of mortality, and placed great dependence on the Holy Spirit, as his
                                name signifies, "Supported of God, or God is my strength." Babylon or the Chaldean
                                empire, where the Jews were then in captivity, was a portion of Mesopotamia, a name
                                which signifies, "A land, or valley lying between two rivers." It embraces many names
                                spoken of in early Scripture. The whole valley was the garden of the earth and the
                                fertile portion of it was the glory of the Chaldean empire. This valley lay between the
                                Tigris and Euphrates. It is said to be from twenty to two hundred miles in width, and
                                from six to eight hundred miles in length. All historians agree that the tower of Babel
                                was enclosed within the very walls of Babylon. This holy prophet could look upon the
                                remains of this idolatrous tower and could see what it had done for many generations,
                                even before Abraham was called from that region. In ten generations from Shem out of
                                this valley Abraham was sent, to start the Jewish nation. Stephen says,"The God of glory
                                appeared to our father Abraham, when he was in Mesopotamia."Acts vii., 2. The Chaldeans,
                                or "worshippers of fire," seem to have been of the blood that Abraham was called out
                                from, to plant a people who should receive the promises, and give birth to the Messiah.
                                By the most remarkable demonstration of power, the Hebrews were led into, and delivered
                                from bondage; received the laws of God in the desert, which they repeatedly broke, for
                                which in the days of Ezekiel, they were sent into the most desolate captivity. The pious
                                prophet had spent the earliest years of his life in the great city of Jerusalem. He
                                began to prophesy five years after the captivity and continued denouncing idolatry for
                                twenty-one years, for which he was slain. Born of the priesthood, he had bowed to God in
                                early years among the sacred types at the Jewish altar, and had trod the courts of the
                                temple in all their magnificence and glory. His lamentations for his people began in the
                                tabernacle of Israel. He had stood in the outer court in which the multitude listened to
                                the word of God, from between the cherubim, and when the <pb n="167" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 167 tribes of Judah went into captivity, he bitterly knew how deplorably they
                                had fallen. When brought under judgment for their sins, he saw them hurled from their
                                high stations, crusht from among the nations, and their beautiful city and temple
                                levelled to the dust. With them, he was hurried away to the dismal prison-house of
                                Babylon, to lie buried in the grave of slavery in the ancient valley. This prophet went
                                into exile with his people, into a land of beauty, watered by the rivers of Babylon, but
                                every scene about him was calculated to embitter his life. As he wandered in his
                                devotions and pious rambles along the banks of the river Chebar, (a branch of the great
                                Euphrates,) sorrowfully and sadly could he say,"Nearly eighteen hundred years ago this
                                ground was made sacred by the footsteps of the righteous Noah, who was perfect in his
                                generation, found favor with heaven, and escaped the deluge. Here in this delightful
                                valley, God made with Noah the second covenant with the race, re-establisht the simple
                                patriarchal religion in the New world, and as with Adam the first, made him earthly Lord
                                of his generations." He could see also where Nimrod came to establish idolatry one
                                hundred and twenty years after the deluge. The very name of that personage signifies
                                "Rebel against God's mediatorial government." He could see the very structure that this
                                ancient turnaway constructed, to oppose God's rule through ancient mediators, and
                                overturn patriarchal authority, and set himself on high to introduce false worship. Noah
                                was clothed with the name of the true God and they who set out to erect this structure
                                said,"Let us make us a new name."Gen. xi., 4. In every direction the prophet could see
                                that the abominable rites started then, had spread abroad and come down to that
                                generation shutting them out from the knowledge of God's rule and order. Here he could
                                see what Abraham was called out from, and why he was cautioned never to return. Perhaps
                                he prayed to heaven by the same river, or in the very grave where Abraham was told to
                                leave his father's house, and plant a new generation of people. In this trying
                                condition, and in these extremes of feeling, he must have viewed the dead condition of
                                his people. Under these disadvantages he, without doubt, labored in sorrow to learn how
                                the promises of God made to Abraham concerning his kindred were to be fulfilled. I have
                                written thus, to take the most direct way to show you that history informs us that the
                                valley in which the prophet saw the dry bones was something more substantial than a
                                vision. I have taken the most simple method to show you that in his entranced state he
                                saw the bones as a figure, but they were evidently in the valley of Mesopotamia. By
                                quoting a few vei'ses of the preceding chapter we can see the meaning of the vision more
                                clearly. The prophet says, "The word of the Lord came to me saying, Son of man when the
                                house of Israel dwelt in their own land, they defiled it by their doings, and I
                                scattered them among the Heathen. I will take you from among the Heathen and bring you
                                into your own land. I will put my spirit within <pb n="168" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 168 THE
                                MANIFESTO. you, and cause you to walk in my statutes, and ye shall dwell in the land
                                which I gave to your fathers."Ezekiel xxxvi., 16, 27. He continues, "The hand of the
                                Lord was upon me, and set me down in the midst of the valley which was full of bones,
                                and he caused me to pass them round about, and behold they were very many in an open
                                valley, and lo ! they were very dry, and he said to me, Son of man can these bones live?
                                and I said, 0 Lord thou knowest. He said, prophesy unto them, 0 ye dry bones, hear the
                                word of the Lord. Behold I will cause breath to enter into you, I will lay sinews and
                                flesh upon you, cover you with skin and ye shall live. And as I prophesied there was a
                                noise and a shaking and the bones came together. The sinews and flesh came upon them,
                                and skin covered them, but there was no breath in them. Then he saith unto me, prophesy
                                unto the wind, and say, Thus saith the Lord, come from the four winds, O breath, and
                                breathe upon these slain that they may live. So I prophesied, and breath came into them
                                and they lived and stood upon their feet an exceeding great army."Ezek. xxxvii., 110.
                                Here is one of the most descriptive visions ever given to a prophet. It was to show this
                                suffering man of God, that his people would be awakened, raised from their dead state of
                                transgressions and brought back to the land and law of their father. There is no lack of
                                evidence to show that this was the real meaning of this vision as you may read. "Then
                                said he to me, Son of man, these bones are the whole house of Israel. They say our bones
                                are dried, our hope is lost, and we are cut off from our parts (lands.) Therefore say
                                unto them, Thus saith the Lord, behold, O my people, I will open your graves, and bring
                                you into the land of Israel." The sending of the Jews into Babylonish captivity was to
                                cast the old transgressors out of Canaan and let their carcasses fall among the heathen.
                                The idolatrous portions of the younger generations never returned to Jerusalem but
                                remained among heathen idolaters. History informs us that the most sincere portions were
                                the only remnant that returned, who built up the city, erected the second temple and
                                establisht the law. This vision is one of the most remarkable pieces of Biblical
                                literature. The Chaldeans, Medes and Persians generally had great reverence for the
                                memory of this prophet. They believed in a sort of literary resurrection, and by this
                                vision, the meaning of which they could not comprehend, they were undoubtedly
                                strengthened in that belief, as were many of the Jews. More than ten thousand sermons
                                have been preached from it for the same purpose. It was the very vision selected by the
                                Advents to prove that the literal body was the real eternal man, and that the four winds
                                of heaven, or the common air we breathe was the true spirit of God which was finally to
                                reanimate these bodies. The simple revelations of Mother Ann Lee which divide between
                                flesh and Spirit, set all right upon this subject. They show that the body returns to
                                the dust, and that the spirit travels up to the spirit- <pb n="169" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. 169 ual heaven in Christ-like purity and the beauty of holiness. It is
                                somewhere said that "the golden moments for proper action should never be lost." On
                                every plane of life, everything elevated and Godlike must be gained by virtue, diligence
                                and labor. There is no way we can attain immortality until we have marshalled for the
                                conflict, fought the battles and endured the hardships of the campaign. On the
                                battle-field conflicts are waged, deeds of valor performed, and palms of victory borne
                                away. I know how the cross of Christ feels to a young, ardent, golden-dreaming,
                                impetuous nature, but there is a priceless knowledge which lies just beyond this battle
                                ground, which has not yet opened fully to your understanding. To those who early embrace
                                the cross of Christ, and are loyal disciples till they pass the meridian of life, there
                                is a serene tranquility that none can experience who have not fought many battles, and
                                come off victorious. Such Christian warriors are crowned with a glory that the earthly
                                hero never knew. They have fought through fields where Napoleon or Alexander would have
                                been put to flight, or slain upon the battle ground. In this condition the Christian has
                                past the first conflict, and firmly stands. He has gained a substance, and enjoys the
                                true rest which remains for the people of God. Your Brother in the Gospel,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Leonard.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Selfishness" TEIform="index"/>SELFISHNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">Q\ ELFISHNESS has been truly called the "first angel of evil." We have k3 only to cast our
                            eyes outwardly, yea even inwardly to have this verified. Self-interest,how like a net-work
                            it runs through the whole fabric of our lives; let us analyze our best motives ; are they
                            not most frequently subject to the influence of personal consideration ? "Know thyself" was
                            the injunction of a Grecian philosopher; yet man knows everything better than himself; he
                            has peered into the stellar world, dug into the interior of the earth, controlled many of
                            the subtle elements of nature, and even mapped the bottom of the ocean, yet he is far from
                            knowing his own nature and its essential attributes, we may suppose that through his
                            knowledge of these things may yet be evolved something superior to the present animal man.
                            It is well for us at times to tear away the veil of selfishness, and let the light penetrate
                            our hearts, revealing our true condition and how far our lives are actuated by this sin. It
                            is not only manifest in the desire to appropriate material gain to personal use, but in
                            pride, arrogance, self-will, love of power, envy and malice, indifference to the welfare of
                            others ; if we harbor these things the love of the Father is not in us; these are but a few
                            of the branches of that great evil tree that has its roots in the lower life, that Jesus
                            told his followers they must lay down to inherit eternal life. <pb n="170" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 170
                            THE MANIFESTO. Popular religious belief is founded upon selfishness,selfishness that has its
                            origin in the sordid heart, not in the true spirit of religion. Many of our churches are
                            gilded monuments of selfishness, where the worshipers idly resting on the merits of a
                            crucified Savior, bow to the gods of wealth and fashion and leave unheeded their suffering
                            brother and sister. "Self-interest is the genuine lever of Archimedesits fulcrum, the sordid
                            heart,it moves the world." Let us take a broader out-look and see how this demon of self
                            rules the world. It is written, "thou shait have no other gods before me," but, "Mammon sits
                            before a million hearths Where God is blotted out from every house." "With what tenacity
                            mankind has clung to the god of gold, that selfish instinct of acquisitiveness that
                            appropriates all it can grasp, while the weaker brother "bites the dust of poverty." "Thou
                            shalt love thy neighbor as thyself;" this would imply a broad fraternal relationship; but
                            let us look at the system of war by which all civilized nations are opprest. Millions of
                            human beings trained, armed, disciplined and equipt for mutual destruction;can anything be
                            more opposed to the love of the neighbor? The whole system of modern civilization is the
                            triumphant despotism of self ; the strong against the weak, producing many inequalities,
                            while the whole earth groans with the countless miseries that come in consequence of its
                            domination. There are none, however imperfect their knowledge of the trend of human events,
                            but what feel a nameless apprehension of danger ahead, a revolution that must sooner or
                            later arise to dethrone the god of self that the divine Spirit may reign in human hearts.
                            "Unselfishness is the very essence of true nobility." Moses taught the principles of "love
                            to the neighbor," but it only extended as far as the Jew ; it was left for the great Teacher
                            to inaugurate the system of universal brotherhood. What an inspiration to all, is his life
                            example of self-sacrificingdevotion to others ; how full of tenderness for the suffering,
                            pity for the afflicted. The parables of the Prodigal Son and the Good Samaritan,how rich in
                            imagery: how full of illustrations of that unselfish spirit that loves the neighbor better
                            than self. In serving the neighbor we are fulfilling the highest law,the law of love; in
                            doing this we are serving God, for the highest manifestation of God is found in human
                            hearts. Oh, that we might dethrone this god of self! Selfishness,it hangs a veil over our
                            eyes, darkening our minds to the true light of the Spirit; it places a stone against the
                            door of our hearts barring them to the reception of every good thing; let us roll away this
                            stone bidding the angel of the Resurrection, the angel of love, come forth enrobed in her
                            beautiful garments. Do we wish to enjoy a foretaste of heaven now? the surest way is to rise
                            above all conditions of self. Do we wish to advance the Divine Kingdom in earth? the only
                            way is through the conquest of selfishness and this should be the aim of every individual.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="171" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1898. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Ordek and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henby C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50 A cross in the margin will show that your subscription has closed.
                            Remittances for subscription by Money Order should be on the Post Office at Concord, N.
                        H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">September. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1897. 61.6 1.75 in.
                                1898. 65. 2.25 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0. Lowest " " " " 36 " " Number
                                of rainy days " " 5 " " clear " " " 15 " " cloudy" " " 10 Oct. 1898. This is the harvest
                                season of the year as the constellation Libra or the Scales denotes, the season of
                                gathering in the fruits of the earth. This work is now nearly accomplisht. Soon we shall
                                be able to draw the Balance-sheet and ascertain the result of the labors of the year.
                                Our hay crop has been excellent. Green fields and pasures have been continuous from
                                budding Spring to the present date. The weather has been rather too wet for potatoes,
                                consequently they have been affected with rot. Corn has been excellent; the same can be
                                said of Hubbard squash and other culinary vegetables. Our apple crop has been medium:
                                cherries abundant; other small fruits variable. Our temporal larder has thus far been
                                well supplied so there is small probability that we shall perish with hunger,
                                physically. The culture of our moral and spiritual necessities depends as much on our
                                own wise tactics as do the temporal. Public Meetings are still held and whosoever will
                                may come and partake of the waters of life freely. New York State has finally shaken off
                                its lethargy and is following the good example set by Massachusetts in the improvement
                                of the highways, so that now, without doubt, there will be a State road built between
                                Pittsfield and Albany, thus making the passage over the Berkshire Hills easier and
                                pleasanter. Our well tried friend Dr A. J. White we learn has past that bourne, whence
                                no traveller returns. Our blessing rests upon the noble Doctor. We have no deaths to
                                chronicle in our Community. All are able to do duty with slight exceptions. Calvin G.
                                Reed. South Family. Oct. 1898. We've liad a splendid pouring rain, And liope we'll get
                                some more, Streams were getting very dry, So well we prized the pour. It rained from
                                north, It rained from south, It rained from east and west, 'Twas just the kind of rain
                                to have, A rain that rains the best. The Notes by Elder Henry C. Blinn in Oct. Manifesto
                                were decidedly interesting. The "Home Notes" department is a pleasing feature, as it
                                forms a link in the brotherhood from Maine to Kentucky, holding spirit communion which
                                is most TERMS <pb n="172" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 172 THE MANIFESTO. profitable in these clays of
                                constant financial ruin, hurry and rush. Our sweet corn drying is in full blast, and the
                                corn could not be better. When finisht we shall have a choice lot of the best and finest
                                stock to be found in market. Our tomato harvest was very light, but the deficiency has
                                been cancelled by the generosity of our North family friends who liberally supplied us
                                with a full and perfect measure which they heaped up, pressed down and filled to
                                overflowing. The demand for Shaker chairs, foot rests, woolen dusters and many items in
                                the fancy work department continues. Sisters Abigail Brooks and Amanda Tiffany of
                                Enfield, Conn., made us a short call last week. The world revolves rapidly, so we must
                                move briskly to keep pace with it all. Genevieve De Grate.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898, In perusing the Notes from the Editorial diary, the closing paragraph
                                introduced a train of thought which is thus illustrated; The conservative mind that can
                                intelligently separate the chaff from the wheat, rejecting the ideas and practices of
                                the past that have proven by their own record their falsity, and retaining those which
                                are founded upon the everlasting truth; and viewing the advance of human life in its
                                progressive march to higher ideals, can call steady, steady, be sure you are right, then
                                go ahead, is of a type so different from that conservatism which opposes the new moon
                                because it respects the old, that no comparison can be drawn between them. "We are
                                living, we are dwelling in a grand and awful time, when to be living is sublime." The
                                forces that are molding human thought, and changing human society, are moving with such
                                rapidity, and displaying such tremendous energy in their operation that those who,
                                because they do not conform to their fossilized ideals seek to check their advance had
                                better heed the warning voice,Beware. While all change is not progress, all progress is
                                change from the old and dying civilizations of the past, into the new and resurrecting
                                life of the advance thought of the present. We can not view life through the same object
                                glass as those who hold that the only ideals worthy of acceptance are those which the
                                past has given us, and any effort to change them for something higher would only result
                                in retrogression. Gerald Massey, in his poem "The Coming Time," voices an everlasting
                                truth in the following, " 'Tis coming up the steep of time, and this old world is daily
                                growing brighter." The opening days of October gave us a sample of the same weather that
                                the preceding months dida summer temperature. At date, Oct. 8, we have had two light
                                frosts; but nothing to injure tender vegetation. It is a season of usual health. One of
                                the dear mothers, Sister Sophronia Dole is patiently waiting for the angel that directs
                                the life boat to pilot her over to the evergreen shores. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898. Octobek, the treasurer of the year is come, and we are collecting the interest
                                due on the toil of the preceding months, and also returning to her safe deposit,
                                treasures which we may draw, on some distant rainy or snowy day. First among her
                                treasures, and enclosing them all like the folds of protecting papers, are the beautiful
                                leaves. Their description becomes a worn subject of the pen, for Webster allows only
                                just so many descriptive words, but never does their beauty become tiresome to the eye.
                                We do not wonder that so many are attracted to the Berkshire Hills, and leaving the
                                crowded cities, throng the towns, to spend a few days in wonder and admiration. Apples
                                are fairly good and sufficient for home use, but ''none to spare." Corn <pb n="173" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 173 cutting and drying completed some days ago, and since
                                that time, the entire lot has been sold, the result of a hasty trip by Brother Ira to
                                New York and Philadelphia. All around are rumors of disasters, the result of the heavy
                                rains. We have escaped even the least of these, for which we are grateful, although
                                sympathetic with those less fortunate. The moisture has averted the frost and kept
                                vegetation in smiling freshness. The mile of State road west of us will be completed in
                                a month, and preparations are making for the building of another mile east. The Electric
                                railway has also crept nearer us, although not near enough as yet to affect us directly.
                                During the summer months there have been, grazing upon our verdant hill-sides, numbers
                                of the quadruped familycalves, but such poor apologies as they were when first sent
                                there! Yesterday, however, as we watched them in their gambols we hardly thought them
                                the same, so improved were they with their pasture diet. An addition is being built at
                                our new barn to house sixty or seventy of them this winter. We have had the pleasure of
                                a few weeks companionship with Elder Henry C. Blinn, a pleasure which we value, and the
                                close of which we have signed "D. C." to be repeated until the finale occurs. If the
                                light of the Divine presence has shone on our darkness, should we not throw out its rays
                                to others who are pursuing life's pilgrimage? "For the soul that gives is the sou] that
                                lives, And in bearing another's load We lighten our own, and shorten the way, And
                                brighten the homeward road." Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898. The articles in the Oct. Manifesto referring to our Florida society, bring to
                                mind the saying,Life is exalted by the action of its varied elements. In the case of our
                                "Olive Branch" kindred, the elements of industry, intelligence and virtue consecrated to
                                faith and life works like that of their Northern kindred, have wrought good results to
                                their honor, and to the honor of Zion at large. May the fruits of their labors yield,
                                not only a large harvest of the fruits of the earth, but an abundance of the joy of the
                                spirit, for the laborious work so nobly and cheerfully done. Our home is environed with
                                nature's most radiant gifts of autumnal colors, making a picture, beautiful to behold,
                                and reminding us that by "the action of its varied elements," the earth never faileth to
                                perform her mission well. Her products giving a silent sermon of loyalty and exaltation
                                to the Creator of all good. We miss the merry songsters, the fields of ripened grain,
                                and the well stockt vegetable gardens, but later on we shall enjoy the harvesting of
                                field and garden, when snow and bleak winds take the place of the present genial
                                atmosphere and beauteous scenery. We are pleased to record a short, but pleasant visit
                                with Brother Arthur Bruce of East Canterbury, and subsequently one with Sister Eliza A.
                                Stratton of the same place. The past month, our townsman Mr. C. Rich, kindly favored us
                                with a fine program of phonographic selections, making an enjoyable evening. Sisters
                                have prepared 218 gallons of varied fruit sauces, and are to add more are also engaged
                                on fancy goods for next year's sales the past season being an exceptionally profitable
                                one. We hope, with Brother Hamilton De Graw, that before long the nation with nation
                                will cease to war, and their "spiritual sensibilities" by "the action of its varied
                                elements" clasp them in bonds of eternal peace. George II. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898. The business outlook for east and south Florida is better than it has been
                                since the great freeze. Field crops have at least come up to the average, while the <pb n="174" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE MANIFESTO. orange groves that have been properly cared
                                for have a fair yield of fruit. The men of the woods are doing quite a stroke of work in
                                the turpentine camps, and the lumbermen at the mills say they have all the work they can
                                do to fill their orders. This speaks very well for our nearest town, Kissimmee, which
                                for two years after the freeze had a very disconsolate look. Being the center of many
                                beautiful orange groves, it depended on them for life, and for many years previous it
                                was about the entire business of the people of middle and southern Florida. To Florida
                                the freeze was a blessing instead of a curse. It showed to them the necessity of relying
                                on something more than oranges for a living. Hundreds of its inhabitants, while they
                                have renewed their groves, have also planted large acres of different kinds of
                                vegetables, which will add largely to the pocket book and also lessen the expenses of
                                living. Everybody is gratified that the summer is past and that there has been no yellow
                                fever in Florida. The State Board of Health stands higher than ever in the confidence
                                and esteem of the people. We are looking with more or less pleasure upon our small
                                acres. Our sugar cane stands over twelve feet high and is a wonder. Ouj- rice which we
                                have begun to harvest is an equal crop and will give us all the hay we want for our
                                mules and horses. Pine-apples are just beginning to ripen and we have a few every week
                                to supply home neighbors at town. Our rainy season is over and Old Sol is again pouring
                                down his intensity upon our heads. Andrew Barrett. Facts About Florida. Olive Branch,
                                Sept. 1898. We now have fenced and in good condition, four pastures. No 1 pasture
                                contains 2000 acres No 2 pasture contains 1000 acres. No 3 pasture contains over 600
                                acres. No 4 pasture contains over 400 acres. Every pasture is on the border of a lake
                                where cattle can get water the year round. The four pastures will furnish choice feed
                                for over two thousand cattle every month during the year, and cattle thrive and grow
                                without any other feed! Not having the means to purchase cattle to occupy the four
                                pastures, which we exceedingly regret, we have been obliged to let most of the pastures
                                to cattle dealers at a small compensation, when compared with the profits made by owners
                                of the cattle. Narcoossee, Fla. B. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898. Having just read in the Oct. Manifesto, the very interesting account of our
                                beloved Editor's visit, I am prompted to extend thanks to him for his kindly thoughts
                                which are both interesting and instructive. We are enjoying a pleasant visit with two
                                Sisters from Mt. Lebanon, Sarah Burger and Annie E. Stephens, also two from Harvard,
                                Mass., Sister Olive Hatch, now over 90 years old, and erect and smart yet, and Sister
                                Myra McLean. The meeting with these gives us a pleasant interchange and one that we very
                                highly prize after the busy summer. Their presence among us is conducive to spiritual
                                strength and the good influence thus shed upon all serves to draw us nearer to the God
                                of purity and love. We have had several privileges the past summer. Prof. Osgood of
                                Boston has kindly favored us with two hours musical training and made several short
                                calls while he tarried at Poland Springs. Later, the two leading musicians from Poland
                                Springs came down to our home and kindly gave us two concerts from the organ and violin.
                                They belong to the Boston Symphony Orchestra which consists of eighty men. Our crops are
                                almost harvested except the apples of which there are but fe w this season. Later,
                                apple-pie will be "a rarity" with us. Winter is close at hand and the Summer has past so
                                quickly that it seems like a dream to look back over the past months. Ada S.
                            Cummings.</p></div3><pb n="175" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 16, 1898. Home Notes rather husky this time, for either by corn or cold all have
                                been touched. The statistician is not prolific on farm topics, merely reporting silos
                                full and more to follow. Dairy steady. Potatoes good crop, probably five hundred
                                bushels, other vegetables very respectable both in quality and quantity. In honor of
                                this unprecedented corn year, a "Corn Corn-cert" was held on the evening of the 6th
                                inst. The program rendered may interest our readers, and at the same time adjust the
                                Home Notes column for East Canterbury to the standard length. Corn Corn-cert.
                                Corn-vivial Corn-vergence. Quartet. Corn-flict, Orchestra. Corn-sentaneity, Children.
                                Corn-glomeration Duet, Piano &amp; Organ. Corn-temporation, Quartet. Corn-cussion,
                                Orchestra. Corn-sumption. Quintet. Piano &amp; Organ. Quartet. Children. Orchestra.
                                Corn-sternation, Corn-temporaries, Corn-cord, Corn-firmation, Corn-vulsions,
                                Corn-elusion, Quartet. Jessie Evans.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898. Oitr peaches and apples are a failure. Vegetables and small fruits are good.
                                It has been many years since we noted a failure in our apple crop, and yet we have many
                                blessings for which to be thankful. JSrancy Hupe.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping warm" TEIform="index"/> KEEPING WARM.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A common error is that Orientals inhabit lands of eternal summer and dress
                                        the jear through in flowing silks and wondrous muslins. Many of them do enjoy
                                        this kind of existence. Those for example, in southern China and on the great
                                        plain of Hindostan, but at least a hundred millions live in a territory as cold
                                        as this city, and at least fifty millions in a land whose conditions are similar
                                        to those of Canada. Centuries of civilization have taught them numberless
                                        expedients for securing comfort and pleasure, in spite of the snow and ice which
                                        surround them in the winter season. Many of these are known and utilized by the
                                        western world, but the most are unknown, or, if known, are viewed as freaks or
                                        laughable oddities. Thus, for example, the Japanese and northern Chinese employ
                                        what are known as pocket stoves. These consist of shells of metal in iron,
                                        brass, bronze, silver, and for the very wealthy gold. Charcoal or perfumed
                                        charcoal is put into the shell and ignited. The shell itself is inserted in a
                                        special belt or cloth, and worn about the waist, or is fastened to the inside of
                                        a woman's skirt. A cold individual may wear as many as a half dozen of these
                                        little stoves, while a warm-blooded person is satisfied with one. There are
                                        beautiful little foot warmers, which can be taken into bed, and in which a
                                        slowly smouldering fire safely secured inside a metal box, emits warmth the
                                        night long, and makes the coldest bed as delightful as a hammock in summer
                                        weather. Then there are portable stoves, which burn perfumed charcoal and can be
                                        carried from room to room. There are pajamas which are lined with fur; kimonos,
                                        whose interior is as soft as fleece or the silkiest goat hair; cloaks and
                                        peignoirs, which are really furs with the warm side in. There are fur-lined
                                        slippers, and most delightful of all for those who dwell in chilly rooms, or
                                        like to sleep with the windows open in midwinter, fur-lined socks or short
                                        stockings, which can be drawn on in a second, and which make the coldest floor
                                        agreeable to the foot.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York Mail and Express" TEIform="index"/>New York Mail and Express.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="176" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I have dreamed of my home" TEIform="index"/>I HAVE DREAMED OF MY HOME.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, Florence" TEIform="persName"/>By Florence Staples.</byline><p TEIform="p">I have dreamed of my home in the morning land, And its visions before me rise; The domes and
                            spires of its city sublime Reared 'neath love's radiant skies. The city where truth her
                            altar builds, And peace her banner unfurls, Where the shining ones pass to and fro, Through
                            the glittering gate of pearls. I dreamed of its gardens so wondrously Of flowers that ornate
                            the sod; [fair, Of fruitage that death's chilling breath could not blight, In the beautiful
                            garden of God. No discord is known in that Eden of bliss; No shadow casts o'er it a gloom;
                            The rich balmy zephyrs wake music most rare, Mid its wealth of perpetual bloom. I have
                            dreamed of its mountains that rise proud and high; Where the lion's foot never hath trod;
                            Nor the eye of the vulture the brightness hath seen That halos the mountain of God. Blest
                            vision of glory! Oh sacred retreat! That feasted my wondering gaze; The holy of holies where
                            pure angels meet; The breath from thy height is but praise. I dreamed of a valley, the
                            valley of rest. Oh grandeur sublime to behold! The river of life gently threading its way,
                            O'er a sandy bed studded with gold; . Its rich vernal margin in flower-crowned grace Lay
                            kist by the beams from above; The lily in whiteness breathed sweetest perfume, There
                            blossomed the roses of love. I dreamed a peace that my soul compast A sweet calm pervaded
                            the air; [round; And there neath the wings of a bright seraphim. I knelt at the altar of
                            prayer, My heart felt the thrill of an unction divine, My being refresht by its flow, A rest
                            in the arms of an Infinite love, A peace that the world can not know. I dreamed of the
                            laurels that might wreathe my brow, The trophies for victories won; Of the bright stainless
                            robe that my form yet might wear When the earthly race fully is run; The gems and bright
                            jewels through toil and pain stored, Where time can not tarnish or blight; Where the weary
                            worn pilgrim the Father calls home To his merited treasures of light. I dreamed of the loved
                            ones who faded As the dew of a fair eventide; [away Through the mists they were waiting and
                            watching for me On the shores of eternity's side; Their whispering so soothing still falls
                            on mine ear; So peaceful no discord or jar; The light of their love beameth bright o'er my
                            way; "To me 'tis the Bethlehem's star." Oh was it a dream? to my questioning soul, There
                            cometh a touching reply; Look upward Oh mortal! mount upward thro' faith! Soon the shadows
                            of earth will pass by; And the city, the garden, the mountain and vale, The bright crystal
                            waters that flow, The laurels of conquest the peace for the strife In the mansions of rest
                            thou shalt know. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curtis, Mary Ann" TEIform="index"/>Mary Ann Curtis
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Mary Ann Curtis, at Enfield, N. H. Sept. 9, 1898. Age 76 years 1 mo. and 5 days. She had
                                been with the Society for many years. A loving interested Sister, and of such it may
                                well be said, "Well done good and faithful servant, enter thou into the joy of thy
                                Lord." R. C.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
AGENTS!
This is   the   oppor
tunity of your  life
Agents are making $50.00 to $150.00 a week.
Fitzhugh Lee, Maj. Gen. U. S. V., and late
Consul General to Cuba, writes
A BOOK ON CUBA
We have on press for early issue, General
Lee's own story of Cuba and the Spanish War
to be produced in a substantial book of over
500 pages, 7x9K inches in size and almost
ONE HUNDRED ILLUSTRATIONS
This is the only authentic work published
on the one subject occupying the minds of the
entire civilized world.
OUTFITS READY.
Liberal commissions will be paid and credit
given.   Address for full particulars,
THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETY,
91-93 FIFTH AVENUE, NEW YORK.
PUBLISHEBS OF GENERAL LEE'S BOOK.
We have authorized distributors everywhereTHE SHAKER COUIAIT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND    CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds.    Price 5 cts. each, postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz..
The New York
Recognized
the    United
and
Oldest     and      Best
Weekly    Paper     in
States.
Improved       Management,
Methods up to date.
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Literary, Scientific,
Humorous, Dramatic, Entertaining. Also G-. A. K., Masonic
Fire and Society News.
One Copy, One Year, $2.50.
Post yourself on what is going
on in     New   York.     Address
The  New  York Dispatch
317 Broadway, IVew York.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. Gr.
Hollisteb of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy,
find in its mathematical calculation, will
and themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIOKS,
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
PROPHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Bear, Preston, Ohio.
AND   THE
SPANISH WAR.
Dispatch
EXPLAINING
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
50  YEARS'
EXPERIENCE
Trade Marks
Designs
Copyrights &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain our opinion free whether an
invention is probably patentable. Communications strictly confidential. Handbook on Patents
sent free. Oldest agency for securing patents.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice, without charge, in the
Scientific American.
A handsomely illustrated weekly. Largest circulation of any scientific journal. Terms, $3 a,
year; four months, f 1. Sold by all newsdealers.
MUNN & Co.3613""-' New York
Branch Office, 625 F St., Washington, D. C.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
ROYAL BAKING POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
HOW TO MAKE MOIEY!
If you are out of employment and want
a position paying you from $50 to $100
monthly clear above expenses by working
regularly, or, if you want to increase your
present income from $200 to $500 yearly,
by working at odd times write the GLOBE
CO. 723 Chestnut St. Phila., Pa. stating
age, whether married or single, last or
present employment, and you can learn
how to make more money easier and
faster than you ever made before in your
life.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world*
Price, 10 cts.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A. remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of external inflammation
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of the
Liangs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthur Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>