<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1305" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18830501" TEIform="date">May 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
    <p> VOL. XIII, MAY. NO, 5. SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT HARVARD,
                        MASS. "Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>
                        </head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="97" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Page. Writing on the sky, .... 97 Gather up the Fragments, - - - 100 Review of Moral and Religious
                            Progress, 101 The Waste Basket, - - - 104 •Tames Daniels,.....- " Truth,........ 106 The Rose, ....... 107 If we
                            had thought,..... " Punctuality, .- ...." The Spirit of Blessing, - ... 108 Reflections,....... 109
                            Conviction,....... " a morning thought,..... 110 Letter Box,.....- - 111 Notes,........ 112 Laws of
                            Health,...... 113 Simple Remedies, More Air, A Bad Practice, The Use of Lemons, Kind Words for 1882, Care of
                            Grindstones, To Clean Mirrors, Cleaning Brass, Balancing Accounts, Oat Meal, ... Washing Fluid, Books &
                            Papers, Visit to the Shakers, The dimensions of Heaven, Confession and Excuses, A Beautiful Legend, Page. 113
                            116 117 119 120 Vol. XIII. MAY, 1883. No.</p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Writing on the sky" TEIform="index"/> WRITING ON THE SKY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> As the sky is the greatest extension of outward sight and contains the highest visible
                            objects, tlr's writing is designed to treat of the highest things of intelligence, which is
                            internal consciousness, or inward sight. If it induces any who fancy they see the best
                            things at a distance, or far in the past or future to investigate shakerism, as a light
                            bringing the best things to our own doors, the purpose for which it is intended will be
                            answered. The doctrine of the supernal life, if we are rightly informed, was made known to
                            Buddha the sage of India, in answer to his searching desire to know and remove the cause of
                            pain. Both Buddha and Jesus taught that though it is an object of hope to all, and the path
                            thereto is open to all who choose to travel therein, it cannot be attained without a total
                            sacrifice of interests in the lower life, and a vigorous and persistent prosecution of the
                            object by whoever would win it. Agonize to enter in at the strait gate said Jesus, "Strait
                            is the gate and narrow is the way that leadeth unto life." Jesus and his immediate followers
                            taught that the obtainment of that life was a matter of first importance "For what will it
                            profit a man if he gain the whole world and lose his own soul, or what will a man give in
                            exchange for his soul." Without it, they were not only liable to perish from the divine
                            source of life, but their greatest glory, beauty and happiness could never be complete, nor
                            their appointed destiny fulfilled. Yet only a select portion of mankind were deemed able in
                            that age of the world to enter upon it while in the birth sphere, and these, according to
                            Paul, <pb n="98" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 1)8 THE MANIFESTO. constituted the elect and first fruits of the
                            harvest, which implied more to follow. Only that select portion could be the disciples of
                            Jeous, according to the terms laid down by him, which were in essence and practical effect
                            nearly the same as those taught by Buddha for attaining Nirvana, and those who accept the
                            terms with a clear understanding, find that the conditions of success are not arbitrarily
                            imposed, but are determined by the character of the prize sought. Hence, when the professed
                            followers of Jesus ceased to comply with the conditions required, all their supposed
                            knowledge of his doctrine and the supernal life, became "a mere hypothesis of knowledge,
                            something to be argued about in their schools, not practiced, but floating in clouds, in
                            endless logic vortices," until the required conditions were again fulfilled by an illiterate
                            woman, urged thereto by irrepressible longings to free herself from that depraved nature,
                            through which the will is captivated, and temptations to wrong doing find access to the
                            soul. Ann Lee owning Jesus Christ as her head, Lord, and teacher, while laboring to know and
                            remove the cause of man's loss from God, (a loss which man's conduct makes too evident to be
                            rationally disputed,) revived anew the law and doctrine of the supernal life, with such
                            advances in its application to earthly conditions as the growth of centuries, the different
                            customs and habits*; of thought among the people to whom her message was directed, and its
                            adaptation to the common mind and the equality of the sexes, demanded. Ann was one of a
                            group of souls, like minded, prepared as tinder to kindle with fire thus again brought down
                            from heaven, and through their agency, and the co-operation of the Holy Spirit, the age of
                            the seventh trumpet, and the woman clothed with the sun, which typifies divine light, has
                            been ushered upon the earthly stage. We are not solicitous herein, to glorify mortals nor to
                            exalt a sect, but to draw the attention of weary, waiting, watching ones to living realities
                            and accomplished facts. The sage of Chelsea voiced a wholepome admonition- when he remarked
                            that "The crime of being deaf to God's voice, of being blind to all but parchment and
                            antiquarian lubrics when the divine hand writing is abroad on the sky, certainly there is no
                            crime which the supreme powers do more terribly avenge." It will doubtless be avenged by
                            allowing such criminals to wander long in their own delusion, and finally, by their
                            exclusion from a forward position in the adjustment of the age which said voice and hand
                            writing prelude. As when Jesus told certain confident opposers "The publicans and harlots
                            will go into the kingdom of God before you." For John came to you in a way of righteousness,
                            and you believed him not, but the publicans and harlots believed him, yet you having seen
                            it, repented not afterward. Ann once instructed her hearers thus, "Go and testify to the
                            world that Christ is reigning on the earth, and that he has sons and daughters, and the
                            world know it not because they do not confess and forsake their doleful abominations." Many
                            have been convinced by studying the prophetic numbers of Daniel and John, that the time has
                            expired for the things there predicted, to take place, and some have admitted that the
                            everlasting kingdom of God may be somewhere be- <pb n="99" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 99 gun,
                            though out of their sight. Daniel referring to the time of the end, says, "Many shall be
                            purified, made white, and tried, but the wicked shall do wickedly, and none of the wicked
                            shall understand, but the wise shall understand." Now as immoral and wicked conduct does not
                            disqualify people for observing and understanding external and natural phenomena, while it
                            does prevent them from comprehending spiritual causes, we have intimation in this passage
                            that the changes and evidence attending the presence of that kingdom, are of an internal and
                            spiritual character, and therefore cognizable only to spiritual perception. Hence, Jesus'
                            repeated charge to watch, lest that day come upon you unawares. If they were sufficiently
                            raised in spirit to hear the voice and read the hand writing now abroad on the sky, if they
                            were not deceived by a false hope and satisfied to remain where they are, they could not
                            long be in the presence of that kingdom without discovering and making their way into it.
                            Buddhism as a philosophy and rule of life would seem to have been a good preparation for the
                            doctrines of self-denial Jesus taught. The renunciations and crucifixions in either system,
                            were much like those of the other, in essence and in the results proposed, though differing
                            somewhat in external routine, the Christian routine being easier because more helpful,
                            useful, and less solitary than the Buddhist discipline. Shakerism is not distinct from pure
                            Christianity in the end sought, and the sacrifices demanded by it, being a new edition,
                            revised and adapted to the present age of progressed thought. Buddhism is at present
                            attracting great attention from scholars and liberal thinkers because of its literature,
                            language, and antiquity, and the influence these are supposed to have exercised upon the
                            growth of human ideas and conduct. Many are so prone to ascribe a natural cause for all
                            existing ideas and developments of thought and conduct, they seem entirely oblivious of the
                            fact that there has been at intervals, communication to man from an intelligence guperior to
                            mortals as evidenced in its power to predict what mortals could not foresee ; that the
                            inmost essence of all human beings is from a divine source, and that whenever through the
                            struggles of the creature to overcome the barriers of sense and unfold in the highest light
                            of its God given dower, the divine germ is allowed to freely expand in its own native
                            element, it always asserts the same general principles of purity, gentleness, humility,
                            self-sacrifice, patient willingness to serve, serenity, rectitude, harmony, and enlightened
                            intelligence, whether in Jesus, Ann, Buddha, Plato, or any who look to them as teachers. The
                            light of primitive Christianity having been obscured by a base substitution, which claims
                            the name and authority, and seeks to secure the advantanges of the genuine by hearing the
                            sayings ot Christ and doing them not, notwithstanding Jesus said, as if to forestall this
                            very perversion, uNot every one that calleth me Lord shall enter into the kingdom ot heaven,
                            but whosoever doeth the will ot my Father in heaven." Shakerism is a return to deeds, and
                            possesses the same efficacy through the co-operation of the Holy Spirit, to transform the
                            inward life, regenerate and purify the soul, and raise it to asionian or eternal life, as
                            had primitve Christianity, and the eight fold path of Buddhism, <pb n="100" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 100
                            THE MANIFESTO. and this too while discharging the ordinary duties of earth life, and
                            performing the reciprocal offices of society in communion with kindred spirits in the body
                            and out of the body Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="So much I realize of the duties of a Christian..." TEIform="index"/>So much I realize of the
                            duties of a Christian...</head><p TEIform="p"> "Gather up the fragments that remain, that nothing be lost." St. John, vi: 12. So much I
                            realize of the duties of a Christian, I am often left to wonder who can be passive, who can
                            repose in ease, thinking apparently of nothing but their personal convenience and comfort!
                            There probably was never a time in the age of man, when more was pending to preserve the
                            spirit of progress and reform, when greater effort should be made to maintain eternal truths
                            already revealed and reached, than the present. Thrones are tottering, dynasties being
                            destroyed, governments being shaken, the sources of life,—stocks and public funds unreliable
                            and last, but not least, the religious element, where, O where is it to be found only in
                            name ! Approach Calvary or the cross of Christ, and priest and people are ready to pounce
                            upon you with rancor and the rabid malignity of fiends. When destruction is near, the cry is
                            peace and safety. When the foundations are rotten and principles corrupt, unrelenting is the
                            heart and inflexible is the purpose to sustain them; and a powerful engine is raised,
                            largely calculated to thwart the purpose of the Almighty, in His plan for the salvation of
                            man ; in that, the adversary has cunningly established the Son of God in the God-head, as a
                            part of Deity, too exalted in life and character to be imitated or followed ; that it is
                            presumption to arrogate the right of profession strictly Christian or Christ-like, or to
                            assume a name angelic ; and whoever attempts it, is an ascetic, a recluse, too rigorous in
                            self-denial, a lunatic or a fool. When will man learn wisdom ? What but the principles of
                            honesty and truth will preserve nations, maintain governments and become bulwarks of
                            strength in the religious world? Ignore truth, even ignorantly, and we close the avenues of
                            light and progress ; we step on dangerous ground, and under our feet burns a volcano ready
                            for our destruction ; eruption is certain to overtake us and swallow us. What then is man's
                            remedy ? It is to sacrifice the beast in ourselves ; to make offerings unto God of our first
                            and best ripe fruits, not the useless and that.of little value. Let it be thoroughly
                            understood that self is to be dethroned ; that our lives are not to be devoted to personal,
                            family or private interest; but for our example, community interest was the pattern set in
                            the Mount of God m the establishing of the first Christian church in the days of the
                            apostles, which cuts off self in to to ; that the relation of husband and wife, although
                            good in nature when its true order is not abused, is not in harmony with spiritual life. It
                            is a natural order, established on an animal plane, having no place in the kingdom of
                            Christ, the resurrection heavens, where there is neither marrying nor giving in marriage,
                            where the subjects are as the angels, in every sense of the word, virgins in chaiacter;
                            whose life is spiritual, higher than can possibly be found on the earthly plane, where its
                            laws are natural and the operation of which produce only natural fruit. It is well
                            understood, that the govern- <pb n="101" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 101 merit of this world
                            must be sustained by natural laws. Its basis, if protective, are honesty and truth ; and
                            when in its most perfect condition, in its highest moral state, it is an earthly government.
                            But when we advance to the church of Christ, we come into and under the baptism of another
                            spirit, into spiritual life, a resurrection from the natural, all good in its order, yet in
                            its decree lower ; nor do we disclaim the rendering to Cagsar the things that are Caesar's ;
                            yet, as after the example of Jesus, not participating in the spirit of the order, which is
                            of the old creation and not the new. Thus being cut off from both fruitful and unfruitful
                            works of darkness, having "crucified the flesh with the affections and lusts," the old man
                            is doomed unto death and the new man, Christ Jesus is put on, and the subject becomes a new
                            creature. This is the testimony of the gospel of Christ, and as I believe, the only
                            redeeming quality in the economy of the heavens for the restoration of the human soul. It is
                            the divine order, foreign to anything and everything of human instincts or animal logic,
                            which neither time nor eternky can change. Therefore, to trifle with truth, in the purpose
                            of God will avail nothing. Hence, to obtain the blessing of love and peace, our only
                            alternative is submission to the will of our Father in Heaven, in which is to be found a
                            satisfactory reward, equal to all the sacrifices of a carnal life ; yea, surpassing all the
                            enjoyments found in nature. Enfield, N. H.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="With all the wild forces gathered home..." TEIform="index"/>With all the wild forces gathered
                            home</head><p TEIform="p"> With all wild forces gathered home And trained for love and care, How great the interest for
                            our own, And much the world dotli share. Be patient, then, with boisterous youth, And lead
                            them to the right, If in their hearts the seed of truth, The future ever bright.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Review of moral and religious progress" TEIform="index"/> Review of Moral and Religious
                            Progress.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Culture, physical, moral and spiritual, requires effort, action, perseverance, continuity of
                            purpose, determined and relentless energy. But, the tendency of the human race, in all
                            historic ages, has been to weary of the efforts to sustain life, physical or spiritual. The
                            development of moral character and soul life has been, like the development of science, a
                            ladder climbing process. But human progress has been undulating. First a Noachian struggle
                            for righteousness in generation, this was attained; then lost for want of continuous toil.
                            Second, A moral righteousness was taught by the Mosaic law. This dwindled into a mere
                            observance of ceremonies, tithe payments of mint, anise and cummin, but a "neglect of the
                            weightier matters of the law, judgment, mercy and faith." Thirdly, A spiritual righteousness
                            taught by Jesus and his disciples, this was closely pursued by conscientious devotees for
                            several centuries; but, at length, this has been tortured into clinical creedism, and was
                            found, expiring in the convulsive throes of revolution misnamed progress, Christianity, so
                            called, became a misnomer, a mockery! The Christianity of history, compared with the
                            Christianity of Jesus, is like rotten stone to the diamond. "Christianity established by the
                            crimson handed Constantine perpetuated by fear, force and fraud, inundated the ages with an
                            ocean of gore! It set an autodafe in the world's tribunal, an insatiate monster, dripping
                            with the blood of heretical martyrs." Its priests, numbers of them by thousands, while
                            preaching the "beating of swords into ploughshares, and spears into pruning hooks'' have
                            ministered to the powers of war, and been the Chaplains of armies, and even instituted their
                            inauguration, that have spilled the blood of more than three hundred millions of human
                            beings. Now, after 2,000 years of historical Christian civilization more than five millions
                            of historical Christians are trained to adroitness of movements and skill in the art of
                            murder- <pb n="102" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE MANIFESTO. ing their fellow Christians. Every so
                            called Christian nation is groaning under an immense war debt, incurred by carrying on wars
                            against other historic Christians.—The Christian world is dotted with forts to protect
                            Christians from Christians. Every sea mottled with iron clad monsters to aid in blowing
                            Christians up to their aerial heaven. Industry is crippled, honest toil robbed of rewards,
                            beggary is taxed to defray expenses of historic Christian warfare. Creeds, dogmas and fables
                            all have failed to save from sin and sorrow, war, strife, hatred and murder, the world of
                            historic Christendom. And such is the distrust of historic Christian nations in each other,
                            that one billion five hundred million dollars are annually expended, in so called times of
                            peace, to support standing armies. The heathen of the fourth century of historic
                            Christianity remarked, "There are no wild beasts as ferocious as Christians who differ
                            concerning their faith." In the name of its God, the Christianity of history has produced
                            every imaginable cruelty, men have exhausted their ingenuity to invent new methods of more
                            exquisite torture to be practiced on Christians who differed from them in Christian
                            faith.—Prisons and Penetentiaries are crowded with so called (Christian) criminals.
                            Historical Christianity claimed divine authority for chattel slavery. It has practiced woman
                            slavery for nearly two thousand years. It has nursed and provided for drunkenness and
                            debauchery. Innumerable lies, hypocrasies and frauds in courts, senates, castles, tribunals,
                            exchanges and churches. Adultery abounds in social, political, and mercantile life in all
                            historic Christian lands. A modern minister, "Beecher," has declared "All the frame work of
                            society seems to be dissolving; on every side we find men false to most important trusts.
                            The judiciary of some courts of so called Christians stinks like Sodom and Gomorrah." No
                            record is written in blacker characters than that of the seven centuries succeeding the
                            reign of Charlemagne; he caused 4,000 Saxons to be put to death in one day, because they
                            would not be baptized. The chair of St. Peter was filled by a succession of degraded
                            Pontiffs, each worse than his predecessor.—" Viler than a Priest" was one of the common
                            expressions of southern Europe, in the twelfth century. Those self-styled ''keepers of the
                            gospel" sneered, secretly, at the teachings which that gospel contained. Both Catholic and
                            Protestant historic christians have vied with each other in torturous persecutions for
                            heresy. Nine millions of persons are computed to have been burned, hanged, or drowned for
                            sorcery under the authorities of historic church domination. Seven thousand victims were
                            burned at Treves by the Christians of history. And the Christian executions which took place
                            in Paris are said to have been numberless. At the time of the black death at the town of
                            Chinon in France, a vast trench was dug, filled with straw and faggots, and two hundred
                            persons, men, women, husbands, mothers and children, thrown into it and burned to death by
                            Christians of history. The historic details of murderous persecutions of Christians of
                            history by their opponents of faith might be continued to a sickening, horrifying
                            culmination of testimony and then fall short of the facts of the subject. Under these
                            influences faith has waned from period to period, in the so called Christianity of the
                            times, and submerging waves of infidelity and even atheism have ilowed forth intermittently
                            upon the race, as a natural result of lost confidence in the so called Christianity of
                            history. Fourthly, At length, Revivalists, of spiritual light, truth and Christian purity
                            and power arose under the name of "French Prophets" this was during the great religious
                            revolution in the time of the Camisards, from 1702, onward to 171)5. These at length
                            perished through ambition of notoriety and the love of worldly vanity and creature comforts.
                            Fifthly, came Quakerism with its inspirations from the heavens ; its burning testimony
                            against war ; the lusts of the flesh in generation; the ostentatious pride of position and
                            power; the worldly glory of prelacy and monarchism ; the waiting on the spirit for
                            inspirations in silence, all, at length dwindled into measurable lethargic sleep and
                            indifference. Sixthly, and now, lastly, comes the Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing to
                            re- <pb n="103" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 103 vive and renew the Christianity of Jesus, and
                            his true disciples, and add thereunto the fulfillment of the mission of the Christ Spirit to
                            earth's inhabitants,—full salvation from war, strife, and every lust of the flesh and of the
                            mind; from all sins against the lawrs of God, and all the terrible consequences of sin. This
                            testimony comes a shaker of all things that can be shaken, in spiritual warfares of the
                            heavens and the earth, destroying all the vile passions of humanity; then follows songs of
                            gladness, and dances of rejoicing, to arouse the dormant spirit and quicken the soul to a
                            heavenly life. This testimony obeyed, brings to the soul eternal life in God; enables its
                            votaries to live purely, peaceably, lovingly and communistically as Brethren and Sisters,
                            possessors of the hundred fold blessings promised by the Son of God. Souls who have been
                            baptized into the life of this testimony, into the faith, confidence; inspiration and
                            salvation of this Christian Dispensation of God's goodness, mercy and love, and who become
                            unfaithful to hs ministrations, and thereby die to its saving power and fall into a second
                            death, from which, if there be any resurrection to a heavenly life, it has not yet been
                            revealed. At present the religious world is in mighty throes of revolution. The dried fruits
                            of mere Creed cease to vitalize the soul; the "vicarious atonement" does not save souls from
                            sin; nominal Christian profession and enrollment on the Church Record merely does not
                            produce a Christian character. Infidelity is becoming rampant; Christian purity, peace and
                            love are couchant. A prominent writer truly says, "Society is on the eve of a moral
                            interregnum Only a small minority of mankind will have anything to do with morals or
                            religion. There is a class shouting that God's Priests and morals are on the brink of one
                            common ruin. A bewildered class even inquire if human action is stable that is conformed to
                            Christian principle!?" "Just now the authority of supernatural or ethesiastical ethics is
                            much less than it has been for some hundreds of years. Intelligent and free men, in and out
                            of the Church are coming more and more to disbelieve that all in the Bible is infallible
                            truth. Many things which both the Church (of historical Christianity) and Bible declare to
                            be right the best part of the world now feels and declares to be wrong." "The best church
                            people, in practice, do really select, modify, drop out of, and add to the express teachings
                            of the Bible itself. The God character, (spoken of as a whole,) is now considered immoral,
                            he orders a prophet to lie ; a city to be given over to pillage, rape and robbery." "The
                            (historic) church has not taken its greatest concern for the practical conduct of its
                            members. Institutional ethics are also out of favor. The transcendental theory of ethics is
                            unsatisfactory. Beyond question, this is an age of transition. Old reasons are slipping out
                            of hand!!" But what are left? "If the motives prompting to morals and goodness are taken
                            away men will cease to be moral and good ! These motives have been fear of hell, or love and
                            enjoyment of Heaven. But, moral laws are as real, as natural as gravitation." And, although,
                            with most persons, this world has more weight than the next, yet, God's laws are immutable,
                            and, the observer and obeyer of them has a covenant with life eternal, but, whoso sins
                            against them is in league with death. The education of experience is the safe school of
                            ethics Who would jump a precipice, ignoring the laws of gravitation after seeing a few
                            people try it? The vices of the Roman Empire produced its destruction. So consummate the
                            vices of an individual. All change is not progression; some of those changes now in
                            operation result in digression from God's laws. The Bible, barring all irreverence, contains
                            more substantial truth as a guide to humanity than all other books of the ages, and in a
                            vastly more condensed and digestible form ; in fact, its delineation of virtuous principles
                            is the foundation of all systems of morals and true religion, and, notwithstanding
                            transitory conditions. Soul is again, and energetically, for the bread and waters of life!
                            Christ angel hosts are marshalling to visit upon human society on the shores of time, a new
                            baptism of life and love that flows from the eternal fountains of God. True Christianity is
                            not a desert system of ethical scholasticism but a vital force of a true and new life ! The
                            God of Jesus, and his Christianity is not a fitful hateful master <pb n="104" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 104
                            THE MANIFESTO. who saves us when Pie pleases, and damns us when He pleases, but the Faithful
                            Rewarder of all who diligently seek and serve Him, bestowing upon all His blessings, and, in
                            His merciful goodness, winning, by love, the unthankful and unholy, yet, in the day of His
                            righteous decision, giving to each soul according as his works shall be. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste basket or labor lost" TEIform="index"/> THE WASTE BASKET-0R LABOR LOST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Thus may it seem to thoe, but 'tis not so; All nojjle ends proceed from embryo. Through
                            self-development thou must arise, And patient practice, fraught with sacrifice, Will bring
                            to thee the gift so much admired, And which thy yearning heart hath long desired. Toil on,
                            then, in the noble cause of truth, Through years of childhood into trusting youth, Act well
                            thy part and do the best thou can, And thou wilt culminate—the living man. And even then
                            though small creation be, The mental talents nature gayest thee, With all the aid
                            development can lend, Thou fail to reach the much expected end, Remember that the stars that
                            gleam on high, Have each their place to fill within the sky, And though their magnitude be
                            great or small Eaeh shines, and shining, twinkles forth its all. No little orb despondingly
                            with-holds Its gleam of light, but cheerfully unfolds Its brilliancy) and though it cannot
                            be The ruling orb within immensity— The greatest in the constellation, still, It may be
                            brightest, and its mission fill. Then earnest toiler, toil away with care : Let patience
                            have its dwelling everywhere. If for the press thou toilest with thy pen, Be not
                            discouraged,—try, O try again; Though oft the "waste-basket" thy toils receive, Try yet
                            again, do not despair nor grieve, Nor in thy weakness throw thy pen aside, And pen and press
                            and editor deride. Take up thy pen and try thy labor o'er, And shouldst thou fail again,
                            'tis nothing more Than other minds have done, who since have moved The mental world and
                            benefactors proved. The great Galileo—immortal light! How much he suffer'd for the cause of
                            right. In mock humility thus forced to kneel, And truth's assertion shamefully repeal; Yet
                            not disheartened as his words do prove, He rises, then proclaims—"The, earth does move."
                            Enough for sample of such sterling worth; Go thou and likewise do—a power on earth, A beacon
                            light with firm persistent mind, To work for God by blessing all mankind. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="James Daniels" TEIform="index"/> JAMES DANIELS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN.</byline><p TEIform="p">The subject of this sketch was born in Nottingham, N. H. Aug. 17, 1767. His father Samuel
                            Daniels was from Madbury, Mass, and his mother, Betty Noble, from Portsmouth, N. H. On his
                            sixteenth birthday his parents gave him liberty to visit his brother Samuel tor one month,
                            as he had till this date remained closely at home with his father and mother. Samuel Jr. had
                            already a family of his own arid lived in the town of London, N. H. A journey from
                            Nottingham to Loudon, in those days, was quite a heroic undertaking for a boy of sixteen
                            years of age. The distance was some thirty five miles and a considerable part of the way was
                            through a dense wilderness. He, however, commenced the journey, on foot and alone, with a
                            seeming bravery, that dared any encounter with man or beast. He soon found it a great favor
                            when he had the good fortune to obtain a ride for a few miles on the horse or ox-team of any
                            farmer who chanced to be driving toward the home of his brother. Although he consummated the
                            whole journey without meeting with any accident, yet the hooting of the owls and the howling
                            of the wolves made it a time of excitement and constant fear. On reaching the residence of
                            his brother, he found that the family were not at home, but as James was so excited from
                            what he had met and exhausted from the long journey that he ventured to enter the house, and
                            hide himself under the bed-clothes, that he might be free from those frightful noises that
                            had followed him since he left his own home in Nottingham. On the return of the family <pb n="105" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 105 they were much surprised to find James in the
                            house as they had not learned of his arrival. After a visit of some three or four days his
                            brother Samuel gave him information concerning the Shakers, who had visited Loudon and had
                            held meetings in that place since the year 1782. As James knew nothing about the Shakers, he
                            concluded to make them a visit and see for himself, but as he had no especial interest in
                            any of the religious denominations, week after week passed away before he accepted the
                            opportunity. In the month of October, 1784, the Shakers appointed two meetings to be held at
                            the house of Stephen Sutton, in the town of Loudon. James made arrangements to attend the
                            meeting but was obliged to go without any company. Long before he reached the house, he
                            could hear them singing and shouting, and soon learned that they were engaged in a powerful
                            revival. Having no acquaintances in the place, he did not venture into the house, but
                            remained near a window where he could see and hear those who were engaged in their religious
                            devotions. James returned to the house of his brother with very favorable impressions in
                            regard to the Shakers, although he had, as yet, formed no acquaintances, nor even conversed
                            with any of the members. He attended the second meeting, and on this occasion was noticed by
                            Elder Henry Clough who very kindly conversed with James and advised him as only a gospel
                            father could, to take up his cross against the sins of the world. Elder Henry at th?. same
                            time gave him an invitation to live with the Believers, but this offer James declined. He
                            subsequently informed Elder Henry that he wished to weigh the matter thoroughly before he
                            could determine what he had better do. Elder Henry said, "That is perfectly right," and
                            commended him for his decision. This time he related all the circumstances of the visit to
                            his brother Samuel, and admitted that he loved the Believers and their manner of life, but
                            had not decided to live with them. A few weeks later he called on Elder Henry and before the
                            close of the interview he made an honest confession of his sins to God, before a witness. As
                            James did not wish to return to Nottingham, his brother Samuel and Stephen Sutton had an
                            interview with the parents, and urged that he should be allowed to remain in Loudon. The
                            father sternly objected for some time, but finally agreed to let James remain with Samuel
                            for two years provided this older son would give up a note of $30 which he held. James
                            worked for his brother till he had cancelled the obligation and then engaged himself to
                            other parties. Soon after this by the request of his parents he returned to Nottingham. For
                            the next year he lived most of the time in his father's family. The religious impression
                            which he had received from the Believers was now a test of his faith. He became convinced
                            that he must serve God for himself if he would keep his separation from the world. It was
                            the custom of the Believers to knetl in silent prayer before and after each meal. With the
                            consent of his parents, and in the company of his brothers and sisters who had no sympathy
                            with his religious conviction, he would kneel all alone in silent prayer, at every meal. <pb n="106" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 106 THE MANIFESTO. So often as he could make it consistent he visited
                            the Believers in London and attended their meetings which privilege obliged him to make a
                            journey of 35 miles. James received a severe rebuke from his father on account of the step
                            he had taken, as his parents endeavored to persuade him to change his religious views. A
                            family by the name of Barker who lived in the town of Warner became acquainted with James
                            and made a journey to Nottingham to see if they could make an agreement with the parents and
                            hire James to work for them the next two years. As they were professed Shakers James was
                            anxious to accompany them home. For his services the Barkers agree'1, to give the father
                            eighty acres of land. James went to Warner to see the property and then made a report to his
                            father. As the offer proved satisfactory Nathaniel Barker made out the papers and sent James
                            with them to see Elder Henry and ascertain his mind concerning the agreement. After Elder
                            Henry had heard the whole story, he advised James to remain with his father, till he was of
                            age and publicly to bear the testimony of a Shaker. James, however, became the apprentice of
                            Nathaniel Barker for two years, and was engaged most of that time as a cooper. When
                            Nathaniel Barker and his family moved to Enfield, N. H. James accompanied them to that
                            place. In December 1788, Chase Wiggin of Canterbury visited Enfield, and on his return James
                            accompanied him, and entered the family of Benjamin Whitcher. While at Enfield James had
                            learned the house carpenter's trade under the direction of Moses Johnson. Our record informs
                            us that he was engaged in the framing of nearly every building that was raised in Canterbury
                            during a term of some forty years. For twenty years he officiated as a family Deacon and was
                            one of the moct faithful and devoted members in the society. He was a man of few words but
                            always encouraged those who were young to be faithful and honest and never to mar a good
                            name. He died Dee. 2G, 1851, at the age of 84 years. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth" TEIform="index"/>TRUTH
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Francis S." TEIform="persName"/>FRANCIS S. SMITH
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If you have a truth to say, Say it always, come what
                                    may. Say it firmly—do not fear— Error flies, when truth is near. When vile slander
                                    stalks abroad, Backed by trickery and fraud, He who fears to speak his mind, Is no
                                    friend to human kind. Speak the truth whate'er betide, Though your enemies deride,
                                    They will have a feeling strong That you are right, and they are wrong But do not
                                    purchase sure remorse By using language blunt and coarse— Truth rages not—she shows
                                    her might In words both simple and polite. Speak the truth and take the risk— Truth
                                    is real, not a myth. It is certain that a lie Will expire—truth cannot die. Oh! 'tis
                                    pitiful to see The sickly shade of misery That marks the dastard liar's face When
                                    truth has published his disgrace. Speak the truth, and then you can Undaunted face
                                    your fellow-man. Truth seeks no hiding-place, for she Is honest, fearless, frank,
                                    and free. Truth had her birth where angels dwell, While the first liar was born in
                                    hell. Then, honor, virtue, reason, say, Which of the two should man obey?</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York weekly" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="107" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rose" TEIform="index"/> THE ROSE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brainard, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>JANE BRAINARD.</byline><p TEIform="p">A poet said,— "What mortal knows whence comes The tint, and perfume of the rose?" Another,
                            said,— "You may break, you may scatter the vase if you will; But the scent of the rose will
                            cling round it still." The rose we know is very attractive, much eulogized by poets and has
                            been called the "Queen of flowers." Dear friends, let us take a view of this beautiful
                            flower, analyze it critically if you never have. In every leaf you will find the finest
                            veins ; it emits the most delicate perfume. Its medicinal virtues are soothing. Thorns on
                            the bush may remind us of providential protection. This coincides with the interior life of
                            a Christian, in whom the innocence of childhood and wisdom gained by obedience to faith are
                            combined, we often see roughness on the exterior, like thorns on the rose bush ; but when we
                            get near enough to view7 the interior, the tennle, we find it is refined, where kindness,
                            gentleness, forbearance and charity seem unbounded. Like the perfume of the rose is the
                            incense arising from the soul of a Christian. Who would not aspire to be a Christian if they
                            knew the real virtue that forms the lovely character, -:nd have the companionship of
                            associates that work no ill ? Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Excess generally causes reaction..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Excess generally causes reaction...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Excess generally causes reaction, and produces a change in the opposite direction, whether
                            it be in the reasons, or in the individuals, or in governments.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Plato" TEIform="persName"/>Plato.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we had thought" TEIform="index"/>IF WE HAD THOUGHT
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If we'd thought at our last meeting With the friend we love so
                                    dear By his grave we'd soon be standing, Dropping down the silent tear, Would that
                                    word we spoke so lightly Have been uttered by us then? Would that in our silent
                                    sorrow We could call it back again. If we'd thought that soon a parting Would us
                                    sever far and wide, That some of the gladsome faces Would be soon across the tide,
                                    Would the hasty word and action, Would the satire sharp and keen From our lips have
                                    ever fallen, Or the action e'er been seen? If we'd thought the friendly counsel Was
                                    the last we e'er should hear, Would we then have scoffed so lightlyLet our
                                    heedlessness appear? If we'd thought the kind inquiry Soon would cease for evermore,
                                    Would it then have been a trouble. Would we then have wished it o'er? If we'd
                                    thought that act of kindness Was the last our friend should seek, Would we have by
                                    cruel harshness Brought the blushes to his cheek? If we,'d thought our heedless
                                    folly Would have left so deep a sore, Would we then have spoken rudely? Would we not
                                    have hushed it o'er? If we'd thought—alas ! the sorrows That the words awaken now;
                                    If we'd thought, ah, then the wrinkles Would be fewer on the brow ; If we'd thought
                                    that death was comingWill that be our latest cry? God forbid! we know he's coming,
                                    Let us think—he draweth nigh.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Evangelical messanger" TEIform="index"/>Evangelical Messenger.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Punctuality" TEIform="index"/> PUNCTUALITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Theobald, Arthur" TEIform="persName"/>ARTHUR THEOBALD.</byline><p TEIform="p">The positive necessity of punctuality cannot be too strongly enforced. As a matter of
                            business, it assumes an importance not to be overlooked. As a Christian virtue, we are <pb n="108" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE MANIFESTO. not, perhaps, so apt to view it, or, if we do, we
                            are negligent in regarding it. Nevertheless, its importance, both as relating to every-day
                            business affairs and as touching the Christian character, are too evident to be slighted.
                            Concerning business, the loss consequent to tardiness is sometimes as great perhaps, as that
                            resulting from carelessness or any other similar cause. Too often has property been
                            destroyed, life and limb endangered, and in many instances lost, consequent to the lack of
                            this mostnecessary accomplishment. The most important business and the best laid plans, have
                            often failed on account of individual neglect in this ..respect. Five minutes in a crisis is
                            worth years. Upon them may depend the fortunes of individuals, or the happiness and
                            prosperity of nations. As a Christian virtue this should receive due attention. We have no
                            right by our neglect, to place another in any position or circumstance, in which we
                            ourselves would be unwilling to stand. Our negligence to keep appointments may cause others
                            to fail in their duties, thereby bring censure, and even punishment upon them, which we
                            should by right receive. The neglect of a minute may cause anguish, which we would scarcely
                            wish to meet; but for which, we would justly be held responsible. The loss of a moment may
                            cause the loss of a soul. We cannot calculate the result consequent either upon our
                            promptness or its opposite. To gain the good of the one and avoid the evils 01 the other,
                            there is clearly but one way, to do now the duties of the moment without hesitation. In
                            this, we have the example and precepts of our Savior. He fully understood and appreciated
                            the value of the present moment. His sayings ring with the declaration, that, "Now is the
                            accepted time," and his example is none the less marked. He said, "Take no thought of the
                            morrow," that, in doing oui duties now, we might be unencumbered by any fears for the
                            future. His words are jus as true noAv, as they were eighteen lrandrec years ago. His
                            example in the right, is jus as valuable now as it ever was. It has beer remarked, that
                            "Punctuality is an angel virtue." While we may reasonably look with some satisfaction to the
                            progress and civilizaion of the present, let us not despise the cachings of the past. The
                            sages of ansometiquity have left us a valuable store. They have gathered together and
                            recorded the fruits of their lives, and let us profit by this experience. If there is
                            anything to be avoided one mportant evil is procrastination. If there as any accomplishment
                            to be cultivated it is punctuality. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of blessing" TEIform="index"/> THE SPIRIT OF BLESSING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, William" TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM WILSON.</byline><p TEIform="p">It is to those who have transmitted to us the greatest of all blessings ; the ever lasting
                            gospel; the light of Christ's Kingdom ; the dawn of a new day, that we iu the fullness of
                            our souls express a thankful and a grateful remembrance. We have been shown the
                            manifestation of the Coming of Christ, the object of his mission into this world, and the
                            manner in which his testimony was received by those unto whom he was sent. We have been
                            shown the magnitude of this mission of Christ and have learned why a manifestation of the
                            same spirit should appear the second time through the medium of a woman. These are true
                            principles, the light of man, which is life everlasting. The spirit of Christ appeared to
                            man through the man Jesus. To make complete that Almighty Arm by which all creation is
                            sustained, the same Christ spirit has its second appearance in the person of Ann Lee.
                            Indeed, and the light of this little company with the assistance of your ancestors have laid
                            the foundation for this our gospel home, and the principles by which it is sustained can
                            never fail, nay never. Those who build upon this <pb n="109" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 109
                            foundation are sure, they have built on the everlasting rock, the Rock of Ages. In this day
                            of great blessings we ask of the fathers and mothers whose tender care and prayerful spirit
                            are always over us, to remember us in the trials of life, that we may share the protection
                            of our Heavenly Father. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflections" TEIform="index"/> REFLECTIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mabee, Simon" TEIform="persName"/>SIMON MABEE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "First that which is natural then that which is spiritual." Why is it that the inventive
                            powers of man lie dormant for so many centuries*, depriving mankind of those useful
                            inventions which are now in operation in all departments of business? Did they not lie
                            buried under the darkness that covered the earth and the gross darkness that covered the
                            people. In those dark ages men's minds were spiritually inactive being led by their own
                            animal natures. The people would hear the priests preach Christ, who in their works
                            practically denied him. Jesus said, "If the blind lead the blind they will both fall into
                            the ditch," that ditch which has been filled with all the abominable deeds committed on the
                            earth: but the power above all powers has caused light to shine so that many begin to see a
                            little light and all that are honest and desire more light will progress, but it seems that
                            some hate to leave the old ditch. Jesus said "Men love darkness rather than light because
                            their deeds are evil." The fire of God's truth will i-earch and burn them out of their darV
                            places and bring them to the light where they will be seen as they are,—no hiding places.
                            God said by the prophet Hagai lie would shake the heavens and the earth, the sea and the dry
                            land, and all nations shall be shaken. This is now taking place both literally and
                            spiritually. The old foundation of Anti-Christ is being shaken, but the foundation that has
                            been laid by Jesus and Mother never will be shaken. All that build on the foundation that
                            Jesus Christ laid, and come out from the old dark system, and confess and forsake all sin
                            they will rejoice for their deliverance. They will feel as the children of Israel did when
                            they crossed the Red Sea. They will shout and sing and dance in praise to God. If such souls
                            continue faithful they will have a treasure in the spirit world where the wicked cease from
                            troubling and the weary are at rest. West Piitsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conviction" TEIform="index"/> CONVICTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p">They who are strangers to the spirit of conviction, have nut taken the first steps in
                            spiritual advancement. We: may become so wj apped in materiality, that the supersensuous
                            realm of the soul, is barred to the ingress of those divine illuminating influences that
                            quicken our perceptions of right and wrong, and reveal to our inner consciousness, the sins
                            and imperfections of the common heart and life of humanity. We may close our eyes to the
                            light, and blindly imagine that there is no sin or error hidden from sight; our past history
                            bears no stains or mars of wrong doing, for we have walked in the straight line of absolute
                            right; and, fondly clinging to the idols we cherish, still grope on in the dimly lighted way
                            of self appointed duty and pleasure. But, how dark our path seems at times ; how confused
                            and clouded the realm of thought; how uncongenial our surroundings, and how imperfect all
                            beside ourselves. ' We think, feel, judge and act, in consonance with that loftv. <pb n="110" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 110 THE MANIFESTO. self-poised pharisaical spirit, which ever proves
                            detrimental to the soul's progress. Measuring ourselves—not with "Truth to the line and
                            righteousness to the plummet,"— by the standard of mortal frailty, we seem to have attained
                            a good degree of perfection; to have advanced beyond the masses in knowledge and
                            enlightenment. We may see and denounce the great evils of society at large, and shun
                            participation in those glaring vices that sink mankind below the level of the brute creation
                            ; but, let us go back to the causes of evil; let us search out the secret springs of
                            thought, feeling and action, welling up in the nature of us all, and we will find occasion
                            for self-criticism. Superior conditions and surroundings may have changed the current of our
                            impulses and desires, and made it easier for our better nature to assert itself, yet have we
                            not ail the germs of evil in our hearts? Is there not some cause for reproach and
                            condemnation? And, Roman-like in spirit let us not fear to meet ourselves in righteous
                            judgment. The mere recognition of wrong, is not sufficient ; the wise man and woman welcomes
                            the spirit of conviction and repentance; in God's light, before His true witnesses, they
                            stand confessed and humiliated; but, in this humility, they feel true exaltation. "Strive
                            with thyself, that striving is not vain, No good comes forth save by the throes of pain."
                            The soul that fails sternly to battle wuh itself that good may rise paramount to evil—
                            answers not the grand design of its existence. If our life and character are made
                            conformable to the divine type manifested in those who revealed the fullness and perfection
                            of the Christ spirit; we must be partakers of their struggles, temptations, sufferings and
                            death. We must cease to tiiink, feel and act from the old Adamic plane of being, we must
                            become regenerate, spiritual men and women, drawing our life elements from angelic spiritual
                            centers of truth. Joy unspeakable awaits the soul, when, true to its relationship with
                            eternity, true to its truth and integrity, true to its innate promptings, it claims to be
                            heard even against itself, and boldly chastises when wrong has been done ! When conscious
                            that its errors have been of its own choice, it applies without shrinking, the just deserts
                            which reason demands. "Such shall triumph over error even in time; and, in the glorious
                            future, will be numbered with those who stand upon a sea of glass ;" transparent in soul and
                            character. "These are they who have come up out of great tribulation, having washed their
                            robes white in the blood of the Lamb" the life of Christ. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning thought" TEIform="index"/> A MORNING THOUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Flora" TEIform="persName"/>FLORA WILLIAMS.</byline><p TEIform="p">"The goodness of God leadeth to repentance." Rom. ii, 4. As we opened the Bible to select a
                            text for our morning exercise, this passage attracted our attention and we were particularly
                            impressed with the idea that it was the goodness of God and not the fear of an over-ruling
                            Power that leadeth the soul to repentance. We are reminded of the experience of Peter, He
                            had sadly sinned, denied his Lord and Master ; but the Lord turned and looked on Peter and
                            he "'went out and wept bitterly." That look could not have been one of hatred and scorn but
                            rather a recognition of Christian love and forgiveness. Behold, how great was the repentance
                            of the Prodigal Son ! How sweet the humility of his confession ! "Father I have sinned
                            against Heaven, and in thy sight, and am no more worthy to be called thy son." Was not this
                            humble confession and repentance wrought through the goodness of God? '-For with the heart
                            man believeth unto righteousness and with the mouth confession is made unto salvation." Let
                            us then through the "goodness of God that leadeth to repentance," enter these cleansing
                            waters which will <pb n="111" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Ill render us holy and acceptable as
                            members of that glorious Church not having "spot or wrinkle.' Then shall we be able to fully
                            appreciate the beautiful sentiments of the little hymn wp sometimes sing ; "Blessed fruits
                            of sweet repentance, Grown while stricken 'neath the rod ; Blessed lessons of instruction,
                            Sent to lead us home to God." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experience" TEIform="index"/> WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. EXPERIENCE.</head><p TEIform="p"> We learn our lessons as we go along. Each rising day a new experience opes. As we go forth
                            with mingled fears and hopes, To plod our weary ways amid the throng, Unmindful of the
                            burdens of the day. But often r.id the struggle and the heat Of life's great battle, Failure
                            and Defeat, The giant enemies of Purpose strong, Are sure to rise defiant in the way, And
                            then, unless by Right we quell the [Wrong, And triumph,-ah! we make the sad mistake. So we
                            will march right onward; let our song Be Faith and Courage ; and this counsel take, To learn
                            our lessons as we go along.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box. </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Elder Abraham;—I have wanted to write to..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Elder Abraham;—I have wanted to write to...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, West Pittsfield, March 6, 1883" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mar. 6,
                                1883.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hattie" TEIform="persName"/>Hattie</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Abraham;—I have wanted to write to you a good long while. I am learning to
                                work and to read. I can sing too, I have learned lots of songs. I like my nice home, I
                                have such good times. I have learned fourteen verses in the Testament and said them in
                                prayer meeting. I guess you won't think very queer for a little girl to write you a
                                letter, for little girls do write letters and I have read them in the Manifesto. Please
                                be real glad to get this and my love. Hattie.—Age, 7. P S. Please, I wrote this
                            myself.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister Caroline;—I thought perhaps you would like a..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Sister Caroline;—I thought perhaps you would like a...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Shaker Village, May 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, May,1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Sister Caroline;—I thought perhaps you would like a letter from your little girl. I
                                will tell you what I do. I knit and sew and play when I am not in school. I am trying to
                                be a good girl. I have learned to mark letters in linen since I have been here. It is
                                very useful, because I can mark the children's clothes. I take music lessons every day
                                with one of my little mates. Sister J. is our music teacher, and she has loaned me a
                                book that tells all about music, and I am going to learn it through I go to school every
                                day. I study music and read and write. I have six companion?. Please give my love to
                                Sister M. A. please tell her I am going to be a good sister. Your little girl.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. Horton.-—Age, 10.</byline></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Toad" TEIform="index"/>THE TOAD.</head><p TEIform="p">The toad is a very useful little animal. It is called the gardener's friend. We ought
                                never to kill a toad for it catches the bugs and insects which destroy the plants. At
                                night after he has got all he wants to eat, he digs a little hole and gets into it and
                                stays there till morning and then comes out and gets something to eat. We had shingles
                                put beside the hills of squashes so we could kill the the squajh bugs ; they get under
                                the shingles over night. I had to go around every morning and take a stick and kill the
                                bugs. Once I was going to kill the squash bugs I saw a little toad under a shingle, he
                                had dug a little hole and got in it. I let him stay there. Another time when some of the
                                boys and myself were weeding peas we caught a toad, we picked it up and it made three
                                little noises which sounded as if he said, "let me go," and we let him go.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Forest" TEIform="persName"/>Forest.—Age, 12.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thought" TEIform="index"/>A THOUGHT
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lucrece" TEIform="persName"/>BY LUCRECE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Here are bitter, bitter tears ; here are weariness and
                                    pain : This is life! Who that hath known it e'er could wish it back again? In that
                                    silent, twilight land; in that land so far, yet near— That is death! Who that hath
                                    known it may not hunger to be here!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Scribner's" TEIform="index"/>Scribner's.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="112" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whatever we may speak or write..." TEIform="index"/>Whatever we may speak or write</head><p TEIform="p"> Whatever we may speak or write in reference to the subject of a religious life, it will
                                invariably resolve itself into this simple formula. "Thou shalt love the Lord thy God
                                with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy strength, and with all thy
                                inind, and thy neighbor as thyself." The extended experience of some two thousand years
                                in that which serves to civilize and educate the minds of men, will not, as yet, take us
                                beyond the testimony that Jesus preached on the Mount. The meek, the merciful, the pure
                                in heart and the peacemakers were to inherit the Kingdom of God. The doctrine was
                                simple, easy to be understood, and was made of practical benefit to the disciple. His
                                was a church without a creed, a divine service without formal ceremonies and the
                                enjoyment of the Kingdom of God, even while he lived upon the earth. If we have accepted
                                this testimony and are able to manifest it in our lives, in our buying and selling, in
                                our conversation with, and representation of others, and in our general deportment
                                before men, we may be able to let our light shine, that others by seeing our godly walk
                                may be led to glorify our Father in heaven. Without this there can be but little effect
                                for good produced by preaching any form of words or by publishing any amount of books.
                                The time has gone by when men are expected to accept a system of religious views without
                                investigation. There are tests by which to prove every thing that may be offered, and
                                unless it harmonizes with the spiritual intelligence of the present day, it is left to
                                waste itself away "on the desert air." With this knowledge our only hope as a Christian
                                people must be in maintaining the principles of righteousness as found in the testimony
                                of Jesus Christ. Separating ourselves from the world and its sinful practices, we must
                                not lose sight of our obligation toward those whom we have left in the rear. Our
                                happiness in a great measure depends upon the happiness of others, and to insure this
                                demands a faithfulness to our gospel call. Our mission should be that of "good news"
                                which will inform the multitude, how they may obtain an hundred fold reward of houses
                                and lands and of fathers and mothers in this world, and with this a divine promise of
                                Eternal Life in the world to come.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How often are we reminded of our religious..." TEIform="index"/>How often are we reminded
                                of our religious</head><p TEIform="p"> How often we are reminded of our religious obligations I Professors of an order of
                                spirituality as "strait as straitness and as pure as the heavens ! !" Is it an active
                                principle, and does it make itself manifest by an increase of good works? Passive
                                goodness may do very wrell to look at as it steps gingerly along the way lest it soil
                                its feet by contact with the earth, but can be of but little use in the warfare through
                                which the Christian must pass on his pilgrimage to the Holy Land. Jesus has recommended
                                us "to watch," but while we are watching we should at the same time be actively at work,
                                and while securing our own redemption, faithfully and earnestly contend for the
                                salvation of the children of this world. In this and with this <pb n="113" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 113 should be our prayers, for without an earnest prayer from an honest
                                heart there can be but little hope. Our mission, although preparatory for the heavenly
                                state, is a mission which belongs on the earth, and has largely to deal with the things
                                of the earth. The voice of God through his servants has called us from "darkness into
                                light," it has given us an inheritance which most assuredly belongs to the children of
                                the resurrection, and to those who love righteousness and hate iniquity. The Christian
                                has no time to squander in idleness, we must move onward and upward, away from the
                                careless, coarse and vulgar practices of the world, whether in our language, in our
                                action or even in our thoughts. Failing to do this we fail of accepting the testimony
                                which is to cut us off" from the world.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Laws of health" TEIform="index"/> LAWS OF HEALTH.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Children should be taught to use their left hand as much and as well as their
                                        right. Coarse bread is much better for children than fine. Children should sleep
                                        in separate beds, and should not wear night caps. Children and young people
                                        should be made to hold their heads up and shoulders back, while standing,
                                        sitting or working. The best beds for children are of hair, or in the winter of
                                        hair and cotton. From one to one pound and a half of solid food is sufficient
                                        for a person in the ordinary vocation of business. Persons in sedentary
                                        employments should drop one third of their food, and they will escape dyspepsia.
                                        Heading aloud is conducive to health. The more clothing we wear, other things
                                        being equal, the less food we need. Sleeping rooms should have a fire place or
                                        some mode of ventilation besides the windows. Young people and others cannot
                                        study much by lamplight with impunity. The best remedy for eyes weakened by
                                        night use, is a fine stream of cold water frequently applied to them.</quote></cit></p><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London lancet" TEIform="index"/>London Lancet.</bibl></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple remedies" TEIform="index"/>SIMPLE REMEDIES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Half a teaspoonful of common table salt dissolved in a little cold water, and
                                        drank will instantly relieve "heart burn" or dyspepsia. If taken every morning
                                        before breakfast, increasing the quantity gradually to a teaspoonful of salt and
                                        a tumbler of water, it will in a fewdays cure any ordinary case of dyspepsia,
                                        if, at the same time due attention is paid to the diet. There is no better
                                        remedy than the above, for constipation. As a gargle for sore throat it is equal
                                        to chlorate of potash, and is entirely safe. It may be used as often as desired,
                                        and if a little is swallowed each time it will have a beneficial effect on the
                                        throat by cleansing it, and by allaying the irritation. In doses of one to four
                                        teaspoonfuls in half a pint to a pint of tepid water, it acts promptly as an
                                        emetic ; and in cases of poisoning is always at hand. It is an excellent remedy
                                        for bites and stings of insects. It is a valuable astringent in hemorrhages,
                                        particularly for bleeding after the extraction of teeth. It has both cleansing
                                        and healing properties, and is therefore a most excellent application for
                                        superficial ulCERATION. Mustakd is another valuable remedy. No family should be
                                        without it. Two or three teaspoonfuls of ground mustard stirred into half a pint
                                        of water acts as an emetic very promptly, and is milder and easier to take than
                                        salt and water. Equal parts of ground mustard and flour or meal, made into a
                                        paste with warm water, and spread on a thin piece of muslin, with another piece
                                        of muslin laid over it, forms the often indispensable "mustard plaster." It is
                                        almost a specific for colic, when applied for a few minutes over the "pit of the
                                        stomach." For all internal pains and congestions, there is no remedy of such
                                        general utility. It acts as a counterirritant, by drawing the blood to the
                                        surface; hence in severe cases of croup a small mus- <pb n="114" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 114
                                        THE MANIFESTO. tard plaster should be applied to the back of the child's neck.
                                        The same treatment will relieve almost any case of headache. A mustard plaster
                                        should be moved about over the spot to be acted upon, for if left too long in
                                        one place it is liable to blister. A mustard plaster acts as well when at a
                                        considerable distance from the affected part. An excellent substitute for
                                        mustard plasters, is what is known as "Mustard Leaves." They come a dozen in a
                                        box and are about four by five inches in size; they are perfectly dry and will
                                        keep for a long time. For use, it is only necessary to dip one in a dish of
                                        water for a minute and then apdy it. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="More air" TEIform="index"/>MORE AIR.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Those who have been housed for the winter, scarcely securing a breath of pure
                                        air for months, should now breath as much of the spring air as possible, as one
                                        of the most important means of purifying the blood. All nature is active,
                                        vitalized, putting on new life and more graceful attire, and it is the privilege
                                        of debilitated women, nearly worn-out house-keepers, the victims of "nervous
                                        prostration." (A new disease, or one with a fashionable name, meaning something
                                        or nothing.) It is the right of all such to rally with the return of spring, and
                                        to do so by breathing more of God's pure air—free to all creatures, and as
                                        life-giving as free ! These exhausted women have a right to throw off some of
                                        the drudgery of kitchen toils—some if not much of this is needless—and enjoy the
                                        air and sun, while managing a flowergarden. Women have "rights," and among them
                                        is that of taking better care of their health, which implies a little more
                                        leisure, less of the burdens, cares and anxieties of domestic life. This she can
                                        have by the adoption of plain, simple and and sensible habits of living and
                                        dress.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="City &amp; country" TEIform="index"/>City &amp; Country</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To sleep in clothes worn through the day..." TEIform="index"/>To sleep in clothes worn
                                through the day</head><p TEIform="p"> To sleep in clothes worn through the day is a bad practice. The clothes are filled with
                                the effluvium emanating from the natural wastes from the body all through the day.
                                Especially is this the case with those who labor hard, or perspire easily. The poisons
                                of the system thus ejected or thrown off by people in vigorous health furnish a strong
                                reason, if there were no other, for removing on retiring every article worn through the
                                day.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Use of Lemons" TEIform="index"/> THE USE OF LEMONS.</head><p TEIform="p">The lemon tree is a native of Asia, although it is cultivated in Italy, Portugal and in
                                the south of France. In Europe, however, it seldom exceeds the dimensions of the
                                smallest tree, while in its native state it grows to over CO feet in height. Every part
                                of this tree is valuable in medicine, though we rarely employ any but its fruit, that
                                is, the lemon itself. And everyone knows how to employ this in lemonade—to squeeze the
                                juice into cold water; this is the shortest way—or to cut in slices and then boil it.
                                Either way is good. Lemonade is one of the best and safest drinks for any person,
                                whether in health or not. It is suitable to all stomach diseases, is excellent in
                                sickness—in cases of jaundice, gravel and liver complaints. The pippins crushed may also
                                be mixed with water and sugar, and be used as a drink. Lemon juice is the best scorbutic
                                remedy known. It not only cures this disease, but prevents it. Sailors make a daily use
                                of it for that purpose. I advise every one to rub their gums daily with lemon juice to
                                keep them in healthThe hands and nails are also kept clean, white, soft and supple by
                                the daily use of lemon instead of soap. It also prevents chilblains. Lemon is used in
                                intermittent fevers, mixed with strong, hot black coffee without sugar. Neuralgia may be
                                cured by rubbing the part effected with a cut lemon. It is invaluable also to cure
                                warts, and to destroy dandruff on the head by rubbing the roots of the hair with it. In
                                fact, its uses are manifold, and the more we employ it, externally and internally, the
                                better we shall find oiirselves. Natural remedies are the best and nature is our best
                                doctor, if we would only listen to it. Decidedly rub your hands, head and gums with
                                lemon, and drink lemonade in preference to all other liquids.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A room in which a bath is taken..." TEIform="index"/>
                                A room in which a bath is taken...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A room in which a bath is taken should not be of a lower temperature than seventyfive
                                degrees F.</p></div3></div2><pb n="115" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind Words for the Year 1882" TEIform="index"/>
                            Kind Words for the Year 1882
                        </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I think highly of the ability and talent displayed in 'The Manifesto,'..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I think highly of the ability and talent displayed in 'The Manifesto,'...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Lyndenboro, December 1882. " TEIform="index"/>Lyndenboro, N. H. Dec.
                                1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">I think highly of the ability and talent displayed in "The Manifesto," and shall be
                                pleased to have you enter my name as a subscriber.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Putnam, J. D." TEIform="persName"/> J. D. Putnam. </byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The general management and printing of 'The Manifesto,' are very good..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The general management and printing of 'The Manifesto,' are very good...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, February 1882" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Feb.
                                1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">The general management and printing of "The Manifesto," are very good and pretty indeed,
                                and as a whole the paper is worthy of much credit. We congratulate our dear Canterbury
                                friends much, on the whole, for getting up so nice a paper.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am well pleased with 'The Manifesto.'' I cannot see that..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I am well pleased with 'The Manifesto.'' I cannot see that...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, North Union, March 1882" TEIform="index"/>North Union, Ohio, Mar. 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p">I am well pleased with "The Manifesto.'' I cannot see that it has suffered any Joss in
                                the change of its location, or in its several departments. I cannot suggest any
                                improvement. Many thanks are due the former Editor and Publisher for the able manner in
                                which they conducted the paper. There is no part of our little paper more interesting
                                and instructive to me than the biographical sketches of the first founders of Shakerism.
                                They will bear reading more than once.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. Prescott</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of grindstones" TEIform="index"/> CARE OF GRINDSTONES.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The following rules should be observed in the care of grindstones. 1. Do not
                                        waste the stone running it in water, nor allow it to stand in water when not in
                                        use, as this will cause a soft place and consequent uneven wear. 2. Wet the
                                        stone by dropping water on it from a pot suspended above the stone, and stop off
                                        the water when not in use. 3. Do not allow the stone to get out of round, but
                                        true up with a piece of gaspipe or "hacker." 4. Do not leave the stone out of
                                        doors in the wind and weather, as this hardens it and makes it less effective.
                                        5. Clean off all greasy tools before grinding, as grease or oil destroys the
                                        grit. 6. When you get a stone that suits your purposes, keep a' sample of the
                                        grit to send to the dealer to select by, as this is the way you can always
                                        secure one that suits.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Mechanical journal" TEIform="index"/>Mechanical Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To clean mirrors" TEIform="index"/> TO CLEAN MIRRORS.</head><p TEIform="p"> Take a newspaper or part of one, according to the size of the glass. Told it small and
                                dip it into a basin of clean cold water; when thoroughly wet squeeze it out in your hand
                                as you would a sponge, and then rub it hard all over the face of the glass, taking care
                                that it is not so wet as to run down in streams. In fact, the paper must only be
                                completely moistened or dampened all through. After the glass has been well rubbed with
                                wet paper, let it rest for a few minutes, and then go over it with a fresh, dry
                                newspaper, folded small in your hand, till it looks clear and bright, which it will
                                almost immediately and with no further trouble. This method, simple as it is, is the
                                best and most expeditious for cleaning mirrors, and it will be found so on trial—giving
                                a cleanness and polish that can be produced by no other process. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cleaning brass" TEIform="index"/> Cleaning Brass.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Government recipe for cleaning brass, used in the arsenals, is said to be
                                        as follows : Make a mixture of one part common nitric acid, and one-half part
                                        sulphuric acid in a stone jar ; then place ready a pail of fresh water and a box
                                        of sawdust. Dip the articles to be cleaned in the acid, then remove them into
                                        the water, after which rub them with sawdust. This immediately changes them to a
                                        brilliant color. If the brass is greasy it must be first dipped in a strong
                                        solution of potash and soda in warm water; this cuts the grease so that the acid
                                        has the power to act. The Manufacturer says that rusted steel can be cleaned by
                                        washing with a solution of half an ounce of cyanide potassium in two ounces of
                                        water, and then brushing with a paste composed of half an ounce of cyanide
                                        potassium, half an ounce of castile soap, an ounce of whiting and sufficient
                                        water to make the paste. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cornwall reflector" TEIform="index"/>Conwall Reflector.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Balancing accounts" TEIform="index"/> BALANCING ACCOUNTS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Every man, whatever may be his business or condition, should at least once a
                                        year ascertain, as nearly as possible the value of his property, and an effort
                                        should be made to set- <pb n="116" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/>lie all open accounts as often as
                                        once a year; once a month is better. The first of January coming at a season of
                                        the year when the farmer has more leisure, it is a good time for him to look
                                        over his accounts, and collect and pay his bills as far as possible. Long
                                        unsettled accounts often lead to hard feelings, hard words, and the severing of
                                        friendship ; it is therefore best to settle accounts often, even if the balance
                                        canno tbe J&gt;aid. If one must owe it is better to owe it to one or two
                                        persons than to owe it to a large number in small unsettled accounts. There are
                                        many advantages to a man to know, at least once a year, just how much he owes,
                                        and how much he has owing to him, and also if his property has diminished or
                                        increased, during the year; if he finds that it is less than a year ago it will
                                        lead him to economize and to put forth greater exertions the coming year, that
                                        the balance may be on the right side: it will also lead him to review the
                                        management of his farm, to discover if possible a more profitable way to conduct
                                        it; this review may open his eyes to many little wastes which had not before
                                        been thought of. The farmer in looking over his property, to estimate the value
                                        of each article or animal will have his attention called directly to it, and by
                                        comparing with last year's value he will know better how well he has managed
                                        during the year; if it be a piece of land he will estimate what has been the
                                        improvement, or how much it has lost, and if an animal, its Talue compared with
                                        last year, will be a reminder of what has been his success in feeding it. In
                                        estimating the value of farm property, permanent improvements should be
                                        considered by themselves and added to the capital stock as well as to the
                                        profits of the year. The condition of the buildings should be considered ; if no
                                        repairs have been made the Talue should be estimated as much less than the year
                                        before, as the average yearly cost of repairs, if repaired, then the cost of
                                        repairing should be added, less the averaged yearly cost of repairs. The farmer
                                        cannot spend one or two days in a year to better advantage than to carefully
                                        look over his property and estimate its value, at the same time recording it, so
                                        as to be able to compare it with what he may possess another year.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Tribune and farmer" TEIform="index"/>Tribune and Farmer.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washing fluid" TEIform="index"/> Washing Fluid.</head><p TEIform="p">—Take five pounds of sal-soda, one of Borax, and one of unslacked lime. Dissolve the soda
                                and borax in one gallon of boiling water; then pour them both into eight gallons of cold
                                water ; stir it a little and let it stand all night. In the morning pour off the clear
                                fluid for use. For two pails of water use a half pint of the compound ; soak your
                                clothes over night, rubbing soap on the soiled parts. Wring them out and put them over
                                to boil in water containing soap and fluid. After boiling fifteen minutes, take them out
                                into cold water, and suds and rinse them. Don't be afraid to boil the clothes before
                                they are washed; it will not hurt them.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mix a little carbonate of soda with the water..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Mix a little carbonate of soda with the water...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mix a little carbonate of soda with the water in which flowers are immersed, and it will
                                preserve them for a fortnight. Common saltpeter is also a very good preservative. The
                                yellow stain made by the oil used on sewing machines can be removed if, before washing
                                in soapsuds, the spots be rubbed carefully with a bit of cloth wet with ammonia.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To tin a new soldering iron" TEIform="index"/> To Tin a New Soldering Ikon.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="T., W. J." TEIform="persName"/>W. J. T.</byline><p TEIform="p"> sends the following: "The old fashioned way is to file your iron or copper on the point
                                into the shape you want it, put it into a clean fire and heat it until it will melt
                                solder easily, wipe it clean and rub it on a pine board with rosin and solder until the
                                point is tinned as you want it. The new way is to heat as above and wipe clean, then
                                apply soldering fluid (made from zinc dissolved in muriate acid,) to the point where you
                                want the tin, and rub it on a board with solder as above."</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oat meal pudding" TEIform="index"/> OAT MEAL PUDDING.</head><p TEIform="p"> If you wish to have it for breakfast, put your meal into a tin vessel large enough to
                                cook it in, pouring on a little cold water sufficient to swell it a little: let it stand
                                over night, and in the morning pour on boiling water, stirring it well. Add salt
                                sufficient to season it; then place it in a kettle of boiling water stirring it several
                                times, or until you tliink it swollen sufficiently, but care should be taken not to stir
                                it after it is cooked, as stirring too much serves to mash it, and it is not as
                                palatable as if whole. We think this method of cooking it better thnn stirring it
                                immediately into the vessel over the fire.</p></div3></div2><pb n="117" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Phrenological Journal and Science of Health, April; Contents; Wagner and Dore, with
                                portraits, On the St Lawrence from Clayton to Montreal, Illustrated, Character of Ladj'
                                Macbeth, A True Ghost Story, A newCephalometer, Illustrated, William C. Bryant and his
                                poetry, Illustrated, Getting used to it, A Dutch Lady Doctor, The Trance State, as
                                related to Seasickness and Surgery, Kitchen Leaflets, Notes in Science, ete, etc. Fowler
                                and Wells, Publishers, 753 Broadway, N. Y. One copy, one year $2.00. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Hall's Journal or
                                Health, March, Contents; Rheumatism, Economy, Cold Feet, Laws of Health, Simple
                                remedies, Digestibility of Coft'ee and Sugar, Analysis of food, Dangers of Phosphones,
                                etc, etc. E. H. Gibbs. A. M. Editor. 135 Eighth St. N. Y. Terms, $1,00 per. year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>The Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Herald of Health, April, 1883; Contents; The treatment of Criminals, Cooked, vs
                                Uncooked, Water, Running as an Exercise, Dyspeptics and the Sick, The good Health
                                Society, Studies in the hygiene for women, etc, etc. Pub. by M. L. IIolbrook, M. D.
                                13&amp;15 Laight St. N. Y. $1,00 per year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Homiletic Monthly for April contains
                                the usual collection of Sermons— and the discourses are mostly men from whom the clergy
                                like to hear. Among them are Bishop Simpson, Canon Farrar, Dr. John R. Paxton, Dr. R. S.
                                Storrs, Dr. II. W. Thomas, Dr. Ormiston, Dr. Joseph Parker and Mr. Spurgeon. Rev. L. O.
                                Thompson furnishes a "Prayer-Meeting Service" for each week in April. Dr. Howard Crosby
                                continues his series on "Important Texts." Dr. Wm. Ormiston begins a careful and
                                scholarly "Commentary on James," and the Baptists are represented by Drs. R. S.
                                McArthur, Bridgman and J. B. Thomas. Rev. Chas. Parkhurst tells "Why the Manuscript
                                should be Retained." $2.50 a year; Funk &amp; Wagnalls, 10 and 12 Dey Street. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="St. Louis magazine" TEIform="index"/>The St. Louis Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">FOR
                                TEN CENTS. The St. Louis Magazine now in its 14th )7ear, is replete with illustrations,
                                stories, poems, timely reading, a carefully prepared fashion article, and in short, is
                                the best magazine for its price published East or West. Sample copy sent to any address
                                for 10 cents. Address Jas. Gilmore, 213 North 8th St. St. Louis, Mo. This paper and the
                                St. Louis Magazine sent one year for $1.10. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mr. Heaphey's ghost" TEIform="index"/>MR. HEAPHY'S GHOST
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In compliance with the
                                emphatic recommendation of Hon. L. C. Draper, of Wisconsin and a numerous list of
                                correspondents, we have issued in pamphlet form, the remarkable account of spirit
                                visitation published in last week's Journal under the title of Mr. Heaphy's Ghost. It is
                                now printed on heavy tinted paper, making a neat tract for general distribution and
                                preservation; and will be sent to any address at 5 cents for a single copy, ten copies
                                for 25 cents, twenty-five copies for 50 cents. It is a splendid thing to scatter among
                                your friends.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to the Shakers" TEIform="index"/> [From Pomeroy's Democrat.] VISIT TO THE SHAKERS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pomeroy, M. M." TEIform="persName"/> BY M. M. POMEROY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Twelve miles northeast from Concord, is Shaker Village, a^ay up there on—or in among the
                            Canterbury Hills. At least it is all the way up, up, up, from Concord to the village. The
                            way is out of the city, then across the river and then out on to a New Hampshire hilly
                            country with here and there some good and some poor farms, houses and homesteads. People
                            think a great deal of their farms with their coverings of stones, and on the principle that
                            the nigher the bone the sweeter the meat, the soil about here, except in the valley or along
                            the river, and called intervale lands, ought to be pretty near clear taffy, or strained
                            honey at least. In company with Frank Ingalls a manufacturing druggist of Concord, we rode
                            to Canterbury in a cutter, the Friday before Christmas and had a most enjoyable ride, making
                            the distance inside of two hours, and arriving at Shaker Village a little before noon. This
                            family of Shakers, occupy here in this portion of New Hampshire a farm of nearly a thousand
                            acres, generally well cleared and under fine cultivation. They had to have a large farm in
                            order to find places to pile the granite rock into fences! But they have piled several
                            thousands of cords of them, more or less, very nicely, and thus are stone fences made. The
                            village itself is a wonderfully clean, neat appearing settlement where live about one
                            hundred and fifty men, women and children, who form this family. There are houses, shops,
                            school rooms, a church, barns, sheds, stables, all on the right-hand side of the road as we
                            enter the quiet village, and on the left there is an office building of good size, a few
                            shops, barns and a post-office which is in the office of the Society. Halting in front of
                            the office from the door of which the deep snow had been nicely shoveled away, we were
                            cordially welcomed, in* vited to enter and shown into a neat reception room in the rear of
                            the building, from the windows of which a view is had of a beautiful hilly country, now
                            heavily buried under the snow. A Shaker brother cared <pb n="118" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> for our horse
                            and here we could indeed say, as said the Spaniard, when lie reached that portion of the
                            country—"Alabama!" Here we rest. Who are the Shakers f They are an honest, earnest,
                            well-meaning religious people who are at home when apart from the rough element that forms
                            the world in general. A morn conscientious people are not upon the face of the earth They
                            believe what they believe, and live right up to their belief, and deserve, as they receive,
                            our good wishes and deep respect. They believe in Ann Lee as Christians believe, or profess
                            to believe in Jesus Christ, and as the Catholics believe in the Virgin Mary. They believe in
                            the life, the teachings and the testimony of Jesus Christ as taught by and through the
                            ministration of Ann Lee. The name of Shakers was given to them as an epithet of opprobium,
                            but they pay no more attention to it than a duck does to rain. No matter what others call
                            them they designate themselves as the "United Society of Believers." The bed-rock of their
                            religious Temple is Confession of Sin, Purity of Spirit, and a United Inheritance. Where the
                            great effort is to Purity, there is but little of sin to forgive and the more willingness to
                            forgive it. Their property is in common, belonging to no one but to all, and therefore they
                            form a United Community. Their belief is: A life of innocence, strict temperance and virgin
                            purity; entirely abstaining from all sensual and carnal pleasures or indulgences. Love for
                            all men as the fulfillment of the law. Peace with all men. Justice to all men; that every
                            one shall have his due. Holiness, which they interpret as being set apart or consecrated to
                            a humanitarian work. Goodness, or in other words doing unto all men as we would that men
                            would do to and by us. Truth as an eternal principle ; meaning an entire departure from
                            lying, deceit and hypocrisy, and an anchoring to the principles of reality, sincerity,
                            fidelity, correctness of speech, and punctuality in keeping vows. They do not worship Christ
                            or Ann Lee, yet love, venerate and observe their teachings. They worship God, and revere the
                            ones they look upon as beautiful, eternal examples. They hold that God's command to go forth
                            and multiply was a proper command at that time to replenish the earth, and that his command
                            to Jesus to go forth was to replenish the heavens. That as Christ was not an exponent of
                            physical reproduction, his followers cannot conscientiously endorse that which he did not
                            engage in. In this respect the Shakers are the truest Christians there are on earth. They
                            hold that marriage and reproduction are commands of God to people on earth, and that the
                            lesson of resurrection which Christ taught was the lesson of how to gain a new life in the
                            heavens, and that there never has been and never can be a child born into this world under
                            Christian auspices, any more than war can be called a Christian idea or a thing for
                            Christians to engage in. That Christ did not come into this world to help people it, but to
                            help open the way for a new kingdom eternal in the heavens, in that great house in which are
                            so many mansions. That Jesus cared as little about "the world running out" and the
                            fulfillment of the reproductive command to Adam as do his true consistent followers. They do
                            not believe in the nonsensical bodily resurrection theory, nor in the absurd Atonement
                            doctrine, or in the incomprehensible Trinity scheme, nor in that cruel relic of ignorance
                            the Predestination humbug, which, like a great morass, sensible Presbyterians have for the
                            past thirty years been walking out of and wondering the while how they ever got in there !
                            The Shakers do not think it a crime or a sin to marry or to bear children, but that a virgin
                            life, or a life of celibacy, once they are in this world is the true Christian religion and
                            that to live as they believe Christ lived is the proper way to gain entrance to the Heaven
                            where Christ is the great pervading spirit and atmosphere of eternal spirit growth and
                            spirit happiness. In short, the Shakers believe that all carnal indulgences must be broken
                            off by mortuary process, or by the change we call death; that in Heaven there is no marriage
                            or giv- <pb n="119" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> ing in marriage : that all individual wealthgetting will
                            cease; and that it is better to prepare for Heaven and these conditions now rather than wait
                            till death and then he forced into doing that which will not be obtainable ¦except by what
                            was evidently known by Christ as it is by those who understand the Spiritual Philosophy, as
                            obsession, or an existence of the spirit outside of Heaven, and in reach and control of
                            certain lines of mediums. In fact, there is much more to and of the Shaker religion than
                            people have ever given credit for, and more about the Shakers to admire and reverence than
                            there is about that religion which runs to miles of cornice, heavy mortgages, high spires
                            and closed doors to the poor. "Charity to all" is a corner stone of Shaker belief and here
                            it is honored to the full. No time is lost in quarreling but consumed in improvement. The
                            hungry are never turned away unfed nor the poor with cruel words. The Shakers admit no one
                            to their family till he or she is acquainted with the tenets of their belief. As there is no
                            chance for driving of bargains and robbing members of the society as in other churches they
                            are not so raided on by hypocrites who want the trade of the brothers and sisters in order
                            to sock it to them. No undue influence is used to attract attention or to secure converts.
                            All who unite with the society does so of his or her own accord, except they be children
                            given to them by parents. No fees, price or consideration ot property is ever offered or
                            given to induce memberships. Those who are dissatisfied can leave at any time, as they want
                            no service that is not free and voluntary in the fullest sense of the word. No wife or
                            husband who believes in their principles can separate from an unbeliever and join them
                            except by mutual agreement, unless the conduct of the unbeliever is such that the laws of
                            the State and church would sanction such a separation. Whoever wishes to become a member of
                            the society must first discharge all debts to his creditors and all filial heirs and rectify
                            all wrongs committed by the applicant. Should these things not all be done in good faith,
                            and there appear something afterward not settled for, the offender cannot remain longer in
                            the society. But he society, as such is not responsible for the debts of any person before
                            or after they become members, except by agreement, as such responsibility would be ruinous
                            to the jeace and prosperity of the brotherhood or family. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Editor :—If the enclosed curious item meets your..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Beloved Editor :—If the enclosed curious item meets your...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Shirley, February 1883" TEIform="index"/></dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whiteley, John" TEIform="persName"/>John Whiteley</byline><p TEIform="p"> AN ITEM FOE THE CURIOUS. Beloved Editor :—If the enclosed curious item meets your
                                approbation, please insert. If the City is of such vast proportions, what must the
                                country be? :Vnd, of course, if "the things unseen are known and understood by the
                                things that are," the inhabitants will want a change. Be it as it may, it is, no doubt,
                                Just right. Yours for heaven as it is, John Whiteley. Shirley, Mass. Feb. 1883</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dimensions of heaven" TEIform="index"/>THE DIMENSIONS OF HEAVEN</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE DIMENSIONS OF HEAVEN "In my Father's house are many mansions." Jesus.
                                        "And he measured the city with the reed twelve thousand furlongs. The length,
                                        and the breadth, and the height of it are equal." Rev. xxi, 1(3. Twelve thousand
                                        furlongs, 7,920,000 feet, which being cubed, 49(i, 793,088,000,000,000, 000
                                        cubic feet. Reserving half of this space for the throne and the court of heaven,
                                        and half the balance for streets, we have the remainder of
                                        121,198,272,000,000,000,000 cubic feet. Divide this by 4,096, the cubical feet
                                        in a room sixteen feet square, and there will be 30,321,843,750,000,000 rooms.
                                        We will now suppose the world always did and always will contain 990,000,000
                                        inhabitants and that a generation lasts 33 and one third years making in all
                                        2,970,000,000, every century, and that the world will stand 100, 000,000 years
                                        or 10,000 centuries making in all 2,979,000,000,000 inhabitants. Then suppose
                                        there were one hundred worlds equal to this in number of inhabitants and
                                        duration of years, making a total of 297,000,000,000,000 persons, and there
                                        would be more than a hundred rooms sixteen feet square for each person.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></p></div3><pb n="120" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confessions and excuses" TEIform="index"/>CONFESSION AND EXCUSES</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">One honest confession is worth a dozen plausible excuses, but it is harder to
                                        get one confession made than twenty excuses. Confessing faults leads to
                                        forsaking them. Making excuses often leads to lying to hide faults ; and the
                                        road is a very short one from excuses to evasions, from evasions to deceptions,
                                        and from deceptions to downright falsehoods There are some men who seem to start
                                        out with the supposition that they cannot do wrong, and hence, no matter what
                                        they have done or are doing, they must find some sort of excuse or justification
                                        for it. It wouldbe far wiser for them to start with the supposition that they
                                        cannot do right, except by special help from the Lord; and that the wonder in
                                        their case is not that they have sometimes done wrong, but that they have ever
                                        done anything but wrong; then, with this understanding, they have only to
                                        confess their faults, repent of their wrongs, and pray God to help them do
                                        better for time to come. A wrong confessed can be forgiven, but a wrong that is
                                        patched and plastered over with evasions and excuses only excites our disgust
                                        and contempt for the man who will not see his faults, or, if he sees them, will
                                        not own them. Especially is this true when men make great professions of
                                        righteousness and purity, while at the same time they are guilty of acts which a
                                        decent sinner would scorn to perform. For the sake of keeping up their
                                        profession and reputation for sanctity they will, after doing things that no
                                        honest man ought to do, evade confession and refuse reparation, until men lose
                                        all confidence in their intelligence or their integrity. How much better it is
                                        in an honest, manly way, to say, "I did the thing: I believe it was wrong; I am
                                        sorry for it," than it is to go wandering around the point with all the
                                        flexibility of the crooked serpent, excusing what we cannot deny and evading
                                        what we are unwilling to confess, till our moral nature is corrupted and we
                                        become so accustomed to deceptions and misrepresentations that we are incapable
                                        of telling the truth as it is.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian" TEIform="index"/>Christian</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To live long it is necessary to live slowly" TEIform="index"/>
                                To live long it is necessary to live slowly
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To live long it is necessary to live slowly.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful legend" TEIform="index"/>A BEAUTIFUL LEGEND</head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by G. B. A..] A BEAUTIFUL LEGEND. A charming tradition is connected with
                                the site of which the Temple of Solomon was erected. It is said to have been owned in
                                common by two brothers, one of whom had a family; the other had none. On the evening
                                succeeding harvest, the wheat havingbeen gathered in separate shocks, the elder brother
                                said to his wife : "My younger brother is unable to bear the burden and heat of the day;
                                I will arise, take my shocks and place them with his without his knowledge " The younger
                                brother, being actuated by similar kind motives, said within himself: "My brother has .a
                                family and I have none; I will contribute to their support. I will take of my shocks and
                                place them with his without his knowledge." Judge of their mutual astonishment when on
                                the following morning they found their shocks, undiminished. This course of events
                                transpired for several nights, when each resolved to stand guard and solve this mystery.
                                They did so, on the following night they met each other half way between their
                                respective shocks with arms full. Upon ground hal lowed with such associations as these
                                was the temple of Solomon erected—-so spacious and magnificent, the admiration and
                                wonder of the world! Alas ! how many in these days would sooner steal their brother's
                                whole shock than add to a single sheaf. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monfort, Love" TEIform="index"/>Love Monfort
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Love Monfort, Jan. 30, at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Age, 72 yrs. and 2 mo. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tann, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Tann
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Polly Tann, Jan. 31,
                                at Pleasant Hill, Ky. Age, 83 years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Van Vick, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Van Vick
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sarah Van Vick, March 29, at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                                Age, 62 yrs. G mo. and 28 days. A faithful burden bearer. Never flinching in the hour of
                                trial, whether her path was among flowers or thorns. Her life has been well spent and
                                from her earthly labors she has gone where "the wicked cease from troubling and the
                                weary are at rest." She was dearly beloved by all her Brethren and Sisters. P. C. L. <pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/></p></div3></div2><!--
                        <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>