<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2101" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">21</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18910101" TEIform="date">January 1891</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="21" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!--
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>JANUARY. MANIFESTO, Published by the United Societies. VOL. XXI. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                        whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. Canterbury,
                        N. H. 1891. THE</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. Page. Woman's Mission, o The Kentucky Revival, 5 True Happiness, ISTo. 2, . ¦ 8 Shun the appearance of
                            evil, 10 Letter,—F. W. Evans, ': A. J. Calver, ?) " C. J. Preter, 11 Confession, 12 Teach me Thy Will, 13 Fire
                            at Mt. L., The New Tear, 14 Kind Words, 15 Notes about Home, 16 Bible Class, 19 Reminiscences, 20 Music,—Praise
                            the Lord, 21 Books and Papers, 24 Deaths, </p>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                        <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies, VOL. XXI. "For what is a man profited, if he shall gain the
                            whole world, and lose his own soul? or what shall a man give in exchange for his soul."—Matt. XVI., 26. East
                            Canterbury, N H, 1891.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
                    --><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman's Mission" TEIform="index"/>WOMAN'S MISSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White</byline><p TEIform="p">"The Lord's of creation men they call, For they think they rule the hall, But
                            they're much mistaken after all, For they're under woman's control; For ever since the world
                            began It's always been the way, For did not Adam, the very first man, The very first woman
                            obey? " If, according to sacred history woman was first to transgress the laws of God, and
                            also lead her brother man astray, should she not, after drinking the cup of sorrow to its
                            dregs, and having her garments tattered and soiled by sensuality, eagerly grasp at the first
                            out-stretched hand to lift her up and out of sin? Most assuredly, Yea. But the voice that
                            said, "He shall rule over thee," has resounded down through the aisles of the centuries. Man
                            has exercised his power over woman to a marked degree. She has either been worshiped by him
                            as an idol, used as a plaything, or banded about as a slave ; and subject to his caprice and
                            whims she has been as a captive bird in his hands, powerless to act only as he directed.
                            True, by lineage, she may be exalted to the highest position the country or nation is
                            capable of bestowing as we see in the eastern continent, where she becomes Queen of empires
                            and kingdoms, upon whose dominions the sun never sets, and sways the same sceptre of
                            unlimited power as does a King. In the humbler walks of life we find a far greater
                            difference existing between man and woman. Though she may work side by side with her lord
                            and master, what does she receive in compensation for an equal amount of labor performed,
                            with not half the muscular strength he is endowed with? Only half pay! And in addition, the
                            bearing and nursing of children from which he is free, and caring for the household
                            generally, that principally devolves upon woman ? Can the blush from the cheek be repressed,
                            as this truth smites the conscience, and reflects dishonor upon such unjust laws and
                            law-makers ? The occupations ot men and women may differ very materially, but does this go
                            to prove that those of women are of the least importance ? Not by any means. While he is
                            engaged in the sterner duties that properly belong to his sphere, she is likewise employed
                            in the varied and all-important responsibilities pertaining to her sphere; <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. thus each, if fulfilling their calling, to be mutual helps
                            one to another, are justly earning and will reap the benefits of co-operative labor. The man
                            is as equally dependent upon the woman as is the woman upon the man. In our own loved
                            country, woman by earnest endeavor year after year, has partially succeeded in convincing
                            leading authorities that she is as capable of holding high offices of trust in the
                            political, moral and religious world, as is man. Exalted and refined sensitives are
                            revolting, and strong intellectual natures are shrinking from the yoke of bondage that has
                            forever been the curse of woman, under the law that "might makes right." From the vast ocean
                            of quickened and illumined thought is evolving the true idea of the God-head. This,
                            especially to woman, is "like a great rock in a weary land" upon which to plant the feet,
                            and those who find this rock, will work intelligently and to profit. When the sublime truth
                            is fully revealed that God is dual—Father and Mother—then we shall understand the words of
                            the inspired Apostle who said, "The invisible things of God are clearly made
                            known—revealed—by the things that are made, even his eternal power and God-head." All the
                            lower grades of animals and plants are dual—male and female—positive and negative,—up to
                            man—the crowning glory of all forms of creation. This great truth is being understood and
                            accepted more and more by enlightened individuals of both sexes. It is in the providence of
                            God that redemptive agencies are given through the female for the emancipation of the race
                            from the bondage of the flesh. "I may not be a prophet, But the time is almost here When
                            woman with the man shall stand And take her proper sphere. Kestricted and confined she's
                            been, In all the ages past; Thank God! those states are almost dead. She will be free at
                            last." The Maternal Spirit will not rest; it is operating in a wonderful manner upon the
                            daughters of men, and is undoubtedly preparing material that shall build up "a new earth,"
                            even as she has established "a new heaven wherein dwelleth righteousness." Aye, woman stands
                            upon the threshold of a new existence: The times are fully ripe for her advent; we hear the
                            coming of her feet, and the doors open at her approach. Already the glorious revelation of
                            divine truth has pierced the heart of humanity, and brought forth an order of people whose
                            central idea is equality ; men and women who have outgrown the old Adamic relationships, and
                            have come up to the higher plane of thought and action ; have recognized in each other
                            capabilities and powers, each supplementing the other's deficiencies. Such have been able,
                            through the counsel of wisdom and love, to work together harmoniously in all places of care,
                            trust and government for over a century. These combine to form a spiritual household, where
                            law, order and purity are maintained. And the everlasting "counsel of peace is between them
                            both.'' Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Believe and trust, God sees and knows" TEIform="index"/>Believe and trust,
                            God sees and knows </head><p TEIform="p">Believe and trust, God sees and knows.</p></div2><pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival" TEIform="index"/>THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard M'Nemar
                            of Union Village, Ohio.</byline><p TEIform="p">Published in Albany, N. Y., in 1808. PREFATORY. For the better understanding of
                            the following history, it will be proper to make a few preliminary remarks. It will be
                            granted, that God has a particular order and manner of working, in which one thing goes
                            before another. Thus : the law and the prophets ivere until John, after that the kingdom of
                            heaven is preached. It then follows that all men press into it. The first thing is the law,
                            which convinces of sin. 2. The Prophets who minister the promise and hope of salvation. 3.
                            The kingdom of heaven is -preached; the way and method of salvation made manifest in word
                            and doctrine : and last of all we must press into it. This is the order of God, and there is
                            no other. Nothing short of pressing into the kingdom can save the soul. Conviction may die
                            away ; hope a&gt;nd comfort desert the breast; and the most lively views of the kingdom
                            be forgotten. Hence, the necessity of so often reviving these things among professors. But
                            whatever can die away, is short of the kingdom of God ; those who are in the kingdom have
                            everlasting life. It is plain that the constituent parts of a revival, which are conviction
                            of sin, a hope of deliverance from it, and a manifestation of the heavenly state can only be
                            preparative to entering into it. How many revivals have taken place, which for a season
                            would raise the people, as it were, to heaven's gate ; and after all, leave them to fall
                            back into their former lifeless state. And why so? Because they did not take the last step,
                            and press into that state which in word and doctrine was opened. It will be granted, that
                            whoever preaches the kingdom of heaven, must preach deliverance from all sin: For where sin
                            is, there can be no heaven. When the kingdom has been preached and honest souls have fixed
                            their eye of faith upon it—longed with intense desire to be in it, and solicitously en-
                            quired for the footsteps of those who have already entered: then has been the time for the
                            grand deceiver to come in with his doctrine of procrastination, and preach up sin for term
                            of life. He could appeal to the doleful experience of past generations, and confirm the
                            fatal error by the doctrines and decrees of a corrupt church. Thus the most promising
                            revivals have been blasted, and all that near sense of heaven's pure enjoyments, common
                            under the preaching of the kingdom, extinguished by men of corrupt minds. The Kentucky
                            Revival, spoke better things. Those who were the genuine subjects of it, ever expressed the
                            fullest confidence that it would not terminate as revivals had generally done. It was not a
                            common portion of law conviction ; nor that faith in the promise, which puts heaven at a
                            distance ; nor merely preaching about the kingdom, that drew out the multitudes to encamp
                            for days and nights in the wilderness. It was a near prospect of the kingdom of God, into
                            which 5 <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO. many were determined to press at
                            the expense of all that they held dear upon earth. The late revival was not sent to reform
                            the churches. It did not come with a piece of new cloth to patch the old garment, to mend up
                            the old hope with some new experience ; but to prepare the way for that kingdom in which all
                            things are new : and whether it be in many or few, the purposes whereunto it was sent, shall
                            undoubtedly be answered. That this extraordinary work sprung from some supernatural cause
                            has been universally granted ; but whether the cause was good or evil, has been a matter of
                            much debate, even among those who profess to take the scripture for their only guide.
                            Christians, of all others, have been the most divided in their judgment concerning it.; and
                            while some without hesitation have pronounced it a glorious work of God ; others who
                            professed to be children of the same Father, followers of the same Savior, and instructed by
                            the same word of God, have with equal confidence pronounced it witchcraft, enthusiasm,
                            fanaticism, and the very energy of delusion. Hence the various predictions concerning it:
                            Some affirming that it would shortly terminate and leave the unhappy subjects of it, in a
                            worse condition than ever; others that it should cover the earth, as the icaiers cover the
                            sea, and gather the nations into one united body. As the continuance of the revival was so
                            strongly predicted and asserted by its subjects, it will be proper to consider how far and
                            upon what footing, those predictions and assertions are tenable. That it should always
                            continue in the same measure and appearance without any increase, was never intended ;
                            therefore if that same power continues to wrork, though it should be in a greater degree and
                            more extraordinary manner, and though it should be among a different people, this will not
                            prove the above predictions false, provided it be the same power working to the same end.
                            While the extraordinary power of the revival was extraneous ; while irresistible beams of
                            light presented objects to the view which persons could not avoid seeing, and they were
                            rushed into exercises of body by a force of operation which they could not withstand, the
                            continuance of the work in this fashion, was precarious, knowing that God will not always
                            work upon man like a machine. Therefore, in order to the continuance of the work, a number
                            of its subjects have found it necessary to receive this extraordinary power as an indwelling
                            treasure, to unite with this supernatural agent, to dwell in him and he in them, and become
                            workers together with him, and without force or violence, believe and practice whatever he
                            teaches. And on this pivot the revival turns with each individual. The power or light of God
                            continues with those who continue in it; his spirit abides only with those who abide in Him,
                            and do continually the things that please Him. No man can serve two masters. Since the
                            spirit and power of the revival has been established upon the above principles, and the
                            divine agent has found a habitation with men, less attention has been paid to former
                            appearances. This strange doctrine of <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            receiving Christ, an-.l walking in him, has engrossed the general concern: and while the
                            singular manner of worship and strange bodily exercises of those who stand in it, have
                            furnished matter of speculation to the world around, their distinguishing faith has been a
                            matt or of serious enquiry with many ; especially those who have begun to open their e}7es
                            on the hidden glories of the kingdom of Christ, and are beginning to move Zionward. Before
                            the temple of God can be opened in heaven and the ark of his testament be seen, it will be
                            proper to recognize" the various operations by which the materials of the tabernade were
                            prepared : According as it is written— "Behold I send my messenger, and he shall prepare the
                            way before me: and the Lord whom ye seek, shall suddenly come to Ms temple." Richard
                            M'Nemar. Turtle Creek, O., June 20, 1807. CHAPTER. I. Of the state of religion in the
                            western country, before the Kentucky Revival made its appearance. In the first settlement of
                            this country, no small part of the inhabitants were Christians by profession. Dif- ferent
                            denominations early began to shine out, and employ their zeal in organizing churches,
                            settling ministers and propagating their respective doctrines and forms of worship
                            throughout the land. The greatest number of professors might be ranked among the
                            Presbyterians, Baptists and Methodists. Although these different sects professedly set out
                            to establish, and promote the peaceable religion of Jesus ; yet in the attempt, their usual
                            debates and controversies were brought to life, which, for a number of years occasioned a
                            hot spiritual war. Notwithstanding these churches acknowledged each other as sisters
                            descended from the same stock; yet such was the zeal of each for their distinguishing tenets
                            and forms of worship, that they stood entirely separate as to any communion or fellowship,
                            and treated each other with the highest marks of hostility ; wounding, captivating, and
                            bickering one another, until their attention was called off by the appearance of a common
                            enemy, viz; Deism, or the religion of nature. For many ages the Christian religion had been
                            incorporated with the civil government, and they had mutu- ally supported each other,
                            consequently when that revolution ir&gt; politics began, which aimed at the overthrow of
                            monarchy and the establishment of a republican government, that religion was particularly
                            involved. Kings, Emperors and Popes, had claimed the Bible as "the only rule to direct
                            them," in their unnatural wars, dire oppressions, bloody persecutions, and unparalleled
                            cruelties toward mankind. Every class of tyrants, both civil and ecclesiastical, had made
                            their common appeal to the Bible, for their authority to lord it over their
                            fellow-creatures, consequently when the eye of reason began to open upon the rights of man,
                            the tyrant's Canon must appear in very pernicious colors, no book in the universe so
                            mischiev7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. ous and hateful. Under this view
                            the Bible was attacked by the political reformers of the last century ; and the dictates of
                            a lawless nature cried out in opposition to its sacred requirements. I do not suppose that
                            Deists have had no cause for rejecting the scriptures ; the contrary is certainly true. Not
                            that the cause is in the scriptures, but in those who profess to take them for their rule of
                            life. It is not the scriptures that lie open to the view of the Deist, but those churches
                            that profess to be governed and influenced by them. What have those churches exhibited which
                            for ages have claimed the Bible for their foundation? Little else but division, animosity
                            and confusion. What have been the lives and manners of professors in general? Do they not
                            stand below the modern De^ ist even in point of bible virtue ? Now if Christians are
                            chargeable with so great wickedness, in the eye of common sense and reason, and at the same
                            time testify that the Bible is their "only rule," what judgment can the Deist form of that
                            book? The tree is known by its fruit; aad if professing Christians acknowledge themselves to
                            be wicked, if they judge and prove one another to be wicked, and claim the Bible as their
                            root and foundation ; it is reasonable for the Deist to judge that to be a wicked book. When
                            Deism first begun to overspread Kentucky, and the truth of the Bible to be called in
                            question ; the cry was against its pernicious fruits and the infinite mischief that had been
                            done in the world by those who supported its doctrines. While the giddy and thoughtless
                            multitude took it for granted that divine revelation was all a cheat, and nature's flowery
                            path the only way to happiness, and were crowding into it by hundreds, many of a more
                            serious cast were unwilling to renounce their hope of salvation through Christ; yet dare not
                            vindicate the lives of those professing Christians, on whose account the Bible was
                            condemned. This made it necessary to examine the scriptures separately and judge of them
                            according to their internal evidence, and the more they were examined, the greater the
                            contrast appeared between their sacred doctrines and the lives of the professors. Hence the
                            only ground upon which the truth of the scriptures could be maintained, was to take them
                            according to their own proper sense, and prove that they nowhere countenanced those evils
                            that abounded in the churches; but the contrary. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by <persName reg="Schreiter, Emil" TEIform="persName"/>Emil Schreiter.]</byline><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True happiness, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>TRUE HAPPINESS. NO. 2</head><p TEIform="p">"The blessed in heaven behold God face to face, that is, are as sensible of his
                            presence as we are of the presence of any person whom we look upon with our eyes. There is,
                            doubtless, a faculty in spirits by which they apprehend one another as our senses do
                            material objects ; and there is no question but our souls, when they are disembodied, or
                            placed in glorified bodies, will by this faculty, in whatever part of space they reside, be
                            always sensible of the divine presence. 8 <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            Vvro who have this veil of flesh standing between us and the world of spirits, must be
                            content to know that the Spirit of God is present with us, by th? effects which He produces
                            in us. Our outward senses are too gross to comprehend Him ; we may, however, taste and see
                            how gracious He is, by his influence upon our minds, by those virtuous thoughts which He
                            awakens in us, by those secret comforts and refreshments which He conveys into our souls,
                            and by those rav- ishing joys and inward satisfactions which are perpetually springing up
                            and diffusing themselves among all the thoughts of good men. He is lodged in our very
                            essence, and is as a soul within the soul to irradiate its understanding, rectify its will,
                            purify its passions and enliven all the powers of man. How happy therefore is an
                            intellectual being, who, by prayer and meditation, by virtue and good works, opens this
                            communication between God and his own soul! Though the whole creation frowns upon him, and
                            all nature looks black about him, he has his light and support within him, winch is able to
                            cheer his mind, and bear him up in the midst of all those horrors which encompass him. He
                            knows that his helper is at hand, and is always nearer to him than anything else can be,
                            which is capable of annoying or terrifying him. In the midst of calumny or contempt he
                            attends to that Being who whispers better things to his soul, whom he looks upon as his
                            defender, his glory, and thelifter-up of his head. In his deepest solitude and retirement he
                            knows that he is in company with the greatest of beings : and perceives within himself such
                            real sensations of his presence, as are more delightful than anything that can be met in the
                            conversation of his creatures. Even in the hour of death he considers the pains of his
                            dissolution to be nothing else but the breaking down of that partition, which stands between
                            his soul and the sight of that Being who is always present with him, and is about to
                            manifest itself to him in fulness of joy. If we would be thus happy and thus sensible of our
                            Maker's presence, from the secret effects of his mercy and goodness, we must keep such a
                            watch over all our thoughts, that, in the language of the Scripture, his soul may have
                            pleasure in us. We must take care not to grieve his Holy Spirit, and endeavor to make the
                            meditations of our hearts always acceptable inhis sight, that he may delight thus to reside
                            and dwell in us. Jesus Christ says : 'If a man love me he will keep my words ; and my Father
                            will love him and we will come unto him, and make our abode with him.'" "Happiness, tliou
                            lovely name, Where's thy seat, O tell me, where? Learning, pleasure, wealth and fame, All
                            confess—"It is not here!" Not the wisdom of the wise Can inform me where it lies; Not the
                            grandeur of the great Can the bliss I seek create. Lord, it is not life to live, If thy
                            presence thou deny; Lord, if tliou thy presence give, 'Tis no longer death to die; Source
                            and Giver of repose Singly from thy smile it flows; Peace and happiness are thine: Mine they
                            are, if Tliou art mine." —Selected from the Spectator.</p></div2><pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shun the appearance of evil" TEIform="index"/>"SHUN THE APPEARANCE OF EVIL."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher</byline><p TEIform="p">'Tis hard to stop in midst of wrong, The hillside is so steep, 'Tis better far to
                            shun the look O'er the unfathomed deep. Walk not too near the slippery edge Lest an
                            incautious pace May plunge you where you would not stand, Or can your steps retrace.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York, November 1890" TEIform="index"/>Mount Lebanon, N.
                            Y., Nov. 1890.</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Henry :—David prayed in this wise : ' 'From my necessities, O Lord,
                            deliver me." It was short, but pithy. Can we not pray, 'From raising and caring for cattle,
                            O self-denial, please release us !' The cows succeed in manufacturing milk from the
                            vegetables and fruits furnished them. Oleomargarine is manufactured butter, and comes from
                            animal fats of doubtful quality. The cocoanut butter is said to be delicious. Women will yet
                            make as good milk from fruit, as cows do from grass. Great progress is being made in England
                            in hygienic food. Women—noble women—are turning their inventive faculties from devising some
                            new, immodest, health and morals destroying fashionable dress ; to creating new, appetizing
                            and health-sustaining kinds of food, and their preparation for a vegetarian table. Vegetable
                            restaurants (restorers) are now established in England by the hundred, and are all the time
                            increasing. America is a fleshmeat-eating nation. The natives— Indians—lived almost
                            exclusively on wild animals : that is the best form of flesh-food. Good times are coming. In
                            love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, December 1890" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.,
                            Dec. 1890.</head><p TEIform="p">M. M. Keniston, Dear Sister :— In reply to the momentous questions you asked in
                            the Nov. Manifesto, I would just say that in the laws of the worldly-wise, Political Economy
                            teach- es that the direct applications of labor to production are transmutation,
                            transformation and transportation, or change of element, a change of form, and a change of
                            place. Yet the indirect application though less obvious is of equal importance, the former
                            being entirely dependent upon the latter. Under this head,—among many others, comes the
                            worker who provides and prepares the food, clothing and shelter, for the producer. All the
                            labor comprised in the raising and care pf children, who are themselves to become laborers,
                            is also reck- oned here, for were their labor wanting, the productive force of the world
                            would soon cease. The toil involved in education either as teacher or learner, is necessary
                            to production, as it adds to the power and efficiency of the individual; for all of the
                            industries require more or less intelligence, and the more of this the worker has, other
                            things beingequal, the greater will be the productive efficiency. There is no calling in <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 11 which ignorance is an advantage ; for
                            an idiot would not even do Tor a hodcarrier. So we see in a natural point of view there is
                            no one who lifts a hand to the work of the world, using his best efforts, but should take a
                            front place as a producer. But what shall we say of the woman question spiritually in a
                            Community which believes in a Motherhood in Deity. We would refer you to Elder F. W. Evans,
                            who is an authority on this subject as he has his whole practical life back of his
                            teachings. We being aware of this, listen with pleasure to his frequent discourses, on the
                            Dual God, the Dual Christ, and his firm belief in the social equality of the Sisterhood. God
                            bless him for his strong faith, and still more for his works, and grateful are we that he
                            leaves not himself without a witness ; for like the ripened leaf, when he loses his hold on
                            the tree of the earth, his teachings will be embodied in his successor. Yours sincerely,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>Amelia J. Calver</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio, November 1890" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, O., Nov.
                            1890.</head><p TEIform="p">Dear and Beloved Brother, J. S.— Your letter of the 18th. inst. was received in
                            due time, and with pleasure I respond. I may not be able to convert you to our most holy
                            faith, for if the Father does not draw a soul, then are all human endeavors in vain, but I
                            consider it to be my duty to do all I can to convince you of the truth, that God has
                            established his holy Zion on earth, but "darkness covered the earth and mankind comprehended
                            it not." For your own eternal salvation's sake, beloved brother, be careful not to condemn
                            what you do not understand. You are ignorant in your zeal as was the beloved Apostle Paul,
                            when he persecuted the primitive Christians, notwithstanding he became, afterwards, a chosen
                            instru- ment of the Lord. I pray God to enlighten your spirit, that you may become convinced
                            how far you are lost in ignorance and superstition, while condemning our heavenly Mother,
                            who by the infinite grace of God was made the true medium to usher in the New Jerusalem, the
                            City of God, which has been flourishing and prospering for more than a century past. I was
                            called into our Community when I was twenty-nine years of age. My present age is
                            seventy-nine years. By the favor and grace of God I have been blessed with visions, have
                            spoken to, and have seen the good angels and happy spirits during many years. It was my good
                            fortune to come among this people during the time of a great revival, which lasted seven
                            years. There was hardly a day or an hour but that some one was under the influence of
                            inspiration. They lay in trances for hours, and spoke in diverse languages, the same as the
                            primitive Christians. They were shown, during such times, the state of happiness of the
                            redeemed in the spheres of bliss, as well as the state of the wicked. Strict chastity and
                            virgin purity were always and ever will be our first principle and practical doctrine and
                            all who live in them are under the special protection and blessing of God. The Lord has
                            guided and protected me so far beyond all my expectations. The good angels of God promised
                            me that, if I would faithfully confess and forsake my transgressions and live a pure life, I
                            should always be blessed and protected, and so I was in deed and in truth. The people of God
                            are peacemakers, not warriors, as are the so-called Christian nations. We honor and respect
                            those monks and nuns among the Catholics, who have, since the time of the primitive Church,
                            professedly lived a celibate life, and we now wonder how they could so far degenerate from
                            the true primitive church, as to advocate war and bloodshed, <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. which they did for one thousand six hundred years.
                            During our Mexican war, Catholic priests were attached to the Irish regiments, praying to
                            God for victory to kill their fellow-men! "Whence come wars and fightings among you, come
                            they not hence, even of your lusts which war in your members?" Christ's people have
                            crucified the flesh with its affections and lusts, and those who neglect this important work
                            are not true Christians! Jesus said, "If any one ¦ will come after me, let him deny himself,
                            take up his cross and follow me." It is written, "Arise from the dead. Are ye risen from the
                            dead, seek those things above." Jesus declared "When they rise from the dead they neither
                            marry nor are given in marriage, but are equal unto the angels and are the children of God
                            being the children of the resurrection." "If ye live after the flesh ye shall die." "To be
                            carnally minded is death." It is generally admitted that during the first three hundred
                            years the Christians did live a celibate life, but when the emperor Constantine adopted the
                            Christian religion A. D. 330, they rapidly fell away and united with the world, so that,
                            when Pope Leo came into power, the last spark of true Christianity expired. In 1747 the work
                            of Christ's second appearing, in a preparatory manner, began, and Christ's true kingdom,
                            God's holy Zion on earth, was fully established at the beginning of this present century.
                            "By their works ye shall know them." Xow to conclude, if the Believers of our Community,
                            have not proved and manifested it by their good works during more than a century, they are
                            hypocrites. If they have lived a pure, honest and holy life, every intelligent person must
                            consider them to be the true people ¦ of God and sincere Christians. Remember, false Christs
                            and Prophets shall appear in these last days, if it were possible, to deceive the very
                            elect. May God and Christ Jesus bless you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Preter, Charles J." TEIform="persName"/>Charles J. Preter</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I will trust my enemies with God" TEIform="index"/>I will trust my enemies
                            with God </head><p TEIform="p">I will trust my enemies with God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Confession" TEIform="index"/>CONFESSION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">Within the latent initutions of man's inmost spirit, are developed power,
                            strength, courage, boldness and true repentance unto radical reform of inward and outward
                            life, by a sincere confession of all known sin, an auricular confession. Neither Jesus nor
                            Mother Ann can be considered singular, in imposing this indispensable obligation of religion
                            upon their followers. The Hierophants of ancient Egypt required of every neophyte an
                            auricular confession of every known sin as a first condition toward an introduction into the
                            sublime mysteries of their religious order. This requisition upon the Jewish church
                            including Pharisees, Sadducees and Essenes, is familiar to all Bible students. There are
                            many excellent reasons why we should all have a share in this peaceproducing privilege. But
                            you will ask, "How do you explain the case of poor brother Achan who was stoned to death
                            upon confessing his theft of a wedge of gold and a Babylonish garment?" Answer. His psychic
                            life was not lost to begin with, but merely re-absorbed into his inmost spirit (whence it
                            originated) and by his confession he underwent a process of evolution and spiritual devel-
                            opment, without which he could never have occupied the condition of glory, atone-ment with
                            God, man and the invulnerable peace he now enjoys. "If we confess our sins, he is faithful
                            and just to forgi re us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness." So friend
                            Achan must be one of the accepted in Heaven. Used as a type the legend goes to show, that in
                            Lrue and sincere confession and repentance, the man of sin, whatever that means, loses his
                            life, and is blotted out forever. But again, the Christ of the universe, see John, L, 1, 2,
                            3, 4, 5, inspired the Divine inmost of Jesus' spiritual intuitions and raised him nearer to
                            his own level. Jesus did the same with his disciples and they with hundreds and thousands,
                            the whole Pentecostal Church. Here is a mediato<pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 13 rial process or plan of mediation in accordance with that sublime law of the
                            universe enunciated by Paul, that "without all contradiction the less is blest of the
                            better." Auricular confession is one of the results of this great law. The sorrowing and
                            afflicted soul weighing itself in the balance of higher and better intuitions and
                            convictions and finding itself wanting yearns to unburden itself to some approachable finite
                            being superior to itself in goodness, perfection and power. This is an irresistible instinct
                            in man and an inevitable result of the above law. When any one feels the full force of this
                            instinct and obeys its suggestions by confessing his or her sins to some upright person, he
                            or she will not fail to feel relieved and absolved from all further guilt and uneasiness,
                            especially if such strenuously endeavor to reform and live thereafter righteously before
                            God. But they will find a present releasement and comfort, and this of itself often leads to
                            a sincere desire and resolution to live a good and holy life when all other means to reach
                            such a desideratum have failed. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teach me thy will" TEIform="index"/>TEACH ME THY WILL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Prudie A." TEIform="persName"/>Prudie A. Stickney</byline><p TEIform="p">Teach me to live, each day, O Lord, As though it were the last; Improving every
                            moment given More wisely than the past. Teach me to seek Thy ways divine, To know and do Thy
                            will, Amid the tempest and the storm To trust and love Thee still. Teach me to act the
                            better part, Though foes my path assail; And give me wisdom, strength of heart And courage,
                            lest I fail. Teach me the way that leads to light, Away from doubts and fears; And bless me
                            with a contrite heart While in this vale of tears. O give me faith to understand My work and
                            calling too; Be firm and loyal in the strife Though volunteers are few. Tea, teach me Lord,
                            that I may gain That blissful realm of peace, And drink from fountains pure and clean Where
                            strife and discord cease. Teach me to live each day, O Lord, Improve the time that's given,
                            With gentle deeds and acts of love Thus fit my soul for heaven. Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, November 25, 1890" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Nov. 25, 1890</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Hesky;—The fire that occured on the evening of Nov. 21st was a
                            building used as a drying kiln. In a considerable degree, a store house for dried apples,
                            sweet corn, medicinal roots with other things was entirely destroyed by fire with most of
                            its contents consisting of nearly 100 barrels of dried chickory, 23)-o barrels of sweet
                            corn, 4 barrels dried apples, 2 barrels boiled cider, a steam engine, 2 corn machines, a new
                            fannin.7 mill, 1 large and one small Fairbanks' scales, numerous barrels for putting up
                            dried roots and for beef etc., etc. Loss estimated at about $4,000. The Church family was
                            running the kiln for drying eLiokory. The wind was strong in northwest until about the time
                            the fire started, and had it thus continued it would have been impossible to have saved a
                            single building belonging to the South family. But some kind Providence suddenly turned the
                            wind very strong in the southeast, so that, by the use of an ample fountain of water un- der
                            80 or 100 ft. pressure and two large three inch hose attached to a good hydrant all other
                            buildings except one small ony adjoining the kiln, were saved. Soon the fire was tolerably
                            and mostly extinguished the wind again siiiited into the northwest, but by the aid of fire
                            extinguishing apparatus, the debris was kept from burning so as to endanger other buildings.
                            Thus, notwithstanding the loss, the South family have tlieir home left to them to be
                            thankful for, and thus have courage to continue the wrestles of life and bless God for the
                            gospel of a full and clean salvation from sin. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery</byline></div2><pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifesto, 1891. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. 1891.
                            OFFICE OF PUBLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of
                            each month, and is the only work issued regularly by the Community.. Its aim is to furnish a
                            plain and simple statement of the religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit
                            of righteousness. All communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury,
                            Mer. Co., N. H. TSRMS. One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample
                            copy, free. .75 .40 Entered at the Post Office at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class
                            matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW YEAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With the current number of the Manifesto, we enter the twentyfirst Volume.
                                Twenty-one years of age ! We have all reason for pleasant congratulations ! It has
                                attained to its majority and now stands an effective representative of the Order that
                                originated it. Anxious anticipations have occupied the minds of those who looked forward
                                to the present day when our little paper could be credited with an honorable age, as
                                well as to know that it was a herald of truth and wisdom. For twenty-one years the
                                Manifesto has been a faithful exponent of that gospel testimony which Jesus has said
                                would save his people from their sins. Like the sower in the parable, the Manifesto has
                                scattered the good seed to the right and left, trusting in faith that it would, in God's
                                time, bring forth much fruit. In this, all have reason for rejoicing, through the law of
                                compensation, that "whatsoever a man soweth that also shall he reap." If he works in the
                                interest of a spiritual life, he is promised life everlasting ; but if he works
                                selfishly in the interest of a worldly life, he must receive a corresponding reward.
                                Many of the faithful laborers who entered with commendable zeal into the work which has
                                been the life of the Manifesto, have passed on to their heavenly rest. They were its
                                pioneers. They devised the plan, overcame a multitude of obstacles, and rejoiced in a
                                satisfactory progress. It was an advancing movement and the laborers were earnest and
                                determined in the projection, and no less in the success which they had anticipated
                                would follow the enterprise. Accepting a more extended view, the work was from the
                                united efforts of the whole household of faith. It was wanted as a spirit messenger, to
                                bear the testimony of light and truth, and there has been a generous contribution to its
                                prosperity. In return, all have shared in the universal <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 blessing that comes from having done our duty before God. From the
                                first, the Manifesto has been doing a good work, and so closely conjoined are the past
                                and present that it is difficult to separate one from the other. It was well understood
                                that something must be presented to the mind, that the development may be correctly
                                carried out as was anticipated. We learn from what we see and hear, and the religious
                                life is largely dependent upon that form of literature or upon the hearing of words of
                                divine light, of faith in God and in practical righteousness. The first thing that is
                                needed, is a change, in thought, in word and in deed ; a new position to be occupied if
                                one would insure success as a Christian. Paul says, "Faith comes by hearing," and he was
                                correct. It comes now by hearing, and comes as freely and fully by reading. If the soul
                                can be reached, that it may see the light of a new and better day, faith must follow as
                                the inspiration of God. It is the power of the press that is working such miraculous
                                wonders in the world of thought to-day. Men are carried to the right and left by this
                                silent but powerful manifestation, and are readily made the servants of sin, or the
                                teachers of morality, as the will of this potent element may determine. Believers must
                                accept the situation, as a matter of course, and then work as God gives them life and
                                ability, in diffusing the light which they have received. Although the efforts may be
                                small and feeble, they may prophetically speaking, be like "the stone that smote the
                                Image, and filled the whole earth." If the little Manifesto is all that we are able to
                                present to the world, for the growing of faith toward God, we may even in that publish
                                the "good news and glad tidings" which have been so liberally bestowed upon his people.
                                Xo effort to do good is ever lost. Three pages of this number of the Manifesto, instead
                                of one page, is occupied with the Anthem, "Praise The Lord." We trust that the good
                                words and sweet music will inspire every singer and reader to praise the Lord. Through
                                the kindness of friends we are able to distribute several copies of the Manifesto
                                gratuitously. We will send a copy of the paper, one year, free to any one sending us his
                                or her address.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Littleton, Colorado, December 1890" TEIform="index"/>Littleton, Col.,
                                Dec. 1890</head><p TEIform="p">Elder Henry, Dear Friend—I have been greatly pleased in reading the Manifesto
                                for the last year. The Oct. and Dec. numbers have been of great comfort to me, and I
                                look upon them as of superior worth. Peace be to you and to all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., A. O." TEIform="persName"/>A. O. P.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let me sing of the joy in the cross" TEIform="index"/>Let me sing of the joy
                            in the cross </head><p TEIform="p">Let me sing of the joy in the cross.</p></div2><pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Center Family. The poet has said, and many have repeated it after him, that
                                "It is greatly wise to talk with our past hours, and ask them what report they bore to
                                heaven."' May we so spend them, as they come to us in rotation, that the review will be
                                a pleasure and not a burden; that the record will be of reports to heaven and not to
                                that opposite place where all is sorrow, guilt and woe! And little if any, to that
                                intermediate place, where things are so mixed it is hard to tell whether good or ill
                                preponderates. Our farmers have done their thrashing, and find 860 bushels of oats,
                                produced from 6J*j acres. The family nearest, north of us, had 808 bushels from about 26
                                acres. Nov. 21.—An alarm of fire roused our Tillage, at 8,30, P. M. At the South Fam-
                                ily was the scene of the conflagration— building, a sweet corn drying kiln—loss about
                                $4,000—falls principally on church family, as they were using the kiln. Health of
                                family, thriving, spiritually and temporally. How can we help it with so much blessing
                                and encouragement. Love to all readers of the Manifesto, and a Happy New Year. Special
                                love to the Editor and workers on the Manifesto. North. Family. Dec. 14, 1890. Volume
                                No. 20 became complete on the 3rd. inst., and it will be found to be a very interesting
                                book. I hope every person under forty years of age, among Believers will read it all
                                through; all those above forty will find very much in it to instruct, edify and profit.
                                After much labor and dust, we have got our new boilers in operation, and having plenty
                                of coal in the cellar and wood in the pile, we feel abundantly able to hold our own at
                                seventy degrees against any attack from North, West or East, of Zero or blizzard. The
                                Canaan family have harvested their ice, some eight inches thick. We expect to do the
                                same pretty soon. We kept thanksgh ing as usual, held meeting in the forenoon, in which
                                we read the account of Jefferson, the then President of the United States, refusing to
                                issue a proclamation calling on the people to hold a religious festival. All honor to
                                Jefferson, not because we are not grateful, but because we like everybody to keep the
                                eleventh commandment. Our cooks did themselves great honor in the preparation of dinner.
                                No turkey, calf, ox or hog disgraced our table. It was emblematical of Peace on earth,
                                good will to man and beast. In the afternoon we showed our thankfulness, by putting
                                things in order; gathering up the fragments and cultivating the good old Believer spirit
                                and gift of prudence and economy. It would have been much more in accordance with our
                                faith and ideas if our Ministry had appointed the day, and not the Governor. We have had
                                considerable of late to incite us to care, and to search out danger in relation to fire,
                                both by impressions, dreams and experience. We have not searched in vain, neither is our
                                extra care unrewarded. A pail of water, a small hand engine, or fire extinguisher is
                                more effective as a preventive, than floods of water as a cure. We ought to be in such a
                                spiritual, receptive condition that we could always heed the admonitions and warnings of
                                our good guardian spirits; and thus bring the science of Spiritu- alism into practical
                                use. Wishing all my gospel friends a Happy New Tear with increased zeal to support and
                                make more interesting and profitable the Manifesto, I am in kindest love,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Offord</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 11. 1890. Dear Editok:—To the readers of the Manifesto we extend kindly
                                greetings. May peace like a benediction rest upon each one as the Old Tear closes its
                                brief existence; and may health, happiness and prosperity be apportioned to all,
                                especially the Household of faith throughout the coming New Tear. May God's blessing 16
                                    <pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 17 crown, as heretofore, the
                                unceasing efforts of our efficient Editor, and unity, love and spiritual power be
                                increased in our Zion Homes. We have thus far had only light snowfalls, yet, the ground
                                being well frozen there is good sleighing which the Teamsters are improving. As King
                                Winter with his chilling breath, compels us to be more retired, and increased
                                opportunities for reflection are afforded, we hope, with good Eld. Timothy, to be able
                                to gather more of the fruits of the Spirit. Br. Daniel in Nov. number gives us sound and
                                valuable truths. His remarks upon thankfulness, impure air, and foul drains are truths
                                which humanity would do well to accept and wisely heed. We have long been convinced that
                                proper ventilation, and good drainage are essential to health and happiness, also that
                                cleanlmess is next to Godliness. Our Venerable Father Elder Frederick utters another
                                truth when he says "no one can be a perfect Christian unless he has good bread to eat,
                                and much less, ex- except he breathes pure air." We believe in good conditions. Our
                                environments have much to do with our happiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., J. L." TEIform="persName"/>J. L. S.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p">At the outset of the new year, new thoughts and new plans should be formed in
                                our minds. We must rise to higher degrees of goodness, not merely to do better work on
                                the farm, but to cherish better purposes of soul culture, and to make our influence more
                                and more felt for good. It is a great mistake not to fill up the spare moments with
                                something useful. While the world is advancing all around vis, we must not stand still.
                                Let us cultivate the heart as well as the land. It will be the best investment we can
                                make. We should begin the new year with a will to make the most of time. The years are
                                made up of months, weeks, days and hours, and it is for us to improve them the best we
                                know how. Let us walk in the right path—it is plain. A change of food now and then seems
                                to suit the taste of a cow as well as that of a man. Cows are most sensitive to cold and
                                hard fare, and the food we give them ought to be such as to keep up the heat of the body
                                as well as the supply of the elements that increase the secretion of milk. Because a hen
                                may be forced to eat almost anything, we should not give her bad food and then expect
                                well flavored eggs. Hens should not be obliged to drink bad water. Hens with low combs
                                are the best layers in winter. The combs are not apt to be frosted, in which case hens
                                never do well. Care, caution, and common sense will raise more chickens than all other
                                remedies.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1890. Dear Editor:—Winter has come in earnest. The thermometer indicates
                                four degrees below zero. We have two inches of snow, and quite good sleigrhing. Those
                                who have been tormented with aches and pains and were included on the sick list, are
                                much better. What a blessing it would be if we only understood the laws that influence
                                the soul and body and be able to keep out of the hands of the Physicians. Our sympathy
                                goes out for our dear friends at Mt. Lebanon who have just passed through another fiery
                                ordeal. What a hard master this fiery element is, when not under control. It is ever a
                                reminder to us to be careful and leave every place properly protected. The Notes in the
                                last Manifesto were beautifully written. They were read with deep interest by all. We
                                await anxiously the coming of the paper but the Nov. number entered the Village and took
                                us by surprise. On entering the family Dwelling we found Eldress Ellen Greene,
                                surrounded by a company of Sisters, reading the "Notes" in the Nov. Manifesto, and we
                                entered, at once, into the same inspiration. Love to all gospel friends, and a "Happy
                                New Year."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. B.</byline></div3><pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1890. Dear Editor:—I have neglected my items for December, but will now
                                give you something for the New Year. Br. Henry Gross and the writer spent a few days
                                among our gospel friends at Union Viilage, O. We left home the 8th. of Nov. and returned
                                the 11th. We had a very pleasant visit; attended a singing service, Sabbath A. M. and an
                                hour of worship with the family in the P. M. The service was very profitable and
                                interesting. Elder Oliver Hampton and Elder Charles Clapp, both preached good sermons.
                                On Monday A. M., Br. Thomas Mann accompanied vis all over the place, and in the P. M.
                                Br. James Fennesey, and one of the Ministry went with us to the West and North families,
                                and we enjoyed a very pleasant visit with all the beloved Brethren and Sisters. On
                                Tuesday we started homeward well satisfied with our privilege. We have purchased an
                                Incubator, which holds 300 eggs. Have built a new fence around our Cemetery. This im-
                                proves the place very much.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., H. W." TEIform="persName"/>H. W. F.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1890. The long drouth of the past season, injured the potato crop about
                                one third, and the crop of corn did not reach our expectations.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H. B." TEIform="persName"/>H. B. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">We send in our hearty thanks to all the writers of "Notes," and to all the
                                dear ones whom these writers are delegated to represent, for their thoughtful kindness,
                                in wishing us in advance, a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year. We would gladly echo
                                the wish in return, with all the loving words which the season of Christmas-tide should
                                make genuine, but shall trust to the white winged messengers who attend us, to make it
                                realized. More soul union is what we need, causing all to understand the real worth of
                                the hundred fold relation, here and now. Indeed, we do not expect aught but persecution
                                from those wlio prefer the broad way for "the world loveth its own," but let those who
                                have been called to "Sing the advent, with no uncertain sound," rally to the rescue of
                                the virgin banner, and cleave to the truth which forms a bond of union indissoluble. At
                                this writing, we are having regular winter weather, mercury below zero, but it does not
                                follow that this statement would be a truthful one, even for the mor- row, as the old
                                time steady going habits of the weather clerk, are among the things that are entirely
                                out of date, at the present time. Old Mascoma folded her arms, and locked in silence the
                                dancing waves, for an all winter's rest, on Dec. 3rd., just a little earlier than last
                                year; but the skating season was brief, as snow, which we hope has 'come to stay,' soon
                                covered both ice and terra firma. Open, mild winters seem to generate colds, often with
                                serious results, and as we would gladly vote these' off the year's programme entirely,
                                we welcome cool, brisk air, instead of the "insipid" quality laden with disease. Our
                                Sisters have more orders for heavy knit goods, (sweaters) than they can conveniently
                                fill; if this profit could only help to beautify our home, by putting a much needed coat
                                of paint on some of our buildings, what a blessing it would be. Three were painted
                                before the Notes made their appearance, but the remaining ones look as if not only hope,
                                but paint has been deferred, until they are sadly in need. Linen bosomed shirts are also
                                constantly coming from a Boston firm, which proves how perishable are all earthly
                                things, or there would be a lull in the making of apparel. Dear Sisters, from Maine to
                                Kentucky, let us in the year that is just dawning, bear in mind, that while "Our hands
                                to needful toil are given," we are also weaving other garments, not of material texture,
                                that shall clothe the spirit; living in the present and providing for the future. Happy
                                thought!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. B.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1890. A Happy New Year gospel kindred! Can you not hear the echo of
                                greetings <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 from the little band at
                                Sabbathday Lake? We wish you all a Glad and Happy New Year, those living among the
                                mountains in N. Y. and N. H., also those dwelling in the sunny vallies of Ky., Conn.,
                                Ohio and Mass., our sister Society at Alfred and not forgetting the little band in
                                Philadelphia. Our earnest desire is that we may grow and prosper in our beautiful Zion
                                homes. We are not dying out. We know of the joy unspeakable and full of glory we feel
                                from day to day while living out the principles of Jesus Christ, whose birth we love to
                                celebrate and we are determined to "Lift the virgin banner higher up." With us, winter
                                has commenced in ear- nest. We hear the jingle of sleigh bells and many teams are
                                engaged hauling lumber, wood &amp;c, which seems to be the leading industry just
                                now. Our lake was fro- zen over the 29th. of Nov. and in a few weeks the ice harvest
                                will begin. General good health prevails at present. Our Sisters are engaged weaving
                                plush rugs which we find to be a profitable business, at the same time keeping along
                                those domestic duties so needful to our existence.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. S." TEIform="persName"/>A. S. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Groveland, New York" TEIform="index"/>Groveland, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 10, 1890. The morning dawns, the noonday wanes And night comes on apace;
                                The seasons come, "and seasons go A never ceasing chase. The weeks fly on with lightning
                                speed And whirl the months away; The years they come and years they go Time's march
                                makes no delay. The earth revolves and man evolves Dissolves this earthly frame, Yet sun
                                and moon and stars above Forever shine the same. The mind Immortal e'er resolves To live
                                expand and grow, Grow in the image of the Lord, And constant progress know. A few short
                                days ago we were taking the last notes of the departing year 1889. This P. M. finds us
                                again engaged in the same occupation, signing the final notes for the year 1890. Only a
                                few more frosty mornings and the dear old year will be counted among the past. For
                                three-hundred and forty-four days we have been constant companions, during its reign we
                                have found new acquaintances and formed lasting friendships, that will ever brighten and
                                gladden our eternal existence. A new and valuable Hay Press was recently introduced,
                                working wonders most satisfactorily. The machine is manufactured at Quincy, 111. and is
                                named "Victor" in honor of its great capacity for perfecting good and pleasing results.
                                The Press presses from thirteen to fourteen tons per day. George Estel Proprietor, and
                                A. J. Crans Agent for the Victor Hay Press. Last week Brother William Bussell whose age
                                numbers nine times nine, performed a bold and daring feat on his hands and feet. A long
                                freight train became detached on a down grade, blockading the road he wished to cross,
                                and not caring to be delayed by the untimely intrusion he found access to the opposite
                                side by going underneath the Avaiting car, just as he finished his perilous journey the
                                engine neared the detached portion and started the train, but William the brave was
                                safe, and has agreed never to repeat such bravery. His fearless accomplishment commends
                                him to the ranks of the heroic. Ice weather has dawned again in all its coldness,
                                clearness, glory and beauty. Snow storms numberless call out tlie juvenile class whose
                                jubilent spirits find jubilee in the fun of ascension and descension.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., D. G." TEIform="persName"/>D. G. D.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bible Class" TEIform="index"/>The Bible Class</head><p TEIform="p">Answer to Bible Question, No. 16. published in Dec. Manifesto. Where in the Old
                            Testament, is the Messiah called the Son of Man? Write the verse. Mt. Lebanon, I saw in the
                            night visions and behold one like the Son of Man, came with the clouds of heaven, and came
                            to the Ancient of days <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. and they brought
                            him near before him. Dan'l, vii., 13. Church has eleven. Center Family has eleven.
                            Canterbury,—has for Dan'l vii., 13th., fourteen and one for Psa. li., 12. Enfield N. H. has
                            for Dan'l vii., 13th., fifteen. BIBLE QTJESTIOJST, iNTo. 17. Which passage is quoted the
                            most frequently,—that may be found in the Book of Daniel?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reminiscences" TEIform="index"/>REMINISCENCES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pick, Ernest" TEIform="persName"/>Ernest Pick</byline><p TEIform="p">We were mending the road north of the Brethren's shop when Elder Frederic said:
                            "Sit down and rest yourself." After having graded a piece of road to his satisfaction and
                            while waiting for another load of stones he took a seat by my side. "That was quite an
                            excitement last night," he said, alluding to a fire at the South family where a hired man
                            had been left in charge of a furnace. "That is one of the abominations of the first cycle,
                            coming from the land monopoly and consequent system of hirelings; when the King of Syria
                            made war against the King of Israel he commanded his captains to fight neither with small
                            nor great, save only with the King of Israel. Likewise, the Believers of the first cycle and
                            dispensation. The flesh is the king of all evils and all their spiritual power and knowledge
                            was concentrated to hate and destroy the flesh, the root of all evil, and not to fight with
                            small nor great besides. Hygienic and dietetic reforms were not in the sphere of their
                            dispensation. But Believers in the second cycle of gospel dispensation," and a bright fire
                            gleamed in his prophetic looks, "will do away with small and great. To the testimony against
                            the flesh will be added that of temperance in all things. Killing animals for their meat
                            will be discarded, and likewise land monopoly and its due appendix of hired labor.
                            Vegetarianism is spreading all over the old country, England and Germany especially. Woman
                            takes hold of this important reform and in her hands it will grow, spread, enlighten and
                            heal the world. This is one of the woman's questions, which does not argue about such
                            tilings, does not seek to adjust or cure them all, but covers them as if it did not see.
                            There will be no end to woman's ingenuity in preparing our daily bread-food from the
                            vegetable kingdom. Look at the elegant table our Sisters spread 'and nothing that defileth'
                            thereon."' Truly, Elder Frederic, our meals are so many feasts, palatable and wholesome,
                            worthy of a prince indeed. "Moreover," he resumed, "nature's products and vege- tation are
                            still a great secret to man; an inexhaustible mine of good things in their manifold chemical
                            combinations. Man ought to have intelligence enough to make an article like milk out of
                            vegetables, if needed at all. Butter is made out of cocoanuts, and their export from Bombay
                            to Germany for this purpose is increasing. Man will free himself from taking care of cattle.
                            As Believers discarded tobacco, alcohol and pork, so they will cease to eat meat and learn
                            how to live true to nature, and nature's laws. Farming and agri- culture, then, will take
                            another aspect and much of our time and labor will be gained. There is a great work to do
                            for the second cycle and it will be successful beyond present conception." With beaming
                            features, the prophet, in vision, measured the distant horizon and his inspiring words and
                            his eloquent silence created waves of happiness in my exalted heart. Unnumbered fields of
                            light and progress unfolded before my vision, uncounted works to will and to do for the
                            righteous. And over all was spread in golden hue, the ether of wisdom and goodness, with
                            glory beyond glory, and glory beyond that. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value a good conscience more than praise" TEIform="index"/>Value a good
                            conscience more than praise </head><p TEIform="p">Value a good conscience more than praise.</p></div2><pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Praise God" TEIform="index"/>PRAISE GOD</head><p TEIform="p">" I will praise the Lord with my whole heart." — Psa. cxi., 1. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                            Sing! sing all ye people praises to God, Enter His courts wit. songs of thanksgiving Praise
                            God Bring forth oblations from hearts sincere. Praise God. Enter His courts with songs of
                            thanksgiving, Bring forth oblations from hearts sincere. Praise God, praise God. Here in His
                            temple where <pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. PRAISE GOD. saints are
                            assembled,Heav en and earth in communion meet. Here souls may feel His holy unction; Know of
                            a truth that God still lives. Praise Him forever, praise Him forever,Praise Him forever,
                            ever more. For great is His goodness, His favors are boundless, His tender mercies o'er
                            shadow all. <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 23 PEAISE GOD. Therefore
                            praise Him,worship and adore Him,Bring precious gifts to the Throne of Grace, And He will
                            accept them,honor and bless them,Crown all your life with His perfect peace.Then join with
                            the angels and sing forth your praises till earth will reecho the sound. Then sing forth
                            praises, Sing, O sing, Sing forth praises, Sing, O sing, Sing forth praises unto God ever
                            more. Praises un to God,</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/> The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. December. Contents. Justice
                                Samuel F. Miller; Mental Evolution; Studies in Physiognomy; The Rev. John Laughiin, D.
                                D. Catharine Booth; Practical Phrenology; Beggars of a Great City; Child Culture;
                                Methods of Medical Impostors; Improper Cooking and Temperance; etc., etc. Fowler and
                                Wells Co., 775 Broadway, N. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to preserve health" TEIform="index"/>How to Preserve Health </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barkan, L." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">"How to Preserve Health "by Dr. L. Barkan, M. D. is one among the many good
                                books, and well deserves a wide circulation. It teaches in simple English, many useful
                                lessons pertaining to the "Laws of Health." The "wayfaring man" can read it at his
                                leisure and be made wiser and better, as all this information extending through the
                                whole course of life, is excellent for consultation and profitable for practice. A
                                careful perusal of its pages would afford many valuable hints to every man and woman for
                                the preservation of their health. The work is supplied by the American News Co., N. Y.
                                Price f 1.00.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What's a million..."/>What's a million... </head><p TEIform="p">What's a million? Scarcely conceivable at times, and yet often accepted with
                            composure. For instance, a million suns, a million worlds, a million Egyptian pyramids,
                            even, are hardly conceivable; but a million dollars lost in Wall street is another affair.
                            Tell a Jerseyman of a million mosquitoes, and he Avon't tell you he is "somewhat of a liar
                            himself;" on the contrary, he will put you down as altogether too good and moderate for that
                            climate. There are 60 million people, and possibly 10 million families in our country. Of
                            the thousands of different kinds of lamps sold in the last 150 years, not every family even
                            has one, for many use gas, and some still use candles. A lamp is something that stays by; it
                            does not decay, and there are hundreds in the country 50 years old or more. And yet in the
                            short period of 5 years, every fifth family has bought a "Rochester" lamp; for the
                            manufacturers report that over two million have been sold within that time.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Coin of polite society" TEIform="index"/>THE COIN OF POLITE SOCIETY </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Whenever a kindly or considerate act is shown you, my dear, be
                                    always careful to say that magic index to good breeding—"Thank you." Certainly you
                                    say it to the man Mend who has given you an evening of amusement at the theatre, or
                                    who has taken you to and fetches you from a friend's home. To whom else should you
                                    say it? To the maid servant who hands you your letters, who makes a special point of
                                    keeping your room in good order, and who, remembering that you liked certain things
                                    placed in a certain way, was always sure to do it. To the stranger who holds open a
                                    door for you, to the elevator man who saves you climbing so many stairs, to the man
                                    who gives you a seat in car or omnibus, and to anybody in any station of life, who
                                    shows you a courtesy of any kind. We are apt to be very stingy with our thanks; to
                                    accept things entirely too much for granted, and to believe, in having courtesies
                                    shown us; that they are only what we deserve. Now this is the wrong way of looking
                                    at it, and some day it will serve that girl right—that girl who believes that the
                                    good things of life in the way of politeness are hers lawfully, and that without any
                                    effort on her part they can be retained, will discover her mistake. You can never be
                                    too generous withthankyou's; they are the current coin of polite society, the
                                    circulation of which tends to make everybody more eager to do unto others as they
                                    would be done by. No girl makes a mistake who has a thank-you always ready. It is
                                    the index to a good character and a loving heart. Politeness is golden, and thank
                                    you is the coin which passes everywhere and is recognized by all. -- Ruth Ashmore, </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in <index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall, Catharine L." TEIform="index"/>Catharine L. Hall
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hall, Catharine L." TEIform="persName">Catharine L. Hall</persName> at
                                Harvard, Mass. Dec. 1, 1890. Age 77 yrs. and 2 mo. Sister Catharine has been a resident
                                of the Society since childhood, and was much beloved. Her's was a life of constant
                                devotion to the cause she so nobly espoused. Peace be to her memory. C. B. W.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gray, Rhoda" TEIform="index"/>Rhoda Gray
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Gray, Rhoda" TEIform="persName">Rhoda Gray</persName> at White Water, O.
                                Nov. 8, 1890. Age 67 yrs., 8 mo. and 11 days.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>