<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0106" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18710601" TEIform="date">June 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="41" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">*' I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME ; AND I WILL FILL THIS
                        HOUSE WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt.
                        Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. I. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y.5 JUNE, 1871. No. 6.</p><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice!" TEIform="index"/>NOTICE!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">1. The Shaker is the official Organ of the United Societies called Shakers. 2. Therefore, be
                            it understood, that "to owe any man aught, but love and good will," is unbecoming a
                            Christian, or Christian Community. No one having connection with the Societies, has any
                            permission to run in debt; any one, therefore, trusting any member, does so at his own risk,
                            under the discountenance of the leading authorities ; and no part of Society will be holden
                            for debts so contracted. *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Running the world out" TEIform="index"/>"Running the World Out."</head><p TEIform="p">Shakers — Salt. The two most stereotyped objections to the rationality and perpetuity of the
                            Shaker Order are, First: That if celibacy be a normal principle, all people are under
                            obligations to adopt it; that if it be right for one, for a thousand, it is right for ten
                            thousand, for everybody. Second: That if mankind should hereafter, at any time, so adopt it,
                            the world would run out—the human race would cease to be upon this earth. The foundations,
                            very extensively laid in the theological education of religious people in Christendom, upon
                            which rest these" objections to a religious celibate life, are the subjoined ideas:— First:
                            That, in the spirit world, there are but two receptacles of the souls of all earth's
                            inhabitants—one heaven, and one hell, the antithesis of each other. That there is no evil in
                            heaven, nor in those who, as soon as they are out of the body, go there. That there is no
                            good in hell, nor in any one who (after they cease to breathe the earth's atmosphere) enters
                            it. Second: Not the solid facts of human experience, which constitute character, will
                            determine to which of these two extreme places the disembodied soul will go ; but the
                            belief, or disbelief, of some abstract dogma, having in itself no in- trinsic good nor evil,
                            and of no practical use nor consequence to either the individual or the race. Third: Of the
                            six hundred (more or less) sects in Christendom, each one supposes itself to be the one true
                            way to tieaven; and supposes that all who die outside of its pale will go to the other
                            location. Practically, they are all one way. In dogmas they differ; in works, which go to
                            the formation of character, they are one; and, after death, they will all go to "one
                            place"—Hades, the place of departed spirits—the first spirit world; and will from thence
                            descend, or rise, according as their works have been, without any reference to their
                            theology, until they find their proper heaven, or hell. There is one thing in which these
                            theological sects are all agreed,—"the works of the flesh,"—the practice of generation, and
                            its inevitable concomitants, or fruits— marriage, selfish property, war, creating rich and
                            poor, bond and free, on the basis of " male and female ; " living to eat and drink those
                            things which afford the most present satisfaction, or gratification, at the expense of
                            future sickness and disease; then employing a class of men to cure them of their sicknesses
                            and diseases, by the use of poisons, as the great cure-all, which induce premature death,
                            and pass them into their heaven or hell in the spirit world. Contemplating ShaJcerism, all
                            these unite and say, if celibacy is right, marriage is wrong, and, the Shakers excepted, all
                            will go into hell, and be eternally lost. Jesus said to his disciples, " Ye are the salt of
                            the earth," to preserve it from decomposition—putrefaction—and ye bear the same proportion
                            to the mass of mankind, that salt does to the bulk of the earth, or that salt does to the
                            quantity of meat to which it is applied as a preserver. "There be few that be saved" while
                            in the physical body, and living upon the earth. But those few will be the Saviours of all
                            who live and die in generation, after they have passed through the gates of death into the
                            land of souls. Thus, as "a little leaven leaveneth the whole lump," and maketh it all into
                            leaven; so is it the tendency of salt to make whatever it is applied to " taste like
                            itself"—like salt. And thus, all who become Christians actually—Shakers—on earth, are the
                            first-fruits of what the whole mass of mankind may hereafter become in the spirit worlds; as
                            those who are themselves saved from the lust of generation, the lust of eating and drinking,
                            the lusts of dress and equipage, and the lusts of the mind, in this stage of being, will
                            have to help other souls up to the same plane of existence in the eternal spheres of spirit
                            life. Jesus was eminently a man of principles and not of persons. He would not alternately
                            love and hate the same man or woman, according as they changed their spirit and character,
                            but would hate the corrupted character and spirit. And, when it is shown, from historical
                            data, that the system of spiritual ethics promulgated by him was rather the result of the
                            "progression of primates " (as Professor Mapes would phrase it), than a new product of his
                            own individuality; and that Buddha, Confucius, Zoroaster, and Moses, the world's Avatars,
                            had each, in their day and generation, built up a compara- tively perfect system of moral
                            precepts and religious maxims, illustrated by their own lives, which were the exponents of
                            the same eternal principles of truth that Jesus taught and practiced; and as the primrose by
                            the hedge-side can, by judicious culture for successive germinations, be progressed to a
                            double-flowering moss-rose, not easily propagated, so the Shaker Order, being the second
                            appearing of Christ to and in humanity, in its entirety of male and female, is where, for a
                            hundred years, the sexes have lived together as celibates, in a spiritual relation, without
                            faltering or deviation {Dixon's "Spiritual wives," and Noyes's Community, or "Complex
                            Marriage," to the contrary notwithstanding), as brethren and sisters, just as they expect to
                            live to all eternity; this being eternal life. Of itself alone, salt would make a poor meal
                            for a hungry man or woman; or poor soil in which to grow vegetables. But, applied
                            agriculturally to the soil, or mixed in proportions with other substances, it is invaluable
                            and indispensable. "I came not," said Jesus, "to bring peace on the earth," to its
                            generative family relations; "but to set a man against his father, a daughter against her
                            mother;" and to make a man's foes, his generative lusts, and their products, to be <pb n="42" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 4:2 THE SHAKER. those of his own houshold, when called into the Christ
                            Order and converted; just as salt is set against meat that is on the highway to
                            decomposition. By reason of "the corruption that is in the world through lust," the earth,
                            in its proper family relations, is fast passing away, is being burnt up by its own internal
                            fires; and society, to-day, is being threatened with general disintegration, which nothing
                            but an increased and more extended application of Skakerism—the Christ Spirit and
                            principles—can avert! No less potent causes can arrest the downward tendency caused by so
                            many seeking pleasure in unrighteousness, through the highest functions of individual and
                            society life—nutrition and reproduction. The end has come, and "the earth, and the works
                            that are therein, will be burnt up," either by the spiritual fires that Jesus kindled
                            eighteen hundred years ago, or by the fires of its own unsubdued passions. So that it is
                            only a question of high-life foeticide, low-life infanticide, or Christian celibacy. A
                            female Saviour—Ann Lee—arises, who makes use, not pleasure—right; not expediency—principle ;
                            sensuous enjoyment, not the object of human existence; seeking, with all the powers of her
                            being, the wealth of others (the Community), not her own; such only are Avatars—Saviours.
                            They are salt, with which to save themselves, and to preserve and protect all upon whom they
                            act, by influence, primarily or approximately. Their followers are the " Ye " who "are the
                            salt of the earth." " But, if the salt have lost its savor, wherewith shall it be salted?"
                            Sure enough! If any one turn to the "weak, beggarly elements," and so become earth, and not
                            salt, such is good for nothing, but to be returned to the earth as manure, to stimulate the
                            growth of earthly plants. Seceding Shakers perform this use They are preachers to the world,
                            like its own priests, knowing more than they practice, and are to be regathered into the
                            fold at some future day. There is an obtuseness in the public mind upon the subjects of this
                            article which cannot be accounted for, except on the principle that " the flesh lustetl
                            against the Spiritual Order, even as the Spirit of Christ warreth against the sin of the
                            world, and seeketh to burn them up, and thus save souls therefrom; even as physical fire
                            consumeth matter that i more gross than itself. St. Augustine said, "Marriage people the
                            earth; Celibacy replenisheth th heavens." Were all females to be mar ried, and each one to
                            bear six children the earth would soon be overpopulated and were all females to become
                            celibates, lie earth would soon be depopulated. If lai'riage were appropriated to its proper
                            use only—the begetting and rearing of ffspring—celibacy would still be neeesary to check
                            population, and to raise up eed of the Resurrection heavens—a class of Jesuses and Anns, to
                            minister the eternal Order of the Resurrection, or Christ leavens to souls after they pass
                            over the iver, into the land where there are no pomegranates nor figs, and where they will
                            ay, "There is no bread here; nor is here any water ; and our souls loath this ight bread. 0,
                            that there were a physical resurrection of our material bodies; ind that we were back again
                            on the earth, where we could have our long-accustomed, stimulating indulgences, and not
                            forever suffer this hungering and thirsting after earthly things in this Hades, the valley
                            of the shadow of death to all our earthly enjoyments." Let the new heaven arise, that it may
                            create and regulate a new earth—a new life!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation" TEIform="index"/>Salvation</head><p TEIform="p">We all want Salvation; but differ in opinion what shall be saved in us, and who shall do the
                            work. The most generally accepted idea of Salvation, is something to be effected here-
                            after, by the imputed righteousness of one who was murdered by the Jews for the purpose j
                            for which the Jews are hated and Jesus very much worshiped. This idea does not require us to
                            cease the practice of sin, but to believe that Jesus "paid it all." We are arrested by
                            conviction of wrong-doing; under this education, we plead for salvation, no1 from the act of
                            stealing horses, but from the penalty deservedly our due; and just so, the next time we
                            steal a horse. Popular Christianity ttaches, that of ourselves we can do nothing; that we
                            must rely on the death of a certain body, not on his life and example We claim, that Jesus
                            never taught such doctrines, has no fellowship with those who believe them, unless he feels
                            the fellowship of pity. We have a noble example of our dutj as students, accepting Christ:
                            "Lord, what shall I do to inherit eternal life?" "Keep the Commandments." "These / have
                            kept.' "Then if thou wouldst be perfect, do as ] have done." " But Lord, these are not wha I
                            want to do; nor the practices I want to be saved from; excuse me!" Thus we have in the life
                            of Jesus, an example; and in his teachings what we must do, and not do, to be saved. What
                            would be the effect, if the mora code were enforced xipon all professing salva tion through
                            the merits of Jesus ? Verily, w believe they would be better exponents o Christian
                            principles than now; and enjoy more salvation from the crying evils of th day, than millions
                            of centuries will save them from, while believing that Jesus has taken medicine that will
                            save them from sin, or th punishment of sin. Jesus teaches that th )oon of salvation is
                            obtained by patterning lis self-denial, and by " Go, and sin no more !" • Those who do the
                            will of my Father, the ame shall be saved." " Not every one that aith, ' Lord, Lord;' but
                            those who do somehing,—my Father's will." Give me a religion that has the power of alvation
                            in it; that is not made up of forms, creeds nor ceremonies, but has in it vitality ;hat
                            yields present salvation. Give me a religion that yields life—eternal ife; not a
                            hypocritical cloak under which I can hide, on the first day of the week, the evil
                            iransactions of the previous six! Give me a •eligion that is the power of God unto salva-
                            ,ion now ; that purifies, elevates, ennobles; that akes cognizance of outward acts; of
                            inward ,houghts; not only at stated periods, but pervades the whole being, from Sabbath to
                            Sabjath; all the weeks of the year; all the years of a life ! And thus is summed up the call
                            of ;he Spirit on every one who "names the name of Christ" or would live a Shaker life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. C, Enfield, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian faith" TEIform="index"/>Christian Faith</head><p TEIform="p">Faith, as usually defined, is the assent of the mind to a statement made, having reference
                            either to the past or to the future. Christian faith almost invariably refers to the future,
                            and denotes the certain conviction which one has of events that will transpire, or of the
                            results of a given course of conduct. In the language of the Apostle, "it is the foundation
                            of things hoped for, the assurance of things not seen." It is a principle of the same
                            character as that which exists in the mind of the Divine Being. " By faith, we understand,
                            the ages have been arranged by the word of God, so that the things which are beheld have not
                            come into existence from things apparent." That the entire future is clear to the mind of
                            Deity, so that he is certain what will be the moving panorama that, in the course of ages,
                            will pass before the eyes of created beings. Though the events which occur in a regular
                            order of sequence have not yet actually transpired, jet they exist as realities in the
                            Divine Mind. " God calls things that are not, as though they were." The Christian, united to
                            the Divine Being by his Spirit dwelling in him, possesses an unshaken confidence in the
                            future; whatever may be the agitations of earth, either in its physical convulsions or moral
                            revolutions, he has a firm persuasion that all things will eventuate in the greatest good to
                            himself and others, and will evince the infinite wisdom of the Supreme Ruler. " His hand the
                            good man fastens on the skies, And bids earth roll, nor heeds the idle whirl." Christian
                            faith, as the term implies, must be the faith of Christ; not merely a belief in him, nor on
                            him, but the faith of Christ, the very faith which he possessed. It is that which influenced
                            him to a life of self-denial, by bearing a daily cross against every inclination that would
                            lead the soul downward to find its gratification in the sensual life, and not up to the
                            celestial; against every prompting of ambition that would have urged him to strive for the
                            renown' of the warrior, of the earthly mon<pb n="43" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THESH-A-X^ER. 43 arch, or of
                            the ecclesiastical dignitary; against whatever would have influenced him to exalt himself
                            above the lowest of those whom it was his mission to elevate to a life of purity and
                            righteousness. By his faith he was united to the Father, so that the future, which was all
                            transparent to the Divine Mind, was laid open to himself in proportion to his capacity to
                            comprehend it, and he was able to show to his disciples things yet to be. These early
                            disciples, who ultimately became firmly established in the faith of Christ, the Apostle Paul
                            exhorted Christians to take as examples of faith and patience: " Whose faith follow,
                            considering the aim of their life,—Jesus Christ THE SAME, YESTERDAY, TO-DAY, AND FOREVER."
                            He is the same in his intimate union with Infinite Love; in faith and hope; in meekness and
                            humility; in unbounded kindness and charity; and in his aspirations for whatever is in its
                            nature of the utmost purity and divinest beauty, both for himself and all God's children.
                            Christian faith, therefore, is not simply an assent of the understanding to some truth
                            presented to it, but an active principle operating throughout the entire existence of man,
                            whether in this or the spirit world, and continually bringing him nearer to the All Good. It
                            embraces not only an assurance of ultimate blessedness, but also the life of faith, which is
                            its very essence—faith in active exercise, manifested in every-day conduct. It is the
                            foundation of an edifice, laid indeed in the present, but whose superstructure is to be the
                            work of the future. This foundation is laid in God; it therefore partakes of the stability
                            of the Eternal, and is a certain prophecy of the beauty and glory that will ultimately greet
                            the eye of the beholder. This faith is not the self-confidence of the worldly-minded. It is
                            not the assurance of a Napoleon that the star of his destiny, which had risen so
                            brilliantly, should continue to shine more and more brightly till he had reached the zenith
                            of worldly power and glory. The throne which he had established by so great efforts, and
                            that he fondly hoped would remain as a permanent seat for many generations of his posterity,
                            was suddenly broken. It lacked the element of durability possessed by that which the
                            Psalmist beheld in prospect when, viewing Christ's final tri- umph and glory, he
                            exclaimed,—" God is thy throne for the age of ages ! " One may learn a valuable lesson
                            respecting the instability of earthly hopes and confidences in reading the biography of Sir
                            Walter Scott. He was a man of wonderful, intellectual abilities, who stood on the very
                            summit of literary eminence in his dajr; was remarkable for his social and amiable
                            qualities, and of decidedly aristocratic tastes and aspirations. As a consequence of these
                            tastes, he was anxious to be the founder of a family with a name and fame above the many.
                            The great wealth which he acquired by his literary efforts was employed in gratify- ing this
                            desire, and Abbotsford, the grand estate, with its beautiful and aristocratic man- sion, was
                            established. But a crisis came in his financial affairs, which stripped him of his wealth,
                            and the remaining days of the distin guished man of letters were spent in toilsome efforts
                            to retrieve the disaster. Abbotsford passed into other, though kindred, hands, and no one is
                            left to transmit to posterity the name which he so highly cherished. He was not of that
                            class mentioned by the Apostle, who look for a city that has foundations whose builder and
                            maker is God. The Christian's faith is always accompanied by a power which enables him to
                            obey the law of divine love, and ultimately frees him from the tendency to transgression. In
                            the language of the Apostle, "it works by love, purifies the heart, and overcomes the
                            world." This indeed is what gives to it the certainty which distinguishes it from the mere
                            assent of the understanding to a proposition. It is the Spirit of Truth, which Jesus assured
                            his disciples should abide with them forever. It does not give to the soul its " longing
                            after immortality," but assures it of its reality. It was this faith, with its accompanying
                            power, that dwelt with so much fullness in Mother Ann. It was the sword of keenest edge that
                            severed at a blow the knot that has troubled so many mere logicians. She needed no long-
                            drawn argument to prove to her the existence of God and the immortality of the soul. She was
                            athirst for the waters, and hungry for the bread of eternal life, and she sought to satisfy
                            her spiritual wants just as she would those of the body. The words of Jesus, " Labor for the
                            food which endures to everlasting life," were to her a divine oracle. She did labor. Her
                            spiritual instincts led her at once to the true source from which all her wants could be
                            supplied. Whatever could be effected by confession and repentance of sin, she did with a
                            purpose. WThatever power was to be obtained by prayer, that she sought by earnest and
                            continual supplication. The Divine Spirit wrought powerfully in her when she consented to
                            yield to its saving influences. It taught her the renunciation of every desire that leads
                            the soul to find its heaven among those who are dead to the experimental knowledge of the
                            hig-her, spiritual and heavenly life. It inspired her with that earnestness and zeal which
                            made effectual all her efforts to rise from the darkness of sin, and to attain that state
                            where the sunlight of Divine Love should shine continually upon her. To accomplish this, she
                            was willing and glad to forego every possible sensual gratification, being assured that what
                            she sought to gain would be an infinite reward for every trial she should be called to
                            endure. And she did gain it. By following Christ in the regeneration, denying herself in
                            accordance with his requirements, she was made partaker of the same life which he
                            possessed—eternal life. God, as manifested by unbounded love, gentleness, kindness, and
                            enduring patience, dwelt in her. His peace was her peace, and his joy, her joy. So that it
                            was with the utmost propriety that she replied to a sister who was expressing the ardent
                            love she felt for her, "You do not love me, but you love God in me." Situations which to
                            many minds would have been utter darkness, were to her all aglow with divine illumination.
                            She beheld the future through a glorious medium, like that which enlightened Jesus on the
                            Mount. What she gained, dwelt in her as a permanent treasure. As a fountain springing up to
                            everlasting life, it overflowed continually for the benefit of others, and many, thirsting
                            as she had thirsted, were eager to partake of its refreshing waters. There ever is, in the
                            faith which is inwrought into the soul by the influences of the Divine Spirit, a certainty
                            that is as satisfactory to its possessor as the demonstrations of the exact sciences. There
                            is need of no complicated, metaphysical process to arrive at this assurance. It comes as the
                            rain from heaven; as the sunlight to the plant, that asks not, " how is it possible ?" but
                            drinks in the light and the dew, and then grows on, and buds and blooms, and sends forth its
                            fragrance, and displays its beauties to every beholder. "Those that are planted in the house
                            of the Lord shall flourish in the courts of our God; " and this planting is the result of
                            that faith which, the Apostle says, " I will show you by my works "—in every day life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Life in God—No. 1</head><p TEIform="p">The foundation of all religion rests on the sublime truth, that man is the image of God;
                            intellectually, the miniature of the Supreme Intelligence, and can only be happy in the
                            Divine. To grow in the Divine Nature is his privilege; to become more and more perfect, by
                            degrees, through time, to the endless ages of eternity! In this approximation to the Divine
                            Attributes, consists his happiness; his heaven; his all: like a well-tuned musical
                            instrument, he has to be attuned into the harmony of the great Prototype; and when the
                            intonations are complete, man will be in possession of all the happiness designed, and of
                            which he is capable. If man were not the image of the great Prototype, how could he be the
                            recipient of any revelation, inspiration or teaching? How could he understand, and come to
                            the knowledge of the Divine Will ? How could he be responsible to the great Tribune, without
                            the consciousness of the Divine impress in his soul ? On this great truth, of man bting the
                            image of God, rests the revelation of our Heavenly Father through the prophets, and lastly,
                            through the great Prophet, Immanuel, the Holy Saviour, which, being interpreted, is, " God
                            with us." When the Lord Jesus opened his mission, by preaching salvation from the evils in
                            the world, his disciples became conscious of the Divine truth, having in their own souls a
                            response. On this fact, of man being the miniature and offspring of God, the Saviour
                            predicated the Judgment: the final justification, or condemnation, of those who heard his
                            Gospel; for said he, " This is the condemnation, that light has come into the world, and men
                            choose darkness rather, because their deeds are evil." They saw and comprehended the Divine
                            truths necessary to their salvation; but on account of the cross, were not willing to accept
                            and obey them. Being endowed with the capacity of understanding the Divine will and mission,
                            man is therefore made responsible for his own happiness or misery; the final result resting
                            on his <pb n="44" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 44: THE SHA.KEH. own choice; for he is left free to exercise his
                            powers of volition, to choose the good and refuse the evil. On this fact, the Holy Saviour
                            predicated his mission. He made no attempts to change the structure nor attributes of the
                            human mind; but in all cases and conditions, to adapt his doctrines and teaching to the
                            understanding of his hearers. And his call was, invariably, " Whosoever will, let him come,
                            and partake of the waters of life freely." A privilege, no compulsion; free liberty to make
                            the choice of the way of salvation, and the kingdom of heaven; or the dark labyrinths of
                            condemnation, and the precincts of the damned! The strongest advocates for sulphur and the
                            other concomitant combustibles, cannot possibly get half enough into their crucible to make
                            a hell comparable to a guilty conscience, and self-abnegation from the enjoyments of the
                            righteous in the kingdom of heaven; to whom the Lord of salvation will say, " Ye goats to
                            the left, and ye sheep to the right; " a condition of volition and election ! Here we may
                            pause aDd ask: "Is it possible for any human being to bear the separation from his or her
                            Heavenly Parents, and their good and faithful children?" Thoughts of everlasting separation,
                            darkness and despair, are hardly endurable by a finite and dependent being. If man could
                            change the intelligent god within him, and obliterate it from his soul, then he would be a
                            fit companion, and there would be a place for him among the swine; but as long as he has the
                            knowledge of Life in God, he must be with his Parents, or be forever miserable!! And now,
                            once for all time, let us cease to teach Divine mysteries; the inscrutable ways of Divine
                            Providence and his specialities in the salvation of his children; the fighting of the winds
                            in the shape of imaginary demons; the groping in fogs of uncertainty of our creation and
                            destination, and come out into the broad day of everlasting light, where creation can be
                            seen and known: let us take the right way, calling on the bewildered and lost in darkness,
                            to " Come into the light, for we have found the way, and are on the road home! " Response
                            from the lost children: "But we are doomed to everlasting fire and perdition!" Voice: "Who
                            told you so?" Response: '•' The holy catholic fathers, John Calvin and Martin Luther."
                            Voice; "A false report, the Holy Saviour is here, and he says, you may come and welcome!! "
                            Response: "All right, we will sooa be there! ! " God the Eternal is positive; positive in
                            his own nature and being; positive in his plans of creation. The universe of mind and
                            matter, now in successful operation, attest his eterna efficiency! His agents, whom he
                            employs must be like himself, ever active in carrying into execution the Divine missions,
                            for the well-being of his creatures. It is the doing of positive good, for ourselves and
                            others, which constitutes the good man or woman. Negatives in agency do nothing they are
                            nothing in -human beings; and the man or woman, who expects a reward for being a passive
                            recipient of heaven's gooc store, and the selfish withholding them from others, will hear
                            the unwelcome sound, "depart from me, for I never knew you." The mission of the Holy Saviour
                            was a life f continuous labor: "My Father worketh, litherto, and I work." Jesus said, "it is
                            more blessed to give than ,o receive;" in accordance, he went about ioing good; giving aid
                            and comfort to his poor ellow-beings; in blessing others, he was the constant recipient of
                            blessings from his Father; and the voice at his baptism, "this is my beoved Son, in whom I
                            am well pleased," attested the Divine approbation and blessing! The very consciousness of
                            having imparted ;o others the means of eternal life and comfort, s a blessing that enlarges
                            the divinity within us. Recapitulation : Man, intellectually, the niniature of God; being
                            thus constituted, it is mpossible for him to be happy only in the divine nature; a constant
                            growth in time, and iirough the ages of eternity to constitute his leaven. God, in his
                            revelations, has addressed man, through his rational faculties, making lim accountable for
                            their use; and predicating lis happiness or misery, on the powers of volition. The false
                            teaching of anti-christ can never change these Divine truths.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Veritas" TEIform="persName"/>Veritas</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Household of faith" TEIform="index"/>The Household of Faith</head><p TEIform="p">As the Trinitarian God of the past; and the masculine church of the present, have neither
                            seen fruitful of the power of salvation, nor grace to redeem humanity from degradation^ so
                            will all religions, all systems, and all creeds srove themselves inadequate to the wants of
                            ;he world, which fail to recognize and be governed by the living principle of duality. As
                            natural things are but types of spiritual, and the more real is comprehended within the
                            crust of the outer, so must the significant fact, underlying this so long negatived truth,
                            be admitted, if we would see the advancement and spread of Christ's kingdom. Can the
                            paternal influence alone beget and bring forth children in the natural order ? Neither can
                            it in the spiritual. What is home without a Mother, either in the natural or the spiritual
                            household ? And, when the true heirs are produced, and '"'the sons and daughters of God
                            without rebuke," they will come of a parentage balanced as that which said in the beginning,
                            " Let us make man in our image, after our likeness; — male and female created he them." A
                            simple, reasonable, theological basis on which to rest the principles which are to redeem us
                            from the thraldom of the earth-plane, and inspire us with the necessary fortitude and
                            self-renunciation, to subordinate the natural to the spiritual, and thus be truly "born
                            again," are essentials to the development and progress of the soul.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. W., Har.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Was the God of the Jews, the Creator..." TEIform="index"/>Was the God of the Jews, the Creator...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Was the God of the Jews, the Creator of heaven and earth ? The Shakers say not. The God that
                            directed the Jews was a tutelar divin ity ; not the Father of the Christ. One believed in
                            and directed war ; the other taught Of an enduring peace. One permitted "an eye for an
                            eye;'1 the other taught, ''love your enemies." Very many complications of opinions may be tm
                            raveled by learning the distinction made by the assertion: " The God of the Christian is not
                            the God of the Jews." *</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poetry" TEIform="index"/>POETICAL</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Servant of the lord must be gentle" TEIform="index"/>'The Servant of the Lord must be
                                Gentle."</head><p TEIform="p">2d Tim. 2:24. Gentle words and gentle actions, Tokens of a tender heart: When to all they
                                render kindness What rich blessings they impart! Thus, when clouds of sorrow lower, And
                                the soul is bow'd with care, Gentle words with magic power, Strengthen us to trials
                                bear. Let us cultivate those virtues Which adorn and beautify ; Clothe the soul with
                                heavenly graces And to angel3 bring it nigh. Peace and love, and tender kindness,
                                Breath'd around us as we go, Scatter all the selfish blindness Which prevents pure love
                                to flow.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. W., Whitewater</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration of the sunlight" TEIform="index"/>Inspiration of the Sunlight</head><p TEIform="p">O beautiful sunshine ! Iioav brightly thou'rt beaming, So warming and cheering I love thy
                                pure light ; Messenger welcome, o'er earth thou art gleaming, Dispelling the darkness
                                and gloom of the night. 2. Thy glory awakens a feeling of gladness,— A happy emotion
                                springs up in my heart! Beholding thy beauty, devoid of all sadness, To me thou doth
                                unbounded pleasure impart. 3. Bright orb of our system, in glory excelling, Dispenser of
                                light, and of warmth to the earth ; Roll on in thy pathway, -forever thou'rt telling
                                'Twas God, who created and gave thee thy birth. His Infinite Power, Creation discloses ;
                                His works so majestic in grandeur are spread Within nature's bosom, in silence reposes
                                The wonders of ages, so awful and dread 1 5. Rich treasures, yet buried in ocean and
                                cavern, In wilderness places, and deep, fruitful soil; In valleys, on mountains, in
                                deserts all barren, Only awaiting discovery and toil. The bright sun of Science in
                                splendor is rising— Now piercing the clouds, long obscuring its ray ; Gray mists are
                                dispersing, and oh, how surprising The light that is ushering in a new day! 7. Strong
                                demons of gross superstition and error, Which long having held many souls in their
                                grasp, Deprived of authority, shrinking with terror, Recoil from the light, like a
                                poisonous asp. In death-robes its victims hath Ignoranc* shrouded, In cloisters and
                                prison-walls.long were they bound; While priestly dictation their vision beclouded, No
                                passage for light to their dungeons was found. 9. But, thank God ! the fetters are now
                                being broken, And thousands rejoice in their happy release ; All hail the glad tidings !
                                and welcome each token Preparing the nations for truth's great increase. 10. When
                                Freedom shall triumph o'er earth's vast dominions, And high shall be earned the standard
                                of right, The angel of love will unfold her soft pinions, And guide honest souls that
                                advance in the light. 11. All hail, then, the morning of true Resurrection ! The
                                sunbeams of glory descend to the earth ; O blessed enjoyment! O happy reflection I With
                                angels we gather a substance of worth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martha" TEIform="persName"/>Martha</byline></div3><pb n="45" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weaver" TEIform="index"/>The Weaver</head><p TEIform="p">I've laid my web for life, And now I'm left to fill it; With care and daily strife, Or
                                ease, if I so will it. An even thread, and strong, WiD weave me sure protection; A '
                                linsey woolsey ' one Will break, and cause vexation. And when the work is done, 'Twill
                                make my seamless garment; Or, clothe my soul upon, In sad and sackcloth raiment.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of John Whiteley" TEIform="index"/>Testimony of John Whiteley</head><p TEIform="p">" I have a very decided opinion of the Shakers," said a Boston editor : " that they are no
                            better than other people, and no worse !" Considering the above remark as indicative of
                            "whatever is, is right," in one man's opinion, at least, I was led to make clear the
                            difference between the Shakers and the world, as follows: Nothing but the spirit of Christ
                            can elevate us above earthly conditions, wherein we are " pretty much all alike." Evidences
                            of possession of Christ's spirit are given, only, in pure, unselfish lives. Riches, honors,
                            place, power and literary attainments, may all be acquired without regard to purity or
                            right; but the righteousness that creates newness of life, has its springs in complete
                            denial of what "other people " delight to engage in. Seeking Christ, the Spirit led me to a
                            Shaker Community; I here found Christ manifested in the lives of individuals, as I had never
                            found elsewhere, though a professional "Disciple of Christ" when I came. All that wore the
                            garb, were not Shakers, but probationers—"being tried by the holy Spirit for acceptance or
                            rejection," as Emerson would state it. I have given the Shakers nearly a quarter of a
                            century's trial; and during that time have been tried and crucified on the same cross that
                            Jesus died to the world; and to-day find mj'self among the antipodes of "other people," and
                            one of them. I see " other people " glorying in all that tends to build up pride, lust, war,
                            private property and marriage, which are the very enemies of the Christ Spirit. The
                            discipline of the Shakers has been good for me; for by it I am redeeming myself from
                            following those fashions that lead " other people " in selfish, fleshly unions; seeking to
                            save that life that can only live at the expense of life eternal. I live for others; "not
                            for myself alone," nor for my natural kin alone; but am giving expression to that love for
                            others, that requires the laying down of my carnal, generative life, and thus I enjoy
                            Christ; and this is the only way to en joy the real Christ. " The Shakers are no better than
                            other people," unless they actually bear more cros against sinful practices than do "other
                            people ;" or if the crosses they bear do not enlarge their sphere of doing good, and bring
                            them en rapport with that life, which we in common with "other people" believe the Angels
                            now live. I bless good wherever and in whomsoever I see it. I love a temperate man; if he is
                            not perfect, he is on the road, and therefore my relation. But a truly honest Shaker forms
                            the most complete idea of what a follower of Christ should be; and to be one, is the daily
                            effort of</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., J." TEIform="persName"/>J. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Divine influences" TEIform="index"/>Divine Influences</head><p TEIform="p">When in a proper condition, physically and spiritually, we inhale and exhale the spiritual
                            atmosphere as really as we do the natural air. We receive from, and impart to each other,
                            spiritual influences, as readily as the Sun's rays are absorbed by objects upon which it
                            shines, or the thirsty earth imbibes the rain that falls from the clouds, and
                            reciprocatingly returns the same in a purer form. It is said, the rays of the sun move the
                            massive monument on Bunker Hill! How much more should the heavenly Luminary—God—sway the
                            masses of human intellect and feeling, to act in consonance with it, for the promotion of
                            the life that is divine—to live, move and exist only in Him—in his service, who is " the
                            way, the truth, and the life!" " When we are resurrected from the mists of error, false edu-
                            cations and superstitions, into the glorious sunshine of everlasting truth, we shall see the
                            right way, and walk therein; we shall know of the truth, and obey; we shall know of the
                            life, the divine, spiritual element, and live in it, as do the Angels, now in heaven. As the
                            soul grows in the divine life, the loves of this gross, animal existence will disappear; the
                            habits will no longer be related to earthly things, but will be fashioned after the Angelic.
                            It is in our power to make a large measure of heaven on the earth, by engaging only in those
                            soul enjoyments that occupy the inhabitants of the Christ sphere. With the All-wise, the
                            All-pure there is no trouble, and in the ratio we are wise and pure, there certainly will be
                            none with us—our life will be divine.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. B., Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tobacco" TEIform="index"/>Tobacco</head><p TEIform="p">It is nearly thirty years, since an inspirational testimony from the heavens was deliver- ed
                            to the Societies of Shakers, against the use of tobacco, swine's flesh, and alchohol; the
                            latter being permitted to be used discretionately, by direction of physicians only. Our
                            people were generally tobacco users; pork and cider were common at every meal; yet they were
                            abandoned and by many, never indulged in afterward, though some had been habitual users of
                            pork, alchohol and tobacco for upwards of thirty years. There never was a time in our
                            history, when the same testimony against tobacco was more needed, though but few of the old
                            Believers use it; and they sorrowfully. It is a lamentable fact, that two thirds of all
                            persons asking admittance to our Society, are habitual users of tobacco in one or more
                            forms! And what are we to do ? We cannot yet feel, that because of its use, thejr should be
                            denied the privilege of confessing and repenting of still greater sins—"the lusts of the
                            flesh, of the eyes, and the pride of life"—acknowledging, that the use of tobacco is a
                            barrier, to speak mildlj^, to the overcoming of the sins of the world. Prominent mind among
                            us do not fear that our testimony is ai all too strong—nor that we shall need to back down
                            from any position we have taken; even while we admit its use with adults having formed the
                            habit, under protest, and denying the right of minors to engage in it at all. The argument
                            that all nations practice it, is one that we will withstand; and nothing will con- vince us
                            that it is respectable, nor any so respectable, as if they did not use the weed. The finer
                            sensibilities of our nature sicken at the thought that our clean, consecrated dwellings,
                            should ever again be polluted with the fumes or saliva of the tobacco user. There is a moral
                            responsibility resting on us, to be exemplars to mankind, by a continuance in self-denial to
                            this bewitching narcotic. Once wre were as deeply in love with it as any outside of our
                            Society are, or can be. We well remember our social smokings,—when, with our well-filled
                            clay pipes of home manufacture, we would make the air blue with the fumes of the weed! Who
                            wishes the return of those seasons ? We accept with joy the light that science has shed upon
                            the subject— that it has, as usual, taken the hand of our religion, declaring tobacco no
                            less respectable than rum, and that it is a moral and spiritual degenerator, and a physical
                            disorganize!1. The writer of this was a rank tobacco user, but has long since abandoned its
                            use; and all honor to those who have done likewise. We cannot be saviours to others in this,
                            nor in any other respect, until we first are saved. It is to be hoped that we will not be
                            hypocrites, by practicing what we preach against, as we commonly fault Christendom
                            generally. We have proclaimed against the lusts of the flesh and of the mind; against rum,
                            pork and tobacco; and if we engage therein, do not let us seek to hide them under Christian
                            colors.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="R—s, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. R-----s, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which is nobler, the aesthetic or the ascetic?" TEIform="index"/>Which is Nobler, the
                            Aesthetic or the Ascetic?</head><p TEIform="p">Were there no sin confronting us at every step in life, with its general accompaniments of
                            poverty, want and wretchedness; were there no ignorance, with its lack of happiness and
                            growth, chafing continually upon the benevolent and philanthropic elements in our being, the
                            gratification of our taste for the beautiful would not seem so contrary to the genius of
                            Christianity. We all believe that we shall have them ultimately to enjoy, unless like the
                            rich man in the parable we have " had our good things in this life " at the expense of the
                            "durable riches and life evermore" which are the product of practical love to the Lord, and
                            to our neighbor. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>[Obituary]</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wells, Freegift" TEIform="index"/>Freegift Wells...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wells, Freegift" TEIform="persName">Freegift Wells</persName>, a worthy member of our
                                Community, deceased on Saturday, the loth of April (1871): aged SS years 10 months and
                                25 days. He was the youngest of a family of 11 children—all now dead, save one, whose
                                present age is over 93 years. The remarkable longevity of this family is worthy of
                                notice. Thomas and Abigail Wells, the parents of said family of children, were each,
                                respectively, 80 and 85 years of age at death. The names and ages of the ten children,
                                who lived to mature years, were as follows, viz. : Set!) Y. Wells, deceased, ased 80 v.
                                2n .11 Thomas " Jr., 1 74 9 16 Benjamin i K ( ' 81 2 19 Calvin I it i ' 81 1 8 Luther (
                                it ( ' 86 5 4 Stephen 1 88 10 5 Hannah ' 86 1 11 Jesse ' now living, ' 1 93 and over
                                Abigail ' Jr., deceased, ' ' 49 2 3 Freegift ' " ' ' 85 10 25 The mother and 10 children
                                have been firm believers in the testimony of Christ's Second Appearing, all but one
                                having died in the faith of Mother Ann Lee. I). A. B.</p></div3></div2><pb n="46" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biographical: teachings of Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/>BIOGRAPHICAL. Teachings of Ann Lee</head><p TEIform="p">(Continued.^ 21. Eliab Harlow records Mother Ann as commenting on the indifference with which
                            Americans involved themselves in debt: " You will run in debt, not only bringing yourself
                            into bondage, but your family; and then, you distress your creditors. Such evil management
                            will ever be a spiritual loss to the soul, until the creditors are paid, and the soul
                            repents of having become indebted." 22. " If I owned the whole world, I would turn it into
                            joyfulness. I would not say to the poor : be ye warmed and be ye clothed, without giving
                            them the wherewith to help them." 23. "Be diligent in business—hands to work and hearts to
                            God. Godliness leads to industry. The devil is a tempter; but an idle person tempts the
                            devil. When doing your duty in the love of God, the devil can have no power over you; there
                            is no room for temptations." 24. "I have taught you the way of God; you must keep it. I am
                            one, called to keep it with you; I must do my work, you must do yours; I can help you; so
                            can the heavenly spirits, but they cannot do your work. You have a day and privilege which
                            many others have desired, but did not obtain. If you take up your crosses against the lusts
                            of the flesh, as Jesus did, while you have the ability to gratify these, you will be the
                            brightest souls in heaven; there are glorious crowns prepared for all such; honor and glory
                            that none can obtain, who live in the indulgences that are darkening, and death to the
                            soul." 25. "Taking up the cross of Christ will be compulsory in the future world, brought
                            about by sufferings; but those who voluntarily take up the cross now, and live as Christ
                            lived, will be more glorious than the Angels—yea, as kings and priests unto God !" 26. " The
                            marriage of the flesh is a covenant with death, and an agreement with hell! the Christ life
                            is eternal life; who would enjoy this, must forsake that." 27. One day there came a poor man
                            to Mother Ann, complaining of his brother, who was rich and able to help him, but would not.
                            She replied: "That is the way of the world; the rich are covetous and will not help the
                            poor; and the poor, instead of crying to God, to soften the hearts of the rich, will envy
                            and hate them ; therefore both are wicked." 28. Of one of her disciples, Mother Ann asked :
                            " Do you believe I can forgive sins ?" "I believe," said Hannah Cogswell, "that the spirit
                            of Christ that is in you, can forgive my sins." "That is the right faith," said Mother Ann.
                            *</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Toiling brother or sister..." TEIform="index"/>Toiling brother or sister...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">1. Toiling brother or sister, do you grow faint in the pursuit of the treasures of immortal
                            life? Give 3'our heart in prayer to Got), our Heavenly Father and Mother, ami supplicate
                            their guidance. 2. Life would lose roach of its unpleasantness, if each one would seek, by
                            acts of condescension, to brighten the pathway and cheer the hearts of dear companions.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ten men fail from defect in morals, where one fails from defect in intellect...." TEIform="index"/>Ten men fail from defect in morals, where one fails from defect in intellect....
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Ten men fail from defect in morals, where one fails from defect in intellect." Let us strive
                            to make this untrue. Integrity and intelligence are natural allies. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>Prayer</head><p TEIform="p">Most prominent among all the subjects engrossing the minds of professing Christians is that
                            of prayer. What is it? Whence its origin? What the benefits to be derived from it ? Prayer
                            has been defined as the heart's sincere desire, uttered, or unexpressed; the motion of a
                            hidden fire that burns within the breast. Jesus advised, for prayer, to enter into the
                            closet, and shut the door; and one of his disciples said: " Pray without ceasing." If these
                            injunctions were literally obeyed, the closet would be our abiding place, and prayer our
                            constant employ; in which case, somebody would soon be hungry, with nothing in the larder to
                            appease that hunger. But, if prayer be the heart's sincere desire, we may prajconstantly and
                            work perpetually; for it is action, at last, that gives vitality to our desires. The grocer
                            who called out to his clerk to sand the sugar and water the vinegar, and come up to prayers,
                            might make money, and use words, but could hardly be said to pray, within the meaning of
                            either Jesus or his disciple. The hosts of professing Christians who enter their synagogues,
                            or places of worship for prayer, enrobed in gorgeous apparel of silks and satins, to pour
                            forth in studied language a form of words, grammatical and rhetorical, agreeing with the
                            gold, diamonds and rubies that adorn their persons, occupying the first seats, have their
                            prayers hindered by the strong contrast presented by the rear ranks of the same
                            congregation—the soiled and threadbare vestments, the haggard and toilworn countenances of
                            the widow and fatherless, who are suffering for the common necessaries of life! Should the
                            spirit of God give form to the prayers uttered, and render it into actions, this unchristian
                            inequality would end in brothers and sisters loving each other as themselves; if prayer is
                            desire, if what we desire, we will; and what we will, we do. If by the closet, the Saviour
                            meant the heart; and by the door, the mouth, heart-felt silent prayer would be the result;
                            then we should enter our hearts, and shut our mouths. If we pray, "Our Father and Mother,
                            God, who art in Heaven, thy Kingdom come, thy will be done on earth as it is done in
                            Heaven," how great the thought! how often it is lightly considered and conveniently passed
                            over. Query upon query crowds upon the mind : Are there " in Heaven " manufactories of
                            firearms and all the implements and horrid machinery of war, demonism incarnate ? Are there
                            arsenals, wherein to store them? Do they manufacture powder ? and have they magazines for
                            the storage of the same ? Have they military academies "in heaven," where all the latest and
                            most improved styles, plans and tactics of popular murder are taught ? Are there colleges
                            for a privileged few to be educated and fitly prepared as hireling priests to bear the
                            testimony of Jesus, enjoining his disciples to love each other, and to lives of virgin
                            purity and spotless innocence as was his own ? Do they have distilleries there, to produce "
                            the ardent" with all its varied " compounds ?" Is there smoking in heaven, among the saints,
                            and angels, seraphs, and spirits of just men and women made perfect? Do the shining hosts
                            worship and chew, expectorate and sing psalms together ? Do they raise the filthy swine,
                            free-soilers, to roam at large and root up the golden pavements, or to spoil the rich
                            verdure of those "pastures ever green," that the saints may be enriched by the sale of their
                            dead carcasses ? It is said that they neither marry nor are given in marriage in heaven, and
                            that the rich do not there oppress the poor! This may be called an external view of heaven;
                            but what, or where is the external, that has not its origin with the internal? The pharisee
                            said: "Go, and be thou clothed, fed, and comforted;" but that prayer did not exist in his
                            heart; neither did it manifest itself in any outward act. Again, we are enjoined to pray: "
                            Forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us." How is this prayer
                            practically carried out in this our Christian (?) country ? Is there not far more of the eye
                            for an eye, and tooth for a tooth system exercised, than that of turning the other cheek
                            when one is smitten; or, of rendering good for evil in our every day practice—which ?
                            Recurring to the invocation, " When thou prayest," etc., we may remark, that every person,
                            having had experience as a Christian, knows that there are " times and seasons" when the
                            soul feels especially drawn out in prayer—when terrestrial things become matters
                            insignificant, and unworthy of a place in the heart's affections—when, lost to things of
                            time, the troubled soul finds rest in prayer, and that solace which thoughts of God alone
                            can give. Sweet and precious are those bliss- ful seasons, when in the closet of the heart
                            we can breathe forth the gushings of a sorrow- stricken spirit. And very pleasant are the
                            seasons set apart for our assembling together in prayer, blending and commingling our
                            spirits in our united capacities. How comforting then, to be baptized by the divine unction,
                            and to have our united body magnetized, so to speak, by the electric current as it flows
                            from the divine fountain, and unites us soul to soul. father, Mother—God—grant us more of
                            this blessed spirit—the power and essence of prayer—that we may know and do thy holy will as
                            it is done in Heaven !</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. F., Wt, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Maxims" TEIform="index"/>Maxims</head><p TEIform="p">A knowledge of our own weakness creates in us, charity for others. The imperfections we see
                            and despise in others, we sometimes possess ourselves. A Christian will never despise the
                            poor, unfortunate, nor fallen ; but will strive to reclaim them by their love of God. We may
                            despise sin, but not the sinner. The most powerful lens is a humble spirit; it enables us to
                            see ourselves. Make thy heart an abode for angels, not a reservoir for sin. What we gain by
                            our own exertions we value ; while gifts bestowed are frequently squandered.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., E. F." TEIform="persName"/>E. F. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This whole life is but one great school..." TEIform="index"/>This whole life is but one great school...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">This whole life'is but one great school, from the cradle to the grave. We are all scholars ;
                            the voices of those we love, the wisdom of past ages, and our own experience are our
                            teachers. Afflictions give us discipline ; the spirits of departed saints whisper to us, "
                            come up higher."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. P.</byline></div2><pb n="47" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Humility—No. 1</head><p TEIform="p">Every virtue has its foundation in the truth and reason of things; and Humility, with all
                            other graces, must rest on this immutable basis. A certain divine being asked which was the
                            most excellent of the Christian graces, answered " Humility." Being further interrogated
                            which was the next, again replied " Humility; " and being a third time pressed with the
                            question, still answered "Humility." Intending thus to intimate that humility must be the
                            constant temper and mental condition of the Christian ; and that without it, all other
                            graces are incomplete. Humility arises from a true sense of our own condition and the real
                            relation we stand in to God and our fellow beings; and as it admits of no assumptions of
                            excellence we do not possess, neither does it consist in any degradation of ourselves below
                            what is strictly true. All degradation below what is real and sincere, is mere
                            mock-humility. It is pride in disguise desiring to be considered a paragon of that lowly
                            virtue of which it is destitute. In vain shall we search the scriptures for one
                            self-degrading expression that Jesus ever made, though he declared himself to be meek and
                            lowly in heart; his humility arose from the perception and acknowledgment of the great
                            truth, that of himself he could do nothing. It has been thought by some, that humilty arises
                            from a proper sense and acknowledgment of our sins; but this cannot be true, since the most
                            glorious and perfect natures are always the most humble. Jesus, though the most perfect of
                            men, was the most humble, and his humility arose from a clear perception of his entire
                            dependence upon God, and a cheerful submission to the divine will. If humility be predicated
                            on a sinful state, then can this divine virtue have no place in the hearts of the just; the
                            saints must be destitute of it; it can have no place in heaven. If humility be an immortal
                            virtue, and of perpetutal obligation, based on the entire dependence of all created
                            intelligences on their Creator, then may saints and the highest archangels will be humble,
                            and eternally so. All aping of simplicity or pretensions to a childish state, which it is
                            impossible we should really possess, is so far either from simplicity or humility, that it
                            is downright duplicity. To perceive the propriety of humility in the intellect without
                            desiring it in the heart, is like mentally perceiving the necessity of food without having
                            an appetite for it. By boasting of our deserts we intrench upon our humility. The being
                            unjustly disgraced is not exactly humiliated, but it may assist us to be humble. Seeing it
                            is our duty to do all the good we can, we cannot merit praise; we have but ''one our duty.
                            Praise belongs to God. How foolish is pride! How vain is ambition ! How absurd for nothings
                            to contend which shall be the greatest! Praise may do for children, and all who seek it may
                            be counted such. Men know that it neither belongs to them nor becomes them. Men may condemn
                            and contemn, but he that has a pure conscience will not be disturbed, unless he be still
                            under the influence of that vile affection which cannot be satisfied with " the honor that
                            cometh from God only," but earnestly craves the honor of mortal worms like himself. In
                            proportion as any one is dead to self, and to the desire of the honors of men, in the same
                            proportion is he regardless of the unjust censures of mortals. He that is greatly disturbed
                            at the reproaches of men, will, if he examine deeply into his own heart, find that he is
                            either more or less obnoxious to censure, or too much alive to self, and eagerly coveting
                            the applause of creatures, rather than the approbation of God, in his own conscience. Seek
                            no greatness but to be great in thy conceptions and love of the one only Infinite and
                            Eternal Good. It is a greater blessing to be censured when innocent than to be praised when
                            undeserving. You say you was equally faithful with your brother, yet he was praised, while
                            you was neglected. Be thankful it was so. You desire to be humble. Praise might puff' you
                            up. How happy was your escape ! What have you to complain of? Did you act from a sense of
                            duty and to please God ? If so, your consciousness of having done your duty is a sufficient
                            reward. If you are not satisfied with that, you may detect in yourself the sordid motive of
                            working for human applause. If you act from the base motive of obtaining the praise of men,
                            disappointment is the best thing that could befall you. "How can you believe, who receive
                            honor one of another?" All the blessings I enjoy flow from the all- bountiful giver of every
                            good, unmerited by me. This must be so, unless. I can make it appear that my talents are
                            self-created—selfderived, and not the gift of God the Creator. Of what can I boast ? What
                            can I claim for my services ? Wrhen I have done all that is commanded, what can I say, but
                            that I am an unprofitable servant ? I have only occupied the talents that wer» given me. How
                            fond we are of fame, and yet what is it ? A mere modification of air, so articulated as to
                            inflate us with the notion that we are, what we are not. A good character is not merely a
                            good name in the mouths of others, but a good nature in ourselves. He that has the peace of
                            God in his soul cannot be rendered unhappy, though all men call him a demon; but he that is
                            unreconciled in heart will be wretched, though all men call him a saint.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P., U. V., Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is all that is noble in living a life of self-denial..." TEIform="index"/>There is all that is noble in living a life of self-denial...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is all that is noble in living a life of self-denial —denying to ourselves affections
                            of wrong ; and all that is lovely in the cultivation of something better— the beautiful, the
                            good. Hard-feelings are the elements of worldly hatred. Worldly hatred derives its origin,
                            often, from a wrong committed by those who hate, towards the object of their hatred. That
                            which we ]ove best, will form the subject of our happiest thoughts ; we will give it the
                            preference of all other themes in our conversation ; it will have the largest influence in
                            forming our resolutions, anc of putting them into execution.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain Talks, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks—No, 3</head><p TEIform="p">Evading the Cross. As Christian people, we should be as far from acting falsehoods, as
                            believing them. As followers of the Christ Spirit, we should not be guided so readily by the
                            interpretations of apostolic teachings, as by the lives of Jesus, and those true Apostles,
                            who lived as did their master. Life is the exponent of an individual's creed, no matter what
                            peculiarity is noticeable in his prayer. The world at large hate selfdenial; they know that
                            Jesus practiced this exceedingly; therefore the teachings of the Apostles are studiously
                            canvassed, not to evidence the necessity of a full cross, but how individuals may shun the
                            cross, and yet maintain their Christian fellowship ! It is noticeable to every reader of
                            Scripture, that the popular Christianity of to-day will bear little or no comparison to the
                            life of Jesus; that there is no unchristian practice, but finds its apologists in some of
                            the popular pulpits. First, look at marriage : a sacred institution, so-called; but what a
                            breach it immediately causes, between the life of the goodly exem- plar, and him who
                            professes loyalty, but who departs thus from Christian practice. How can Christians follow,
                            where Jesus did not go ? Had Jesus married a wife, reared up a family, gained to himself a
                            property, and maintained these at the expense of his neighbors, then would the popular
                            Christians of to-day be his genuine followers ! Take war: where was there a popular pulpit,
                            but took sides with the combatants in our late war, and justified it, on one side or the
                            other; yet where, in our Exemplar's life, did they get their authority? Had Jesus been a
                            warrior; had he led hosts on to battle and been successful as a wholesale butcher of
                            humanity, then no fault could be found with popular Christians, nor their pastors, for
                            following these in the life of Jesus. But who can wonder that lust is rampant; that war is
                            respectable; that private property is endeared, when the people, generally, eager to evade
                            the crucifixion of their unchristian loves, will spend millions of dollars in educating
                            ministers to interpret to them what Scripture does not mean ? to hide the beautiful,
                            self-denying life of Christ behind an ambush of unmeaning words, and secure to them the
                            license of living the very reverse of him whose honorable name they prostitute ? The light
                            of the Spirit is making these things plain to the hitherto hoodwinked and blindly led, but
                            would-be honest followers; and this light will increase until he who dares preach any
                            evasion of the cross that Jesus practiced, will blush all over at his hypocrisy, and
                            sleeplessly lament his heaven-daring attitude. We honor the Romans for demanding of their
                            teachers, that they shall represent one prominent feature of our Lord's life—Virginity ;
                            while we claim that no cross that Jesus applied to himself, can be evaded by clergy or laity
                            without a denial of the profession of Christianity. "Follow me," said Jesus. We bear witness
                            to the progress of the age. Once, and not many years ago, we would have been as our
                            spiritual relatives were, imprisoned, impaled, crucified and burned, for utterances not so
                            plain, yet only as true. *</p></div2><pb n="48" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Communication</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor of the shaker:" TEIform="index"/>Editor of The Shaker:</head><p TEIform="p">"While numberless charges are being made against the Shakers, because of their depopula-
                                tive life, I propose to own up to these charges, and include Jesus as one of our number
                                who pleads guilty to the same. Speaking of the natural order, Jesus said: "They twain
                                shall be one flesh," and only flesh; and his apostle says, "nevertheless, if they marry,
                                they will fight! " (1 Cor. 7:28) and the relations of marriage furnish abundant
                                corroboration to-day. The life of Christ puts an end to generations; whoso practices
                                under the ordinance of marriage of the flesh, knows nothing of Christ's Spirit, and such
                                would do well to look after their laurels as Jews; for they are not Christians, and if
                                they are not Jews, then are they willing to own up to the charge of "carnal
                                Corinthians?" Man is a progressive being, capable of ascension above the culminating
                                point of animal nature—a superior state into which he may enter while yet upon the
                                earth—" thy will be done on earth, as 'tis in heaven." Is this a romance? Man was made
                                in the image of God; we propose, b)^ leaving the animal works of generation, living
                                temperately in that which sustains life as Jesus did, to rise with him, above the image
                                into a oneness xoith the Father. The mission of Jesus was to awaken us to a knowledge of
                                our spiritual natures, apart, and superior to our earthly beings ; to our earthly,
                                generative lives—and the spirit of Christ wars against every feature of the flesh; not
                                merely brings it to temperance, but puts it to death ; and thus he run the world out in
                                himself—"I have overcome (destroyed) the world." Jesus was called " the harvest man; "
                                what was he to reap, but human souls from earthly conditions, and present to them a
                                spiritual life ? In man's haste to fulfill the great command, he does not stop to read
                                of the work of subduing attached thereto; showing, that as a natural, earthly being,
                                there should -be a check to the extravagant abuses of his animal desires. But is man
                                "fruitful?" We deny the assertion. We positively state that " the unfruitful works of
                                darkness" is the rule; and instead of fruit, worth}'of the handiwork of God, we witness
                                a bundle of perversions, disease and death, that moans from the cradle to the grave ! If
                                being "fruitful" implies the works of the flesh according to perverted desires,
                                regardless of moral law, setting at nought times and seasons, quantity and quality, then
                                humanity stands acquitted—hold, we err in the remark—there are multitudes of professedly
                                Christian people, according to John Todd, and " Satan in Society," who will not be
                                fruitful in anything but spasmodic lusts—but, dear Editor, I do not mean to rob you of
                                your "Plain Talks." Mankind generally claim the right to use the command of God for the
                                peopling of the earth, for the most debasing indulgences—such as would cut the brutes
                                off from the face of the earth ; and is fast " running the world out! " Why the dominion
                                of man over woman ? I tell you, kind Editor, it is to crush in the bud, the voice that
                                would speak in the Councils of the nation, deciding how far and how long woman shall be
                                a common prostitute ! Whoever will keep the laws of nature strictly in his generations,
                                will be more wonderstruck at his surroundings, and of the threatened "end of the world,"
                                than any now are at the lives the Shakers are living. Now, provided the Shakers took no
                                higher ground than to operate as a balance to the populative principle, would this not
                                be an exemplary improvement upon the embryotic murders ; the infantile deaths; inherited
                                and acquired diseases; wars, or wholesale murders ; legions of suicidal practices, that
                                spring from the unfruitful works, and which strew along the road allotted to life,
                                myriads of human wrecks ? Bury the victim of self-murder at the cross-roads as of yore,
                                and you would multiply Greenwoods and Auburns incalculably; and truthful tombstones
                                would declare : " Died under the age of twenty, a victim to the violation of
                                physiological law! " There is no extravagance in saying that the sins of our first
                                parents, compared with those of to-day, are as ant-heaps to Andes! Let there be no
                                misunderstanding: The Shakers are running the world out—the world of sin; and they are
                                as a testimony of salt to the generating animals of the earthly order, predicting a
                                running out of the world's inhabitants, numerically, if they continue in the unfruitful
                                practices of the present day. Let him who is perfectly fullfilling the Mosaic
                                injunctions in his generations, ask: "What lack I yet?" and the answer will be returned
                                from the Christ heavens:—" You have learned the song of Moses, now learn the divine
                                life-song of the Lamb ! " and the result will be, a flight upward, from earthly
                                practices into Angelic livelihood; and there, a similar order of life is in vogue, that
                                the Shakers are seen to practice. The natural man willingly gives up the earthly for the
                                heavenly; the lusts of the animal, for the loves and joys of the heavenly host. The
                                earth, losing its attraction for him, his aspirations and polarity will be toward
                                heaven; and then, if he have any regrets, it will be that he did not put an end to the
                                world, flesh and devil sooner, and ere then have lived, as well as professed the Chris-
                                tian!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A living people will have a live religion..." TEIform="index"/>A living people will have a live religion...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A living people will have a Iive religion ; this religion will resurrect them into life
                                eternal; life eternal is a condition that is obtained by denial unto ourselves of
                                practices we know the Angels oi" God do not, tootdd not engage in. How can we better
                                make ''living sacrifices unto God," than by so living, that evil in its every form is
                                sacrificed, and the pure and lovely only, shine forth in their Christian splendor?
                                Humanity arc getting thoroughly awake to the fact, that much that has been considered
                                pleasure, is illegal for Christians to practice ; is corroding and corrupting to both
                                body and soul. The name Christian signifies a follower of Christ. " Who would be my
                                disciple, must do as I do." We will have no controversy with any ; but while we ask none
                                to be Shakers, we ask them, for their eternal welfare, to live like him whom they
                                profess to adore. "Only introduce marriage into your institution, and we will become
                                Shakers immediately, " is the most common of observations. "Come down from that cross
                                and all men will believe on you," was remarked some time ago. "Do the Shakers want
                                accessions?1' However this may be, we do not, nor ever will want accessions badly enough
                                to recede from any principle in life, maintained by our great exemplar—Christ. Should we
                                admit any, who would not confess and depart their sins—then there would be a humiliating
                                spectacle—the Shakers joining the world.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Answers to correspondents" TEIform="index"/>Answers to Correspondents</head><p TEIform="p">" Editor of The Shaker i " Some things I would like to know . Do you have revelations
                                from the spirit world, as of old, or at all ? and, if not, what is the cause ? " Second:
                                What do you think is to be the ultimate of the" orthodox churches ? Will they grow to a
                                spiritual life ? or will they ' wax worse and worse ? ' '• Please answer through ' The
                                Shaker.' '•E. F. Curtis." Answer. We have just such kind of communications as we desire
                                and labor for, whether rapping, table-tipping, moving of matter, or the deepest
                                spiritual inspiration. Second : The ultimate of the orthodox churches will be,—a part
                                will remain in their dead materialism ; retrograde into infidelity to their orthodox
                                theologies; or will settle down in pantheistic atheism. A large part will progress into
                                Spiritualism ; and the coming conflict will be between these two classes—mate- rialists
                                and spiritualists. The latter will ultimately prevail, progressing out of the
                                rudimental—the generative—into the Angel order, in this life, keeping the higher law of
                                celibacy.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. P.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker, monthly journal, devoted to the exposition of religion, acording to Shaker theology" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. MONTHLY JOURNAL, DEVOTED TO THE EXPOSITION OF RELIGION, ACCORDING TO SHAKER
                            THEOLOGY.</head><p TEIform="p">Fifty Cents, Pek Amrox, in Advance. G. A. Lomas, Resident Editor, Shakers, Albany Co., N. Y.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of .Editors. Elder F. W. Evans,
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt.
                            Morris-, Livingston. Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield. Mass. " Stoughton. Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm.
                            Leonard. Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. 11
                            Nebemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton
                            Co., N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred. Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilrnan, West
                            Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Charles Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O.,
                            Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton,
                            Shakers. Ohio. " George Runyon, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union,
                            JLogan Co., Ky. " J. S. Presoott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto .... Millennial Church.....
                            Compendium of Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is
                            paid. m 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>