<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0810" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName">G. A. Lomas</persName></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18781001" TEIform="date">October 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">236-261</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
 	              <p> Vol. VIII. NO. 10 OCTOBER. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL. MONTHLY.)
                        PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT CANTERBURY, N. H. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD."
                        PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. THE SHAKER 1878.</p>--><!--                    <pb n="236" id="p2"/>
                  <p>The Exercise of Authority God's Love Universal True Freedom What Has been done May be Indians
                        Civil Government vs Spiritual Government The Two Reformers . The Shaker Manifesto Was Jesus The
                        Christ Editorial Notes Ann Lee 237 238 240 242 243 243 245 245 246 247 249 Worldly Conformity
                        For The Children Selected Scientific Thoughts for the Times Farm & Garden Society Record
                        Home Topics Obituary There is no Death Music 250. 251 253 255 255 257 257 258 258 253 26 TERMS
                        OF ADVERTISING. For one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column, " " $ 3. 00 one " " " ¦$
                        G. 00 page, " " , $12.00 Continued insertion for three rnonths, 20 per ct. discount. i, gix »*
                        25 » » " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, Shaker
                        Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription wiu begin when order is received.—No back numbers.
                        CONTENTS.</p>--><pb n="237" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Exercise of authority" TEIform="index"/>THE EXERCISE OF AUTHORITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">I have, latterly been making some critical researches into the origin and necessity of
                            Authority. One reason for my entering upon this investigation is the fact that I am, and
                            have been for many years occupying what are termed places of authority, burden, or care ;
                            (which, as our Institution understands it, are convertible terms, at least to a consider-
                            able extent.) 1 am therefore interested to inquire severely into my own stewardship. If I am
                            amenable to God or any Intelligences above me for my conduct of this stewardship, then
                            vastly more am I amenable to those below me; because it is upon this class and them only,
                            that this stewardship takes effect. The very first principle of any value, connected with
                            the subject of authority or government seems to me to be this : That any government to be
                            beneficial to an enlightened community, must be so by virtue of its receiving the consent of
                            the governed, and conversely; any individual or individuals refusing to yield this con-
                            sent, are not legitimate members of such community, and ought to be separated from it
                            without loss of time. Waiting for such undeveloped persons to become reconciled is merely
                            waiting for the Institution to go to pieces ; a melancholy truth which all past experience
                            and observation fully attest. It is waiting on a mortified limb, before excising it, un- til
                            it has gathered destructive energy enough to kill the patient. But before going any further
                            I will try to define my ideas of the necessity and origin of all government and authority
                            with which man needs concern himself. I am persuaded that the origin and ne- cessity of all
                            authority is to be found in the imperfections and rudimentalisms of our egotistic humanity.
                            Its necessity grows out of the fact, that we are too selfish to respect the rights of our
                            fellowdenizens ; and its origin grows out of its necessity. This appears to me the major
                            premise, the minor premise and conclusion of the whole matter. We all admit without
                            hesitation, that all men, women, children and even brutes have rights which we are bound to
                            respect; but very many of us if not all, being too selfish to yield that practical respect
                            to those rights which we ought, it seems necessary that some form of government should be
                            established, by which unbearable outlaws, and<pb n="238" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 238 THIS SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. tramplers on the rights of others should be restrained to prevent the world from
                            being actually depopulated. Consequently divers modes of governments have been resorted to,
                            to compel outlaws and unreasonable persons from infringing the rights of their fellow
                            beings; such as Monarchies, Empires, Autocracies, Aristocracies, Democracies, and Republics.
                            It is especially worthy of observation, that just so fast as men become refined and
                            civilized, two results have uniformly followed; (1.) Greater liberality in the form of
                            government, and consequently greater individual freedom. (2.) The right of appeal from lower
                            to higher tribunals of decision. There are good reasons for these results. It is patent to
                            common sense that as men improve in the amenities of life, from motives of benevolence,
                            conscience, and justice, they may, and ought to be left more and more to their own mental,
                            moral, and spiritual manipulation. It is further to be supposed, that they will not only be
                            more sensitive to unnecessary eneroachments upon their rights, but when deprived of these
                            rights, will sec at once the dire and keen necessity, of an appeal from the oppressive
                            surveillance and inexorable tyranny by which these rights have been trampled upon. From this
                            natural course which the self-mending energies of man seem to have taken through all former
                            ages, even to the present time ; by which man has been certainly improved and greatly
                            progressed, it would seem that the vanguard of all the mighty hosts who have peopled the
                            earth, arc, or ought to be, ready for that form of government mapped out by that greatest of
                            all reformers, and esteemed both by professor and profane—the most highly progressed
                            individual the world ever saw—-Jesus Christ—as follows : "The King3 of thegentiles exercise
                            Lordship over them, and they that exercise authority upon them are called benefactors. But
                            yo shall not be so ; but he that is greatest among you, let him be as the younger, and he
                            that is chief as he that doth serve." It may be high time for me and every one who like me
                            may be "clothed with a little brief authority," to think solemnly of these things ; for as
                            the poet says— "When later, there's less time to play the fool." Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's love universal" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S LOVE UNIVERSAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>ELDRESS A. DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">As the vast ocean is made up of drops of water, so are nations composed of individual beings.
                            But we need to pass beyond the narrow channel of individualism, where hopes, affections and
                            interests cluster around, and center in the selfish family circle, to be able to comprehend
                            even in a limited degree, the ways and plans of the Infinite Designer and Producer of the
                            Universal whole. Co-operative principles, Wisdom and Love, are eternal and unchangeable, one
                            in attribute and perfection, creating, bringing forth, and harmonizing all. Peoples,
                            kindreds and nations are tributaries conveying towards the source and center; but names,
                            sects and parties, as such, are unknown to the Infinito Mind. The voice of parental love is
                            heard, saying "All souls are mine." When we cast our eyes over the sea thusformed, so
                            boundless to our finite perception, how atom-like we seem to ourselves, and iow exceedingly
                            small must we appear in sight of the dual God whose love and care extends to all in every
                            land and clime in our<pb n="239" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MLAJSTIIHESTO. 23Q sphere, and in all
                            worlds. May we not repeat the question again and again, "What is man," when
                            individualized—"that Thou art mindful of him?"' Yet the whole is so perfectly organized and
                            governed—so compact, like the veins and tissues of the human body, that the least
                            displacement creates pain, and mars its perfection and beauty. God, inspects character,
                            moral and spiritual conditions, and places the signet of approval or disapproval
                            accordingly, upon persons, nations or races. The Arab who traverses the sandy deserts, the
                            Indian who takes shelter in wild forests and hunting grounds, and the Ethiopian who thrives
                            best in tropical regions, are objects of love and care of the All Father and loving Mother.
                            God does not see with mortal vision; but with eyes that pierce every cloud and incrustation,
                            and the same light illumes, the same love pervades, and all things are balanced duly; for He
                            looks into the interior—the heart, and judges rightly; while finite beings look at, aad
                            judge from exterior appearances, and decide imperfectly, if not unjustly. The great heart of
                            humanity, in the hour of trial and need instinctively turns to the Universal Father and
                            Mother for aid and relief; with outstretched arms, and uplifted voices, the soul utters in
                            deep-toned and trustful accents, "O help and save!" Do they, or can they turn a deaf ear
                            when thus invoked? Nay, they do not f.&gt;rget their children, though they err, and
                            wander in devious ways: but as a loving mother traces the course of her wayward child over
                            rolling 6eas, and distant lands,.and with deep solicitude and a yearning heart strives to
                            draw and call him or her home to the parental roof, there to find a father's protection and
                            feel a mother's love; so Humanity—the offspring and product of the Eternal Parents are held
                            and drawn by cords of love; though many times it be through adversity, and stern rebuke, as
                            the only means of restoration. Limited and f.iint, at best, are our conceptions.of the great
                            structure of worlds inhabited by countless beings; but circumscribed as is our vision, we
                            trace the lines of perf jction and beauty in all ttie vorks of God; and we are often
                            inspired to sing anew "Great is the Lord, and greatly to be praised!" We perceive it was not
                            in the divine economy instantly to evolve a perfected plant—a full grown tree, or completed
                            manhood from the germs of such life; but to vivifiy, and give time for expansion and growth;
                            and through culture to mature and perfect the whole, though ages may intervene, we sec no
                            limit to creation; from the great womb of Nature, spring forth new worlds teeming with
                            vegetable and animal life, moved by the same forces, and regulated by the same laws.
                            Agencies are at work to develop and consummate the original plans of the great Master
                            builder, in every department from the lowest strata to the acme. Few centuries have rolled
                            by, since America, our own loved country was a vast wilderness ; now a large portion is
                            under the hand of cultivation, and is a broad land of fruitful fields. From the Atlantic to
                            the Pacific shores, the once traceless desert has been penetrated; and by supernatural
                            agencies—combined with human skill and labor, hills have been leveled—valleys raised, and
                            the iron horse now wends its way over the rocky mountains with such velocity, that scarcely
                            the farewell echoes from friends on the Atlantic coast cease to vibrate, before welcome
                            greetings from others on the Pacific shores, break upon the ear. Thus by successive degrees
                            will the terminal point be reached, the keystone, in all created existences. The seasons may
                            seem to linger, in a spiritual point of view, and to many who are weary of waiting and
                            impatient of delay, may look at the present time, as a wintry season when the spiritual
                            forces lie dormant; others feel that the powers of the inner worlds are all astir; that the
                            hastening of the fulfillment of Prophetic periods are at hand and that the incoming flowing
                            tides of spirit power, will issue from the fountain whence proceeds every good gift to
                            humanity. And those who wait and watch, will realize promises fulfilled, and find God's ways
                            justified; that even now the heavens are full of rejoicing, and the sound is heard by those
                            who have listening cars, on themountains and in the valleys throughout Zion's domains. Aft.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="240" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True freedom" TEIform="index"/>TRUE FREEDOM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">"If the truth shall make you free ye shall be free indeed." The great boast of Americans is,
                            that ours is a land of freedom, and independence, and every fourth of July there is an
                            annual jubilee to celebrate the independence of our nation ! The questions are: Are we free?
                            How are we free ? From whom and from what are we free? Are we free governmentally,
                            politically ? What is it to be free from King George and King William or Queen Victoria, and
                            slaves to a bribed Congress of politicians, whose opinional decisions are bought and sold in
                            the political market like potatoes at a grocery ? whose moral character is traded off for
                            the office of commissary to the "Indian Bureau," and who, in the ambitious wrestle for
                            promotion, for the sake of mercenary gain would sell at auction, to the highest bidder, his
                            political wardrobe and standard flag! What kind of national freedom is it when one half the
                            population that is taxed is not represented, and woman, politically, is unknown, except, as
                            property? Are we, as a nation, free, mentally, though the chamber maid is sent to dust down
                            the parlor, and the library, in comes the post boy, and upon that center table of the
                            parlor, or the library desk, we find the daily paper, loaded with all the filth of the slums
                            of the town, and gulches of the country, reeking with the fumes of whiskey, or the
                            decoctions of tobacco, spouted out from swearing lips at the grog shop, and the strong
                            demoniac verbiage of the gambler's den ? Or, as food for the juvenile minds, '•'•Old Mother
                            Goose's Stories" '•'•Jack the Giant Killer" "Dime Novels" or "Grundy's Gossip"? Is not the
                            temple of the mind profaned with frivolities? with day dreams of pleasure, and fooleries of
                            fashion ; or ravished with false views of life's experiences—lies, dressed as truths? The
                            new, monthly novel, streaming with unreal life-portraits and pictures, in gor- geous, ideal
                            colors, to dazzle and beguile, are found at almost every '•'¦News room" "Book store" and
                            often, on the same shelf with the sacred library ! Is the Church, denominated " Christian"
                            free? Behold its theology, ankleshackled, wrist-cuffed and mouth-gagged, with false
                            philosophies of God, of Heaven, hell, of rewards and punishments ; of faith and works ; of
                            life and death ; of damnation and justification ; of resurrection and eternal life ; of
                            social and spiritual righteouness ; of justification and condemnation ! • Its theological
                            teachers make a God of Jesus, of whom the prophet said: "A Prophet shall the Lord YOUR God
                            raise up unto you, of your brethren, like unto me," (Moses.') Of whom the Jews said: "Is not
                            this the Carpenter's Son, and his Sisters, are they not all with us?" and of whom his
                            disciples said, he was "their Elder Brother," '•'•The first born" (into the New Creation)
                            "among many brethren," "made a little lower than .the angels?" Yet, he was "The Messiah,"
                            "The Mediator of the New Covenant," The "Lord and Master" of the Kingdom of Heaven and Earth
                            (the new Earth) the King! These false teachers, (of bondage,) make Heaven the gifted boon of
                            God's foreordination and election to a favored few, without regard to merit, and hell the
                            MANIFESTO. 240<pb n="241" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 241 burning lake of God's wrath,
                            awaiting the doom of all who disbelieve that their God, (Jesus,) suffered an ignominious
                            death at the hands of wicked Jcavs,— wicked because they killed Jesus, but still, in doing
                            so, fulfilled the predetermined purpose of his Father, God, to appease His wrath for the
                            sins of mankind, so that certain men may sin at their pleasure, without condemnation or
                            suffering ; and with the assured possession of heaven, if they only believe that Jesus,
                            (their God,) died for them! Is that Church, misnamed "Christian," free, whose character is
                            such, that, when one looks for its graces, its charities, its loves, its sympathies and
                            affections, he feels, as did the two Marys and Salome, on looking into the empty sephulchre
                            of Jesus? viz: "They have taken away the Lord, and we know not where they have laid him !"
                            For his spirit of inspirational baptism, his love, his consecration to God, his unselfish
                            service, his purity of character, are not to be found in these churches ! Are we free ? Free
                            from the conventionalisms of fashion, the prejudices of ambition and avarice ? from the
                            vanities and inconsistencies, even the fooleries of worldly life ? Far from it. Why ? A
                            character truly free from all the ligatures of fashion, pride, vanity, duplicity, deceit,
                            subtlety and bigotry ; free from the false, complimentary usages of custom, to appear
                            honestly and determinedly, true and just to all, with evil purpose to none, would walk the
                            earth a prodigy, too pure to be a denizen here ! Are we free, when we quarter upon our so
                            called Christian land of peace, troops of soldiers, to kill our enemies, (our fellow-men?)
                            when our mechanics are inventing engines of death on week days, and, on Sundays listening to
                            the chaplain of an army of soldiers, who melxs up church bells for cannon balls ? When we
                            quarter upon our poor, starved souls, physical bodies, festering in filth, but clothed in
                            silks, ribbons and broadcloths, and scented with musk and ilEau de Cologne" to neutralize
                            the effluvia of dissipation and debauchery ? Is it freedom from duplicity to compliment our
                            neighbors as Masters (Misters) and Mistresses, and sign ourselves their '•'•humble servants"
                            when such complimenters would feel insulted to be asked by them to black one's boots,—much
                            more, as did Jesus, their Lord, ("GW;") to wash the feet of their brethren ? That nation
                            only is free, which dares to do right, to disband its armies, spike its guns, burn its
                            magazines, turn its navies into merchantmen, and its hired soldiers into agriculturists,
                            employed by government! Whose statesmen should not be purchased by bribery, and whose
                            political partizans are brothers ; whose women have the right of franchise,—to
                            representation as well as taxation. Whose judges are the ministers of justice, instead of
                            injustice, whose lawyers plead for the authority of law in righteousness, instead of policy
                            and how to evade law. Whose jurymen cannot be bought with bribes ; and whose taxpayers will
                            not falsely enter their property for assessment. Whose police members are not accomplices in
                            the nefarious plots they essay to bring to justice, and whose courts are places where
                            justice, instead of injustice, is legally administered. That Church only is free, whose God
                            is a living God, instead of a dead Jesus ! whose members are the council of the living, in
                            spirit, instead of the dead, in<pb n="242" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> thp: shaker iviA.isriirKSTO. creeds ;
                            whose spiritual food is the fresh, ripe fruits of the tree of life, "yieldin its fruit every
                            month," instead of the dried plums of lifeless creeds; whose ritualism is the baptism of the
                            Holy Ghost; whose creed is the unlimited revelation of truth, and eternal progress in
                            righteousness ; whose worship is the entire consecration of life to the service of God ;
                            whose house of God is neat, substantial and plain, without a steeple to advertise its
                            aristocracy ; whose cross is borne in the selfdenying life of its members, rather than on
                            its steeple's crest; whose*" pulpit is the elevation of superior godliness of its preacher;
                            whose organ is the chime of pure, worshipful souls attuned in harmony ; whose songs arc the
                            outpourings of souls, filled with thankfulness to God for the power of salvation from sin,
                            rather than the lip seiwice of souls trusting in the sufferings of Jesus, to save them from
                            the consequences of continued sinning. That individual alone is free, who has the power of
                            God sufficient to govern the animal passions, and all emotions of the mind and soul ;
                            subjecting them to the law of God for the sphere, natural or spiritual, in Avhich the person
                            is professing to live ; whose mind is at liberty to seek, accept and pursue the truth, in
                            science, c.rt, morals, social conditions or religion, without regard to what the iiGrundys*'
                            may say or what the populace may think; who has the moral courage to be consistent, without
                            the fct tors of foolish fashion, the vanity of worldliness, or the pride of custom; whose
                            spirit is not trammeled by the fetters cf transgression of the laws of God, to him manifest,
                            because of the infidelity, wickedness or stupidity of his neighbora or fellows ; who dare to
                            live godly in the midst of temptations, and bear the scoffs and scorns of a sinful world,
                            rather than to endure the reproaches of a condemned conscience, and the sullied and
                            besmeared garments of the sinful and vile ; whose tongue and lips may utter, without
                            restraint, their gratitude and praise to God for the blessings of salvation from sin and
                            sorrow, though surrounded by those whose lips are sealed with pride, and whose tongues are
                            dumb for want of confidence before God, and before the souls of the good and true. As a
                            nation, our Government, Councils, Courts, Judges, Lawyers, Jurors, Priests, Laymen,—our
                            non-professors, our juveniles, all, all, and each, need to go with a resurrected John the
                            Baptist, down into the Jordan—river of Judgment—and confess our sins, and bo baptized into
                            the repentance of '¦¦Go and sin 710 more!" Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What has been done may be" TEIform="index"/>What HAS Been Done MAY Be</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">The old expression, long so true, What man has done, same man may do, The other tide we now
                            would view "What not, then how can we? We have a thought on married life— Where long has
                            been the earnest strife For purest joys with pleasures rife, Which never yet we see. We do
                            not think we could outvie, Showing the past has been a lie, A.nd should succeed, if we
                            should try, But fail, as others have. What never has beneath the sun, Been a success by any
                            one ; We will not think, we could have done, And mid the sunshine live. But we believe that
                            just the shade, Which has our betters overspread, 242<pb n="243" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER Would
                            all have been upon our head, If Peasant, King or Queen. And we should had the sour, the
                            miff, Our food without and season with, And all our life as full of if As ever has been
                            seen. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 8" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 8</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">The history of the United States with few exceptions is but a little move than a history of
                            frequent and protracted wars with the Indians. They were entailed upon the colonies by
                            emigrants from the old world, long before the U.S. became a free and independent nation.
                            Being of long standing and complicated they will be hard to eradicate. It took one hundred
                            years to abolish slavery after it was admitted it was a grievous sin and a reproach to the
                            people. This delay was caused by a division among the people, and as are the people, so is
                            the Government, and as is the Government, so will be the Indians. The Indians arc what the
                            Government makes them. They arc wholly at its mercy. If they go to war iL is because the
                            Government makes them, by withholding their supplies, and curtailing their appropriations.
                            Rather than starve they will fight and who would not, who are not Christians? No doubt the
                            present Avar might have been avoided if there had not been a failure on the part of the
                            Government to properly provide for the Indians of Lemlii and Fort Hall Agencies. There is
                            too much of human nature about the Indians ever to be conquered by the sword. They may yield
                            for the time being, or, they may be exterminated, but never conquered. It is a law in nature
                            that like begets like. The spirit of war begets war, the spirit of peace begets peace. North
                            Union, O. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Civil government vs. spiritual government" TEIform="index"/>CIVIL GOVERNMENT vs. Spiritual
                            Government</head><byline TEIform="byline">(Address of <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder F. W. Evans at Watkins, N. Y.)</byline><p TEIform="p">"Ye shall call every man his neighbor under the vine and under the fig tree." The Law shall
                            go forth from Zion and the Word of the Lord from Jerusalem." Where is Zion, What is the Law
                            and where shall it go to? When primitive Christianity came into being, in the Augustan age,
                            it was as distinct from the Roman Civil Government as the Shaker Government is distinct from
                            the Civil Government of the United States. Jesus said, "My kingdom is not of this world,
                            therefore will not my servants fight." He was the Prince of Peace. The Christian Church fell
                            when it made converts of the Roman Aristocracy and of many Officials of the Empire. Instead
                            of lifting them up out of the world, the Church went down from the cross and blended with
                            the Civil Government of Rome. Under Constantino, the Heathen and Christian systems were
                            mixed, united together. Babylon means mixed. As dowry to the incestuous marriage of Church
                            and State, the Civil Government brought war, and the Spiritual Government, or Church brought
                            religious controversy—the gate of hell. This made the Inquisition a Christian institution,
                            and war was thenceforth an integral element of anti-christianity. MANIFESTO. 243<pb n="244" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 244 THE SHAKER The Spiritualist John described this complex, compound system
                            as a woman "sitting upon many waters"—and again as a "woman sitting upon a scarlet colored
                            beast," that had a plurality of heads and horns growing out of them. The beast was full of
                            names of blasphemy. The waters and the beast are interpreted as both being the same,
                            peoples, multitudes, nations and tongues. Such as "give their power unto the beast" are all
                            those who give their adherence to Church and State governments, whether Christian, or
                            Infidel. In his vision, the Revelator next describes the horns—powers—that had grown out of
                            the multitudes and nationsthe beast. These were the Voltaires and Paines, the Jeffersons and
                            Lincolns, the Ingersolls, Greens and Bennetts, who "hate. the whore of Babylon—the Church
                            and State arrangements." They make her desolate and naked—torment her with books, papers,
                            lectures and Liberal Leagues—burn her with the fire of rationalism and scientific truth.
                            They collate, damning, historical and existing facts that cannot be successfully
                            controverted. Of such were the founders of the American Government—Skeptics and Infidels,
                            who carried the American Revolution to a successful issue. • Their most deadly foes were of
                            their own household—Tories, members of the Orthodox Churches, Episcopalians, Methodists
                            &amp;c. Paine's Crisis, Rights of Man and Common Sense converted enough of these
                            Christians to save the nation, for God put it into the hearts of these Infidels to fulfill
                            his will by establishing one Government on earth where liberty of conscience should be for
                            the people, as well as for the Priest. Yet it is said that the horns—the opposers—gave their
                            power unto the Beast, "until the word of God be fulfilled."—Until the New Heavens and New
                            Earth be created, forming two distinct Governments, Civil and Spiritual. Even Ingersoll and
                            Green, Abbot and Bennett yield obedience to the existing mixed Government, wherein there is,
                            as yet, much priestly power and influence. "The wretch" of Ecclesiastical and Civil power,
                            that has so long lorded it over the souls and bodies of heretics and free thinkers, is not
                            yet entirely crushed. Church and State are not quite separated even in these United States.
                            Long ago, in a lecture in Worcester, Mass., I canonized Thomas Paine as a Saint, enrolling
                            his name among the friends of God and humanity. He did the will of God in helping to found
                            theAmerican Government, a means of protection to the Shaker Church and Order,, and assisting
                            to tear down Babylonr blasphemously called Christendom. Victor Hugo, in his oration at the
                            Voltaire Centennial, like Paine, denounced War as the direst of human woes and greatest of
                            human curses. While Voltaire made war upon a Constantine Christianity, he eulogized Jesus
                            and was a friend of the Peace loving Quakers. He freed France from the horrible practice of
                            Priests and Magistrates uniting to torture prisoners and witnesses in Courts of injustice,
                            extorting confession before execution. He did crush out that wretched practice in France. He
                            arraigned the Judges in the name of Justice, Warriors, in the name of Jesus, the Prince of
                            Peace, and he called the fighting, torturing clergy to order, in the MANIFESTO.<pb n="245" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE 34,5 name of God, Christ and human nature. In place of Heathenish,
                            Constantine Christianity, he substituted Liberty and Fraternity. As our American Republic
                            was founded by Skeptics, with a Government Infidel to Anti Christianity, the Shakers want
                            nothing to do with it, and they attend this gathering, hoping to influence the Convention to
                            make it impossible for any other religious sect to have any thing to do with it. Ingersoll
                            would be a proper successor to Jefferson and Lincoln, as President of these United States.
                            Let us have two manners of people, with two Governments—a purely Secular Government, run by
                            Infidels, and a purely Spiritual Government under the Shakers. We want a New Earth, that
                            will exclude theology, and admit Women as Citizens, making the land as it was in Judea—the
                            inheritance of all the people who live by eating its products. Then will Peace come to stay,
                            the Army and Navy be abolished, tramps be as scarce as slaves, for on our Providential
                            Continent, War shall cease to the end of time, and thus shall every one call his and her
                            neighbor under the vine and under the fig tree with none to make them afraid. Co-operation
                            will obtain in the New Earth and Community of labor and of goods be the practice of all in
                            the New Heavens.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two Reformers" TEIform="index"/>The Two Reformers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">Some years ago, when the two political parties of the Empire State had got so near on the
                            same platform that they were stepping on each other's toes, Erastus Root, of Delaware
                            County, spake, in the assembly, the following parables : Two Beggar Girls, in the street—one
                            was beating the other unmercifully. Being questioned as to the wherefore, she
                            exclaimed—"Why, she has stole my story!" "What is your story?" "My daddy is dead and my
                            mamma is sick"—and so on— But what has this to do with our text? Not much in particular—just
                            a little in general. Reformer No. 1. reforms himself, puts his house in order and radiates a
                            wholesome influence to the extent of his&gt; ability. Reformers No. 2. have just one
                            idea, to reform every body but themselves. And when they meet, they're not much unlike the
                            Beggar Girls. Mt. Lebanon,N. Y.. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto: the superior Christian index" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO, THE
                            SUPERIOR CHRISTIAN INDEX</head><p TEIform="p">Let all reforms mean an evolution unto progress. Some modern thinkers or tinkers propose
                            reforms that shall transcend Christianity ; to which we make no objections whatever. But
                            until Christianity shall have been attained, in all its radical bearings upon the character,
                            there can be no such thing as a reform that shall be its superior. The index of Christ
                            points unto perfection—is perfection so far as mortals can, or have yet been able to
                            appreciate perfection. To every reform yet adduced from the minds of humanity, the
                            MANIFESTO. <pb n="246" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKKR JMLAJSnOTJCSTO. Christ Spirit still points to
                            something higher. The beautiful rule, called golden, teaches us to love others as ourselves.
                            It has been disputed, that this excellent axiom originated with Jesus. But who disputes that
                            the more excellent rule of lovivg our neighbors better than ourselves, and at the expense of
                            self, came to us directly from the life and testimony of Christianity's founder? The reforms
                            of to-day have many beauties for us to admire, and are significant of an increase of thought
                            and of conscience. But where is there a movement that can possibly mean more than genuine
                            Christianity has proposed for the people? As a rule of State, it urged the most discreet
                            principles and spirit of Mosaism. And there is no nationality now extant whose laws of state
                            arc an improvement in the health, life and prosperity of its people, beyond what the spirit
                            of Mosaism proposed. Upon Mosaism as a foundation, Jesus built a superstructure so grand and
                            transcendent, that those who would be as perfect as its precepts propose, are made no more
                            debtors to the law; having progressed beyond its restrictions into higher and better life.
                            To the inequalities of human conditions—of the sexes, of the rich and poor, master and
                            slave—what could comprehend more denial of self- ishness, and a more excellent lesson for
                            the times than ""Ye arc all brethren?" Do we seek labor in the field of temperance?
                            Christianity will supplant intemperance; while nothing can suppress it. Do we seek peace, in
                            households or in nations? What has equaled the non-resistant principles of the Clirist to
                            these ends ? Are we moved to reconcile capital and labor? "Let no man seek his own, but
                            every man another's wealth." Do we seek superiority above the relations that are
                            paradisiacal upon the earthly plane? ''Follow me"—in a denial of these, that "thy kingdom
                            come, thy Avill be done on earth"—now —"as it is in heaven." Is there any doubt, in the
                            minds of dullards even, in what consists the difference of earth life and heavenly life? And
                            as the heavens are in the ascendant, so in like manner was the life of Jesus superior to the
                            best regulated of earthly lives. Therefore, let those who will, "marry and be given in
                            marriage ;" in heaven, and heaven on earth this will not be. Let war and contentions and
                            politics engage those who choose not to follow Christ. "My servants will not fight, but
                            return good for evil. My Kingdom is not of this world." Let worldly emulation succeed ; and
                            riches and monopolies severely grind the faces of the poor and thorn the' rich; under
                            Christ, these things cannot obtain ; for "all who believed (in Christ), were together, and
                            had all things common; and sold their possessions and goods, avd parted them to all, as
                            every one had nezd." Accepting the good of all reforms, the index of Christianity points
                            still higher than aught else yet made known to us.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Was Jesus the Christ?" TEIform="index"/>WAS JESUS THE CHRIST?</head><p TEIform="p">We have ever endeavored to be plain and single-minded upon this subject; and invariably have
                            taught that it is not a question with us, but a veritable fact. It has been strongly hinted
                            to us that we dealt thus with the subject from matters of policy; not so, but from faith,
                            love and principle. Having thus, 246<pb n="247" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE very plainly reiterated what
                            our "little book"—"Plain Talks"—so reverently delights in repetition, we Avould just as
                            plainly add: That as Jesus was the Christ, during the introductory days of Christianity, so
                            others may have been and are the Christs of later periods and dispensations. That as
                            "Saviours shall come up on Zion," and these Saviours are Christs, so will each cycle or
                            dispensation of Ziou's progress have its Christ or Christs. As truly as was Jesus the Christ
                            of his day, so was Ann Lee the Christ of hers; inasmuch as her life, testimony, profession
                            and poiver of salvation were equal to her predecessor Christs. It is enough that the
                            "disciple be as her master and the servant, as her Lord." That "there will arise false
                            Christs" has been abundantly fulfilled— those making the profession, but wanting the life
                            and power of salvation. Mother Ann Lee satisfied her followers that she was a veritable
                            Saviour— the Christ of the second dispensation of Christianity—for there accompanied her
                            ministrations salvation from the sins of the world and the flesh. And till who believe in
                            this ministration, sufficiently to find deliverance from worldly sins, arc enabled to save
                            others', '¦'¦become sons and daughters of Ood"—Christs to the people—dispensers of the
                            gospel, which is "the power of God unto salvation." As in Jesus' day, he gave others "power
                            to be sons of God"—Christs— illustrations of saved men and women of that dispensation ; so
                            may we, by following his godly example be saved as he and his disciples were, and be Christs
                            unto the people now. Christ means anointed—simply, truly this and nothing more. And because
                            we know Jesus to have been the Christ, we would never intimate that he was other than an
                            elder brother of other Christs, who win the distinction in being saved from sin, by
                            following the life-practices of the elder Christ. Whoso will deny self, live purely, love
                            humanity as fully, and exalt character unto godliness as did Jesus, is also the Christ of
                            his or her day. * </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Just for a change" TEIform="index"/>JUST FOR A CHANGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">In view of the slanderous persecutions some of our cotemporaneous communists are
                                receiving; and of the grand, good openings these are making both for religious inquiries
                                and financial markets ; will not the N. Y. Times or some paper of equally large
                                circulation abuse the Shakers a little or a great deal? We believe it would be good for
                                a change ; as nearly all men arc •'speaking too well of us," and we are feeling the
                                "woe' of stagnation. Please, knights of the press, be more impartial, and let us a have
                                share of the apparently bitter dose. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obscenity" TEIform="index"/>OBSCENITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Let obscenity in all its features bo abolished. Let the moral tone of Society everywhere
                                be timed to a higher, holier key. But let not the campaign merely deal with obscenity in
                                literature ; let it begin with the lives and secret acts of every one. The present
                                excitement is very much of it bosh, being more in the interests of a false theology than
                                elss. This same crusade, would, if successful, seal the lips from the de- SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 247<pb n="248" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 348 THE SHAKBE MANIFESTO. livery of Shaker
                                testimony, and imprison and fine us for preaching against the lusts of the flesh and
                                world. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watkins convention" TEIform="index"/>THE WATKINS CONVENTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We were very kindly and respectfully treated at the Liberal League Convention. Our
                                addresses were listened to with much interest, and very many questions were asked
                                regardful of Shaker life and principles. But it wras very apparent, that the
                                Materialists were determined that neither Shakers nor Spiritualists should predominate
                                in influence there; and they therefore made efforts beyond the ordinary that Mate-
                                rialism should not be compassed. We were very happy and satisfied, however, that the
                                masses, by thousands, never accepted much of Materialism in preference to radical
                                Christianity or pure Shakerism. As at Watkins, so will these latter find a preference
                                whereever they may be diligently taught. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks" TEIform="index"/>"plain talks."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Another edition of this little work has been necessitated ; and through the generosity of
                                Elder H. L. Eades, who has thoroughly revised the same, it has become a stereotype work.
                                If there is any better pamphlet to circulate, we hope it will take precedence of ours ;
                                but if not, let this last, enlarged edition circulate as on angels' wings in abun-
                                dance. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harbinger of light" TEIform="index"/>"the harbinger of light."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">This Australian (Melbourne) monthly lately honored us by publishing, under the title of
                                "Shaker Christianity," the entire article of our Bro. Wm. H. Bussell upon "Christian
                                Culture." How silently the good work goes on ! and how very deeply the waters of hu-
                                manity are stirred by Shaker testimony ! How fraught with hope for the better life of
                                the world, as found by earnest seekers, far and near, in the simple pages of our
                                manifesto ! And yet there are those, so in love with the root of evil, that they live in
                                unrest, striving to make themselves and others believe that the shaker manifesto is a
                                non-essential or superfluity. Soon, such will pass away ; and we make all such welcome
                                to their rewards. And to those who are sensible of the grand work we are doing, we add
                                to their present, sufficient reward of "God bless," our sincere gratitude. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder F. W. E. at Watkins, New York" TEIform="index"/>ELDER F. W. E. AT WATKINS, N. Y.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We present Elder Evans' address at Watkins, N. Y. The Elder preferred that others should
                                be presented ; but having a little advantage just now, we use it, and -present his. We
                                may publish ours at another time, as it has been printed from direct reports elsewhere.
                                We would say however, that Elder Frederick largely elaborated upon and extended the
                                discourse as presented by us; but it is a valuable paper, and as such was duly
                                appreciated by his hearers.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anonymously" TEIform="index"/>Anonymously</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Why do people send us anonymous communications ? We put them into the Waste basket
                                without reading them; while our basket fills sufficiently soon without them. Please save
                                your time, temper, talents, ink, paper and stamps for better uses. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When a man dies, people ask,..." TEIform="index"/>When a man dies, people ask,...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When a man dies, people ask, "What property has he left behind Mm?" But the angels, as they
                            bend over his grave inquire, "What good deeds hast thou sent before thee?"</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Mahomet" TEIform="persName"/>Mahomet</byline></div2><pb n="249" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, seventh paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE.
                            Her work, her People, and their Critics. Seventh Paper.</head><p TEIform="p">While Ann Lee and Companions were yet in Massachusetts, in Ashfield, a curious meeting was
                            held. More than sixty sleighs, carrying more than six hundred people, met to hear their
                            testimony. Undaunted by past abuses, they opened the batteries of their testimonies against
                            fleshly lusts, which, as stated by an ear witness, "sounded like the roaring of many waters,
                            driven by mighty winds ; and so great were the operations of the spirit among the people,
                            that itseemed as though heaven and hell had engaged their forces in contention for the
                            mastery." The noise of this revival meeting was heard for seven miles ! The meeting was a
                            protracted one ; the people became hungry, and there was not food for so great a num- ber.
                            But all were requested to be seated, and each one partook of what bread and cheese there
                            were, until each declared having received a plenty. In these less credulous times, it will
                            be difficult for many to see that herein was the miracle of the loaves and fishes
                            reproduced; but those partaking thereof thought so. After this and similar meetings, the
                            persecuting spirit of their enemies was aroused beyond anything in the past. They would take
                            two or three of the brethren, tie them to trees, whip them until their backs were beaten to
                            a jelly, then disperse to escape legal proceedings. About these times some of the sisterhood
                            received cuts from whips and clubs, the scars from which they carried to their graves. A
                            tree to which one of the believers was tied and whipped, was then green and flour, ishing;
                            but it soon withered and died, and stood as a reminder of the incident a number of years.
                            Another of the brethren was knocked down with the butt of a whipstock, and falling as if
                            killed, again there was a fleeing from justice. After many powerful meetings and many scenes
                            of horrible persecutions in eastern Mass, the believers journeyed towards the west, and
                            reached Kichmond and Hancock. Under the inspiration of an elder of the Baptist church,
                            (named Valentine Rathbun, who led several mobs, and during one riot nearly killed his son
                            who stood in believers' defence,) there was much suffering. Besides being mobbed, the
                            Shakers were arrested on warrants for disturbing the peace, and for blasphemy. At one of
                            these trials the charge of blasphemy was quashed; but they were fined twenty dollars for
                            disturbance, and ordered to leave the State. This latter they would not do. As a consequence
                            some were sent to jail, refusing to give bonds. On the 23 of Aug. 1783 Mother Ann and her
                            traveling companions arrived for the first time at New Lebanon, N. Y. stopping at John
                            Bishop's. Here began a series of powerful meetings; and as the believers would go from house
                            to house large crowds would follow, even for miles, singing, shouting and clapping their
                            hands, so great was their joy ! Yet here, wicked mobs congregated to disturb their religious
                            zeal. At one of these meetings, a company of Indians assembled. William Lee was moved upon
                            by the spirit to speak to them in their tongue. The Indians understood and answered him;
                            being struck with wonder at his power of speech. Many curious instances are told us,
                            happening in those days, which require considerable credulity to accept; but that they were
                            true, any amount of evidence could be obtained. As instances : John Bishop says : "I took
                            the horses of the believers, nearly forty of them and put them in my cow pasture; I thought
                            my feed would soon be gone. The horses with my four cows remained in about ten acres for two
                            days; yet it remained as fresh and green as if no hoof had been into it for a week! A number
                            of pails of milk had been served to the multitude to drink; yet my family made more butter
                            that week than any other during the season! These things, which in nature appeared
                            impossible, I felt confident were effected by the same power as fed the multitudes with the
                            five loaves and two fishes." Nathan Farrington permitted meetings to be held in a meadow
                            near his house. The neighbors called him a fool for permitting the Shakers to ruin his
                            grass. Nathan says : "In <pb n="250" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>a short time the grass grew and flourished in
                            the circle where the meetings were held, so that it was much more abundant there than in any
                            other part of the field; the difference being easily observed as far as the meadow could be
                            seen, to the great astonishment of all unbelieving neighbors." At one of these Shaker
                            meetings, there came a company of young men and women to ridicule the proceedings. When the
                            Shakers began to dance they began to laugh loudly, and to ask: "Do you dance to worship
                            God?" "Yea," answered one of the brethren, "and you may dance too." At this, these carnally
                            minded young people joined in. Soon, however they found they could not stop when they wished
                            to. The head dresses of the young women flew off in every direction, while the young men
                            were thoroughly mortified, and all were glad to get quietly away as 1100n as they could.
                            Such scenes and circumstances were not uncommon; and happening amid great persecutions,
                            encouraged the believers to feci that God was with them. Our next paper will begin with the
                            narration of proceedings, happening upon ground where the Church building at Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y. now stands. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Worldly conformity" TEIform="index"/>WORLDLY CONFORMITY. </head><p TEIform="p">[The fqllowing contribution is timely, though we are unable to give the author's name.
                            Plainness of dress, and modesty, and economy are really Christian distinctions. We do not,
                            personally, believe in dressing so as to excite undue attention to our dress because of its
                            uncouthness; nor to excite ridicule by its antique cut or color. If there is any religion in
                            dress, language or behavior, it is in their simplicity, plainness and cleanliness: certainly
                            there is none in their oddity. Have we looked at this subject with propriety? nn.] The
                            Church will soon be under the necessity of returning to the old habits of plain dress, in
                            order to distinguish her members from the people of the world. Some external badge will soon
                            be required. The disposition, the natural expression of character, the general tone of the
                            conduct, ought to plainly indicate the follower of Christ j and they always do when the
                            Christly spirit has supremacy in the soul. But the absence of this inner-life force and the
                            fruits of the Spirit in the character, puzzles tho most observant and calculating to know
                            who is a Christian and who is not. Some Christians label themselves with verbal professions,
                            and imagine that this boastful advertisement of their piety will be a sufficient guarantee
                            to the world of their genuineness. But alas! the profession challenges inspection of
                            conduct, and the heart and the tongue do not always agree. The deficiency in character is
                            supposed to be supplemented by profession j but blossoms can never take the place of fruit
                            to hungry men. "What do you more than others?" was the test of a disciple by our Lord.
                            Sinners can hate, publicans can love those who love them, men generally can do acts of
                            kindness when they expect returns j but "I say unto you, Love your enemies, do [load to them
                            that hate you, and pray for them which despitefully usc you." "What do you more than
                            others?" The world is ready to sec and must admire Christian acts. As soon would men curse
                            flowers, as censure or condemn self-sacrificing and Christian deeds. They have a winning and
                            commanding power, and claim the respect of even tho wicked, and the admiration of all.
                            Character and conduct, thc fountain and streams of Christian lifc, arc the truo marks of a
                            disciple. He needs no other badge, no external ensign, 110 advertising of his virtues-his
                            spirit and <pb n="251" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/>the tone of his conduct are sufficiently convincing. But
                            alas! where do we sec this difference in character and conduct? The professing Christian,
                            in his love and eagerness for money-making, and the tenacity with which he holds earthly
                            possessions, does not look like "a pilgrim of earth" journeying to heaven. He carries the
                            world on his back and the cross in his hand. Silly mortal! The burden impedes his progress,
                            and then he must throw off the heavy load before he can enter the narrow way that leads to
                            life. We see the same similarity between the church and the world in the character of their
                            pleasures. The Christian is presumed to find his chief delights in Christian service, the
                            worship of God, and helping his fellow-men into the pool of healing; but this' is not the
                            case. Sabbath devotion is a duty, and worldly amusements a delight. The church is neglected
                            for the pleasure of attending the opcra and theatre. Not to enter in a discussion of the
                            sinfulness of such conduct, to say the least, this tendency of the lite shows whcre the
                            heart is, and what kind of food best suits these world- 'ly church members, If a man's
                            enjoyment and chief delight is not in Christian service, he does not love Christ supremely,
                            If he is not living for heaven, and endeavoring to become more and more like his Master, he
                            has not realized the resurrecting power of Christ in his soul. When a soul is converted, a
                            new spirit is put within man, with new ufllnitics and tendencies, and he dies to sin find
                            lives unto God. He renounces all criminal and forbidden pleasures. This world loses his
                            heart, he lives for heaven, and knows no au- thority but that of Christ. Woddly conformity
                            is like seeking like. Tendencies are signs of character. Tho true christian is not at home
                            in this world. He is seeking conformity to Christ and meetness for heaven. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the children" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="story" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter IX" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP.IX</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Leaving our kind native friends at Affraito, we went to Matear, our future home whilo
                                staying at Eimeo. Being here a short time, our friend James Martin, with Yankee
                                ingenuity, cut a lot of sapling Burow-a wood resembling our Bass. Stripping off the
                                bark, and cutting them tho right length, placed them upright and close together on all
                                sides of our house. This made us a house good enough for the climate, which is never
                                cold ; but was needed as protection for our household goods, and clothing, from the
                                ravages of the natives .and pigs. While my three companions were at work on the house, I
                                went to the opposite side of the island to buy some shoes for the family of our
                                employer; should' there he any in the English whale ship, that was anchored in the
                                harbor. This harbor was nearly opposite to Matear, the place where we were then living.
                                The traveling was pleasant, for the Broom road, is a path about three or four feet wide,
                                built and supported by the government. Natives who in any way violated the laws, were
                                punished by making a certain number of fathoms of this road. Deserters from ships were
                                required to mate from twenty to fifty fathoms, whereby they gained a right to live in
                                Queen Pomare's Dominion. My brother and I escaped this penalty, by coming to Her
                                Gracious Majesty's Queendom, in <pb n="252" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> a vessel belonging to the
                                American Consul. The road leading to the harbor, was skirted much of the way with Guava*
                                bushes, bearing plentifully. Limes were also in abundance, and with some sugar I could
                                have prepared an excellent antiscorbutic drink. From the many brooks that crossed thi
                                Broom road, there issued cool and refreshing water from the mountains. I reached Cook's
                                bay at noon, and had the pleasure of seeing Chief Tirapar, with whom I was acquainted,
                                having seen him at Parpatie. He was at Cook's bay with a party of native men and women,
                                having a feast; they gave me food, which was very acceptable after my long walk. Tirapar
                                very kindly sent one of his men to escort me through the woods, shortening the distance
                                about one third. When I reached Parpatie, I met a middle aged native, who recognized me
                                as one of the sailors, with whom he had fought on the mountain three years previous. To
                                explain this I would say, that one of my shipmates, Francis Lyons, of Spencer, Mass, and
                                my- self, deserted from the ship Phenix, which had anchored at the place two different
                                times, during our voyage. After we left for the mountains, the ship went to sea. We came
                                down and lived in Parpatie for a short time. When our vessel came back, taking us by
                                suprise, we fled to the mountains, the natives following; and a pretty severe struggle
                                succeeded in capturing us. We were marched to the beach where our boat was waiting to
                                take us on board. The price at the Society islands, was eight dollars for every deserter
                                captured. When the crew of the Phenix were paid off at New London, Conn, sixteen dollars
                                were taken from our wages. This capturing of deserters, was the work of English
                                missionaries. The laws that governed these people were framed by them. The native I met
                                that afternoon, was pleased to see me, and talked of the fight as *The Guava is a fruit,
                                somewhat resembling a pear in shape. The flesh is of a reddish color, and slightly acid.
                                The bush or shrub grows from 4 to 15 feet in height. It is a native of Tropical America
                                and was planted on the island, where it grows with wonderful luxuriance. though it had
                                been something amusing; notwithstanding he was wounded quite seriously at the time. It
                                was a convincing proof that they are an amiable, gentle race, quite equal to the
                                description given by Captain Cook, on his first visit to these islands. The amount of
                                money received by some of the natives, for the help rendered at the capture, was fifty
                                cents: some had more. I think the party was thirty strong, and it took them several
                                hours to get us. They would not have succeeded, had it not been for the tall grass which
                                covered the ground. This, they set on fire, and we were forced by the flames, from our
                                strong-hold on the top of the mountain. As we were unarmed, they overpowered us. We
                                found two ships at anchor at Parpatie, one an English whaler; the other, the John Adams
                                of Nantucket, which I had seen in my first voyage at this harbor. Her crew were mostly
                                Portuguese from the Azores, and I received the impression, that there had been some
                                wrong perpetrated with her officers. The captain and mate had been forced to leave the
                                ship by a strange sickness, and the crew were suspicious of the Portuguese steward.
                                Going aboard the English whaler, to see about the purchases, I found they had not the
                                kind of goods my employer wished; so going ashore and walking a short distance, I came
                                very unexpectedly upon the house of a Welsh carpenter, with whom I had formed an
                                acquaintance during my short stay at Parpatie. He seem pleased to see me and told bis
                                companion who I was, by describing in native style, our battle on the mountain. She
                                gazed at him, as he described with gestures, the attack of the natives upon our little
                                strong-hold, telling her of the flying stones, the sweeping flames, and picturing out n
                                glowing colors the whole affair. He had also been a deserter and was persued in like
                                manner, and overtaken by one native. He gave his coat as the price of his iberty. At
                                first he was badly treated by the natives, but now seemed quite at home. fie had made
                                several very fine boats, which lad outstripped others that were racing in ;he bay.
                                MANIFESTO. 325S<pb n="253" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 353 Leaving my friend the carpenter, I
                                went to the house of a chief, to whom I presented a message from a woman who was chief
                                in Affraito. He said it was from Queen Pomare to the chief of the Parmotu Natives. The
                                Parmotuan seemed much disturbed, when informed that the Queen wanted him to take his
                                people to the other side of the island at Affraito. Their canoes were curiously made,
                                being constructed of pieces of the Bread-fruit tree, sewed together. In this way they
                                make large canoes, in which they venture, out of sight of land. From the Parmotu group,
                                to Tahiti, i^ a very long distance to go in such a rudely constructed vessel. I was very
                                kindly entertained by the chief and his family. This I think was due to the message I
                                had brought from the Chief's wife at Affraito. They had built a new house,— evidently
                                trying to imitate the missionary buildings. The house was unfinished, rough boards being
                                laid for a floor. In one corner was a rude attempt at a bedstead. To them it was a
                                foreign luxury, kept more for show than use. They invited me to occupy it while the
                                family made themselves comfortable on mats placed on the ground in their native hut,
                                which they occupied in preference to their frame house. In the morning the chief women
                                seemed very curious to know how I liked the bed— or rather bedstead—for there was
                                nothing but mats spread upon boards, with curtains drawn around the rude affair; yet I
                                slept well being young and hardy. The Mosquitoes did not trouble me. On my return to
                                Matear, I went across the Island passing through the very gap in the mountains where
                                Francis Lyons, my good shipmate, and I, had watched our ship getunder weigh and go to
                                sea. We had been waiting ten days in these very mountains, with nothing to eat except a
                                few cocoa-nuts and a kind of wild plaintain much sought after by the natives. We had
                                ample time during our waiting for the departure of our ship, to examine this lofty gap
                                in the mountains. There were two level spots of noigreat extent that appeared to have
                                be'en built up or terraced at some remote time. The one on which our little shelter was
                                built, was the lowest, the other was about ten or twelve feet higher, and was reached by
                                broad steps cut into the rock. I have no means of knowing what use these terraces were,
                                to the natives who had inhabited the interior of the island. That it had once been very
                                populous I have no doubt, from the numerous slabs of stone placed in squares to form the
                                outline of the walls of native houses. Within some of these en- closures I saw large
                                cocoa-nut trees growing. On the highest part of the gap in the mountain over which my
                                path lay wild sugarcane was growing, the stalk about one half inch in diameter. In the
                                valley below where it was cultivated, it grew ten or twelve feet high, and two or more
                                inches in diameter. (to be continued.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fault finding" TEIform="index"/>Fault Finding</head><p TEIform="p">In speaking of a person's faults Pray don't forget your own ; Remember, those with houses
                                of glass ¦ Should never throw a stone. If we have nothing else to do, Then talk of those
                                who sin, 'Tis better we commence at home, And from that point begin. We have no right to
                                judge a man, Until he's fairly tried; Should we not like his company, We know the world
                                is wide. Some may have faults, and who has not? The old as well as young, Perhaps we
                                may, for all we know, Have fifty to their one. I'll tell you of a better plan, And find
                                it works full well; To try your own defects to cure, Ere other's faults you tell. And
                                though I sometimes hope to be No worse than some I know, My own short-comings bid me let
                                The faults of others go.<pb n="254" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER Now let us all, when we begin,
                                To slander friend or foe, Think of the harm one word may do, To those we little know.
                                Remember curses chicken-like, Sometimes to roost, come home. Don't speak of other's
                                faults until You have none of your own.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to treat scandal" TEIform="index"/>How to Treat Scandal</head><p TEIform="p">What "they say" is beneath your ziotice. What's the use of lying awake of nights with the
                                unkind remark of some false friend running through your brain like forked lightning?
                                What's the.use of getting into a worry and fret ovdr gossip that has been set afloat to
                                your' disadvantage by some meddlesome busy-body who has more time than character. These
                                things cannot possibly injure you, unless, you take notice of them, and in combating
                                them you give them character and standing. If what is said about you is true, set
                                yourself right at once; if it is false, let it go for what it will until it dies of
                                inherent weakness. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Better way" TEIform="index"/>The Better Way</head><p TEIform="p">Not often that we need to repent of having said too little. Tears and bitterness of- ten
                                because we said too much. Never regret our patience under insult and scorn, but sorrow
                                oft because of our haste and resentment. No heart-breaking and pining because we treated
                                our fellow-man with love and respect, but plenty of poverty within because of our
                                rudeness. No mourning because we helped to care for the sick, and eased their dying
                                moments, but abundance of anguish because we did too little. No "leanness of soul"
                                because we helped our poor brother, and sympathized with him in his troubles, but plenty
                                of "poverty of heart" because of our selfishness. On all sides, on every hand, regrets
                                and sorrows strike us because we did not as the Master teaches. AVill we turn just where
                                He turned, walk as He walked, be rich in love and good works, or will we go on in the
                                ways of the world and suffer the torments of the damned?</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small means" TEIform="index"/>Small Means</head><p TEIform="p">The power of money is, on the whole, overestimated. The greatest things which have been
                                done for the world have not been accomplished by rich men, nor by subscription lists,
                                but by men generally of small pecuniary means. The greatest thinkers, discoverers,
                                inventors and artists have been men of moderate wealth, many of them little raised above
                                the condition of manual laborers, in point of worldly circumstances. And it will always
                                be so. Riches are oftener an impediment than a stimulus to action, and in ¦many cases
                                they are quite as much a misfort{ une as a blessing. The youth who inherits wealth is
                                apt to have life made too easy for him, and he soon grows sated with it, because he has
                                nothing t left to desire. Having no special object to t struggle for, he finds time hang
                                heavy on his 3 hands ; remains morally and mentally asleep j and his position in society
                                is often no higher than that of a polypus over which the tide floats.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian consistency" TEIform="index"/>Christian Consistency</head><p TEIform="p">To hold high principles, and live on low ones, is Christian inconsistency. We are all
                                more or less inconsistent. There is no man whose practice is not worse than his profes-
                                sion, no one who does not live below his own standard. But absolute inconsistency is
                                when a man's life, taken as a whole, is opposition to his acknowledged views and
                                principles, if a man says that it is more blessed to give, than receive, and is forever
                                receiving, scarcely ever giving, he is inconsistent. If he professes that to please God
                                is the only thing worth living for, and his plans and aims and contrivances are most to
                                please men, he is inconsistent.—The Guide. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hopeful minister says he has no doubt..." TEIform="index"/>Hopeful minister says he has no doubt...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A hopeful minister says he has no doubt that the time will come when the members of a church
                            choir will behave just as well as other folks.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="255" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science" TEIform="index"/>SCIENTIFIC</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tea as a poison" TEIform="index"/>Tea as a Poison</head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Chemistry asserts tea is not the simple, harmless, beverage that is
                                generally supposed; but that its effects, in their character, may rightly claim to be
                                classed with those of tobacco and alcohol. The paper also adds : "Many disorders of the
                                nervous system are the direct result of excessive tea drinking.—Tea is a 'narcotic
                                poison;' its essential principle, theine.. is allied in composition with such poison as
                                strychnine and morphine. It first excites the nervous system and then exhausts it.
                                Experiments show that both in man and other animals, it impairs power in the lower
                                extremities; so that it affects the 'understanding' in a double sense—literally as well
                                as figuratively. It is not the harmless exhilarant it is supposed to be but a powerful
                                agent whose effects are often serious." </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Disinfecting foul places" TEIform="index"/>Disinfecting Foul Places</head><p TEIform="p">The Boston Scientific News calls attention to the importance at this season of getting
                                rid of all vile smells about dwellings, and make this practical suggestion: The article
                                commonly used to disinfect foul places is chloride of lime, but in reality it is not of
                                much value. It may, and generally does, remove bad smells, but the cause still remains,
                                as the chloride simply destroys the gaseous emanations. The much advertised
                                disinfectants are usually catchpenny nostrums and unworthy of notice. One of the very
                                best known disinfectants is old-fashioned "copperas," or sulphate of iron, which can be
                                had very cheap. A barrel of copperas would weigh probably 300 pounds, and can be
                                purchased at wholesale price at a cent and a half per pound. And every family ought,
                                especially in warm weather, to have a supply of it on hand. A couple of handfuls of
                                copperas thrown into a bucket of water will soon dissolve, and it can then be used
                                freely, and is a valuable disinfectant. The best plan is to fill a half barrel or keg
                                with water, and suspend within it a moderate sized basket full of copperas. In this way
                                it dissolves more rap idly than when thrown to the bottom of the wooden vessel, and thus
                                a supply is always at hand ready for use.—Boston Courier. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every time a man rides on a street car..." TEIform="index"/>Every time a man rides on a street car...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every time a man rides on a street car he takes five bricks from the house he might have
                                in the future. Every time his wife wants a real stylish new hat it takes 500 bricks and
                                a good share of the foundation walls.—Detroit Free Press.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A strong glue is produced..." TEIform="index"/>A strong glue is produced...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A strong glue is produced by adding powdered chalk to common glue. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Josh Billings remarks..." TEIform="index"/>Josh Billings remarks...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Josh Billings remarks : "Sum people wo'nt beleeve enny thing they kant prove; the things
                                I can't prove are the very things I be- leeve the most." </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="By an ingenious instrument..." TEIform="index"/>By an ingenious instrument...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">By an ingenious instrument the officers of the Royal Observatory at Greenwich, England,
                                have been able to register the exact number of hours of sunshine during the last year.
                                In the twelve months ending with the 10th of February the sun was above the horizon at
                                London 4,454 hours, but the amount of sunshine during that time was only 1,286.1 hours.
                            </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS FOR THE TIMES</head><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker Manifesto (Shakers, New York) has made its appearance..." TEIform="index"/>The Shaker Manifesto (Shakers, New York) has made its appearance...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Shaker Manifesto (Shakers, N. Y.) has made its appearance in this village. As a guide
                                to peace on earth and goodwill among men, the pamphlet is pre-eminently the book for the
                                times.—Saratoga Co., Standard. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What strong drink does" TEIform="index"/>"what strong drink does."</head><p TEIform="p">It costs $1,000,000,000 annually in money. It makes 50 per cent of our insane. It makes
                                65 per cent of our paupers. It is the direct cause of 75 per cent of the murders
                                committed. It makes 80 per cent of our criminals. It sends forth 95 per cent of our
                                vicious youth. It sends one every six minutes into a drunkard's grave, or, 87,600 every
                                year. In our own happy or unhappy America, in this enlightened 19th century, facts and
                                    MANIFESTO.<pb n="256" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> TH.IG SHAKER figures show that 60.000 lives are
                                annually destroyed by means of intoxicating drink, 4, €00 commit suicide, and 200,000
                                orphans are made. The crimes resulting from the use of intoxicating drink cost the
                                country annually $40, 000,000 and send to prison 100,000 persons. New York City spends
                                annually f 70.000,0 00 for strong drink and only $3,000,000 for public education. In the
                                State of New York there are 21,242 licensed dram-shops, and perhaps one-fourth that
                                number more not licensed, and only 7,000 churches. In the State of Pennsylvania
                                $83,487,000 is annually spent for strong drink, and only $6,000,000 for public
                                education. In the United States over 400,000 more men are engaged in the liquor business
                                than in preaching the gospel and teaching the youth. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To live in a perfect world would be easy..." TEIform="index"/>To live in a perfect world would be easy...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To live in a perfect world would be easy. The problem is how to live in this world, and
                                not be one of it; how to participate in its labors and cares, and not contract its taint
                                of moral wrong. . The problem can be solved only in the light of Christianity, which
                                shows us how to live in, and yet above the world; how to be citizens of Heaven and yet
                                sojourners on earth; how to retain a devout temper of mind amid the pressures of worldly
                                duty and difficulties. The Christian restores harmony by bringing Heaven down to earth.—
                                ZiorCs Herald. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The truths that we least wish to hear..." TEIform="index"/>The truths that we least wish to hear...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The truths that we least wish to hear are those which it is most to our advantage to
                                know.—Rural New Yorker. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An officer of the Brooklyn Police force..." TEIform="index"/>An officer of the Brooklyn Police force...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">An officer of the Brooklyn Police was lately dismissed the force for lying. If judgment
                                for lying begins at station houses in Brooklyn, when will it reach the pulpit? </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Holy liberty; but liberty in service..." TEIform="index"/>Holy liberty; but liberty in service...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Holy liberty; but liberty in service, not from service. Not liberty to choose and refuse,
                                but holy liberty in obedience. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Messrs. Moody and Sankey are expected" TEIform="index"/>Messrs. Moody and Sankey are expected
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Messrs. Moody and Sankey are expected to labor in Albany during the fall and winter. Rev.
                                Dr. Barbour of Yale College is not an admirer of the Sankey songs He thinks it is a
                                prancing style of music, and says "men and women go dancing, now, as it were, into the
                                kingdom of Heaven." </p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some men die not..." TEIform="index"/>Some men die not...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some men die not; the grave's abyss Is never deep enough to hide Their grandest acts,
                                whose light shines on Like beacons on a mountain side. The deep pulsations of their
                                lives Throb on, and on, through ages vast, As ceaseless as a river's flow, And Time and
                                Death's eclipse outlast. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men must not be asked in the name..." TEIform="index"/>Men must not be asked in the name...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Men must not be asked in the name of so holy a sentiment as religion to give up reason,
                                and good sense, and every feeling of justice, and to lie down and be spit upon and
                                trampled in the dirt. They wo'nt do it, and I am glad of it.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Rev. Dr. Thomas. </byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give him a lift" TEIform="index"/>Give Him A Lift</head><p TEIform="p">Give him a lift! do'nt kneel in prayer, Nor moralize with his despair; The man is down,
                                and his great need Is ready help, not prayer nor creed. 'Tis time when the wounds are
                                washed and healed, That the inward motives be revealed; But now, whate'er the spirit be,
                                Mere words are but a mockery. One grain of aid just now is more To him than tomes of
                                saintly lore : Pray, if you must, in your heart; But give him a lift, give him a start
                                The world is full of good advice, Of prayer, and praise, and preaching nice ; But the
                                generous souls who aid mankind Are scarce as gold, and hard to find. Give like a
                                Christian—speak in deeds ; A noble life's the best of creeds ; And he shall wear a royal
                                crown Who gives them a lift when they are down! </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alas! if the principles are not within us..." TEIform="index"/>Alas! if the principles are not within us...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Alas! if the principles are not within us, the height of station and worldly grandeur will as
                            soon add a cubit to a man's stature as to his happiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Sterne" TEIform="persName"/>Sterne</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="257" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Land measurement" TEIform="index"/>Land Measurement</head><p TEIform="p">—In order that the farmer should keep an account with his field, it is first necessary
                                that he should ascertain its area. If he provide himself with a straight, stiff pole one
                                rod long and notched into yards, he will be able to ascertain the area as follows: If
                                the sides of the field are all parallel, multiply its length in rods and divide by
                                160—the quotient will be the number of acres in the field. Second, if the field is
                                triangular in shape multiply the longest side in rods by the greatest width in rods, and
                                divide half the product by 160, and you will get the area in acres. Third, when the
                                sides of the field are irregular and unequal ones, run a line from one extreme corner to
                                the other, and then find the area of the two triangles as above, and add them together.
                                This will give you the number of acres in the whole field. Fields, no matter how ir-
                                regular, may be measured in this way by dividing them into triangles.—Tournat of Ag-
                                ricultu 'e. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In speaking of the value of bone-dust..." TEIform="index"/>In speaking of the value of bone-dust...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">—In speaking of the value of bone-dust as a manure, Prof. Gray says that one bushel to a
                                load of yard manure increases its value—as determined by experiment—one half; and he
                                estimates that it is eight or ten times as valuable as cow-dung. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our public roads" TEIform="index"/>Our Public Roads</head><p TEIform="p">—Keep the roadsides clear of noxious weeds that would otherwise scatter their seeds in
                                pastures and cornfields. Mow the grass twice in the season for hay, if it cannot be done
                                oftener. Plant trees along the boundaries, or so far within them as to give space for a
                                side-walk. The trees should be mostly two or three rods apart, in order that their forms
                                may become fully rounded and developed as they grow old. In bleak and windy places,
                                plant Norway spruce and other evergreens nearer together, or ten or twelve feet apart,
                                on the windward side, for purposes of shelter and to prevent snow drifts. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bloated cattle can quickly be relieved..." TEIform="index"/>Bloated cattle can quickly be relieved...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bloated cattle can be quickly relieved by the insertion in the moiith of a straw rope of
                                good size, tying it over the head. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A correspondent says a tea..." TEIform="index"/>A correspondent says a tea...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent says a tea made of cayenne pepper, used twice a day, will kill cabbage
                                worms.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is estimated that 45.000.000 eggs..." TEIform="index"/>It is estimated that 45.000.000 eggs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is estimated that 45.000.000 eggs are consumed every day in the United States. New
                                York alone consumes 40.000.000 dozen annually. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every farmer should use a part..." TEIform="index"/>Every farmer should use a part...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Every farmer should use a part of his garden as an experimental plot. In no waycan he so
                                advance his own interests and promote the agricultural advantage of the country. </p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A current paragraph informs us..." TEIform="index"/>A current paragraph informs us...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A current paragrapli informs us that a Frenchman accidentally covered up some eggs with
                                earth in September, and by accident discovered them the following Spring, "as fresh as
                                if just laid, and fit for either eating or setting." </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We have made two valuable discoveries..." TEIform="index"/>We have made two valuable discoveries...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We have made two valuable discoveries this season : 1, that cuttings of grapes, currants,
                                etc. succeed in growing best, when shaded by a little straw—sufficient to cover their
                                tops. 2, That the leaves of the common helebore being drenched with boiling water, make
                                a decoction, which being sprinkled on bushes covered with worms, proves sure death to
                                them, while being much safer to use than the powdered helebore. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North Union, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>North Union, Ohio</head><p TEIform="p">At the Middle family, a spacious barn has been built this season, the dimensions of which
                                are 80 ft. long; 38 ft. wide, well lighted on every side with glass windows and a
                                prominent observatory in the center for ventilation. It stands about 40 rods west of the
                                dwelling house. This barn was much needed and will be an honor and credit to the family
                                and society. Crops are good.—Fruits in abundance. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><pb n="258" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parched rice" TEIform="index"/>Parched Rice</head><p TEIform="p">— We have used parched rice in hot weather to check bowel complaints, and find it very
                                effectual. • Parch till well done, and then boil it in water for half an hour. Eat then
                                slowly, and it will check the most violent diarrhoea. It is a good diet with boiled
                                milk, in case of flux. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lady correspondent from Canterbury writes as follows..." TEIform="index"/>Lady correspondent from Canterbury writes as follows...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A lady correspondent from Canterbury writes as follows concerning churning in the
                                winter-time : "Scald the cream before churning, and there will be no difficulty in
                                bringing the butter. It makes the butter sweeter, for it takes away the bitterness which
                                is apt to pervade winter butter."—The People. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement for petroleum lamps" TEIform="index"/>Cement for Petroleum Lamps.</head><p TEIform="p">—A cement particularly adapted for attaching the brass works to petroleum lamps is made
                                by boiling three parts resin with one part of caustic soda and five of water. The
                                composition is then mixed with half its weight of plaster of Paris. It sets firmly in
                                half to three quarters of an hour. It is said to be of great adhesive power, not
                                permeable to petroleum, a low conductor of heat, and but superficially attacked by hot
                                water. Zinc white, white lead, or precipitated chalk may be substituted for plaster, but
                                hardens more slowly. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To get rid of foreign bodies in the throat" TEIform="index"/>To Get Rid of Foreign Bodies
                                in the Throat.</head><p TEIform="p">—A British naval surgeon, Dr. Beveridge, states that for foreign bodies in the throat,
                                such as pieces of meat, etc, a simple mode of relief is to blow forcibly into the ear.
                                This excites powerful reflex action, during which the foreign body is expelled from the
                                trachea. The plan is so -easy of execution that, if there is anything in it, it ought to
                                be generally known and applied. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Apple custard pie—the nicest pie ever eaten" TEIform="index"/>Apple Custard Pie—The
                                nicest Pie ever Eaten</head><p TEIform="p">—This recipe is hardly in season, but our readers can keep it for reference when needed.
                                Peel sour apples and stew until soft and not much water left in them; then rub them
                                through a cullender; beat three eggs for each pie to be baked, and put in at the rate of
                                one cup of butter and one of sugar for three pies; season with nutmeg. One egg for each
                                pie will do very well, but the amount of sugar must be governed somewhat by the acidity
                                of the apples. Bake as pumpkin pies, which they resemble in appearance. Dried 'apples
                                are very nice by making them a little more juicy. You can frost them, and return them to
                                the oven for a few moments, which will improve their appearance. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For headache" TEIform="index"/>For Headache.</head><p TEIform="p">—Put a handful of salt into a quart of water, add one ounce of spirits of hartshorn, and
                                half an ounce of camphorated spirits of wine, Put them quickly into a bottle and cork
                                tightly to prevent the escape of the spirit. Soak a piece of rag with the mixture and
                                apply it to the head; wet the rag afresh as soon as it gets heated. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To fasten labels to tin" TEIform="index"/>To Fasten Labels to Tin.</head><p TEIform="p">—Put a teaspoonful of brown sugar into a quart of paste, and it will fasten labels as
                                securely to tin cans as to wood. Housekeepers may save themselves much annoyance in the
                                loss of labels from their fruit cans when putting up their own fruit, by remembering
                                this. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of the simplest remedies for neuralgia..." TEIform="index"/>One of the simplest remedies for neuralgia...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">One of the simplest remedies for neuralgia, is essence of peppermint. Bathe the part
                                affected, keeping the hand over it. It will burn and draw, but not blister. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jones, Phebe Ann" TEIform="index"/>Phebe Ann Jones
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt, Lebanon, N. Y. Aug. 13, <persName reg="Jones, Phebe Ann" TEIform="persName">Phebe Ann
                                Jones,</persName> aged 67 years. "Made perfect through sufferings."</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patterson, Della" TEIform="index"/>Della Patterson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shirley, Mass. August 81, <persName reg="Patterson, Della" TEIform="persName">Della Pat-
                                terson,</persName> aged 14 years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Banks, Nelson" TEIform="index"/>Nelson Banks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, NY. Aug. 19, <persName reg="Banks, Nelson" TEIform="persName">Nelson Banks</persName> aged
                                78 years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morris, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane Morris
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. July 12, <persName reg="Morris, Jane" TEIform="persName">Jane Morris,</persName> aged
                                67 j'ears and 10 months. </p></div3><pb n="259" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no death: in memory of Phebe Ann Jones" TEIform="index"/>THERE IS NO DEATH. In
                                Memory of Phebe Ann Jones</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia" TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA CALVER</byline><p TEIform="p">"There is no death," a wiser poet said, Than those who deem this changing life of ours A
                                dying one. 'Tis but uncultured thought, That fastens terror to the sure decline Of
                                mortal life. The blossom falls, and we Eejoice that soon perfected fruit comes forth;
                                The real successor of the fragile flower. And e'en these ripened treasures are but
                                forms, That hold the living germ, the deathless seed, Which in its turn, in earth's cold
                                bosom hides, New life to start. And thus from year to year, From age to age 'tis life
                                increasing life. O friends, Our sister is not dead, nor e'en may we As sleeping think of
                                her; that casket which, Hath long unworthy been to hold so pure, So fair a jewel of the
                                heaven-wrought type, Unclasps its rusted lock, and angels take The sparkling treasure to
                                its home above. Dear sister we have loved thee long, and fain With sweet affection's
                                cord would hold thee here, To lustre add, where oft earth's leaden clouds Too sombre
                                are. Thy cheerful spirit was A beam of light; which seemed astray from heaven s Own
                                fair, effulgent radiance. And O, Thy spotless, pure and virgin life, will leave Its
                                regal worth, enstamped upon the hearts Of all within the radius of thy light. O tell us,
                                can a richer treasure pass From earth to heaven, than an immortal soul, Unblemish'd,
                                pure and snowy white? 'Tvvould seem That angels e'en would pause with lowered wings In
                                humble reverence ere they bear away A gift so rare. But sister dear, we will not think
                                of thee, As gone from home and friends, or buried deep Within the damp of earth; but
                                will rejoice To know, that now untrammeled, you can flit Among thy earth-life friends,
                                and tell us how, In spirit life you found that endless bloom, Which faith and hope, and
                                love, and charity Have given thee Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><p TEIform="p">We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory
                            indeed, Being among "the wonders in this age" of machinery. Their utility and expedition in
                            business should be expe. rienced by all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of wood
                            variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or rely on the
                            metal ones offered us by Washburn, Moen Co. We are at a loss to speak as yet, of the best
                            Wateb Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the firms of Leffel &amp; Co. and N. F.
                            Burnham, who enter into friendly competition in our columns, are both most honorable. We
                            find Stinson and Co. very honorable in their dealing. Try them. We hope "everybody and his
                            neighbor" will send us six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for two copies
                            post paid. It is a pretty book. Please procure it and present it to your friend. We are able
                            to speak of the various agricultural implements of Wheeler &amp; Melick Co., and of
                            Westinghouse manufacture. We have tested their Thresoers and Powers for years, and found
                            them unexcelled. We would call especial attention to the new advertisement of K. F. Burnham.
                            As enterprise is ever praiseworthy when applied as they apply it, let every one lend this
                            firm a token of praise. If any can do better for the furnishing of Dry Goods, etc. than can
                            be done at Wm. M. Whitney &amp; Co., we would be pleased to hear from such party. Take
                            choice and choose soon from among the most beautiful musical instruments advertised in our
                            col- umns. Quite a number of families are the happier to-day for taking our advice, and
                            buying their Organs and Pianos of-------well "read and you will know.' D. II. Fonda, the
                            most enterprising of Druggists, etc. can be relied upon by parties, near by or distant, who
                            are in want of anything in his line, wholesale and retail. Try him, prove him. Any parties
                            who would learn how we make such good, "gilt-edged" butter, must read an article entitled "
                            Oilt-Edged Butter Maker'." Gillott's Pens are unequaled by any other steel pen; and we deem
                            his No. 332 equal in every thing but wear, to the best gold pen. Get Gillott's Pens. We
                            would call attention to a new paper called " The Sword and Shield," Dubuque, Iowa. Its
                            purpose in life is to fight for the Lord and defend the faith deliv- ered to the saints. It
                            is a beautiful and interesting monthly. We hope it will do as it says, and not step to
                            pander to the unholy desires of the people. Too many are doing this and the world would be
                            the better without them. We wish it success in every good endeavor. </p></div2><pb n="260" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ angels" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST ANGELS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W., Elder" TEIform="persName"/>Elder F. W. EvANS</byline><p TEIform="p">1. My heart is in the Spirit world; My 2. Years follow years, the centuries pass, And 3.
                            Then O my soul immortal, thou Shalt 4. They sing to us in accents sweet, The 5. "New
                            earth and heavens are coming up, The soul thus nev mu old is roaming there; 1 dwell a mid
                            the earth ages roll. Unnumbered figures er, never die, While truth to feed thee sic of
                            their sphere; "A rise and stand upfast fade away. The night of an tiden i zens may not tell
                            shall exist, on your feet, christ is o'er, Of that The his And love to We come, our All
                            hail the bright tory world' of viv home com so the i is ing fair, soul. fy here, day!
                                MANIFESTO.<pb n="261" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 361 seasons days are angels more shall
                            gospel 4ftin this deeds, its in the war with kindred earthly years are in dire firm
                            ner fill and sphere shown sphere curse strong The By In Stain Cheer cycles come changes in
                            age eter earth with hu up, your zeal and go; Their it wrought; It nal-------all—, man re
                            gore ; new : cease lessons lives when God's own In God they live, in Contending armies
                            Leave all the errors none spir God fight of may it they for the see They rules The move,
                            God right, The are not counted secret springs of is their all in reign of sin is past,
                            Christ Angels are with so. thought. all. o'er." you." MANIFESTO. Like Its • The No
                        Blest</p></div2><!--                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]
</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>