<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0704" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18770401" TEIform="date">April 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="25" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " 0a prench the kingdom of (§od!
                        *' j$f(e hntimon^ of eternal tt[uth. Yol. TIL G. A. LOMAS, Editor, Shakers, N. Y. APRIL, 1877. i
                        N. A. BRIGGS, PUBLISHER, i Shaker Village, N. H. No. 4.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Discussion" TEIform="index"/>Discussion</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia E." TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA E. HASTINGS</byline><p TEIform="p">Discussion and free thought seem to be occupying the platform more and more ; may it continue
                            thus till error is swept away, and truth and right prevail. Discussion, and even contest,
                            managed in a good, earnest, loving spirit, may be very profitable on many subjects ; but
                            when the debate becomes so heated and strong as to merge into antagonism or total egotism,
                            and unkindly dispute and wrangling, it might be well for the contestants to pause and take
                            breath, imbibe a little more moderation and self-examination. Review the page to see if, in
                            their ardor to win the mastery, they are urging their point consistently and to the
                            enlightenment and conviction of other thinking minds ; or whether, in their earnestness to
                            prevail, they are becoming a trifle vexed, (wrathy?) that their opponent does not readily
                            see eye to eye with them and accept all their theory, (which they themselves on more mature
                            deliberation may possibly see cause to change). Since no one writer for The Shaker, to our
                            knowledge, assumes the superhuman position of infallibility of judgment or opinion, why
                            should not each be willing to accord to others the same freedom of expression that he woulc
                            reasonably claim for himself? How good and how pleasant it is for brethren to work together
                            in unity ! that is, unity of purpose to secure the genuine metal, the true and the sound. We
                            hope and trust that all our gooc brothers and sisters who are interestec in obtaining and
                            diffusing light and true knowledge, will take heed to this matter, battle errors and wrongs
                            with suitable weapons, and sharp, but be carefu not to hurt the oil or the wine. Let al
                            communications be savored with love in the heart and Christian earnestness to do good and
                            benefit others, (which course will also bring home benefit,) exercise the golden rule and
                            cherish love anc kindly feelings towards all mankind and our little missionary may be the
                            means of dispelling many clouds anc dispensing much blessing. With sin cere desire for the
                            success of the enter prise and the prosperity of its managers, aids and many friends.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earth is as much God's residence as heaven." TEIform="index"/>Earth is as much God's residence as heaven.
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The earth is as much God's residence as heaven."</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Bellows, [Dr.]" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Bellows</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Awake to the danger!" TEIform="index"/>Awake to the Danger!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Daniel Offord" TEIform="index"/>DANIEL OFFARD</byline><p TEIform="p">The Shaker is intended for the nunciation of truth ; and what truth is nore important to
                            human welfare than hat the American government should be very unsectarian ? Believers should
                            realize how great the dangers of a church-and-state combination in our government! The
                            Shaker should awaken such as are asleep to the dangerous fact that old anti-christian,
                            persecuting theology would injure unto death those who would not, could not think as it
                            does. There is no crime known to men which church-and-state governments have not committed,
                            and in the name of God and Jesus Christ too ! I do earnestly hope that The Shaker may be
                            true to its name, and wage spiritual war, in battles of shaking, against every evil
                            principle and power that is at work against the good of humanity. And let us, as brethren,
                            true to the faith, hating the lusts of the flesh and of the mind, have our entire lives in
                            accord with the sincerity of truth ; and though there may be differences of opinion
                            theologically, the main purposes of our faith will be accomplished.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hot-house Christians" TEIform="index"/>Hot-House Christians</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">How lowlv were the saints of old. Who, from the grove or cavern wild, To God their sins and
                            sorrows told In language artless as a child; While winds and waves and tides are still,
                            Their heart-warm songs and prayers arise That echo wafts, o'er dale and hill, To heaven from
                            the list'ning skies. But progress moves with time apace, And art succeeds to nature now; And
                            those who seek God's saving grace, Their churches, not their hearts endow: How well devised
                            and shrewd the plan, To build to God with brick and stone; And buy His choicest gifts to
                            man, With consecrated gold alone ! How piety walks hand in hand, With ostentation here
                            below; And pomp and potence now command All gold-fleeced reverends dare to know! What
                            gorgeous structures now obtain, With spires that pierce the Heav'nly blue As though to
                            cleave the skies in twain, And let man's gilt-edged off'rings through The heart now beats to
                            man's control, Nor dare beyond his biddings soar; And ice has fossilized the soul That warms
                            to God and heaven no more : The world that war's red sins subdued To bold imperial Caesar's
                            sway; The world God's angels loved and wooed, Is fashion's willing slave to-day! ^earned
                            priests now daily interview The Deity on things below; Suggesting much He ought to do, And
                            many things He ought to know; Or broaching some transcendent plan, (More suited to the time,
                            and higher,) ?o save intact the soul of man, Without the slightest use of fire. *fow
                            fashion's found a fairer road, That all her glitt'ring hosts pursue, With palace-cars to
                            Heaven's abode, And passes for the favored few; Urbane conductors, just secured, With music
                            daily by the choir; And every passenger assured, From damages or loss by fire. How tempting
                            this on fashion's line, With ease and safety promised there ! Yet many still to doubts
                            incline That all is gold that shines so fair: Perhaps 'twere best for those who doubt, Where
                            fashion's cream-cheese votaries go, To take the less attractive route, Tear-worn by saints
                            of long-ago. I wonder if 'way up on high, Man's piebald thoughts and acts they know; And if
                            they oft'ner smile or sigh, At his queer capers here below: Perhaps they think this world a
                            stage, And saints and sinners actors all; And trembling wait the closing page, To see life's
                            star-gemmed curtain fall.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bitter, but wholesome" TEIform="index"/>Bitter, but Wholesome</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">The festive holidays in New York city had clouds whose dark side we must look at in spite of
                            the transient, surface merriment of the masses. "Child frozen to death in the public
                            street." Not merry talk at the breakfast table. Some say the passers-by were all to blame;
                            others that they did just right to hurry by,—plenty of their own to provide for,— careless
                            alms-giving makes matters worse; others still, that liquor-sellers must answer for this and
                            a thousand daily cases of " man's inhumanity to man." Now, what right, human or divine, have
                            people coolly, voluntarily to add to the drifting, useless, shiftless swarms of beings that
                            disgrace the name of humanity? Face the sad fact, look at the dark side a moment, that we
                            may learn truth sweeter than sensual pleasure, more lasting than holiday merriment. Is
                            America to be a land of hopeless poverty? This question is a serious one for to-day,—not to
                            be put off to the future, when it may be a problem for civil war to settle. Humanity is
                            somewhat " off the track." All admit it. It might be worse. Thank God, the bridge is not
                            broken yet! The sooner the passengers get out of the lazy, shaky risky seats, and lend
                            willing hands to th work of private and public reform, the soon er humanity's train will be
                            " on " again, anc the bridge of redemption will hold if we do our part. Laugh and jeer as
                            people do at the mere mention of self-denial, society's best lesson :o-day is this same
                            curbing of all useless, iotous desires of the senses and intellect. ^he man or woman who
                            learns to control one single desire within bounds, so that it oes not run away with sober
                            judgment of what he or she knowis to be right, noble, aealthy, useful, will receive strength
                            to rule over mightier forces than brutal armies. £ven our strongest propensities,—too often
                            worthy the name of "passions,"—can be aeld from their willful, natural courses, and urned to
                            nobler work. Thus only can God's first beautiful, orderly plan be brought back. Self-denial
                            for individuals is the very spirit of Christianity. If more of it were with us, it would
                            indeed work like a "holy" spirit, which is prayed for so much, and grieved away by unholy
                            deeds. Do people never think of a more radical cure for pauperism, and milder forms of
                            soverty, disease, and degeneration than almsgiving? Or are they afraid to advise unucky
                            mortals, who are morally and physically unworthy of multiplying God's image, :o abstain?
                            Afraid to, because they know aow all unworthily they live themselves ? Some may reply in the
                            words of Dickens' Christmas ghost: " Why should one speck of animated dust complain of the
                            too-much ife among the hungry brothers on myriad leaves around ?" At first thought, true, it
                            does look like disrespect, almost blasphemy, to find fault with increasing population. For
                            does not the Infinite give souls to earthcaskets, and what have mortals to say about it?
                            Would that there are no worse ways of checking population than the total abstinence called
                            celibacy! Is it honoring God to think he cannot give immortal life—souls —to better earthly
                            forms than many specimens we see? " But," say some; "your plan is too radical. Humanity must
                            gradually work into better conditions." How can it, unless some few people commence thorough
                            home-work ? Nay, radical cures are needed. Reform will be slow enough among the masses
                            anyway. So let thoughtful ones reflect on the signs of the times, especially on present
                            bodily health, comparing with the past, and ask, "Are coming generations likely to inherit
                            an average standard of health ? or more, or less ? " For on healthy bodies depend the
                            well-balancing of minds and the progress of soullife. Once, a mere handful of persons were
                            all in the world who were able to understand, even partially, the wholesome, sin-cleaning
                            spirit of Christ's testimony. Not many, now, know the fullness of meaning which the light of
                            to-day unfolds from the everripening teachings of the New Testament. We are called upon to
                            live higher, Christian lives than the world was able to grasp an idea of, a few centuries
                            ago. One strong proof is in the physical degeneration of the race. Religion that does not
                            control the most important vital function of men and women is worse than no religion. <pb n="26" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. Moody revivals do not reach the root of the worst sins
                            among the people. Sad, sad is the need, as honest physicians can tell, of some motive strong
                            enough to turn man's appetites and passions to a nobler work than dishonoring God's gifts of
                            immortality with poor, imperfect, imbecile, lust-consumed tenements of clay. Consumptives
                            are kept from spreading their misfortunes among posterity, as far as common-sense can rule
                            over passion in general society. Why should not many other forms of hereditary disease and
                            deformity be cut off by noble, honest sacrifice of carnal lives ? Let unlucky heirs of the
                            sins of parents and grandparents take up crosses like followers of Christ, and say : " We
                            will do what we can to check the increase of sin that threatens the coming twentieth century
                            more than the nineteenth." This is the call to large numbers to-day. Happy are souls who
                            give up carnal, selfish lives for any good motive; for they receive the promised
                            hundred-fold, and grow toward divine life, with a joy the world knows not of. Sonyea, N.
                        T.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wisdom, the principal thing" TEIform="index"/>Wisdom, the Principal Thing</head><p TEIform="p">John Phillips of Pleasant Hill, Ky., sends us the following report of a short, pithy address,
                            by Larz Erickson of that place : " Let us gather heavenly things. We stand in greatest need
                            of wisdom, to lead us to be happy and satisfied and dutiful. A wise man or woman is of
                            inestimable worth on this earth. Each is like the losing sun, manifesting the glory of God
                            to all men. All who receive wisdom as a guide, flourish in temporal and spiritual blessings.
                            Whoso is governed by wisdom, does not think nor say much of self as being exalted above his
                            fellows. Wisdom never controverts ; it teaches by example the better way. War is not of
                            Wisdom. Peace is one of Wisdom's children, her rule is "peace on earth, and good will to
                            men!" [To which we add "Amen!" even at the expense of being so much a Methodist. Preach on,
                            brother ; it is just such thoughts as feed the would-be wise, and many of our readers will
                            bless you for so doing.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social life topics" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL LIFE TOPICS</head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H., \ January 28, 1877. J Beloved A.: How very singular, indeed, that you
                            should have addressed me upon subjects which form so much the essential feature of our whole
                            life. I think that you have more readily anticipated me than I could hope to do in my reply.
                            I am so thoroughly convinced of the essential necessity of a rigid discipline for the mind,
                            and no less for the body, that I almost reverentially look upon the requirements of the
                            originators of our order, and hesitate at the thought of changing or repealing, unless fully
                            persuaded that it will be for the development of protection for the order, or open an avenue
                            more spiritual, and consequently place us nearer the city of God. Very well do I know, as
                            you remark, the times that our order are each day in the attitude of prayer. As commonplace
                            as its frequency may seem to make it, the believer whose soul is awakened in the interest of
                            the gospel cause, finds it an exalted position before God. To the children and youth it evi
                            dently has a most salutary effect, in that it demands of them, for a few moments, reilec
                            tion. While they bend their knees in prayer they should be conscientiously instructed in
                            thair thank-offering before God. That the ceremony may become formal we cannot deny. That we
                            may suffer from abstraction, forgetting the place we are in, may also be true; and the same
                            might be said of many or all ceremonies which are of frequent occurrence. I am fully
                            persuaded that the discipline which forms the essential part of our work comprehends,
                            measurably, the saving grace, on the principle which Jesus taught: "Deny thyself, and follow
                            me." But I have thus far been so interested in your remarks that even now I reluctantly pass
                            from them to another subject. Ah, shall I in this anticipate you, and with you a arge body
                            of our brethren and sisters, as I make reference to the signal-call of themornng? It is
                            generally conceded, order is characteristic of the kingdom of God, and hence the imperative
                            necessity of its strict maintenance by every body of professing christians. Confusion, or
                            disorder, belongs to Babylon. When we publish that our signal for rising is at 5 or 5 1-2,
                            it is by many received with astonishment. One says: "I rise at 6, and consider that early,"
                            while another begins the day at 7. This may do for those who have no systematic order for
                            retiring, and it may do for families organized on the basis of selfish relations ; but a
                            prominent feature of protection in the Shaker order, and an active testimony against a
                            morbid indulgence, is found in the careful attention to I the hours of retiring and of
                            rising. The old adage says : " Six hours of rest for a man ; seven for a woman; and eight
                            for a fool." The Shakers have given the extended margin. Some do not wish the greatest
                            number ; others readily accept it. As we have no slaves, no servants, our religious compact
                            is formed of brethren and sisters, who stand on a foundation of equality, covenanting
                            together to abide by the rules of the institution, and to bear the cross of practical
                            self-denial. Sickness, infancy and old age form exceptions to this rule. It was only a few
                            mornings since, as I was passing from one dwelling to another, at a few minutes past 5, that
                            I met a little boy, as bright as a lark. "Why are you not in bed and asleep, my little man
                            ?" said I. When he as readily answered : " They have rung the bell, and I didn't want to
                            sleep any longer." He had in all probability enjoyed the luxury of "rest from his labors"
                            some nine or ten hours. The amount of rest that a person needs may be an open question.
                            Health reformers sadly disagree on this point, as they do on every other. Nervous
                            temperaments plead for an indefinite extension, while the indifferent and indolent of every
                            phase still say, "yet a little sleep, a little slumber." As my correspondent, whoever he may
                            happen to be, dwells with so much interest upon certain religious forms, I trust that he as
                            faithfully begins the day, by a strict observance of that religious discipline which calls
                            us to a renewal of life as " the morning dawn is breaking." Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., H. C." TEIform="persName"/>h. c. b.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unanswered prayer" TEIform="index"/>An Unanswered Prayer</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morse, Rosie" TEIform="persName"/>ROSIE MORSE</byline><p TEIform="p">Oh, saints on earth, and powers above, Do grant one boon we pray! For it we ask, for it we
                            plead, Oh, turn us not away : Oh, give us one breath of pure air, Our waning strength revive
                            ; One sniff of oxygen, O grant, To keep our souls alive. Our vital energies are weak— Our
                            aspirations dead! Our inward fervency is spent— Our zeal and ardor fled ! All for the want
                            of God's free air! Essence of mortal life— That all-supporting element, Which warms us for
                            life's strife. In church, I cast my eyes around, To find an open door; But through no
                            crevice comes the air, My dull brain to restore. And here, we're breathing o'er again, The
                            air that's been exhaled ! I think, O whither can I go, And oxygen prevail? Ah, might I roam
                            through trackless air, And like the eagle soar! To this benighted, mundane sphere, I would
                            return no more. I'd take my flight most joyously— In the air of heaven I'd lave— I'd feed
                            and feast on oxygen, As pure as God e'er gave. But while I'm destined here to stay, I must
                            not soar too high; To earth, I turn reluctantly, But give me air, I cry. Throw up the
                            windows, ope the doors— Give nature broader scope ! We shall be paid in better gifts, In
                            spirit, life and hope. Now should we be denied this boon That serves to vitalize? Nay, let
                            us heed before too late, Exhausted nature's cries. I do implore, with all my prayer, In
                            supplication's voice : Oh, gospel friends, let's breath pure air, And then in truth rejoice.
                            Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every child of God saved!" TEIform="index"/>Every Child of God Saved!</head><p TEIform="p">We are always glad to add admiration to any churchal declaration; and we find so little to
                            object to in the following, from the Christian Leader¦, (universalist,) we copy, asking how
                            many genuine universalists there are ? Every child of God being herein provided for, what of
                            the " lost sheep," according to the universalist creed? ' 'A man's mere belief that God will
                            finally save all souls, does not, in itself, make him a universalist. His life will give
                            some evidence of his creed. He will be mei'ciful and loving. Humanity will shine in his
                            countenance, and wax eloquent in his speech. His sympathies will be enlisted in behalf of
                            every true charity and reform. He will not be ashamed to confess his faith before men. He
                            will be proud and glad to declare ' I am a believer in the ultimate salvation of every child
                            of God.'"</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word to grumblers" TEIform="index"/>A Word to Grumblers</head><p TEIform="p">The Dansville (Ky.) Record says: "Don't be a grumbler. Some people, old and young, contrive
                            to get hold of the prickly side of everything; to run against all the sharp corners, and to
                            find out all the disagreeable things. Half the strength spent in growling would often set
                            things right. You may as well make up your mind that no one ever found the world quite as he
                            would like it; but you are to take your share of the trouble, and bear it bravely. You will
                            be very sure to have burdens laid upon you that belong to other people, unless you are a
                            shh'k yourself; but don't grumble. If the work needs doing, never mind about the other one
                            who ought to have done it and didn't. Those workers who fill up the gaps and smooth away the
                            rough spots, and finish up the job the others leave undone, they are the true peace-makers,
                            and worth a whole regiment of growlers."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is this a Christian country?" TEIform="index"/>"Is this a Christian Country?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jastrow" TEIform="persName"/>Rabbi Jastrow of Philadelphia, in a discourse demanding the opening
                            of the centennial exhibition on the Sabbath, answered the above question, No !</byline><p TEIform="p">" I confess my inability to undei"stand what a Christian country means, and I defy any of
                            those who make use of this argument to explain it satisfactorily. Is Christianity a
                            nationality by which a country may be defined, that we should be permitted to say, ' This is
                            a Christian country ?' Should a compound of two terms, which have neither a political nor a
                            geographical connection, one of which designates the soil, and the other a religious creed,
                            be allowed to be made use of for denominational purposes in a country where, one hundred
                            years ago, liberty of conscience was made the basis of all government? Just as absurd as it
                            is to speak of a Christian soil, it is to use the expression of a Christian country in the
                            sense of a Christian government, with Christian political institutions. Where is that
                            Christian country? Thanks to the Lord, we look for it in vain on the map of the United
                            States. " Here where the separation of church and state has been laid down as the foundation
                            of our government; here should we, in the sight of our liberties, in the year of their
                            jubilee, speak of a Christian country in the same sense as we speak of a French or a Spanish
                            countiy ? Are the citizens of this country Christians, by either birth or adoption? Are her
                            officers Christians? If this be so, let there be, in spite of the constitution, a test
                            established for every one who lands on our shores ; let him swear that he is a Christian,
                            though it may be hard to state what sect he belongs to ; let there be no one admitted to the
                            privileges of citizenship who refuses to swear allegiance to Christianity. Until such a test
                            shall have been established, no one has a right to say ' This is a Christian country ;' and
                            whoever says so pei'verts the truth for the sake of misleading the people into intolerance
                            and fanaticism. This is no Christian country so long as the first amendment of the
                            constitution stands unchanged, and we trust in the good sense of our people that it will
                            stand so forever."</p></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kindness to animals" TEIform="index"/>Kindness to animals</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Van Amburgh could handle his lions and tigers with impunity. No animal will fail
                                    to respond to kindness and good treatment. And especially will the noble horse
                                    respect and confide in and faithfully serve a master who deals gently and kindly
                                    with him. We have ourselves taken a spirited Morgan mare which had been rudely
                                    handled and become entirely unmanageable through harsh treatment, and by appealing
                                    to her intelligence and respecting her needs, in three weeks' time made her entirely
                                    safe and reliable for wife and children, and all who would treat her kindly and
                                    handle her gently, and we have, after five years, seen the same mare resume her old
                                    vicious habits when again under the control of one who resorted to arbitrary or
                                    brutal treatment. Always appeal to the better instincts of the horse, the mule, the
                                    ox, the cow, as well as the dog and other domestic animals, and they will never
                                    become vicious nor unmanageable.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Semi-tropical" TEIform="index"/>Semi- Tropical</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="27" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Listening to evil reports" TEIform="index"/>Listening to evil reports</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The longer I live, the more I feel the importance of adhering to the rule which I
                                    have laid down for myself in relation to such matters : i. To hear as little as
                                    possible whatever is to the prejudice of others. 2. To believe nothing of the kind
                                    till I am absolutely forced to it. 3. Never to drink into the spirit of one who
                                    circulates an evil report. 4 Always to moderate, as far as I can, the unkindness
                                    which is expressed towards others. 5. Always to believe that, i\ the other side were
                                    heard, a very different account would be given of the matter.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Camus's life of Simeon" TEIform="index"/>Camus's Life of Simeon</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Best friend" TEIform="index"/>The best friend</head><p TEIform="p">The most agreeable of all companions is a simple, frank man, without any high pretensions to
                            an oppressive greatness ; one who loves life, and understands the use of it; obliging alike
                            at all hours ; above all, of a goldem temper, and steadfast as an anchor. For such an one we
                            gladly exchange the greatest genius, the most brilliant wit, the profoundest th i n ker.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lessing" TEIform="persName"/>Lessing</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A reform is needed; when shall it commence?..." TEIform="index"/>A reform is needed; when shall it commence?...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wetmore, M. S." TEIform="persName"/>M. S. Wetmore</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A reform is needed ; when shall it commence? Right here in Boston, where there is
                                    wealth sufficient to support ministers at enormous salaries—to save souls—and to
                                    build churches and furnish them extravagantly, in which to worship God on Sundays,
                                    are men and women starving and freezing,-and no " man of God" to stay their feet in
                                    the course of ruin. Saloons bright and cheerful invite them to enter. Churches dark
                                    and dismal are closed against them, for these latter places are God's houses, and
                                    must not be desecrated ( by the poor, the hungry, and forsaken. So Satan has it all
                                    his own way in his alluring hells. Why not open the church es, or the vestries at
                                    least, every even ing through the winter, make them a comfortable and cheerful as
                                    Satan' realms, and have it an understooc thing that hot coffee and substantia food
                                    will be served to the cold and hun gry, and lodgings furnished—if no there, then
                                    from a fund for the purpose instead of furnishing tracts for the mil] ions and money
                                    for the heathen—to thos who have no homes ; thus making th churches God's houses in
                                    very earnest and causing the hearts of the suffering to rejoice that at last
                                    humanity has dis covered a new way of saving soul through warming, feeding and
                                    clothing the body?—M. S. Wetmore, in New Age. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>New Age</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Rev. Joe Cook has drawn picture of the church..." TEIform="index"/>The Rev. Joe Cook has drawn picture of the church...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cook, Joe" TEIform="persName"/>Rev. Joe Cook</byline><p TEIform="p">The Rev. Joe Cook has drawn picture of the church of the future. H says: "If the churches
                            continue to develop in accordance with present in dications, a few centuries hence th
                            members will be fanned with eloqueni sermons, as they swing in hammocks one end of which
                            will be fastened t the cross and the other held by mammon." </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="People frequently reject great truths, not so much for want of evidence..." TEIform="index"/>People frequently reject great truths, not so much for want of evidence...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">People frequently reject great truths, not so much for want of evidence, as for want of an
                            inclination to search for it.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When Cornelius Vanderbilt departed this life..." TEIform="index"/>When Cornelius Vanderbilt departed this life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> When Cornelius Vanderbilt departed this life, the clergyman at his funer1 said
                                    that his last moments were hap)y because Christ had died for him, in whom he had "a
                                    singularly child-like "aith" as his Saviour. Of course. Jeus said that a camel might
                                    go through he eye of a needle easier than a rich man enter the kingdom of heaven ;
                                    and Vanderbilt thereupon proceeds to amass fifty or an hundred millions, to show his
                                    " singularly child-like faith." We don't see how it was child-like, except in the
                                    sense that shows a babe's wisdom. But it is not necessary for a man of property or
                                    good position in society to get converted. We never knew such a man to die, who,
                                    however destitute his life might have been of any religious purpose, was not at
                                    once, by the hand of some theological exponent of the divine counsels, safely landed
                                    in Abraham's bosom.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>The New Age</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If I were on trial for my integrity or my life..." TEIform="index"/>If I were on trial for my integrity or my life...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Talmage, DeWitt" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Rev. DeWitt Talmage says: "If I were on trial for my integrity or my life, I would rather
                            have my case submitted to a jury of twelve lawyers than :o a jury of twelve clergymen. The
                            legal profession have a keener sense oi justice than is found in the sacred calling-"</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Christian is not safe and reliable unless he has sent a tap-roote..." TEIform="index"/>A Christian is not safe and reliable unless he has sent a tap-roote...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A Christian is not safe and reliable unless he has sent a tap-root down into
                                    hard, strong foundations of Christian doctrine. Surface-roots of sentimen' and
                                    emotion have their uses, but they are not good for much, either in a dry time or in
                                    a tempest.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Words of faith" TEIform="index"/>Words of Faith</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How the dumb creatures loved him" TEIform="index"/>HOW THE DUMB CREATURES LOVED HIM</head><p TEIform="p"> A French writer says of an old Bordeaux sailor of sixty years ago: He was so kind to dumb
                            creatures that I have known his boat was coming sometimes through seeing the pigeons start
                            off seaward, and wheel and hover around her till she touched the landing steps, when, almost
                            before he had stepped on shore, they would perch on his shoulders ; and then, when his head
                            appeared above the quay, the goat would come capering down, bleating. Old Tinker, the
                            donkey,—such a rascal that it was said he could open every gate in the parish, and the
                            cattle all knew it, and would follow him, and he had to be tethered,—would, as the old man
                            advanced, whisk his tail, prance, throw back his ears and bray; and the very pig, who was
                            often let loose for a run would come shambling down, anc grunt, and arch his back for a rub,
                            noi to speak of the tortoise, which woulc follow him about, and eat out of hi and no other
                            hand. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hebrew darkness" TEIform="index"/>Hebrew darkness</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">In a Jewish synagogue in New York, one of the pew-holding brethren has been
                                    convict ed of being a receiver of stolen goods and now the trustees refuse to take
                                    hi money for the rent of the pew. They are glad to have him come to churcl and get
                                    good, but they won't touch hi money. Suppose a Protestant churcl was run on such
                                    principles, and prohi bitionist clergymen compelled to de cline money the brethren
                                    made at rum selling, for example, there would very soon be a coolness among the
                                    brethren An exchange hints that some Christia churches would be exposed to bajikrupi
                                    cy.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston advertiser" TEIform="index"/>Boston Advertiser</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What's in a name?" TEIform="index"/>What's in a name?</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The pious Cincinnati Enquirer, and the evangelzed Democrat, are holding up their
                                    dious heads in holy horror at Col. Inersoll, as an " infidel." History inbrms us
                                    that Thomas Jefferson, the aulor of the Declaration of Indepenence, and father of
                                    the democratic Darty, was an infidel. John Adams, a igner of the Declaration of
                                    Indepenence, was an infidel. Benj. Frankfin, a signer of the Declaration of
                                    Indepenlence, was an infidel. Thomas Paine, one of the most distinguished of the
                                    revolutionary patriots, was an infidel. And Jefferson says, in his "Notes on
                                    Virginia," that even Washington himself was an infidel. In fact, a very considerable
                                    number of the leading and wisest politicians of to-day are infidels.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Common sense" TEIform="index"/>Common Sense</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To hundreds of Shakers, and professing Christian people, this will not read pleasurably..." TEIform="index"/>To hundreds of Shakers, and professing Christian people, this will not read pleasurably...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To hundreds of Shakers, and professing Christian people, this will not read pleasurably. But
                            when we think how very infidel true Shakers are to "orthodox" theology, we do not know o\
                            greater infidels anywhere !</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum..." TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. (V DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Organization of spiritualists" TEIform="index"/>Organization of Spiritualists</head><p TEIform="p">The Shaker has no ill-will toward spiritualists of our own country, nor of other lands. The
                            constantly-recurring evidences of courtesy from the columns of the spiritualistic press in
                            behalf of our medium, leave us without an excuse for uttering a word of unpleasant criticism
                            upon its almost universal position of organization. Our strictures must be considered,
                            therefore, as an earnest for its welfare, and for the milions for which it continues to live
                            so healthily. It is pretty generally known that The Shaker is the organ of the earliest
                            organization of the most spirit ual body of spiritualists in our country or that has existed
                            as such an organiza tion since the days of Pentecost. Our organization is eighty-five years
                            of age ; and its every pulse-beat tending to an increase of organization, has meant a
                            stronger, purer, unselfish spiritualism. For twenty-five years we have admired the
                            opposition of spiritualists generally, to any suggestion of organization, upon bases that
                            formed the foundation of the popular churches; and the spiritualistic press is worthy of all
                            praise for its continued persistence in thus encouraging its people. A few months since, a
                            large congregation of spiritualists met at Philadelphia, among which wei"e found some of the
                            leading, and most worthy lights of that unorganized persuasion of spiritualism, known as
                            "modern." The object of the meeting was for organization, upon a basis of deeper¦, genuine
                            spiritualism than the body had known before; and which was there declared as a positive
                            necessity, to keep within the fold those who had been faithful members, but who were
                            leavening back to the old arks from which they once had departed, a sincerely and suddenly
                            as Abraham ever left his kindred, or Lot and his family went out from Sodom. There is no
                            doubt le proper time had come for their oranization ; that the proper parties had nere met
                            for this purpose ; and that most properly did they report a basis which any and all of the
                            popular hurches of all lands could pattern to heir greatly increased spiritual benefit.
                            STone of the old saws of theology were embodied in the reported constitution ; and we
                            remember of reading the resoutions with much pleasure, as being good grounds for abandoning
                            further opposition to organization. Again the press of the persuasion raised a warning cry,
                            and particularly vented anathemas against the admission of '•^Christian" as denning
                            '•''spiritual'sts." One by one, however, this press las abandoned opposition to organizaion,
                            but seem desirous of a new deal n resolutions ; the formation of a new, and, to us, most
                            indefinite and impossi}le platform to organize upon. The Banner of Lights and
                            ReligioPhilosophical Journal, two mostwidey known and respected journals of spiritualism,
                            seem to have due appreciation that mediumistic impostors are abundant, that honest mediums
                            are persecuted, that "social freedom" overrides morality and purity; and that many of the
                            best educated and more reigiously inclined spiritualists have connected themselves with
                            liberal, Christian denominations. Yet these, and other periodicals, have just roused up from
                            a Rip Van Winkle-like sleep, to come out zealously for organization. But the motto—the
                            platform—a plan upon which they propose to found and organize a church, would excite our
                            pity more, if it did not make us laugh! Here it is—all there is of it—all! "think for
                            yourself and express that THOUGHT! FREE THOUGHT WILL GIVE US TRUTH ! ! " " Precisely so,
                            says the atheist of Paris, and the mormon of Utah. This may be an effort to organize
                            spiritualists, with spiritualism left out—without any admission of communion of spirits !
                            Think of it; spiritualists trying to organize their scattering forces without a recognition
                            of God, of Christ, of morality ! without any recognition of repentance, of confession of
                            their sins, or a communion, and communication with their superiors in the world of spirits !
                            The plan may be proper with atheists, deists, radicals, religion-haters, and a few
                            spiritualists, but what will J. M. Peebles, Dr. Watson, A. J. Davis, Nellie T. Brigham, Dr.
                            Child, and a host of other spiritualists, say of it? In a former article, we expressed our
                            disappointment in spiritualists. We had hoped they never would organize uiftil they could
                            agree upon a basis that was less earthly, more spiritual, fuller of brotherhood and stronger
                            in the bond of love than the organizations of the Shakers; and when we read of the spiritual
                            platform arranged in Philadelphia, we still had hope. For realizing, that though it was not
                            uas strait as<pb n="28" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> straitness," nor "pure as the heavens," it tended largely
                            that way, and to lift spiritualists up, and out of themselves and selfishness ; and until
                            this resurrection takes place, spiritualists will continue to wear the swaddling clothes of
                            its childhood, while thoughts and talks of its growth into more genuine spirituality will be
                            all bosh ! The spiritualism of the Shakers is none too intense, neither approaches too near
                            the life of the heavens ; and until our spiritualistic friends determine to excel the
                            Shakers in angelic occupations of body and soul, they had better live here, as spiritually
                            as they do. Until they take some course more radically spiritual than the platform noted
                            above, the decimation of their ranks will be hailed with joy by the old systems which they
                            once so gladly forsook, and toward which they never more can give faithful adherence.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our biographical studies, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>Our Biographical Studies. No, 1</head><p TEIform="p">I. JOHN BAPTIST. Every important movement from good to better, and best,—from conservative to
                            more radical goodness—has had its forerunner ; and between Judaism and the mission of Jesus,
                            there came John Baptist, crying to the bewildered people, '; Prepare for Jesus "—for
                            something better than you have ever heard! The testimony of this Baptist is valuable: "I
                            indeed, baptize you with water, while you are confessing your sins ; but he that cometh
                            after me, will baptize you with fire, while you confess, and give you the holy spirit to
                            help you refrain in the future !" Again : '"''Isaw and bare record that this is the son of
                            God I" So far, John is to be admired. After a time, this same John—unwilling to yield to his
                            convictions, and submit to the superior authority of Jesus—doubted, and sent some of his
                            followers to Jesus, to ask of him whether he was the promised Messiah! Jesus replied by
                            sending back the fruits of his works. The next we hear of this John, he dies by violence.
                            This Baptist has many scholars—faithful followers in our time—in all excepting his tragic
                            death. He has, incomparably, more followers than Jesus ! Professing allegiance to Jesus, and
                            acknowledging his life as that of the son of God, they to this day doubt the propriety of
                            giving up their selfish sovereignties to become his disciples ; while the majority will be
                            beheaded, and die, before they will admit that Jesus' life was the proper life to be copied
                            by Christians! The lives of the majority are like the Baptist's, too selfish to submit to
                            Christianity ! John was a nice man, a splendid Jew ; too proudspirited, however. " None
                            greater has been born," said Jesus, not even excepting himself. But because of the want of
                            an humble, self-denying, obe,ient spirit, neither John nor the mul; itudes who follow him in
                            arrogant opposition to the unselfish, angelic life t f Jesus the Christ, "the least of the
                            i.ingdom of heaven is greater" than these followers of John out of heaven. II. NICODEMUS. We
                            must be excused from the condemnation of Nicodemus. " He came by night," 'tis true ; and he
                            may thus have shown a want of moral courage ; 3ut his admitted testimony, " We know that
                            thou art a teacher of God," places him far ahead of tens of thousands, who, condemning
                            Nicodemus, will not come to the acknowledgment of the truth of Christ's life, neither by day
                            nor night! We except from this number some known individuals, who, having faith in the
                            correctness of Shaker testimony and life, "come by night" with offerings as genuine,, as
                            that of Nicodemus. We cherish the confidence of very many, who, sick of the carnally fleshly
                            life, realize no more pleasure in such worldliness, but find it corroding, corrupting, and
                            very unspiritual to the soul, who yet are so strongly bound, Nicodemus-like, by the fashions
                            of our day, that they cannot " come by day," cannot come out and own their genuine
                            convictions, and brave a scorning world; and so they " come by night," in loving epistles,
                            in tokens of remembrance; come themselves under cover of our confidence. Our sanctum library
                            denotes scores of volumes, presented by living, loving, modern Nicodemuses, and our
                            editorial chair, admired by so many, is the gift of a "comer by night." Letters from all
                            parts of the English-speaking world are abundant; and sincere protestations of these infant
                            souls into Christianity are at no time wanting. We love them, nevertheless. Their half-loaf
                            admissions by starlight are better than no bread by day ; and for their kindly donations by
                            letter and otherwise we have only grateful returns to offer, for which they shall lose
                            nothing, but be remembered as those only wanting daylight to make them " near the kingdom of
                            heaven." And yet we encourage none to be Nicodemuses. would have denied the Christ in
                            doc:rine, saved them and the testimony before the world. The denial by Peter is to be
                            severely condemned, there beng no Christian apology therefor; but :here should be all
                            charity for his admitted and repented-of weakness. There are some who offer Peter's mistake
                            as an apology for their own misdoings; but this will never do for Christians. Let us condemn
                            whatever is wrong in Peter, Paul, Appollos, or ourselves; and then let us be as
                            encouragingly repentant as any one. As a denier of his master, Peter was, is ondemnable ;
                            and wherein we at all deny his life in our lives, we are therein condemnable. Peter's
                            repentant and estimable future, so far as he represented Christ, we should copy as closely
                            as circumstances demand. In the absence of physical martyrdom, let us crucify the world, the
                            flesh in us, heads downward, being vigilant for the cause to the end. With the truth ever
                            apparent, that there are myriads who deny Christ, not only three times, but all their lives,
                            might we be more able to make as apparent that a few more hundreds might own and represent
                            Christ than now do, as "him crucified unto a sinful world," and themselves offered to
                            "follow him," the exemplar Jesus, the brilliant pattern of the Christ life. III. PETER.
                            Peter, it is said, denied his master, fulfilling the prediction of Jesus that he would.
                            Jesus was a natural phrenologist, a ready reader of human nature ; and with Peter's
                            inordinate expression of what he would do, Jesus coupled his knowledge of Peter's want of
                            firmness when the time of trial came, and said to him, " You will deny me three times, more
                            easily than you think." We all love Peter's future. How well he contended for the faith
                            afterward, and died head downward from choice! And from this future we may learn a
                            profitable lesson. There are millions of persons whose characters are like unto Peter's when
                            he denied his Lord. There are only a few who repent as sincerely as he did after his Lord
                            had been crucified. There is no doubt that Peter, on discovering his weakness, determined to
                            strengthen therein, and accomplished his determination: and when others ias ruined the
                            happiness of many homes and made its inmates narrow and selfish—should never take possession
                            of a Christian's heart; for where the true spirit of Christ reigns, there will exist ^ove,
                            charity, peace, forgiveness, and all the heavenly graces that tend to develop the true
                            character. The golden rule will be the Christian's guide instead of selfishness; and we
                            shall find that as, step by step, we ascend the hill of progression, to be a Christian is to
                            be a savior. Don't criticise. — Whatever you do, never set up for a critic. I don't mean a
                            newspaper one—some people are obliged to earn a living that way— but in private life, in the
                            domestic circle, in society. It will not do any one any good, and it will do you harm—if you
                            mind being called disagreeable. If you don't like any one's nose, or object to any one's
                            chin, don't put your feelings into words. If any one's manners don't please you, remember
                            your own. People are not all made to suit one taste ; recollect that. Take things as you
                            find them, unless you can alter them. Even a dinner, after it is swallowed, can't be made
                            any better. Continual fault-finding, continual criticism of the conduct of this one, and the
                            speech of that one, the dress of the other, and the opinions of the other, will make home
                            the unhappiest place under the sun. If you are never pleased with any one, no one will ever
                            be pleased with you. And if it is known you are hard to suit, few will take pains to suit
                            you. [We copy the following from The DewDrop, a beautiful little sheet, published at Shaker
                            Village, N. H. As it is the only rival The Shaker has, we are happier for thus noticing it.
                            It is printed anonymously, a favorite pastime with the people there, but it may be had by
                            addressing itself, as above, enclosing a two cent stamp.] Be a Christian. In journeying
                            through this life, long or short as it may be, the highest ambition, and greatest desire of
                            the mind should be to become a Christian ; not after the common acceptance of the term,
                            which is often a mere profession, but the inward life should be so «guided by the spirit of
                            Christ, that no evil thing would iind a place of abode therein. The spirit of retaliation—an
                            evil that</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Theological questions answered" TEIform="index"/>Theological Questions Answered</head><p TEIform="p">' Do you not believe that Jesus was an atonement for the sins of all who have believed, and
                            all who may believe in him as such?" g. d. w. As Shakers, we do not so believe \ although
                            some who are now living cirumspect Shaker lives have not yet fully persuaded themselves to
                            the contrary. We believe Jesus atoned for the mistakes of Jesus, if he made any ; or, if he
                            made none, illustrated how each might atone for his or her own misdeeds. The grand feature
                            of Jesus was not as a proxy, but as an exemplar ; by which others, seeing his good works and
                            godly life, might "go and do likewise." Herein, alone, is the index to true atonement. "
                            What was the mission of Jesus, while on earth ? "—Ibid. To save all who would be his people
                            from the necessity of committing sin— by setting an example for all who would be his
                            disciples, by which even the temptations to sin would become numbered among the
                            circumstances that were, but are no more. Jesus never even intimated that he came to save
                            people from the penalty of wrong actions committed. "According to your works, so shall your
                            reward be." " What is your opinion of baptism ? " A. Seeley. We have a very sacred opinion
                            of it. Without it there is no Christ, nor work of Christ in the soul. The baptisms of John
                            were good, as a figure to the baptism which was an antitype—the baptism of fire and the holy
                            spirit. Immersions, and sprinkling of water by the priests, may well be classed with the
                            sacrificial overtures of the Jews and heathen. But far better is that inward baptism that
                            convicts (teaches what is wrong) and converts (turns from sinful ways). We have no
                            confidence in any baptism, conversion, nor church-membership that does not speak a reform to
                            a better life. " Do you think the married can never go to heaven ? " c. s. t. That
                            necessitates a question from us. Heaven means a happy condition ; and there may be many who
                            are very happy in marriage. If marriage is no barrier to your highest conception of and
                            desire for heaven, then you should marry ; for the Jews thought so of old before
                            Christianity was broached. But do not think of living in the heavenly condition of Jesus,
                            nor of Christians, while marriage is your highest ideal of happiness. True christjans do not
                            condemn marriage, but live higher and better than it permits. Do not mistake us 38 <pb n="29" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHiiKEE. 29 in this : Marriage is good in its place— in the
                            world—good " for the children of the world ! " But there is a life as far above the
                            happiness of marriage as the heaven of Jesus is above the reproductions of Adam. Are you now
                            happy in marriage? "Is not the Shaker cross very unwillingly borne?" A. V. Secor. My dear
                            Secor: You will be surprised when I tell you that a faithful Shaker, by bearing his cross
                            against "the lusts of the flesh and of the mind," enjoys a satisfaction and justification
                            daily, which he would not exchange for all your pleasures of the flesh ! A Shaker not only
                            bears the crosses assigned him willingly, but finds it far easier than to engage in any or
                            all sensual pleasures. In fact, relieve a Shaker from bearing the crosses of his faith, and
                            you put him in hell immediately. You are mistaken. It would be very difficult, if not
                            impossible, to induce a Shaker to resign his cross, for he has worn out its unpleasantness,
                            [and it is now his crown of glory. "When will the Shakers give up the idea of Christ's
                            duality?" Andrew Judson. Never ; at least, not " So long^as sun and stars give light, And
                            Reason sways her scepter bright." There are, and are to be, female Christs as really as
                            Jesus became Christ. Christ means anointed ; and of the saviors that shall yet rise up on
                            Mt. Zion, we opine the majority will be female Christs. " What proportion of those who
                            become Shakers, remain so through life?" J. D. Although not a theological query, we answer:
                            Every one, without exception, who loves the life Jesus lived better than gross or refined
                            sensuality. Young man, as soon as "you are able," not before, you had better become a
                            candidate of Christianity, " for the kingdom of heaven's sake." "Can you advise me, as a
                            Christian, to relinquish my love and faith in the man Jesus, and to rely on my own efforts
                            for salvation?" E. Stacy. Our conscience commands us to advise no such thing. We do advise,
                            a a Christian, that you love Jesus more than you have ; and with an increase of genuine
                            love, will be an uncontrollable desire to live like him. Whatever we really love and worship
                            we will strive to be like. We grow in the likeness of God, or the god our lives worship. Our
                            fault-finding, is that people do not love Jesus sufficiently, nor have sufficient faith in
                            him, to aid them in doing the work every man and woman must do for himself and herself.*</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cement unequaled by any in the world" TEIform="index"/>A Cement unequaled by any in the World</head><p TEIform="p">"There is an excellent cement, which ought to be used freely by everyone. This cement is good
                            for family jars and social cuts. It heals wounds, and leaves no scars; mend life; binds
                            enemies together; mends damaged reputations; and is splendid for hun feelings. This
                            universal cement is love Love is a thing to be cultivated, as you woulc a solitary stalk of
                            wheat, supposing that there was not another grain of wheat in the world.' The above was
                            copied from the Am. Phren. Journal, and sent us by Joseph Slingerland of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                            It is very good cement,—good, like gold; its scarcity making it extremely valuable. Of this
                            cement, an ancient Shaker hymn thus engages : [s pure love and union my only free choice?
                            And do I this union possess? When others are honored, then do I rejoice And pity all those
                            in distress ? Is my heart delighted, when others are blest? And do I their happiness seek?
                            Or am I e'er striving their peace to molest? I call on my conscience to speak! For by this
                            criterion I now can decide, And know just the truth of the case; If I have that love that
                            will ever abide, It will selfish nature abase. I shall not be lofty, nor haughty, nor high ;
                            But little, and simple, and mild! I'll learn to esteem others better than I, And be an
                            obedient child. And the hymn goes on et cetera. If this cement proves cankerous, caustic,
                            clashing, and contentious; corroding, corrupting, lustful, or longing for lascivious
                            legitimacy; if on the tongue's end always, and never in the active heart's engagement, the
                            same is composed of spurious materials, and should be refused immediately. As good pudding
                            is best known, sometimes, by "chewing the pudding-string," so let us test all so-called love
                            by what if heals,—what it does that hate cannot do! "And though its name Has been usurped by
                            power, And profaned to unholy uses through all time, Still the eternal principle is pure "—
                            pure love. And where in the world can we find it? **</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Encouragement" TEIform="index"/>Encouragement</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hooser, Hortense" TEIform="persName"/>HORTENSE HOOSER</byline><p TEIform="p">Let all who believe in the second appearing Of Christ, the anointed, through good Mother Ann,
                            Resolve to go forward, by faithful crossbearing, And practice true peace and good-will unto
                            man. By daily obedience and strict self-denial, The soul is enabled to prosper and grow;
                            Through many earth-conflicts and many sore trials, Be joyfully leaving all sorrows below.
                            Remember, this work is not done by the slothful, The crown is not won, nor the treasure se
                            cured, Except by the brave, the devout, and determined, And such have their passports to
                            heaven insured. Should all within Zion live to their profession, How sweetly and smoothly
                            the moments would roll! The weak, inexperienced, be nursed and pro; tected, And love's
                            cheering pinions wave peace to the soul. The streamlets that flow very small at beginning,—
                            They deepen and widen while rippling along; Just so doth the soul that's established in Zion
                            Gain strength,—swell the ranks of the glorified throng. Then let all unitedly move on
                            together, The life-giving water will bear us safe through; While angelic guards are
                            surrounding the faithful, Diffusing rich blessings like heavenly dew. This earth-life is
                            only the time of probation, Through which living pilgrims are willing to go; Well-knowing
                            elysian fields lie before them, Where shortly they'll reap all the good seed they sow. With
                            hearts of thanksgiving, we'll adore God forever, That we have a place in his kingdom of
                            peace; With hearts of thanksgiving, we'll praise Christ and Mother, Whose fountain of love
                            will forever increase. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rleasant Hill, Kentucky, February 20" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hill, Ky., Feb. 20</head><p TEIform="p">Dearly beloved brother—G. A. Lomas: After expressing my thanks for your zealous and
                                persevering labors of love, in defence and support of our glorious cause, I present as a
                                brief apology for my protracted silence, the throng of duties consequent upon the heavy
                                loss we sustained by fire, and other adversities not convenient now to enumerate, the
                                preponderance of which has fallen upon the writer, in which his time is closely
                                occupied. In a. concise correspondence with the dear friends of Canterbury, N. H., we
                                men. tioned the demise of our very worthy and beloved Elder Thomas Shain, in the
                                eightyfourth year of his age, by-which it found its way into our precious literary gem,
                                The Shaker. I then thought it unnecessary to write any further on the subject; but
                                learning since that as it transpired so suddenly, there was some anxiety abroad to hear
                                the particulars of the case, we thought it would be proper to explain the sad event,
                                which, though it may be prized as a blessing to him, has deprived us of his useful and
                                muchneeded help in things spiritual and temporal. It is believed the primary cause of
                                his death was a fall from his horse, occasioned by a splint of the fence catching in the
                                stirrup, which threw him to the ground before he could check the horse, his head
                                striking the turnpike road, producing a concussion of the brain. He walked home, a
                                quarter of a mile, and was confined to his room a week or two, but revived enough to
                                ride out over the premises, perhaps too soon, and was again taken down with vomiting,
                                when paralysis ensued, which soon proved fatal. We could say much touching the long,
                                useful, and exemplary life of our beloved brother and earnest toiler in the Christian
                                cause, in which he enlisted in his youthful days, and consecrated his whole life to God,
                                never faltering while life was spared; but as we perceive your views accord with our own
                                on the subject that lengthy obituaries would not be expedient, we refrain. But we deeply
                                regret the loss of so substantial a pillar at this time. Dear friend, we enjoyed a rich
                                feast of good things with our beloved ministry of Mount Lebanon while on their western
                                tour, whose ministrations were with demonstrations of power in the holy spirit. Their
                                gift of quick perception enabled them to readily comprehend the situation and direct
                                their labor ot love where most needed for the protection, blessing, and prosperity of
                                Zion. It is to be hoped that their words of wisdom, their admonitions, and their living
                                testimonies may long live in the hearts of their children in this branch of Zion, and
                                bring forth the fruits of righteousness and peace an hundred fold. Concerning our
                                temporalities : After the fire that destroyed our barn and other buildings, we went to
                                work as soon as we could make the necessary arrangements, to rebuild in part, and the
                                barn, including horse and cow stables, was ready to be occupied in just three months
                                after the fire. We have since added a wagon-shed and crib. We were very opportune in
                                stabling the stock the first cold night of a severe spell of weather at that early
                                season. And when it moderated, got up the crib and shed just in time to escape a deep
                                snow and one of the severest spells of weather ever experienced here; during which
                                protracted cold the thermometer frequently ranged below zero,—at one time 120 below. It
                                has, in our remembrance, been lower, but the cold was not so protracted. This may sound
                                like child's play compared with your climate, but it was literally awful for us ! The
                                weather is now quite mild; but we find all the tender fruits destroyed in the bud,
                                including peaches, cherries, plums, etc., our principal preserving fruits, except
                                strawberries. Dear friend, we had been talking of sending for some copies of " Plain
                                Talks," if any were to be had, and were pleased to learn they were to be reprinted, as
                                we think it the best document for sincere inquirers, for genral circulation, and a good
                                home instructor. We shall be pleased to have our order filled for two hundred copies. *
                                * * A wail of hard times and dull business goes up from all parts of our great country,
                                in which, of course, we are included; and our rebuilding has so exhausted our available
                                means that we shall have to suspend business till we can recuperate our finances a
                                little. The religious element in this part of the world is a scarce article, and it is
                                difficult to find all the subscribers we want for our precious missionary, The Shaker,
                                because, instead of bringing peace to their order, it brings " rather division," being a
                                minister of Christ, whom they yet reject as did the Jews of old ; but the flood will
                                eventually overtake them. We are pleased, however, to find our friends from the "
                                evergreen shores " visiting" our children and youth of late, which is having some good
                                effect; and may the Lord prosper the good work, is our fervent prayer. In love unbounded
                                and ever-renewing fo all, and do not fail to impart from our order to the good ministry.
                                Your brother and fellowlaborer in the cause of truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dunlavy, B. B." TEIform="persName"/>B. B. DUNLAVY</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nicholville, New York, February 20, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Nicholville, N. Y., Feb. 20,
                                1877</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend Briggs : To you, as the publisher of The Shaker, and to the united societies
                                of Shakers, I do hereby tender my heartfelt thanks for the official monthly, called The
                                Shaker. * ** * I have carefully read every number of the last year, every article
                                therein, by which I have obtained a more thorough knowledge of your moral and religious
                                positions as a Christian community than I ever had before. In 1829, I was a member of
                                the New Hampshire legislature; and one Saturday, after adjournment, myself and two
                                others,—John Kent and John Peavey of Barnstead,—walked from Concord to your place, a
                                distance of twelve miles, and tarried in the society until Monday, attending your
                                meetings on Sunday, and were treated as kindly as if members of the society. There is no
                                other community of worshipers of God whose character for honesty, sincerity, and
                                uprightness stands so high in the estimation of the public of the nineteenth century,
                                through the length and breadth of our land, as does that of your people. Free from the
                                abominations so common in the world, satisfied to labor in your modest, unassuming
                                methods, which are very worthy of imitation. There is an economy in your system that all
                                should know of; and that is that your earnings are not expended for useless ornaments of
                                dress and buildings, so common for show, but without benefit. Had I known as much about
                                the Shakers years ago as after reading last year's volume, I can hardly tell you what
                                the consequences may have been. I am very happy to realize that there are such good
                                people in America as the Shakers ; and in my eighty-ninth year I happily, thankfully
                                subscribe myself your well-wisher, while wishing the utmost God-speed to The Shaker.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newell, Samuel" TEIform="persName"/>Samuel Newell</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York, March 1, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y., March 1, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker: The article in the February Shaker upon " The Shaker Covenant," clearly
                                defining our obligations as a community to stand unflinchingly in its support, not only
                                meets my warm approval, but I do not see how it could have been materially im- <pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> proved. None of us can deny the binding force of this sacred
                                compact upon us, as members of our societies. And our obedience thereto, or our
                                non-compliance with it, determines whether we shall stand or fall by it, from the
                                Christian standard. Its justness is clearly manifested, in that it controls each and all
                                alike; and if delegating superiority to any, it is upon the gospel principle, "let him
                                be servant of all." Our rights are all secure, so long as this covenant remains in full
                                force; and no privileged class can exercise an unchristian power upon any, but all are
                                bound to the most unselfish brotherhood by its wise provisions. But there is great
                                danger, beloved editor, as believers in our faith grow in the wealth of this world's
                                goods, that selfishness and a worldly ambition for place and power may seek to exercise
                                an unShaker dominion over the weaker brethren. A vast amount of trouble may be made or
                                avoided by carefully studying your excellent treatise upon this subject, and guiding our
                                conduct thereby. Man naturally loves to exercise authority over his fellows; and if he
                                is not brought under Christian influences, becomes oppressive by a little brief power.
                                Aware of this fact, let us jealously guard our sacred charter against any entering wedge
                                that ignores the golden rule and the rights of all the brotherhood. Thanking you for the
                                ringing clearness of that article, I am yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beaver, Orrin" TEIform="persName"/>Orrin Beaver</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="N. A. Briggs, publisher—dear sir:" TEIform="index"/>N. A. Briggs, publisher—Dear Sir:</head><p TEIform="p">Please find sixty cents inclosed for The Shaker, for 1877. Have you last year's numbers
                                for sale, and at what price? The Lord bless your paper and the good work it is doing.
                                May the Lord use it as an instrument to bring souls to Christ; that they may take the
                                waters of life freely, and be thereby saved from their sins, is the prayer of your
                                brother in Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burns, L. A." TEIform="persName"/>L. A. Burns Leominster, Mass.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Louisville, Kentucky, February 15, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Louisville, Ky., Feb. 15, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Bro. Eades: I have this day received another evidence of your kindness in the
                                welcome visit of that highly-prized periodical, The Shaker. I recognize my indebtedness
                                to you for its regular visits, which afford me so much instruction, refresh my spiritual
                                man, point me to a purer, higher life, and elevate my aspirations above that sordid and
                                sensual plane upon which humanity plods its weary way to the grave. I feel that I cannot
                                sufficiently thank you for having placed that periodical in my hands. But for you its
                                existence might have been unknown to me, and I would have been deprived of that valuable
                                information which I receive from its columns, It is no ordinary periodical, intended to
                                advocate mere selfish human interests. It isnot set for the defence of worldly
                                organizations, founded for the acquisition of worldly honors,~\ emoluments, or personal
                                aggrandizements ; but it is a harbinger of the reign of peace, purity, and true
                                holiness; and I earnestly wish it may find its way into every professed Christian home ;
                                that it will reach thousands of firesides, where at present it is unknown. You will
                                excuse me for saying that with all due deference to the judgment of the publisher, I
                                think the selection of the present quarto form instead of octavo was injudicious, and is
                                regretted by many friends of the periodical. Its present form makes it very ephemeral,
                                and from being frequently folded and unfolded in its perusal, it is soon and easily worn
                                out, and few of its subscribers have an opportunity of reading the pages a second time,
                                though much of its matter is worthy of being read many times, and preserved in a bound
                                volume. In its present shape it would make, if bound, a large, cumbersome, and unhandy
                                volume of 11 1-2 by 15 inches. By changing the form to an octavo it would be 7 1-2 by 11
                                inches. It might then be read and laid aside for subsequent perusals previous to being
                                bound. * * * I make these suggestions only on account of my high appreciation of the
                                work, and my firm belief that the matter contained in it is worthy of frequent perusal;
                                and will make any man or woman better, who shall diligently study its teachings, and act
                                upon the principles inculcated therein. Present my kind regards to Elder Jno. R. Cooper,
                                and believe me to be fraternally thine,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., J. H." TEIform="persName"/>J. H. B. Elder H. L. Eades. [We would make all Kentucky stare
                                if we should print the above initials in full name— and we do not care for the stare
                                particularly; but hope that The Shaker may find its way into a good many more homes in
                                Kentucky, and be as highly appreciated as by this highly-honored individual, equally
                                well by state and nation! Ed.]</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual Eden" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL EDEN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert; Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Albert Lomas. ±31 James G-.
                            Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">We are told of a blest spirit land, Where flowers eternally bloom, Whose "evergreen shores"
                            whose angelic band— Will greet us beyond the cold tomb. We arp told of its cities of light,
                            Whose streets are all paved with gold, Whose inmates are clothed in purity bright, where
                            none suffer hunger nor cold.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture. No. 2</head><p TEIform="p">KNOWLEDGE. Knowledge in the human being is the foundation of all culture—physical, mental,
                            and moral. It is so intimately connected with all true thought that it is impossible for the
                            one to exist without the other. The Infinite possesses infinite knowledge, and hence devises
                            and executes all his plans with unerring certainty. Man is limited in all his faculties, and
                            necessarily limited in his knowledge, and thus liable to errors. There is no necessity of
                            supposing a self-existing devil or principle of evil to account for the zigzag course of
                            mankind ever since its existence <pb n="31" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>upon the earth. Ignorance in the
                            beginning may be the cause of early faults and mistakes, and the effects of early mistakes
                            trans mitted may and do form proclivities to still other faults, proceeding in an increasing
                            ratio, unless checked by some superior power. Knowledge is not the saving principle, yet it
                            must precede the internal power that checks, restrains, and delivers. Whoever invoked God
                            that had no idea of God ? Conscience, the internal monitor that warns, reproves, or
                            approves, takes its name from the fact that knowledge is always its attendant when it is in
                            its normal condition. The more extensive an^ accurate the knowledge of duty, when the
                            judgment is well-poised, the greater the power felt of obligations to duty. An unenlightened
                            conscience — if that is not a misnomer—has been the originator of unnumbered wrongs done in
                            the name of conscience—wrongs of the most aggravated character. It is true, there are those
                            " who know their duty and do it not." Many are accomplished villains, polished scoundrels,
                            who avail themselves of their knowledge of law the more effectually to evade law. But where
                            must the blame be laid—upon knowledge itself, or the moral condition of the individual
                            person ? Perversity of character may turn the very best of blessings to curses. A broad
                            assertion respecting knowledge has been ascribed to the Apostle Paul,— "Knowledge puffeth
                            up."—/. Corinthians, viii. 1. But our English translators are responsible for that rather
                            than Paul. If they had rendered the two words, he gnosis, in the first verse as they did the
                            very same words in the seventh verse, " that knowledge," they would have made the statement
                            particular rather than general, as Paul did. The apostle evidently alluded to some in the
                            Corinthian church who had much self-satisfaction in their knowledge that there is but one
                            God, and could therefore eat with impunity the meats offered in sacrifice to idols, without
                            regard to their weaker brother who was still influenced by his former superstitions. They
                            were "puffed up" with their knowledge instead of possessing the " love which edifies." It
                            was a just reproof given them, " that they knew nothing yet" respecting Christian love, " as
                            they ought to have known." There is much in the world that passes under the name of
                            knowledge which is not really such. It is found in connection with theology, medicine,
                            jurisprudence, and science, generally. The doctor of divinity professes to be teacher of
                            sacred things; the doctor of medicine claims to know somethink about human health and
                            disease; the doctor of laws to be acquainted with the methods that should regulate human
                            society, or with the laws pertaining to the physical universe; but, compared with the vast
                            fields that yet lie unexplored, how little do they all know! And, if they sift from the mass
                            of what appertains to their several departments that which they positively know, what heaps
                            of rubbish remain ! The fact of their ignorance is made very evident by the want of harmony
                            among those who listen, week after week, and year after year, to those who profess to teach
                            divine truths; by the vast amount of disease still existing even where physicians are most
                            numerous; and the discords that still prevail in spite of the efforts of politicians,
                            statesmen, and rulers generally to govern the world. What, then ? Has nothing been gained to
                            repay the time and labor spent in making the vast accumulations displayed in those several
                            departments of human effort? Not so. Truth is evolved from error. It has made its
                            appearance, little by little, all along. First the seeming and then the real. Man's
                            resurrection is nothing more than a succession of steps from the lowest depths of earth to
                            the sun-lit realms of the highest heavens. Something can and will be acquired all along the
                            way. It matters not, though the process be slow, if the ultimate acquisition be sure. The
                            divine forces are ever active, and have already formed a world of wondrous beauty and
                            splendor. Yet there are deserts here and there; and, if we would see them "rejoice and
                            blossom as the rose," human efforts, conjoined with human wisdom,^must unite with divine
                            power to bring about the glorious consummation. The streams from the river of life must be
                            directed wherever they are needed to produce the desired fertility. If there are
                            inequalities throughout, then so much more the need of knowledge to convey the waters over
                            hillock and hill, as well as through ravine and valley.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual Eden" TEIform="index"/>Spiritual Eden
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert; Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Chorus. Zion,-— our Eternal home. No darkness, nor death, but life, light and Oh, what joy to
                            be there in that bright land above— That beautifill love In that Spiritual Eden— our eternal
                            home. 2. We are told of its seasons so fair,— Its eternal spring and its youth, No
                            sickness—no pain, nor poisonous air, No slander—no pride, nor untruth. Of its bright "sea of
                            glass" we have heard— The pearls and the gems on its shore, No troublesome noise—the songs
                            of the birds Are adding their joy evermore. Chorus 3. We are told that the spirit of war Is
                            known in that land, never more, But halcyon love and union are there— A brotherhood scene
                            evermore. We are told, would we reach that blest sphere, And earn an inheritance there, To
                            labor with care for heaven while here— By living the life they live there. Chorus. 4. To the
                            joys of a heaven made here, Add bliss of the angelic band, A heaven on earth, sure then will
                            appear, A foretaste of that happy land. Let us press for the "evergreen shores;" We'll make
                            all its pleasures our own ; And be angels here, and there evermore— In Eden—our eternal
                            home. Chorus.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is duty?" TEIform="index"/>What is Duty?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p">For a very long time my mind has been exercised upon the condition of our Zion; how the
                            gospel of Christ was maintained by our spiritual fathers and mothers ; how, unto the present
                            time, it has been perpetuated and its powers preserved ; and how, by the present and coming
                            generations, it is to be supported and preserved inviolate, free from the impurities and
                            amalgamations of human influences and worldly principles. The effects of the demoralizing
                            influences of society, almost universally in all ranks of life, are largely realized; even
                            in the quiet, peaceful, Christian Shaker church, so peculiarly characterized for its
                            religious devotion, consecration, and sacrifice, the young and inexperienced are not
                            unfrequently befogged and ruined ; and older members, superficially planted in gospel soil,
                            correspondingly suffer from the blight and infection of the spirit of the times. The
                            highly-revered testimonies of our church, " Take no thought for the morrow," and " Live
                            to-day as though you had a thousand years to live," are in the letter conflicting; yet both
                            have their valued significance, and in their significance and meaning a principle <pb n="32" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. is involved. The idea of living only for today is contracted and
                            selfish; it unveils lowmental conditions and discloses lack of judgment and absence of
                            reason. Again, living principally for the future is miserly and inconsistent with reason. It
                            deprives man of present enjoyment, and is eminently calculated to weaken the power of
                            protection and destroy the basis of progress. The two principles of the foregoing quotations
                            are as essential to promote the growth, development, increase, and prosperity of Zion, as it
                            is necessary that the two great principles, conservatism and radicalism, should not be lost
                            sight of, but should be faithfully cultivated and unremittingly maintained, if we would
                            retain an unadulterated existence, and find an unfoldment of greater truths. As dear to us
                            as have been the form and manner of ca:*rying out the order of our gospel institution, as
                            transmitted to us by our spiritual leaders; as great sticklers as we have been to orthodoxy,
                            for the maintenance of principle in the support of pure society relations; yet, as we find
                            conditions, legitimate or illegitimate, so we must meet them, shaping our course as our
                            wisdom will best subserve the object for which we labor most successfully, to meet the end
                            and give justification to our own souls. The momentous question before us is,— What is.
                            duty? The peace, the justification, and comforts of life hang upon this lesson; and however
                            wantonly or superficially the subject is considered, future welfare is largely predicated
                            upon present calculation, and present action. Although in a variety of forms, principle may
                            be sustained ; yet under no circumstances can we depart from it in justification. This is a
                            fundamental axiom. Change of condition often requires change of operation, but will never
                            justify abandonment of principle. It may sometimes be in our power to control circumstances,
                            by which we secure more favorable results. Napoleon the First, under a pressing trial,
                            strove to impress this idea upon his generals ; to this principle of action were very much
                            owing his success and prosperity in life; yet the poor man was sometimes amazingly
                            misguided, and with all his talent, wisdom, shrewdness, and strength of intellect, he failed
                            in the end, closing his days in misery and suffering, produced by miscalculation, stimulated
                            by pride and unworthy ambition. From fruits of others' and personal experiences, we may
                            learn lessons of wisdom ; or we may, by our conceit and selfishness, unprofitably and
                            blindly toil, making life worse than a blank, ending in dishonor and shame, and emblazoned
                            as a curse on the pages of history. Although this production may shed no light, may present
                            no other than cogitations of a personal character, yet some may be able to indorse them as
                            painful truths.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><p TEIform="p">Again, dear children, I sit down, with an exceeding pleasure, to have a talk with you. I say
                            exceeding, because I have received very flattering evidences from some of you, and your
                            friends, that I am doing good thereby. Let us talk of Thoughts. Do you know that thoughts
                            are real things? that they have an existence as really as trees, flowers, birds and men ?
                            There are things that are thoughtless ; but there are few or no animals but have thoughts.
                            The steam engine, the waterwheel, the wind-mill, etc., are powerful, but cannot think. But
                            thinking beings made these and all other machinery, to aid the development of thought. Once,
                            the steam engine, as all other mechanical and artistic arrangements, was as chaotic as
                            thousands of inventions yet unthought of. Our thoughts at first, may be compared to stores
                            of crude material, out of which we take a mind-full, as of clay we take a handful; and of
                            our mind-full of material, we can form figures fair or foul, just as we please. Knowing
                            this, my children, I am anxious you should always make good images from the much
                            thoughtmaterial at your command. When you make a thought, it becomes an image of some kind,
                            and we call it imagination—which being defined, means, the act of making images. Now let us
                            discover where our actions come from. Before we act at any time, we necessarily think how we
                            shall act. Some of you may be prompted by your experiences to unfavorably criticise this;
                            for, you may ask: 'Does not a boy or girl sometimes act without thinking?" To which I reply:
                            Never! Too commonly, we all act without sufficient maturity in our plans of thought—without
                            due consideration. Now, as we must first :hink before we can act, then let us carefully
                            train our modes of thinking, and our deeds and words will illustrate this thought-training.
                            Who thinks only good thoughts, always speaks and acts goodness! Every word we speak, every
                            little or large act we perform, every good and every evil we speak or do— all are formed in
                            the mind, mapped out ere they are committed ! Sometimes, we pause, consider, make a new
                            image, mark out a new course, and do differently—because we remodeled our intentions. All
                            the causes of good and ill feeling lie within the limits of our thought-factory—in our
                            imaginations. STow for the application, children: Make good thoughts, beautiful pictures of
                            the mind, and beauty, and love, and blessing will De the certain fruits. Resolve not to make
                            up an unworthy figure to think upon; not to ;hink angrily, uncleanly, jealously, enviously,
                            avariciously. Resolve to be noble men and women! manufacturers of godly thoughts-images we
                            know that God looks on with pleasure. Would you resist evil temptations ? Deny them
                            formation in your mind; for, when you have made evil images, and permit yourselves to
                            worship or admire them, jrour heart is getting ready for the full act of commission of sin!
                            Now, dear children, think how great is your power, if you deny to yourselves the practices
                            of making evil thoughts. A little child, in this self-denial and at the time when plans of
                            mischief are laid, has more power for good, than the giant intellects, who, failing to work
                            in the mind, for proper guidance of imaginations, become the subjects of the worst of
                            tyrants— the passions!</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind editor:" TEIform="index"/>Kind Editor:</head><p TEIform="p">I read your article to " youth and children" in the last number of our paper, at the
                                opening of school as soon as in my possession. The children seemed to appreciate the
                                paternal advice ; and Henry Clough has written his thanks, and the expression of our
                                little school. You will accept it as a purely original letter, and know, should you feel
                                to give him any advice, it will be acceptable. He seemed afraid I might alter the letter
                                somewhat, and thus I gave entire place to his expanding, manly powers, knowing the keen
                                eye of the editor would detect any blunder; and should he offer amendments it might do
                                quite as much good as though from one who has the constant discipline. With many thanks
                                for past favors, and especially those kind words to we little folks, I subscribe myself
                                your humble sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Emma J." TEIform="persName"/>Emma J. Neal Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, February 14, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Feb. 14, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Dear brother Albert : As soon as the February number of The Shaker was committed to our
                                keeping, my eyes fell upon the beautiful piece, entitled, "The Children's Grotto,"
                                "Talks to youth and children." Perusing it, I could not refrain from thanking the
                                author. Such considerations for the young, should not and cannot (by the thoughtful)
                                pass unnoticed, among believers or by others. Being one of those fortunate, or
                                unfortunate boys, possessed of much life, I am capable of making things rattle a little
                                sometimes, and perhaps when I ought not to. But there is life in children as you remark,
                                and it must come out one way or another. I have read your article several times, but
                                will do more than read; I will impress it on my mind and mould my actions by the
                                principles it contains. I really wonder a brother, having so many things to occupy your
                                mind, and things that are above childhood too, could spend time to have such an
                                interesting ;alk with us; and so we have reason to be :hankful for this also. I may not
                                appreciate your remarks as deepy in my ignorant condition, as in riper years, but hope
                                to show an increasing appreciation by my future deportment. I am not alone in
                                appreciating your sentiments, but many others of my schoolmates lave resolved to
                                discipline ourselves that we may make agreeable and useful men at some iuture date. In
                                love and respect I subscribe myself,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clough, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>Henry Clough</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">[Thank you, little friend, for the comfort yourself and companions return to me. We do
                                not know how old you are, but your penmanship is admirable. We could scarcely do better
                                ourself. Try on. Ed.] </p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meteorological observations" TEIform="index"/>Meteorological Observations, for the year
                            ending Junuary 31, 1877;</head><byline TEIform="byline"> taken af Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., by <persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>Louis Basting</byline><p TEIform="p">Elevation of station above sea-level, about 1200 feet. Result based upon two daily
                            observations, taken at 5 a. m., and 12 m. : Mean temperature,...... f44 1-2 Mean temperature
                            at 5 a. m., . . . f$8 Mean temperature at 12 m., . . . f5o 1-2 Lowest temperature, Dec. 17,
                            . . . -9 Highest temperature, July 12, . . 193 73 &gt; Mean Temperature, at Labrador,
                            |25; Archangel, f44 5 Lomberg, f44; Gottenburg, f46; Trieste, f5g; Vienna, +51; Melbourne,
                            {59; London, }$o; Algiers, f 63; Barbadoes, f8o; Manheim, f5o; Bahamas, fS3; Batavia, t78.
                            Winds. West, 167 ; northwest, 38; southwest, 11; south, 57; north, 35; east, 32; rest
                            scattering.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crooker, Sarah Amelia" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Amelia Crooker
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canterbury, N. H., Feb. 13, <persName reg="Crooker, Sarah Amelia" TEIform="persName">Sarah Amelia
                                Crooker</persName>, aged 50. Mentally, morally, spiritually, a brilliant adornment of
                                our Israel; but physically fragile. Pity it is that such could not have bodies that
                                would last a thousand years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jones, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Jones
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky., Feb. 10, 1877,<persName reg="Jones, Polly" TEIform="persName">Polly Jones</persName>,
                                aged 93.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Webber, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>Caroline Webber
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., Feb. I5, 1877, <persName reg="Webber, Caroline" TEIform="persName">Caroline
                                Webber</persName>, aged 80 years. Influential in bringing some of the most staunch
                                supporters of our faith into our ranks on earth, she has ever deserved the grateful
                                thanks of all Zion.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our congratulation" TEIform="index"/>Our Congratulation</head><p TEIform="p">Our noble publisher writes us : "The general verdict is such, that I congratulate you upon
                            the improvement of our paper. Your editorials are very worthy of consideration. I am
                            unchanged in my opinion, that it is far oetter to say pussy sometimes, than to say cat
                            always! (This advice prevents our saying things very plainly, except in ' Plain Talks.' )
                            Even Jesus, the radical, was reticent upon subjects which he knew would not be appreciated
                            nor understood. He was wise. The gospel, though so simple that ' a "ool needs not err,'
                            cannot be sustained 3y fools, nor will a foolish, rash zeal tend to its increase."</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Briggs, N. A." TEIform="persName"/>N. A. Briggs</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are remembered" TEIform="index"/>We are Remembered</head><p TEIform="p">The dear, good sisterhood of a certain mountain home, appreciating our labors on our little
                            Shaker have most kindly sent us a set of nice shirts. We do not know what we have done
                            worthy of such a compliment; but we are full of resolves to work more earnestly for the
                            cause, because of such kindly remembrances. We should be pleased io publish the loving
                            letter accompanying—so full of the clear, sweet, tangiole gospel love and sentiment; but
                            they will not permit. Unsalaried, but we are remembered!</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Particular notice" TEIform="index"/>PARTICULAR NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The American Agriculturist is a very worthy monthly. Its subscription price is $1.60. We will
                            send The Shaker and it together during 1877 for $1.50!! Now take advantage of our offer, and
                            get both for less than quar:er cost. Address the Publisher of The Shaker.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The days of man's years would be much more rounded..." TEIform="index"/>The days of man's years would be much more rounded...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., A. A." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"The days of man's years " would be much more rounded and sweet did he understand
                                    and appreciate the real object of existence. To keep alive the divinity within, at
                                    whatever sacrifice of reputation, fortune or sensuous enjoyment, should be his
                                    highest endeavor. Standing in awe, as we sometimes do, at the heights and depths of
                                    thought and feeling, we know our own spirits to be capable of reaching, dwarfed and
                                    marred as they are, we are dumb with wonder at the glorious possibilities of peace
                                    and power that await the more enlightened human soul. Why are we not better taught
                                    in childhood ? Why does not some friendly guide show us the paths that surely lead
                                    to the azure heights of contentment and trust whereon man was meant to dwell ? So
                                    much time is lost in retracing false steps; so many days are consumed in waiting for
                                    wounds to heal before we can attempt further progress, that lo ! old age finds us
                                    still gasping amid the noisome fogs of the valley. I believe that man, by being true
                                    to his highest conceptions of right, can surround himself by such an atmosphere of
                                    love and hope, that the crimson glories of each rising day will be but faintly
                                    typical of the glowing aspirations that shall fill his soul each morn, and the
                                    golden splendors of eventide shall pale before the sacred fires that give light and
                                    warmth to all who come within the range of his affections.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit> A. A. W. in New Age</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I have been and seen the wants of people, and returning to my own home, have fairly hated the                                 comforts that surrounded me" TEIform="index"/>I have been and seen the wants of people...          </head><p TEIform="p">" I have been and seen the wants of people, and returning to my own home, have fairly hated
                            the comforts that surrounded me."</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Hall" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Hall</byline></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>