<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2508" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="18950801" TEIform="date">August 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">171-194</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
AUGUST.
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL. XXV.
'' Cast tht bread upon the waters ; for thou shalt find it after, many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
THE
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MA JV IFEb TO.
CONTENTS.
The Separating Line,
Sermon on the Mount,
The New Day,        7
Dietetics,
Letter,O. C. Hampton,
E. B. Gillette,
Charity,
Ill-Temper,
Elnvy,        -       -       -       Be not deceived,
Xotes about Home,
S unitary,
Good Manners,
Exchanges,
Strength for To-day,
If you woul 1 make,
"Mother Ann"
The Easy Road,
Gaining Ground,
Acrostic from Piov.,
Deaths,
Books & Papers,
Page171
-    172
13
170
-     177
-     178
180
-     18-2
185
-     189
190
192
195
191
WANTED
Good reliable men, to sell
our Choice and Hardy
I Nursei'5' Stock such as Fruit
'Trees, Roses Shrubs and Ornamentals. Ladies make this business a success. Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Frkk. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
!E\  1ST.  M^-Y   COM^AJNTY,
Nurserymen  and   Seedsmen,   Roches,
ter, 3S". Y.
AGENTS
Salary or commission to t/ood men.
Fast selling Imported Specialties.
Stock falling to live replaces free.
Also Pure Seed Potato Stock our Leader
"Lincoln," (480 bu, per acre pastseasor
Address   R. D. LUTCHFORD &   CO.
( Letters promptly answered.)   ROCHESTER,  N. Y
THE DIVINE AFFLATUS
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
CAVEATS .TRADEMARKS;
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I ORTATN A PATENT? Fora
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN fc CO., who liave bad nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning I'atelits and bow to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue Of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world.   S3 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, ijS cents. Fvery number contains beautiful plates, in colors, arid photoprapbs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and Foeure contracts.   Address
MUNN & CO., New York, 301 BJRCU.DWAT.
DICTIONARY
U. S. HISTORY.
United States History, less of a mvstery
Now to the masses than ever before.
W e have a great want supplied, all facts we've
simplified,
And to all knowledge we've opened the door.
So simple the chronicle, gaze through a monocle.
!   But one eye's needed to gather the fact.
Our volumn a peer '.s and all that we hear is.
The sounds of applause for our genius and tact.;
All facts alphabetical, 'tis less enigmatical,
We acknowledge it came with the cleverest
thought.                                             ence,
.The best book of reference, we say it with deferNo other book like it has ever been bought.
The man who compiled it, who wrote out and
styled it
In Historic Research has reached the extreme;
A prcfessor of colleges, you'll agree that his
knowledge is
By the great masses considered supreme.
"We want men to sell it; no one can repel it;
At homes, schools and colleges, sales can be
made.                                                tions,
Just write for instructions, our Bmall introducThere's more money in it than ever you have
made.
can make more gales with less talk
and less walking with this book
than with anything else they ever sold. It
appeals to everybody. It is handsome, entertaining and useful. It is good for every
member of the familyuseful alike to
schoolboy and grandpa! Write for circulars and terms to
Puritan Publishing Co,, Boston, Mass.
The ordinary pot is sometimes hot to
lift, as well as always heavy, and sometimes the liquor splashes. You can not
tell exactly when it will start, for the tipping must vary with the quantity in the
pot. Sometimes it is hard to avoid getting too much and "pouring over;" sometimes it is hard to get enough. Is it not
delightful to be delivered from all this?
See "adv." on another page,
WANTED--><pb n="171" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Separating line" TEIform="index"/>THE SEPARATING LINE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE pure in heart shall see God. No others have this promise. If any can not see God and know
                            that He is, it is because their hearts are impure, or are devoted to secular affairs.
                            Without holiness, no man shall see the Lord. Holy means cleansed, conseciated, or set apart
                            for Divine service. The saints and holy ones, both mean the same. These form the kingdom of
                            the God of heaven, which is destined to consume and break in pieces all the kingdoms of this
                            world; and become a great mountain and fill the whole earth: for out of Zion shall go forth
                            the law, and the word of the Lord from Jerusalem. And the kingdom and greatness of the
                            kingdom under the whole heaven, shall be given to the people of the saints of the Most High
                            and they shall take and possess the kingdom forever. The Lord, bread-giver and Ruler of this
                            kingdom, is Jesus Christ, who is King of Kings, and Lord of Lords. He said "For their sake,"
                            meaning his disciples, "I sanctify myself." To sanctify, is to cleanse and make holy. He
                            that sanctifieth and they that are sanctified are all one. "Ye are clean through the word
                            which I have spoken unto you" said Jesus, to his disciples. It was his testimony against the
                            evils of the natural heart. From within, out of the heart of man, proceed evil thoughts,
                            adulteries, fornications, murders, thefts, covetousness, wickedness, deceit, blasphemy,
                            pride, foolishness, false witness. Christ has a word of testimony against all these things,
                            which are part and parcel with the corrupt nature of the flesh ;Matt, xv., 18, also Mark,
                            vii., 21. We can be cleansed from these things only by the word of our testimony, given in
                            the power of God, and by the daily cross against the loves, desires and emotions of the
                            flesh. Mother's gospel teaches us to hate these and put them behind us. The AUGUST, <pb n="172" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 172 THE MANIFESTO. works of the flesh, are among the most deadening,
                            and soul darkening, that creatures can commit. It is the root of all other sins, and is the
                            nourislu r and support of all. Its affects are the most persistent of an}7, and its stains
                            most difficult to wash out. The shame and dishonor which cultivated people feel, in exposing
                            those deeds to the light, is the mark and seal of Divine displeasure thereat, and of their
                            utter condemnation in the judgment, and perpetual banishment from Divine Presence. Be ye
                            clean, be ye pure that bear the vessels of Jehovah. The line of separation betwixt clean and
                            unclean, is drawn in the heart of all true disciples. He that looketh on a woman to lust
                            after her, hath already committed adultery with her in his heart. And this we say, No
                            adulterer, no unclean person can enter the kingdom of God. The New Jerusalem state is clear
                            as crystal and diaphanous, transmitting light in all directions, and the pure in heart shall
                            see that God and the Lamb is the light thereof. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sermon on the mount" TEIform="index"/>THE SERMON ON THE MOUNT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>By Aurelia G. Mace.</byline><p TEIform="p">IN the Arena for March, 1892, Charles Schrodes asks the question, "Where do we find the
                            Christian teachers of any sect, creed or denomination, who dare to preach and live, or even
                            accept this grand Sermon in its entirety?" If he should visit the Shaker Communities, he
                            would find a people who do accept the Sermon on the Mount, as their guide, whose aim is to
                            control their lives by its teachings in every respect. He would find in them some who are
                            true followers of Jesus the Christ, and who have in reality, entered "The Path" and are
                            walking the straight and narrow path that leads to life eternal. During the six hundred
                            years, from Buddha to Jesus, spiritual light was increasing, and Friend Schrodes is right in
                            ranking the teachings of Buddha second to those of Jesus. Both of these great teachers
                            opened to the people a l 'Path, which the vulture's eye hath not seen : The lion's whelps
                            have not trodden it, nor the fierce lion passed by it." "Enter the path," said Buddha to
                            those who would be his followers, (among these were some of his nearest relations,) when he
                            returned from the wilderness, enlightened, illumed and all animal passions subdued.
                            "Straight is the gate and narrow is the way which leadeth unto life, and few there be that
                            find it," said Jesus. In all the ages that are passed, how few there have been, who have
                            entered the straight and narrow way and turned neither to the right nor to the left, but
                            kept onward and upward until they have reached the heights for which they started. <pb n="173" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 173 Few, by the discipline brought to bear upon their
                            daily lives, have found their spirits purified, all selfishness eradicated and every evil
                            passion subdued, but that it can be done has been proved by loyal souls. If Friend Schrodes
                            will visit Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., East Canterbury, N. H., even our little home at Sabbathday
                            Lake, Me. or any of the Shaker Societies, he will find people who lift up their voices in
                            denunciation of war and all the evils of the day and also of the night. It is not because
                            their number is so small that they are not heard. The multitude have blinded their own eyes
                            and stopped their own ears. They will not see, they will not hear. Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New day" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW DAY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McLeod, Isabella" TEIform="persName"/>By Isabella McLeod.</byline><p TEIform="p">Shine out, O glorious sun of truth And usher in the day When all mankind shall brothers be,
                            And equal rights bear sway. When tramping, needy workers Of God's fair fruitful land Will by
                            a Moses guided In triumph take their stand. A stand for life and liberty. For justice, truth
                            and right, And not for sordid millions Gained through oppression's might. When sturdy honest
                            toilers Need never suffer dearth, But find in hours of plenty Sweet peace upon the earth.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dietetics" TEIform="index"/>DIETETICS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">fTIHE life-blood as it courses through the body, building up waste tissue, I vitalizing and
                            vivifying the constituent elements of the animal organism tells us by its varied
                            manifestations, whether it is composed of good or poor material. If bone, brain and muscle
                            are strong and vigorous, we may conclude that they receive their proper aliment; if the
                            osseous structure is frail, <pb n="174" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE MANIFESTO. the nervous system
                            weak, and the muscular fibre incapable of sustaining labor and fatigue, then is the cause
                            apparentinsufficient nutrition. In order to ensure a perfect state of health, the digestive
                            organs must be in good condition, for the nourishment of the body is dependent on the
                            healthful action of the stomach. Thorough mastication greatly aids the gastric fluid in the
                            assimilation of the food, which after it passes into the intestines in a state of
                            chylification, is taken up by the lacteals and the thoracic duct, and conveyed in a fluid
                            state to the heart, thence to the lungs, where it becomes oxygenated, and chemically
                            changed, prepared as fit material for constructing the house we live in. The primary
                            elements contained in food, are oxygen, hydrogen, carbon and nitrogen; the combination of
                            these in different apportionment, makes the variety in the animal and vegetable kingdoms. A
                            certain amount of each is necessary for structural purposes, but nitrogen is essentially one
                            of the flesh forming ingredients ; some carbon is needed for warmth, but an excess of
                            carbonaceous matter clogs the machinery of the human system, and superinduces disease, which
                            in its various manifestations, is the effect of the accumulation of foreign matter, and the
                            effort of nature to rid the body of it. Oxygen and hydrogen also act an important part in
                            carrying forward the great processes of physical construction. The result of chemical
                            analysis proves, that the common idea that animal food being more nutritious than vegetable
                            is false. "It is the stimulating property of meat which has led to the impression .that it
                            is more nourishing than a vegetable diet." There are no nutritive properties in fat; like
                            sugar, and other concentrated articles, it is purely carbonaceous. Persons who for many
                            years have been accustomed to a certain regime, find it difficult to change, especially if
                            they depend on the stimulus of a flesh diet, which they mistake for strength. Children
                            inherit the vitiated appetites of their parents for food as well as alcoholic drink, and
                            meat eating has much to do with the abnormal thirst for liquor. ;iOne of the strongest
                            proofs of the radical impropriety of man's feeding on flesh, must be that which is armed
                            with the fact, that the human body invariably withers and perishes most miserably when
                            constantly confined to it. It cannot be denied that a diet consisting exclusively of fruit
                            and farinaceous matters is favorable to the constitution." That flesh is unsuitable for
                            human food, has been insisted on by philosophers of all ages. Celsus affirms, "that much
                            animal food induces premature old agedecrepitude and disease." The ancient athletes who were
                            fed much on flesh, were said to be the most stupid of men; Diogenes said, when asked the
                            cause, "It is because they are wholly formed of the flesh of swine and oxen." Atilla, the
                            king of the Huns, a cruel and blood-thirsty monarch, devoured large quantities of meat. It
                            was said of him that he never knew the taste of bread, while Appolonius, the pure souled
                            humanitarian, lived on bread and <pb n="175" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. . 175 drank water
                            only. Who can judge how much the diet affected the extremely opposite character of each.
                            Nomadic races need more land to supply them with the fruits of the chase, than do the
                            peasantry of those civilized countries-who gain a livelihood by tilling the soil. Indeed,
                            perfect scientific agriculture would limit a man to a very small tract of land from which to
                            obtain needful food. The laboring classes of almost every nation are obliged to live simply,
                            and their very necessity is their physical salvation, and in them lies the hope of the
                            perpetuity of the race. Americans as a rule are a nation of dyspeptics; meat three times a
                            day, hot biscuit, lard-crusted pie and strong tea destroy the digestive apparatus and create
                            a host of nervous invalids. Helen Campbell, in her charming New England story, "Some
                            Passages in the Practice of Dr. Martha Scarborough," makes the doctor say some plain and
                            caustic things in reference to the health-destroying diet of the descendants of the Pilgrim
                            Fathers. Our ancestors knew something of privation and want, but in this age of reckless
                            extravagance, even among the poorer classes, perverted appetites are pampered, and "sugar,
                            starch and fat" enter largely into the regime of the masses. A highly wrought, nervous
                            temperament which predominates among the Americans, needs nutritive, but not stimulating
                            food, the former is found in fruits, grains and cereals,the best gifts of Mother Earth; yet
                            how sad to think that even these are turned into body and soul ruining beverages, and
                            thousands more of God's rich acres are wasted with the raising of the obnoxious tobacco
                            plant,the nerve shatterer and blood poisoner of the people in this so-called enlightened
                            age. God in his beneficence has made abundant provision for the feeding of all his children
                            without the slaying of animals. We are in the ascending scale of evolution, from grosser to
                            higher forms of life. The time cometh when "He that killeth an ox will be as he that slew a
                            man." The yet unwritten law of the New Earth, shall give to every man a heritage, "He shall
                            sit under his own vine and fig tree," eating the fruits thereof in peace, each living in
                            harmony with his neighbor, while the nucleus of the New Heavens will be formed of the more
                            progressed portions of humanity, who shall gather together in heavenly communism, obeying
                            the leadings of the divine in all things pertaining to physical and spiritual life. "Then
                            shall they not hurt nor destroy in all God's holy mountain; for the earth shall be full of
                            the knowledge of the Lord as the waters cover the sea." Isaiah, xi., 9. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some individuals strive to build..." TEIform="index"/>Some individuals strive to build...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Some individuals strive to build themselves up on the ruins of other people's character. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="176" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is a little precept..." TEIform="index"/>There is a little precept...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Union Village, May 1895" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, Ohio. May, Irt9"&gt;.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Tiiekk is a little precept which has been handed down from generation to generation, from
                                time almost immemorial. It is a very simple percept, a child can understand it, and yet
                                it is one of the most important, all-coinprehending precepts that was ever uttered. If
                                it had always been obeyed, no war would ever have been possible, no persecution for
                                religion's sake, or miv other sake, would ever have been perpetrated on the earth, no
                                moneyed aristocracy would ever have ground the faces of the poor, nor sent hundreds and
                                thousands of poverty-stricken wretches out of the world, through the ghastly portals of
                                suicide. Peace and plenty, comfort and health would have long since brooded in silence
                                over the world, and the voice of sorrow, contention and strife been hushed forever. The
                                good and righteous spirit of man, would have impressed the universal current of thought,
                                and the terrible cyclone and drouth, famine and plague would never have been. The
                                pinching economies of the poor by which they eke out a mere existence and which give no
                                opportunity for higher aims and satisfactions, would have never blasted the fate of the
                                masses. Slums, charities, infirmaries would never have been needed, and would never have
                                existed. No animal would ever have had to be sacrificed to the voluptuous gluttony of
                                man. Je-ilousy, revenge, cruelty and extortion would never have been hoard of. But alas
                                ! We have heard this little precept sounded in our ears, iterated and reiterated, almost
                                ever since man existed on the earth, and it is continually repeated day after day up to
                                ttr.s very moment, and yet how very lew hear it and how infinitely fewer, heed it. How
                                is it that we are so unmindful of it, when we see misery, squalor, sickness, and suicide
                                on every hand? It would seem we are almost insane, when we must know there is a safe and
                                salutary remedy, when we know that we might see smiling contentment on every side and
                                happiness among all creatures, those below, as well as on, and above our own plane. A
                                little serious inner thoughtfulness and meditation every morning, would place every
                                individual in a mood of mind which would enable him or her, to so regulate their conduct
                                as to obey that little precept, and if every one would avail himself of this facility
                                and be governed by the suggestions of conscience in the matter, the present status of
                                horror brooding over the earth, would be followed by the immediate advent of the long
                                looked for Millennium. O! that the whole earth would hearken to the voice of the "Son of
                                man" and come to judgment on the merits of this one little precept. The whole face of
                                nature and of grace would undergo a change so wonderful, that all pres- <pb n="177" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MAN (FES TO. 177 ent conditions of society would be instantly
                                metamorphosed and struck with joyful wonder and praise and thanksgiving to God. In view
                                of such magnificent and astounding results, you will of course want to know what can be
                                the form and character of this wonderful precept ? Here it is "Thou shalt love thy
                                neighbor as thyself." Is that hard to understand? is it unreasonable? is it impractical?
                                is it unjust? By no means. It is not so hard, or half so difficult as a contrary policy,
                                and yet how very slow we are in adopting it into our theory and translating the theory
                                into our practical life. O what a strange medley of contradictions man is! Do let us for
                                Heaven's sake, turn about and revolutionize this world of ours, why not make of it a
                                heaven instead of a hell as it now is, owing to our constant violation of this simple
                                precept? Echo answers "Why not?"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Elder Henry;--In the June Manefesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Elder Henry;--In the June Manefesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Alabama, Mentone, June 21, 1895" TEIform="index"/>Mentone, Ala. June 21, 1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder Henry;In the June Manifesto was a letter from C. G. Reed, of Mt. Lebanon,
                                containing matters of vast importance to those of obscure vision. A medium of
                                unquestioned integrity who lives in our neighborhood, read Brother Reed's letter at my
                                solicitation, and although somewhat prejudiced against the Shakers, consented to try for
                                a view of the Florida enterprise with an eye single, so to speak, to the spiritual side
                                of the work. He passed down the east side of Florida for a distance, thence inland to
                                the place of the temporal operations of the colony in Osceola Co. His view of the
                                plantation was brief. Immediately a cloudy pillar, glistening and pure white was
                                presented to his view. Its base rested in the center of the colony's possessions. He was
                                impressed that it reached from earth to heaven. He says it was heavenly and beyond his
                                powers of true description. So far as I know no one has anything against the above
                                medium whose name is Henry Mason. He says this letter contains no false impressions so
                                far as he is concerned. Yours for a life as pure as the cloudy pillar.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillette, E. B." TEIform="persName"/>E. B. Gillette.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Charity" TEIform="index"/>CHARITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Esterbrooks, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>By Fidella Esterbrooks.</byline><p TEIform="p"> is an ethereal substance, so light that it may not be seen by natural sight, yet so powerful
                            as to still a battle cry. As oxygen, entering a room filled.with poisonous air, quietly and
                            invisibly changes it, filling it with life-giving properties ; so the sweet breath of
                            charity, if allowed to permeate the spiritual atmosphere, disperses the poisonous germs of
                            ill-will, and gives new strength and nourishment. CHARITY <pb n="178" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 178 THE
                            MANIFESTO. The standard works define charity as love, liberality. Shakespeare charity is,
                            "Gently to hear, kindly to judge." The faithful teacher and minister of Christ's doctrine,
                            Paul, says, "Charity suffereth long and is kind." In no manner, we think could a truth be
                            placed more plainly and forcibly. "Charity suffereth,"not alone in enduring great trouble
                            and hardship, but by its power the unkind word, the frowning look, or despicable act, can be
                            divinely borne. All the "thousand littlenessess," which make up the sum total of existence,
                            it suffers, and suffers "long." "Charity suffereth long, and is kind." In the last three
                            words is found the key-note of charity; strike this and others will follow, to form a
                            beautiful harmony. For the frown it gives an answering smile, for unkind words a forgiving
                            reply, for those around us always a lenient spirit, being slow to judge evil, and quick to
                            throw its mantle over sin. Charity and love are one and inseparable. Where charity finds an
                            abode, love will soon follow. How can we repeat the Savior's divinely given prayer, "Forgive
                            us our debts, as we forgive our debtors," and harbor unforgiving thoughts for those around
                            us. We would not wish to judge unkindly were our own to hi weighed by the same measure, yet
                            the rule is applicable. Many miracles have been performed, and martyrs bravely met death.,
                            by the strong power of faith. By hope, others have borne privations and afflictions, to the
                            laying down of their lives, cheerfully. But we are told, that great r than faith and hope,
                            is charity, for by it we may suffer and forgive. Let us then, diligently search for this
                            priceless jewelcharity, remembering that without it we are nothing, and our faith, void ;
                            but with it we are everything well armored to fight for the Lord. West Pittsjield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ill temper" TEIform="index"/>ILL TEMPER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">ILL temper is one of the worst passions of the human mind even in its mildest form, and when
                            fully and freely exercised becomes disgraceful and despicable in the extreme. In this
                            breathing and beautiful world, filled as it were, with the presence of the Deity, and
                            fragrant with incense from unnumbered altars of praise, it is almost impossible to conceive
                            how an element so painful and base as this, could find a place even for a moment of time. To
                            be angry in any degree is to sin. The command is, "Let not the sun go down upon your wrath."
                            Following are a few quotations from authors of past and present time, who have denounced in
                            meaning terms the evils of ill temper. If any of them were guilty subjects, their fault
                            condemned and confessed became at least says, <pb n="179" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFES TO. 179
                            half redressed. We can all agree in the truth of their sayings, learn the lessons which they
                            present, and exercise them practically upon our own lives. It was Cumberland who, comparing
                            ill temper, put it in the superlative degree, he said, "Of all bad things by which mankind
                            are curst." Their own bad tempers surely are the worst." Webster felt likewise, when he
                            wrote, "There is not in nature A thing that makes man so deformed, so beastly As doth
                            intemperate anger." Dean Swift said,"-Our passions are like convulsion fits, which make us
                            stronger for the time, but leave us weaker forever afterward." Marcus Antonius expressed the
                            same sentiment long ago in the following,"Consider how much more you often suffer from your
                            anger and grief than from those very things for which you are angry and grieved." "If anger
                            proceeds from a great cause," said Jeremy Taylor, "it turns to fury; if from a small cause,
                            it is peevishness, and so is either terrible or ridiculous." Clarendon likens angry and
                            choleric persons to thunder and lightning, ungrateful and unsociable, being in themselves
                            all storm and tempest ; but quiet and easy natures are like fair weather, welcome to all.
                            Still another condemnation appears in the words of Johnson who said, "The round of a
                            passionate man's life is in contracting debts in his passion which his virtues oblige him to
                            pay. He spends his time in outrage and acknowledgment, injury and reparation." "An angry man
                            is again angry with himself when he returns to reason," says Publius Syrus. This is true
                            with all who care for reputation, morals or character; who care for the angelic development
                            of their souls ; it is the spirit of conviction and repentance that is able to correct all
                            the wrongs of human life. Anger blinds the moral vision, numbs every sense of propriety, and
                            disgraces the individual over whom it gains control. It is as desperate as a furious and
                            frightened horse which, when under way, still plunges along till its force is spent and pain
                            and suffering become a consequence. Cotton likened it to "intoxication, which like that of
                            grape, shows us to others, but hides us from ourselves, and we injure our own cause in the
                            opinion of others, when we too passionately and eagerly defend it." It is impossible that
                            any of enlightened mind or conscientious principle should willfully or willingly allow
                            themselves indulgence in such wanton ways, or at any time so far to forget themselves as to
                            be easily ignited into a flame of feeling by offences or circumstances be they ever so
                            annoying ; or in any way to approve it; for it is a terrible enemy to gentle peace and
                            happiness. Neither power, place nor condition fortify the soul against the upheavals of the
                            lower animal nature; the superior faculties in man, divinely <pb n="180" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE
                            MANIFESTO. inspired, must dominate and overcome in every state and stage of his existence,
                            otherwise there is no salvation. The great and the wise; artists, poets and even musicians
                            whose souls it would seem must live in the realm of ceaseless harmony have given themselves
                            up to these abnormal feelings, and many becoming victims to their deadly discharges have
                            fallen to rise no more. It is dreadful to contemplate but it is true that on the throne and
                            in high places it has burned like the fiercest fire, and found the most fuel. It has opened
                            many a gloomy pit with its murderous hand when in a moment of frenzied passion thousands
                            have been condemned to die, often guiltless and without trial. It is the despoiler of home
                            loves, the destroyer of friendships, and is often a fatal injury to the health of those who
                            yield to its influence. Whoever finds ill temper among his spiritual foes, should seek
                            earnestly and sincerely to be filled with the power of God's love, which is the germ of
                            moral excellence; the fullness and completeness of all the excellence of God, and is able to
                            help us to rise above the imperfections to which we are all more or less subject. Our
                            greatest heroic aim should be to control and conquer, not nations and tribes and persons,
                            but ourselves. Said the ancient Dhamiuapoda, "If one man conquer in battl a thousand tim &gt;s
                            a thousand men, and if another conquer himself ; he is the greatest conqueror." Conquer
                            thyself! till thou hast done that, thou art a slave in bondage more than that realized under
                            unjust despotic law. It is wise to be moderate. "Moderation is the silken string running
                            through the pearl chain of all virtues." It is virtuous to be forgiving, "Never does a human
                            soul appear so strong as when it foregoes revenge and dares to forgive an injury." It is
                            Christian to be patient. "How poor are they who have not patience," who hath it not is out
                            of possession of his soul. All the words of Jesus teach self-denial, and the lives of all
                            good men and women testify to the virtue of an humble spirit and a well governed mind. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Envy" TEIform="index"/>ENVY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lincoln, Julia M." TEIform="persName"/>By Julia M. Lincoln.</byline><p TEIform="p">AMONG the many vices inherent in the human heart, there is none perhaps, which yields more
                            unhappiness, unrest and dissatisfaction than envy. Like a rank weed, which springs up and
                            destroys the growth of valuable plants, so is this evil, if left to become deeply rooted in
                            the heart; it saps the life of those noble virtues that should adorn the Christian
                            character. Envy is an outgrowth of selfishness, and springs from the love destroying
                            elements of pride, deceit and covetousness. Where one of these evils <pb n="181" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 181 exist the rest are close by, cramping the mind and blinding the
                            perceptions of the soul to such an extent, that it observes the good and true in others,
                            only to repine, and sorrows at their prosperity and success. One wisely said, "Base envy
                            withers at another's joy, and hates the excellence it cannot reach." What a true expression
                            this is of the condition of a selfish, envious heart. The proud and arrogant man sees
                            another who possesses a stronger intellect, greater abilities in art, science and
                            literature, or is the owner of larger wealth, or who has more advantages in many ways than
                            himself, the fires of envy are kindled, and burn with an almost quenchless flame, consuming
                            divine qualities of love and generosity that belong to a brotherhood of peace and good-will.
                            All have not equal capacities; all could not reach the perfection of the skilled architect,
                            sculptor, artist or musician, yet each one fills a niche in the structure of life; each one
                            is important in the duties that he should fulfill; therefore we should be content with the
                            small gift that is ours, nor let the arrows of envy wound the hearts of those who do better
                            and greater things than we are capable of doing. We have but to read history, to know that
                            this loathsome evil has, in ages gone by, ruled the hearts of mankind, and caused largely
                            the strife, dissension and confusion among them. Ruler against ruler, and nation against
                            nation, have been impelled by this inward foe to war with one another, causing desolation
                            and destruction where beauty and abundance once reigned. Are not these lessons applicable to
                            the present time ? Was it not envy that prompted Joseph's brethren to cast him into a pit in
                            the wilderness, and then sell him to the Egyptians, that they might see no more of him ? It
                            was the same evil motive that controlled the hearts of the Jews and stirred them to hatred
                            against Jesus because of his goodness and humility, and envy that was consummated in his
                            crucifixion. Many promulgators of the truth, philosophers and scientists have been condemned
                            to torture and death, by those who were actuated by this vice. The generous, noble,
                            unselfish heart untainted by envy and its accompanying evils, is ever rejoicing in the
                            attainments and excellencies of others, is happier when a friend wins than when he fails,
                            and is always content with his position though humble. That spiritual man Prof. Henry
                            Drummond, once wrote : "Only one thing, truly, need the Christian envy,the large, rich,
                            generous soul which envieth not." One seeking to buildup rather than pull down the good
                            character of others, for the spirit that undermines, is the most treacherous form of this
                            despicable evil. How much better and happier mortals would be, if they would work by the
                            rule of love which "envieth not," which thinketh no evil, and lives and toils for the good
                            of all. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="182" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be not deceived" TEIform="index"/>BE NOT DECEIVED. </head><p TEIform="p">IT is highly necessary for every one who wishes to accomplish any kind of work, either mental
                            or fysical, to be thuroly assured that they hav not been deceivd by false representations or
                            by the following of a shadow to their own ruin. When the Apostl Peter admonisht his brethren
                            to "be ready always to giv an answer to every man that asketh a reason of the hope that is
                            in you," he evidently was quite wel assured of their ability to meet the demand. That he had
                            no hesitancy in giving this advice is evident from his own testimony. "Blessed be God who
                            hath begotten us unto a lively hope, to an inheritance incorruptibl and that fadeth not
                            away." Such an assurance was no matter of guess work, but wel understood. Very few bodies of
                            pepl would be likely to form thernselvs into societies without being certain to sum extent
                            that the combination would prove to be advantageous to the individual as wel as to the body
                            as a whole. In the acceptance of these religious dogmas, with the vared theological views
                            that ar to form the basis of this new eommonvvelth or society, a careful analysis is made of
                            sum Scripture texts, which no dout, appear reasonabl as wel as Scriptural, and upon which
                            they must act in order to obtain the anticipated results. That there ar a large number of
                            religious sects, is very natural, as there ar a large number of pepl from whom to form these
                            religious bodies. If the forms and ceremonies, or the general belief of one party ar
                            especially singular or even peculiar, it is no argument against them, and the next in order
                            may stand in a corresponding position so soon as they becum actors, and the first party
                            becum the ones to criticize. The Apostl was not slow to lern this fact, when he went among
                            either the Jews or the Greeks. Their religious belief was old and the Christian order became
                            to the Jews a sad stumbling block, which belief they would not accept. God had calld them
                            his sons and for hundreds of years had manifested himself to them, and it was not strange
                            that they should stumbl on the appearance of the Galilean whose very simplicity of dress and
                            preaching they were ready to condemn. When the intellectual and worldly-wise Greeks were
                            confronted by the Christians, they at once turnd as from a system of foolishness and gave an
                            off hand dismissal to the whole affair. By the mass of mankind the utterance of disbelief or
                            condemnation may be an easy matter as it requires neither education nor even common sense,
                            and the setting aside of <pb n="183" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 183 one party by another, ads
                            no beneficial quality to the self-constituted judges, and has no force to harm those who ar
                            accused. There ar men in the world who ar calld the one idea men. Their church is the only
                            church, and without its pale is everlasting death. Their God is the only true God, and they
                            worship him on the murderous field of battle; in the accumulation of mammon for individual
                            selfishness and in the mazes of sensuality. They hav accepted a passage of Scripture which
                            confirms them that it has redeeming features. Any light thrown upon this passage except from
                            their own tallow candle, is at once severely ignored. Fortunately the privileges of a free
                            cuntry ar open to all and we ar at liberty to accept or reject any plan that may be
                            presented to us. In our own case we think we ar consistent followers of our accepted guide,
                            the Lord, Jesus Christ. His mission was in the interest of a spiritual relation, and his
                            discipls were to deny themselvs of all ungodliness and every worldly lust. All the selfish
                            relations of the worldly order were held in their legitimate place, while the exam pi and
                            the testimony of Jesus and his discipls carried them into a higher sphere and into a
                            spiritual element. It is a pseudo Christianity that has thru sofistry and selfishness most
                            thuroly amalgamated the gospel truth with pagan filosofy, and sown it broadcast thru the
                            world. Religious communism has its activ, life principl in the advent of the carpenter's
                            son, the man of Galilee, the divine Teacher, the son of God. Direct from him we hav this
                            remark, "The son of man hath not where to lay his head." He had no selfish home and no
                            private interest in any property, and yet no one for a moment would suppose that he was
                            deprivd of his food, or a suitable place for rest at night. Jesus and the twelve discipls
                            formd the first Christian community in which their lives and all that they possest was
                            consecrated to God. The mine and thine system of selfishness has arisen at a later date, and
                            largely obscured the light and truth of the testimony of Jesus. Peter's declaration that was
                            evidently spoken under the full responsibility of the cross of Christ opens to us the order
                            which had been establisht for the evangelizing work,"Behold, we hav forsaken all to follow
                            thee." It was not a special matter of faith, but an active work ; not a fractional surrender
                            of a few things, but it was to forsake all. Peter was a married man, and the narrator is so
                            explicit as to state that Peter's wife's mother was sick, and this relation warrants the
                            Christian in saying that the Apostls were married men, and that it was a feature of the <pb n="184" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 184 THE MANIFESTO. Christian church. However, Peter's inventory of
                            earthly treasures may possibly have been as follows ;A faithful, loving wife ; A cmfort;ibl
                            huuse by the sea shore ; Two wel furnisht boats on the sea of Galilee ; some excellent
                            fishing nets and a good stock of provisions. Now the question arises,Did Peter mean what he
                            said or was he tinctured with the spirit of Ananias ? Matthew tells us that Peter left his
                            nets to follow Jesus, and that would imply that he also left his boats ; but Peter more to
                            the point, has said, "Behold, we have forsaken all. What does Peter's inventory of all that
                            he possest include? That he forsook the whole is agieeabl to his statement. Jesus had at an
                            earlier date informd his discipls that if they would follow him in the regeneration, they
                            must forsake all the relations of the old Adamic order and count only those as Brethren and
                            Sisters who gave their lives "to do the wil of God," and Paul emphasizes this by ading, "Put
                            ye on the Lord Jesus Christ, and make no provision for the flesh, to fulfil the lusts
                            thereof." It must be a very unobservant mind that can project a statement so at variance
                            with fact as the following;"The Shakers can find no authority for their system of Community
                            life." Henry Ward Beecher once remarked, that a person would see things corresponding to the
                            color of his glasses, and certainly sum glasses must be very defective when everything
                            becums so sadly distorted as to confuse all history, all Biblical authority and all common
                            sense. As witnesses for the truth it wil be wel for us as Believers, to live in such a
                            manner that every one may "show the same diligence to the full assurance of hope unto the
                            Lord."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">J[^We are without a page of music this month, as it has not reached us in season for
                            insertion.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When the dews of inspiration fall..." TEIform="index"/>When the dews of inspiration fall...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When the dews of inspiration fall upon the heart, the lips can no more refrain from speaking
                            beautiful words, than can the flower refuse to send up incense after the refreshing of a
                            summer shower.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. Staples.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love is a flower of rainbow hue..." TEIform="index"/>Love is a flower of rainbow hue...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Love is a flower of rainbow hue, Nurtured by heavenly light and air; And trust is but the
                            deathless dew, Keeping its leaves forever fair.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F., M. M." TEIform="persName"/>M. M. F.</byline></div2><pb n="185" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. AUGUST, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy per year,
                            postage paid .75 " " six months, " " .40</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. June. Thermometer. Bain. 1894. 68.9 1.4 in. 1895.
                                10.53 5.5 in. Highest Temp, during this mo. 90 above 0 Lowest " " " " 48 " " Number of
                                rainy days " " 10 " " clear " " " 12 " " cloudy '? " " 8 C. G. Reed. July, 1892. "While
                                the earth remaineth seed-time and harvest, cold and heat, summer and winter, day and
                                night shall not cease." This promise given so long ago, still remains fulfilled in the
                                beautiful variety of our temperate zone, for which we are ever grateful. The strawberry
                                season with its abundant and delicious harvest has passed too quickly; but the heavily
                                laden currant bushes, the dlasters of ripening raspberries and well grown blackberries
                                and dew-beiries, show the regular progression of summer. Cherries are plentiful and of
                                such a variety that the season lasts about six weeks. It is said "He who plants a tree
                                plants a hope." This being so we can readily see the hopes which have actuated the
                                inmates of our home to provide so bountifully for their posterity; these hopes never
                                wane, for we were delighted in walking about in the fruit orchards to find no vacant
                                places. Noticing in particular so many young and thrifty peach trees, we learned that
                                Br. James Glass had set out one hundred and twenty from pits planted last Autumn. Our
                                district school closed the 21st of June, and showed a record of thirty-two weeks divided
                                into three terms, during the school year. This with our opportunities for an industrial
                                education gives us who are young, advantages for which we are deeply grateful. On the
                                20th of June a company of twenty,including horses and carriagesenjoyed a pleasant day at
                                Lake Queechy. Selecting one of the longest days with "not a ripple on the wave nor a
                                cloud in the sky" it was a full day of pleasure. Previous to starting we prepared the
                                ingredients for our ice cream and on arriving at the lake we found that the motion of
                                the carriage during a three mile's drive was just sufficient to produce our coveted
                                delicacy without further trouble. Taking a pleasant ride with an ice-cream freezer is
                                quite an inprovement on the usual turning of the crank. We are much pleased with the
                                addition to our family of Sister Sarah Neale from Watervliet, N. Y., who is appreciated
                                foilier own intrinsic worth; she is also interested to fill the vacancies left by our
                                Florida pioneers. Daisy Wells. North Family. July, 1895. Not at all from a lack of
                                interest in our monthly, were our Home Notes for its <pb n="186" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 186 THE
                                MANIFESTO. last issue withheld; but with regret we found that we were too late. At this
                                writing we are in the fullness of cherry harvest. Brethren and boys are busy gathering
                                the fruit, while Sisters are preparing the same for the Pittsfield market and for home.
                                The rains are proving beneficial to fruit and vegetables and with a combination of
                                sunshine, fnithful, untiring toil with hoe and cultivator, the husbandman may look
                                forward to bountiful crops. A few weeks ago we were more than pleased to meet beloved
                                Eldresses, Joanna Kaime and Eliza Stratton, from Canterbury, N. H. We have also held
                                short, but sweet converse with other clear Sisters from ISTew Hampshire. On the 21st
                                ult. a company of Sisters left home to enjoy the hospitality of gospel kindred at
                                Enfield and Canterbury, N. H. They returned on the 5th inst. greatly benefited, and
                                laden with mess ages of enduring love and friendship, that they bore from souls who are
                                rich in spiritual growth and life, to which our hearts earnestly responded. On the 26th
                                ult. another company of four Sisters left us for a short but profitable stay with
                                friends at Watervliet, N. Y. From them we learn that there is a growing interest among
                                young people at that place, in the maintenance of gospel life and principles. Public
                                services have been open for several weeks. Although there seems to be a spiritual
                                dearth, inside as well as outside of our Order, yet we feel assured tha^ the spirit is
                                working among us to awaken and redeem; there is a silent, but powerful concentration of
                                forces, a baptism that will soon come down upon us and prepare us for the great work of
                                the coming time. We must live in the spirit if we would be fruitful in righteousness,
                                and keep our hearts ever open to receive that divine inspiration, which always comes to
                                those who are aspiring for higher and better conditions of life. We have bright hopes
                                for the future, and are working patiently and fearlessly in the cause of virgin purity,
                                not for the few, but for the many whom the spirit will in due time prepare for the great
                                work of salvation which is, indeed, the hope of the race. Julia M. Lincoln.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. July, 1895. There is no division of labor that seems to give the pleasure
                                and satisfaction of being able to enjoy its productions fresh as they are gathered, like
                                that of the agriculturist and horticulturist, although at present the economic
                                conditions of human society are making him bear proportionately more than a just share
                                of the burdens of life; However we are "looking up through the clouds to the sunlight of
                                heaven, and will continue thus, believing that out of the confused and trying conditions
                                of the present will come a time that will permanently gladden the spirits of those who
                                are honestly laboring to evolve better conditions. As we write we hear the booming of
                                cannon from the different towns around us in their celebration of the glorious Fourth,
                                giving thanks for the great liberty they are enjoying. (?) At present we are having
                                fresh vegetables from the garden. It makes us forget the labor necessary for their
                                production, when we witness the pleasure of those who share these benefits, and as the
                                natural is but the material reflection of the spiritual and eternal; so when that labor
                                and anxiety needed to develop the fruits of the spirit has passed into the realm of f
                                orgetfulness, nothing but the joy and satisfaction in their possession will remain. By
                                legislative enactment our town has been divided and the old and historic name of
                                Watervliet has been changed to Colonie. During the last week of June we enjoyed a visit
                                from Sisters Catherine Allen, Agnes Lee, Sarah F. Bodine, May Rulhausen of the North
                                family, Mt. Lebanon. They brought with them that precious treasure appreciated by every
                                one who is <pb n="187" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 187 seeking the higher life; garnering
                                the fruits of the spirit through obedience to the teachings of the divine life. On the
                                11th inst. Sisters Isabell White and Louie Bussell from our North family at this place
                                left home for a visit to Mt. Lebanon. We feel like exclaiming, "O how swiftly time is
                                passing!" and may it be improved to our spiritual benefit! It seems but yesterday when
                                the gladsome sound of "Happy New Year'' was ringing far and near, and we have already
                                passed the meridian of the year. We hope it has brought pure enjoyment and solid comfort
                                to every faithful Zion traveler and may the protecting care of the Divine Fatherhood and
                                Motherhood rest upon all faithful ones who are laboring to uplift humanity from those
                                conditions that deprave, into the presence and light of the truth, is the humble prayer
                                of your brother in the cause. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1895. When the mind is filled with good and pure thoughts, and the hands with
                                pleasant work, time flies so unconsciously that we do not realize its flight till it is
                                past. We live in a busy world, but whether good or bad depends on how we make it. Good
                                lives show that we have found the happy side of this world, and speak the loudest in
                                favor of a Christian life. We have been abundantly blessed with rain, and now if kind
                                Nature will give us two or three weeks of sunshine we shall be doubly grateful. We had a
                                good fulfillment of the promised seed-time; have had green peas, and other vegetables
                                since the 20th of June. The drought injured our potatoes so they are unusually late this
                                season. Now harvest time is at hand; our hay crop is better than we anticipated, though
                                not equal to that of last year. We have not as large a crop of herbs as usual owing to
                                the failure of the seed to germinate. We are raising no fruit at present. We ever strive
                                to keep our hearts attuned with gratitude and prajer, and in obedience to tl;e commands
                                of the apostle John, be like little children in loving one another. March, M. Hal
                            lard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1895. We can but echo the sentiments expressed in Sister Catherine Allen's ottering
                                to the June No. of The Manifesto. Surely, all the years we have given to a life of
                                self-denial must have had a tendency to enrich our minds with a goodly development of
                                solidity and intelligence of a Christ-like type, and it is our duty to utilize these
                                powers for the best good of humanity. It would seem to be a senseless assertion to
                                declare that certain cherished ideas were absolute and unchangeable, for nothing is so
                                except truth, substantiated by personal experience and the evolutions oi' nature.
                                Turning the reflector of memory backward, we see that by the removal of old
                                conventionalities and useless ceremonies, there has been wrought out larger human
                                qualities that enrich and brighten Christian life. In every progressive movement are
                                experiences both bitter and sweet, teaching lessons of truth which blossom into deeds of
                                righteousness inasmuch as the aim is to benefit mankind. We are pleased to add to the
                                record of our Society history, the pleasant visit we have enjoyed with Sisters Maria
                                Blow, Jane Cutler, Cecelia DeVere, and Lydia Staples, also Brother Ezra Stewart,
                                representatives from the North family of Mt. Lebanon. Such events give a flood of
                                thought that bring friends near, and convince us that the company of the pure in heart
                                constitute the joys of Heaven. We would that there were more of such pages of
                                remembrance. <pb n="188" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 188 THE MANIFESTO. Harvesting of hay in full
                                operation, and proves to be of excellent quality. Elder William Wilson who is interested
                                in bee culture, has been successful in enlarging his colony from three to nine hives. We
                                hope they may increase an hundred fold as we regard honey profitable as food and
                                merchandise. With renewed love for all, we hope an impetus will stir Zion to new
                                movements to spread her God-revealed truths, while those who have taken hold of the
                                plough of progression, press nobly on not looking back to view the stones of impediment
                                unearthed in their onward march for justice and truth. George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. The Apostle says, "Let the peace of God rule in your hearts, and be ye
                                thankful." True peace within is gained by denying self. Thousands are seeking for peace
                                which they never find, in worldly pleasure. If we follow Christ we shall be partakers of
                                his peace which he gives unto those who walk in his footsteps. The command is to let
                                peace rule in our hearts; therefore we should not despair as though it were
                                unattainable. Peace reigns with the virtuous and true. "Come ye out from among them and
                                be separate," applies to those who are true and faithful, with peculiar force. The
                                Manifesto is a messenger of good things in our home, it seems to make life brighter and
                                happier. "Each one should have a grand ideal, and seek to attain it. We may waste all
                                our life waiting for the opportunity which may never come; but since little things are
                                always claiming our attention, let us do them, from a great motive,human good." "The
                                first newspaper advertisement appeared in 1652. More poultry keepers make one dollar of
                                profit on each hen than double that amount. It requires experience to produce great
                                results. Better begin it small; go it slow; not expect much with little. Rather the
                                reverse. Sick or ailing hens may be fed on scalded milk and boiled rice. Daniel Orcntt.
                                South Family. July, 1895. How lovely all nature is at the present time. July is beaming
                                with splendor in every point of view, inviting to an enjoyment that bespeaks the spirit
                                of worship and gratitude that our land is the land of freedom of thought, and of
                                religious liberty. The Fourth is past with its noisy demonstrations. Here at the South
                                family we enjoyed a pleasant picnic on our own grounds; tables beneath tents well filled
                                with good things. About twenty partook of the refreshments, and expressions of mirth and
                                pleasure ruled. The young people passed the time with games, etc., but the rain came a
                                little too soon and we were driven to the house for shelter. Haying has commenced, but
                                the weather has been unfavorable the past few days. Fruit trees are looking well and
                                good crops of peaches and pears are expected. Apples will be better than was feared
                                after the three severe frosts in May. Corn and potatoes are in good growing conditions
                                and look exceedingly well. Tomatoes are of better growth this season than at any
                                previous year. Our thanks shall be given to Him "from whom all blessings flow," for the
                                continued bounties that we daily share. We recently enjoyed a delightful visit with some
                                gospel friends from Canaan, and received strength and blessing. Associations of this
                                character are always fraught with good to the recipients. The present is the time to
                                accept the blessing which we need. Maria Witham.</p></div3><pb n="189" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">July, 1895. The historic day of which we promised to tell you in the last Manifesto, is
                                now of the past: The Dedication of the Maine State Building, and the Centennial of the
                                Kickers in Poland. As the preparations were not completed, the event was postponed until
                                Monday. July 1st. It was a perfect day, so much so that it seemed to have been made for
                                the occasion. Some of our people were present as we received a kind invitation. The
                                principal speakers were our two State Senators, Hale and Frye. In the course of his
                                speech Sen. Hale apostrophized the building and said to it: "Stay right where you are
                                and thank the Lord that you are out of Chicago. You ought to feel like a man who has
                                just emerged from an election riot in the lower streets of New York City and has
                                launched himself into the placidity of a Shaker meeting here in the state of Maine." All
                                the buildings were decked with red, white and blue burning; flags floated in the breeze
                                while the band played the national airs at intervals. The time occupied by the speeches
                                was two hours. The guests were then served with a sumptuous, free dinner, the menu for
                                which cost the proprietors $87.00. We fared with the rest and also made good sales. The
                                half of home interests and blessings can not be told, but the links of love and gospel
                                friendship forged in our little eastern Society, help to strengthen and lengthen the
                                chain of our union which encompasses all our Zion homes. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">June, 1895. May came in hot and dry, and continued much the same throughout the month,
                                affording little encouragement to the gardener. Asparagus and rhubarb afforded but scant
                                supplies to our table. June has done better, copious showers bringing forward vegetation
                                finely. Peas, asparagus and new potatoes, have appeared during the past week upon our
                                well supplied table. Berries, and later a fair crop of cherries have added their crimson
                                beauty and luscious juices to the feast. Corn is growing finely; wheat is almost ready
                                for the reaper, and our crop of barley is already cut and thrashed. Situated as Union
                                Village is, in one of the richest if not the richest valley in the world, it seems
                                almost superfluous to say we have an abundance of the fruits of the earth. 'Our peace is
                                like a river, and our fountain of blessing full and runningover;'' individual happiness
                                however depends upon the degree of health, wisdom and consecration of the individual. If
                                I had taken as much pains in writing my last home notes as in this, the type would not
                                have made me say, "snug days and wintry ways," instead of "sunny days and windy ways,"
                                as the manuscript was intended to read. But "the most uukindest cut of all," is the
                                "t'orceful dreams," whatever they are; even the critics declare they can not imagine.
                                But "fearful dreams" anybody can uuderstand, having had them when living a sinful life;
                                but a "forceful dream "is surely a new invtntion. IHifnon Andrews.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Food" TEIform="index"/>FOOD.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Theke is in the May number of the Phrenological Journal an articl by J. G.
                                        Stair, M. D. on "Manufactured Foods" that is wel worthy a careful perusal. While
                                        the helthof an individual depends so largely upon the food that is eaten from
                                        day to day, it becums not only necessary but also an imperativ duty to exercize
                                        a great deal of care, in the selection of those articls of diet, that ar obtaind
                                        for the general nutrition of the system. <pb n="190" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 190 Tl IE MA
                                        XIFES TO. Food in its natural state may generally be determind so clearly that
                                        the fear of injury may be quite slight, but that which lms been manipulated by a
                                        manufacturer may not be so easily determind. "Careful investigation by the
                                        Department of Agriculture has shown that most of the cannd goods in tle market
                                        contain salicylic acid and sulphites as preservativ materials, and that these
                                        substances decidedly lessen the digestibility and wholesunmess ol thtse article
                                        of diet. All goods cannd in tin ar found to contain traces of lead, which is of
                                        course a poison to the human system." The Dr. says, "There is no dependence | to
                                        be put in any food product which can not be examine! and tested without a
                                        chemist, and daily with one's own eyes." To live and lern seems to be quite
                                        essential at the present time, and to lern speedily seems to be equally
                                        necessary especially if we expect to keep pace with the microbe family. "A
                                        microbist, has found that very pretty ice, transparent and seemingly clean, may
                                        contain more, than seven times the amount of organic matter which is safe for
                                        drinking purposes, and even half a million microbes to the teaspoonful. Ice is a
                                        great luxury, even a necessity for this season, but since we can seldom know its
                                        source or purity (or rather impurity) the better way is to avoid letting it melt
                                        in or cum in direct contact-with our beverages."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dr. Foote's Health Monthly" TEIform="index"/>Dr. Foote's Health Monthly.</bibl></cit> Good medical authority says that oatmeal is one of the best of foods. "There is
                                an inestimable blessing in a cheerful spirit. When the soul throws its windows wide
                                open, letting in the bright sunshine and presenting to all who see it the evidence of
                                its gladness, it is not only happy, but it has an unspeakable power of doing good. To
                                all the other beatitudes may be added, 'Blessed are the joy makers.' " The fruit diet
                                curbs ostentation and luxury, and makes it possibl for rich and poor to feed more alike.
                                As such pure foods cum into vogue, the passions wil be better controlld and cruelty and
                                war wil becum sooner impossible As we cease to be carnivorous, we shal "let the tiger
                                die" within us. Then sensuality wil be kept in check, crimes of violence wil greatly
                                diminish, while disease wil be largely prevented. W. S. Manning in The Temple of
                            Health.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good manners" TEIform="index"/>GOOD MANNERS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Theobald, Frank" TEIform="persName"/>By Frank Theobald.</byline><p TEIform="p">As a Christian society, professing to follow Jesus the Christ, it should be our aim to
                            cultivate those attributes to morals and good manners, that marked his character, and which
                            always denote the noble man or woman. True courtesy should not be used by us merely as a
                            surface-wash to be put on when entertaining special friends, but it should be universally
                            given; as the manners of persons are the criterion by which the moral and religious life may
                            often be judged. "As the twig is bent, the tree inclines, "So it is with the human mind, if
                            in early life, children are taught to respect virtue wherever found, and above all to
                            respect themselves, they will be quite sure to develop an amiable obliging character. It is
                            sometimes remarked that, "Good manners should be the religion of childhood." This is very
                            true, but mature years do not justify the forgetting of those simple kind courtesies which
                            so enrich life and beautify the Christian man or woman. A violation of the law of kindness
                            at any age is subject to the law of condemnation. Good breeding should characterize our
                            daily lives. I think the American Nation lives too fast, hence the social part of their
                            lives, is lost sight of in the hurry and worry to accumulate those treasures which perish
                            with the using. Press of business, or want of proper time is but a poor excuse for
                            self-cultivation. Passing along life's journey, I have ob- <pb n="191" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 191 served that virtue surely pays, and that the willing kindness rendered as
                            opportunities offer, are as threads woven into the fabric of our lives, and as we enter into
                            that rest which is promised to the faithful, I have no doubt our satisfaction will be just
                            in proportion as we have followed Christ in scattering the steeds of truth, justice and true
                            courtesy. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="College index" TEIform="index"/>College Index
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The "College Index" is published month ly by the Student's Publishing Association of
                                Kalamazoo, Mich.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diocese of Albany" TEIform="index"/>The Diocese of Albany
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> "The Diocese of Albany" is edited by Rev. J. N. Marion of Johnston, N.
                                Y. It is published in the interest of the Episcopal church and the Rt. Rev. William
                                Croswell Doane is the present Bishop.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Human nature" TEIform="index"/>Human Nature
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Human Nature" is published in San Francisco, Cal.
                                and edited by Prof. Allen Haddock. It is devoted to Phrenology, Physiognomy, Health,
                                Medical and Social Reform. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parish record" TEIform="index"/>The Parish Record
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> "The Parish Recokd" is published in Nashville, Tenn. in the
                                interest of the church of the Advent. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel messenger" TEIform="index"/>The Gospel Messenger
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"The Gospel Messenger" is published in Syracuse,
                                N. Y. in the interest of the Diocese of Central New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mental world" TEIform="index"/>The Mental World
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"The Mental World" is a
                                beautiful paper of 16 pages. It is Edited and Published by A. M. Prentice of Chicago,
                                111. Its advent into the world very pleasantly reminds us that "Advanced Thought,
                                Scientific Achievements, Spiritualism and Psychical Research" demand more attention by
                                those who are interested in the wonderful presentations which are fast coming before the
                                world.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strength for to-day" TEIform="index"/>STRENGTH FOR TO-DAY.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Nancy Dowe.] Strength for to-day is all that we need, As there never will be a to-morrow; For
                                    to-morrow will prove but another today With its measure of joy and sorrow. Then why
                                    forecast the trials of life With much sad and grave persistence, And wait and watch
                                    for a crowd of ills That as yet have no existence? Strength for to-day; what a
                                    precious boon For earnest souls who labor, For the willing hands that minister To
                                    the needy fm-nd or neighbor. Strength for to-day, that the weary hearts In the
                                    battle for right may quail not, And the eyes bedimmed by bitter tears In their
                                    search for light may fail not. Strength for to-day on the down-hill track For the
                                    travelers nearing the valley, That up, far up on the other side, Ere long they may
                                    r;illy. Strength for to-day, that our precious youth May happily shun temptation,
                                    [sun And build from the rise to the set of the On a strong and sure foundation.
                                    Strength for to-day in house and home To practice forbearance sweetly; To scatter
                                    kind words and loving deeds, Still trusting in God completely. Strength for to-day
                                    is all that we need, As there never will be a to-morrow; For to-morrow will prove
                                    but another to-day, With its measure of joy and sorrow.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you would make yourself unhappy..." TEIform="index"/>If you would make yourself unhappy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"If you would make yoursalf unhappy it is one of the easiest things in the world
                                    to bring about. The art of being miserable, though an art not taught in our schools,
                                    is not one without method, and may be pursued until the person following it has
                                    fully acquired it. As a first step in the art, start forth in the world with the
                                    single, unbending purpose to live for self and for self alone. This rule is
                                    important, and rightly put into action, makes it more easy to follow out the later
                                    provisions. With this thought in mind, always seek the best of everything for self.
                                    Make it a rule to occupy the easiest chair in the sitting-room, and failing to
                                    secure it, keep thinking how uncomfortable are all other chairs in which you are
                                    compelled to sit. If there is an errand or any oth- <pb n="192" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 192 THE
                                    MANIFESTO. er trifling duty to discharge, be sure to put it on others; or if
                                    necessity demands that you yourself do it, grumble during the whole time occupied
                                    with it at the in dolence of everybody else. At table, if there is some dainty
                                    tidbit of insufficient quantity for all to partake, strenuously endeavor to secure
                                    this, and feel miserable if you are so unfortunate as to fail. Seeing a friend with
                                    finer clothing than you possess, think how much you should like to dress as finely,
                                    if not just a little bit better. In the every-day affairs of life, if another
                                    possess a grander home and has more money to spend than yourself, keep constantly
                                    wishing you were in his place, brood over it and let discontent and covetousness
                                    rule in mind and spirit. By doing all this, you will be in a fair way to be
                                    continually unhappy and what is more you will make many other people unhappy."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother Ann" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER ANN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Foster, Charles Elwood" TEIform="persName"/>By Charles Elwood Foster.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by Eldress Harriet Goodwin.] This name was given to a rocky profile at the end of Eastern Point, Mass. "O
                                    Mother Ann." Above the sea! With ferns and asters at thy feet! Hast thou not e'en a
                                    nod for me, Nor smile, thy summer friend to greet? Why seeks thy face the rising
                                    sun? Spyest hope there for a better day? Or future conquests, to be won When yonder
                                    clouds have passed away? No answer comes:calm, cruel, cold, Her eyes the skies
                                    forever scan; Earth's secrets surely she must hold While silent watch keeps "Mother
                                    Ann." Unmindful of the breaker's roar, Or storm winds play with scattered spray; On
                                    rugged, lonely Eastern shore She's eastward looking night and day.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston Journal" TEIform="index"/>Boston Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whoso keepeth his mouth and tongue..." TEIform="index"/>Whoso keepeth his mouth and tongue...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Whoso keepeth his mouth and tongue, keepeth his soul from trouble.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Easy road" TEIform="index"/>THE EASY ROAD.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">By the road of "By-and-By" Stretching on forever, One who travels comes at last
                                    To the house of "Never!" Very tall, and very high, Iron barred securely, Those who
                                    enter find themselves Guarded very surely! 'By-and-By" 's an easy road; Through soft
                                    fields and mosses, No high hills, no sandy soil, Anywhere it crosses If hard places
                                    come between, Round them it goes winding, Very slowly leading on, Smoothest travel
                                    finding! Looking on ahead, one sees But a soft mist showing, While on either side
                                    the scene Ever fair is growing. But there comes an end, some day, Where one sees
                                    forever, Dark and grim the iron gates Of the house of "Never!"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gaining ground" TEIform="index"/>GAINING GROUND.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">We had read with great interest the account of the revival of the Woman'a Suffrage
                            Association, and our hearts went out in sympathy and blessing to all workers in the Cause,
                            therefore it was a pleasing and interesting occurrence when at our doors appeared a modest
                            and intelligent young woman bearing a book for petitions, in which she solicited the names
                            of all who were interested in the movement, and of suitable age to register in favor of
                            Woman's Suffrage. She had been commissioned to this work by the Rev. Theodore Harris, Pastor
                            of the Congregational Church of New Lebanon, who in visiting our homes became much
                            interested in our religious views and practical reforms, especially in vegetarianism to
                            which he became a convert, and very deeply was he impressed with our system of social and
                            industrial economy, based <pb n="193" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 193 upon the recognition of
                            the equality of the sexes, and resulting in the practical solution of many of the knotty
                            problems of the day. He therefore rightly believed that although our Societies would on no
                            account give votes for, or become connected with any political party, we would gladly avail
                            ourselves of the Right of Petition in giving support to any cause for the furtherance of
                            liberty, justice and truth. Therefore, although it was the busy season of house cleaning and
                            seed sowing, appreciating the worth in possession among ourselves as an Order of that which
                            this movement would eventually secure for humanity at large, both Brethren and Sisters
                            gladly enrolled their names among the petitioners, believing that when attained, Woman's
                            Suffrage will be a prime factor in securing her freedom from all man made restrictions,
                            giving her an equal voice with him concerning all the laws by which she is governed. Every
                            true and intelligent woman will give her strength in this direction as a means to an endthat
                            end the uplifting not only of woman, but of man. Together they have been degraded, together
                            they must rise. Of little moment is civil liberty compared to that love of chastity which
                            inheres in the nature of every true woman. To those who realize the debasement and thraldom
                            to sensual passions to which man and woman alike are bound, no boon will be so highly prized
                            as that which will be granted to woman through correct civil laws; rights of her being, body
                            and soul! Thus will she be freed from that galling slavery which more than anything else
                            retards the progress of the race. When the ballot is hers, woman will be swift to legislate
                            to the effect that man shall be obliged to conform to the same moral standard as herself.
                            Purification of the social life of the sexes is of the greatest importance for two reason:
                            first, that their present corrupt state is the primal cause of all sin and misery, for thus
                            the very fountains of existence are poisoned, entailing diseased conditions of body and mind
                            upon future generations. Second, that in this perversion lies not only the cause of every
                            other evilby the creation of false appetites and unjust systems in other departments of
                            life, but the dissipation of those vital forces which give energy, strength of will, and the
                            power of self-denial, without which no reform can be accomplished in the individual or the
                            community. As a matter of science and physiology it is well understood that by the
                            conservation of these life forces, those higher faculties of mind and soul are developed
                            through which the divine spirit of truth can operate for the redemption of the race. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic from proverbs" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC FROM PROVERBS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Appleton, Flora" TEIform="persName"/>By Flora Appleton.</byline><p TEIform="p">In all thy ways acknowledge Him and He shall direct thy paths.iii., 6. Whoso loveth
                            instruction loveth knowledge.xii., 1. In the house of the righteous is much treasure.xv., 6.
                            Love not sleep lest thou come to poverty. xx., 13. [17. Let not thine heart envy
                            sinners.xxiii., Better is a little with righteousness than great revenues without
                            right.xvi., 8. Even a child is known by his doings, whether his work be pure and whether it
                            be right.xx., 11. The fear of the Lord is the instruction of wisdom and before honor is
                            humility. xv., 33. Remove far from me vanity and lies. xxx., 8. Understanding is a
                            well-spring of life unto him that hath it.xvi., 22. Enter not into the path of the wicked
                            and go not in the way of evil men.iv., 14. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To forgive and treat kindly our enemies..." TEIform="index"/>To forgive and treat kindly our enemies...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> is their best reproof, and how calmly can the conscience rest that forgives or rescues a
                            fallen brother or sister.</p></div2><pb n="194" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Iii the July number of "The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" is found a very interesting
                                article on The Physiological and Scientific Basis of Religion by T. V. Gifford, M. D.
                                Every influence that can assist in the unfolding of the mind of man in regard to a
                                better moral or physical life is a friend to humanity. Other articles are to be found in
                                the same number, that are of great value to the thoughtful reader. Dr. T. V. Gifford
                                &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind. "</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cosmopolitan" TEIform="index"/>Cosmopolitan
                            </head><p TEIform="p">'O, will he paint me the way 1 want,' As bonny as a girlie,
                                Or will he paint me an ugly tyke, And be dd to Mr. Xerli! But still and on and which
                                ever it is, He is a canty Kerlie. The Lord protect the back and neck Of honest Mr.
                                Nerli.'* This, one of the last verses ever written by Robert Louis Stevenson, is in
                                reference to the portrait of himself, which is given to the public with his verse for
                                the first time in the July Cosmopolitan. The lines might have come from the pen of
                                Burns, and are inimitable in their way. The portrait was declared by Stevenson himself
                                to be the best ever painted of him. In this same number of The Cosmopolitan Rudyard
                                Kipling tells an Indian story, to which Remington adds charming illustrations; Mrs.
                                Burton Harrison makes a serious study of New York society in "The Myth of the Four
                                Hundred," and Kate Douglas Wiggin contributes a storjT of one of the most delightful of
                                Welsh retreats. The Cosmopolitan was with this number reduced to ten cents per copy, and
                                as a consequence, notwithstanding its large edition, it was "out of print" on the third
                                day of publication. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for July is a
                                beautiful number. All wi)l wTant it. It contains an interesting phrenograph of Walter
                                Damrosch by Edgar C. Beall, M. D. including several portraits of this remarkable
                                musician. The benefits of phrenology to the preacher by Rev. N. F. Douglas, Chinese
                                Cruelty by Arthur H. Lee. Then follows a welcome sketch of Phrenological Biography by
                                Mrs. (;. F. Wells which brings to our notice, our universal friend Rev. Geo. S. Weaver.
                                Where are we, by H. S. Drayton, M. D. A study in conceit by the Editor. Everybody will
                                be pleased with Precious Treasures by Prof. Sizer, with its beautiful, true to life and
                                instructive illustrations. The Science of Health bristles with information on subjects
                                near to the public mind. In'short, hasten to procure a copy and enjoy the excellent
                                reading with us. Fowler and Wells Co. 27 East 21st St. New York City.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Frank Leslie's
                                Popular monthly for August is a brilliant midsummer number. It is a beautifully and
                                elaborately illustrated work of some 130 large, quarto pages. The extended Index
                                includes not less than thirty four interesting articles and on such a varied list of
                                subjects that every one, young or old, will be amply compensated for obtaining the
                                number. Even those who do not care to read all that is published, will find a fund of
                                information and a great deal of pleasure in studying the beautiful illustrations. Frank
                                Leslie's Pub. House. 4-2-44 Bond St. New York, ST. Y. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Comfort" TEIform="index"/>Comfort
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Comfort, is a large, illustrated
                                Monthly of 24 pages, published by "The Gannett and Morse Concern," Augusta, Me. at 50
                                cts. per year. Comfort is said to have "the largest Circulation in the world." It is
                                full of entertaining matter, for every member of the family and only five cent's a copy.
                                The publishing of Comfort is an additional wonder in the world and yet it may not
                                astonish all who see it, as the marvelous inventions of this wonderful age are coming to
                                us nearly every day. Some of the pages are printed in five bright colors, which adds
                                much to the beauty of the illustrations. Not less than 8000 copies of this beautiful
                                paper are printed, pasted, folded and ready to to be mailed every hour till it reaches
                                its edition of more than a million of copies. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Anti-tobacco crusader" TEIform="index"/>Anti-Tobacco Crusader
                            </head><p TEIform="p">  "There is a time to laugh," says the wise
                                man, and in the "Diary of the Rev, Solomon Spittle" in So. 13 of H.L.Hastings'
                                Anti-Tobacco Crusader, which has just come to our table, we recognize and heartily
                                welcome a new departure in dealing with the tobacco problem. We have had the heavy
                                artillery. Call out now the reserve forcethe light infantry of fun and ridicule.
                                Statistics and scientific facts are all useful in their way, nay, indispensable, but
                                often a good laugh does more to shake the foundations of an evil custom or a vicious
                                habit. Every tobacco-using pastor should be presented with a copy of this book, that he
                                may see his own portrait; and the tobacco-using deacon or Sunday School superintendent
                                should not be forgotten. Send ten cents to H. L Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.,
                                for a copy. You will find it just the thing to circulate. On quantities, special terms
                                will be given to tract distributors, churches, temperance and reform clubs and Sunday
                                schools.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Davis, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Davis
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Eliza Davis, at Second family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. July 12,1895. Age 13 years, and 5
                            mo.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE. MANIFESTO.
THE   CLIMAX.
This  is an American   Stem-windar,   UE to elate.    It represents  the  most  important step taken in watch evolution in many  years.    It  describes  a line beyond
which nothing radical will pass for years, not only in the matter of price, but quality
Two styles.    Gilt and nickel,   Snap  back, Bevel crystal,
Stem Set.   Fully timed and regulated.
For $2.00 we  will  send  the Watch, and also a copy of The Manifesto for one
year, to any address in the U. S.           Address
The   Manifesto.
EAST    CANTERBURY,    N.     II.
A YlSIT TO THE
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYDH. CHANDLER.l.S.5
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of peusoxs and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15 cts.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and < oO< o Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or t    !> n.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and aiti^tic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY-PAINB MFG. CO., Phila., Pa.
This it a good thinyEd.
Inspirational Hymns and Songs, illustrative of the Resurrection Life and 7Y,slimony of the Shakers.                10   cts.
BY
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFtiS TO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
 Latest United States Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
THE   ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling1, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley
2 N. Fourth St.",   St. Louis, Mo.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
= ttI.USTBATEB HOMB JOURNAL=
SO cts. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
Thomas a. firswisAiar & soav
CHICAGO, ILL.
SHAKERS'
3  CONCENTRATED
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA, I
With 1 oz. Hydriodatk of Potassa to 12 Bottles.
PREPARED AT
Shaker Willsge, Memraack n., B.i^
This medicine has proved to be most *
valuable in the following diseases :      #
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs ; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion ; Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Rheumatism; Salt Rheum; Secondary Syphilis;
Functional Disorders of the Liver; Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofidoiis
diseases and disorders arising from impurities of the blood. It is also an excellent, remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery, and Diarrhoea, and
for the complicated diseases of females,
so apt to end in consumption.
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or live times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHEENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEFOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>