<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0209" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18720901" TEIform="date">September 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">65-73</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="65" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORT, SAITH THE LORD. Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas, Editor. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., SEPTEMBER, 1872. No. 9.
                        Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conservatism and progression: how shall they be reconciled?" TEIform="index"/>Conservatism
                            and Progression. How shall they be Reconciled ?</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>ELIJAH MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">The desire and effort for preserving what is established, as first principles of rudimental
                            truth, are not necessarily antagonistic to Progress. Radicalism is the forced, unwilling
                            antipode of near-sighted Conservatism. Conserve and preserve are synonymous. Hence, what is
                            good, sound, and true of the past, should conserve the present and future, interblending
                            like the colors of the rainbow. The conflict between finality and young germs of truth, in
                            the individual mind, is carried into sects and communities. The former depending upon its
                            defensible ability, forces the latter into a war of triumph, as portrayed by Bunyan. All
                            real progress is sanctified by adhering to first principles. The prophets and philosophers
                            of each dispensation could only give utterance to the truths of their day. "The old heavens
                            and earth " will continue to give place to the new, in each succeeding cycle; and, when
                            reason and wisdom shall take the supremacy of fear and superstition, the change will not
                            necessarily be attended with " a great noise." Isaiah, 45:22. "They shall not build, and
                            another inhabit; they shall not plant, and another eat; for, as the days of a tree, are the
                            days of my people ; and mine elect shall long enjoy the work of their hands." This
                            beautiful, significant figure, symbolizes growth ; and the existing harmony between
                            conserving and expanding, rightly recognized, is mutually dependent; and an issue is
                            detrimental to both. Should the extending bud refuse to respond to the inward pressure for a
                            new growth of life, and say to the sun of revelation, " Touch vie not; this is the final
                            growth ; obedient to God's law, I shed my foliage, and his cold winter closed me up
                            forever," the internal pressure, induced by the external warmth, would produce an argument
                            in favor of eternal progress ; a fitting rebuke to the adherents of the dead past. All real
                            good belongs to the present; and the present should willingly yield to the future; not lay
                            dormant, to be exhumed lundreds of years hence. Let each dispensation glory in, and be
                            glorified by, the other. Conservatives, as leaders of old organizations, block the wheels of
                            progress, and falsify the declaration and prophecy of Future increase. Resistance to
                            improvement contradicts the noblest instinct of the soul, and begets its opposite—fanaticism
                            of reform—caused by the obstructions which perverted conservatism has thrown across the
                            stream of progress; and revolution is the sudden sweeping away of barriers which should have
                            been reasonably and seasonably removed. On Progression's banner is inscribed, "Let there be
                            light;" and may the time soon come, when all human governments shall form a co-partnership
                            with the divine, in carrying this baptism and benediction into fulfillment. The beautiful
                            fragments of the Roman aqueducts made level across vallies, and through hills, for the want
                            of the knowledge which every intelligent child now possesses, are often cited to test the
                            power of their builders ; but, they are only so many monuments of their weakness, instead of
                            strength. Job, 38: 35, " Canst thou send the lightnings, that they may go and say unto thee,
                            'Here we are ?' " If that question were put to modern science, it would answer in the
                            afiirmative. When thought cannot find vent, the mind ceases to think; it will not continue
                            to produce its births of power and beauty, to see them fall dead-born into the world. Even
                            the rapt spirit of Isaiah would droop its wings, but for the effulgence of the vision they
                            project, reflecting pictured glories on the solid earth. What deep floods of the direful
                            miseries of superstition and barbarity have, in consequence of stifled thought, been poured
                            upon the world ! Hence, a disastrous alienation has ensued between the disciples of science
                            and the teachers of religion. Between science and true religion there can be no conflict.
                            With an earth, sky, and heavens full of truths all around and before us, upon the extreme
                            margin of which we are but just entering, how can such a world produce a dogmatizer, or a
                            bigot ? Bigotry shuts itself up in narrow limits, and would bind the thoughts, and manacle
                            the limbs too, had it the power. Forming a co-partnership ages ago, with its natural allies
                            (ignorance and superstition), it strove to hinder the dis- covery of hitherto unknown parts
                            of this globe, and the navigation of the same, and denied the true astronomical knowledge of
                            the terrestrial, as it now does of the celestial heavens. But let us think, betimes;
                            knowledge is but an instrument, free alike to the profligate and the just; therefore wisdom
                            must be commissioned its guardian. The un- pardonable error of education has been, that it
                            did not begin with simple truths and elementary ideas, and rise by gradation to combined
                            results. It began with teaching systems, rules, schemes and complex doctrines, which years
                            of analysis would scarcely serve to unfold ; all is administered in a mass. In this way,
                            errors and truths are passed over to our successors, done up in the same bundle, and they
                            pass them to others, and so onward, to be perpetual sources of error, alienation and
                            discord. A new era is opening upon the world ! the history of the future is like a widening
                            stream, and is about to pass through regions such as have never been traversed before ; we
                            must prepare ourselves to pass with safety through this new ordeal: " Pat hand to the plow
                            of endeavor, Place feet in the truth-furrowed track; Set face to the future, and never One
                            wavering moment look back. For none, who confidingly center All hopes on the by-gones, and
                            ban. The present, are fitted to enter The on-going progress of man." Just in proportion as
                            man becomes Christlike, he passes out of the region of finality —system building—into the
                            region of perpetual activities for good; his is the religion of philosophy, science, love,,
                            which expands the mind, reaches out to every capacity; says: " Suffer little children to
                            eome unto me;" and as "I am lifted up (progressed) so will I draw all men unto me." Could
                            Jesus stand where we now stand, and view his record o'er, Would he still cling to that star
                            light,—-and that alone restore 1 And say 'tis done, ' tis final, all that man can ever be,
                                <pb n="66" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 66 THE SHAKER. That through one twain the race did fall, by one
                            alone they're free ? He was the promised Saviour ; first saved himself from loss ; Then
                            said, " If ye would Saviours he, come bear your daily cross." His life was one great
                            prophecy, which told of future good ; Declared, the state of infancy betokened angelhood.
                            All truth undiscovered, or unrevealed, partakes of the nature of the concrete ; it is like
                            gold in quartz ; a part of the mass ; and as it forever sparkles, it is viewed by some as a
                            mere curiosity ; by others as an object of worship, not knowing its value and use, till some
                            adventurous hand liberates it from the crude mass. Then, despite the bigots who claim this
                            to be the only known specimen, other discoveries are made, and the supply is found to be
                            inexhaustible. Then every known appliance is brought into requisition, and new ones invented
                            to blast and grind, wash and melt, and coin, till the whole nation is enriched thereby. And
                            the poor devotee sees his past object of adoration appropriated to the living present. So
                            with first principles; they discover truth, pure truth, to be wrought out under the hammer
                            of reason, and smelted in the refiner's fire, till in their conscious purity they can look
                            smilingly in the face of every essayer. I freely endorse Elder Frederick's article in the
                            July Shaker, on "Finality." I think it meets the demands ofthe age. The diversity of
                            opinions and beliefs respecting a certain book has been the means of disintegrating society,
                            creating conftision. The world would be a thousand times better off to-day, were it to drop
                            all the old systems of theology, and adopt the simple, childlike religion of the human soul.
                            All the blessings of the past would be combined with the present, and make the religion of
                            to-day grander than that of any preceding age. Rejecting still the corner stone, which
                            devotees have worshipped 'round, Forgetting greater works are done by those who rear the
                            building, They falsify that holy truth, that progress means perpetual youth ; And all the
                            living must, forsooth, be to the future yielding. The teo common practice of looking
                            exclusively to the past, is unworthy of this enlightened age. A hitching post is good when
                            ahead; when passed, it is of no further use. In no age of the world's history was
                            discrimination between truth and error so acute as now. Reason assumes supremacy, and
                            demands fearless investigation. Is not the subjugation of, and ruling over woman, traceable
                            to sacred tradition, and legend ? And is not the world depraved by such antiquated belief ?
                            Brigham Young is a fac-simile of the wisest man of Bible fame ; and children are still
                            taught to do homage to his exalted wisdom. If either of them now lived in Massachusetts,
                            they would be escorted to a temple of justice.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical resurrection" TEIform="index"/>Physical Resurrection</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="De Vere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>CECELIA DE VERE</byline><p TEIform="p">Is this temple—painful prison— With its throbbing bolts and bars, All the dwelling of the
                            spirit, When redeemed from earth-made scars ? Shall the body be triumphant? Shall this
                            accident of sin Make or shape the life eternal, Clog1, or give us power to win ? Shall the
                            humpback, and the cripple, And the dwarf, diseased and lame, Take their bodies, somewhat
                            bettered, But essentially the same ? Shall the soul that hid its evil In a beauteous form of
                            clay, Still unchanged, and undiscovered, Dwell in heaven's unclouded day ? Shall the face
                            that screened, and shaded reelings tender, deep and true, Mask the soul that toiled and
                            suffered For a life and spirit new ? All things in the Lord are perfect; Accidents are not
                            of Him; They belong to earth's confusion, To our own pei-ceptions, dim. If we seek the
                            heavenly portion Of the meek in heart, and pure, God will mark our earnest travel, Bless,
                            and make our treasure sure Then the soul shall dwell in victory, Far above the body's fate,
                            And be seen undimmed, unshadowed, In its true and perfect state. If we feel the resurrection
                            Of the spirit day by dayFeel the power of God, that bears us From earth's elements away—
                            Shall our thoughts to graveyards center, When our loved ones are set free ? Shall we give
                            our loathsome body All our wealth of sympathy ? We are called to know the spirit, And let
                            dust to dust be given; While our hearts, with love unfailing, Find their kindred hearts in
                            heaven. O how pure, and how exalted, Is the faith by which we're taught! Through the door of
                            Kevelation, We can " see what God hath wrought." From the earth he made the mortal; But he
                            never marked the place: Why should we of death's dark portal Seek or leave the slighest
                            trace ? Lay my frame in earth's cold bosom, When my spirit takes its flight To that land,
                            where fruit and blossom Never suffer frost nor blight; Not on stone, or sculptured marble,
                            Be my memory ever traced; But from hearts that hold and love me, May it never be erased.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notices" TEIform="index"/>Notices</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">''Witch Poison," being a severe, but merited rebuke to a discourse by one Dr. Baldwin, of
                            Troy. The doctor's discourse is included; but there appears but little of it remaining after
                            the review and re-review by Bro. J. M. Peebles. The pamphlet is worthy the perusal of the
                            thoughtful investigator. Price 25 cents. B. C. Barto, Troy, N. Y. "The "Festal " is a neat
                            little quarto of prose and poetry by a Spiritualist — Mrs. J. M. Wilcoxson. Much good sense
                            and spiritual light is imprinted oil its pages. As an evidence, we copy in present number of
                            The Shaker a poem, by which the two great antipodes in humanity are fairly illustrated.
                            ReligioPhilosophical Publishing Co., Chicago, 111.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Second revelation of the gospel, vice Christ's second appearing" TEIform="index"/>Second
                            Revelation of the Gospel, vice Christ's Second Appearing</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">When the writer first visited the Shakers, in 1817, he soon became a sincere and deeply
                            interested inquirer into their faith and theology; and the most puzzling thing he met with,
                            was the statement that Christ, or Jesus Christ, had made His second appearing in a Woman !
                            Whatever recondite sense they may have attached to the word Christ, I understood it to mean
                            the man called Jesus, or Jesus the Christ, who lived in Judea 1800 years ago, and of whose
                            history we have a fragment in the New Testament. And, I asked myself, do they mean to say
                            that this man has made his second appearing ? And, still more perplexing, that He has made
                            His second appearing in a Woman ! How could He come in a Woman ? This phraseology was in
                            full use then, and probably had been from the beginning of the institution, and is continued
                            to the present day. After becoming a member of the Society, I set about probing the meaning
                            of this mode of expression, and trying to deduce the radical idea, and to set it forth in
                            rational and intelligible language. In this search my thoughts ran in this wise: Jesus the
                            Messiah was the first man in and through whom the way of salvation from sin was revealed.
                            This revelation wras called in Greek, Euanggellion—Good news or Glad tidings. Jesus first
                            promulgated it under that name, translated " Gospel," Matt. 4 : 23, and elsewhere. Its true
                            principles were first practically carried into effect on the day of Pentecost, when the
                            community of goods was fully established at Jemsalem ; though previously Jesus and his
                            disciples had their needs supplied from a common purse, and Judas was their deacon or
                            trustee. That true church, through divers causes, mainly a relentless persecution by Jews,
                            Romans and Catholics, was ultimately "trodden under foot of the Gentiles ;" and that
                            glorious Evangel or Revelation was banished from this sphere of being and became extinct
                            among men. As this Gospel was not a human invention, it could only be restored by a Second
                            Revelation. When, therefore, the Shakers tell you that Christ has made His second appearance
                            in a Woman, they mean that the Gospel which was revealed in and by Jesus, the Christ, after
                            having been lost, has been revealed a second time through a woman. Thus, we do not pretend
                            that Jesus Christ has made his second appearing in a woman, or in any other way literally,
                            nor do we believe he ever will; but we testify that there has been—not a second appearing of
                            Christ, but a Second Revelation of the Gospel first revealed by Jesus, the Christ; and that
                            revelation was made through a woman. This is plain common sense, easily comprehended, and
                            without mystery; and, for one, I should like to have our testimony presented to mankind on
                            this subject in this way. But if it be generally preferred to continue the old mystical
                            method, I am well aware that in Paul's writings there are abundant examples to support the
                            practice. With his licentious use of the term, almost anything means Christ, <pb n="67" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SH^KEK. 67 and Christ means most anything you please. We shall notice some
                            of the figurative and mysterious senses in which it is used in his Epistles. Under Paul's
                            manipulations the term Christ becomes impersonal. The per- sonality is last in the
                            principle, and the individual character diffused in the Church or community, and as a
                            hod3r—a unit—that community is the Son of Man—the Christ, the Lord's anointed, the Lord from
                            Heaven. "For," says Paul, "we being many are one body. For as the body is one and hath many
                            members, and all the members of that one body, though many, are one body; so also is Christ
                            ! For by one Spirit [God] we are all baptized into one body, whether we be Jew or Greek,
                            wrhether bond or free, and have been all made to drink into one Spirit!" Paul sends his
                            salutation to Andronicus and Junia of Rome, " who," he says, " were ix Christ before me." In
                            Christ does not mean in the bowels of Jesus the Messiah, but they were members of the Church
                            before him. So he often uses the term Christ with scarcely an allusion to Jesus of Nazareth,
                            or Jesus the Messiah. Again, he speaks of there being " one body in Christ," "helpers in
                            Christ," " approved in Christ," etc., etc., all the time meaning in the Church. He also
                            makes the term signify the Christian religion. " Christ," says he, " is the end of the Law."
                            The Christian religion or institution is the end of the Mosaic law. "If Christ be in you: "
                            If the Christian religion or Christian spirit be in you, etc. " Christ liveth in me : " The
                            Christian religion is manifested in my life; or, he may mean that his life was a transcript
                            or true pattern of the life of Jesus the Christ. " Christ hath redeemed us : " The powrer
                            and efficacy of the Christian religion hath redeemed us, as he says in another place: " The
                            Gospel is the power of God to salvation." After all these, and many more varied senses, in
                            which the term Christ has been used, it remains a simple truth that the original application
                            of it to Jesus was to designate him as the Messiah; translated into Greek, the Christos;
                            into English, the Anointed—not a proper name but an official title. (See Jno. 1: 42-3.) " We
                            have found the Messiah, which is, being interpreted, (in Greek) the Christos, and he brought
                            him to Jesus." This Hebrew term Messiah, or Greek Christos, or English Christ or Anointed,
                            then, was the functional title of Jesus, and not his proper name, nor the name of some
                            invisible being distinct from him. We find not the least trace in either of the four
                            Evangelists, or even in Paul's epistles, of the Gnostic doctrine that the pigeon or dove
                            seen by John the Baptist was a high intelligence— a person—distinct from Jesus, that came
                            from the Pleroma, and took possession of him. That dove was simply a visionary sign given to
                            John to point out to him the Messiah, as he himself declares : " I saw a spirit descending
                            from heaven like a dove. He who sent me to baptize, the same said unto me, ' Upon whom thou
                            shalt see a spirit descending, the same is he who baptizeth into a holy spirit.' " He who
                            sent John was God, as the Evangelist declares : " There was a man sent from God whose name
                            was John." It was this same God who inspired Jesus, anointed and qualified him for his
                            mission to preach and establish the Gospel, reveal the new dispensation, as he himself
                            testified in the Synagogue at Nazareth: " The Spirit of Jehovah is upon me, because he has
                            anointed, me to preach the Gospel to the poor," etc. Thus, Jesus possessing the proper
                            endowments and qualities, was authorized, inspired and appointed of God to the Messianic
                            office—to initiate the new dispensation ; to preach the Gospel, which, as Paul says, is the
                            power of God to salvation ; that is, salvation from sin. There is not the least hint that
                            any intermediate spirit came in between him and Jehovah. He was not the Son of a Christ, but
                            the Son of God, by virtue of regeneration and the new birth. He himself was the Christ, and
                            was inspired, led and directed of God the Father, as he himself declares. As to this Jesus,
                            or Jesus the Christ coming the second time in person, it never will be. The promise of his
                            coming is to be understood as other similar prophetic language in Scripture. It is not
                            necessary that the same person should come, but one who has the same spirit to minister, the
                            same revelation to make, and possesses the same " power of the spirit," and promulgates the
                            same Evangel. The second coming of Elijah the prophet had been promised the Jews, and they
                            looked for the same person; but Jesus, pointing to John the Baptist, said : " If ye can
                            receive it, this is Elijah that was for to come." The Evangelist Luke also speaks of John as
                            going forth " in the spirit and power of Elijah." So we point to Ann, or Ann the Christess,
                            by and through whom a Second Revelation of the same Gospel, with an increase, is made; and
                            testify that "this is the Jesus, or Jesus the Christ, that was for to come." And she, also,
                            came forth in the same power of the Spirit, was inspired from the same eternal source, and
                            qualified of God to initiate and establish the Second Revelation of the Gospel, and she did
                            it! I will only add here, that as it was the special mission of Jesus to reveal the
                            Fatherhood in God, so it was the special mission of Ann to reveal the Motherhood in God.
                            This Revelation is day by day revolutionizing the world.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stability of principles" TEIform="index"/>Stability of Principles</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Mankind are continually tossing like the waters of a troubled sea, forsaking present
                            opinions, fashions or improvements for something they fancy is better, or to return after a
                            season to the same again, because no solid foundation of happiness is attained. Pleasure is
                            oft the impelling motive, and this is sought in sensual indulgences, or in ease, riches, or
                            in novelty and change, none of which afford happiness ; for abiding happiness is the result
                            of growth, and stability in the principles of virtue and goodness ; and its proper
                            nourishment can only be obtained by self-denial. Young minds partake very largely of this
                            changing element; and the more so as they receive their mental pabulum from the fictitious,
                            passionate and trashy literature of the day. If they ever become reliable and substantial
                            members of society, it is necessary that they should grow conservative ; not shut up in the
                            unreasoning elements of passion and will, but their feelings must be weaned from those
                            external and changing elements of superficial excitement, and become fixed to the principles
                            of understanding and habits of thought. The principles of eternal life revealed in Christ,
                            are unchangeable, remaining the same to every individual that receives them, now and ages
                            hence. For instance, the doctrines of the New Testament, which lie at the founda- tion of
                            our faith, and which are just as real and important to believers, in this day, as they were
                            to those who first taught them, more than 1800 years ago; the revelation upon which we claim
                            to be founded being a new revelation, not of essentially different truths, but of the same
                            truths, by the same spirit, to every soul that receives that Spirit; and a revelation of
                            further truths in the same line, as the increase and growth of souls in these, and the
                            general progress of the work of God demands them. One can no more neglect any of these and
                            be a disciple of Christ, than he can skip over the four fundamental rules of arithmetic and
                            become a mathematician; or than he can neglect the letters of the alphabet and be a good
                            philologist. Those whose motives and conduct are guided and governed by these principles
                            will exhibit a uniform and stable character, in all the varied conditions and carcumstance
                            of life—a character which they have not naturally in them, though the natural disposition of
                            some will approach nearer it than others—but a character that is formed in them by the
                            agency of the Holy Spirit, ministered by the gospel, in obedience to its principles ; a
                            character that will overcome and eventually eradicate from the soul every disposition,
                            opinion or principle that is contrary to the pure nature of God.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My experience" TEIform="index"/>My Experience</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Brainard, Jane Maria" TEIform="persName"/>JANE MARIA BRAINARD</byline><p TEIform="p">The second chapter of Matthew gives a parable, clearly illustrating a Christian character. I
                            know of no people who so readily accept a stranger, as a brother in full fellowship, if
                            earnestly seeking the truth, as the people called Shakers. They open their hearts and homes
                            to such, and say: " Come, partake with us, of all our good things." It apparently matters
                            not, whether such are blest with this world's goods or not; or even if they must need be
                            cared for in many ways. The hungry, naked and sick are attended to; the afflicted are
                            comforted, and the seeker after righteousness is shown how to be a practical Christian. I
                            often think how secure I am, from many evils that are in the world; how shielded I am by
                            visible friends, and the invisible hosts of heaven, by living a Shaker life. I have a
                            feeling for those not blest as I am, and would let them know what I have found. I am glad a
                            way is opened, whereby streams of goodness can flow from our Zion, to my needy
                            fellow-beings. I feel confident that the little Shaker will be the means of <pb n="68" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 68 THE S H A. K E PL . turning many from their unrighteousness, to the way of
                            truth. We read of the necessity of improving our talents, and of the utter darkness into
                            which one was cast for failing to improve the one talent given him. I want to throw in my
                            mite; it may feed some hungering soul. My parents were Methodists, and very strict. They
                            labored continually with their children to keep them from what they termed " the follies of
                            the world; " keeping precepts and examples, and the Methodist discipline always before us.
                            When eleven years old, there was a revival among the youth. I was one of its subjects, and
                            felt conviction for sin, and much relcasement ; it was whispered, I had met with a change. I
                            did have a feeling at that time, which though I could not utter it, yet was impressed that
                            Christians should not live like the world ! This remained on my mind as a sacred truth.
                            Thirteen years after, I took up a book at the house of a friend, commenced reading it, when
                            I felt as if cold water was running over me. Its title was, " Christ's Second Appearing, by
                            the Shakers." I found on inquiry that they lived like angels ; and that unuttered feeling
                            again came upon me, and I resolved to visit them. I did so, and cast my lot with them ; have
                            never, for a moment regretted doing so; for I know I have found true Christians. Their daily
                            life is my life; and their sacred truths are food to my soul. I have lived a Shaker more
                            than forty years; and have eaten the bread of life from my heavenly Parents' table, and can
                            never be satisfied any more without it. If my mite should prove a crumb to some soul
                            similarly hungry, I shall be thankful.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Idolatry" TEIform="index"/>Idolatry</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>ELIJAH MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">Would men draw down the smiles of heaven, let them convert the lavish, sinful expenditures on
                            the dead, to the comfort and elevation of the ignorant and poor; turn all the Mt. Auburns
                            and Greenwoods into homes of industry and comfort, or into grain fields for their support.
                            Such institutions for the dead have wrought an unworthy reformation (?) by setting up the
                            image of the beast, caste, in place of the beast sect, which made the churchyard their
                            burying place. How aptly does the saying of Jesus apply: "Let the d,ead bury their
                        dead."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Magna est veritas" TEIform="index"/>Magna est Veritas</head><p TEIform="p">It is beginning to be suspected now that digestion and indigestion have a good deal to do
                            with " a Christian spirit and temper;" but investigations of this kind proceed very slowly,
                            as it is so nice to eat and drink what we like, and so trying only to eat and drink what
                            likes us. Rich dishes look like that fruit in Eden, " pleasant to the eyes," and we forget
                            the shadows behind them. This morning I me1 our excellent and srorthy church-warden, quite
                            in low spirits about" church-rates," and other sublunary matters, and I knew well the rea-
                            son of it, but it wouldn't do to tell him Entre notes, there was a supper last night and the
                            roast beef and strong ale have at last ;aken an ecclesiastical shape.—Good Health.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love and lust—the difference" TEIform="index"/>Love and lust—the difference
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Love and Lust—the Difference. Love is lasting, lust is shifting-, All unrest and
                                    ever drifting; Love adores and saves its object, Lust would make all virtue subject.
                                    Love subordinates low feeling, Lust lives on by double-dealing; Love doth bear the
                                    heaviest crosses, Lust ne'er counts its victim's .losses; Love doth bridle speech
                                    and action, Lust for law hath no attraction; Love doth pity, breathes compassion,
                                    Lust doth spurn such kindly fashion; Love doth lavish all protection, Lust doth urge
                                    to misdirection. Love, disease and woe would banish, Lust, would make all beauty
                                    vanish; Love in use and joy abideth, Lust in base indulgence hideth; Love doth give
                                    the hearty hand-clasp, Lust may give, but with the death-grasp; Love builds homes
                                    and makes them brighter, Lust its withering chain draws tighter. Love is an angel,
                                    Lust is a devil, Stalking where furious passions revel; Love is the voice that
                                    cheers the dying, Lust is the coward his victim flying; Love is the sunlight, warm
                                    and cheering, Lust is the dread flame we go fearing; Love is the hope that cheers
                                    the living, Lust is the lease that dies with the giving. Love is saviour and
                                    redeemer, Lust a fraud—a treacherous schemer! Love doth selfishness despise, Lust,
                                    never bloated self denies. Love, spikenard pours on broken hearts, Lust seeks fresh
                                    victims for his arts; •: Love is fulfilling of the law," Lust is a traitor—scorns
                                    that saw ! Love gives worth, and wealth, and labor, Lust robs dearest friend and
                                    neighbor; Love is the coin that always blesses, Lust is the counterfeit that curses;
                                    Love is of home the light and charmer, Lust the destroyer, deadly harmer ; Love wins
                                    sweetly, all devotion, Lust makes a hell—a wild commotion ! Love yields fruits of
                                    the richest flavor, Lust wrecked hopes and a rotten savor; Love is the tried and
                                    true availer, Lust is the lawless vile assailer; Love doth bloom in happy faces,
                                    Lust doth lurk in low disgraces; Love may promise, none to doubt him, Lust may swear
                                    good faith—we scout him! Love is the freedom time makes stronger, Lust is the
                                    slavery time makes longer; Love doth lead to the noblest teachers, Lust doth abhor
                                    all faithful preachers; Love doth brave the greatest danger, Lust is to courage true
                                    a stranger; Love doth unmask the frowning despot, Lust in excuse is a senseless
                                    bigot; Love doth exalt both man and woman, Lust is the foe of all that is human!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Vestal" TEIform="index"/>The Vestal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who are Christians?" TEIform="index"/>Who are Christians?</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Barker, G. Josiah" TEIform="persName"/>G. JOSIAH BARKER</byline><p TEIform="p">Christ answers this question in Luke xiv, 26. If the people are judged hy this standard, iow
                            large a proportion would be found to be the true followers of Christ? If they are not
                            followers of Christ, can they be Christians ? We assert that the majority of professing
                            Christians have not fulfilled the text, and are not walking the self-denying path Jesus trod
                            before, inviting all who would be Christians to follow. Are they admirers of Jesus' life?
                            Or, do ihey jeer and ridicule those who live as he lived, and is now living ? Why are
                            Christian Shakers maligned by evil reports, if it is not because they bear Christ's
                            testimony and live the life ? They believe faith without works will never make a Christian;
                            and believe that the doctrine of the atonement is an invention, to save man's nature from
                            the cross. If men believed they must live as Christ lived, then would there be a difference
                            in their lives. The people have been blinded by blind teachers, who have sugar-coated vital
                            passages of scripture, so as to mean, that the people may live in the base indulgences of
                            their passions, while Jesus alone must bear the cross ! How absurd ! If we are ever saved
                            (and. we are not Christians until we are saved), it will be by a thorough self-denial after
                            the manner of Jesus, the Christ. Professing Doctors of Divinity say Jesus was God, and
                            therefore could not be our exemplar—for we are not divine ! It may be a pleasure for them to
                            teach such foolishness, but it will be a bitter disappointment to them when the truth is
                            made apparent. They do not want to live as Jesus did ; it is not because they cannot, but
                            because they icill not ! Hoping to go to heaven sometime; expecting to be an angel in time
                            to come; yet while the filthiness of the flesh presents its enticing charms, they are
                            content, to be the slaves to lust, while they sing of how good a Christian Jesus Avas ! We
                            are willing to face the question—do you live like Christians ? We take the responsibility
                            upon ourselves of being like, or unlike Jesus. If unlike, we are not his followers, and only
                            as we subdue our inclinations to sin, we are not the followers of him who said : "Be of good
                            cheer, for I have overcome the world "—we are not Christians. Now, who are the followers of
                            Christ—those who speak many good words for him, or those who live a very good life like him
                            ? They are Christians, who are daily denying themselves of worldy pleasures and sinful
                            lusts; who are living on earth as the angels are living in heaven; who, acknowledging Jesus
                            as their Elder Brother, follow his example, overcoming as he overcame—not relying upon his
                            merits, but their own. Such do not look to the future for salvation, but experience it
                            to-day—such alone are Christians.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head">At the recent meeting in Kelloggsville, Ohio...</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">At the recent meeting in Kelloggsville, Ohio, hings were spicy for a time. Bigots
                                    refused ;o permit our speakers entrance into one of the so-called God's houses. At
                                    last the Shakers came. They said, yea, yea, we will try and get into the church. The
                                    bigots exclaimed, Oh yes ! we are willing to let the pure Shakers n. And so the
                                    Shakers went in. Spiritualist ireachers took the same road. The bigots vere
                                    dumbfounded, when the Shakers declared rom the pulpit that they were out-and-out
                                    Spiritualists, and that Spiritualism led to nirity of life. Troy, N. Y.: The Shaker
                                    Elder, G. A. jomas, of Shakers, Albany Co., speaks before ,he Spiritual Society the
                                    latter part of August.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Banner of Light" TEIform="index"/>—Banner of Light.</bibl></p></div2><pb n="69" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Individuality and organization" TEIform="index"/>Individuality and Organization</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C HAMPTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear Shaker :—While so many peculiar views are receiving attention through the columns of the
                            Shaker, I am inclined to say somewhat upon the subject of Individuality. The Spiritualists
                            harp on this a great deal, and are very jealous of their individuality; so much so, indeed,
                            that they systematically attack and resist every effort at organization that happens to be
                            suggested by any of the more progressed among them, with the argument that all organizations
                            are in danger of neutralizing and destroying their individuality by subordinating the same
                            to the proposed organization. There seem to me to be two plain issues to this question: 1.
                            Mankind must go on in their present isolated and completely selfish condition, and
                            individual efforts represent all the good the world may ever hope from Spiritualism, or any
                            other reform which may arise to bless and improve them; or, 2. Spiritualists must organize
                            in some shape or other, even at the risk of the loss of their individuality more or less (if
                            there be any such loss involved, of which more further on). But how is this ? A Spiritualist
                            will tell me it is his duty to develop his individuality to the highest degree; and,
                            consequently, he must keep aloof from all organized institutions, because no organization
                            can exist which will not more or less cramp and compromise this individuality to the behests
                            of itself. This same Spiritualist, however, will straightway go and get married. Where now
                            is his individuality? It is nowhere. He has become part of a duality. In process of time he
                            has a number of children. Now he is no longer even a duality; he has developed himself into
                            part of a plurality. His independent existence is completely gone up, and his fate is
                            inexorably tethered to his wife and children. He is a complete slave. True, he may be so
                            unenlightened as to hug his chains ; but he is none the less a slave on that account, and
                            leastwise his individuality no longer exists. But sup¦ pose he is pleased not to shoulder
                            the responsibilities of a married life, but still hankers after "the fleshpots of Egypt "
                            only enough to desire a mate of the opposite sex, to whom he shall be partially attached and
                            devoted, to the exclusion of others equally worth}of his love, and perhaps far more so ?
                            Hfere, again, his judgment is a slave to his inordinate affections, and he is shut up from
                            the Godlike exercise of that universal equal Love which JesuS enjoyed (see Matt. ch. 5, v.
                            44-45). How dwarfed and wretched such a love, when the conscience is all the time
                            proclaiming in thunder tones, " The whole world is famishing for your love, and you a*e
                            wickedly lavishing it upon one single individual, violently subordinating your higher,
                            holier obligations to your lower instincts." And this must be the conclusion, leaving out of
                            the account the consideration that this exclusive love is merely a gilded, glittering ignus
                            fatuus, the design and object of which is to attract the sexes toward each other for the
                            ultimate purpose of coition, and so belonging entirely to the animal plane. At all hazards
                            individuality must be bartered away to obtain it, and Spiritualists should be the last ones
                            to plead for such partial love or favoritism. On the other hand, organization is a condition
                            of complete individualism in the highest and most glorious sense of the term ; that is,
                            organization such as was exhibted in the Pentecostal arrangement of old. Here every man's
                            and woman's best talents, qualities, loves, affections, may go on expanding in all heavenly
                            and sublime directions to all eternity. Not only so, but the wholesome rules and scientific
                            arrangement of such an organization tend continually to protect its adherents from those
                            lower influences of our common nature— " the lust of the flesh, the lust of the eye and the
                            pride of life," the very influences which alone cramp, belittle, enslave and gradually
                            extinguish all our independence and individuality. Shakerism professes to be established
                            upon the Pentecostal principles of Celibacy and Community of goods—all things in common,
                            etc. And the Shakers are willing to be judged by their works in regard to this, their high
                            profession. Therefore we would advise all progressed Spiritualists to give us a call before
                            looking elsewhere; and, above all, before staking their all upon the issues of any
                            organization not having for its basis " Celibacy and Community of goods."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lafayette" TEIform="index"/>Lafayette</head><p TEIform="p">Lafayette visited Mother Ann Lee at Watervliet, in the early and trying season of her
                            settlement there. She told him his time had not yet come to be a Shaker; that he had much
                            suffering to undergo, and a great work to perform in this world; but when he went into the
                            spirit world he might then unite with her children. Abijah Worcester, being a medium of the
                            Spirit, was violently moved by the unseen influences while Lafayette was there; and
                            Lafayette would touch him, as with a view to receive the influence. Abijah said to him: "
                            You love this power, don't you ?" " It seems very desirable," was the reply. (Witness) Lucy
                            Wood. It is a curious fact, that fifteen days before Lafayette's death was published in the
                            United States, the same was made known by himself to a medium at Watervliet (now Shakers),
                            N. Y., and was a matter of common conversation among our people. He, at the same time,
                            referred to his visit to Mother Ann, when on earth, and of her remarks to him. The above
                            Lucy Wood was an eye and ear witness of Lafayette, in propria persona. *</p></div2><div2 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pruning apple trees" TEIform="index"/>Pruning Apple Trees</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Trimming these so that they shall bear the largest quantity of fruit, other things being
                            equal, is good economy. Professor Mapes once stated to me that he trimmed pear trees so
                            closely and scientifically, as to insure each fruit bud, a blossom; and each blossom, a
                            pear. That is the principle. Look at a young apple tree, begining with the trunk, and ask
                            yourself, how many of these largest size limbs does that tree require ? It has six ; 3^011
                            take out three or four, for two or three main limbs springing from the trunk, will make a
                            tree. Is it well balanced ? Then look at each one of those main limbs, just as you looked at
                            the tree; and see how many of its largest limbs you can take out. Do the same by the next
                            size branches. And, if your tree is still too thick, follow the same plan, trim the next
                            size, until nothing remains on the tree that may not blossom without waste, and bear fruit
                            without there being any to drop off. Your apple tree will then be neither full of poles,
                            trimmed up to make room for them; nor yet so crowded, that it spends its forces in blossoms
                            that cannot set fruit; nor in setting fruit that can never ripen.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Devil—has he reformed?" TEIform="index"/>The Devil—Has he Reformed?</head><p TEIform="p">My Dear Editor :—It would seem, by the perusal of a couple of articles in a late World's
                            Crisis, that the editor, Miles Grant, has made some wonderful discoveries, and is in great
                            tribulation because of certain articles in the Shaker. Hear him talk : " We are most fully
                            persuaded that the whole thing (Spiritualism) is but the devil's system of religion ; and
                            that it has nothing in common with the religion of Christ, any more than a counterfeit bill
                            has with one that is genuine." To prove this assertion, he quotes largely that most
                            excellent article from the pen of James M. Peebles, in June number of the Shaker. In this
                            article, as your readers will remember, Brother Peebles says that Spiritualism will call for
                            " speakers with tongues of fire, hearts pulsing with prayer, and souls touched with the
                            baptism of the living Christ." His concluding remarks were: "Let us, Oh Spiritualists, be
                            true to our convictions, true to our moral and religious natures, true to the principles of
                            purity and right." From such sentiments as these our friend finds conclusive evidence that
                            it is the " Devil's religion." Why, what a change has come over that noted old personage
                            with the cloven foot! We had supposed his teachings were just the opposite of those quoted
                            It helps, however, to prepare our minds for his comments upon the article entitled Shaker
                            Cemeteries; of which he says : " Shakerism and Spiritualism are half brothers (true). They
                            have both one father— the Devil. Both systems are founded on Satan's lie—' Ye shall not
                            surely die.' " Can it be possible that the old deceiver and lifelong enemy of purity has
                            repented of his past life, confessed his sins and become a Shaker! For, of course, he must
                            be a Shaker if he begets children who are Shakers ! If this is really so, it puts Paul's
                            conversion quite in the shade, and must be set down as the most remarkable instance of
                            change of heart on record. If he can have half as much influence on the minds of the
                            millions now as before his conversion, when they were so ready to be led by him, what
                            wonderful changes will take place, even in what is called Christian Society! <pb n="70" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 7O THE SHAKER. Instead of serving Mammon they will choose to serve God;
                            instead of fostering pride they will cultivate simplicity ; instead of war, with its
                            slaughtered thousands and ruined cities, "we shall find peace that bindeth up the
                            brokenhearted and maketh glad the waste places; instead of lust, that now fills the land
                            with corruption and murder, we shall find continence, purity and mercy; instead of riches
                            and poverty—twin evils and legitimate children of selfishness—we shall find universal
                            brotherhood, with its community of interests as exemplified in the first pentecostal Church.
                            The whole Christian world will be converted to Christianity! And even friend Grant would
                            realize how much better it is to save men from their sins than it is to burn them up in
                            their sins. Alas, in the midst of my exultations therein, comes the thought unbidden to
                            mind, that even the Devil would lose his influence upon the minds of so-called Christians if
                            he should become a Shaker! In former times he has shown them the whole world, and said, "
                            all this will I give if ye will fall down and worship me." And how few have refused ! As a
                            Shaker he would show them the whole world and say, " all this you must forsalce if ye would
                            fellowship with me." And how few would accept the terms ! Kealizing how anxious the old
                            adversary is to retain his present very large company of followers, we shall require the
                            very best of evidence to convince us that he has decided to be a Shaker, or his "half
                            brother," a true Spiritualist. It occurs to us, also, that this is not the first time that
                            the Devil has been calumniated. We read that in ancient times certain of the Jews accused
                            him of assisting Jesus to cast out devils, which charge was afterwards proved to be false,
                            as this will be. As to our founding our faith on Satan's lie—" Ye shall not surely die "—we
                            see too much evidence of that death that comes from sinful ivories, to have the least desire
                            to put our confidence in that or any other of Satan's lies. But we do have confidence in
                            that promise, and trust that friend Grant will yet be induced to, given by Christ through
                            Jesus : " He that believeth in me, though he were dead, yet shall he live; and whosoever
                            liveth and believeth in me shall never die." Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vance, John B." TEIform="persName"/>John B. Vance</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="War" TEIform="index"/>War</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">Those who defend war, must also defend the dispositions which lead to war. Now those
                            dispositions are absolutely forbidden by the Gospel. Our Saviour said, "put up thy sword,"
                            and ever since that time true Christians must not, cannot go to war. The safety of a nation
                            is not to be found in arms; and morality and true religion forbid war, both in its motives,
                            and consequences. "From whence came wars and fie-htinss among you ? " asks the Apostle; "
                            Come they not hence even of your lusts, that war in your members ? " If these warlike
                            passions were effectually subdued, all wars would cease. Those who are governed by these
                            passions, are blind to their own interest; they are blind to their own best good, both for
                            time and eternity. " Wisdom is better than weapons of war." Eccl. ix, 18. Warlike passions
                            are hard masters; and they should be subdued betimes and thoroughly. Otherwise their power
                            will increase over that of reason, and will in the end lead to ruin. A.t the advent of our
                            Saviour was published the glad tidings of " Peace on earth, good will towards man; " and
                            Peace was his last gift to his disciples. " Peace I leave with you, mj Peace I give unto
                            you." "Blessed are the peacemakers." Christ is the Prince of Peace, and his kingdom is one
                            of Peace. But war belongs to the Prince of this world. War is contrary to all Christianity;
                            but wars will continue, as long as that policy is maintained, which is calculated to promote
                            a warlike spirit. The power to overcome warlike passions is found in the Gospel. It imparts
                            a peaceful, holy influence, which enables those who submit to it to conquer their passions,
                            and even to love their enemies, and thus to conquer them. Many have conquered kingdoms who
                            could not conquer themselves, and manjr crowns have been given to conquerors of ancient and
                            modern times; but God himself has prepared a crown for all the self-conquered, bearing this
                            inscription : " He that overcometh shall inherit all things."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God" TEIform="index"/>Life in God</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Redmon, William N." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM N. REDMON</byline><p TEIform="p">In the creation, God has given to his works a specific identity, nature and destination,
                            which must ultimate according to the Divine Will and purpose. All the lower orders, as far
                            as we are informed, are satisfied toith their condition ; having no aspirations of changing,
                            and rising to a higher order; or of retrograding, and sinking into a lower. The conditions
                            assigned each species, whether on the earth, in the water, or the atmosphere, seem to be
                            consonant and satisfactor}r. Man alone seems to be the recipient of discontent, unrest and
                            aspirations ; not feeling at home, but an inhabitant or tenant at will, liable to change of
                            tenure at any moment, and removal from earth. The acquisitions of time are not his, only the
                            portion necessary to his sustenance while a tenant; the stores of earth, of whatever nature,
                            fall into other hands, and remain in their appropriate sphere. The extreme folly of
                            selfishness, as set forth in the parable of our Lord, in the case of the husbandman, whose
                            barns, store-houses and granaries were already full, and his contemplations and
                            anticipations looking forward to larger barns, store-houses and granaries, remains a
                            standing lesson to after generations. " Thou fool! This night shall thy soul be required of
                            thee, and whose shall all these things be?" Man brings nothing of earth with him into time,
                            consequently has nothing of lasting ownership in all his possessions, and can take nothing
                            with him when he departs. If he has acquired little, or nothing of the true riches, he
                            leaves earth in poverty, and has to begin a new acquisition in the spirit home; very
                            different his compeer, who was called into the Vineyard of his Lord on earth, receiving
                            wages of the kingdom of righteousness, and clothed with the garments of salvation. Man
                            having the Divine impress, and aspirations in his soul, must attain to the Divine Nature,
                            and become one with the Creator, in his capacity as a recipient ; this attainment, and this
                            alone, can satisfy the unceasing desires of his Nature. Man cannot escape from himself; he
                            must be a man; yea, a man of God; or be forever miserable! The trust and responsibility lie
                            with himself; and the sooner he commences the all-important work in the new life, the better
                            ; for procrastination increases the burden, and at the same time lessens the ability of
                            bearing it. With the outward man ceases the ability to use the alimentations and desires of
                            earth; the soul must be the happy recipient of the spiritual and divine benediction of a
                            higher order; of which there are ample preparations in the heavenly mansions, according to
                            capacity and advancement. The provident Lord, before he left time, paternally and
                            fraternally informed his Apostles, that there were no suitable mansions for them; there-
                            fore, he was going to prepare a place, that he might receive them unto himself. In all
                            probability there will be astonishing disappointment to many of the professors of
                            Christianity, who expect to be taken immediately into the mansions of the Lord; whose claims
                            are mostly resting on a mere profession; having made but little, or no advancement in the
                            Divine Life. The annunciation in all probability will be, " depart from me, for I never knew
                            you !" They will be compelled to take mansions more suitable to their conditions; and thence
                            commence the divine life, and progress onward and upward in their own order and fraternity;
                            never being able to attain the Apostolic advance; but must always remain in the rear,
                            according to attainment and allotment. Our Heavenly Parents, in the Gospel, have called, are
                            calling, and will call all their children; and all who accept, and enter into newness of
                            life, following the example of their Lord by invitation, will be placed in the Miansions of
                            the kingdom, and continued in their places, according to faithfulness in their heavenly
                            Home. Those who reject their privilege, and take the retrograde and downward course, "
                            counting themselves unworthy " of the call, must be content to take the station of the
                            disobedient and froward, and bear the sad reproach of disloyalty! The impossibility of man
                            erasing from his mind the divine aspirations for the heavenly life, by attainment in the
                            Divine Nature, he cannot be satisfied with the filthy nature, and its degradation; and after
                            he has gone his whole length, and nothing remains in the lowest deep, then to his great
                            mortification, when he comes to himself, he has to retrace his steps to his Father's house,
                            and commence the new life, in the self-denying, narrow way of the Saviour; for if we go to
                            his king<pb n="71" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. dom, we must follow him in the regeneration, living
                            the new life. Justice alone can give us our dues; and these must be the result of our own
                            choice, volition and attainment; and just here the decrees of God come in, and leave the
                            children of earth without excuse or palliation ; for the Heavenly invitation is, " whosoever
                            will, let him come and partake of the bread and waters of Life freely." We cannot shift the
                            responsibility. It was a great favor to the prodigal son to be accepted, after his sad
                            experience in the swine region. It is a matter of mercy, as well as justice, to assign to
                            the inhabitants of earth, mansions according to attainments; for how could the soul, just
                            released from the precincts of alcohol and the narcotics; smoking, chewing and snuffing
                            tobacco ; swearing, blasphemy, and debauchery, bear the presence of the redeemed Saviour,
                            clad in the white garments of the heavenly kingdom ? 0, the blackness of darkness ! 0 for a
                            place to hide this debauched and adulterous generation ! ! And shall we repeat the heavenly
                            record, " Come unto me all ye ends of the earth, and be saved." "Be ye pure, for I am pure,
                            saith the Lord."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God speed the day" TEIform="index"/>"God Speed the Day."</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">He speeds the day; it is his own, And hastens swift along; For suffering souls there yet is
                            born A gladness bright and strong. He speeds it most in seeming ill, In times of trouble
                            sore ; For when each earthly idol's still, We turn to Him the more. A peace is born of
                            conflict deep With carnal selfish ways; And those who this sweet peace can keep, Fear not
                            while truth delays. He speeds it in the hurricane, The fiery fiend and hail, To help us find
                            that greater gain, Which tempests can't assail. He speeds it iu Ihe justice deep, Which
                            sinful living scorns; That what we sow we sure shall reap, And not the grape of thorns. That
                            if our life is full of greeds, And narrow, selfish aims, The sphere we move in feels the
                            seeds Which such a life proclaims. The miasmatic state it breeds, Engenders evils sore,
                            Until in pestilence the seeds Spring up and grow the more. Or, if in burning lust or hate
                            The life be inly spent, The outer sphere is only mate To that by which it's rent.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Essentials and non-essentials" TEIform="index"/>Essentials and Non-essentials</head><p TEIform="p">Progress means a movement upward, forward ; and intends that we leave the errors of the past,
                            as soon as they are demonstrated to be such, in t'he rear. To cling to a custom, for
                            custom's sake, would deny to us the benefits of all modern blessings, and in all things we
                            should compare with the old custom of going to mill—on one side of the horse's back, the
                            grain in the bag, on the other, a stone to balance it. We have proved the stone a
                            non-essential; and there are many such, that are now disturbing the balance of mind, in many
                            otherwise estimable Believers. To some the wearing of the beard is " wanting in
                            refinement,'neatness and convenience ! " This was a sister's remark, at Enfield, Conn. To
                            others, the wearing or non-wearing has a religious importance attached to it—if to either,
                            we should agree to do as Jesus did— but we don't believe in attaching so much importance to
                            customs, opinions or theologies, which are antiquated, unreligious and nonessential to
                            salvation. " The union is the gift," is a truism of our Mother Lucy Wright; and we must
                            learn to be united on all points of doctrine, of custom, even if new, when proved to be
                            essential to our well being, and when in conformity with our visible lead. The stubborn
                            conservative, hurts the union— the gift—and ties the hands and hearts of our good Ministry,
                            from jaelding their consent to have Society improve in all that would make her beautiful,
                            without departing a hair's breadth from the essential, heavenly, fundamental principles of
                            our beautiful Gospel. If Society really needs an organ to improve it, then let us be united,
                            regardless of past custom. If the beard will prolong life, or induce better physiology, who
                            will take the responsibility of lost health and life by its further abandonment ? We do not
                            say we are now in their favor; but should the decision be made in their favor, we will
                            abandon all opposition. We want only the good and pure in life; we want all the protective
                            measures that can be had, to throw around our young people, and to save them from sin. We
                            want to make home so delightful, so beautiful, that it will gather and retain individuals,
                            and would not omit a single feature that did not conflict with the purity of life, as taught
                            by the saints, and practiced by the angels. Therefore, begone, all opposition to music and
                            flow-ers; to any and every improvement that will and can stand on our everlasting
                            foundational principles. We do not ask sympathy for a progress into anything that will breed
                            a lack of industry, or permit the lending of an eye, ear or feeling to worldly inducement;
                            but we do ask the consideration of all, the good, and the too-indifferent, if we are not
                            faltering in an age of progress to our harm. If an individual will be pure and good, yet
                            wants to retain some instrument of music; wear his beard or keep some theological whim,
                            shall we reject him as an associate in the higher life ? Shall we refuse him a privilege to
                            unite with us in our consecration ? We propose the throwing away of the tobacco-box in
                            preference to the organ; and the pipe and snuff-box rather than the continued absence of the
                            harp; the flesh-pots of mutton, beef, etc., rather than the fruits and flowers, indigenous
                            to our climate. Let us move away from the wrong, and only towards the pure and good. The new
                            cycle calls for progress, as really towards some things as aAvay from many improprieties. We
                            ask charity of our comrades for our radical propositions ; we feel deeply for Society's
                            improvement, and would stop any and every leak of her strength.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things I love" TEIform="index"/>Things I Love</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Sproat, G. T." TEIform="persName"/>G. T. SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p">I love the honest, truthful soul, Who is not ashamed to say, "I own I'm wrong ; help me to
                            walk In a more perfect way." "A wrong confess"d is half redressed," Pray speak of it no
                            more; You have acted nobly, and I lore You better than before. I love the artless, noble
                            soul, Who will not wince, nor start, To learn his faults, though from a foe, With malice in
                            his heart. " Strike on, strike on, keep striking on!'' The wise old Roman said; " Your
                            blows, good friend, may mend my heart, And will not break my head." I love the brave and
                            fearless soul, Who dares, in open day, To meet his heart alone, and hear All that it has to
                            say. " If you have anything to say, Speak on, good friend, -within; Together let us seek the
                            light, And search out every sin."</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Most radically religious monthly in the world. Organ of the societies of people called
                            Shakers. Teaches thorough Christianity, unbiased by man-made creeds. Proclaims self-denial
                            to be the efficacious remedy for sin. Declares that Jesus was baptized Christ, and thence
                            became the pattern for all who name the name of Chribt, to follow. Gives information of
                            Shaker life, habits, economy, success; theology, prophecy, inspirations, revelation and
                            expectations. Deprecates war, either in the nation or in the household. Demands of all
                            Christians, lives devoted to communion of interests. Certifies that celibacy is the or- der
                            of heaven, and that marriage belongs to the earth only, and is not practiced by Christians.
                            Testifies against all intemperance, lusts of the flesh, and worldly pride. Inculcates true
                            love; separation from worldly customs, politics, etc. Claims God as Father and Mother of all
                            souls—a duality, and therefore teaches the equal rights of their children, regardless of
                            sex, color, race, education, circnmstances, or custom. Is a radical exponent of true
                            SpiritualismShakers are Spiritualists. Objects to riches; poverty; slavery of either mind or
                            body. Establishes the only true system of dietetics, and is a preserver of health.
                            Guarantees salvation to all who will live as our great e:semplar, Jesus, lived. Believes all
                            can be baptized by the same Christ Spirit, and thus become saviours to the lost or fallen,
                            first being saved themselves. Is just the thing for the uneasy infidel, and bigoted
                            sectarian. Loves all, means all shall be saved; teaches the way. Every individual expecting
                            the re-appearance of Christ, should read The Shaker, and learn that the Shakers believe
                            Christ's life puts an '• end to the world." Price fifty cents per annum; costs, and is worth
                            one dollar. Address G. A. Lomas, Editor, Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hancock, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Hancock, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Passing through Hancock recently, we were pleasantly surprised at her improved
                                appearance. Always neat, she now looks beautiful. Meeting-house modernized ; the
                                antiquated, elevated aqueduct by the roadside is no more; beautiful stone fences, with
                                posts and boards above; large permanent gates, painted red, and fastened by spring
                                padlocks—all looked rejuvenating. Very likely her people are being illustrated as those
                                consecrated souls who " put their hands to work, and give their hearts to God."</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miller, Festus" TEIform="index"/>Festus Miller
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Died, at Hancock, June 26, <persName reg="Miller, Festus" TEIform="persName">Festus Miller</persName>, aged
                                70.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon is alive to many new things. The South are building an extensive chair
                                factory, with 71 <pb n="72" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. tenant houses attached. A
                                thousand-dollar engine from Haskell's Albany works is to drive the machinery. The Chobch
                                have also purchased a powerful engine from the same firm, for their herb and root
                                department. Paint has been busy here on many buildings this season. As Brooklyn is noted
                                for churches, so may The North be for nice, commodious barns. Another mammoth has arisen
                                on the flats, and is, no doubt, ere this well filled. Orrin Haskins had his ankle broken
                                by an accident on the 6th August. We hear that the Mt. Lebanon Ministry speak en-
                                thusiastically of the singing now heard at Canterbury and Enfield, N. H.. when connected
                                with their organs! At SHAKERS (Watervliet, N. Y.). some improvements are apparent. The
                                Church remodel their workmen's lodge into a building of line appearance. The South have
                                just laid nearly a hundred feet of aqueduct, fifteen inches diameter, boiler iron, be-
                                tween the middle pond and machine shop—the wooden one having given out. South Union and
                                Pleasant Hill have each their respective Ministry's Order, as years ago, but of recent
                                date they were consolidated. We wish both many blessings. UNIOH Village, O. Daniel
                                Miller reports a large gathering of believers and Spiritualists at Mason, O. The Shakers
                                bore their testimony faithfully, which the Spiritualists received kindly, but silently.
                                Among the multitudes of Spiritualists there are a few who, having received light and
                                testimony against sinful works, are practically fulfilling the call of the Spirit, and
                                failing to fulfill unspiritual, fleshly lusts. Enfield, Conn. Our visit here was short
                                and sweet. No prettier Society do we know of. All looks neatly; buildings in good
                                repair, and improving. The Church have built an excellent carriage house and stable, and
                                have so improved the farm as to double its yield. The family garden is already a
                                picture, as well as affording an abundance of vegetables for home use and for sale. Of
                                its magnitude let us only mention that it has a thousand pear trees. The North seem very
                                flourishing. Their new shop is nearly finished, and is of palatial appearance—the
                                prettiest we ever saw. The South looks beautifully clean and inviting.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Died</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanchard, Louisa" TEIform="index"/>Louisa Blanchard
                                </head><p TEIform="p">July 30, <persName reg="Blanchard, Louisa" TEIform="persName">Louisa Blanchard</persName>, aged nearly
                                    57 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wells, Johanna" TEIform="index"/>Johanna Wells
                                </head><p TEIform="p">August 6, <persName reg="Wells, Johanna" TEIform="persName">Johanna Wells</persName>, aged 70.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice to believers" TEIform="index"/>Notice to Believers</head><p TEIform="p">The Shaker, under its present patronage of subscribers nearly or quite sustains itself. We
                            would consider it a personal favor, if any interested in its success, would write us their
                            opinions, by answering the following queries, or their equivalent: 1. Does The Shaker pay as
                            a missionary enterprise ? if not, why not ? 2. Would it be sustained, if its size and price
                            should be doubled ? 3. Are you in favor, or not, of its suspension for 1873 ? 4. What
                            substantial encouragement do you feel to assure to it from your locality? 5. Are you in
                            favor, or opposed, to the insertion of modest advertisements ? 6. Wherein could The Shaker,
                            in your opinion, be improved ? Remark : We circulate 5,000 copies monthly, among the best
                            classes of society, over an extensive territory; the benefits to advertisers are clearly
                            apparent. Please reply.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. Albert" TEIform="persName"/>G. Albert Lomas</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Send for a dozen tracts from the pens of Elder Evans and a noted, but at present anonymous,
                            lecturer—25 cents, this office. Mat&gt;AME Olympe Audouahd says in her speeeti on Woman
                            and her position in marriage, a speech delivered in France a few months since, "The only
                            thing which can make of marriage a calm, happy and ennobling union, instead of, aa it is
                            now, an eternal torture, is—-divorce.''</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beauty of my shaker faith" TEIform="index"/>The Beauty of my Shaker Faith</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Bullard, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>HARRIET BULLARD</byline><p TEIform="p">My call to be a Believer is something more than a casual circumstance. I feel its force, and
                            realize its holiness. As a woman in the sphere of nature, I realize how enslaved I should
                            be, to the fashions and life that gratify the merely animal; the object and slave of man's
                            passions. As a sister in the spiritual family of Christ, I am relieved from earthly
                            servitude, and am a free being—free to live and to be as pure as the heavens, with com-
                            panions who also are pure. I have the association of brethren, upon whom I can depend for my
                            spiritual and physical protection—who are not seeking the spoliation of the angel virtue in
                            woman. We, as their sisters, are enabled to be their ministers of comfort and love. The
                            reciprocity of gentleness and sweet companionship between brethren and sisters, who are true
                            and well tried, may find an equal illustration in the heavens, but no other condition on
                            earth yields an equal joy. I realize every day of my life, the beauty of my gospel faith.
                            Living in pure virginity, apart from the excitements of a worldly life; with a privilege of
                            confessing and forsaking the mistakes of the past, and of feeling my attachment and relation
                            to the spirits in the heavenly world. My whole being is under the guidance and ministration
                            of the superior world. I love its discipline; I am happy in my call to an entire consecra-
                            tion of soul and body to a cause so noble; and though many rebel against the call of God, I
                            know the discipline of a Shaker life is of God, and that its principles can never fail. I
                            have tasted of the bread and waters of a regenerated and eternal life, and to every sincere
                            seeker after truth, I send greeting, a welcome to share with me.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Briefs</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shakers have most certainly struck at the root of all evil..." TEIform="index"/>The Shakers have most certainly struck at the root of all evil...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"The Shakers have most certainly struck at the root of all evil, but in our opinion they
                                have struck a little too deep." Thus writes Dr. R. T. Trail; and yet, who cares how
                                deeply any strike, if the object of the stroke is accomplished, and the root of all
                                discomfiture and separation from godliness annihilated ? </p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Deacon David Osborn had frequently met neighbor Camp..." TEIform="index"/>Deacon David Osborn had frequently met neighbor Camp...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Deacon David Osborn had frequently met neighbor Camp, and compared their knowledge of
                                the scriptures, until the Deacon was nearly out of patience. In a hurry, he was passing
                                near the field where friend Camp was at work, when Camp, as usual, began : " David, do
                                you know what Haul says ?" " Yea," replied the Deacon, " It is good for a man not to
                                touch a woman ! " " No, no," said Camp, " I don't mean dat, not dat! " </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Issachar Bates, Sen., was getting his horse shod at a smith's..." TEIform="index"/>Issachar Bates, Sen., was getting his horse shod at a smith's...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Issachar Bates, Sen., was getting his horse shod at a smith's, in a western State, when
                                he, as usual, opened a sermon at man's fallen fleshly nature, and assured the company
                                present that Christ had come again, and that he was a representative of the new gospel.
                                He then showed the necessity of a man's confessing his sins, and living a new life like
                                Jesus, and lie should then be enabled to do greater works than even Jesus. While
                                preaching to his iriotly hearers, he Was annoyed by one who kept demanding a miracle ! "
                                What shall I do for you ?" h.e finally asked. " Turn that cart-wheel into a horse!"
                                replied his annoyer. " That's just like the evil one," he remarked, " to leave the owner
                                of that cart only one wheel to go home with." </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Father Joseph Meacham was convinced..." TEIform="index"/>Father Joseph Meacham was convinced...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Father Joseph Meacham was convinced, it is said, of the truth of Mother Ann's mission,
                                when, after a question from him as to her authority to preach Christ's second appearing,
                                she replied : " When the Man (Jesus) is gone, the Woman has her right." </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At the great religious revival, in Kentucky, many years ago..." TEIform="index"/>At the great religious revival, in Kentucky, many years ago...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At the great religious revival, jn Kentucky, many j'ears ago, it will be remembered that
                                a little boy was spiritually wrought upon to speak with much feeling and eloquence.
                                Closing an appeal to sinners, with the dropping of his handkerchief, wet with tears and
                                perspiration, he exclaimed: "Thus will you drop, sinners, into hell, unless you repent!
                                " This little boy is now the very reverend John Rankin, who has told the story often, to
                                many, without in the least inferring that he was once that little boy. * </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brief exposition of Shakerism" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Universal church" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">We wish to circulate a few hundred copies of our " Brief Exposition of Shakerism," and "
                                Universal Church," and will do so, post paid, to any address, on receipt of ten cents.
                                Parties, at all interested in the people, called Shakers, can get a good view of our
                                S3rstem and government, multum in parvo, by the reading the above, little but very
                                expressive works. Other works not in the list of Publications, can be procured at this
                                office.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">PUBLICATIONS. Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto ... Millennial Church
                            .... Compendium of Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Shaker Communism—Evans
                            Tracts free, where postage is paid. Ill 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 0 50 </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. ¦ Elder F. W.
                            Evans. Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Heed,
                            Mt. Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " H. S. Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm.
                            Leonard, Aver, Mass., Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Tillage, Middlesex Co., Mass. " B.
                            H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. . " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co., N.
                            H. " John B. Vance, Alfred. Shakers. York Co., Me. " Joseph Brackett, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. 72</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>