<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2603" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18960301" TEIform="date">March 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type  and  on  excellent  paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price  in cloth 75  cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER. U. S N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Tillage of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price 15         cts.
AUTHORIZED EXILES
OF
THE   SHAKER   COMMUNITY,
The religious'basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the  individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
MILLENNIAL
BY
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
In 1894 Eugene Field wrote a story which he
called "The Werewolf." When it was finished
he laid it aside and a year afterward entirely
rewrote it, and during the nine years between
that time and his death in November last,
he rewrote it eight times. His revision pleased him and he decided to print it. But death
came too suddenly, and the story was found,
unpublished, among his effects. Mrs. Field,
concluding to have the story appear, gave it
to the editor of The Ladies' Home Journal which
magazine all of Mr. Field's work, outside of
his newspaper articles, was presented to the
public. The story will be printed in the next
issue of the Journal, strikingly illustrated by
Mr. Howard Pyle.
Among the unique exhibits at the Atlanta
Exposiiion is a collection which is in itself a
miniature biblical museum. The Smithsonian
Institution has prepared the exhibit, and Dr.
Cyrus Adler, of the Institution, writes in The
Sunday School Times of Dec. 7 an article
which gives one a clear idea of the varied and
instructive features of the collection. The
geography and natural history of the Bible',
its plant life, its animal life, and its archeolo.
gy, are all represented. For the many who
will not have an opportunity of visiting the
Exposition, Dr. Adler's article otters an unusual opportunity of becoming acquainted
with the life and conditions of ancient Palestine.
JOHN D. WATTLES & CO.
1831 Walnut St., Philadelphia, Pa.
"Reaching the Masses." This is an address
to Preachers by H. L. Hastings, Editor of "The
Christian." Preachers will, no doubt, want to
read it and learn its valuable lesson. The
masses will be quite as interested to know
how they are to be reached and for what purpose. It is safe to say that no one will lay the
book aside until they reach the closing of the
thirtieth page. The good man asks, "Are we
certain that we really wish to reach the masses? And if so, for what purpose do we wish to
reach them? What is the good of reaching
them? Have we anything they wish? What
do we want of them after we have reached
them? Published at 47 Cornhill, Boston,
Mass.   Price 10 cents.
"No difference how much one knows intellectually that would enable him to believe in
a God and the angels and in a great future life
no difference how good he may be morally,
nor how much he may do toward helping humanity with love, money or means, it is of a
lower order of life than this grand possible
unfoldment of spiritual expression in man
which in its higher development enables him
to know all things and control all things to
the best interest of the world of mankind."
T. V. Gifford, M. D., Kokomo, Ind.
FREE TO LADIES AM) GIRLS.
The annual FREE distribution of rare and
beautiful flower seeds to tho.ie interested in
floriculture, which has been inaugurated by
the LADIES' EVERY SATURDAY of Philadelphia, Pa., will open on Feb. 25th and last
until the entire stock of Collections are exhausted. Each person will be entitled to but
one Collection, which will contain fresh seeds
of ten different varieties of the choicest flowers. It will be necesssiry for those residing
outside of Philadelphia t(> enclose seven twocent stamps, with name and address, to cover
charge for postage and mailing, which will be
returned to sender if received after stock is
exhausted. These Collections are distributed
for the purpose of attracting attention to this
popular weekly for ladies and girls.   Address
LADIES' EVTERY SATURDAY,
"Seed Distribution," 920 Walnut St. Phila. Pa.
The Living Topics Magazine is a unique
publication which will greatly interest all
who wish to keep informed concerning the
progress of the world, and especially all owners of cyclopedias.
It records such items concerning current
events and the progress of knowledge as one
would naturally look for in a first class cyclopedia were it up to datewhicli no cyclopedia
is or possibly can be. Even the latest cyclopedias.are generally one to five years behind
date of consulation; and yet the average
reader inquires more concerning things of
the past three years than concerning things of
the preceding three centuries.
Topics are treated in strict alphabetical order, and as often as the alphabet is covered a
new volume begins and the same course is resumed. Subscriptions only 50 cents for each
ooo pages. Specimen sent free on request.
John B. Alden, Publisher, 10 and 12 Vandewater Street New York.
The Lee family of Virginia is the subject of
d, series of profusely illustrated articles whicli
will constitute a leading feature in Frank
Leslie's Populak Monthly during the current year. The February number of this magazine, just out, contains the initial article of
the series, entitled "The Ancestors of General
Robert E. Lee, and the Times in which They
Lived," written by Mrs. Roger A. Pryor, embodying many rare portraits, coats-of-arms,
etc. This same February number of Frank
Leslie's also contains beautifully illustrated
articles upon "A Roman Festa," by Theo Tracy
"Sardinia" by Charles Edwards; "The Social
Settlement in America" by Rufus R. Wilson;
"West Point" by Carl J. Becker; "Art Students
in Paris;" and stories, sketches and. poems by
Howard Paul, George Edgar Montgomery, Dr.
J. H. Porter, J. F. Sullivan, Ella Rodman
Church, Lena L. Pepper, and other popular
contributors.
The new Frank Leslie's Pleasant Hours
for Boys and Girls improves with  every
number.    That for February is the best yet;
(Continued on 3rd page of Cover.)--><pb n="41" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of Chas. D. Hampton of Union Village, Ohio, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF CHAS. D. HAMPTON OF UNION VILLAGE, O. NO. 2.</head><p TEIform="p">IN the progress of my experience a change came over the vision of my life. From viewing the
                            face of affairs in the moral, political and religious world, my unseen adviser commenced a
                            close examination of my own particular moral standing as a rational and accountable being.
                            He began to expose to my mental vision the secret motives which moved me to action ; showed
                            me their interior indications of selfishness, and seriously called in question their
                            sincerity, purity and sound integrity. My internal state and real moral condition was shown
                            up as clear as anything had previously been exhibited and my partial, selfish feelings were
                            arraigned as being in antagonism with the general good and as having a tendency to
                            perpetuate the evils of existence and to poison the streams of human life. About this time
                            in the course of my experience, I became feelingly sensible of the operation of an influence
                            acting independent of the operations of my own mind or the suggestions of my own will, often
                            strangely producing effects even contrary to my own voluntary volitions. Sometimes it opened
                            before me a flood of light and such a power of perception on a particular subject as would
                            enlighten my understanding to see with unerring certainty the truth of a proposition which I
                            had previously rejected and thus commanding my assent and final belief. At other times by an
                            intuitive perception, which at first sight was repugnant to my former mode of thought and
                            entirely foreign from any view of the subject which had ever before been presented to my
                            view. Thus my MARCH <pb n="42" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 42 THE MANIFESTO. familiarity with this unseen
                            "mentor" increased daily and my confidence in his wisdom, justice and purity continued to
                            increase with our aquaintance until I found myself almost constantly in his company and
                            listening to his counsels. Our intimacy continued until I yielded almost entire obedience to
                            his suggestions and submitted my difficulties to the censorship of his decisions and always
                            found increasing safety and protection from his friendly and faithful guardianship. About
                            this time a circumstance occurred which I will record as it shows the stronghold my unseen
                            friend had gained on my feelings, and how awrse I was to do anything which might mar the
                            amicable relation between us. In the town where I resided there lived a man who had been an
                            old schoolmate. Between us for a long time had unhappily existed a state of open,
                            undisguised enmity in our feelings so far that we did not speak to one another when we met,
                            or give the most remote recognition of a friendly disposition. We finally settled down into
                            a formal indifference, and a most thorough contempt for one another, and it seemed probable
                            to all that it would continue through all coming time. Sitting in the presence of my kind
                            instructor and having grown so familiar as to hold converse with him by plain question and
                            answer, and entirely unsuspicious of the existence of anything wrong in my own case, the
                            following soliloquy took place. Mentor.You have done well. You have been guided by my
                            counsel and have been favored in all your understanding. Your mind is tranquil and thankful
                            for my aid and protection. I have hitherto required nothing at your hand, but to enjoy life
                            and do nothing wrong in your knowledge, but the pathway of the just can only grow brighter
                            by the renunciation of self and the mortification of pride. Are you ready to malve a
                            sacrifice? Ansiver.I am ready to make any sacrifice which your goodness may demand, only
                            grant me the continuation of your kind protection. Mentor.It is required of you that you
                            humble yourself to Jthat you confess in his presence the way you have spoken of him and the
                            contempt with which you have treated him, and in all things in which you have misused and
                            ill-treated him, you must make all the reparation of which you are capable. Confess it all
                            in his presence and then ask his forgiveness for the injury you have done him.
                            Horror-stricken at the idea of humbling myself in the presence of my equal, and of all men
                            the most hateful. I attempted to reason the matter. It seems to me unfair to descend to him
                            in this abject manner as I can not help thinking of him as most to blame. He,has said and
                            done everything to injure and distress me and to make life uncomfortable. Mentor.What he has
                            done he is accountable for and he alone must bear it, but you must do right whether any
                            other one does or not. To you it has not been awarded to judge your brother. Your present
                            peace and justification can only be maintained by obedience to my request. <pb n="443" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 43 After long meditation on the subject and summoning all the
                            fortitude of which I was master, I aro^e from my chair and walked slowly to the door. I
                            intended to comply with the command of my instructor. To my utter astonishment I met the
                            very man at the door. I faltered a moment through excess of my feelings and then in a
                            subdued tone of voice invited him to come in and sit down. He did so and after a few moments
                            silence, I commenced my confession and honestly exposed the errors of my conduct in regard
                            to him, to the best of my ability and asked his forgiveness. When I began he scowled on me
                            most contemptuously, but as I proceeded and taking all the blame to myself and laying
                            nothing to his charge, his countenance changed and became profoundly solemn. His lips
                            trernbled, tears flowed from his eyes which he had no power to suppress, and he soon melted
                            into a kind and forgiving spirit. Both of us were overcome by the intensity of pur feelings
                            and rushing into each others' arms, silently buried every inharmonious sentiment, and the
                            accumulated wrath of months and years was swept away, and forgotten forever. A mutual
                            cultivation of kind feelings was entered into and all our disunion was conquered and
                            subdued. After this scene my mind became remarkably calm and my soul seemed to be bathed in
                            an ocean of love, and for many days the measure of my joy was full. My self-love was
                            extremely mortified, but my interior consciousness was strengthened and I retained the
                            friendship of my guardian spirit. I felt in truth that righteousness was on my side, and my
                            time for many weeks rolled on as a placid stream, and I was strengthened and instructed and
                            it began to seem as though the bitterness of death had passed, and the bright morning of
                            eternal life was just dawning in my spirit. I was thus solacing my soul in its infant,
                            spiritual existence, and was instructed in its visions which were continually opening to my
                            astonished view. I was now subjected to another test. Sitting in my room, and enjoying the
                            society and converse of my spiritual attendant, the following scene was opened. (To be
                            continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As birds wake up..." TEIform="index"/>As birds wake up...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">As birds wake up when Winter goes to sleep ; As birds bring gladness with their cheering lays
                            ; So God's good angels always closely keep Some glad surprise for those who sing his praise. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="V., C. C." TEIform="persName"/>C. C. V.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is more important to gain..." TEIform="index"/>It is more important to gain...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is more important to gain a knowledge of our duties in this life, than to seek to know the
                            unknowable.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., A. R." TEIform="persName"/>A. R. S.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True nobility of character..." TEIform="index"/>True nobility of character...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">True nobility of character is the outgrowth of a life spent in devotional service and godlike
                            deeds of mercy and kindness to our fellow-beings.</p></div2><pb n="44" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto;--It is Christmas evening..." TEIform="index"/>Editor Manifesto;--It is Christmas evening...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mexico, Cerno Island, December 25, 1895" TEIform="index"/>Cekno Island, Mexico.
                                Dec. 25, 1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor Manifesto ;It is Christmas evening and I want to give a happy greeting to all the
                                faithful workers and readers of The Manifesto. Although many thousand miles divide us we
                                are one in spirit. I would like to say to all the Brothers and Sisters just a word. In
                                1854, it was predicted, when the ranks were well tilled, that man}' of them would be
                                sent out into the world to spread the gospel. The word" was,-Do not think of them as
                                wanderers but as your missionary workers. Even though some make mistakes it is better to
                                be illy spoken of than not at all. When I was quite a young girl, I stepped into the
                                railroad station to wait for the train for Troy, N. Y. There was a woman there sewing
                                over and over and I remarked how rapidly she did it and she answered, "Oh yes I learned
                                to do this at the Shakers." I asked her about them and her answer was, "their belief is
                                all right, but they do not all live up to it." I could not believe what she told me so I
                                wrent to try it myself and found that the wrong was within herself and not with the
                                Shakers. I believe the time is not far distant when the fruit will be gathered home to
                                Zion from the seeds that have been scattered. I feel that there is a great and mighty
                                power working in the world for good although it seems like an age of disbelief and I
                                believe that Mother's gospel will spread over the land. I, for one, will do what little
                                I can to live according to the teaching of the gospel, precept and example. I never miss
                                an opportunity of spreading the teachings of the gospel. Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Powers, Cornelia R." TEIform="persName"/>Cornelia R. Powers.</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">[The above has just been received at the Office of The Manifesto, and certainly, such a
                                kind word will be read with pleasure and as Christmas greetings should last till the
                                introduction of another Christmas, these are not one day too late. Ed.]</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year's prayer" TEIform="index"/>NEW YEAR'S PRAYER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>By Ada S. Cummings.</byline><p TEIform="p">Another year is dawning, O Father, may it be Unto my soul the warning, To make my peace with
                            Thee! Through days of toil and labor, I've shared Thy love divine; <pb n="45" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 45 And in return I render My all, forever Thine. This year that lies before me,
                            With pages clean and white; To Thee, shall be devoted, By walking in Thy sight. And as I
                            turn its pages And view them one by one, May I through future ages, Repeat: "Thy will be
                            done." And should I find before me, New fields of labor spread ; O Father, from Thy fountain
                            May my needy soul be fed! Sabbathday Lake, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ of the ages" TEIform="index"/>THE CHRIST OF THE AGES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mace, Aurelia G." TEIform="persName"/>By Aurelia G. Mace.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Ring out the darkness of the land, Ring in the Christ that is to be." IN the January
                            "Humanitarian" is a communication by Paul Tyner entitled "The Christ Ideal in Shakerism." He
                            says that the spirit of Jesus came to our Mother Ann Lee when she was in prison in
                            Manchester, England. No doubt it was Jesus, the Christ, for from that time she was clothed
                            with the Christ as with a garment. In that prison more than one hundred and twenty-five
                            years ago, principles were revealed unto her which the development of the Sciences have been
                            unable to overthrow. Principles that will stand to the end of time. The Revelation which she
                            received was a harvest from the generative life. Also that the mission of Jesus upon the
                            earth was to teach a higher life to those who were able to receive the doctrine. When she
                            returned to her people from the prison, she took up the work where Jesus had left it, and
                            her followers were not of the world even as the followers of Jesus, in his day, were not of
                            the world. In the Order or Community which she founded, she was second to Jesus. Jesus was
                            the first to teach the higher life, Ann Lee was the second. Both were inspired by "The
                            Christ." Our Mother being second to Jesus in the Shaker Order, was the cause of her
                            followers making use of the expression, "Christ made his Second Appearance in Ann Lee."
                            Christ had appeared in thousands before our Mother lived, and also before the days of Jesus.
                            New truths have been revealed to the disciples of Mother Ann from time to time, ever since
                            the Shaker Order has been established. Our brother, <pb n="46" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 46 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Paul Tyner is right in this, fast upon the downfall of the generative life has come the
                            enlightenment. Creeds have fallen before the Star of Revelation. The Trinity is dethroned.
                            God is our Heavenly Father and Mother. The Atonement by the death of Jesus has passed away.
                            Endless punishment is also routed, and an angry God is no more. But the sinner finds
                            punishment enough. Each must atone for his own sins, by bringing them to the light and
                            forsaking them forever. When reformation is complete the punishment is removed. Progression
                            after death is also established. A travel of the soul from one degree of grace and glory to
                            another forever and ever. A soul can recede from G-od after death, yet the farther he gets
                            away the harder he will find it to return, but return he must, sooner or later. Even the
                            Parsees bring back their first old evil one, Ahriman and his rebellious host. After being
                            purified by fire they all return and are forgiven. In the Shaker Community woman has taken
                            her place as an equal with man, by intellectual if not by physical strength. Where there is
                            an Elder, there ' i's also an Eldress, where there is a Deacon, there is a Deaconess,
                            considered equal in their powers of government. ' A Shaker must live in the light, he must
                            walk the straight path of purity, and consecrate himself and all that he has to the
                            upbuildi'ng f the cause1, should he depart from either of these principles he ceases to be'a
                            Shaker. The arts and sciences, in a future day, will flourish under the patronage of those
                            living the highest life,the Shaker life. 'Heretofore the1 work'of drawing the lines between
                            flesh and spirit'have be'en so great that there has been no time to give to any other
                            thought but that of watching'kll' the 'avenues to keep out the evils that might enter and
                            destroy the good that had been gained. In the New Heavens arid Uew Earth, all that is pure
                            and elevating in Art and the Sciences will be understood and appreciated. Sabbathday Lake,
                            Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meditations" TEIform="index"/>MEDITATIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>By Oliver C. Hampton.</byline><p TEIform="p">There's peace in the knowledge "Thy will is best" When sorrow or danger are near, It causes
                            our bark on the billows to rest, And calms the dark waves of despair. There's peace in
                            forgiveness, though oft we offend; 'Tis the elixir of life, And silence is better by far
                            than descending To angry contention and strife. <pb n="47" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 47
                            There's Heavenly peace in the union of souls, Far more than in folly and mirth, And the
                            church where this halcyon union controls, Is the happiest region on earth. Beloved Mother
                            Lucy once said to the Church, "Your union will yet be your all," And is it not best to look
                            well to our ways And see that we live to this call ? There's peace in confession of every
                            known sin, For sweet consolation ensues ; Yea! here the fruitions of heaven begin And holy
                            at-one-ment accrues. There's peace in forbearance and patience, withal, And charity has its
                            reward, When we the sore trials and sorrows forestall Of dear waiting saints of the Lord.
                            Then let us all seek the rich treasures of peace And walk in obedience and love, And build
                            up the Church in a holy increase And look for the light from above. What are we here for but
                            to work for the cause Of righteousness, purity, peace, To cleave to the Lord and obey his
                            just laws And from sinful negations to cease. To leave all our toil and our labor severe For
                            those who succeed us to share, Surrender our talents, and all that we are, For still higher
                            realms to prepare. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patience" TEIform="index"/>PATIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vinneo, Cora" TEIform="persName"/>By Cora Vinneo.</byline><p TEIform="p">Not unto every one comes wealth or fame, The pomp of triumph, and the gift of pride; Not unto
                            all comes glory's wond'rous name, Whose theme and altar have been deified. All may not wear
                            the martyr's cloak of fire, Nor clasp with fervent hands the burning stake; All may not feel
                            the prophet's high desire; Nor drink the cup of poison for truth's sake. <pb n="48" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 48 THE MANIFESTO. These call for courage which to few is given; But humbler martyrs meet
                            us every day, God's patient ones who steadfastly have striven 'Gainst foes within, and kept
                            them all at bay. Yea, all sometimes may feel the stress of toil; The disappointment that has
                            failed to win; All may with sorrow burn the midnight oil, Alone with trouble, doubt,
                            distrust and sin. All may be tried as never soul was tried; For so I know, no two can feel
                            alike; No one can die the death another died; No one has struck where you and I must strike.
                            No one has felt the triumph we may feel, The victory we gain is ours alone; No one has heard
                            the music grand and real, That swells when life gives up its undertone. Then take new
                            courage where before you failed, Guard well the heart with watchful faith and prayer, And
                            when your eyes with falling tears are veiled Look o'er the cloud, the Patience-bow is there.
                            Mt. Lebanon, 2V". Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tenderness" TEIform="index"/>TENDERNESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>By Annie R. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">Down in the woodland's deep and fragrant gloom, Where shadows quiver, green boughs interlace,
                            And soft, cool zephyrs tremble in each space; The violets grow, arrayed in purple bloom, All
                            wet with dews exhale their rare perfume. We gaze into each bright uplifted face, They
                            sweetly smile with soft and tender grace, A hint of joy from wrorlds beyond the tomb. They
                            seem to wear an angel's aureole, Such as we see in pearly dew-drops shine. Their silent
                            speechan oracle divine, Breathes forth this message to each listening soul; "All life is
                            rich that humbly seeks to bless." Oh petaled music of Love's tenderness ! Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mirth is like a burst of sunlight..." TEIform="index"/>Mirth is like a burst of sunlight...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Mirth is like a burst of sunlight in the midst of clouds which lasts but a moment, but
                            constant cheerfulness is like the bright and golden day.</p></div2><pb n="49" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saviors" TEIform="index"/>SAVIORS.</head><p TEIform="p">IT has been more than one hundred years since Mother Ann Lee published the testimony of the
                            gospel of the Christ, in this country or since the Shakers moved into the town of
                            Watervliet, N. Y. After reaching their new home they toiled faithfully for three years to
                            establish a soceity on a religious foundation, without having any accessions to their order.
                            To some of the company this was very discouraging, but Mother Ann never doubted the
                            sacredness of her mission. She placed her trust in God, and in the spring of 1780 the
                            Believers were visited by people from many of the adjoining towns. The word of God was
                            preached and the testimony of the cross accepted. Ignorant and simple minded people
                            circulated the story that the Shakers worshiped Ann Lee, and in accepting her doctrine they
                            must ignore the doctrine of Jesus the Christ. Ignorance, like every other thing, will have a
                            place and a chance to display itself and it does not hesitate to appear before the public to
                            be heard in its own defense. A minister on meeting one of the Shaker Elders, said to him,"I
                            understand that the Shakers worship a woman,Ann Lee." We worship neither man nor woman, said
                            the Elder, but we worship the Christ, whether it be found in man, woman or child. Jesus, as
                            history informs us, was the son of a Jew and was born in Bethlehem. His father was a
                            carpenter and Jesus worked with his father till he was thirty years of age. Ann Lee was the
                            daughter of an Englishman, and was born in Manchester, England. Jesus earned his daily bread
                            as a carpenter. Ann Lee earned her daily bread as a domestic or servant. These Saviors thru
                            moral and spiritual discipline arose to a position from which they were called as
                            instruments in the hands of God to accomplish a spiritual work for the peace and salvation
                            of mankind. Moses, Joshua, Deborah, Samuel, David and others received largely of the same
                            spirit and were engaged as leaders of the religious work of their day. Other saviors have
                            arisen with more or less light, in the civil and religious world, and have so advanced the
                            cause of freedom of thought and action that in all fully civilized countries every one can
                            worship God according to the dictates of his own conscience. Thru our great distance from
                            those of the first advent of the Christ, and thru the legendary stories that have been
                            written and thru the confusion of religious tongues and of creeds and of churchal dogmas
                            that <pb n="50" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE MANIFESTO. have arisen in the world and have been forced
                            upon the minds of men, we have been induced to believe many things for which there can be no
                            substantial evidence. Of this one thing, however, we are quite certain. All good comes from
                            God and the manifestations of righteousness are received of God by his witnesses and then
                            given to man. George Fox the first Quaker was a shoemaker, and yet a man inspired of God, in
                            whose heart the spirit of the Christ found a receptive place, and the doctrine of
                            non-resistance which he urged upon his people has never been excelled since that day. It was
                            thru a daily self-denial that Ann Lee received the spirit of God and become one of the
                            saviors that should stand upon the Mount Zion. "Other foundation can no man lay than that is
                            laid, which is Jesus the Christ," "who is the power of God and the wisdom of God." In the
                            power of this spirit Ann Lee became a savior of the children of men, and thru her
                            faithfulness in teaching her followers to build on the foundation,Christ, in the power and
                            wisdom of God, she aided largely' to save her people from the sins of the world. Other
                            "saviors shall come upon Mount Zion and the kingdom shall be the Lord's." A savior is one
                            that saves, and salvation may be equally, as well for the body as for the soul. The savior
                            who could heal the multitplied diseases of the civilized world of to-day, would stand in an
                            exalted position. But above this would stand the one who carries the healing balm for the
                            many diseases that afflict the moral and spiritual world. If the testimony which Ann Lee
                            delivered before the world is allowed to be obscured by the rubbish that may accumulate
                            around worldly minded Christians it will inevitably result in the loss of that soul. The
                            foundation has been laid on which to build and Jesus has said, "Follow me." To follow is
                            death to the worldly mind, but the the beautiful promise in return is the treasure of
                            eternal life. Our Lord Jesus may have gone before us to glory, nearly two thousand years,
                            and Mother Ann may have passed on for more than an hundred years, and still we need, to-day,
                            living Saviors of a living God, who can be to us what Jesus was to his disciples and what
                            Mother Ann was to her faithful children. To call on the name of Jesus because it has become
                            a popular expression of the churches, is worship without vitality and of no more use than
                            the "sounding brass or tinkling cymbal." All our protestations of care and deep anxiety for
                            the cross of Christ is no more than the blowing of so much wind, unless our lives correspond
                            in the thoughts we cultivate, in the words we speak and in the work which we perform.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn.</byline></div2><pb n="51" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MARCH, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. One copy one year, postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Feb. 1896. Two months of the New Year already passed. How rapid the flight
                                of time reminding us that it is too precious to waste in idle revery. The poet asks
                                "What is Time? The shadow on the dial, the striking of the clock, the running of the
                                sand, day and night, summer and winter, months, years, centuries, these are but
                                arbitrary and outward signs, the measure of time not time itself. Time is the life of
                                the soul." To improve it righteously is of all importance. February 3rd, Brethren
                                commenced the ice harvest, it took but two days as the large house for cold storage is
                                out of repair, and the season is not a favorable time for making improvements, the small
                                one alone was filled, which holds sufficient for all necessities. The ice is conveyed
                                direct from reservoir to storage room, by means of a slide regulated by crank and rope.
                                Though the winter by some is thought to be rather unhealthy not having the heights and
                                depths of snow-banks to encounter, yet colds and influenzas have kept their proper
                                distance with majority, and we hope it will continue thus throughout the remaining
                                season. Health is a .blessing to body and soul. jThe mind affects the delicate members
                                of the body, and when out of tune, the vibration in the physical world is very
                                discordant. To be attuned to all that is good and beautiful we must remember that the
                                "Golden age is not behind us, but before us. Sarah J. Burger.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> North Family. Feb. 1896. When the anouncement came to us that our Manifesto would
                                discontinue its publication for the present, we were depressed at the visible lowering
                                of the banner that had so long waved, upholding the testimony of the higher life. But
                                when the report came that it would continue its monthly mission, the reaction was great,
                                and we felt like shouting Glory! long live The Manifesto. The feeling here at the North
                                family is unanimous for its prosperity and continuance. Our winter to present date lias
                                been an average winter. Not as much snow as the preceeding one, but enough to make fair
                                sledding, which has been improved in hauling logs and fire wood. We are looking
                                anxiously to the opening of the season in which begins active operations on the garden
                                and farm and earnestly hope that the tillers of the soil may have a fruitful year and
                                enjoy a bountiful harvest. From your Brother who continues to work for the success of
                                the cause. Hamilton DeGraiv.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we burn the incense of devotion..." TEIform="index"/>If we burn the incense of devotion...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If we burn the incense of devotion in the clay vessel of formality, instead of arising into
                            heaven as a prayer, its essence may settle down upon us as a cloud.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Staples, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. Staples.</byline></div2><pb n="52" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Among the Osgoodites" TEIform="index"/>AMONG THE OSGOODITES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">It was on a Suuday morning, several years since that Br. Colby and wife and Sister Grover
                            held religious services in the school-house in District No. 2. As the disciples of Jacob
                            Osgood are not very numerous, and their meetings held only semi-occasionally, there may be
                            many a wise man who has not been privileged to be with them on the Sabbath. From a little
                            book which we purchased at the close of the service, we are enabled to learn authentically
                            some things concerning the "Life and Christian Experiences" of Jacob Osgood, or as he is
                            known by his followers, the "Prophet Jacob." Jacob was born March 16, 1177 in South Hampton,
                            N. H. When twelve years of age he moved to the town of Warner with his parents. At fourteen
                            he was the subject of deep, religious impressions, but did not join the church till he had
                            reached his twenty-first year. The church members, however, could not appreciate the Prophet
                            very highly as they were unable to regulate him in his manner of preaching. In 1812 he
                            announced himself the leader of a distinct order, and from that time the sect was known as
                            the "Osgoodites." The society arose in Merrimao Co., and held almost wholly within its
                            boundaries. In the western part of the town of Canterbury is a section now known as "Zion's
                            Hill," a beautiful location, which was formerly the abode of several members or this church.
                            In speaking of his own people, Br. Osgood says,"The sect suffered much from persecution.
                            Oct. 4, 1820, they took Br. Wheeler and put him in Hopkinton jail for his faith in Christ.
                            They robbed Br. Wheeler of between six and seven thousand of brick. They drove off Br.
                            Morrill's cow which was worth twenty dollars." The "Prophet" follows up a long list of
                            persecutions which were inflicted upon his people, and then notes a reaction of peculiar
                            significance. "In 1826, God made grasshoppers and they troubled the persecutors and ate up
                            almost all before them; but they did not hurt my farm much." From his own testimony, it
                            would seem that the church people dreaded to see the Prophet enter their places of worship.
                            While speaking in one of these churches "the young preacher jumped up and commanded Br.
                            Osgood to stop;saying, 'It is my meeting.' Br. Osgood answered; 'I guess it is your meeting,
                            it isn't God's' and sat down." His biographer says that the Prophet, at one time, weighed
                            not less than 356 lbs. He died in Warner, Nov. 29, 1844, at the age of 68 years. Kesuming
                            our stoiy,We were pleasantly surprised on our arrival at the little, lonely hall of
                            education, in the western part of Canterbury, to find that so many were already in advance
                            of ourselves. Nearly every seat was occupied at this early hour, and before the services
                            closed the room was densely packed, while many were obliged to listen by the doors and
                            windows. The congregation which had met for worshipful interest, or for instruction or for
                            curiosity, included members from many of the best Christian families within a circle of some
                            eight or ten miles, to which was added a fair representation of "City boarders." Br. Colby
                            occupied a chair in front of the Teacher's desk. Throwing off his coat, he conducted the
                            services in his shirt sleeves. He had no especial form of ceremonies; but accommodated
                            himself to the necessities of the hour, by standing or sitting, while he addressed the
                            audience. He informed us that he had been in the faith some forty years. During the meeting
                            he made several exhortations in a plain, straightforward manner, but dealt unsparingly with
                            the churches, the ministers and the temperance societies. He thought the ministers were a
                            pest on the earth. They worked on Sunday and for this were paid large salaries, and yet they
                            were always begging for more. "Where do we read in the Bible" said <pb n="53" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFES TO. 53 he, "that the prophets and apostles were ever paid for preaching the gospel?"
                            He made free and extended remarks, having reference to the temperance societies, but which
                            he preferred to designate as "Cold water societies." At one time the curse of their
                            preaching was so powerful," said he, "that for fifteen years the apple crop was almost a
                            failure throughout New England." As the Prophet Jacob, however, had blessed the orchard and
                            the vine, the speaker thought that the prophet had prevailed over all his enemies, and the
                            apple trees and the grape vines were again yielding bountiful returns to the faithful
                            husbandman. Mrs. G-rover, or Aunt Sally, as she was familiarly addressed, after making a few
                            remarks against the habit of lying and stealing, kneeled, alone, in prayer. Her humble
                            petition to God was eminently practical, and no doubt proved as effectual as many of greater
                            pretentious. At the close of the prayer she sung a hymn, which had been committed to memory.
                            When Christians to Mt. Zion start, They leave the world behind; They leave their spirit and
                            their pride A better world to find. And as they travel on this way Some people, they will
                            cry Come hack! come hack! and stay with me Or you will surely die. And if you meet Apollyon
                            You must with courage stand; And never turn your back to him, But do the best you can; And
                            if you will stand fast in faith, He soon will have to run, This is the way, my brethren
                            dear, That we must overcome. Br. Colby also sung a hymn of eleven verses, giving an account
                            of a plague of locusts. As the piece closed we learned that, by the prayer of the Prophet
                            Jacob, the locusts were driven away. "In eighteen hundred thirty-two A band of locusts hove
                            in view They had great meetings all around They were quite thick in every town." Those
                            interested in the entire hymn can obtain it of Br. Colby. Before the close of the service an
                            invitation was given for any one to speak, and several persons availed themselves of the
                            opportunity. Br. Colby next exhorted all to come to Christ, to the only true church, and
                            save their souls from the sins of the world. He then made the closing prayer. Ko change of
                            position was needed. Eemaining seated, and rocking easily in his chair, he offered up a
                            sympathetic and universal invocation. As in every place of religious worship there may be
                            some chaff among the wheat, still it must have been a stolid mind that did not obtain a
                            treasure of good by this peculiar privilege. The neglect to maintain order during the
                            service was most unfortunate as it gave a license to a few unbalanced minds to trespass upon
                            the kindness of our Osgoodite friends, by laughing and talking so that they might be heard
                            across the room. Alter dismissal, a general good feeling prevailed and Br. Colby and the two
                            sisters conversed with us quite freely. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let in sunshine" TEIform="index"/> LET IN SUNSHINE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Man is a product of naturelike the grass and the flowers. He has come like
                                        these, as the result of natural and Divine conditions. Find a lone island in the
                                        Pacific, with soil and rain, and behold you discover vegetation and animal life.
                                        It is not more difficult for nature to make a blade of grass than to form a
                                        coral reef, nor is it more difficult for nature to make a man than it is to form
                                        a blade of grass. In the course of time either came forth as the result of
                                        successive natural laws. What is essential for the existence of one thing is
                                        essential for the other. Light, heat, moisture, air, electric forces, all go to
                                        bring forth the great essential motion of the Universe, that is Life. Withdraw
                                        any of these and the world becomes either <pb n="54" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. a
                                        desert of sand or a sea of ice. All vegetable and animal life adjusts itself to
                                        the whims and passions of nature. Man is no exception. A cloudy sky tends to
                                        make him feel gloomy. Fog has a depressing effect upon him. The sultry
                                        atmosphere of the South makes him indolentthe bracing wind of the North makes
                                        him active. There is nothing more helpful to the spirit than the sunshine,
                                        sunshine and a great deal of it. We are too apt to forget that we are natural as
                                        well as a divine product, and that like the grass and the flowers we need
                                        sunshine and all the natural energy to our well-being.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Raisins for food" TEIform="index"/>RAISINS FOR FOOD.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"It is absolutely certain that the world would be better for it, from the
                                        hygienic point of view if we were to eat more fruit and less meat." In
                                        California the country of grapes, raisins are cheap. And the raisin, which is
                                        only the grape dried in the sun, is a natural food, if there be any such thing.
                                        Sugar which the dried grape contains has long been recognized as a genuine food,
                                        so much so that manufactured sugarthat is, sugar extracted from the sugar-cane,
                                        sugar-beets, sorghum, the maple-tree, or what notis no longer regarded as an
                                        article of luxury, but as a necessity. This being so, it would seem that dried
                                        grapes or raisins would furnish the sugar which the system needs in its purest
                                        form, for nature's laboratory surpasses all the skill of the chemists and
                                        outdoes all the triumph of analysis, quantitative and qualitative. It is
                                        sincerely to be hoped that the subject of raisins as food may be thoroughly
                                        investigated and exploited, for while they may not take the place of other
                                        foods, they may well stand up high in the second rank of food products.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal of Hygiene" TEIform="index"/>Journal of Hygiene.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The old saw, 'Stuff a cold..." TEIform="index"/>The old saw, 'Stuff a cold...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The old saw, "Stuff a cold and starve a fever," has been the source of much mischief.
                                When you have taken a cold and have some local inflamation, as a nasal catarrh or an
                                inflamed throat, it is just as improper to eat stimulating food as when you are
                                suffering from any other inflamation. If for example, the cold takes the form of
                                pleurisy, no one feeds it on beef and mince pie. But I see no reason why a pleuritic
                                stitch may not be thus fed, if lungs inflamed by a cold may be.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Dio" TEIform="persName"/>Dio Lewis.</byline></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Deacon used tobacco" TEIform="index"/> THE DEACON USED TOBACCO.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">'The Deacon felt sad and said to the sick man, "I'll pray with you brother."
                                        "Not much you won't," declared the old man. You use tobacco, and I know more
                                        about salvation than that myself."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="War Cry" TEIform="index"/>The .</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children should never..." TEIform="index"/>Children should never...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Childben should never be allowed to chew gum promiscuously, nor to put slate
                                        or lead pencils in the mouth.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Temple of Health" TEIform="index"/>.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Secret thoughts" TEIform="index"/>SECRET THOUGHTS.</head><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by R. A. Shepard.] I hold it true, that thoughts are things Endowed with bodies, breath and wings, And these we
                            send swift forth, to fill The world with good results, or ill. That which we call our secret
                            thought, Speeds to the earth's remotest spot And leaves its blessings or its woes Like
                            tracks behind it, as it goes. It is God's law. Eemember it, In your still chamber, as you
                            sit [known, With thoughts you would not dare have And yet make comrades, when alone. These
                            thoughts have life, and they will fly And leave their impress, by and by. Like some marsh
                            breeze, whose poisoned breath Breathes into homes the fumes of death. And after you have
                            quite forgot Or all outgrown some vanished thought, Back to your mind, to make its home, A
                            dove or raven it will come. Then let your secret thoughts be fair; They have a vital part
                            and share In shaping worlds, and molding fate, God's system is so intricate.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><pb n="55" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of sister Catherine Van Houten" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of Sister CATHERINE
                            VAN HOUTEN.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Agnew, H. R." TEIform="persName"/>By H. R. Agnew.</byline><p TEIform="p">Again we've assembled in presence Divine As befitting the theme of to-day; One more of our
                            circle is taken from time, Nor would we the summons delay. Affliction severe has sorely
                            oppressed, Tho' attendants endeavored to soothe; At length death has quietly caused its
                            arrest, And time's troubled waters made smoothe. Our Sister's long suffering has made her
                            more dear Our sympathy deep to the last; Love and kindness bestowed by friends ever near
                            While the vale of the shadows she passed. In the high path of virtue, her own daily choice,
                            The pearl of great price she has won; And we've no cause to mourn but with her we rejoice
                            That peaceful transition has come. With those whom she suffered and toiled here in time She
                            has met, to be parted no more; The turmoils of earth are all left behind And she rests on
                            that beautiful shore. With her it is well, Heavenly Father, we pray, Aid us in thy way to
                            press on; Open fountains of life, give us bread for the day; [the strong. Send strength to
                            the weak and comfort Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nineveh brought to repentance" TEIform="index"/>NINEVEH BROUGHT TO REPENTANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilmarth, Clara" TEIform="persName"/>Clara Wilmarth.</byline><p TEIform="p">When Jonah came out of his dark, damp prison he must have felt humble and repentant; and when
                            the Lord told Jonah to go and preach to the people of Nineveh a second time he did not run
                            away, but set out on his journey at once. He entered the city crying, "Yet forty days and
                            Mneveh shall be overthrown." This duty must have been very hard for Jonah, but the power of
                            God was with him. It took him a long time to go through that large city. He felt repaid for
                            his work however, for on the first day the people began to repent. The king himself was one
                            of the first to repent and he sent a message throughout the kingdom for all people and
                            cattle to eat no food and drink no water. The king took off his royal robes and put on
                            sackcloth; instead of sitting on his throne he sat on the ground with ashes on his head and
                            all around him. This was a sign of deepest grief; but God would not have pitied them if they
                            had not repented. This lesson should teach us to repent of our wrong-doing. God will ever be
                            with us if we ask him and give us strength to do right as he did to Jonah. Hancock,
                        Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Harding, Florine" TEIform="index"/>Florine Harding.</byline><p TEIform="p">It is a trusting and reverent heart that God loves, on such his fullest blessing rests. If we
                            pray to Him how willing He is to give ear to our pleadings. He has promised if we trust Him,
                            He will remove the burden and give strength to bear it; to clear the path, or guide us
                            through it; to lighten our sorrow, and give us comfort. With all these precious promises why
                            should we not love and trust our Heavenly Father? The Savior set the example of a trusting
                            and prayerful heart, he "leaned not in his own understanding" but trusted that the Lord
                            would guide him through all temptation. It is said "God had one son without sin but no son
                            without temptation," but he resisted only by his Father's help. This teaches that of
                            ourselves we are weak, and if we wish to overcome the wrong in ourselves we will follow the
                            example our loving Savior set, to seek guidance from God and trust all things to his
                            keeping. To those that love and trust him he has given the promise, "I will never leave thee
                            nor forsake thee." Hancock, Mass.</p></div2><pb n="56" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pickpockets" TEIform="index"/>PICKPOCKETS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sprout, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>By Granville T. Sprout.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Delays," says a quaint writer, "are the pickpockets of time. The sun does not wait for his
                            hot water or his boots, but gets up at once. Delays are like sponges, they wipe out all our
                            good intentions." Fretfulness is a pickpocket. We spend more time in fretting over one evil
                            than it would take to cure a thousand. "If this and that had not happened," we say; "or if
                            it had only been so and so," and then we sit down and fold our hands and fret, instead of
                            rising with clenched fists to light and overcome the evil of which we complain. Care is a
                            pickpocket, an arrant thief; with a file in his hand he tugs away at the bolts and bars of
                            life and digs into the foundation of the strongest citadel. No Burroughs, with his steel and
                            aquafortis is half so busy as he, lie will break through stone walls and barred windows and
                            steal away all the sweet wine of life. Pleasures are pickpockets. They rob us of our armor
                            and leave us weak and helpless in the battle of life. We grow weak in the sun of prosperity,
                            lying down and basking in it like the Dutch captain in the story who, in a calm at sea tied
                            up his rudder, got drunk, laid down and went to sleep heedless of the rocks on to which his
                            vessel was drifting. Great talkers are pickpockets. They steal from us our minutes which are
                            the "golden sands of life." They talk on, who of all persons have the least to say, stealing
                            at once our own precious time and their own borrowed moments thus committing a double theft.
                            Working energetic men have always been impatient of such. "Madam," said the sarcastic old
                            Dr. Abernethy to a patient who was describing to him her disease with a tongue that ran like
                            a trip-hammer, "Madam how much longer time will it take you to finish your story? I was
                            thinking, I have a patient across the way, I will go and visit her, in the meantime you can
                            sit here and keep on talking, I will return in about half an hour, perhaps in that time you
                            will have finished your story." Idlers are the greatest pickpockets. One would think that
                            time was to them a gift to be treated as a child treats its toys, to be broken to pieces and
                            thrown away. Do not parley with such, but make them feel by word and example, how highly you
                            prize the wealth that they so lightly esteem. "Have you any business with me?" Cecil used to
                            say to those persons who taxed his time too heavily, "If you have not, pray excuse me,
                            because Time and I have weighty business together." ''You are welcome to my house, my
                            grounds, my horses, my pictures, my books, but I cannot say thus to you of the best portion
                            of my estatemy time." A ate great scholar and statesman used to say to his guests, after
                            having devoted to them what time he could well spare from other duties: If I have ever been
                            able to do anything worth mentioning in life it has been by setting a trap to catch the
                            minutes. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Those who are interested in the Shakers will find a clear and candid article on "The Christ
                            Ideal in Shakerism," in the "Humanitarian" of January, 189G. . A. Sequin of Chicago, Editor
                            of the "True Protestant" has entered the Lecture field in the interest of a Home for
                            ex-priests, nuns and monks, who have left the Church of Home. Ira A. Fuller has donated for
                            this purpose a tract of twenty acres of land in the state of Wisconsin. Mackintoshes and
                            Rubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to users. Sample free.
                            Manufacturer, P. O. 1871 New York.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pomeroy, Bishop" TEIform="index"/>Bishop Pomeroy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Bishop Pomeroy, at Hancock, Mass. Jan. 31, 1896. Age 84 years and 6 mo. He was a good and
                                virtuous man, true to the cause he had espoused, and a kindly willing helper. He was
                                well spoken of by all. E. B.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Van Houten, Catherine" TEIform="index"/>Catherine Van Houten
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Catherine Van Houten, at Mount Lebanon, N. Y. Feb. 7, 1896. Age 78 years and 2 mo. H. R.
                                A.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
it is full of good things for young people.
Oliver Optic starts the number with an interesting Washington's Birthday Story. An article that all readers of juvenile literature will
enjoy is "Favorite Story-writers for Young
People," by Frank Lee Farnell, in which are
described the methods of work of Oliver Optic,
Edward S. Ellis, Nora Perry, J. T. Trowbridge
and Susan Coolidge; finely illustrated with
their latest portraits. It is the first of a series
of papers on the subject. Then there is an article on "Costumes for a Fancy Dress Party";
an entertaining chat about chameleons; several short stories; the continuation of the two
serials by Edward S.Ellis and Jeannette H.
Wai worth; a story for the little folks; the editor's talks about the new books for boys and
girls: and a number of puzzles, for the solution of which a prize of $5 is offered.
The Altruist is a monthly paper, partly in
Phonetic spelling and devoted to common
property, united labor, Community homes,
and equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all live
and work together, and hold all their property in common, all the men and women having
equal rights in deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year; specimen
copy free.   Address A. Longley, Higbee, Mo.
The A ltrurian is a six-page weekly paper
pupblished by the Altruria Cooperative
Colony. It is one of the ablest reform journals now published. Price: One Year 50 cents.
Six months, 25 cents; Ten weeks, 10 cents.
Sample copie s no charge. Altruria, California.
William H. O'Bryan, Business Mang.
CALL THINGS BY THEIR EIGHT NAME.
Rev. Makk Guy Peaese tells the following story:
A member of the church once got drunk.
He sought to go back to God and get his
peace restored. He could not find the
Savior, so he sought again. His minister
called upon him. The minister said to him :
"You pray again."
They knelt down together. "O God!
Thou knowest thy servant in a moment of
unwatchfulness was overtaken by sin."
"Nonsense!" said the minister. "Tell
the Lord you got drunk."
He began again: "O Lord! Thou knowest thy servant in his weakness and frailty
was overtaken by a besetment."
"Nonsense!   Tell the Lord that you got
drunk."
At last the poor fellow said: "O God,
have mercy upon me! I got drunk."
Then very speedily that man was at
peace with God again.Selected.
the shaker covenant
This work sets fortli the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community :  of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
he same   time, afloid  instincticn to all   inquiring   minds.    Price 5   cts. each,   postage
paid, or 3(! ets. per doz.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF   THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price,  10 cts.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND   THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latent   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
Good reliable men,   to sell
our    Choice    and     Hardly
Nursery Stock such as Fruit
Trees, Roses Shrubs and OrWANTED
namentals. Ladies make this business a success. Easy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Fkee. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F. N. MAY company,
Nurserymen and Seedsmen, Rochester, N. Y.
POUR
By Pressing the Lid.
Tea and Coffee Pots that pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and'artistic.   Send for pamphlet.
THE ASBURY=PAINE MFQ. CO., Phila., Pa.
This is a good thingEd.
The Hawks Nursery Co.,
Rochester, N. Y.
We
want
one or
WANTED SALESMEN
  two GOOD MEN in each County to take
orders for a Choice line of NURSERY
STOCK or SEED POTATOES- Stock and
Seed guaranteed. We can give you Steady
Employment with Regular Pay. It will
cost you nothing to give it a trial. State when
writing which vor prefer to sell.   Address
Popular Science
NEWS
Nature, Invention,
Botany, Electricity,
Chemistry, Medicine,
Hygiene
HEALTH
Formerly BOSTON JOOBML OF CHEMISTRY
Enlarged and Improved
Contains a large, number of Short, Easy,
Practical, Interesting and Popular, Scientific
articles, that can be Appreciated and Enjoyed
by any intelligent reader, even though he
knew little or nothing of Science.
Profusely illustrated  and  Free
from Technicalities
Newsdealers, 10 cts.   $1.00 per year
/KrMention this paper for a sample copy.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper in the World.
PUBLISHED  MONTHLY  BY
BENJ. MLAKD, New York.
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, *83.Oa
year; $1.50 six months. Address, MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 361 Broadway, New York City.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 861 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brouprht before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Scien'dfsG American
Agency for ^
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>