<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0205" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18720501" TEIform="date">May 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">33-40</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="33" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">SHAKER " I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THK DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLOKY,
                        SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A. Lomas,
                        Editor. SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., MAY, 1872. NO. 5. Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saviours" TEIform="index"/>Saviours</head><p TEIform="p">Analyzed, signifies persons or things which save. Salt is a preservative; and individuals, who are " Saviours
                            come to Zion," have been alluded to as " the salt of the earth." The aspiration of every spiritually inclined
                            soul, is to be saved. Salvation, to the multitudes, signifies an escape from a just penalty—having been wicked,
                            to avoid punishment. This is folly. " He shall save his people from their sins; " but never in their sins ! The
                            power to be a Saviour presupposes the individual saved. A drowning man is in no condition to help, much less of
                            saving a companion in a similar plight. Physicians have no right to be sick ; when they are so, they are no
                            longer qualified to help the sick. What lever and fulcrum have parents, with bad habits, to arrest and correct
                            those same habits in their children ? The name Saviour, like the title Christian, is good for nothing unless
                            accompanied by evidences of its work. Shakers are called to be Saviours—and this call of the spirit should be
                            accompanied by the qualification of themselves being saved. Are we saved from the lusts and vices of the world ?
                            Therein are we the empowered ao-ents to work for others. Are we free from all vicious habits which we know would
                            disgrace a saint ? Can we, from practical experience, bear testimony against worldly pride, fancy fooleries ;
                            against patent medicines and all other medicines ? Can we be abused and not feel to return it ? Do our ideas of
                            being the inhabitants of Zion consist as really in soul-consecration to Christian principles, as in the hope and
                            love of reward for some crosses we fully take upon ourselves ? Do we ever balance the crosses we endure, with
                            the increase of the Gospel, which leads unto full salvation from every pernicious habit—every worldly way?
                            Truly, we can number Saviours among us! Jesus was and is a Saviour, inasmuch as his life and invitation yet are
                            seen and heard : " Follow me!" The hope that God will dispense salvation unearned, is su- preme folly. We know
                            that all the salvation we experience, from evils that have afflicted us, has been obtained by severe and
                            constant labor, aided by the examples and influences of those already saved. The world, to-day, needs Saviours
                            more than aught else. Belief in one, three or many Gods will avail nothing. God saves souls by giving them
                            instruction how they can be saved, and blessing them with the help of individuals already saved—not otherwise.
                            Let those who prate about salvation, from week to week, but give their congregations evidences of their
                            salvation from sin, by living a clean, holy, self-denying life, as did their humble exemplar—Jesus; then will
                            there be less sound and more salvation. God calls for volunteers to fill the ranks of Saviours to the race, even
                            as was Jesus; and the re- quired credentials are, be ye saved. Rise, Believers, in the majesty of your faith,
                            and give evidence of your Saviourships by an increasing, personal salvation; not alone in one particular, but in
                            a fully redeemed character— " Sparing no idol, great nor small— Passing one sentence on them all.'' ^</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is man a fallen being?" TEIform="index"/>Is Man a Fallen Being ?</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">1. If man hath never fallen, then he hath no sin, for sin premises a departure from rec- titude, or uprightness,
                            that is, a violation of a known law of God. 2. If there is no sin in the world, then there is no spiritual
                            darkness or death ! Do spiritual life and light universally prevail and become generally manifest ? 3. If there
                            is no sin in the world, then there can be no sorrow, for sin is the cause of all sorrows that mankind know.
                            Sorrow is suffering for the violation of law ! Is there no sorrow among mankind ? 4. Spiritual death is the
                            consequence of sin ! If there is no spiritual death in the world, then there is no resurrection from the dead.
                            The English word resurrection, is from the Greek word, " Anastasis," which literally means to stand up again.
                            How can that stand up again which never hath fallen down from an upright or standing position ? Christ said : "I
                            am the resurrection." If there be no fall, consequently no resurrection, then Christ spake falsely, and hath
                            come in vain. But are all mankind spiritually alive ? And do they stand spiritually upright ? 5. If there is no
                            spiritual darkness, the fruit of sin, then Christ is not " the light of life! " as the Scriptures declare. But
                            every true follower of Christ can testify to the truth of his words. 6. If there is no spiritual darkness among
                            men, the fruit of sin, then the testimony of Jesus, " This is the condemnation that light is come into the
                            world, and men love darkness rather than light, because their deeds are evil," must have been falsehood, for
                            condemnation is the fruit of sin ! But, alas, how many millions suffer condemnation ! 7. If there is no sin,
                            sorrow nor condemnation, then all our senses belie us. 8. If man hath not sinned, then he is not lost, and needs
                            no salvation! And Jesus Christ, as a Saviour, hath been vainly sent upon earth, for there is nothing lost to
                            save, and when Jesus Christ declared " I came to seek and save that which is lost," he spake foolishly. The
                            language should have been, '' I came to seek and save that which never hath been found nor developed !" 9. If
                            man hath not fallen from rectitude, then the present work of generation among men is perfect, or the Scriptures
                            belie the character of Noah, who, it is said, " was perfect in his generations." For the Scriptures declare the
                            present race of man to be the descendants of Noah. Is it the general understanding of mankind that they are
                            perfect in their generations ? Nay, verily! The corruption of generation is the crying sin of our whole race !
                            10. If man hath not sinned and fallen, the whole law and the Prophets are a deception, for they all recognize
                            gross sin in the human family. 11. If man hath not fallen, then the whole Gospel plan for man's redemption from
                            a fallen state is a myth, and God has made a great mistake of man's needs, in commissioning Christ to preach
                            such a gospel. 12. If man hath not fallen, all the testimony of Jesus, concerning tares in the Gospel field, is
                            false, and the whole field is good wheat, though not fully grown I What does universal experience say to this ?
                            13. To deny the fall of man, is to deny the whole revelation of God to man (so called), manifested in both the
                            Old and New Testament Scriptures. 14. If man hath not sinned and fallen, there is no regenwation necessary,
                            because there is no degeneration from which to be regenerated, since, according to this theory, man hath nothing
                            lost. 15. If man hath not sinned and fallen, then the peaceable state of the kingdom of Christ, anticipated by
                            the prophet, when the lion and the lamb should lie down together, is now reigning on the earth, or God created
                            man in <pb n="34" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. a state not good, that is, not in harmony with creation at large ! But,
                            does universal peace now reign ? 16. If man hath not fallen and sinned, then the brute is not fallen, and man is
                            his Lord invariably, and the whole brute creation is his willing subject. But, is it so ? 17. If man hath not
                            fallen, then the whole testimony of taking the kingdom of Heaven by force, as manifest by Jesus, is falsehood;
                            because Heaven is man's pristine home, or God created him in misery! Hence there would have been no need of a
                            waffare to take it! 18. If man hath not fallen, then either the harvest of the world, instituted by Christ, is
                            prematurely commenced, and God did unwisely to send his Son to inaugurate that dispensation, or, being
                            instituted, and souls, by the voice of God, being called to come into it, through God's vicegerents on earth,
                            all souls would immediately obey the command of God, as the next step in their normal and legitimate
                            development, which they do not do. 19. If man hath not fallen, then as do the waters cover the sea, so doth the
                            knowledge of God cover the earth. For, it would be cruel in God to create an intelligent, accountable being, and
                            make that being punishable for not obeying His will, and then not reveal that will to him until myriads of ages
                            after his creation ! But does the knowledge of God thus cover the earth ? 20. Verily, man is in darkness, loss,
                            sin, sorrow and woe, and very much needs salvation and redemption ! And, to deny it, is to deny all revelation
                            of God to man, of which we have any record or experience. It is to make Noah, Moses, all the Jewish Prophets and
                            historians, John the Baptist, Jesus, all the Prophets and Apostles of the New Testament Scriptures, liars and
                            blasphemers ! It is also to deny all present experience ; for there is not a living man, but recognizes, in some
                            degree, both himself and his fellows have transgressed some known law of right, for which a degreee of
                            condemnation is resting upon the soul, until confessed and repented of.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker communism" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Communism</head><p TEIform="p">When Elder Frederick was in England last summer, people got impatient at his dissertations on Bible history and
                            spiritual doctrines. They desired to know what Shakerism could do for them physically; how easily and
                            comfortably it could fill their bellies and clothe their backs, and enable them to provide themselves with those
                            conjugal relationships which are so highly prized amongst mankind generally. Thus there was a decided
                            misunderstanding between the Shaker missionary and his auditors. They looked at the subject from the side of the
                            flesh, while the Elder viewed it from a spiritual aspect. The history of communistic efforts exhibits the fact
                            that these schemes have been founded in all instances upon the physical appetites of man, rather than the
                            spiritual principles of his nature. Hence, the Shakers say, that no form of communism has been able to
                            perpetuate itself, except that of their order. Numerous communities have been established, but they have all
                            eventually been broken up through selfishness and anarchy. The Shakers avoid such a calamity by adhering to
                            their principles, which they consider to be as scientific as any functional law in physiology. The little work
                            before us* is partly historical and partly scientific. It treats of certain peculiarities of man's spiritual
                            constitution, the observance of which constitutes the essence of religion, and reviews the progress of this
                            religious life from its early dawn amongst the primitive peoples. Historically, Elder Evans accepts the Bible
                            narrative, perhaps more as a symbol of man's spiritual experience, than as a chronological record of mundane
                            facts. From this source he divides man's spiritual efforts into four dispensations or churches. During the
                            first, which ended with the flood, man fell. The function of generation given to man for a use, was abused by
                            him. This constituted " the forbidden fruit," and therefore the fall of man. The second, or Patriarchal era,
                            commenced with Abraham, on whom was enjoined the right of circumcision, and procreation, though permitted, had
                            to be atoned for as a sin. Jesus introduced the third dispensation, or First Christian Church, of which Love was
                            the soul or life, and community of property the body or outward form. The fourth era was instituted iri the
                            person of Ann Lee, who, on the part of the female side of humanity, received the Christ baptism, and inaugurated
                            the order of the male and female capable of living in accordance with the requirements of this fourth
                            dispensation. So much, then, for the historical part of the work : next comes the anthropological or scientific.
                            The Elder regards man as a spiritual being with access to the spirit-world. These dispensations have been the
                            results of revelation, originating in the spirit-world, and afterwards becoming part of the life of mankind. By
                            the inauguration of these eras man was successfully enabled to commune with still higher degrees of spirit-life,
                            and therefore able to manifest more si irituality in his outward nature. " In this fourth dispensation," says
                            Elder Frederick, " is established the final church and kingdom of Christ which possesses the ' Urim and
                            Thummim,' and therefore cannot be deceived or overthrown by evil or ignorant spirits." The ostensible purpose of
                            the book is to afford " tests of divine inspiration," whereby those having communion with the spirit-world may
                            be able to decide as to the purity of the matter communicated. The test recommended is the acknowledgment, on
                            the part of the spirits, of the " Christ principle," which teaches self-denial, purity, and fraternity; and he
                            adds, "the practical effort of this church is the entire banishment of poverty and want, sin and misery, and a
                            full suply of physical and spiritual necessaries for the body and soul of every one of its members." The one
                            essential evil to be controlled is the sexual function. " He who teaches that Christ and generation can coalesce
                            is deceived, or is a deceiver." It therefore appears why it is necessary to introduce so much theology and
                            religion into the discussions of Shakerism; for that part of the book treating of religion makes it apparent
                            that Shakerism is the practice of a purely religious life, in which the functions of animal existence are used
                            only in so far as may be necessary for the physical sustenance of the individual. The Shakers are thus ruled, as
                            to their head, by spirits from the " Christ sphere," and therefore they consider themselves as much in the
                            spirit-world, and living as near to its laws, as if they were divested of their bodies. Such then, is a
                            condensed view of the prin- ciples of this book, which is a text-book of Shaker doctrines. It is a very
                            interesting and suggestive little work. There is scarcely one word which could be omitted. The author possesses
                            a terse and perspicuous style, and his very apt introduction of texts and quotations throws a great amount of
                            light upon the meaning of many passages of Scriptu.e which seem to be perfectly misunderstood by the usual
                            expositors. We consider this work of so much interest to our readers, that we give them the oportunity of
                            purchasing it with this month's Human Nature at half the published price.—Human Nature (Eng.}. * Tests of Divine
                            Revelation : The Second Christian or Gentile Pentecostal Church as exemplified by 70 Communities in America. By
                            F. W. Evans. London : J. Burns. Wrappers, 50 cents.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Revelation" TEIform="index"/>Revelation</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>ELIJAH MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">The ever-developing law of necessity, implanted in our being, demands perpetual reve- lation : for " the eye is
                            never tired of seeing, nor the ear with hearing," nor the living soul with new inspirations. The Scriptural, the
                            sacred, the prophetic and commonly accepted word of God, as relates to the spiritual, have their votaries with
                            all shades of belief—their skeptics and infidels. Yet all are believers in present revelation in the ma- terial
                            world; no one doubts the revelations, through the science of astronomy, which tells with unerring certainty, the
                            motion of the planets with such accuracy that an eclipse is foretold with mathematical precision years before
                            its occurrence; the evidence is undeni- able, though the mystery of the science may hang like a miracle before
                            the vision. All discoveries, inventions, improvements in the arts and sciences, are so many revelations
                            emanating from the same source as the spiritual. Mind transmits from the world of causes to the world of
                            effects; these being objective t &gt; he sensuous vision, impel universal belief. Who doubts the revelation
                            to Columbus of a new world, which permeated and inspired his whole being, enabling him to confront calumny and
                            all manner of derision; stay the hands of a mutinous crew, till the physical vision confirmed his soul
                            inspiration and gave us this land of the free—God's reservation from the tyrant's rule, where " the meek begin
                            to inherit the earth ? " The acknowledgment of revelation in the terrestrial world is universal; admits of no
                            issue, no shade of opinion, it being a legitimate supply of a demand. But why has spiritual revelation come into
                            such disrepute when the spiritual has always gone parallel with the material, or followed close in its wake
                            ("first the natural then the 34 <pb n="35" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 35 spiritual") yet unrecognized ? Because
                            people of sincere motives, in all ages, through a false punctuation, have put a period or an exclamation in
                            place of an interrogation or comma, or where the subject indicated no pause; and in- tolerance, the child of
                            ultra veneration and twin brother to selfishness, saw fit to stamp with eternal infallibility what was proper to
                            the child development of the race, or perhaps mere local circumstance. And bigotry has handed down this
                            hermetically sealed dogma, declaring it to be the ultimatum of all spiritual intercourse or revealments; hence
                            the darkness of the sun of spiritual revelation. The human family is like a child in a con- tinued series of
                            revelations; and what is proper to one age is not always adapted to another ; like the rounds of a ladder, the
                            first is necessary to the succeeding. " Except ye become as a little child ye cannot enter the kingdom of
                            heaven." Little children are artless truth seekers, always inquiring, desiring to learn; importuning, impatient
                            to solve all objective problems and incorporate into their experience; then again pursue their interrogations in
                            response to new impulses and aspirations. This demands present and continued revelations. Such, Jesus said, were
                            the subjects of the kingdom of heaven. " Marvel not that I said unto you ye must be born again; " born of the
                            spirit, to enter the kingdom of heaven as a little inquiring child, a disciple learner of the spiritual alpha-
                            bet, and through it, the science of the spiritual heavens. Would it not discover sublime ignorance and idiotic
                            obstinacy to contend that repeating the alphabet by rote was the culmination .of all literary acquirements, and
                            that it revealed all that these letters were intended for, or capable of? when it is by their ever-varying
                            combinations that they convey intelligence from mind to mind. So is it with spiritual induction in this
                            ever-recurring, infinite combination, conveying a knowledge of truths adapted to our present conditions and
                            circumstances, instead of the old, bottled-up, traditional, time-hallowed theology. The spirit world is
                            progressive; and its denizens, like mortals, cannot impart what they have not acquired. Mortals have expected
                            too much perfection from its early manifestations, and through an excess of veneration, made them objects of
                            worship; hence they became dead to the ever living present. Much of the revelations held most sacred, are the
                            experiences of departed spirits in various stages of progression ; and if we go with them they will give us
                            better experiences; but if we entomb and worship them, they become our hitching post on the highway of
                            progression. John the revelator received an instructive admonition, when he fell at the feet of the spirit who
                            was communicating with him, to worship him. " And he said unto me, see thou do it not: I am thy fellow servant,
                            and of thy brethren that have the testimony of Jesus; worship God, for the testimony of Jesus is the spirit of
                            prophecy." Worship the source of this testimony and prophecy, but not the medium. Worship the primary cause
                            —intelligence—perfected mind. For according to the best authority, " in the beginning was mind, and mind was in
                            the beginning with God, and the mind was God." And mind was revealed to man, and he became a living soul—a
                            reasoning, reflecting and accountable being. This first and greatest revelation is the unqualified essayer of
                            all others. All the revealments in the material world affecting man's physical wants, have been eagerly
                            appropriated, while only of late the science of the spiritual world was almost entirely ignored. No wonder
                            Jesus, in attempting to introduce his spiritual philosophy, exclaimed : " 0 fools and slow of heart, to believe
                            all that the prophets have spoken." " Ye read the Scriptures, for in them ye think ye have eternal life : and
                            they are they which testify of me. And ye will not come to me that ye might have life." The inference is, that
                            they adhered to their old traditions, instead of recognizing in him the culmination of the prophecies. His
                            invitation is : "Come on, we have outgrown the past;" and then, as if to forestall infallibility, adds, and
                            ''greater works than I do shall yet be done." If all revelation were in the past, it shows poor design in
                            placing the eyes in the fore part of the head, or giving the feet the direction they have. The physical, mental
                            and spiritual vision, prophecy forward, onward, upward. True prophecy is a science, by which the higher
                            intelligences reveal to faith, what experience will record in the book of knowledge. " Where there is no vision
                            the people perish," is the natural sequence of the " blind leading the blind." John saw a woman clothed with the
                            sun, the direct source of light and heat; and the moon under her feet—standing above or upon all semi or
                            reflected lights; wanting the heat of the sun, of direct revelation to permeate and vitalize into life. " The
                            children of this world are wiser than the assumed children of light." Though each man's invention is patent to
                            himself, the label of infallibility would not be worth the printing, as the records of present revelation in
                            inventions, and daily improvements on the past will testify. Every new era, cycle or dispensation is prophetical
                            of progress; and the bigot that would arrogate and dogmatize its life into a fossil, finds his parallel in the
                            poor ignorant emigrant trundling all his earthly goods in a wheelbarrow, denying that there is any improved
                            method of transit; while the earth-vibrating locomotive at his heels shakes the libelous falsehood out of his
                            mouth. We need more of the childlike spirit that asks the simple truth and seeks its revelations daily; we must
                            have the living testimony of Jesus, the spirit prophecy. The subscription to the gospel of progress adds nothing
                            to that of the gospel of salvation; we have both at one price. The children of light are growing wiser; to them
                            by-gone inspirations are like flowers without fragrance; though real, they have diffused their life. The
                            children of this world are exceedingly wise; they will not trust to the vision of Solomon, his wisdom nor his
                            gold. They have vision to gratify, wisdom to emulate, and a passion to appropriate gold to themselves. " The
                            children of this world are," but by what authority shall they ahvays be " wiser than the children of light
                        ?"</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker sermons" TEIform="index"/>(From Troy [N. Y.] Times.) Shaker Sermons</head><p TEIform="p">SPIRITUALISM—THE CHARACTER OF JESUS CONSIDERED—CONVERTING THE HEATHEN—SOME GOOD IDEAS FOR THE CHURCHES—REMARKS OF
                            ELDERS EVANS AND LOMAS. Among the persons in attendance at the late Conference of the Shakers and Spiritualists
                            in this city, were Elder Evans, of the Lebanon Shaker Society, and Elder Lomas, of the Watervliet Society. Both
                            are esteemed as Leaders among their peculiar people, and from the addresses which they delivered here during the
                            Conference we have selected two, which set forth somewhat at length their views upon relig- ious questions. They
                            will be found interesting : SERMON BY ELDER LOMAS. " Watchman, what of the night? ''—" The morning dawns.''
                            Spiritual Friends: I draw some delightful inferences from this assemblage of familiar spirits. I have a larger
                            faith that there is greater good in humanity; even a zeal for the truth, and an increased desire to live it.
                            Shakers and Spiritualists mutually conferring upon what truth is, what its demands, and who are its most
                            obedient subjects ! How shortly the time when this happifying conference was deemed an impossibility ! Truly, "
                            the morning dawns ; " the world does move ! If there ever were a people, whom those who are properly denominated
                            " the world " have despised, that people are the Shakers. If there was ever an organization which the popular
                            religions of this or any other age were quite willing should be enjoyed by its own members alone, that
                            organization is the Shakers. And yet, if there is a living demonstration of greater spirituality—a greater
                            fervency to know the truth and to live it; if there is a stronger testimony against, and opposition to sin;
                            popular, but erroneous theologies, human woes, and unspiritual practices; then I am here, a willing listener, to
                            learn of the way; to make its precepts the life-line of my conduct; to be thereby a better Spiritualist—one who
                            "walks in the spirit, and fails to fulfill unspiritual lusts." The Shakers date their distinctive existence from
                            Ann Lee. You have heard of the carpenter's goodly son; Ann Lee was the beautiful daughter of a blacksmith. There
                            has been none foolish enough yet, to surround her conception and birth with anything miraculous. " Many
                            daughters have done virtuously; " but Ann Lee's system of virtue has been elevated too high for worldly reach or
                            admiration; and to the world it is there still—if obtained, it is by an exertion upwards. She was the spiritual
                            medium for the introduction of those organizing principles that made up and sustain Shaker societies. In view of
                            some of our social regulations, we have been termed " woman-haters !" and by the same vituperative class, we
                            have been branded as the " fanatical followers of an old woman !" " Consistency, thou art a jewel."
                            Spiritualists, and hate a woman ! better ask us to worship a monstrous three-headed God, whose subjects make the
                            best fighting material the world ever saw. <pb n="36" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 36 THE SHAKER. How false these charges are, we
                            will not waste time to advert, but will assure you that we are the followers of no mere man nor woman that ever
                            lived; and we will not admit that any have greater love for woman than ourselves. We love her so well that we
                            are anxious that she shall become as good, pure and angelic as the heavens ; and no desire of ours shall ever
                            soil her spiritual aspirations; and if woman becomes angelic, we are determined to be there too. But " Watchman,
                            what of the night ?" The age in which we live is not yet remarkable for its religious enthusiasm—religious zeal
                            is not prevalent. The spiritual faculties are not roused. Eevivals " are few and far between "— those that knew
                            an existence have died for want of breath. The speculative, the acquisitive, united with the inventive and
                            discovera- ble, demand a large attention, while the senses receive a support beyond my power or wish to
                            estimate. The multitudes seek daily, joys that are earthly, and how they may obtain "the almighty dollar," while
                            very few are deeply concerned in " What shall I do to be saved ? " Hence, on the planes of genius, of
                            self-gratification and aggrandizement, there is light, there is a brilliancy. But upon themes of spiritual life,
                            of eternal growth and practice, darkness is prevalent, and humanity seems swayed into a callousness that makes
                            the spirit's voice almost unheard, unfelt, unknown. We go to church; this is honorable, fashionable and proper.
                            We there hear much theological teaching, but experience only a little practical religion, for one is not the
                            other. Religion is life—eternal life; and so certain is there an eternal life, so sure is there a theology that
                            teaches how to live this life. Amidst the cries of " Lo, here ! and Lo there ! " darkness has flourished, the
                            night has seemed almost profound. Images for worship have nearly everywhere been elevated—thus have we seen
                            Moses and Mahomet, Confucius and Jesus. These very names are adored, while the characters which made these
                            individuals objects of esteem seem unworthy a consideration. Idols of fash- ion and objects of lust sweep
                            unrelentingly against spiritual aspiration; and thus, in the nineteenth century, idolatry is almost universal ;
                            erroneous theology prospers, but religion —the elevating, spiritual kind—is at a very great discount. The man
                            Jesus occupies a prominent place before the multitudes to-day ; the masses bow in reverence to his name. The
                            crucifix, emblematical of the manner he met His physical death, is also an object of worship. To these, millions
                            look for their eternal salvation, while just so many are doomed to disappointment. Jesus was the medium of the
                            Christ Spirit for the introduction of spiritual truths. Through the influence of this spirit He became a most
                            noted theologian—He taught the science of true religion; more, He practiced spirituality and realized that the
                            Gospel was " the power of God unto salvation" from His sins. It has been asserted that Shakers and Spiritualists
                            ignore Jesus. For the Shakers, I deny the charge. We love Jesus Christ, the firstborn Spiritualist and very
                            honorable Shaker. He taught an exceeding self-denial, illustrating in His life that its results were an
                            exceeding spirituality. Jesus, under the influence of the I Christ Spirit, is " the way, the truth and the
                            life-example" of true Spiritualists; but without the baptism of the Christ, I have just as much honor, and no
                            more, for Jesus, than for the millions of ancient Jews whom I have never seen! The human mind, clouded by
                            constant draughts of sensual pleasure, never will be illuminated until it enters the church of true
                            Spiritualism, and there learns that true theology is true to life. For he is a fool who believes that even God
                            can save him from the just rewards of his service to sin, unless he repents and lives differently. No more solid
                            truth does Spiritualism teach, than " that every human tub shall rest on its own bottom;" and let the millions
                            of Christian heathens prepare to face the music ! But, " Watchman, what of the night ? " There is a light
                            breaking through the clouds of darkness, and the wise are taking advantage of it. Those that were dead are alive
                            again ; the lost are found. They return and tell us they are not in the graves of clay and sand; more, they tell
                            us they never have been there : and more, that an attempt to bottle lightning would be as fruitless as to put
                            them there ! So-called orthodoxies, which find exponents in some Bap- tist churches, in other churches, and in
                            some Young Men's Associations, cry aloud: " We don't believe it." And truth remains whether they do or not; for
                            the bell of their monstrous theologies is cracked by the spirit's return, and the light is shining through. They
                            can never ring those theologies as of yore, even in their chimes, without divulging the mortifying but
                            delightful truth that they are so badly cracked by the light of Spiritualism as to be entirely useless ! "The
                            morning dawns!" We have seen the patriotic elements stirred to their very foundations. We have heard the guns of
                            Sumter, and have witnessed the uprising of a mighty nation. If the patriotism of humanity can be so ruffled, why
                            may not the spiritual elements be excited ? We claim that they may, and that we as self-denying Spiritualists
                            must set the ball rolling. If the God of the Jews can use the thunders of Sumter for the emancipation of the
                            physically enslaved, cannot the God of the Christian Spiritualist use claps of spiritual thunder to wake up the
                            sleeping, and the dead in darkness and sin; and for the cleansing of the atmosphere in that far better day that
                            shall disenthrall the millions of theology-stuffed, but religiouslystarved souls, called Christians ? " The
                            morning dawns !" The spirit of inquiry is unfolding itself as never before, and this reveals large
                            dissatisfactions with existing theologies that have no religion in them. Honest souls say : " We went to church
                            to be fed ; we returned hungry, with no more power to take up our crosses, no more salvation from our besetting
                            sins; we went to drink, and returned worse than dry !" And these individuals come to the conclusion that popular
                            churches would make very good sepulchers for dead men, but are no place for the living. What follows ? They
                            become infidelic—this is the first work of Spiritualism—it makes of its subjects thorough infidels to
                            preposterous errors. This was what made Franklin, Paine and Jefferson what they were ; Parker and Peebles, your
                            Starbucks, Waters, McCoys and others, honest engineers of unpopular truths; this is what persuaded Ann Lee,
                            Elder Evans, Abraham Lincoln and an innumerable host of honest men and women to be what they were—thorough
                            infidels to man-made creeds ! And blessed are such infidels. The call of the spirit is for progress, and no
                            progress is more necessary for humanity than a belief in and reliance upon the revelation of the holy spirit
                            to-day. We may use the revelation of the past to stand upon, but we must lean, move, press forward to hear the
                            voice of God speaking to-day. Why need we rely on Hebrew bounties, while from all around, more truthful
                            revelations are daily unfolding ? Here is one of the fruits of condemnation—men choose the darkness of past
                            ages, rather than the spiritual light of to-day, for very obvious reasons. Can we vitalize our souls with the
                            bread of the ancients ? Never! Yet this is what millions are trying to do, forgetful of the living present.
                            Souls have grown since then, so have their necessities. The yesterdays have gone, let them go; let us use them
                            only the more effectually to draw out the present; let us do them homage only as far as they speak truth to the
                            soul. Wisdom did not die with the ancients. God speaks to us as fatherly, more motherly, and as frequently as to
                            the ancient prophets, and it is through the influences of present revelations that we look to see torpor and
                            darkness, the sting of death and the victory of the grave destroyed. When we all shall ask for spirit aid as a
                            necessity— as " give us our daily bread," then will it be forthcoming in abundance, as the sweet bread of
                            heaven, and as fountains of living waters, ever refreshing, ever vitalizing. The natural manna answered its
                            purpose very well, but give vis the life-giving substance of the spirit to-day. The baptisms of John were
                            positive essentials to his Judean followers; but give us a refreshing shower, as a baptism of the holy spirit,
                            and we care not if all the fonts and ducking holes are as distant as the Red Sea. " The morning dawns," teaching
                            us to say our prayers and to do them—to ask for the kingdom of heaven on earth, and to deny ourselves of every
                            unheavenly practice. To profess less, and possess more of the divine spirit of true religion, which will make of
                            us " new creatures " of light, and wrork out in our lives the purity of the angels. Said Wesley : "I am sick of
                            opinions ; let us have good works, and the faith of practical benevolence." Was not Wesley a better Spiritualist
                            than his pretended followers ? When we yield ourselves to the inspirations of the angel-life, we see how dark
                            are the century-mossed systems of the past. By this life, we learn that if we would be more spiritual, we must
                            be less sensual. It teaches the truth of our father and mother —God. It shows the uselessness of war on the
                            plane of spirituality, where the causes of war—the lusts of the flesh—are being daily crucified. It makes us
                            dissatisfied with theologies that would teach us to be content with <pb n="37" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SH^KEH. 37 mortal
                            pleasures and carnal indulgences; and opens our eyes to the Christ planisphere where the resurrection of life is
                            established, and where an exceeding self-denial is the powerful lever for its accomplishment. And the watchman
                            answered, " The morning dawns ! " We see it dawning by the progress of spiritual truth in the churches, and
                            particularly out of them. We see it in the call of the spirit to the millions of Spiritualists to " come up to a
                            higher life ! " We see its light in the tottering power of Rome, in the foolish dogmas of " Immaculate
                            Conception " and " Papal Infallibility; " in its excommunication of thousands of its former subjects, who are
                            almost ready for Spiritualism. We see it in the downfall of empires, and the purification of republics; in the
                            eternal separation of church and state; in the exclusion of "God" and "Christ," "Virgin Mary," "Ann Lee" and the
                            "Methodist Church" from the constitution of the United States. We see the dawning of the better day in the
                            excitement over woman's wrongs and woman's rights—her wrongs of oppression, and her rights to do as she pleases,
                            when she pleases to do rightly. In the trial of Theodore Cuylerwe see light, and in the apologetical manner of
                            rendering the verdict against a woman's opening her mouth where Theodore Cuyler does his, shows the day is not
                            distant when the question of woman's having a soul will be settled in the affirmative. We believe these very
                            same stick- lers for church government, who have been so fearful lest woman in the pulpit should create a breach
                            of Divine injunctions, would be among the first to violate her rights as a phj^sical being ; and while abusing
                            her privilege of being true to her womanly instincts, they would exclude her soul from heaven, were it possible
                            to get a man to go to heaven and stay there without her ! Having given woman a representative in the Godhead, we
                            look to see her rights effected entire ; and then, if she aspires to fill the White House in Washington, or the
                            White Throne in heaven, the same will be her right, as really as her rights now are supposed only to extend, to
                            the filling and rocking of the cradle. In the face of the light of present revelation, we protest against the
                            prostitution of the so- called heathens, by the promulgation of the most erroneous doctrines the world ever
                            knew. While these heathens, so-called, are living better lives than the majority of missionaries sent among
                            them, we call up Bergh, or some more active humane power, to arrest the infliction of these theological
                            barbarities. Rather than a God should send men and women to teach of the atoning blood of Jesus ; of a triune
                            monstrosity ; of a physical resurrection of the body, and hundreds other non-essentials to a pure life; as men
                            and women, we had better hang up that god and let the heathen go; or rather, call upon the heathen to convert
                            these barbarian missionaries ! " The morning dawns." The Spiritualists have accompanied the Shakers in many
                            degrees of spirituality; they havq untrammelled their souls from many burdensome obstacles; and yet the call is
                            for progress. We present for their kindly consideration the following radical propositions, from the Shaker
                            standpoint: 1. That marriage is an honorable institution; but that it is an earthly, not a spiritual relation.
                            Angels do not marry. 2. That the flesh is opposed to the spirit; the engagement in fleshly lusts is unbecoming
                            the progressive Spiritualist. 3. That private property, war, riches, poverty, pride and worldly ambition
                            originate with unspiritual lusts, and will be discontinued when these lusts are done away. 4. That the life of
                            the angels constitutes Heaven; and that same life will introduce the millennium on earth. 5. That salvation from
                            sin, and the enjoyment of eternal life are realities that can be enjoyed here on earth, as in the spiritual
                            world. That salvation from sin means the cessation of sinful practices, and not an evasion of merited
                            punishment; and that eternal life is an unchangeable condition—having had all elementary conditions removed from
                            it. Standing on these bases, and the cry comes, " Watchman, what of the night ? " We will answer: " There is no
                            night; all is concert, all is Summer—we have reached eternal day! " ADDRESS BY ELDER EVANS. THIS AND THAT. The
                            revelation of to-day is the key to revelation in the past. Upon this rock the church of Christ must be built as
                            its foundation to rest upon—not upon the record of a former revelation. How absurd for one generation to ignore
                            revelation and spirit communion; hold- ing them impossible for their attainment; while implicitly believing that
                            some previous generation was open to them in the fullest degree ! Spiritualism comes to remove this absurdity;
                            and to explain the mysteries of the Spiritualistic history of Jesus and the Apostles. All the miracles—so
                            termed—become miraculous, as the growing of the grass, and the falling of a stone, or the continued suspension
                            of the earth in space, are miraculous. And the conclusion is reached, that either these things were not
                            performed by reason of the divinity of Jesus, or that his Apostles and such as shall do "greater works than
                            these," are also divine beings—Gods. Possession of spiritual gifts and powers proves that persons may be
                            Christians, not that they are so—wanting these gifts cuts off the claim altogether—but not at all does
                            Christianity prove infallibility. Like Adam, or John the Baptist, Jesus was born a natural man—a generative man.
                            Not until born again of the Christ-spirit could he say in truth, " I am the way, the truth, the life"—" I am the
                            resurrection." The popular error is, to make Jesus all that he was, or all that they claim him to be, by means
                            of his superior generation—a fatal error—that deprives Jesus of his chief crowning glory. Abstinence,
                            self-abnegation, selfdenial, persevering adherence to principle, by means of which he formed his own character
                            (just as all men can do or have done) up to his Christ Baptism : and then the same regeneration—travail—that
                            awaits all who shall "follow him" into the holy of holies, the inner heavens; as it also deprives humanity of
                            the great comfort, encouragement and hope implied in the exhortation : " Be of good cheer, for I have overcome
                            the world." If he was born a Christian—an utter impossibility—he is our inferior; we, who have "fought the good
                            fight, kept the faith," and overcome by means of " Christ within" us, have done what he never did. He may have
                            possessed the innocence of childhood, of an unbodied A.ngel, but not that sturdy, manly innocence which has been
                            attained under the hammer of temptation, and in the fiery furnace of affliction. Being the first—" treading the
                            wine-press alone "—may somewhat balance the ante-natal superior advantages of his class. He was subject to his
                            own parents, who did not comprehend the spiritual impressions impelling him, and foreshadowing the future work,
                            on a higher plane than the natural, which they occupied. As a natural man, Jesus had to learn Judaism—a natural
                            law applicable to the material world. 1. The law of physiology—no sickness. 2. The law of property—no monopoly
                            or usury. 3. The law of reproduction—use, not indulgence. 4. The law of war—force— right against wrong. When
                            Moses killed the Egyptian, that was war on the lowest plane—physical force. Mediumship War.—When Jonathan with
                            his armor-bearer defeated a whole host, saying, " There is no restraint to the Lord to save by many or by
                            few."—1 Samuel, 14, 6. When Gideon discharged twenty-two thousand men from his army, leaving ten thousand, the
                            Jewish God still said, " The people are yet too many." "By the three hundred men that lapped will I save you,
                            and deliver the Midianites into thy hand; and let all the other people go every man into his place."—Judges 7.
                            And with the three hundred men, with trum- pets, lamps and pitchers, Gideon created a Bull Run panic in Midian,
                            and a hundred and twenty thousand men fell, mostly by their own swords. Sampson, with the jaw-bone of an ass,
                            slew a thousand men; and then a spring opened in the jaw-bone, and he drank of it. That was medium war. Jesus
                            also was thus inspired in cleansing the temples.—Matthew 21, 12. Jesus went into the temple and cast out all
                            them that bought and sold therein, " and overthrew the tables of the money-changers, and the seats of them that
                            sold doves." This, too, was Jewish medium ivar. The entry of Jesus into Jerusalem was in the faith that the
                            kingdom of God was to be set up outioardly and by outward means; for as yet I do not think Jesus himself was
                            converted to know that his " kingdom was not of this world;" and he still believed in Jew- ish Mediumistic war,
                            as did also his disciples even until after his death. The highest form of Jewish war was where the medium of the
                            spirits did nothing, any more than the medium of table-tipping or other manifestations is expected to do—sit
                            still. Even to the last, it is not clear to me that <pb n="38" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE SHAKER. Jesus was yet a
                            consistent non-resistant. Luke 22: " He that hath no sword, let him sell his garment and buy one," was the
                            advice of a war man; and, like the advice of Paul to a young woman to marry, was not proper advice to give to
                            full Jewish Christians. And when he told them that two swords were enough, he expected spirit aid in the work of
                            destroying men's lives—Jew like. At another time, when under better and more Christian influences, he went even
                            beyond Elias, wbo called down fire, bj the spirits, to kill one hundred men, which Jesus refused to do—then he
                            was as " Prince of Peace" under the Christ influence. In short, it was a matter of travail towards Christianity
                            with Jesus, as with his apostles and all who follow him. He took the sword and perished with it—crucifixion. "
                            Jesus was not yet perfected," even after he was out of the body— in Christian principles—is the record. There
                            was a travail, and there were sufferings left behind for others to fulfill and endure, before the body and the
                            head could all be compacted together. Does the presence of Jesus at a wedding prove that at his " beginning of
                            miracles " he was already converted to celibacy, as a Christian virtue ? The fact that it takes ages upon ages
                            for the rays of the natural sun to become converted into a diamond, and that many superior stones are formed
                            before the diamond of the first water is produced, may be a fit simile of the effect upon humanity of the
                            shining of the Christ spirit for the seventeen hundred years, during which period there has been one con- tinued
                            succession of efforts to produce the true pentecostal church—the kingdom of heaven— a spiritual diamond of the
                            first water. ERRORS OF SWEDENBORG AND THE APOSTLES. Swedenborg, as an embodiment of the Angel of Spiritualism
                            (see Rev. xviii), in assuming to set up a "New Church," committed the same error the Spiritualists of to-day
                            fall into when they set up Spiritualism as a Religion. The chemists, or the agriculturists, or the professors of
                            any one of the sciences, might, with equal consistency, resolve themselves into a religious sect. Swedenborg was
                            never resurrected (either in this world nor the other) out of the Natural Order—having generation for its
                            central power. Hence, "conjugal love" was the primary law of his Church—" New Church "—and of the heavens to
                            which he had access in the spirit world. Consequently, the theology of Babylon, in its fundamentals, was not
                            subverted by the doctrines of the " New Church." The Scriptures, as the " Word of God," were never so glorified
                            on earth before by mortal man. The Trinity—" the Divinity of our Lord "— he was wholly absorbed in. With him,
                            Jesus was born the Christ. " The Lord had a Divine essence from conception itself. His soul was Jehovah, and
                            Jehovah was God. Thus the inmost of the Lord was essential Divinity; and that clothing of matter was from the
                            Mother—the humanity. The humanity of the Lord was not as other men, being conceived from the Divine Being
                            Himself. Jesus was the Son of God from eternity." This is orthodox, and is one with the general creed of
                            Christendom. Even the Apostles were not infallible. They " knew in part, prophesied in part, and saw as through
                            a glass darkly." They confounded the ideas of a physical resurrection with those of the true resurrection. Acts
                            ii, 32 : " This Jesus hath God raised up, whereof we are all witnesses. David spake of the resurrection of
                            Christ (meaning Jesus, for they confounded Jesus and Christ, as they did the physical and spiritual
                            resurrection), that his soul was not left in hell, neither did his flesh see corruption." His physical body,
                            with the wounds in the hands and side, was not left in the grave (hell), and his fleshly body did not putrefy,
                            as the body of Lazarus had begun to do when it was brought to life. Yet, what became of the body of Lazarus
                            after it was raised ? Did it not die again ? And why should not the body of Jesus do the same, provided it ever
                            was quickened like that of Lazarus ? are proper questions. The same also of the " dead bodies of the saints,
                            which came up out of their graves, and were seen of many." Scriptures could be cited to show that Jesus, the
                            Apostles, and the angels first believed in the reanimation of the body of Jesus (and of other men to follow in
                            due season), also to show that they thought a certain transmutation would occur, by means of which the physical
                            body would be spirit- ualized; in fact, become a spiritual body that could go to heaven. " This same Jesus whom
                            ye have seen go up to heaven, shall so come in like manner as ye have seen him go," etc. Phil, iii, 21: " Who
                            shall change our vile body, that it may be fashioned like unto his glorious body." " This corruption must put on
                            incorruption, and this mortal, immortality." " For if the dead rise not, then is Christ (Jesus^) not risen. Now
                            if Christ be preached that he rose from the dead, how say some of you that there is no (physical) resurrection ?
                            then would your faith be vain," etc. In short, it is no clearer that the Apostles looked for the setting up of a
                            temporal kingdom, that would be sustained by the sword, than it is that they believed and preached a physical
                            resurrection. Election.—It is also in evidence that the Apostles believed in the doctrine of Election. Rom. ix:
                            " Jacob have I loved; Esau have I hated, before they had done either good or evil; that the purpose of God might
                            stand, not of works, but according to election." Chap, viii, 9: " For whom he did foreknow, he also did
                            predestinate," etc. The Apostles were also in confusion in their understanding respecting Melchizedek, his
                            character and office; and of the character and office of his successors, the Prophets, down to John the Baptist.
                            According to orthodoxy, Jesus going to John to be baptized with water (a rite administered by John only to the
                            people of Jerusalem and Judea, when and after they had come to him " confessing their sins " —their Jewish
                            sins—physical sins against their own bodies) was confusion, as " the less is of the better blessed." And, after
                            the water 'baptism, his baptism by the holy Christ Spirit, through John as the medium, is as Greek to Catholic
                            and Protestant divines, as is the fact that Jesus is established as the Head of a new priesthood, '' after the
                            order of Melchizedek," a heathen—and that is nearly all we know of him, except that he " was a priest of the
                            Most High God, a king of Peace and of Righteousness, like unto the Son of God," etc.; and that he blessed
                            Abraham, the ancestor of Jesus, who bowed to him, as did Jesus to John the Baptist; all of which is sufficiently
                            confusing, not to say confounding, to poor orthodoxy, which is in a bad way at this time, having Spiritualism
                            incessantly at work undermining the old orthodox heavens of Christendom, and Shakerism substituting entire new
                            heavens in place of them. Rev. xxi, 1 : " I saw a new heaven and a new earth ; for the first heaven and the
                            first earth had passed away; and there was no more sea"—no more world. " For there was sor- row on the sea, and
                            it cannot rest and be quiet." There was a civil governmental organization which should know no war, poverty or
                            prostitution ; nor the want of any rational supply for the body. " He that sat upon the throne said, ' Behold, I
                            make all things new.' God shall wipe away all tears from all eyes; and there shall be no more death "—the result
                            of sin—" neither sorrow, nor crying; neither any more pain; for the former things have passed away. The
                            tabernacle of God is with men." The kingdom of heaven has come upon earth, securing human beings their
                            inalienable rights to all of the elements of existence—religious communism. The valleys are filled by the
                            leveled mountains : there is neither rich nor poor, for all things are common ; neither bond nor free, for all
                            labor and share alike ; neither Jew nor Greek, for the Gospel is for all people. " There is neither male nor
                            female; " for both of the sexes have risen, in the resurrection, to a life of divine Christian celibacy, finding
                            an Angelic sexual union c in the Lord." The prophecies are realized, and the vision of John is fulfilled, to the
                            honor of God, by its good to humanity.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gods" TEIform="index"/>Gods</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Jews worshiped the God of battles— the Lord of hosts of fighting angels—a great warrior. The Heathen, when
                            converted to Heathen Christianity, made a God of Jesus— declared him to be Jehovah—the God of the Jews—and as
                            such, he could not object to Marriage, Private property, nor War, all of which, as Jehovah, he had blessed, in
                            his chosen people—the Jews. Therefore the Heathen Christian nations practice all of these things unto this
                            day—for all people will be like the God they worship. If Jesus was a celibate, it was because he was God, not
                            man. If he owned no property, it was because he did not need it; and if he did not marry, it was because he
                            could make children out of stones. And the reason he did not fight was, that he himself had created the weapon
                            and him who used it.</p></div2><pb n="39" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hour of worship" TEIform="index"/>THE HOUR OF WORSHIP</head><p TEIform="p">Ad libitum. Arranged for The Shaker by the Society at Canterbury, N. H. 1 Once more the sacred hour has come,
                            When saints together meet, To bow be-fove Jehovah's throne, And worship at His feet. O holy spirits, do in
                            spire Our hearts to sing His praise, And touch our lips with heavenly fire, Our minds from earth to raise. 2 We
                            would forget its scenes and cares, With angels to commune; And offer up our fervent prayers— Thy will, O God, be
                            done. This brings the promised blessing down, And knits our souls in lore; While heart with heart in spirit
                            joined, Still heavenward we move. 3 How strong our bond of union is! 'Tis heaven thus to share; Nothing of earth
                            affords such bliss, Nor can with it compare. May love divine unceasing flow From Christ, the living Head;
                            Through His Anointed here below, To make His people glad.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Song of our little sisters" TEIform="index"/>The Song of our Little Sisters</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">Dear brethren and sisters, though simple our song, At least, like the singers, 'tis not very long. 'Tis one,
                            you'll discover, but only too soon, We sing most delightfully—all bnt the tune. We hope 'twill convince you,
                            before we are through, We're not Katy Bids, but are Katy's that Do. We sweep with such skill—though we don't
                            like to boast— That dirt's nearly frightened away from our coast. We knit and we sew—even milk with good grace.
                            And smile, though 'tis sometimes the wrong side the face. And if, like the clock, we are often too slow, Please
                            think of the time that it talces us to grovh We've oft been so sadly done over with play, That even our shadows
                            near fainted away. Oh, pity us ! pity us ! lend us a tear, To drown ourseives in—when our trials appear. We'd
                            scorn to live merely to eat and to drink; Though merry, we often stop laughing to think. To think, though the
                            heart be all throbbing with pain, 'Twill cease, by and by—and we're smiling again. When the winter winds howl
                            'round our beautiful home, We think of the spring-time and summer to come, When baby birds waiting, like us, to
                            be strong, Will join us in singing our holiday song. We list when you tell of that Beautiful Way, Where children
                            learn something more pleasant than play. We want to walk in it, that we, too, may share The Heaven that comes to
                            the pure-hearted there. Then, though the salt tear may still come to the eye, We'll smile when we think of the
                            Good By and By. Then though, like the-winds, we are often too wild, We know you'll remember you once were a
                            child. The dear little stars peeping down through the sky, Are they little angels, whose home is on high ? They
                            waft us their love for the love they receive, And smile, in return, for each smile that we give. Oh ! oft, in
                            our slumbers, like music, they come, To sing us the songs of their beautiful home ; Pointing still, as they
                            leave, to the sunny land shore, Inviting us there, when our journey is o'er. How pleasant it is, that above or
                            below, We've friends to smile on us wherever we go. We know we've a Mother 'way up in the sky, Who loves little
                            children, and hears when they cry. We feel, in our hearts, that she ever is near, To bless us and shield us when
                            dangers appear; And should we, oh, sometimes be careless or vain, She knows we're but children, and loves us
                            again. As mists of the morn disappear in the day, Thus, too, may our faults with our youth pass away. Our
                            hearts, now so little, with love may expand, 'Till blooming with fruits of the Heavenly land. Oh, bless us, and
                            love us, that we may be strong, In singing not only, but living our song. Now thanks for your kindliness, thanks
                            for your care, And love for remembering how little we are.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God" TEIform="index"/>Life in God</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Redmon, William N." TEIform="persName"/>WM. N. REDMON</byline><p TEIform="p">" Cease to do evil; learn to do well." This sentence comprehends the whole moral duty of man, and is worth a
                            wagon-load of theological metaphysics. All the so-called " divine mysteries " are a thousand times worse than
                            nothing, as they have led myriads of innocent minds into error, thereby causing great distress of soul and
                            fearful forebodings as to the future, tinctured and imbued with sulphuric hell-fire ! The delusion and utter
                            worthlessness of these theological speculations, bring forcibly to our mind Dr. Johnson's Egyptian Philoso-
                            pher, whose fame spread over the land, and to whom was committed the equal distribution of rain ; and whose
                            unfaltering integrity had stood good, in the face of many bribes from millers and other interested parties.
                            Among the throng attracted by the renown of the philosopher, were the Prince and Princess of Abyssinia,
                            sojourners in Egypt; the Prince, who having heard of the fame of the celebrated wise man, sought his presence,
                            that he might be instructed in the wisdom of the age. The interview continuing for days, his sister became
                            solicitous to know with whom he was spending his time, as he must be engaged in matters of importance which
                            could cause him to stay so long from home. The Prince, in order to increase her anxiety and raise her
                            anticipations to the highest pitch, told her of the marvelous wonders revealed by this extraordinarj1personage.
                            The Princess becoming charmed with the excellence of the philosopher, insisted on paying him a visit, with her
                            brother, that she might see, hear and know for herself—as all her sex are determined to do. The Prince being no
                            longer able to restrain or conceal his mirth, said : " Dear sister, I must tell you the facts ; our teacher is
                            one of those philosophers of whom it may be said, ' the more he says, the less you know.' The visit could add
                            nothing to your store of knowledge worthy of your acceptance, or that could raise in your estimation the
                            excellence of the masculine gender." This illustration may not exactly coincide with the views and feelings of
                            those who have spent the best part of their lives in a theological education and the study of Oriental divinity,
                            but it is the best we can do for them at present. The life and simple teachings of the Lord Jesus, are worth
                            more to the unsophisticated minds of the children of earth, by way of instructing and leading them into the
                            Divine Life, than all that has been written or printed since by the outside world. Commentaries on the New
                            Testament have been multiplied, according to the views and conditions of the writers; speculations, without the
                            spirit and power of the Gospel unto salvation. But the writers of polemical divinity have <pb n="40" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER. not been confined to the use of the pen or the tongue; in their heated controversies, the worst
                            passions of the human mind have boiled over; men and nations have come to blows, to arms; and individuals to the
                            stake and torch ! Heresy, in every age of the world has been called to an account, and made to pay the
                            forfeiture of life for its inability to see and believe the " divine mysteries," as held by the standard bearers
                            of mythology. The gods have multiplied in numbers, and increased in severity, ever since " the falling away" of
                            the Apostolic Church. And now, when the Martyr fires have gone out and men have ceased to settle their polemical
                            discrepancies on the field of battle, wisdom would suggest, that the materials of discord should never again be
                            collected; but be permitted to remain, with the history of the past, as a memento of the consummate folly and
                            ignorance of the nations and the age; and with all effete matter be cast off, and in deep humiliation and
                            mortification be left behind. In preceding time, to be the greatest human butcher, has been the most consummate
                            glory of brutal men; gloating on the wide-spread field of mortal carnage, as the tiger over his bleeding victim
                            ! To quarrel and fight is not the vocation of philosophers ; and Christianity teaches men to govern their
                            passions, and bring them into subjection to the law of Love ! To irrational animals let us leave the field of
                            blood and carnage; as, after nations have exhausted themselves on the fields of whole- sale murder, from
                            inability to continue the bloody strife, they cease, then diplomacy has to resume her work, and settle the
                            disputation. But men and nations can never make repa- ration in time, for the ungodly deeds committed on the
                            fields of blood! One wrong can never right another; Justice, in the even-handed balance, alone can weigh out the
                            dues of indi- viduals and nations. Right must ultimately prevail; and Might be instructed, that "he that takes
                            the sword, must perish with the sword ! " Let us suppose, that men in all ages had preferred one another; and in
                            all the departments and vocations of life, given precedence to each other; that all the lives and treasures
                            lavished in wars and destruction had been devoted to the good and upbuilding of nations, peoples and families ;
                            can any one imagine or describe the blessedness of the condition of earth ! Fair and honest dealings between
                            nations and individuals will yet obtain ; and the children of earth, of whatever nation or people, will learn to
                            love and respect each other ; consequently envyings, jealousies and strifes will cease on our globe, " and
                            nations will learn war no more ! " Then will be consummated the advent of the Lord of Glory, and the kingdom
                            resigned to the Father, according to intent; because the evils of earth have been overcome by kindness and Love,
                            which have drawn the children of time to the Father, and they become one with him, according to their measure,
                            in His sublime perfections.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O, speak the loving word" TEIform="index"/>O, Speak the Loving Word</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WHEELER, UNION VILLAGE, OHIO</byline><p TEIform="p">" Love, and love alone is the loan for love!" O, speak the kind and loving word, To every heart, or friend, or
                            foe, Or stranger lone. For human hearts by words are stirred, And leap with joy, or weep with woe, So oft
                            unknown. Yea, speak the kind and loving word, E'en tho' their hearts are happy now, And no dull woe Sits
                            guest-like at their hearth; unheard May come some grief with clouded brow, A nameless foe. O ! let thy words of
                            love be strong, Thy sister needs them, tho' she frowns, Her heart is sore. She may hare wrestled with the wrong,
                            Grown hopeless of the victor's crown, And strives no more. Or if from virtue's path she's strayed, And pleasure
                            won her heart's embrace, O. love her yet. Perchance for kindly words she's prayed, And smiles, instead of
                            frowning face, And love for hate. O, speak in love, and live its praise : The truth may shine with lustre bright
                            Around our way; * And yet a film may cloud our eyes, And shroud us from its glorious light, Obscure its ray.
                            Hearts oft grow cold, and proud and stern, For love to melt their ice away; So firmly set; O ! never teach a
                            heart to spurn, As meaningless, kind words, for aye, So rarely met. Unto the happy, light and gay, Give kindly
                            words, for sorrow needs No herald here; Unto the child in guileless play, To Age, whose step and dim eye pleads
                            Our gentlest care. How sweet the music kind words bring, Into the heart and household dear— No chimes so sweet.
                            No warbler can so softly sing, The choirs of heaven pause to hear The strain complete. Nay, never will the kind
                            word die, Or ever cause a throb of pain, But live alway. "Will glow like planets in our sky, Will plant sweet
                            flowers for our gain, O'er life's rough way.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Generation of vipers" TEIform="index"/>"Generation of Vipers.'</head><p TEIform="p">To the Editor of " The Shaker :"—I observe in the March issue of " The Shaker " an adimadversion upon the use of
                            the above words in the article in the same number upon " Eternal Damnation," in which article Jesus is
                            represented to make use of the unchristian expression in question. As the argument of that article greatly
                            depends upon the fact that Jesus sometimes spoke under the influence of a spirit inferior to that which is now
                            looked upon as so peculiarly his own, even after he had received the first ministration of the Christ Spirit,
                            that article would be grossly presumptuous unless Jesus did use those words. It is not, however, a personal
                            question, but one of historic truth in which are involved some of the gravest spiritual issues. I there fore, in
                            all meekness, beg to place before you the fact that the expression, as used by Jesus, will be found in Matthew
                            xii, 34, in accordance with the reference in the early part of the article. Again, in Matthew xxiii, 33, Jesus
                            said, " Ye serpents, ye generation of vipers, how can ye escape the damnation of hell?" </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas I." TEIform="persName"/>Thomas I. Stroud</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We offer an apology for the space used by 'Shaker Sermons'..." TEIform="index"/>We offer an apology for the space used by 'Shaker Sermons'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">We offer an apology for the space used by " Shaker Sermons ;" but failing to get our supply of The Times, this
                            was our only alternative to meet the demand for them. The Shaker, abjuring creeds, relies upon "the Spirit" to
                            finally lead it into all truth; therefore, each contributor is measurably responsible for his or her
                            utterances—opinions only, being growing truths—knowledge in the process of formation. </p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fifteen years a Shakeress" TEIform="index"/>Fifteen years a Shakeress</head><p TEIform="p"> a series in the Galaxy, we pronounce some truth founded on fiction. </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The American Spiritualist, commenting on the Troy Conference of Spiritualists and Shakers..." TEIform="index"/>The American Spiritualist, commenting on the Troy Conference of Spiritualists and Shakers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The American Spiritualist, commenting on the Troy Conference of Spiritualists and Shakers, thus speaks of Elder
                            John B. Vance : " We regret being unable to give more of his able address. There was no more smooth and eloquent
                            speaker present than Elder Vance.'' Beautifully true. </p></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hawkins, David" TEIform="index"/>David Hawkins
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> On Thursday, April 4, at Watervliet, N. Y., deceased : <persName reg="Hawkins, David" TEIform="persName">David Hawkins</persName>,
                            aged 84. One of the most able, amiable and good men that ever blest the earth. His character was apparently
                            faultless. * </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address of Antoinette Doolittle..." TEIform="index"/>Address of Antoinette Doolittle...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Address of Antoinette Doolittle" at Troy Conference is crowded into June number. It is interesting. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Subscriptions to The Shaker are credentials..." TEIform="index"/>Subscriptions to The Shaker are credentials...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Subscriptions to The Shaker are credentials that pass as Season Tickets to all Shaker meetings this season.
                            Fifty cents per annum. Secure your tickets. </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="F. W. Evans and company have been again invited to Troy, New York" TEIform="index"/>F. W. Evans and company have been again invited to Troy, New York
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> F. W. Evans and company have been again invited to Troy, N. Y. We hear he has also accepted an invitation to
                            extend his lecture to Utica. Utica is 96 miles from Troy ! </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The article on Shaker communism is a review by James Burns..." TEIform="index"/>The article on Shaker communism is a review by James Burns...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The article on Shaker Communism is a Review by James Burns—a self-sacrificing Spiritualist of London—of a
                            valuable treatise on Shaker Spiritualism. His assistance is gratefully acknowledged by the author in a thorough
                            revision of the work. Copies supplied from this office. Price 50c. Postage 6c. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persons desirous of circulating sample copies of The Shaker..." TEIform="index"/>Persons desirous of circulating sample copies of The Shaker...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Persons desirous of circulating sample copies of The Shaker can obtain all they need for such purposes on
                            application to this office. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We feel compelled to warn our readers..." TEIform="index"/>We feel compelled to warn our readers...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> We feel compelled to warn our readers that we have such a pressure of matter as to necessitate an enlargement of
                            The Shaker, or the issuing of the same as a semi-monthly, should all be printed. How will this please ? </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> MEMBERS OF SOCIETY Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of .Editors. Elder F. W. Evans,
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates, Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt. Morris, Livingston Co.,
                            N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stonghton Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert
                            Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shaker3. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village,
                            Middlesex Co., Mass. " B. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co.,
                            N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me.,
                            Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren .Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio,
                            Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades,
                            South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. 40</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>