<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1303" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18830301" TEIform="date">March 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. MARCH. NO. 3. SHAKER MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        HARVARD, MASS. " Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>
</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="49" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                    <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS. Eternal Existence, Christ,..... Consecration, - ¦ .» Aceticism, No 2 - - - . Come up higher, - - -
                            Zeruaii Clark, No 2 Letter from E. Myrick no time to be lost, The World is growing better, A Dialogue, The
                            Principles of Christ, The Shaker Home in Ohio, Letter from Eld. Otis Sawyer, Faithfulness in Duty, Only a Dream,
                            GE. 49 51 n 53 54 55 56 56 8fl :>' 58 ¦'lit 60 61 62 Obedience, Effect of Christ's Wohic, The Valiib of a
                            letter, Unity, - Letter Box, Boys Read and Lisa km, Notes,..... Sanitary, - OK. 62 6364 64 6fi m 66 67 68 69 70
                            70 70 71 72 Life in the Woods, No. 3, Kind Words fob 1882, Gentle Words, 1883, ..... Death*. Music, - - . Books
                            and Papers, Vol. XIII. MARCH, 1883. No. 8. </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eternal existence" TEIform="index"/> ETERNAL EXISTENCE. Mortality and Immortality of
                            the soul.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY.</byline><p TEIform="p"> In the understanding of some persons immortality and eternal existence are synonyms, but,
                            seen in the light of the Gospel of Christ, they widely differ. ''The soul that sinneth, it
                            shall die." Ezek. xviii, 4. "Our Savior Jesus Christ hath abolished death" (soul death) "and
                            brought life and immortality to light through the gospel." II. Tim. i, 10. It is often
                            asserted by many, generally well informed and enlightened pei\sons, that " all human souls
                            are immortal" meaning thereby to express the idea that they are subjects of eternal
                            existence. This, however, is a very different state from immortality. That which is still
                            subject to death, cannot be immortal ! And, while souls are yet in a condition to be tempted
                            to sin, and liable to yield to temptation and sin, they are not yet immortal; for, if they
                            do sin, in as much as they sin, in so much they die. It is important to keep clearly in mind
                            the distinction between a state of life, and one of mere existence. A dead physical body may
                            have an existence, when petrified, as eternal as matter, in its elementary parts ; and, in
                            its form, as eternal as stone, so a dead soul may have the eternal existence of a spirit
                            body, but, for aught we know, for unnumbered cycles of ages bound in death,—
                            torpor—metaphorically speaking, in a petrified condition ! Embalmed with the poisonous
                            antiseptics of earth life in sin, it may remain intact in form, for ages untold, but this
                            approximate infinite existence is not life! It is only life's mockery, soul death ! The
                            constituents of death are insensibility, un- <pb n="50" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 50 THE MANIFESTO.
                            consciousness, inability to act, by Webster defined as ''permanent", but, this is not the
                            only idea of death; a person may be drowned and absolutely dead, but yet life, hi some
                            instances may be restored. But, death, spiritual sou! death, differs from physical death in
                            this, that the dead soul is dead only by insensibility to goodness, heavenly spirit life,
                            and affinity to that sensitiveness of soul that is eternal! The soul may retain its
                            organization or form, also its sensibility and affinity to sinful emotion. Yet, at the same
                            time it is dead to consciousness and desire for or power of action in a good direction, that
                            is, it is alive to sin, but dead to righteousness As a frequent or constant abrasion or
                            excoriation of a nerve will, at length, destroy its ^sensibility, so a frequent cr
                            continuous violation of spiritual rectitude will destroy sensitiveness of conscience, pure
                            heavenly spiritual emotion, sensibility to goodness, love, pure soul affection and living
                            friendship. A truly living soul is sensitive to the faintest blushes of pure and heavenly
                            aff'ectiou and sympathy, its emotions beat responsively to every pulsation of love and
                            heart-felt union to it extended ; its ear is unstopped to every appeal for aid or charity ;
                            its eye is ever open to the just merits or demerits of a fellow being ; its life interests,
                            sympathy, mercy and care is poured out like the pool of Bethesda to heal the wounded soul,
                            its love is not fitful and ' scathing, like fiery ../Etna's breath, but constant, warm,
                            soothing, full of sweetness, gentleness and health, like the breezes of summer's Edenic
                            freshness from the gardens of God! Its charity, boundless as the ocean, never faileth; its
                            peace is like a river never dry, whose fountain springs are ever welling, up in the
                            mountains of holiness. Living souls are ever interested in the work of humau progress and
                            happiness, toiling on, toiling on for a present salvation from sin, and redemption from all
                            the powers of evil, the sources of human misery. To a truly living soul, selfishness,
                            covetousness, hatred, revenge, backbiting, evil-speaking, hardness of heart against a
                            brother, sister or friend, and impurity are sins. But it is the life practice of souls
                            baptized into eternal life, not only to regard the claims of conscience, but to educate and
                            train the conscience ; to guide its courts by the sweet, loving and truthful laws of a
                            heavenly life. Ethical idealism has claimed conscience to be the "voice of God in the soul,"
                            such it would be, had its possessor and his antecedents never violated God's laws ; but, as
                            society is now found, human experience does not prove this to be a universal fact.
                            Conscience has a character much modified and moulded by tuition ; it is often so educated
                            falsely, as not to recognize what is right, nor descry what is wrong; it dictates, but, not
                            always truly. To illustrate, the social custom and tribal in fluences and examples of
                            cannibal races, train the conscience to feel that it is. right, to slay a human being for
                            food, and by their conscience tribunal it is no more judged a crime as murder than the
                            civilized Christian citizen judges it a crime to slay an ox for food. Thus conscience may be
                            as restive and erratic as a balky horse. But, the Christ life example is the pattern set in
                            the mount of God's love by which it should be fashioned. We have witnessed souls so dead
                            that the sweetest strains and anthems of the <pb n="51" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. heavens
                            warbled from the inspired lives of heavenly songsters created in them no wake of emotion, no
                            response of sympathy, neither the jubilant joy of souls saved from sin and basking in the
                            warm sunshine of God's love, nor the tears of the penitent, writhing irjder the lash of
                            condemnation and pleading at the gate of mercy, moved the icy statue of soul death to one
                            seeming wake of sympathy or concern ! Death had sealed his livid lips and locked his stony
                            heart with steeled indifference. But, the soul who has the baptism of immortality, eternal
                            life, is quickened even by the soft strains of angels' Avhispers, it bounds in rapturous joy
                            when the souls of the saved make the welkin ring with praises and thanksgivings ; it lists
                            to the faintest pleadings of mercy from penitent hearts, and joys in the feasts of
                            forgiveness prepared for the returning prodigal foii or daughter. Such living spirits thrill
                            with tha* universal love which Mother Ann Lee, of blessed memory expressed in the following
                            sentiment. "If I owned the whole world I would turn it all into joyfulness by giving bread
                            to the hungry, clothing to the nake;!, and comfort to the afflicted." Such living souls
                            dwell in &amp; city that hath foundations eternal in the Heavens, and cannot be
                            deflected from virtue's pathway ; for virtue is the pabulum of their life ; and their love
                            to humanity is boundless as the ocean and pure as the dew drops from the gardens of
                            Paradise. Blessed Immortality ! Purchased only by redemption's price ! My soul bows humbly
                            at thy deathless heavenly shrine ! Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="sayings" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Active natures are rarely melancholy, activity and melancholy are incompatible" TEIform="index"/>
                            Active natures are rarely melancholy, activity and melancholy are incompatible
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Active natures are rarely melancholy, activity and melancholy are incompatible. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Before Abram was, lam." The Law was before Abram, and the Gospel before Jesus. The law of
                            God in nature was written in the hearts of all human beings, their own thoughts accusing or
                            excusing one another, under the leadership of conscience, the light within that lighteth
                            every man that cometh into the world. The Gospel, good news from a far country the hope of
                            etei'nal life, does also exist, as a receptive germ, in all human souls, to be quickened in
                            due time, by a Christ Spirit from the inner heavens, the Rock of Ages, the source of eternal
                            life and immortality. It being the first materialization from God, who is dual spirit, the
                            Father and Mother fountain of all being and intelligence, a holy parentage. Each descending
                            materialization therefrom is a new world, or sphere of dual existence, more and more
                            external,manifestations of Deity, of the God sphere and all the truth and goodness that it
                            contains, down to the earth and material universe of which our globe is an infinitesimal
                            point or speck. Thus, by the things made visible, the invisible dual Godhead is clearly seen
                            in their creative power and character of father and mother. As the tree is known by its
                            fruit, causes are known by effects. Nature is the revealment of God, as the law, in the
                            outward and natural order, is a revealment of the gospel in the spiritual order. The law was
                            the word of God in the world that could be seen by the external eyes. It was a type and
                            shadow, under the law of correspondence of good <pb n="52" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. things
                            to come, the gospel, which is an emanation from the Christ Heavens, and is the word of God
                            in the world "not seen." The first, temporal and transitory, the second, eternal and
                            permanent. The law was holy, just and good, whose right it is to reign and rule, regulating
                            humanity in food, generation and property. Heaven and earth will pass, but that law of right
                            remains. The law is a schoolmaster to educate and prepare souls for Christ, for the gospel,
                            or resurrection state and order, in which the dual forces of male and female are changed.
                            They cease to marry. They live, on earth, as the Christ angels live in heaven, forming an
                            entirely new sexual relation, one step nearer Deity. This is the order to which Jesus so far
                            attained that he could say, "I am the Resurrection." He was risen with Christ. To know God
                            as a dual being, and Jesus, not after the flesh, but as a resurrected man, is eternal life.
                            The Law shall go foi'th from Zion, and. the word of the Lord from Jerusalem, in Christ's
                            second appearing. In the first appearing the law went forth from Jerusalem, and the word of
                            the Lord Jesus from the Primitive Church. Inasmuch as Jesus and the Apostles in the
                            Pentecostal Convents were all Jews, or became Jews to find a placi. in the Christian Church,
                            who sang the song of Moses and the song of the Lamb, the Law did not need to be preached to
                            them. Christ's second appearing was to a Gentile woman, Ann, and to a Gentile people who
                            knew not the Law, neither the original law of nature, that was holy and good, in food,
                            generation and property, nor the penal law, added because of the transgression of that
                            higher law, but who, in all these things that they should know naturally as [brute beasts,
                            do corrupt themselves, just as did Abram and his people, when he was called, of the Spirit,
                            to get out from his kindred and country, to a land to be shown unto him on Mt. Pisgah. The
                            Law, both original and penal, may be proclaimed. Both laws were to be preached to operate,
                            as schoolmaster? to prepare souls for Christ's second appearing, as really as they were
                            needed to prepare them for the first. And even those who are gathered in need to^be redeemed
                            from their Gentile auti-christian educational tendencies. In our efforts to unravel the
                            mysteries of godliness, in the natural and spiritual order, we must find our starting point
                            and mirid our stops. We need the help of the spirit that searches all things 'wyea, even the
                            deep things of God." We have spoken of the higher and lower laws; the Jews of Jesus' time
                            lived under a yoke that neither they nor their fathers were able to bear, the yoke of the
                            gospel, hence they killed Jesus for imposing it upon them. Also, while they were under the
                            lower or penal law of pains ,.nd penalties for things that itself allowed, being weak
                            through the flesh, there were always prophets, mediums, inspired by Ch:ist angels, who spake
                            as they were moved upon and proclaimed truth pertaining to the future Kingdom of God upon
                            earth. These prophets, or Christ mediums had great power, often dethroning kings and
                            deposing high priests of the lower law, until their work was done, then they were stoned or
                            killed, as their brethren, the children of Abram, saw fit. Mt. Lebanon. N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The flower of sweetest smell is shy and lowly" TEIform="index"/>
                            The flower of sweetest smell is shy and lowly
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The flower of sweetest smell is shy and lowly.</p></div2><pb n="53" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecration" TEIform="index"/>CONSECRATION</head><p TEIform="p">WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. ' CONSECRATION. No longer mine, the gifts I bring and Jay At feet
                            of God, with lowly heart to-day; That they are gifts of mine I would not say. Not mine the
                            will to stny, to come, or go, The will divine is all I seek to know, And God it is, who
                            willing, wills it so. If He should place me keeper of His gate, Outside His kingdom to abide
                            and wait, I would obey, nor doubt, nor hesitate. And if, on lowly errand I were sent, Or
                            bade to work at home, I'd be content, And know at once what the sweet counsel meant. Oh!
                            thus it is, my soul can understand The nature of each message, each command, Whidi cometh
                            with such wisdom from His hand. And thus my hands are filled with labor sweet, So staid from
                            weary wand'rings are my feet, I do not heed the shades which round them meet. Nor mind the
                            clouds that frequent o'er me break; Fear not the storms, feel not the winds which shake; But
                            all these chastenings I as mercies take. Because I live in faith, His will, while mine Is in
                            the keeping of Love's holy shrine, Where Truth will purify it, Grace refine. And so I trust,
                            with sweet confiding love God's will; and safe within His care above, My heart comes home
                            like a returning dovo.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aceticism no.2" TEIform="index"/> ACETICISM. NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Saint Basil, speaks glowingly of the supreme satisfaction derived from the pious exercises
                            of a religious life, where labor occupies the hands, the proceeds of which are used for
                            charitable purposes ; where holy and divine thoughts inspire the mind, and pure Christian
                            love absorbs the interests and affections of the heart. He pronounced him a slave to carnal
                            nature, who loved a brother in blood, more than a brother in the religious community." He
                            says : "Can you imagine felicity more desirable, than that of imitating on earth the life
                            the angels lead in heaven?" Saint Anthony, the Father of Christian Monasticism, not only
                            established houses for meu, whose inclinations and convictions led them to embrace the
                            Christlife ; but, under his direction at a later period, institutions were founded for
                            females who took upon themselves the sacred vow of virginity. Chrysostom speaks thus of
                            them, "¦Transport yourself in imagination into Egypt; there you will see a new paradise,
                            more beautiful than the richest gardens ; innumerable troops of angels in human forms ; an
                            entire nation of martyrs and virgins. Thei'e the weaker sex rival the most fervent
                            solitaries in their virtues. It is a jife worthy of heaven and not inferior to that of
                            angels." Communism, truly Christian, is socialistic ; the fullness of that love which Jesus
                            exhibited in his life and character ; revealed his perfect manhood. He loved Martha and Mary
                            no less than Lazarus and the beloved John ; and no doubt had a glorious ideal of a heavenly
                            brother-hood and sister-hood. But the order of male and female, could not have been
                            consummated under the then existing forms of government, civil and spiritual in the eastern
                            world ; they were exclusively masculine in spirit and sentiment, expi'essing th e attributes
                            and qualities of man, to the entire exclusion of the feminine elements of love, mercy and
                            refinement. The doctrine of the Trinity, was the out-growth of man's one-sided conception of
                            Deity, revealed to his understanding as purely masculine in form arid spirit. It was only
                            when a Heavenly 53 <pb n="54" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. Mother was revealed, in the full
                            beauty and perfection of love, tenderness and benign goodness, through the instrumentality
                            of one of Her inspired daughters, that an angelic state of human society was organized,
                            molded by divine laws, and based on the exalted principles so clearly enunciated by
                            the^lowly Nazarene. The spiritual communistic order, remained to be established in a land
                            where woman was ennobled; where rights of conscience were acknowledged and the inspiration
                            of continual revelation could have free course. This, the highest and most perfect type of
                            human association, requires a greater degree of self-denial, than is needed to sustain
                            celibacy where the sexes are arbitrarily separated. Not that self-abnegation that injures or
                            destroys the body, in order to stifle and subdue inordinate passion ; but, voluutary
                            sacrifice of all that belongs to the lower loves and desires. A self-denial which proves
                            death to the carnal life and quickens the spiritual nature and which elevates souls to a
                            relationship superior to the tics of consanguinify. As we progress in truth, we may glance
                            toward the historic past, and mark the characters that have made their impress for good on
                            humanity ; no less the philosopher, the sage and scientist, than the religious devotee.
                            Wisdom has revealed her choicest treasures through the intellective genius of many minds,
                            who have labored with zeal and devotion in their various spheres xxxr the elevation and
                            improvement of the race. But, "the one thing needful," the power of redemptive principles,
                            has come to human hearts through the world'1: great Saviors; those spiritual lights, that
                            have arisen like stars from the darkness of ignorance and error, and shed a glowing radiance
                            over a sin benighted earth. These grand luminaries, revolving in the great orbit of time;
                            poised in the herculanean strength of self-con~ trol, have expressed the highest ideal of
                            human happiness. Thus out of the depths of mental philosophy, and innumerable forms of
                            religious belief, we gather wisdom, knowledge and truth ; safely garnering the precious
                            sheaves.of wheat, harvests from the world's history ; adding good to good: rejoicing in the
                            ever recurring cycles that bring to humanity, broader and clearer views of eternal
                            fighteofis-&gt; ness and truth. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Come up higher" TEIform="index"/>COME UP HIGHER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> By the dew of life's morning The dawn of thy youth; By brightness now shining Of mercy and
                            truth ; By clear springs of joyIn thy soul which o'erflow ; By prospects immortal Now
                            budding to grow,The love of thy Maker Is calling thoe higher, Up hither, up whither All true
                            souls aspire; Up hither, up whither The wise and pure go, In ways of the just. Heaven's
                            kingd &gt;m to knowBe firm in thy purpose Full duty to do, The path of uprightness
                            Intently pursue; . Though rugged and thorny It seems to thy sight, It opens on beauties
                            Internally bright. It is trouden by martyrs Who crucify self, Rejecting the world with its
                                <pb n="55" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>54 THE MANIFESTO. 55 Honor and wealthy Its ease and its pleasures,
                            Because they are dross, Enchaining not those who are Bearing the cross, Determined to break
                            All the fetters of earth; But flee as a shadow Before solid worth. O come ye up whither ?
                            The holy ones are, Who've conquered their spiritual foes, Those who wear The crown of the
                            victor; thiy've passed 'Yond the pain,— The test of the furnace, Triumphant to reign. They
                            beckon'you onward. They minister cheer; Be constant in purpose, In hope persevere. With love
                            that surpasseth They echo the call, Up hither, up whither God's love crowneth all. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zeruah Clark no. 2" TEIform="index"/> ZERUAH CLARK. NO. 2.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jesus Christ said, "If ye believe not that I am he, ye shall die in your sins." Jno. viii,
                            24. The wicked not only refused to beJieve him, but rejected him, and spoke evil of him.
                            They called him "A gluttonous man, and a wine-bibber, a friend of publicans and sinners;"
                            and through malice, and by the influence of false witnesses, they put him to an ignominous
                            death. "If they have called the master of the house Beelzebub, how much more them of his
                            household?" Matt, x, 25. What charges of wickedness,—what names and titles of disgrace have
                            they not palmed upon Mother Ann! Through ignorance of the real cause, some may think strange
                            that so many evil reports should be circulated concerning her, if she was a truly pious
                            woman. But I consider these evil reports the best evidence to those who never saw her, that
                            she did belong to the house-hold of Christ. Had she been of the world, and lived as her
                            accusers stated, the wicked never would have trembled her. nor themselves on her
                            account—thej never would have slandered her, nor pabliohed a single line against ber. But
                            she was not of the world; for God had chosen her out of the world, and because she bore
                            testimony against their evil works, they hated her while living, they calumniated her after
                            her decease, and they hate her testimony and despise her followers to the present day.
                            According to the testimony of Je?us Christ; "I have chosen you out of the world, therefore
                            the world hateth you." I know that Mother Ann was a woman chosen of God, and endowed with
                            the spirit of Christ, beyond any woman I ever saw. From my first acquaintance with her, I
                            have had reason to esteem her as the first of spiritual women in this day: and any person
                            may as well attempt to blow out the light of the sun as to try to destroy my confidence in
                            Mother Ann, or to overthrow the work of God which through her has been established in this
                            land. I received many powerful evidences of her divine mission while she resided with us,
                            and even since her decease, and I can never entertain a moment's doubt concerning her godly
                            character. She has planted that living gospel faith, and established that work of true
                            Christian righteousness among men, that all the powers of earth can never destroy. Nearly
                            forty six years have passed since I received the testimony of the gospel through the
                            ministration of Mother Ann, and I can say Avith confidence that I have been faithful
                            according to my understanding and abilities. The greatest bondage is the bondage of sin,
                            under which all the wicked are bound; and none more strongly than those who bring false
                            charges against the society of Believers. Before I accepted this gospel of Christ, I was in
                            bondage to a sinful nature, but 1 found deliverance from it by confession and repentance of
                            sin. I now consider myself a free woman in Christ. If there is delusion. I know of none
                            greater than sin and wickedness ; nor do I know of any people more deluded than those who
                            live in sin, and yet flatter themselves that they are regenerated and born of God;
                            forgetting the testimony <pb n="56" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. of the apostle John, the
                            beloved disciple of Christ.:-"¦"W-hosoevev is born of God, doth not commit sin;—and, "He
                            that committeth sin is of the devil." The knowledge of salvation ds,' I consider, superior
                            ;to all other knowledge. This will increase forever, while all earthly knowledge must
                            eventually fail.-,' ¦;,-¦¦ v This testimony I give in favor of that gospel which I received
                            from Mother Ann, and which I know is the gospel of Christ; a gospel by which I have lived
                            and for which I am willing to die. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ed. of Manifesto:—'A Christmas Offering' has been..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Ed. of Manifesto:—'A Christmas Offering' has been...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, January 1883" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass. Jan. 1888.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Ed. of Manifesto:—"A Christmas Offering" has been read and re-read with pleasure and profit.
                            It is instructive and encouraging, and is one of the best productions that has ever graced
                            the columns of "The Manifesto." It is free from theory and theology, a historical sermon,
                            instructive alike to old and young. Indeed, it is the fruit of a well ordered life of
                            unfeigned' religion, wrought out in works, resulting in happy reflections and cheering
                            prospects. How beautiful is the thought, "My reward is with me; I have not all my life, been
                            building air castles, neither have I built upon the sand. Nay, I have secured my treasure in
                            heaven, and the garments wrought here in earth life, will be mine to wear in the land of
                            souls." What a passport is such a consciousness of right doing! "My reward is with me." No
                            waiting, no uncertain trusting. Leaving "this beautiful world, another sphere is mine to
                            inhabit." This is true philosophy. "Heaven here and now." I wish that we had a modern Bible,
                            made .of such chapters. Would it not be an improvement on all others? Please accept gospeL
                            blessing and many thanks.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/> Elijah Myrick.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No time to be lost" TEIform="index"/> NO TIME TO BE LOST!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cochran, Dorothea T." TEIform="persName"/> DOROTHEA T. COHRAN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Haye.yo.u a duty to do? Then begin it at once.rand do not sit dreamily dreading the cross.
                            You never can accomplish any undertaking without resolute and persistent efforts. The longer
                            you procrastinate, the stronger the adversary will seek to bind your conscience. In this way
                            souls often become captivated and are enticed from virtue, until they are ruined. There is
                            danger in delay. The enemy takes advantage of those who say within their mind: "Tomorrow
                            will do as well. There is time enough yet." For when tomorrow comes, courage has fled, the
                            duty which seemed but a mote, now appears like a mountain. Then comes a thousand bitter
                            regrets. Instead of being able to erjoy the blessings which are ever springing up in our
                            pathway, like beautiful flowers, testimonials of God's goodnes8, we walk constantly among
                            thorns and briers, the fruits of our own idleness and folly. "Never put off till the morrow,
                            what should be done today." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="1883" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1883" TEIform="index"/> 1883.</head><p TEIform="p"> The world is growing better Every year; It throws off many a fetter Every year; There are
                            many things to relish, Though the ancient things must perish, But the beautiful we cherish
                            Every year. Many changes have come o'er us Every year; Many friends have gone before us
                            Every year; Through many a strange mutation We have reached a higher station Every year. We
                            have had our slight vexations Every year; • And pleasing jubilations ' Every year; There are
                            visions to remember Of flowers in September, u <pb n="57" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 57 And
                            Christmas in December, Every year. The sun shines now as brightly Every year; And the
                            snowflakes fall as lightly Every year, As in days when we were younger, And the years
                            appeared much longer To our hearts, which then felt stronger, Every year. Afflictions have
                            not shrouded Every year: And troubles have not clouded Every year; But hope the whole
                            discounted, While the former were recounted, And the latter all surmounted Every year. The
                            end of life comes nearer Every year; The friends left become dearer Every year; And tlv3
                            "goal of all that's mortal" Opens wider still its portal To the land of the immortal Every
                            year. And thinner grows the curtain Every year: That divides us from the certain, Every year
                            : We look forward to the morrow Which shall close all earthly sorrow With the calmness Hope
                            can borrow.Every year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, William" TEIform="persName"/> William Reed, in Taunton(Mass.) Gazette.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/> A DIALOGUE.</head><p TEIform="p"> A. I wish you a Happy New Year, dear sister ; and may it be so in reality to all of us; and
                            why not, if truth and purity are the aim of each one? You know many hands make light and
                            pleasant our temporal work; why not as well, in our spiritual work, or religion. B. Many
                            thanks for your kindness ; I heartily wish you and all my friends the same blessing, but why
                            do you use the term, religion? Can we not have the general compliments of the season without
                            having religion mixed up with them? A. Wait my friend, do not be in so great a haste to
                            denounce the right of the term, for really I cannot see how kindly feelings and religion can
                            be very well considered apart from each other. B. I do not know as I hare any objection if
                            you must have it, as it gives us a chance for a discussion on the subject of religion, and
                            the effect it has on different minds. Please inform me of your definition of religion? A. I
                            am quite ready to give it. Worcester tells us it is duty to God and man; and this agrees
                            exactly with my idea. B. But people differ very much in their ideas of duty to God. Some
                            think it their religious duty to torture themselves physically; others to deny themselves of
                            everything that could possibly afford them any pleasure. A All this being granted, still
                            what might seem right to one person might not be to another. B: Well, my religion does not
                            prevent me from admiring the beautiful both in nature and art; nor would I object to some
                            innocent amusements. A. I must admit that everything beautiful justly claims our admiration,
                            but would not some of those innocent amusements of which you speak, be more rightly termed
                            unprofitable indulgences? B. Unprofitable indulgences! Then you think that those who profess
                            religion should have no amusements at all. If that coat fits any one, let him put it on, for
                            I am sure it would pinch me unpleasantly. My religion is not a set of rules, nor a whip to
                            duty, which are all the time saying, "You shall, and you shall not; you may come here, but
                            you must not go there." Religion, should no more fetter a person, than wings do a bird, but
                            should stimulate to high and holy actions. A. Do you say that your religion contains no laws
                            which you feel obligated to obey? B. Creed, not religion binds; I have no faith in creeds.
                            A. I have; my creed is, I believe in the Love of God, submitting myself to be governed by
                            his laws. B. I do all that without any creed. A. You seem willing to accept the work, and
                            still unwilling to have it called by the right name. B. Well, I do object to it. I think
                            creeds have done more mischief in the world, than <pb n="58" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE MANIFESTO.
                            religion -with all its divine influence car. undo, for a long time to come A. That seems
                            pretty strong. Faith, without works, is dead, so there may be no creed which alone can save
                            the soul, but if my creed harmonizes with the laws of justice, and are written in my heart,
                            then my creed has served me well. B. You seem to think a creed essential to religion. A.
                            Nay, I am sure I do not. B. Then I can sec nothing in your last remark but the effects of
                            true Christian religion, leaving the creed entirely out. A. Well, bidding adieu to the
                            creed, I will ask you if j'ou have not in the course of your life found those who
                            exemplified the effects of religion that they have won your respect and admiration? B.
                            Certainly, but can I not admire the principle without a reverence for the person? A. Why do
                            you make that objection? If a person embodies that which is noble and of superior quality,
                            is he not worthy of a reverential regard? B. Well, I declare! I thought God only was Avorthy
                            of our reverence. Look here, my friend, we have got into something of an argument on the
                            subject of religion, and I want more help. Sister Conservative, can you not come to my
                            assistance? C. I have been listening very attentively to your argument and my ideas fully
                            coincide with my sister's upon the subject of reverence. All that is good and Christ-like
                            a&gt; tracts toward itself, and Ibis stimulates! our reverence for the act and then for
                            the person. B. It may be as you say. Some people have a greater reverence for persons and
                            places than I do; perhaps I need more of that quality of mind. C I readily admit that I am
                            deeply interested in the subject Why, I have a reverence for sacred places which is no doubt
                            owing to the divine influence that I have experienced from time to time; and it is easier to
                            fraternize with the angels of God while in the apartments kept sacred for devotion, than in
                            an abode of common labor. A. I have no peculiar reverence for a room which is kept
                            especially for religious services, but at the same lime must admit that I have a respect for
                            the conscientious scruples of every person. B. I also have respect for the conscientious
                            scruples of every one but I luire none for these false notions of religion. C. What do you
                            call false notions of religion? B. Clinging to old forms and ceremonies; urging that
                            religion consists in a particular, order of worship, or in the style or color of apparel, or
                            even in the form of speech. 0. All manifestations of religion might be termed mere ceremony.
                            It s?cms to me to be very essential that professing Christians should dress plainly and with
                            economy. B. I did not better myself very much by applying to that conservative, did I? A.
                            Every one seems to have some idea.of a religion which demands our respect even though we do
                            not accept the faith. C. Time changes and people change; here is a document written only a
                            few years ago. Reads. A Recipe." Take a soul full of conviction for sin, and add to this,
                            honesty of } urposc. Pass through the order of confession and fill the spirit with love and
                            a desire for good. By this time you will have taken sufficient humility to keep you by the
                            cross. Now, you may need some simplicity and obedience which will aid you to put your good
                            resolutions into practice. All your Avords and actions should be governed by principle and
                            that alone. A willing consecration of time and talents together with, a faithful fulfilling
                            of the Golden Rule will not fail to make you a Christian. Now what can you say?Shirley,
                            Mass. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principles of Christ" TEIform="index"/> THE PRINCIPLES OF CHRIST.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/> RUTH WEBSTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> If we wish to obtain a valuable article wa expect to pay a price corresponding to its value.
                            Salvation from sin is called a great salvation. If we obtain it we must comply with the
                            conditions which will fit us for the Kingdom of Heaven on earth and for Eternal Life in the
                            world to come. When Christ dwelt on eartli in material form his constant theme was "the
                            Kingdom <pb n="59" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 59 of Heaven is at hand." In his similitudes
                            and parables he likened it to many things some of them I will mention. A man found a
                            treasure in a field and selleth all that he hath and buyeth the field. A merchant seeking
                            goodly pearls, when he found one of great price sold all that he had and bought it. How are
                            these likened to the Kingdom only as it takes all that we have to gain and enjoy it. Many
                            try to enter the Kingdom without counting the cost; soon they get into trouble. This is
                            wrong and that is not right; they are making provision for the flesh and they find that
                            flesh and spirit will not mingle any more than we can serve God and mammon. He that
                            receiveth not the Kingdom as a little child cannot enter therein. We must be teachable and
                            confiding; such arc -willing to be taught gospel principles and are easily governed by the
                            same. Christ said, "Except yc forsake all ye cannot be my disciples" and lest any one should
                            mistake his meaning he specified the things to be forsaken. Private property, natural and
                            partial relation, and our own life also. It has been said by some that the condition of
                            discipleship cannot be carried out without one makes a pauper of himself. So far from this
                            being the case, tho-sc who carry out the teaching of Christ the most perfectly, arc the
                            farthest removed from pauperism, for they have a united consecrated interest; they have no
                            rich nor poor, all fare and share alike, while all labor for the universal good. It is
                            evident that Christ had the idea of a community life in view in his teaching at different
                            times. For instance, in his parable of the man who made a great supper and bade many; at
                            supper time he sent his servants, saying, "Come for all things are ready, and thejr began to
                            make excuses." They had involved themselves with private property and they must attend to
                            their own private interest. Another had married a wife therefore ho could not come. Thus
                            showing that neither private property nor marriage were admissible in the kingdom on earth,
                            for this seems to be the"subject under discussion, any more than in the kingdom above, where
                            it is said "They neither marry nor are given in marriage." In the kingdom of Christ all
                            things are to become new, uo one seeking his own, but another's welfare. The forsaking of
                            partial and natural relation is not to leave them to suffer, for there is ample provision in
                            the fold for every child, yea, all who will submit to the discipline and claim its
                            protection. Where justice and equality are foundation principles and of which we must in no
                            wise lose sight. If we would live out the principles of Christ wo will live in community,
                            and we cannot carry out a community life, successfully, without giving up our partial ties,
                            and living an unselfish life. Union Village, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Home in Ohio" TEIform="index"/> THE SHAKER HOME IN OHIO.</head><p TEIform="p"> From Chicago Weekly News. Topography of the Society Home— JLeng'th of Time tlie Society lias
                            Existed, Origin of Their Appellation— Shaker, a Term of 49pprol»riutn —
                            Xoii-ltegistaiit*itlorte of Worship—Shake figuratively— Are Celibates—I»o Hot 'Exclude
                            Animal IMet. Lotus, Ind., Nov. 10.—Forty years ago I visited Union Village, the home of
                            believers, commonly called Shakers, situated in Warren county, 0., and within four miles of
                            Lebanon. The impression made upon me by that visit never having been erased, I concluded to
                            visit the society again, and, on the 1st of November, did so. Shaker, formerly Union
                            Village, is located thirty miles north of Cincinnati, between the Miamis, six miles
                            southeast from Franklin, on the Cincinnati, Hamilton and Dayton railroad, four and one-half
                            miles north from Monroe, on the Cincinnati and Dayton Short Line rail way, and four miles
                            west of Lebanon, on the Cincinnati and Northern railroad. The society owns a large tract of
                            highly-improved and profitably cultivated land. They have existed as a Christian
                            organization about a hundred years and assumed the a »pellation of believers in
                            contradistinction to the numerous sects who profess to adopt t'.ie doctrines and teachings
                            of Jesus and show by their practice that they do not believe their;. The term "Shaker" was
                            applied to them by way of opprobrium, which they neither adopt nor reject; but in that as
                                in<pb n="60" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 60 THE MANIFESTO. everything else they are non-resistant. The
                            appellation I regard as unjust and untrue anc no more applicable to them as regards their
                            religious exercises than Fallers would be to the sects who were strangely affected in that
                            way in the early part of the present century. Their mode of worship is as orderly; gentle,
                            pure and soul-inspiring as I ever witnessed elsewhere by any sect of Christians. They only
                            shake figuratively, as it were, to remove from their garments the dust of impure,
                            hypocritical and false religion. They are celibates; neither marry nor are given in
                            marriage. They are Christians, not Jews They adhere to the gospel, not the Mosaic
                            dispensation; to the new, which superseded the old or Jewish dispensation, which was
                            generative-—to multiply, to propagate, to procreate ; to the gospel dispensation, which is
                            to follow the teachings and example of Jesus which is to people heaven, not earth. But the
                            generative element claims that abstention from propagation would depopulate the earth. This
                            is no more to be apprehended than that the advocacy of a republican form of government would
                            cause that form of government to supersede all others upon the earth. The Mosaic
                            dispensation, orLevitical laws, are no more binding upon the followers of the gospel
                            dispensation than are the teachings of the 31st chapter of Numbers. But why talk of the
                            binding character of laws after their repeal? Moreover, in no division of animated nature
                            are required for propagation or breeding; but what is of greater moment is to produce
                            improved stock or progeny, of which believers raise and educate a greater number in
                            proportion to their numbers, perhaps, than any other people. It is untrue, as represented by
                            some, that the society excludes from their cuisine animal food. Pork is not in general use
                            with them, but they set an excellent table and are good livers. The only linguistic
                            peculiarity observable among Believers is the use of yea and nay for yes and no, which I
                            regarded as euphonious. In apparel there is nothing which can be regarded as peculiar to
                            them or unique or antiquated. They dress with good taste and elegance. Their buildings of
                            recent date are constructed in accordance with correct principles of architecture. Of the
                            history, character, manners, and mission of Ann Lee, the founder of the society of
                            believers, I know but comparatively little, not having access to her biography or life; but
                            she has been deceased perhaps a hundred years, and I shall, in reference to her, adhere to
                            the adage; "Dice de moriuis nil nisi bonum." I do know that she was a pure and persecuted
                            Christian, too pure to be popular with depraved and unregenerated human nature, as was her
                            great prototype, the author of the gospel dispensation. There are those who assert that the
                            society of Believers worship her. They do not. They claim to believe, however, that in her
                            person was the second appearance of Jesus Christ, and that she taught them how to live and
                            die as pure Christians in accordance with the principles and teachings of Jesus and his
                            disciples while sojourning upon the earth, and by their pure life are ever proclaiming—
                            "Since truth and constancy are rain, Since neither love nor sense of pain, Nor force of
                            reason can persuade, Then let example be obeyed." If the society of Believers, commonly
                            called Shakers, are not honest, pure, and upright Christians, striving literally to live the
                            life of such, then I think there are none.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cogley, R." TEIform="persName"/>R. Cogley, M. D.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor, Manifesto —The swiftly rolling seasons..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear Editor, Manifesto —The swiftly rolling seasons...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, West Gloucester, January 1883" TEIform="index"/> West Gloucester, Me. Jan. 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Editor, Manifesto ;—The swiftly rolling seasons brought around the interesting days of
                            Christmas and New Year, while yet we were holding in fragrant memory, the pleasures and
                            profits of the past season. Christmas found us universally engaged in righting all wrongs,
                            forgiving one another's trespasses as we ourselves would be forgiven by our Heavenly Father
                            and Mother, cleansing "the temple of God" to make it a more fit receptacle for the
                            indwelling of the Holy Spirit. The Christmas festivities were reserved to be combined with
                            those of New Years, which was an occasion of great enjoyment for "Mother's Children" of <pb n="61" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 61 all ages from 8 years on to 90. At seven o'clock in
                            the evening the doors were opened into the Meeting room of the Old Mansion, when ab illiant
                            beautiful sight greeted all eyes, the wide spreading evergreen tree displayed more than,
                            "twelve manner of fruit," the product of busy hands to meet the wants of the needy.
                            Beautiful songs composed for the occasion were sung, and original and select pieces were
                            read ; of which the following. "Gentle words" was one. The little folks were well trained by
                            their efficient teachers, who rehearsed a very entertaining Dialogue. A kind and commendable
                            feeling prevailed in advance of the festivities to render the meeting pleasant, and
                            increased brotherly and sisterly love. Almost every person contributed some needed article,
                            and the good Deaconesses displayed justice in their allotment to each one according to their
                            needs, combining all with contributions from choice friends abroad. Here wss forcibly
                            demonstrated how successfully we could add to the happiness of each other when an effort is
                            made for that purpose, and if accomplished for one day, why not for seven, and if for seven,
                            why not for a whole year and on,—then with our work before us, the reward would be ever
                            present, and would not this be heavenly ? At the close of the two brief, pleasant hours, we
                            were reminded of the s-ad calamity at Mount Lebanon and of the hearts of dear, gospel
                            friends there, bowed in grief and sorrow, and as we knelt in prayer that the Lord would send
                            angels to comfort them, we sang in subdued tone the sweet, sympathetic prayer Remember,
                            Lord, thy chosen people Who have kept thy holy way, O, do protect and strengthen them On
                            their journey, night and day. When they're brought in tribulation,— When they feel thy
                            scourging rod,— 0, then appear for their Salvation, O help them keep thy way, 0 God. Letters
                            were read from gospel friends at Enfield, Conn, containing rich expressions of fraternal
                            love, when at the same hour the society there were holding dedicatory services in their new
                            and elegant Infirmary. Songs were selected to be sung by each Society at the same time in
                            reciprocal friendship. The following of Elder Omar Pease was one. Away with all doubting and
                            fear, Away with all doubting and fear, While morning around us is breaking, And angels are
                            hovering near. If others have stood through afflictions, With firmness to day we will stand;
                            And gladly we'll banish all weakness United in one happy band.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/> From Your Brother, Otis Sawyer.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faithless in duty" TEIform="index"/> FAITHFULNESS IN DUTY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crooker, Jane" TEIform="persName"/> JANE CROOKER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our success or failure in life depends upon our fidelity to the trust reposed in us. No
                            matter how important, or how trivial, whether agreeable or unpleasant; we cannot neglect our
                            life-duties, or carelessly ignore them, without paying the penalty, and forfeiting our right
                            to the respect and confidence of those whose good opinion and love is- more precious than
                            any selfish consideration. No amount of regret or repentance, can atone for repeated
                            omissions of known duty. It may be our privilege, and the greatest amendment we can make, to
                            confess and re pent of willful or careless neglect: but in justice it leaves its impress
                            upon our character, even if our friends in their kindness try to cover our failure with the
                            mantle of charity. The stern fact is before us ; turn where we may, we see the words,
                            traitor and selfishness attached with double meaning to our works. And we cannot efface
                            these odious words, unless we make earnest and persistent efforts to fulfill all engagements
                            and bind ourselves to duty by self-denial and a firm de- <pb n="62" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> G2 THE
                            MANIFESTO. termination to conquer the habits of indolence and procrastination. To Avork with
                            the hands is not sufficient. The mind should be employed on useful and ennobling- themes ;
                            for there are many kinds of labor that cost but little brain effort; the faculties of the
                            mind become depraved, and lose their healthy vigorous tone, if not used and improved. Then—
                            "Work and think, the world's great motto E'en your anvils ring it forth; Mine, and mint, and
                            granite quarry, Wake the echo round the earth." Self culture^ then, is duty, an important
                            and imperative one, if we would fit ourselves to associate with the intelligent pure
                            Christian workers. Our manners, as well as thoughts, should be cultivated, and no one is
                            justified to remain an unpleasant companion to friends, superiors or inferiors, because of
                            disagreeable manners and habits. If we know what seems unpleasant and unlovely to us in
                            others, let us be careful that we do not practice the same errors in speech or action. But
                            our greatest and highest trust lies in fidelity to our religious faith and spiritual growth.
                            "When life commences, Eternity begins." How important that we remember and regard the
                            warning that those few words convey. No person can be truly happy who is not religious.
                            Thorn are earthly pleasures and treasures that may for a time satisfy. But to a soul who has
                            once been convicted for sin and has heard the call, "Come ye out from among them, touch not,
                            taste not, handle not the unclean thing," there is no justification in aught but sacrifising
                            the worldly, selfish propensities and coming fully to the truth. Let us perform our
                            Christian duties with cheerfulness, no matter what the internal conflict. "For he that
                            ruleth his spirit is greater than he that taketh a city." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Only a dream" TEIform="index"/> ONLY A DREAM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH A. COLLINS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> We read that old men shall dream dreams and young men shall see visions, but we do not read
                            any thing about the dreams of little girls. I am about to tell a dream I had when I was
                            about ten years of age. Formerly, there used to be a great deal said of a certain bad
                            place,—What shall I call it—Hades ! Generally I went to bed quite early. This time I retired
                            feeling rather uneasy, but soon fell asleep, and found myself in that place that is thought
                            to be uncomfortably warm. Tt appeared to me like a very large basement room, and in the
                            center of this fearful place I saw a large furnace; the mouth was kept wide open ready for
                            the cremating of wicked people. It was larger than any furnace I had ever seen. What an
                            impression it made on my mind! Not very far from this furnace sat the engineer. I pitied
                            him, but perhaps he did not realize the heat as much as I did. Not far distant I saw a
                            friend and making my way thither I soon fell into conversation. On asking my friend who that
                            man was, that was tending that large furnace, he said, he is a relative of the wicked one.
                            All! indeed, so then he has relatives to attend to his business. He must be greatly
                            patronized. I told my friend that I had heard a great deal about such a place but I never
                            once expected to go there thus early, if ever. I said, I am afraid to move for fear the man
                            will come after me ! "O nay," my friend said, "never. They never go after any one. If you
                            get burned it is because you go too near them and are caught in the trap. To sum it all up,
                            if you keep away from them, they will keep away from you." Very well, then, I think I can
                            easily do that if I can only get a little farther off now, I think I can keep off. Presently
                            I awoke finding myself safe, but very much frightened and soon began to rejoice, knowing my
                            experience was only a dream. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience" TEIform="index"/> OBEDIENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hillsgrove, Elmira" TEIform="persName"/> ELMIRA HILLSGROVE.</byline><p TEIform="p"> In the principle of Obedience to higher laws, is the power of present salvation, and final
                            redemption from error. We are not by nature what we would desire to be, when influenced by
                            an intelligent <pb n="63" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. G3 mind, and a love for the beautiful
                            and good. How often we sigh, and regret the depravity of an unregenerated heart, imploring
                            spiritual aid in prayer, crying with all sincerity of desire : O Father, Mother, our God in
                            heaven. I have known thy divine will, yet have sought my own pleasures, walked where I knew
                            lay temptation ; name any measure that is mete suffering for atonement, I will bear it
                            cheerfully. H &gt;w clearly the spirit voice answers our petition ; "Obedience is better
                            than sacrifice." Be not deceived, repentance does not consist wholly of tears, heart-rending
                            agonies, or regrets ; you have sinned ; humbly confess the same ; you have disobeyed known
                            laws of right; by obeying, you are repenting; continued obedience to principles of
                            godliness, will bring you nearer and nearer the standard of uprightness, farther and farther
                            removed from the snare out of which you were taken; while each repetition of error delays
                            the glorious day of victory which may crown you with Redemption. Obedience to correct
                            principles is the grand lever raising us. to success in the gospel work ; it is an
                            all-important power of resurrection from the infirmities of the flesh. A soul may be
                            convicted of sin, and be brought to confession, yet without the full repentance unto
                            obedience to the spirit which condemns, we are merely mortifying the deeds of the body, not
                            crucifying the nature of "sin, not striking the ax, at the root of the evil tree, and we
                            fall into sin again and again, each time with greater loss of strength and confidence in
                            ourselves. Obedience strikes at the cause of siu, the latent opposing elements ; confession
                            is the first important step after disobedience has led the soul astray; yet alone,
                            confession is but merely trimming, pruning, so that the twigs, leaves and branches, (our
                            thoughts, words, and actions,) draw with greater effect upon the root. Obedience, with
                            earnest prayer, embraces our whole duty ; it embodies the Christian warfare, is +.hc
                            effectual sword of the spirit, the self-denial, the, cross, our defence and our standard of
                            loyalty ; by its effect we conquer the most subtle fos, put to shame and crucify the nature
                            of sin, and thus hasten the glorious day of complete redemption. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Effects of Christ's work" TEIform="index"/> EFFECTS OF CHRIST'S WORK.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The effects of the work of Christ are even to the unbeliever indisputable and
                                    historical. It expelled cruelty; it disbanded passion ; it branded suicide; it
                                    punished and repressed an execrable infanticide; it drove the shameless impurities
                                    of heathendom into a congenial darkness : There was hardly a class whose wrongs it
                                    did not remedy. It rescued the gladiator; it freed the slave; it protected the
                                    captive ; it nursed the sick ; it sheltered the orphan; it elevated woman ; it
                                    shrouded, as with a halo of sacred innocence, the tender years of the child. In
                                    every region of life its ameliorating influence was felt. It changed pity from vice,
                                    into a virtue. It elevated poverty from a curse into a beatitude. It ennobled labor
                                    from a vulgarity, into a duty. It revealed, for the first time, the angelic beauty
                                    and purity of which men had despaired, and of meekness which they utterly scoffed.
                                    It created the veiy conception of charity, and broadened the limits of its
                                    obliga'ion from the narrow circle of a neighborhood to the widest horizon of the
                                    race. And while it thus involved the idea of humanity as a common brother-hood, even
                                    where its tidings were not believed, all over the world, wherever its tidings were
                                    believed, it cleansed the life and elevated the soul of each individual man. And in
                                    all lands, where it has moulded the characters of its true believers, <pb n="64" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. it has created hearts so pure, and lives so peaceful,
                                    and homes so sweet, that it migh seem as though those angels who had herald ed its
                                    advent, had also whispered to every despairing and depressed sufferer among the sons
                                    of men; "though you have lain among the pots, yet shall ye be as wings of a dove
                                    that is covered with silver wings, and her feathers like gold."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dr. Farrar's Life of Christ" TEIform="index"/> Dr. Farrar's Life of Christ.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value of a little" TEIform="index"/> THE VALUE OF A LITTLE.</head><p TEIform="p"> Do thy little, do it well; Do what right and reason tell; Do what wrong and sorrow claim;
                            Conquer sin and cover shame. Do thy little, though it be Dreariness and drudgery; They whom
                            Christ apostles made, "Gathered fragments" when he bade. Do thy little ; never mind Though
                            thy brethren be unkind; Though the men who ought to smile, Mock and taunt thee for awhile.
                            Do thy little ; never fear While thy Savior standeth near; Let the world its javelins throw,
                            On thy way undaunted go. Do thy little; God hath made Million leaves for forest shade;
                            Smallest stars their glory bring, God employeth everything. Do thy little, and when thou
                            Feelest on thy pallid brow, Ere has fled the vital breath, Cold and damp the dew of death.
                            Then the little thou hast done, Little battles thou hast won, Little masteries achieved,
                            Little wants with care relieved, Little words in love expressed, Little wrongs at once
                            confessed, Little favors kindly done, Little toils thou didst not shun, Little graces meekly
                            worn, Little sights with patience borne. These shall crown the pillowed head, Holy light
                            upon thee shed; These are treasures that shall rise Far beyond the smiling skies. 8elected,
                            UNITY. Let strife forever cease, And envy quit the field; Come join and live in love and
                            peace, And to the gospel yield. Let bitter words no more Among the Saints remain ; Let every
                            member every hour Submit to Jesus reign. One Lord we have to fear, One Faith we all confess
                            ; To the same baptism we adhere, And magnify free grace. Then why should we contend, For
                            meat, and drink, and dress, And crucify the Lord again And pierce his wounds afresh. When
                            bitter words arise, Then Satan has his ends ; We wound the heart and hands of Christ, Amidst
                            his chosen friends. No more then feed the flame Nor judge ourselves too wise; But search
                            with care to find the beam That lurks within our eyes. Unto the world we'll prove That we
                            disciples are ; They shall behold us walk in love, And'say the Lord is there. Then we will
                            live like those Who now agree in lov,e; And when our eyes in death shall close; We'll join
                            with them above. Selected. Vanity makes men ridiculous, pride odious, and ambition terrible.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Steele" TEIform="persName"/>Steele.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Needs, and reformatory..." TEIform="index"/>The needs, and reformatory...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "The needs, and reformatory spirit of our age abhor the useless works of vanity and of self
                            interest. Many enthusiasts, by their fanciful ideas and fine spun spe^ilations, have formed
                            to themselves a heaven and a kingdom of God which nowhere exists. Mistaken men, you try to
                            arrange affairs with God, before you are reconciled to your fellow creatures, by whom you
                            are surrounded."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rapp, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Rapp.</byline></div2><pb n="65" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corresponce" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Manifesto ;—I am pleased to hear from..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Manifesto ;—I am pleased to hear from...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Shaker Station, January 8, 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Jan. 8, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Manifesto ;—I am pleased to hear from so many of my Young Sisters through your
                                columns, and thought I would try to write. I am fourteen years of age, and have lived
                                with Believers four years; I love all my dear gospel relation, and I often wish that
                                many more children that are without true friends to guide them in the path of purity,
                                might he ealled into the same fold, and have the same care and instruction that I have.
                                It makes me feel very sad when I ride away a few miles to a city, or a village, and see
                                the children dirty and ragged, and using un. becoming language, to each other. I think I
                                ought to be very thankful for my beautiful home, and Fathers and Mothers who take such
                                an interest in my welfare.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cora" TEIform="persName"/>Cora.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister E ;—As I am going to..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Sister E ;—As I am going to...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, December 31, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, Dec. 31. 1882</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Sister E ;—As I am going to meeting this afternoon, I am thinking of what I have so
                                often been told;—to remember all we could of the speaking of the good brothers and
                                sisters. It would teach us to be good, and help us to behave properly in public, by
                                giving our attention to something useful instead of the dress, looks, and actions, of
                                our companions. I was thinking and talking to the girls, yesterday of the beautiful
                                holiday we had the past autumn and our ramble on the mountain gathering Ferns,
                                Evergreens, &amp;c. also our visit to the Cranberry patch. I never knew before that
                                they grew on little creeping vines close to the ground, andO, so thickly matted
                                together. They say Br. James has worked seven long years to get the vines in such
                                beautiful order, and they gathered over one hundred and sixty bushels this year from the
                                little piece he has cared for. Not much more than one acre somebody told one of the
                                girls. I think him very good and kind, but he seems very feeble. I have much to make me
                                good and happy in my home and will strive to be a dutiful child to those who do so much
                                for me. Your affectionate,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fannie" TEIform="persName"/> Fannie,—Age, 12.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister S:—You always have such a smile on..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Sister S:—You always have such a smile on...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon, December 12, 1882" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon; Dee. 12, 1882.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Sister S:—You always have such a smile on your face I love you xery much, and as we
                                were writing today I asked Sister E. if I might write to you. I do not love winter it is
                                so cold, and I have to stay in the house so much ; and I cannot tell you of anything
                                which seems so really nice as what we enjoyed last summer, when Sister Ann Maria took us
                                into the grove and then to the graveyard. The first I noticed was dear Eldrcss Polly's
                                grave. I gathered some, pretty flowers and put them'on it, and after awhile we went back
                                to the orchard and had some candy and fruit to eat, when our good times were ended out
                                doors. Eldress Polly brought me here to live with believers and I would love to visit
                                her grave every day and put flowers all over it. I hope to be good enough to see her
                                when I die for I did love her so much. I could say many things to you if it was as easy
                                to write as it is to talk, but Good bye.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emeline" TEIform="persName"/>Emeline,—Age, 11.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boys, read and heed" TEIform="index"/>BOYS, READ AND HEED
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Many people seem to forget that character grows; that it is
                                    not something to put on ready-made with womanhood or manhood; but day by day, here a
                                    little and there a little, grows with the growth, and strengthens with the strength,
                                    until, good or bad, it becomes almost a coat of mail. Look at a man of
                                    business—prompt, reliable, conscientious, yet clear-headed and energetic. When do
                                    yon suppose he developed all those admirable qualities ? When he was a boy ? Let us
                                    see how a boy of ten years gets up in the morning works, plays, studies, and we will
                                    tell you just what kind of a man he will make. The boy that is too late at
                                    breakfast, late at school stands a poor chance to be a prompt man. The boy who
                                    neglects his duties, be they ever so small, and then excuses himself by saying, "I
                                    forgot; I don't think !" will never be a reliable man, and the boy who finds
                                    pleasure in the suffering of weaker things will never be a noble, generous, kind
                                    man—a gentleman.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian helper" TEIform="index"/>Christian Helper</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="66" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prophetic minds, in the spirit of that divine gift..." TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MAHCH, 1883. Prophetic minds, in the spirit of that divine gift, have informed
                            us that, "The stroke or testimony that wakes up the children of this world will also wake up
                            the Believers." Are we asleep! Have we fallen into a lethargic state, dreamily passing away
                            our days, waiting for some form oJ an electric shock to arouse us to more active duty? Does
                            the same manifestation of divine presence that acts upon all the sects in Christendom, act
                            correspondingly upon us? As God sends the rain upon the just and the unjust, upon the barren
                            wasteas well as upon (he fruitful fields, we practically learn the lesson that he is no
                            respecter of persons, but those who work righteousness are accepted with him. Some have the
                            idea that a religious wave will pass over the land and all who are so fortunate as to get
                            baptized are the especially favored with a divine notice : forgetting that it is those who
                            work righteousness that are accepted of God. It is admitted that there is a worldliness in
                            the Christian churches and that nine tenths of the people are more deeply absorbed in money
                            making, than they are in their religious obligations ; success in business, bank stock,
                            bonds and notes come first to satisfy the increasing demand for the treasures of earth, and
                            to quiet the dread of coming want. "Give us this day our daily bread," is an invocation that
                            is made in every home. We should not become indifferent to the state of mind that exists in
                            the religious world, as its influences are powerful and may become permanent even within our
                            own order. We are informed that, "Out of every thousand, church members only one in five
                            attends prayer meeting, and only one in five of those attending can be depended upon to take
                            any part in the meeting. There is a woeful lack of Chrietly earnestness in doing God's
                            work." These signals of distress should prove a warning to the observing or reflecting^
                            mind, and prevent in our own home, one of the most insidious means of disintegration. The
                            human family are creatures of wonderful susceptibility, a thourand and one things, in the
                            air, in the clouds, in the water or in the vagaries of the mind conspire to form an
                            impression which often shapes the course of life for a long series of years. AVe laugh at
                            the Indians for their ignorance, in supposing that a great dragon was about to swallow the
                            sun, at the time of an eclipse, and smile at the shrewdness of Columbus who took advantage
                            of the event, and obtained from the frightened natives a large store or food. We make sport
                            at the expense of the African tribes who, during a midnight storm will arm themselves, and
                            in a wild frenzy shoot arrows into the storm cloudsA Christian and a civilized people would
                            not for a moment be found among these superstitious heathen, but tea grounds, witch hazle
                            wands, dark seances and idle dreams open an avenue through which a Christian walks on to
                            glory. When men will devote themselves to the cultivation of religious principles with the
                            untiring intensity, and study the advantages of the situation with the same acumen, that
                            they do for the a ecu- <pb n="67" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 67 mulatiou of worldly treasures
                            ; religious communities will evidently flourish with corresponding marks of success. We need
                            a revival, a revival of truthfulness and honesty, and a living kindness for poor humanity.
                            We need a school of prophets from which men and women can graduate as saviors and redeemers.
                            Preachers of the testimony of Jesus Christ, which is the sure word of prophecy, and the only
                            effectual door of hope.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conscience and compulsory vaccination" TEIform="index"/> CONSCIENCE AND COMPULSORY
                                VACCINATION.</head><p TEIform="p"> Sir,—For the past twenty years, during which time an organized opposition to compulsory
                                vaccination has been carried on, magistrates in hearing vaccination cases, have
                                generally united the magisterial function with that of advocate of the State enforced
                                ordi nance, and have either refused to listen to any 'reasonable excuse' whatever, or
                                done so with extreme reluctance and impatience, and often have mingled the penalty
                                imposed with a diatribe against the unfortunate recalcitrant and his co-agitators. The
                                wide publicity, however, which has been given through Parliament to the terrihle vaccine
                                disaster amongst the recruits at Algiers, and by the press to the catastrophe disabling
                                500 vaccinated persons at South Georgia, U.S., and still more recently to the fatalities
                                at Norwich, and other places, coupled with the painful fact admitted by all leading
                                bygiests, that in spite of improved sanitation, the mortality to the infant population
                                from a number of inoculable diseases—seems at last to have touched the magisterial mind.
                                The recent vaccine prosecutions in London, Leicester, Bedford, and Gloucester, indicate
                                on the part of the Bench a somewhat less intolerant attitude towards the persistent and
                                unwavering objections to vaccination, who are prepared to undergo the extreme legal
                                punishment, rather than incur the positive risks attending vaccination. Magistrates are
                                now advising anti-vaccinators to obey the law, and then agitate for its repeal. It must
                                be allowed that to disobey the law is a serious matter, and it is reasonably argued that
                                if one law may be broken, why not all laws, which would reduce civilization to anarchy.
                                There are, however, exceptions to every rule, and I venture to submit that vaccination
                                (which the leading statisticians of Europe, like ,Dr Kolb,of Munich, and Professor A.
                                Vogt, of Berne University, after examining all the statistics in Europe, have pronounced
                                to be devoid of scientific foundation, and affording no protection against disease
                                whatever,) is one of these exceptions. Lord Brougham I think it is who has said, "There
                                is no tyranny so great as that which is committed in the name of the law," and one of
                                our greatest publicists referring to the Vaccination Acts, says "It may .sometimes
                                become the part of a noble heroism to brave the law and accept all risks." The evils of
                                vaccination can be no longer denied, and it has been pertinently asked, 'Has the State
                                aright to choose for the child whether it shall take the risk of small-pox or
                                syphilis?'" What attention would Parliament; be likely to afford by Mr. P. A. Taylor, if
                                the laws which he so justly arraigns, met with universal acceptance. A general obedience
                                would be triumphantly and successfully urged as proof of the belief in the beneficence
                                of vaccination. History shows that unjust laws, are never repealed until resisted, and
                                the resistance must be very strong indeed to be effectual, where, as in the Vaccination
                                Acts, medical prestige, and powerful vested interests in the shape of an enormous staff
                                of paid officials, blocks the way. It was-only by resistance that theQuakers obtained
                                exemption from taking oaths: the Dissenters from the payment of Church rates, and'the
                                Jews from their Parliamentary disabilities. No legislation would be influenced for a
                                moment by the consciences that obeyed first, and protested afterwards. This vaccination
                                law, which treats 3000 conscientious men and women as criminals every year, and which
                                coerces millions of people into the adoption of an operation repugnant to their judgment
                                and instincts, (and as they honestly think affords no single benefit for all the injury
                                and cruelty inflicted,) are entitled to the same obedience that William Lloyd Garrison,
                                Abby Kelly Foster, Wendell Phillips, Lucretia Mott, Theodore Parker, and other noble men
                                and women in America, gave to the tyrannical Fugitive Slave Law of that country during
                                the regime of the Slavocracy twenty five years ago.—I am, Sir, yours &amp;c,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tebb, William" TEIform="persName"/> William Tebb. 7, Albert Road, Regent's Park.
                            London.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="68" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in the woods, no.3" TEIform="index"/>(See December No. 1882.) LIFE IN THE WOODS, NO. 3.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville T." TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE T. SPROAT.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Unless protected by Me-no Man-i-to, the Spirit of life; wicked spirits did not gain the
                            other side of the river. They fell into the deep, roaring waters and were carried by the
                            current again to the shores they had left, again to wander over the prairie, till they had
                            repented of their evil deeds, and then, Iveche Man-i-to, (the Great Spirit,)took pity upon
                            them, and brought them, at last, to the beautiful country in the Land of Souls. This
                            beautiful country was all that the Indian had ever imagined, in his happiest dreams. It was
                            ruled over by Ke-che Mani-to, (the Great Spirit ) and Che-bi-a-bos, his servant, the Wise
                            and the Good. There was no pain there, nor sickness, nor sorrow. Pauguk,—the terrible Death
                            Angel, could not hurt them there. The inhabitants feared not the cold, Ke-wah-din, (the
                            North wind,) did not blow there. They felt the breath of Sliawwon-da-win, (the South wind,)
                            through all the festal year. There was no darkness there, Wah-bun An-nung, (the Morning
                            Star) shone there continually, and chased all darkness away. No venomous beast, or poisonous
                            serpent, (Ken-e-beek,) or ravenous wolf, (Ma-ing,) did not infest its shores. Over all these
                            beautiful plains, white lodges were seen scattered, in which were heard the merry voices of
                            children; and they were often seen dancing down towards the rivers, to bathe in the crystal
                            streams. The sound of music was heard in all the groves. Birds of beautiful plumage, the
                            O-pee-che, the O-wai-sah, the O-see-o, (the robin, the blue bird, and the oriole) were heard
                            in all the pleasant woodlands, singing their songs of melody and love. Old men, from all the
                            ages, sat under the majestic trees, and talked of the scenes they had witnessed, and the
                            toils they had endured, before they entered the Country of Souls. "Mus-co-da, (the meadows,)
                            around them were covered with perpetual flowers, through which the rivers danced and sung on
                            their way to the Ke-che Gah-me, (the Great Sea.) Such was the Indian's dream of Paradise,
                            his vision of a future state. May we not hope that he found a resting place at last, from
                            the sorrows that awaited him here, in some fair Spirit Land beyond the sky? The parting
                            scene is with the Indians, very impressive. They bring the dying man into the centre of the
                            wigwam, and his friends gather around him, sitting in a circle, to take with him the last
                            smoke which they will ever take, as a token of friendly regard and brotherhood. The chief
                            speaker puts the end of the stem of the long pipe into his mouth from which, if he is able,
                            lie draws a single quaff of smoke, and then it is passed round to all the company, who
                            perform the same ceremony. lie then arises, and says, "Well, brother, you are about going on
                            your journey!"' To this the dying man assents. "Well, we will take good care for you on your
                            journey. We will put a pot of water, and a basket of meat, one at your head, and the other
                            at your feet, into your grave, for your three day's journey over the prairie. When you come
                            to the river, don't be afraid! You have been a brave, good Indian, and will pass safely
                            over. When you come to the Camp of Souls, remember us whom you leave behind, and don't keep
                            us waiting, when we pass over; but come out and welcome us in," To all of which the dying
                            man assents. Then they send messages to all their friends who have passed over the river,
                            the news of their success in war and hunting, the changes in their families, all Avhich they
                            think would have interested them here on earth. They then paint the face with the paint of
                            death, half black, half white, and cover it with a blanket, for the Indians consider it a
                            bad omen to look upon the face of a dying man, and he is seen no more. After death the body
                            is not taken through the door, but through an opening made in the side of the wigwam. When
                            asked the reason for this, they will say, "He has gone a way he never went before." They
                            will therefore take him through the sides of the wigwam, where he never went before, as a
                            symbol of his new, untried journey. They bring their dead to the grave at sunset. After
                            depositing the body in the grave, they will march in solemn procession around it, chanting
                            thus, "Ra-mo-saig! Ha-mo-saig! es <pb n="69" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. ne-kah-nis,
                            &amp;c." "Go on thy journey, brother, go on thy journey! 'Tis late, and the sun is set.
                            Tremble not for the river that is before thee ! Step lightly over, and go on thy journey!"
                            Then comes the chorus in which all join: "Ba-mo-saig! Ba-mo-saig!" &amp;c. When asked
                            why they bring their dead to the grave at sunset and not at some other hour, they will reply
                            with this question, "Has not the journey of a day closed? Has not the sun gone down?" Some
                            of these expressions are very forcible. Of the white man who walks with his toes turned a
                            little out, while the Indian walks with his straight forward, they would say, "He walks two
                            ways at once," by which they meant the trader, who told them one thing and practiced
                            another. Of a lying tongue, "It is hung in the middle, and talks at both ends," meaning, at
                            one end it speaks lies, at the other truth. Of the Great Spirit, "He always looks from his
                            windows towards the South." by which, they meant to be understood, the warm love, and tender
                            affection r with which God regards his children. The Indian knew nothing of theft. A stick
                            of wood, placed against the door of his wigwam, when the family was absent, was all the lock
                            and key they required. Hear what Keche Be-zhe-ke, (Big Buffalo,) of the Lakes, once said to
                            the writer.—"When the Pale face came across the Big Waters, we had straight paths running
                            all through our forests Our warriors walked in them. They were very narrow. But our warriors
                            feet went straight forward. It did not hurt them to walk in straight, narrow paths. But the
                            Pale Face could not walk in them. His toes turned out. He was trying to walk two ways at
                            once. He could not walk straight. His ways were crooked. He taught our people to steal. He
                            came creeping into our wigwams at nightHe crept in like a mouse that nibbles the children's
                            corn. He had long fingers, so long that they would reach to the bottom of the suga
                            mo-koks,(birch bark boxes.) He stole all the women's suga. And when our people told him of
                            this, and he opened his mouth to speak, we saw that he had two tongues. One tongue laid very
                            still. The other moved very fast. The lying tongue r walked the faster. (To BE
                        CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/> Kind Words for the Year 1882.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I herein enclose 6Octs. for the good 'Manifesto'..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I herein enclose 6Octs. for the good 'Manifesto'...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Wau pacca, Wisconsin " TEIform="index"/>Wau pacca, Wis.</dateline><p TEIform="p">I herein enclose 6Octs. for the good "Manifesto" for another year. I am pleased with it.
                                It is eagerly read each month. I wish every family in the land would take a copy for the
                                spirit of its benign and truth loving pages would be a powerful leaven, working for good
                                in the hearts of our poor, suffering race.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miles, H. N." TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto has come to hand as clean and neat as a coin..." TEIform="index"/>
                                The Manifesto has come to hand as clean and neat as a coin...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Union Village" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, Ohio</dateline><p TEIform="p">"The Manifesto" has come to hand as clean and neat as a coin right from the mint, and so
                                far as my knowledge extends, it gives universal satisfaction and is being read with
                                increased interest. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clapp, Charles" TEIform="persName">Charles Clapp.</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'The Shaker Manifesto' has manifestly profited by the removal of its local habitation..." TEIform="index"/>
                                'The Shaker Manifesto' has manifestly profited by the removal of its local habitation...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="South" TEIform="index"/>The South, published in New York city, edited by 0. A.
                                        Clough </bibl><quote TEIform="quote">The Shaker Manifesto" has manifestly profited by the removal of its local
                                        habitation. It has the usual diversity of contents upon matters worthy of the
                                        attention and thought and enjoyment of men and women, and a variety of
                                        interesting communications which add spice to its life and shows general
                                        interest of New Hampshire's good people in their new acquisition.</quote></cit></p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'The Shaker Manifesto' is the title of a neat publication from Shaker Village, N.H...." TEIform="index"/>
                                'The Shaker Manifesto' is the title of a neat publication from Shaker Village, N.H....
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Freeman's Magazine" TEIform="index"/>From "Freeman's magazine." </bibl><quote TEIform="quote">"The Shaker Manifesto" is the title of a neat publication from Shaker
                                        Village, N. H. It is an attractive monthly, containing twenty four pages of
                                        choice reading.</quote></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="instruction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Subjects for thought" TEIform="index"/> SUBJECTS FOR THOUGHT.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I tell you to bo honest in your dealing*', take no advantage even of a child. Be
                                    conscientious in your bargains. Have a single eye and a single heart. Seek not to be
                                    shrewd. Be not ashamed to be called simple. A cunning man is never a firm man, but
                                    an honest man is. A double minded man is always unstable; a man of faith is always
                                    as firm as a rock. I tell you there is a sacred connection between honesty and
                                    faith; honesty is faith applied to worldly things, and faith is honesty quickened by
                                    the Spirit to the use of heavenly things.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Vanity fair" TEIform="index"/>Vanity Fair.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vanity of vanities, saith the preacher, vanity of vanities ; all is vanity." TEIform="index"/>Vanity of vanities</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Vanity of vanities, saith the preacher, vanity of vanities ; all is vanity.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Bible" TEIform="index"/>BIBLE</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="70" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gentle words. A lesson for the year 1883" TEIform="index"/> GENTLE WORDS. A lesson for the
                            year 1883.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/> OTIS SAWYER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> More precious far than mines of gold Or fragrance sweet that flowers hold, A wealth that
                            never's yet been told,— • Are Wisdom's gentle words. What so adorns in every place, And
                            qualifies with Christian grace, Lights, beaming halo on the face— Like pure and gentle
                            words. What power can calm the passions wild Like pleadings breathed in accents mild, And
                            melt in tears the erring child— Like earnest, gentle words. The soul sin-laden, sorrow
                            feels,— With bleeding heart each wrong reveals, Then, what the wound so soothes and
                            healsLike sweet forgiving, gentle words. What draws the soul in valleys Ioav, From giddy
                            heights, and bids to go Where angels can their gifts bestow,— Like Jesus' gentle words.
                            "Come unto me ye weary souls, For I have rest that love unfolds" We yield,—the heavy burden
                            rolls ! O power of gentle words. What surer proof can e'er be given, That we, within, have
                            formed a heaven That peace is not by passion riven,— Than calm and gentle words. This is the
                            test, the heart within Is purified and cleansed from sin, That from it flows expressions
                            clean,— Chaste and gentle words. These are the gems in silver set, The golden fruit that
                            worth reflect, The gift, the godly man perfect,— Christ like, gentle words. When dying, then
                            what pleasure given To know our words were fitly spoken, Then sure as God, so sure of
                            heaven,— Immortal fruit of gentle words. West Gloucester, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be slow to anger, slow to blame..." TEIform="index"/>Be slow to anger, slow to blame</head><p TEIform="p"> Be slow to anger, slow to blame, And slow to plead thy cause. But swift to speak of any gain
                            That gives thy friend applause.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spring" TEIform="index"/> SPRING.</head><p TEIform="p"> As bursts forth Spring, Our hearts expand With new and joyful feeling, And we for life Make
                            new demand, And should new life be dealing. To take and give, Our balance shculd Stand true
                            for daily weighing, And nothing kind By others said, Should out-weigh our kind saying.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1883" TEIform="index"/> 1883.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patric, Marion" TEIform="persName"/>Marion Patric.</byline><p TEIform="p"> A New Year has dawned upon us, bringing its train of peculiar thoughts, and aspirations as
                            the Spring brings buds and blossoms. All the experiences of the Year come up afresh, and as
                            we count up our sorrows, and number our blessings, how does the balance find us ? Not as
                            way-worn, weary travellers, melancholy, and depressed; but with the guiding star of Hope, we
                            stand upon the hill-top of this New Year, and with heart-felt gratitude press forward to
                            gain new victories, for we cannot wrap ourselves in the downy mantle of indifference and say
                            we have no more to do. What we have failed to accomplish in the past, we hope to do in the
                            future, and therefore would consecrate ourselves anew to the service that lies nearest and
                            dearest to our hearts. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="index"/> Ruth Webster</head><p TEIform="p">, Jan. 23, at Union Village, O. Age, 75 yrs. and 20 days. She has been one of our most
                                faithful and upright sisters from the first day she united, till she passed over, and
                                has gone to receive a reward of unspeakable glory among saints and angels, made perfect
                                through sufferings.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. H.</byline></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Russell, Abigail" TEIform="index"/> Abigail Russell</head><p TEIform="p">, Feb. 6, at North Union, Ohio. Age 68 yrs. 8 mo. and 21 days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="71" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Praise" TEIform="index"/> PRAISE.</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury. N. H. 1. Praise the Lord sweet anthems .singing, Praise thro' ev'ry light
                            2. Time and tide may bring us burdens That may test our faith for his chastening, Humble, trustful, hopemid the harvest, When the sheaves of joy y 3. Praise the Lord e'en
                            4. Praise the Lord a and shade; Let our lives be and prayer ; Thro" the testing ful,
                            pure; Anchored firmly are full; When in life and true praise-giving, praise Him ever,
                            in His service, health the strongest, Let Be His love For His love Peace is gained, His
                            praise our strength, our aid. is even there, and heaven is sure, possess the soul. }
                            Praise the Lord sweet anthems singing, Praise the Lord, Let our sweetest songs ascend;
                            Praise the Lord. Praise the Lord. Praise the Lord, Praise the Lord. Praise the Lord. Praise
                            the Lord, Praise the Lord, For his love is ev'ry where. </p></div2><pb n="72" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elzevir library" TEIform="index"/>THE ELZEVIR LIBRARY
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A unique little semi-weekly magazine under this title has begun
                                publication in New York. Each number is to contain a complete literary/ gem, a
                                characteristic specimen of the best production of the brain ef the author who is
                                represented. The numbers taken together will form a beautiful little cyclopedia of the
                                world's choicest literature. Price only two cents a number, or $2 a year. Number one
                                contains Washington Irving's delightful story of Rip Van Winkle, Number two, Canon
                                Farar's graphic story of The Burning of Rome, and the persecution of the early
                                Christians under Nero. Oilier numbers folio1". ing are "The Sea Serpents of Science,''
                                by Dr. Wilson; Tennyson's ' Enoch Arden;" Goldsmith's "Deserted Village," "The
                                Traveler," etc. Specimen copy sent free on request. JOHN B. ALDEN, Publisher, 18 Vesey
                                Street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good digestion or the dyspeptic's friend" TEIform="index"/>
                                Good digestion or the dyspeptic's friend
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Goon Digestion or the Dyspeptic's Friend" by J. II"."llaiiaford, M.D.
                                is a pamphlet of sixty two pages and is well worth a careful perusal. If any one needs a
                                friend in this lower world, it would seem that the poor dyspeptic is the person. Simple
                                obedience to the rules of the good physician which are fully and clearly laid down in
                                this little book will warrant you a visit from tills good friend whom you will never
                                tire of seeing. Price 20 cts. Address Dr. J. II. IIanafoud, READING) Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>The Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The February
                                number of The Homiletic Monthly contains twelve sermons by eminent preachers, among whom
                                the eloquent Stopford A. Brooke appears for the first time in that excellent periodical.
                                The A niericMii sermons are by Dr. MeGosli, of Princeton; Dr. John II. Paxton, of New
                                York: Dr. D. F. Harris, of Cincinnati; Dr. D. II. Wheeler, of Brooklyn, and the Rev.
                                John Edgar Johnson, of Philadelphia; and both Spurgeon and Joseph Parker appear with
                                abridged discourses. Among1 the articles a notable, one is by Thomas G. Shearman, Esq.,
                                of New York, on "The Proposed Bounty on Whisky and Tobacco," and showing how the repeal
                                of the taxes on vices will put burdens on virtues. The Sermoiiic Criticism and other
                                editorial departments are full of good things for ministers amt other students of
                                Scripture. The Homiletic Monthly grows s:e:idily in value and public favor. Price, $2.50
                                per year; single number, 25 cents. Ftjnk * Wagnaixh, 10 and 12 Dey Street, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tourist's guide" TEIform="index"/>The Tourist's Guide
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The
                                Touhist's Glide of California, a beai.tifully illustrated work of some 282 pages, has
                                reached us, through the kindness of the Author, Major. Ben.C. Truman. From the first
                                page to the last it is an enchanting volume, taking us as it does through a
                                semi-tropical country, a land of flowers and fruits, and presenting to us such an
                                extended series of "Natural wonders." One writer says that,—"Yosemite conveys to the
                                soul of man, through the eye. what might be the orchestra of Heaven, through the ear,
                                were peals of thunder composed into harmonius notes of music, then suddenly silenced,
                                and followed amid instant stillness by nature's most tiny voice." It tells us of
                                Mountains with an elevation of from 10.000 to 14.000 feet, whose tops are covered "with
                                fields of everlasting snow?" Of tree* 275 ft. tall and over 100 ft. m circumference at
                                the base!! of Falls and cataracts and cascades from 100 ft. to 2526 ft; ain] one v£
                                these having 1.500 ft. perpendicular descent: of the wonderful mineral springs that are
                                to be found in erery part of the state, and which are unsurpassed in the mission of
                                doing good, and in healing the sick. The pleasure of reading the book comes next to that
                                «f making a visit to this land of extreme wonders. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>The Herald of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Herald of Health : February.
                                Contents. Is Lager Beer a wholesome Drink? An Ideal Home. Some Earnest Thoughts:
                                Contagious Diseases in Schools : Eights of Animals : Girl's Folly : Imaginary Diseases :
                                Effect of Tea on the skin, etc. etc. Pub. byM. L. Holbrook, M.D. 13 * 15 Laight St. N.
                                Y. $1.00 a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church spider" TEIform="index"/> THE CHURCH SPIDER.</head><p TEIform="p"> Two spiders, so the story goes, Upon a living bent, Entered the meeting house one day, And
                            hopefully were heard to say, "Here we shall have, at least, fair play, With nothing to
                            prevent." Each chose her place and went to work; The light webs grew apace : One on the
                            altar spun her thread, But shortly came the sexton dread, And swept her off, and so half
                            dead, She sought another place. "I'll try the pulpit next," said she, 'There, surely is a
                            prize : The desk appears so neat and clean, I'm sure no spider there has been; Besides, how
                            often have I seen, The pastor brushing flies." She tried the pulpit, but alas ! Her hopes
                            proved visionary : With dusting brush the sexton came, And spoiled her geometric game, Nor
                            gave her time nor space to claim The right of sanctuary. At length half starved, and weak
                            and lean, She sought her former neighbor Who now had grown so sleek and round, She weighed a
                            fraction of a pound, And looked as if the art she'd found, Of living without labor. "How is
                            it, friend," she asked, "that I Endure such thumps and knocks, While you have grown so very
                            gross? "Tis plain," she answered : "not a loss I've met since first I spun across The
                            contribution box."</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Chosen, a religious sect in Michigan..." TEIform="index"/>The Chosen, a religious sect in Michigan...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "The Chosen," a religious sect in Michigan, is not flourishing, as members worth over three
                            thousand dollars have to divide with their poorer brethren.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>