<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2503" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">25</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18950301" TEIform="date">March 1895</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="25" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
MARCH.
THE
MANIFESTO
PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES.
VOL.
1 Cast thy bread upon ths waters ; for thou shalt find it after many days."
Eccl. XI: i.
East Canterbury, N. H.
1895.
XXV
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Page.
History of South Union, No. 17,              -         49
A S haker's Testimony Against War, - 53
Come to Judgment,              ..."
Letter,Bernard E. Harding,             -         -   55
"          A- - - - -            -          -         -         -         56
Do not judge your neighbor, - - - 57
Effective Soul Labor,          ..."
Look Upward, . - - - - - 59
True Knowledge, - - - - "
"Learn of Me," - - - - - 60
MusicToil & Win,                                             62
Notes About Home,         .         -         -         -   63
Florida,           .....               69
Acrostic,        -         -         -         -         -         -   70
Home,      ..- -.."
Father, take me,            -         -         -         -   "
Speak, Lord to me,                                    71
Deaths,        -        -        -         -        -        -   "
Books & Papers,         -               -         -         72
Exchanges,           -         -         -         -         -   "
CAVtAldJITOiVIAKKS
COPYRIGHTS.
CAN I OBTAIN A  PATENT ?    For a
prompt answer and an honest opinion, write to
MUNN fc GO., who have had nearly fifty years'
experience in the patent business. Communications strictly confidential. A Handbook of Information concerning Patents and bow to obtain them sent free. Also a catalogue of mechanical and scientific books sent free.
Patents taken through Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the Scientific American, and
thus are brought widely before the public without cost to the inventor. This splendid paper,
issued weekly, elegantly illustrated, has by far the
largest circulation of any scientific work in the
world. 83 a year.   Sample copies sent free.
Building Edition, monthly, $2.50 a year. Single
copies, 25 cents. Every number contains beautiful plates, in colors, and photographs of new
houses, with plans, enabling builders to show the
latest designs and secure contracts.  Address
MUNN  CO., New York, 361 Broadway.
WANTED!
Agent to sell our new book, Dictionary- of
United States History, by Prof. J. Frank,
lin Jameson. Needed by every teacher, pupil, and family; indorsed. Agents selling fifty books per week. Successful agents will
be made general agents.   Big1 pay.
PURITAN PUBLISHING CO., Boston. Mass.
TEE DIVINE AFFLATUS,
A
FORCE IN HISTORY.
Price, 10 cts.
           " sell our choice and
hardy Nursery Stock, and Seed Potatoes, full and complete line. Many varieties can only be obtained through us.
Commission or salary paid weekly, and
promptly. Exclusive and choice of territory given. Don't delay, write at once
for terms.
ALLEN NURSERY CO.
Rochester, N. Y.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
qual rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
oflBcers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley,
2 N. Fourth St.,  St. Louis, Mo.
SHAKER'S   ANSWER
To THE OFT REPEATED QUESTION,
"What   will   become   of  the
World, if all become Shakers ?"
Price, 10 cts.
tee mm comtiT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring minds.    Price 5 cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
Reliable  men   to
WANTED.
A--><pb n="49" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="History of South Union, Kentucky, no. 17" TEIform="index"/>HISTORY OF SOUTH UNION, KY. NO.
                            17.</head><p TEIform="p">AY 13. 1863. A company of fifty Confederate cavalry come dashing across the railroad not far
                            from our buildings. The frightened Brethren hastily unhitched their horses from the ploughs
                            and wagons and rode away, either to tell the story of a guerilla fight or to find for
                            themselves a place of safety. The Confederates soon formed in line of battle on the north of
                            the railroad, while several persons were engaged in placing a heavy fence rail under the
                            iron rail on one side and on the rail on the opposite side. Soon the train came rolling
                            along under the charge of the Federals. Several of the Brethren and neighbors tried in vain
                            to give warning to the engineer. The men in line of battle by the side of the track, and the
                            obstructions were soon discovered, however, and the brakes were put on, but not soon enough
                            to stop the cars. As the train moved slowly along it was very fortunate that the cow-catcher
                            caught under the wooden rail and threw it around, without stopping the passage of the cars.
                            So soon as the cars were near enough the guerillas fired into them, which was immediately
                            returned by a squad of Federals who were on the train. This sudden outburst resulted in the
                            death of a, young southern soldier, a ball having struck him in the region of the heart. His
                            horse carried him some forty yards from the scene of action before he fell. One beautiful
                            horse was also wounded. On the Federal side no one was either killed or wounded. In about an
                            hour after the fight, a company of fifty Federal cavalry were MARCH, <pb n="50" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 50
                            THE MANIFESTO. in hot pursuit of the flying guerillas. One soldier swinging his hat in the
                            air, cried out that he had sent three rebels to glory. Capt. Johnson does not approve of our
                            making a coffin for the young man who was killed, but says he ought to be hung up where the
                            crows could eat him. We do not conclude to heed this advice but make a plain coffin, and
                            place the body in it as best we can. It is then taken to Russellville for interment. Thus
                            ended this scene of blood which for a short time caused quite an excitement among the
                            peace-loving members of our little village. May 14. General Order No 18, is issued from
                            head-quarters U. S. forces at Russellville, Ky., and is placed in the Post Office : "All
                            male citizens of Logan Co., who have not taken the oath, are required to report at the
                            Provost Marshal's office in the town of Russellville, on or before the 1st day of June next,
                            and take the oath of allegiance to the U. S. Government. Any one failing to comply with this
                            order will be at once arrested and sent south of the .Federal lines not to return again
                            during the rebellion under penalty of death." (signed) Brig. Gen'l Shackelford. Two
                            Brethren, as a committee foi the Society, go to remonstrate against taking the oath, which
                            might be construed to force us to take up arms in case of seeming necessity. Gen'l
                            Shackelford being absent, Lieut. Holloway said we could return to our home and wait the
                            return of the general, and if they wished us to take the oath, some one would visit us. On
                            the return of the general he wrote to us, saying, "You will not be requested to take the
                            oath." So it is that the Lord hath a care for his people. [ We copy in this place a letter
                            ivritten to the President of the TJ. S. on the 16th of Aug. 1863. Ed. ] To the Honorable
                            Abraham Lincoln, President oe the U. S. Kind Friend;"Strike, but hear." The armies of the
                            south, like a great prairie fire swept over this part of Ky. in the fall and winter of 1861,
                            licking up the substance of the land. We were humbled before its power and for many months
                            remained the quiet subjects of the Confederate Government, obeying all its behests save one
                            which nobly and generously they permitted us to disregard, and that was, to take up arms in
                            their behalf. They encamped for days, as many as a thousand at a time, in our lots and
                            occupied our buildings. We chopped and hauled wood for their camp fires and slaughtered our
                            animals for their commissariat, and at all hours in the night we were compelled to furnish
                            food for hundreds at a time. They pressed all our wagons and horses of value for army
                            purposes; but for these they paid a moderate price in Confederate scrip. It was then we
                            prayed earnestly, "0 Lord, who art Almighty ? if it be thy will, deliver us from our
                            enemies." <pb n="51" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 51 The worst of whom were our elated and
                            high-headed neighbors. This, our prayer was partially answered, when your loud ordinance was
                            heard, to open on Bowling Green, fourteen miles noith east of this place. Since that time,
                            we have suffered much from the ebb and flow of the tide of war, until a good part of what
                            the fire left, the merciless and surging billows have in their turn swept away so that we
                            have been left, as it were, writhing sometimes under the heel of one power and sometimes
                            another. Your armies have visited us from a small squad, to five or six thousand at a time.
                            Our barns were cheerfully relieved of their contents, our fences turned into camp fires,
                            (for these we have been paid by you) but gratuitously have we furnished food for thousands
                            of your men. Of this we complain not. To our uniform kindness, (if we must say it,) all your
                            armies that have passed us, all your hospitals within our reach, all your post surgeons and
                            commanders can bear witness. When your supplies were cut off at Green River, your officers
                            pressed our sugar for hospital purposes, our cellars disgorged themselves of nearly a
                            thousand dollars worth, for which so far, on account of some informality, we have striven in
                            vain to obtain one cent of remuneration. We state these things now, not by way of complaint,
                            but merely as grounds, (coming to your knowledge) on which we may rest a hope that we may be
                            treated on the sensitive point, with as much lenity and as much justice, as we were by the
                            Confederates while we were subjects of their government. Is it impossible that ones friends
                            can be as tolerant, as just and generous as their enemies ? Must our prayers be reversed,
                            and we cry to the Lord to be delivered from our friends? After we have uncomplainingly borne
                            until we can scarcely bear longer? Must we receive from our friends "the most unkindest cut
                            of all," besides the derision, jeers and mocks of our enemies? Shall the main support of one
                            hundred and fifty women, children and invalids be taken from them? Must this, indeed, be
                            added to our yet untold sufferings? Heaven grant it may not be. We have yet in our Society
                            about twenty-four young men between the ages of eighteen and forty-five years, a majority of
                            whom would be capable of doing some kind of service in the Federal army, but who are the
                            main support of the women, children and invalids above mentioned, a number of whom will not
                            shoulder a musket, nor bear about their persons the weapons of war, who having been taught
                            from infancy to love, and not to fight their enemies, would sooner lay down their own lives
                            than to aid, even remotely, in taking that of another. If this was respected by the
                            Confederate government, can it be ignored by the Federal ? It is to be hoped not. Were it
                            possible to convince us that we could love a man and shoot him at the same time(!)we could
                            hardly spare either the numbers or the few thousand dollars demanded in lieu of them. Add to
                            this the serious fact that these young men, through us their leaders, have pledged
                            themselves (we do not swear) not to fight against the <pb n="52" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 52 THE MANIFESTO.
                            Confederate government. Must we be compelled to violate this pledge? Certainly not; still,
                            as long as we are able, we will "feed the hungry and clothe the naked," as an act of
                            humanity and Christian duty, but not for the purpose of supporting war, but will cheerfully
                            "render unto Caesar the things that are Caesar's and unto,God, the things that are God's."
                            We are aware that you are oppressed and harassed on all sides and deeply do we sympathize
                            with you and therefore make our words few. If you can not exempt all the Shakers in the
                            north, who have scarcely felt the war, never having witnessed your marshaled hosts nor the
                            desolating and deathly tread of an army,Is it selfish in us to claim that our pledges, our
                            losses and our sufferings, and that in the midst of your enemies, demands that our Society
                            in Ky. should be the object of your commiseration and fostering care? Or can it be God's
                            will, that after having been spared by our enemies, wre shall be blotted from the earth by
                            our friends? Surely not. To take the young men of our home to sure demoralization and
                            slaughter or further wrest from us our means of support, with all that has been done, would
                            seem cruel. Our principles are above conditions. There is not money enough in the vaults of
                            the nation to buy them nor to induce one truly honest Shaker to engage in any war against
                            his fellow man. We do not expect that absolute equality of burden is attainable in the
                            present condition of things, only an approximation toward it; but where it can be, it should
                            be. We ask for simple justice, nothing more,hardly that. We look upon you as not only the
                            friend of humanity and the rights of man, but as the chosen instrument of God, in this time
                            of the nation's peril. But the instrument of God dares to do right. Now that our young men
                            are threatened with enrollment and draft, and are only held (some of them) by their friends,
                            from crossing the Tennessee line,we ask and feel almost certain you will, from the foregoing
                            consideration, grant exemptions from draft the few young persons of our Community, on whom
                            so much depends, seeing especially that each one has more to do for the support of others,
                            than the only son of a widow, now by law exempt. With what ease you can render us the simple
                            justice for which we pray, and enable us to hold within our sacred precincts these of whom
                            we shall shortly be bereft if wre "find not favor in thy sight." Only tell us at the
                            earliest possible moment, consistent with your other duties, that you will release them. You
                            will then have done for us a favor equal to all the losses we have sustained and will
                            receive the cordial and heart-felt thanks of a grateful Community. We will not wreary you
                            more, but humbly wait and hope and pray. We are sincerely, Your friends, To the Honorable
                            Abraham Lincoln, John N. Rankin President of the United States, II. L. Eads, Leaders of the
                            SociWashington, D. C. ety of Shakers at So.. Union, Ky. (To he continued.)</p></div2><pb n="53" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker's testimony against war" TEIform="index"/>A SHAKER'S TESTIMONY AGAINST WAR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas J." TEIform="persName"/>By Thomas J. Stroud.</byline><p TEIform="p">I AM unable to see how it can admit of an argument that, as disciples of the Prince of Peace,
                            we can not fight or commit any act of violence. The Christian does not worship or even
                            respect "the God of battles ;" in fact, the true Christian is a great deal better than such
                            a God. We are not discussing questions of public policy by worldly-minded politicians, but
                            we are representing the teachings of Christ. As a question of public policy, behold what the
                            war spirit has done for Europe. Its manhood is kept from the pursuits of peace by military
                            exactions; the public treasure is expended on its armies and navies until several of the
                            greatest military nations are on the verge of bankruptcy, and all the people of Europe are
                            .galled and nearly overwhelmed by excessive taxation. Supposing it were possible for the
                            nations of Europe to do away with their armaments and to live in peace with each other,
                            would they not manifestly be in a much happier condition ? It is to be regretted that the
                            government of this country is expending public money on military and naval armaments, and
                            that the military spirit is being encouraged by drilling pupils in high schools and
                            churches. If the people of this country desire the blessing of the God of love they should
                            cultivate the art of peace. The founder of our faith, Mother Ann Lee, received her
                            revelation in England, and came to this country in the time of the Revolution. She had been
                            driven from England on account of her testimony,that the Christian religion was one of
                            peace, and a life of virtue was the only Christian life. When she came to this country she
                            was persecuted for uttering the same testimony; was arrested and imprisoned at Poughkeepsie,
                            N. Y., on a charge of being a British spy, because the country was at war with the British,
                            and her testimony if obeyed by the people at large, would leave them a pr'iy to their
                            enemies. Is not this an exact parallel to the testimony of Jesus. His enemies said,We must
                            kill him, because if the people believe his word, the Romans will come and destroy us. But
                            the testimony of Mother Ann took deep root in the hearts of many, and has continued to bear
                            fruit to the present day. Shaker Station, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Come to the judgment" TEIform="index"/>COME TO THE JUDGMENT. (A Visionary Dream.)</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>By Catherine Allen.</byline><p TEIform="p">I SEEMED to be in a spacious hall dedicated to religious purposes, the end of which was
                            arranged with rising seats, facing isles which occupied the body of the room, and where were
                            seated many Brethren and Sisters, and some not yet numbered with Believers, who had been
                            attracted by some magnetic influence. <pb n="54" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 54 THE MANIFESTO. On the first
                            rising seats, facing the isles, were the present Ministry and Elders of Mt. Lebanon; on
                            either side of them were the Orders of Ministry and Elders from other branches of Ziou.
                            Behind these, on still ascending seats were a glorified number,the spirits of departed
                            Ministry and Elders. Among them I recognized many whom I had known as standing in the gift
                            of the Anointed while in this life, and I realized that all with them associated, had been
                            called as witnesses in the judgment work of souls. The appearance they presented can only be
                            conceived by the interior sense. The collective body of Elders of themselves formed a White
                            Throne from which the emanating aura ascended like a shining mist in a cloud above them,
                            over which radiantly glowed the Divine presence in the light of Shekinah. The garments of
                            this number were of a gleaming whiteness, and the atmosphere around them seemed dense with
                            spiritual force. From each individual came forth an ethereal substance direct as shafts of
                            light, all converging to one centre. That centre was an altar placed at the feet of the
                            Elders, and that substance was the pure love of God; and formed the living, quenchless flame
                            which glowed thereon. From the illuminated cloud pendent above the altar, rolled forth in
                            mellow cadences, the richest harmony. A song unclothed with words, but strong, deep and
                            tender in sentiment which the soul could understand. It was divinest music, which reached
                            the innermost being with an earnest pleading to "Come to the Judgment! Come to the Judgment!
                            Enter the flame and be purified." So appealing were its tones ; so rich in a love unknown to
                            the natural miud, that it brought to me an overwhelming power of conviction, under which I
                            felt such a sense of the "sinfulness of sin;"such an abhorrence of its nature within my own
                            being, that to be freed therefrom was my only concern. The thought of the privilege to be
                            cleansed from sin, so far exceeded the fear of burning, that it was with joy intense I
                            approached the altar. But the work could not be done in a moment. It was first to lay off
                            all covering, and then to unfold my inner self deed by deed, thought by thought. While
                            commencing this, I glanced upward to those above me who formed the White Throne of Judgment,
                            and Cloud of Witnesses. Every eye was centred on the work that I was doing; but with no
                            glance of scorn or severity, only'that of compassion and encouragement. I felt deeply
                            humiliated in exposing to the view of those pure and exalted beings, all the deformities and
                            miserable conditions of my fallen state. But, under the burden of sin, I felt as Mother once
                            expressed;"I could confess before the whole wrorld." In agony of soul I cried out:"It
                            matters not how I appear, I am just as I am, a poor, weak child of nature. I will lay bare
                            my condition; 1 will uncover to the deepest depths. O beloved Ones! Anointed of Christ,in
                            mercy to my poor soul do witness for me. Turn not your gaze away lest your power cease to
                            come, and the altar fires grow dim!" As I proceeded in the work, I experienced as never
                            before, how potent <pb n="55" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 55 was the love of G-od to cast out
                            every fear, and also realized how flimsy and vain were all the reasonings and excuses of
                            nature to satisfy conscience, for, as soon as opened to the light, these were consumed like
                            cobwebs, leaving only the bare motives,the soul quality in its exact meaning that had
                            prompted each deed and word. On this occasion many were deeply exercised under the power of
                            conviction, and sought as the greatest privilege of their lives that of accepting the
                            invitation to "Come to the Judgment." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="Section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Manifesto:--My first letter..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Manifesto:--My first letter...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Watervliet, January 1, 1895" TEIform="index"/>Watervliet, Ohio. Jan. 1, 1895.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Manifesto :My first letter of this new year shall be devoted to you. Will beloved
                                Elder Henry Blinn and the readers of your esteemed pages, kindly accept the love and
                                compliments of the season, from the members of our little household of faith dwelling
                                here? A happy new year to all who love and live Mother's gospel. By this same mail I
                                enclose you a copy of a small tract on "Pork, or the Dangers of Pork-eating Exposed." It
                                proves that pork is unfit for human food and refutes the various apologies offered for
                                pork-eating. I should like to know whether it merits your approval. If it does, and you
                                should care to recommend the tract, it can be had of the Pacific Press Publishing Co.,
                                Oakland, Cal." The cost is merely nominal, a cent or two a copy. As far as I know, the
                                world has ceased its active persecution of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, but
                                having ourselves suffered in the past, we ought to know how to sympathize with all
                                honest people who are suffering persecution now for conscience sake. From Seventh Day
                                Advent friends and from the newspapers, it is painful to learn of bitter persecution of
                                inoffensive "Bible Christians" by their fellow Protestants in America and Europe and in
                                far off Australia as well. Religious intolerance and persecution are the marks of the
                                beast. The Protestant reformers ate sour grapes, and their children's teeth are set on
                                edge to this day. These persecuted seventh-day keepers have formed an association having
                                branches in this country, and Canada, and England, and Switzerland, and Australia. The
                                following is its platform. DECLARATION OF PRINCIPLES OF THE INTERNATIONAL RELIGIOUS
                                LIBERTY ASSOCIATION. We believe in the religion taught by Jesus Christ. We believe in
                                temperance, and regard the liquor traffic as a curse to society. We believe in
                                supporting the civil government, and submitting to its authority. We deny the right of
                                any civil government to legislate on religious questions. <pb n="56" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 56 THE
                                MANIFESTO. We believe it is the right, and should be the privilege, of every man to
                                worship according to the dictates of his own conscience. We also believe it to be our
                                duty to use every lawful and honorable means to prevent religious legislation by the
                                civil government; that we and our fellow-citizens may enjoy the inestimable blessings of
                                both religious and civil liberty. Is there a true Believer in our own Society who would
                                be unwilling to endorse this declaration? I am persuaded that there is none. Surely,
                                those possessing the spirit of Christ, could unite with secularists and all upright men
                                on the last three articles of this declaration. Shall pious ears never cease to be
                                offended by such self-contradictory expressions as a Christian nation, begetting
                                Christian offspring, the American Sabbath and the like? In the venerated Bro.
                                Hollister's Shaker Catechism, I have found a perfect treasure. Many have felt the need
                                of such a work. Selections from it are being read here to the Community. Our good Elder
                                intends to order several copies for general use, but sad to state, the "filthy lucre" is
                                somewhat scarce at present; but we are living in hopes of better times. Eldress Hester
                                broke her arm some six weeks since, but is recovering fairly considering her age. The
                                feast of Jesus' nativity has been celebrated with much joy and Christian hilarity by
                                both our families. Meetings well attended and love and blessings mutually exchanged. May
                                the grace of our Lord and Mother's love be with us all. Sincerely yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harding, Bernard E." TEIform="persName"/>Bernard E. Harding.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Friend, Elder Henry..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Friend, Elder Henry...</head><p TEIform="p">[The following is a little pleasantry,
                                taken from a letter that was not written for publication, so we withhold the name. Ed.]
                                Dear Friend, Elder Henry ;I think you and we will have to blow the blast a "'leetle"
                                louder before the dead will awaken. How about going to Florida, to the miasmatic swamps
                                where the bull-frogs croak, and the crocodiles play hide and seek? Where the flies and
                                fleas abound, and the humming-birds bask in the tropical sun, where all can sing praises
                                and where the banana, fig, pine-apple and oranges all grow, even in the night while we
                                are asleep. All this without labor. It is a fine place. There we can have plenty of
                                hoe-cake and bacon, all for the asking, as it flows as freely as the milk and honey did
                                to the children of Israel when they entered the promised land. O what a glorious
                                country;let us flee ! Where? to the land of promise, where we can sing praises without
                                working, as all we will need will grow spontaneously. Let us give all that we have to
                                the poor that are around us, and flee from the wrath to come that we enjoy the blessings
                                of the solid south where some things rule and other things abound. O it is a beautiful
                                prospect and we are interested in all good things. Yours kindly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A." TEIform="persName"/>A.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="57" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do not judge your neighbor" TEIform="index"/>DO NOT
                            JUDGE YOUR NEIGHBOR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schenck, Sophia L." TEIform="persName"/>By Sophia L. Sehenck.</byline><p TEIform="p">[Contributed by Eldress L. E. Greene.] Do not judge your neighbor, harshly, Be not hasty to condemn ; Things unknown to you may
                            alter What now seems averse to them. Shadows, looking dark and dismal, Could you rightly
                            comprehend Might assume a brighter aspect And ward off some bitter end. Often in this life
                            of trial, Upright hearts are falsely charged ; Gossips toss the merest trifle Till it soon
                            becomes enlarged. Do not add your censure to it, Lest you live the deed to rue. Think, what
                            seems to brand your neighbor. Possibly may prove untrue. Better far defend a brother When
                            sharp, poisoned arrows fly ; Your kind word may change the current Of the public hue and
                            cry. When a man is down, don't strike him But extend your friendly aid. One lift may give
                            him courage And his downward coarse be stayed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Effective soul labor" TEIform="index"/>EFFECTIVE SOUL LABOR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lane, Mabel E." TEIform="persName"/>By Mabel E. Lane.</byline><p TEIform="p">IT has been said that the divine attributes of God-Love, Truth, Charity, Mercy and Justice
                            are in all men and women, either in the germinal form or in different stages of development
                            and are destined to give power over every form of evil. The chain of error which so often
                            confines the soul in a dark prison can only be broken by the force of divine goodness and
                            only when the soul is released, can it breathe the clear atmosphere of heaven and behold the
                            beauty and glory of God. It is impossible to attain the heights of holiness and perfection,
                            without first passing through the trial and experience which serves to eliminate from our
                            character all that hinders our spiritual progress. <pb n="58" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 58 THE MANIFESTO.
                            The tiny rivulet courses down the mountain side, meanders through meadows, ripples through
                            valleys and joins a broader stream which will carry it to the boundless sea ; so the flow of
                            pure thought and action broadens into the river of soulful life, whose current is ever
                            flowing on to the ocean of perfect attainment. The ways of human nature are subtle and so
                            often the king of Wrong usurps control of the heart and rules with his cruel scepter, that
                            it is necessary to become strong and valiant for the right, to be clothed in an armor of
                            purity that no earthly power may penetrate to harm or destroy the good. We can not enter the
                            beautiful temple of righteousness, kneel before its sacred altar and receive the holy
                            unction from heaven, without first passing through long avenues which lead away from centers
                            of selfishness where we keep our cherished idols. Although there may be many doors and
                            windows in the house of God, yet the entrance through which every one must pass is the lowly
                            gateway of humility. How often sentiments from elevated minds inspire us to higher motives
                            and aspirations, they seem to add rich harmony which not only blends with the simple melody
                            of the soul but its vibration thrills the whole being with ecstasy, touching chords which
                            have hitherto been silent, or they are like threads on which we may string our purest
                            pearlsthe best thoughts and highest motives of the soul. "Ideals are the world's masters.
                            That self which thinks, judges and knows is always in advance of that other self which
                            wills, acts and lives ; and all the spare capital of the soul, all that is not appropriated
                            to the daily uses and experiences of its life, is invested in ideals, projected into forms
                            where it may be kept, contemplated and worshiped, as the instituted sources of inspiration,"
                            and lead us nearer to God. How often these ideals gleam and wave before our inner sight, yet
                            for want of true moral courage and diligence we fail to reach them and embody them in our
                            lives. No achievement is wrought without patience, the jeweled talisman which generally
                            brings success. It is said of the silver-leafed poplar that it grows in one decade but dies
                            in the next, while the sturdy oak requires a century to attain its full growth and then
                            lives and dies at leisure. Is it not measurably so with human life ? Good which is gained
                            spontaneously may not always be of enduring worth, but virtue attained by self-mastery is
                            lasting and will not pass away. "The crutch of time eventuallv does more than the club of
                            Hercules." It is only by degrees that we can receive the unfolding truth, thus bring the
                            spiritual nature into oneness with God. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We speak of petty trials..." TEIform="index"/>
                            We speak of petty trials...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"We speak of petty trials which we would not allow to destroy our peace as if the waves could
                            affect the majesty or touch the depth of the ocean! "</p></div2><pb n="59" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Look upward" TEIform="index"/>LOOK UPWARD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lincoln, Julia M." TEIform="persName"/>By Julia M. Lincoln.</byline><p TEIform="p">Look upward, e'en tho' trials compass thee And clouds hang o'er the path thy feet must tread,
                            And doubts and fears disturb thy heart with dread, 0, ever trust and watchful, humble be And
                            from temptation thou wilt yet be free; By waters calm and sweet thou wilt be led ; Thou wilt
                            have living joy in sorrow's stead And hope will gladden thee continually. All hearts must
                            know vexation, pain and grief, All feet must walk the valley dark and drear, But thro' God's
                            mercy cometh sweet relief, His love hath power to banish every fear; Look upward then, and
                            thou wilt yet behold, The fadeless, golden light of heaven unfold. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True knowledge" TEIform="index"/>TRUE KNOWLEDGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McLeod, Isabel" TEIform="persName"/>By Isabel McLeod.</byline><p TEIform="p">A little knowledge dangerous proves It fills the soul with pride, The mind goes upward
                            soaring And thinks there's naught beside. But with a true desire We long for some brave soul
                            To guide our wayward spirit Unto some purer goal. Unto a fount whose waters Will cleanse
                            from pride and woe That we may find true knowledge And meet no adverse foe. No foe of evil
                            promptings Of jealousy and strife, But ever looking upward Attain the purer life. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The every day cares and duties..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The every day cares and duties...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The every day cares and duties which men call drudgery, are the weights and counterparts of
                            the clock of Time, giving its pendulum a true vibration and its hands a regular motion.</p></div2><pb n="60" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Learn of me" TEIform="index"/>"LEARN OF ME." </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">WHEN the Teacher began his mission of "good will," he early taught those who were anxious to
                            follow him, that the first and essential requisite for their spiritual success was their
                            obedience to God's light in the soul. He, at once, impressed this fact upon their minds, "I
                            am the Light," Then came the lesson upon which their hope and ultimate victory must rest,
                            and which was,"Learn of Me." The disciples who had been up to this date, a class of devout
                            Jews according to the Mosaic Law, wrere now meeting something that claimed their closest
                            attention. Moses the Law-giver had been the Savior of Israel. He had freed them from the
                            bondage of the Egyptians and directed them safely to the "Land of Promise." Through many
                            generations he had been their inspired teacher and all that was necessary to be known for
                            their present protection or for their future success over all their enemies, they were
                            assured had been faithfully arranged for all time to come. Suddenly there appears among them
                            one who teaches lessons of peace and good-will to all men. Moses had instructed his people
                            to love their friends but to hate their enemies, and to hate ones enemies is quite like
                            doing all that may be done to injure them, even to the destroying of life. The disciples who
                            were full of Jewish revenge, were ready at an early date to impart this information to Jesus
                            as a reminder that he was trespassing upon the privileges which had been granted to them.
                            Jesus understood perfectly well all that preceded him, but his mission was in advance of
                            that of Moses. Times had changed and where one had taught a hatred toward an enemy, the
                            other was now teaching them to love their enemies. If they had fulfilled the Law in their
                            lives, they would be justified by the Law, but if any one wishes, said Jesus, to be my
                            disciple he must"Learn of Me." A new way is now being established and this must claim
                            present attention. All the crooked ways of man must be abandoned and strait paths must be
                            made suitable for the Lord to walk in, and this strait path would be equally as good for man
                            to walk in. No more hating those whom we called enemies. No more deceptive weights and
                            measures while buying or selling. The pupil can not be of special credit to his Teacher
                            unless he profits by the lessons that are imparted. Although they may include in their
                            illustrations the whole life of man, they must not only aid him to do his whole duty to
                            humanity, but also elevate him to that position that he <pb n="61" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            61 may witness the'glorious light beyond, and in this"exalt the Lord our God," for Zion's
                            sake, although it may be at "the cost of our life." In this rests our hope of success.
                            "Learn of Me." And what have we learaed, as messengers, who are called to bear a light to
                            those who are wandering in the "broad way." Just note this simple lesson and mark the
                            progress. "Be not over-anxious," said Jesus, "what ye shall eat, or what ye shall drink."
                            There were many things, seemingly, of far more consequence that should be done in the
                            interest of humanity, than to be over-anxious and give so much thought to the pleasures of
                            appetite. The learning of a lesson implies much more than the committing of it to memory. It
                            must be absorbed into the very life principle, if it is to become an active worker in the
                            interest of others. As faulty as Christianity may be in many respects, it is a growing good
                            in the world, and in many instances has ascended quite above the general mass of humanity,
                            even though a close application to the voice of the Teacher has not been carefully heeded.
                            This may and will be demanded to give an assurance of harmony with the spirit of God, and so
                            allow them to be called the children of God. If the darkness has been partially dispelled,
                            we may begin to run our heavenly race and not become weary, and we may walk and not faint.
                            If we can be so fortunate while on this pilgrimage as to be learning the great lessons of
                            the Teacher, our time may not have been spent in vain. This education must include all that
                            is for the moral and spiritual good of mankind. To fail in this is to fail in the direct
                            object of our mission, and to become a class of angular. Christians wIid are more concerned
                            about some religious formula or some outward observation, than we are about our own personal
                            discipline. In connection with this too much care can not be exercised over the language
                            that we use from day to day. Not only profane and obscene words should be avoided, but words
                            that influence toward that which is profane or even vulgar. A Christian who indulges in
                            carelessness of speech must be making a sorry use of his privilege. This care should extend
                            not only to man, but with equal care toward all of God's creation. Not even a horse or a dog
                            should be forced to hear unchristian words from a Christian mind. In this way the lessons of
                            the Teacher may be wrought out for the good of the many, and the light that has been
                            received from God be made to shine on the pathway of many a weary pilgrim.</p></div2><pb n="62" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Toil and win" TEIform="index"/>TOIL AND WIN.</head><p TEIform="p">"It God which worketh in you both to will and to do of his good pleasure."Phil, ii, 13. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. 1. Would'st thou stand in triumph with the brave, And wear the laurel wreath
                            of praise? 2. Would'st thou wear in lionor vestal robes, And dwell in light of perfect day ?
                            3. Would'st thou live in harmony and love, Apart from strife of sin and woe? Would'st thou
                            share the treasures of the true, The recompense of righteous ways? Then Joining in sweet
                            melodies of song,'Mid beauties that will not decay ? Then Give thro'faith the sacrifice
                            required, The heaven of heavens to know. Control toil for the gaining of the prize, The
                            blessing of the earnest heart; take not for wearing garments old, The spotted folds of sin
                            and shame, ev'ry passion of the mind, Thy restless tho't subdue in pray'r, Effort alone will
                            for thee obtain, The substance of the better part. Wash, and be cleansed by the living
                            truth, Thus merit what thy soul would' stgain. Bright is the goal that thy winning waits
                            When endless peace thy soul may share.</p></div2><pb n="63" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. MARCH, 1895. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Okdeb and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All communications should
                            be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. .75 .40 One copy per year,
                            postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. January. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1894. 25.52 % in. 27
                                in. 1895. 23.36 % " 15 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 52 above 0 Lowest " " " " 10
                                below" Number of rainy days " " 4 " " snowy " " " 8 " " clear " " " 10 " " cloudy " " "
                                9 C. G. Reed. Center family. Feb. 1895. We the people of Mt. Lebanon have for the last
                                few days been experiencing one of the severest storms in many years. The snow continues
                                to fall, although the wind has abated somewhat just at present. Water-works have given
                                us more trouble than usual owing to the intense cold wave that struck our Village on
                                Tuesday the 5th inst. the next day the mercury fell to 18 deg. below zero and our hands
                                have been full ever since in caring for the premises. This old and blustering weather
                                has made some of the people wish for a more genial climate even to be tormented with
                                mosquitos and gnats and other pests incident to tropical climes. Next Thursday morning
                                two Brethen of of the fraternity, Henry G. Hollister of Watervliet and Andrew D. Barret
                                of Mt. Lebanon leave for Florida to make some initial preparations for a home for those
                                who wish to migrate and we trust they will be abundantly prospered in the undertaking.
                                General health of Society good. Timothy Hay son. North. Family. Feb. 1895. "As the
                                lire-fly shines only when on the wing, so it is with the human mind, when at rest it
                                darkens." At this time we mentally take a trip to our different communistic homes;
                                unperceived we take a visionary peep into them, and what do we see and feel? a physical,
                                mental and spiritual activity that seems to say, inaction brings stagnation; while
                                workearnest, soulful work that strives ever for the highest and the best, awakens
                                sleeping forces and eradicates evil. Are not "the powers of the world to come" already
                                upon us? and are we prepared to receive them? We have another cry from "Macedonia." The
                                Unitarian minister of Pittsfield, nine miles distant, has again invited us to hold a
                                meeting in his church, where we shall set forth our faith, principles and life.
                                Regardless of that visible mountain of difficulty over which we must pass, that rears
                                its snowwhite peak in bold defiance; and of the thermometer which now holds its own at
                                sixteen below zero; regardless of that conservative element that clothes with the
                                garments of self-righteousness the people of a wealthy city,we have determined to go,
                                and preach the everlasting gospel of purity and unselfishness. How much the TERMS. <pb n="64" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 64 THE MANIFESTO. world needs such a gospel! We hold the meeting
                                Feb. 17th. Brother Walter Shepherd, greatly loved and valued by all, leaves us to make
                                his liome among the dear friends of Enfield, Conn. This is not a voluntary sacrifice on
                                our part, but what is our loss will be their gain, for no one can come into the sphere
                                of his high-toned moral and spiritual nature without being "lifted up" also. Sunday,
                                Feb. 3rd, our beloved Ministry attended with us a season of spiritual communion. Truly
                                the sword of the Spirit has hewn down all the idols of self in their hearts. Their lives
                                of sacrifice and devoted service to others, are as guiding, shining lights to all;
                                genuine goodness can not be hid under a bushel. We have recently received a letter, from
                                a man living in Nebraska, who, several years ago painted for this village; he writes,
                                soliciting aid for the suffering poor of that state. He gives a heart-rending account of
                                their condition, which is actually approaching freezing and starvation, occasioned by
                                the failure of crops. He tells of instances where supplies have been sent to them, but
                                unable to pay the freight required, the railroad companies retained the goods. How long
                                must a betrayed people submit to the tyranny and greed of soulless corporations! How
                                long will gold crush out, not only the love of God, but all human instinct! Willingly
                                would we stretch forth our hands to help, though it may prove but a drop in the bucket.
                                Do we not all need an awakened intelligence in these times? Annie ./'. Stephen*.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Feb. 1895. The increasing length of daylight which at present is quite
                                perceptible reminds us of the approaching spring time which is advancing rapidly,
                                crowding out old Winter with his boisterous weather. ' 'How swiftly time is passing!"
                                Soon the seedtime will be upon us with the farmers and gardeners busily preparing the
                                soil and sowing the seed. The Feb. Manifesto came laden with so many good essays that it
                                is difficult to draw the line and say which is best, but we wish to thank Sister M. J.
                                Anderson for "Public Spirit." To consecrate the powers of mind and body unselfishly to
                                help those around us, satisfied with the reward of doing good is perfect service.
                                Working in a humble sphere requires a higher development of the spiritual life than to
                                give vast sums in a manner that draws forth the plaudits of the multitude. That there
                                are those who are able and willing to give their life services to doing good proves to
                                us that beneath all the selfish forces that largely dominate humanity there is a
                                spiritual principle that will eventually evolve the Divine brother and sisterhood of the
                                race. "Pure religion and undented before God and the Father is this, to visit the
                                fatherless and widows in their affliction and to keep himself unspotted from the world."
                                It is a pleasant passtime to review the beautifully illustrated catalogues of the
                                seedsmen as they come to our table. The luscious vegetables and beautiful flowers there
                                displayed make one forget the winter time. To gardeners who are looking for tools best
                                adapted for all general purposes of garden work whether hand or power we can heartily
                                recommend the Planet Jr. goods. Having had twenty years' experience with this firm we
                                have found them very satisfactory. A careful examination of the fruit buds of the peach
                                up to date (Feb. 4th) proves that they are largely destroyed. The mild weather of early
                                winter caused the buds to swell, for in a dormant state the peach can stand a lower
                                temperature than we have yet had, safely. What a desirable thing to cultivate the habit
                                of looking on the bright side of life. At best tribulations will come, and they are the
                                disciplinary forces that chasten the soul for the higher life. Then 1 et patience have
                                her perfect work. Hamilton DeGraiv.</p></div3><pb n="65" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. "Let us govern our passions with absolute sway, and thus grow wiser and better
                                as life wears away." It is our privilege to grow purer, better, more true and loving, so
                                let us make the most of life and its possibilities for good. Each moment of time is
                                valuable, and now is the accepted time. The years are made up of months, weeks, days and
                                hours and it is for us to improve them the best we know how. Pleasant and peaceful is
                                the self-denying path and peace reigns with those who are pure. It is a great mistake
                                not to fill up the spare minutes with something useful. While the world is advancing all
                                around us we must not stand still. Let us cultivate the soul as well as the land, it
                                will be a profitable investment. We must rise to higher degrees of goodness, not only to
                                do better farm work, but to cherish better purposes of soul culture and make our
                                influence felt for good. How much happier we become when we feel that God is shaping our
                                lives, and we are content to let Him, just lying passive in his hands, knowing that not
                                one more sorrow" or trial comes to us than we are able to bear, and that every cross and
                                affliction is for our eternal good; and how much peace it brings to us if we yield our
                                entire will to his blessed keeping. Every day brings with it many opportunities to learn
                                truth, to shun evil, to do good, and by these means to lay a foundation for a spiritual
                                character. "Bank notes were first issued in China as early as the ninth century, when
                                the art of printing was unknown in Europe." "Platinum has been drawn into smooth wire so
                                fine that it could not be distinguished by the naked eye, even when stretched across a
                                piece of white cardboard." A good hen should pay all her expenses and three dollars
                                besides in twelve months. uSnshine should be admitted into the poultry-house whenever
                                possible. With fowls as with other stock, the best feeding is a generous diet regularly
                                given. Generous feeding means generous laying. Profit is the keynote in poultry growing,
                                and the quicker an unprofitable flock is disposed of the better. Daniel Orcutt.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. The first of this month is the coldest weather we have experienced this
                                season. To-day the Oth the most blustering, mercury 14 below 0. According to
                                prognosticators this is to be the coldest and most stormy month. So far the mercury has
                                hovered around 0 most of the time. But if all without is secure, and our hearts are warm
                                with Christian love and charity, what matters the storm? only that the poor and
                                destitute must suffer. This touches the heart of every sympathetic Christian. Then there
                                are those who "go down to sea in ships." What must their sufferings be in such storms?
                                But would there be as much suffering, if fathers would cease robbing their homes to
                                obtain that key which unlocks the doors to destitution and misery? HowT much better that
                                our abodes should be opened by that key that unlocks the gates of paradise. Sleighing
                                excellent, which the farmers delight to improve in logging. Our aged people endure the
                                inclemency of our rough New England winter very well. No illness in Society at present,
                                and hope we may live so wisely and be so protected that all may be well with us. We
                                remember all our sister Societies and pray God to bless and prosper them. Mar da M.
                                Bullard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Shirley, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. These are days to be remembered. February Oth, the thermometer marked 15 below
                                zero. Yesterday the 7th the weather moderated somewhat, so that we <pb n="66" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. could have an old-fashioned snow-storm this a. m., the 8th, which has
                                made it very difficult to get about in any shape. The snow-plow was heard go by on the
                                R. E. a short time since, proving that we are not entirely shut off from communication
                                with our gospel friends in particular, or the outside world in general. There seems to
                                be a great correspondence in all the elementsnatural, spiritual, physical, social, moral
                                and political, and what shall the end of all these things be? Where are the Wise Men to
                                tell us? on whom we can rely! Loud-mouthed demagogues are plenty is there any better
                                way, than to so live, that we can justly claim^ a right to the promises of God,
                                applicable to the order in which we are called. They are many and cheering, amid all the
                                changing scenes and storms of life, and we seem to have need of all the courage and
                                energy they are calculated to inspire. May we not fail in the day of trial. We are
                                enjoying a good degree of health generally. Next winter's wood well under way so that
                                when spring opens(as it soon will) we shall not be far behind, at least. We are glad to
                                hear the good words that come to us from month to month in The Manifesto, or in other
                                ways, and desire to have our love and prayers mingle with those of our gospel relation,
                                so they may arise as grateful incense before our Heavenly Father and Mother, and the
                                Hosts of Heaven, whom it is our ambition to join, when earth's labors and sorrows are
                                ended. With some of us, the time can not long be delayed, but we intend to keep our
                                armor bright, and "never give up the ship." John Wliiteley.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. Since our last we have secured the ice harvest which is thought by some
                                persons to be one of the important things of the season. Not less than 103 tons was
                                securely packed in the ice-house, and this of excellent quality and not less than
                                sixteen inches in thickness. At the present time there is a great scarcity of water in
                                this part of New Hampshire and some farmers are obliged to drive their stock not less
                                than half a mile to procure the much needed supply. Our reservoirs have failed us and we
                                are really suffering from a water famine. All that is used for domestic purposes must be
                                pumped from the wells and carried in pails to all places where it may be wanted. As all
                                our Laundry work and our machinery for knitting and for printing are dependent upon
                                steam power, we are forced to shut down and wait patiently till the arrival of a few
                                warmer days, as the melting of snow and ice does not progress very rapidly when the
                                mercury is 16 deg. below zero. The water for some one hundred head of cattle is hauled
                                from a pond at a distance of about one half a mile and after being turned into the
                                trough is warmed by a very curious stove that is placed in the trough, mostly under
                                water. All the water that the cows drink through the winter is warmed in this manner,
                                and the herdsmen consider this arrangement a very valuable acquisition. The 100 tons of
                                ensilage is not quite all gone, as it has been used very sparingly the past month, and
                                only fed to special animals. Fiftynine gallons of milk from a herd of twenty-three cows
                                is carried to the dairy each day. We have had nearly a week in which to study the freaks
                                of the blizzard. The wind whirling around the buildings, trees and fences, piled the
                                snow into huge drifts and for several days made all traveling a matter of much anxiety.
                                II. C. Blinn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. Oh! for a thaw! Scarcity of water for power purposes, makes us fearful of a
                                ack for domestic use. We have had no 66 <pb n="67" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. G7 thaws
                                nor any rain for two months and everything is either dried or frozen up. Mascoma Lake is
                                five feet below the top of the dam, which is as low as it can be drawn. We are glad that
                                it happens in winter, as the same conditions in warm weather might be dangerous to
                                health. The zero weather has made bad work with the water pipes, as well as large holes
                                in the woodpile. Last month we sent a small donation of clothing to the sufferers in
                                Nebraska.. We are glad to see The Manifesto is still flourishing and full of good
                                things. We wonder though, sometimes, where some of the old contributors are. We
                                appreciate every new one however. Long live The Manifesto! G. IT. Kirklei/.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred., Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. Time well improved does not move with "leaden wings." We were so busy at the
                                time that Home Notes should have been written that the day passed by before we were
                                aware of it. It is true there was not much to write about. We have completed the
                                ice-harvest and the wood-pile in the door yard is steadily growing larger. The weather
                                is very mild. Candlemas day was overcast, with no sun to make a shadow for the badger or
                                woodchuck to scare him back into his hole and according to the good old sign the worst
                                of the winter had passed. But we have to learn that all signs fail sometimes as this one
                                did. Tuesday the 4th was a stormy day and Wednesday was stormy, more stormy, most
                                stormy, with the ther. at 16 below zero in the morning, 7 deg. at noon and 8 deg. at
                                evening, with a wind that could well be called a blizzard. Fires in some of the cellars
                                became necessary to save vegetables1. After reading the accounts in the papers we still
                                think Maine a good place to live. We can hardly say as they do at the North family, Mt.
                                Lebanon, that we have been free from colds because we are not strictly vegetarians,
                                although we yet hope to be. No one has been confined to the house long. Our term of
                                school, 14 weeks, will soon close. The change from the district to the town system adds
                                somewhat to our school term. Our Ministry go to New Gloucester the 15th inst., having
                                tarried with us eight weeks. May health and prosperity attend them. Let not the standard
                                be lowered, but preach the gospel proclaimed by the Christ and Mother Ann Lee, which
                                will save to the uttermost all who obey. Fannie Casey.,</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. He said to the snow, be thou on the eai'th,and here it is in beautiful white,
                                covering the earth for more than a week, and keeping it warm from many a chilling blast:
                                sent by Boreas from his arctic home. Such a change in climate is delightful when
                                accompanied by a clear, blue sky, and a calm, still atmosphere. It is so agreeable to
                                have a universe of sky and snow, once or twice in a decade of years. Frost and snow
                                kills many a deadly germ in the soil and atmosphere; and while it purifies the one, it
                                fertilizes the other, a gift and provision of nature for the welfare of the human race
                                who are made in the image and likeness of their Creator. The health of our Society is
                                reasonably good, for it could not well help being otherwise, being endowed as we are
                                with a full supply of muscular energy, a force which is very useful in many an
                                occupation. Now as some of our eastern Brethren are out prospecting for a more genial,
                                climate and fertile soil than they possess in their northern homes, let them not forget
                                to give our zone a thorough examination and blend their mental culture with our muscular
                                energy, and we will have a Society that will be a beacon upon a hill. James Carr. <pb n="68" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 68 THE MANIFESTO. [The following article was received from our
                                beloved Elder Watson too late for insertion in the January Manifesto, tout we take
                                pleasure in receiving even this notice. The dear Elder at the present time is suffering
                                from loss of sight to that extent that he is unable to read what he has written.
                            Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/> Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Jan. 1895. With the New Year comes our Society Monthly. It is always rich in sentiments
                                and this number especially, bringing the glow of fraternal love and gospel union, so
                                pleasant in this holiday season and so warmly expressed particularly in the "Home
                                Notes." Realizing this seems to suggest this word of counsel. "Go thou and do likewise,"
                                as every additional brand though ever so small, adds to the genial warmth. Hence, these
                                few lines of home, comforts our dear gospel relation. "O how I love those precious gifts
                                That flow in our communion Though times may change, we are not left, We still support
                                our union." Ours is a farmer's home depending upon seed-time and harvest for our
                                temporal support, which during the past season have been quite good and the drought has
                                seemed to effect our crops less than it has some of the farms about us. Our garden,
                                however, has suffered very severely, from which we harvested about 200 bushels of quite
                                good potatoes. The past season was mild and remarkably pleasant until about the 10th of
                                January, when the mercury went down to zero and one morning to 10 deg. below, and with
                                but little snow on the ground. We shipped 50 hogs to market a few days since, weighing
                                in the aggregate 13200 lbs. We also had 4000 bu. corn, 3650 bu. of small grain, 75 tons
                                of hay, 40 cattle and 144 swine. Wishing all contributors to this department and all
                                whom they love a realization of the kind wishes so warmly expressed, for the holiday
                                season, we would tender a like greeting of gospel love and fraternal sympathy. February
                                came in fair but cool. Woodchuck day was unusually bright all day. The children seem to
                                think that if the sleeper came out at all, he must have gone back to his hole under the
                                conviction that he had better stay there a few weeks longer We are having a remarkably
                                long season of cold weather, the thermometer touching zero and then up to 20 degrees.
                                Brethren are busy preparing the fire-wood. There is but little manufacturing done in the
                                Society, except shoemaking. This is conducted by our good Elder Thomas Mann. We have two
                                inches of snow. Watson Andrews.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 9, 1895. Yesterday morning the mercury stood 14 deg. below zero, and this morning 10
                                below. We have had very cold weather for about six weeks. I do not know but that we had
                                better think about moving to some sunny, southern climate. //. B. Bear.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Feb. 1895. Our winter can not continue a great while longer, for here it is Candlemas
                                day, and we have not seen the sun but it has been clouds and storm all day. ISTow if the
                                old saying is true, "Winter is gone and will not come again." We have had but very few
                                hard storms, but there is a great deal of snow on the ground and the Brethren are
                                improving the opportunity, hauling out the big logs from the pine woods. Br. Henry Green
                                of Alfred is with us this week assisting in getting out the poplar strips from which the
                                Sisters make their basket work. Our Brother Henry is always welcome here and his coming
                                this time has especially gladdened the hearts of the children as he has brought them the
                                present of a chair swing which will be erected under some shady tree. Thus <pb n="69" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 69 they are anticipating a great deal of pleasure, for the
                                coming summer. The integrity and fidelity of Br. Henry is widely known at the Summer
                                Resorts of New England, where he spends the season, making sales of the fancy work for
                                this Society and Alfred. He is a noble representative of our Order of life. The Sisters
                                have woven some very pretty plush rugs which will find a ready sale when the season
                                opens. School is still in progress and will continue for some weeks yet. We record a
                                successful term with twenty-two pupils. Ada S. Cummtnys.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Florida" TEIform="index"/>FLORIDA.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">A lettkk from the Brethren of Mt. Lebanon, states that the Societies of Mt. Lebanon and
                            Watervliet have purchased some 4400 acres of land in Osceola County, near alligator lake.
                            The property is now being fenced in and we hope in the near future a residence may be built
                            and a family of Shakers engaged in tilling the land. Until then we may not know fully,
                            either of the land or climate. At present the reports are very diverse. Some think they can
                            grow all kinds of fruits and vegetables, while others say that the number is very limited.
                            Br. Alonzo Hollister who is in touch with the Koreshan colony on Estero Creek, writes that
                            they "had on December 25 th, string beans, green peas, onions, radishes and sweet potatoes
                            fresh from the garden, and time enough to plant again and have another good crop. They also
                            have fish, clams, oysters, honey and chickens." Another writer who has been a resident in
                            Florida for several years says "they have flies, fleas, mosquitos and snakes. That there is
                            but little fertility in the soil. You can not raise a hill of beans without fertilizing. We
                            have no grass on which to pasture horses and cattle. It will not grow as the sun is too hot
                            and burns it up." What a wonderful margin all these views give us for conjecture. It may be
                            about Florida as it was about the land of Canaan. The company that Moses sent on a tour of
                            inspection did not all see exactly alike, and while some reported favorably, the others did
                            not. The land owners in the state of Florida may sometimes be influenced to see quite
                            differently from a disinterested person and hence, the conflicting statements of honest,
                            honorable men. This writer also says that he has not eaten an ear of green corn since he
                            entered the state, and he has been a resident ten years. "The corn will not grow in
                            Florida." By and by we shall understand more fully all the ins and outs of the "Land of
                            Flowers" and then may write of Florida as it really is. Since writing the above we have
                            received the "Florida Times Union"1 with a request that we notice the letter of John H.
                            Wei-sh, having reference, to the cold wave that passed over Florida in December last. He
                            says, "I have talked with five of the most extensive orange growers in the state. One whose
                            orange crop is 50,000 boxes. "We lost the greater part of our oranges, but I do not think we
                            will lose any bearing trees." Another says, "I will lose considerable tops, but no trees.
                            One thinks he will lose 20 per. cent in trees and fruit. The actual loss has fallen upon
                            owners of young trees and nursery-men. "The loss on lemons was larger than on oranges, but I
                            do not believe many trees are absolutely killed. Quite a number of the planters say that
                            their loss will be slight. I am frequently asked by northern farmers looking to Florida as a
                            home; What can you raise in Florida besides oranges? To this I make answer, one of my
                            neighbors, Mr. Benjamin Sutton tells me he cleared, the past season, on strawberries at the
                            rate of $400 per acre. Another raised (&gt;40 bushels of sweet pototoes per acre. Florida grows
                            practically everything grown in the United States, and is the natural home of the
                            industrious agriculturist." A writer from Thonoto- <pb n="70" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 70 THE MANIFESTO.
                            sassa, says that "the orange trees are sprouting out and in a few days will be green. Just
                            how bad the young trees are hurt, can not be told yet." A writer in Eustis says,"Vegetables
                            are coming in again, and doing well. If frost will only keep off, truckers may be happy
                            yet." Eustis is in Lake Co. and may be some 160 miles below Jacksonville. But as the frost
                            fingers have already touched the dear friends at Estero Creek, in Lee County, it may be
                            difficult to escape its presence in any other part of the state. East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Acrostic" TEIform="index"/>ACROSTIC.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Walker, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName"/>By Mary Ann Walker.</byline><p TEIform="p">Let us love one another for God is love. 1 John, iv., 7. O Lord give me understanding
                            according to thy word.Psalms, cxix., 1(39. Verily, verily, I say unto you, He that believeth
                            on me hath everlasting life. John, vi., 47. Every good gift and every perfect gift is from
                            above.James, i., IV. This is the promise that he hath promised us, even eternal life.1 John,
                            ii., 25. Honor all men.1 Peter, ii., 17. Every valley shall be exalted, and every mountain
                            and hill shall be made low. Isaiah, xl., 4. Let your conversation be without
                            covetousness.Heb. xiii., 5. One Lord, one faith, one baptism.Eph. iv., 5. Resist the devil
                            and he will flee from you. James, iv., 7. Do all things without mumurings.Phil. ii., 14.
                            Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Father, take me to thy care..." TEIform="index"/>Father, take me to thy care...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Father, take me to thy care, In thine arms, O take me. Let me lie and rest me there Till thy
                            voice shall wake me. And when thy voice shall call me, To rise and come to Thee, Thine arms
                            are still around me, I shall in glory see.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leavens, Mary Agnes" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Agnes Leavens.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, Isabella" TEIform="persName"/>Isabella Russell.</byline><p TEIform="p">A. poem written for the occasion and read in The Young People's
                            Meeting, Feb. 8, 1895. What pleasant memories cluster round The enchanted spot, our childhood's home No matter where
                            in after life The heart may turn or footsteps roam, There lingers still a cherished thought
                            We cannot break the magic spell. Instinctively we're carried back To that dear home we loved
                            so well. Once more we tread its hallowed soil, Once more we breathe its balmy air; The joy
                            and gladness who can tell That filled our world so bright and fair, Ere yet the changing
                            scenes of time Had made its impress on the soul, While innocence and childish mirth Held
                            over us its sweet control. What cared we then for grief or pain, At most 'twas but a passing
                            day, For when the glad to-morrow came 'Twas gone, had vanished far away. And in its place
                            new joys arose, Created by our magic skill; We somehow had the faculty Of changing fate at
                            our sweet will. We loved the birds and bees and flowers; We loved the sunlight's cheering
                            rays; We loved to walk in shady bowers; O these to us were happy days. The waving grass on
                            yonder plain, The murmuring brook with music sweet, Are interwoven with a charm That helps
                            to make our life complete. The placid lake we see it now, As in the days so long gone by;
                            The trees upon the mountain, top Seem almost reaching to the sky. And thus our childish
                            fancies weave A web of thought so pure and grand, That in our lives they wield a power We do
                            not, cannot understand. Perhaps symbolic of that home To which we turn in faith and prayer,
                            Where dwell our friends who've passed beyond The ken of mortal pain and care. Whose gentle
                            influence o'er us steals Like dew upon the thii-sty flower, While we, unconscious of its
                            source Are guided by this unseen power. O what a grand and noble theme, Inspiring heart and
                            brain and hand, To work with unremitting zeal For God and home and spirit land. Convincing
                            us that here and now <pb n="71" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 71 Are duties we should well
                            fulfill, For in that higher, better home, Each deed shall count for good or ill. Could any
                            theme our minds engage, Productive of more good than this, Which bids us now commence a life
                            For present gain and future bliss. O could we know what lies beyond Our mental vision so
                            obscure, How joyfully the race we'd run How patiently would we endure. Life's ills along our
                            pathway strown, intended only for our good, And yet God's laws we oft ignore, Because so
                            little understood. Then let us make our earthly home A place where joy and peace abound,
                            Where Christian charity prevails, Where God is praised and virtue crowned. Where each one
                            seeks the good of all, In consecrated deeds of love; Creating thus a heaven below, Allied to
                            our sweet home above. Then let us sing the gladsome song, In accents clear with music sweet,
                            Till all inharmony shall cease And heaven and earth in concert meet. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak lord to me" TEIform="index"/>SPEAK LORD TO ME</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>Annie E. Stephens.</byline><p TEIform="p">Speak, Lord to me and show Thy law divine; My inner soul would know Thy will, not mine. The
                            carnal mind may shun The cross, the light, Again to Thee I come, Lead me aright. O, send Thy
                            chastening grace And holy fire, Consume each darkened trace Of sin's desire. Serenely I will
                            stand In armor bright, With sword of truth in hand, Defend the right. Speak, Lord, Thy words
                            repeat, Give life, to-day; Thy whispering voice so sweet I will obey. Though lingering
                            shadows fall Across time's vale, If Christ is all in all Strength will prevail, Oh, when I
                            walk in hope And heavens' light, In doubt I need not grope, In error's night; Perfect Thy
                            grace in me Thy power and life, And make me one in Thee, Through holy strife. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Potter, Eleanor" TEIform="index"/>Eleanor Potter
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Eleanor Potter, at the Church family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.. January 21, 1895. Age 82
                                years, 9 mo. and 21 days. Sister Eleanor has for eighty years been a loved member of our
                                family. Virtuous, intelligent and useful through a long life, when the end came, she
                                "wrapped the drapery of her couch about her, and lay down to pleasant dreams." A. J. C.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Small
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sarah Small, at South Union, Ky. January 25, 1895. Age 84 years. Eldress Sarah came to
                                South Union at twelve years of age. In early years she laid her life down and devoted
                                her all to the faith she had chosen. At her dying hour she said,"Angels take me, do take
                                me." She was kind, patient, industrious and pious. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Atkinson, John" TEIform="index"/>John Atkinson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">John Atkinson at White Water, Ohio.
                                January 28, 1895. Age 83 yrs. 8 mo. and 17 days. Br. John was one of the adventists who
                                came to White Water in the spring of 1846. His testimony was always in favor of the
                                gospel taught and lived by Mother Ann. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bauer, Jacob" TEIform="index"/>Jacob Bauer
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Jacob Bauer, at Shakers, N. Y.. January 29,
                                1895. Age TO years and 7 months. He made his earthly home one of cheerful industry and
                                contentment and none knew him only to love and bless, therefore he will be better fitted
                                to begin enjoying heaven at once. R. II. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hennessy, Kate" TEIform="index"/>Kate Hennessy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">
                                Kate Hennessy, at North family, White Water,
                                Ohio. February 7, 1895. Age 50 years and four days,</p></div3></div2><pb n="72" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p">DR. PARKHURST ON CLUBS. Dr. Paekuukst will pay his respects to clubs aud elub-life in his
                                article in the next issue of The Ladies' Home Journal. "I consider the club," writes the
                                great reformer, -'to be one of the cleverest devices of the devil to prevent homes being
                                made, and to sterilize and undermine them when they are made." </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation via the rack" TEIform="index"/>Salvation via the Rack
                            </head><p TEIform="p">LATE LITERARY NEWS.
                                Geueral Lord Wolseley makes a most im portant contribution to the literature of the
                                China Japan war. In an article for the February Cosmopolitan, he discusses the situation
                                and does not mince matters in saying what China must do in this emergency. Two other
                                noted foreign authors contribute interesting articles to this number. Rosita Mauri, the
                                famous Parisian danseuse, gives the history of the ballet, and Emile Ollivier tells the
                                story of the fall of Louis Philippe. From every part of the world, drawings and
                                photographs have been obtained of the instruments used to torture poor humanity, and
                                appear as illustrations for a clever article, by Julian Haw; thorne, entitled,
                                "Salvation via the Rack.' Mrs. Reginald de Koven, Anatole France' W. Clark Russell,
                                Albion W. Tourgee, and William Dean Howells are among the story tellers for the February
                                number of The Cosmopolitan. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of Hygeio-Therapy" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy; Feb! Contents. Primary Facts
                                for Doctors; Phren ology; Anti-Vaccination; A public Benefactor; The Cowpox Merry go
                                Round; Cow Tuberculosis Retrospective and Prospective; Letters from Absent Friends,
                                etc., etc. Dr. T: V. Gifford, Kokomo, lud. In the "Anti-Infidel Library" Xo 43, we have
                                a very interesting Lecture by H. L. Hastings, that has been delivered in London, Eng. as
                                well as in America. When a man gives his life to a worthy cause, with an unflinching
                                purpose of doing good to humanity, he not only makes himself the friend of man, but also
                                becomes the friend of God. The little work before me is illuminated by the genial spirit
                                of the writer, ami he has no hesitancy in te 1ing how to meet the objections of the
                                skeptics. Get the book and read it, and you will have learned many good and profitable
                                lesson. Address H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological Journal and Science of Health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health for February more than fulfills the promises made in the January
                                number. In variety, solidity and attractiveness of matter, as well as typography, it is
                                thoroughly up to date. The Hon. John W. Goff is the subject of the opening phrenograph
                                from a personal examination, by the editor, Dr. Edgar C. Beall. As the new Recorder of
                                New York is a figure of national interest this desciption of him will attract wide
                                attention. A Psychological incident, by Jessie M. Holland, will appeal strongly to
                                lovers of occult phenomena. Prof. Nelson Sizer gives a fine phreno-biological account of
                                the late distinguished Prof. John S. Newberry, and contributes also six pages of
                                excellent illustrated matter to the Child Culture department. Mrs. Charlotte F. Wells
                                sketches the career of the eminent Spanish phrenologist, Don Cubi I. Soler. Spurzheim as
                                Organizer and Teacher, by Dr. H. S. Drayton, is valuable phrenological history. The
                                departments of Hygiene and Anthropology contain the usual variety. Character sketches
                                from personal examinations, of Em ma Goldman and Marie Louise, two wellknown anarchists
                                of New York, with portraits form one of the striking features in this issue. How to
                                Prevent Dishonesty in Banks (illustrated,) with a lesson in the physiognomy of the eye,
                                with two beautiful drawings, are among the leading editorials.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World's advance thought" TEIform="index"/>The World's Advance Thought
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The World's Advance Thought, edited and published by Lucy A. Mallory, Portland, Oregon.
                                This paper is earnestly engaged in "The Unity of Humanity and the Millennium of Peace."</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Islamic world" TEIform="index"/>The Islamic World
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Islamic World, a pamphlet of 32 pages published in Liverpool, Eng., in the interest
                                of the Mohamedan religion, and has found its way into a Shaker Village, as an exchange.
                                From this work we learn that the "Koran is not only the standard for religious teaching,
                                but it governs the daily life. It denounces evil speaking', covetousness and excesses of
                                every kind. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian standard" TEIform="index"/>The Christian Standard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Christian Standard, of Cincinnati, Ohio is a pleasant exponent of the
                                religious truths that are accepted by the church of the "Disciples." The church is
                                largely represented in the western states. Iowa is said to have a membership of 40,000
                                and Ohio of 65,000. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Times" TEIform="index"/>The Times
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Times is published in Manchester, N. H. The cause of temperance
                                could have no better advocate, and we wish for it the fullness of success. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church monitor" TEIform="index"/>The Church
                                Monitor
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Church
                                Monitor is published at Union Mills, Ind. G. F. Welcome, Editor. It is only 25 cts per
                                year and contains much that is very interesting. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American messenger" TEIform="index"/>The American Messenger
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The American Messenger, is from the
                                American tract society of New York City. It is a very interesting paper and has just
                                entered its fifty-third year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living epistle" TEIform="index"/>The Living Epistle
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> 
                                The Living Epistle is edited by J. C. Ilornberger and
                                published at Cleveland, Ohio. It is an evangelical monthly and in the interest of
                                Scriptural holiness. 72</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p27"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type and on excellent paper.
It contains  130 pages and has
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
The work gives quite an extended account of the Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price in cloth 75 cts;   in boards 50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blink,
East Canterbury, N. H.
AUTHOEIZED RULES
OP
THE   SHAKER   0OMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
 NE DOLLAR MUSIC BOOK,
r DC O
I    ri r_ L.-*-11 one hour you am learn
to accompany on the Piano or
Org-an by using Clark's Lightning Chord
Method. Wo Teacher arecessary. Should
be on every Piano or Organ. A limited number given away to introduce. The price of
this book is $1.00, but if you will talk it up and
show it to your neighbors, we will mail you
one copy free. Send one dime for mailing.
Address, Musical Guide Pub. Co., Cincinnati,
Ohio.   Mention this paper.
Should have the beautiful 36-page Monthly
= JXIiUSSRATBR HOM JOUBJffAL =
5O cts. a year.   Sample free.   Agents wanted.
Chicago. 111.
SHAKERS'
COMPOUND CONCENTRATED
SYRUP of SARSAPARILLA,
With 1 oz. Htdbiodatz of Potassa to 12 Bottles.
PREPARED AT
This medicine has proved to be most'.
valuable in the following diseases:
Chronic Inflammation of the Digestive
Organs ; Dyspepsia, or Indigestion ; Weakness and Sourness of the Stomach; Rheumatism ; Salt Bheum / Secondary Syphilis ;
Functional Disorders of the Liver ; Chronic
Eruptions of the Skin, and all Scrofulous
diseases and disorders arising from im purities of the blood. It is also an excellent remedy for the Erysipelas, Asthma,
Dropsy, Dysentery,  and Diarrhoea,   and
\for the complicated diseases of females,
I so apt to end in consumption.
Dose.For an adult, a teaspoonful
four or five times a day, with or without
a little water, which may be increased to
a tablespoonful, as best suits the patient.
To guard against counterfeits, observe
! the signature of the inventor on each
label and on each wrapper.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHRENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDI0AL
& SOCIAL REF0EM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
<pb n="" id="p28"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar  baking  powder
Highest of  all in  leavening strength.
Latest   United  States   Government
Food Report.
Royal Baking Powder Co.,
106 Wall St., N. Y.
HOW I CAME
TO  BE
.A.  SHAKER.
Price 5 cts.
Much knowledge for a few pennies.
Sent Postage paid to any address in the
U. S. We have on hand a few copies of
"Rip Van Winkle and other Sketches."
240 pages, 4x6.                          10 cts.
"A treatise on The Horse," by Dr. B.
Kendall. 90 pages. 5x7)^. Profusely illustrated.                                  12 cts.
Second vol. of Cassandra written originally in French by Sir, Charles Cotterell.
Published 1125.                                  .25
Sacred Roll and Book written by Inspiration in 1843.   A wonderful Book.     2.00
Hamlet, Prince of Denmark.
From Shakespeare.
.10
An old, brass eight day clock, in long
case, in excellent order.           fTO.OO
An eight day brass time piece made in
1810  by Dr.  Thomas Corbett.    $20.00
Several small, old-fashion clocks at reasonable prices.
Address   H. C. Blinn, E. Canterbury, N. H.
1 American Bee Journal,
- - - - - - - - - - -                (.Established 1861.)
IS Oldest, Largest, Best,
Cheapest and the Only
weekly Bee-Paper in all
America. 32 pages, $1.00
a year.   Send for Free Sample.
$1.00 3ES-EOOK FREH
G. W. Y0SK & CO., 199 Randolph St., Chicago, 111,
PLAIN TALKS
ON
PRACTICAL RELIGION
Being   Candid   Answers for Earnest
Inquirers.
By Geo. A. Lomas.
Price, 10 cts,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>