<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1201" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18820101" TEIform="date">January 1882</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p>VOL. XII, JANUARY. No. 1 MANIFESTO PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. CANTERBURY, N. H. Blessed are they that hear
                        the word of God and keep it. Shaker Village, N. H 1882. SHAKER</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p2"/>
                            <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="1" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">CONTENTS. Page Page Soul Travel No. 5 . 1 Deaths, 17 The Simpi:e Gosi&gt;el or Christ. 3
                            Catching Sunshine, 17 In Remembrance of, 5 The Bots we Need, 18 Cod,—Dual, 6 Letter Box, 18
                            Be Not Faithless, - 8 Things to be Remembered, 20 Shaker View of Marriage, 9 Pork vs.
                            Health----20 In Union thebe is Strength, 10 Milking Machines, 21 In Memory op----12 Deaths
                            by Ice Drinking, 21 Circular Letter, 12 Every One Pleased, 22 Good Morning, 13 Handle Dairy
                            Stock Kindly, 22 The New Year, 14 Angels' Visits, 23 Correspondence, 15 Music,-----Prayer.
                            24 Vol. XII. JANUARY, 1882.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul travel no. 5" TEIform="index"/>SOUL TRAVEL NO. 5</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">However much infidelity exists today to a belief in the existence of God; the future
                            existence of man after the death of his mortal frame, in a world of soixl life,—a spirit
                            sphere, where human consciousness of misery or happiness is even more vividly to be realized
                            than in this present world, the day of human progress is too far advanced for this phase of
                            human weakness and folly to be of long duration ; for, untold millions have, within the past
                            quarter of a century, received, and are still receiving such, to them, undeniable evidences
                            that God is, and that man exists in a future world of spirit, that, as well the svm might
                            cease her shining as to cause such millions to doubt their experiences. These enlightened
                            souls, for themselves, know that God is, and that He is working for the good of man through
                            His ministering spirits, and, not all of these are yet in the spirit world, and divested of
                            mortal frames. These avenues of open communication between these orders of beings are the
                            sources of new revelations of light and truth from Wisdom's inexhaustible fountains, now
                            accessible to man. Thus it behooves soul travelers,—seekers after happiness,—the would be
                            children of God, so to gain and hold a relation to these ministering spirits, that we may
                            have access to heavenly garners, wherein are hidden, not only "all the treasures of wisdom
                            and knowledge" but the inspirations of soul love and life that shall wean the recipient from
                            the love of sin, and the follies and foibles of worldly life. But, the great and important
                            need of humanity is to convince them of the fact of the existence of these superior heavenly
                            treasures :—to give them confidence and faith that God is, and is the rewarder of all them
                            that diligently serve Him. To make this fact an universal conscious experience to each and
                            every individual soul of man. Many still lack belief because the promised benefits, or
                            because the evidences of a future state for man's abode when done with time, are contrary to
                            their individual personal experience, thus far in life. Like the King of Siam, when told by
                            missionaries that the American rivers were often so congealed by cold, that his elephants
                            could walk upon them, could not believe, it was so contrary to his experience. Savage
                            nations disbelieve in the laws overning the heavenly bodies, enabling the scientific to
                            calculate eclipses; the conjunction of planets ; the times of the appearance of comets
                            &amp;c. Human experience is necessarily so finite, that, to live, in the widest sense,
                            much of :no. i. <pb n="2" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER M ANIFESTO. life's experiences have to be
                            accepted on the strength of the testimony vf other people. It is a fact, but, doubtless
                            revealed to the observation of but few persons, that a gorgeous butterfly is but the
                            evolution of a caterpillar. And who, that has never examined the sub- ject, but almost
                            questionably wonders how electricity can be made to write; wires be made to talk; light be
                            made to paint pictures ; coal, black as tar, made to yield candles white as snow; and how
                            dirty cotton rags can be made to yield sugar. But, these things, and thousands equally as
                            strange, are facts, and forced upon our credulity, because demonstrable ! Even so it is
                            demonstrable that there is a God, the rewarder of the life sacrifices of the righteous, and
                            the awarder of the just dues of the transgressors of His laws. A. Revelator of the fact that
                            happiness is not to be computed by the amount of earthly riches a person possesses; by the
                            hours of idle leisure to spend in sensual pleasures ; by the gaudy dress to wear; by the
                            grandeur and convenience of a tasty home; by the amount of beautiful and gorgeous flowers
                            bordering the clean cut lawns, nor the decorations upon the coffin containing the remains,
                            when the soul has emigrated to its eternal bourne, and the costly monument erected over the
                            casket when consigned to its mother earth; but by the innocence, righteousness, peace and
                            harmony of life, compared with the laws of the Lift-Giver! Divested of these graces of
                            character, life is but a mocking chase for the goal of Heaven ! But, while the gates of
                            Paradise are wide open to souls who, spiritually, self-sacrificingly, travel in harmony with
                            the Divine will) by a loving and devotional obedience; they are not even ajar to souls who
                            grudgingly conform to the same, in the ceremonial sense only; for, in the Kingdom of God, no
                            forced compliance to His laws does He recognize as obedience ; what is yielded by force, in
                            God's sight, is but mockery, and not yielded at all in spirit and verity. Jesus introduced a
                            travel of soul from the confines of the ceremonies of the Mosaic Levitical law and the
                            fiat,—" Thou sJtali" and lithou shalt not" to the freedom of conscience " Whosoever will,
                            let him. come and partake of the waters of life freely." That soul whose affected obedience
                            to the laws of God is but servilely and grudgingly given, can never, while in that state,
                            taste the bliss of His sweet love, nor feel the kindly sympathy of His nursing hand of care,
                            much less can they be fed, filled and inspirited, with the vivifying juices of the fruits of
                            the spirit, that grow in His heavenly vineyard! The environments of human creeds and empty
                            forms of religion, is a hedge that fences out the flowers and fruit bearing trees of
                            Paradise ; and the refreshing dews of Heaven cannot distil upon the plants impaled in their
                            domains. As well might the agriculturist attempt, hopefully, to raise corn, wheat, and the
                            luscious summer fruits of the earth in the deep gloomy grottoes and caves of its bosom,
                            wherein the stylactite displays its bleached, fanciful subterranean grandeur, as for a soul
                            to anticipate cultivating the flowers and fruits of Heaven while entombed in the caverns of
                            earth bound loves and foolish fancies that attract life's journeymen to the haunts of sinful
                            pleasure, or charm the senses so as to detract them from the pursuits of solid virtue. To
                            attempt to gain soul food by stuffing life with the pleasures of the physical senses, on the
                            one hand, and loading it with torturing pangs of physical sufferings on the other, is as
                            fruitless of gain as grasping at the shadow of a flower, which, in the sunshine of today is,
                            but, in the clouds of even, the night of darkness, or the morrow of storms, has no existence
                            ! Shall the human race forever, like the Prodigal son of the parable, feed on husks, while
                            in our Heavenly Father and Mother's house, and growing in Their Heavenly Vineyard of love,
                            there i.s blissful soul food enough, add fruits of exquisite richness, ar.d soul sustaining
                            and inspiring sweetness? Shall the sin frost bitten flowers of earthly sensual pleasure
                            forever lure the soul to disappointed hopes of happiness? Shall the dried fruits of a
                            lifeless, soulless, empty form of godliness forever starve the needy soul into a skeleton
                            ghoul of a soulless firm? Shall mere wordy righteousness and sentimental songs of and about
                            the bliss of heaven forever to be the lullaby of quiet for the soul into an incubus of
                            imagination that a heaven is already in the grasp of the spirit, which the future day of
                            trial will reveal to be only a mirage in the distant horizon? 2 <pb n="3" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. The answer lies within the purpose anc power of every soul traveler, each one for
                            one. Angel missionaries in armies, are com missioned to hold out the sceptred boon o: royal
                            bliss and glory, to every suecessfu winner in the race of life who reaches re demption's
                            goal from the thraldom of eartl and sin, set free by salvation's purifying furnace of trials
                            in the fire of truth. Who so wills, and emphatically strives, a heaven to win, to such the
                            gates are ajar Come, come, all created souls come! The Gospel trumpet of free salvation is
                            sounding an inviting welcome blast. The sun of revealed truth is beaming forth in
                            resplendeni brightness ! A high way of purity and holi- ness is cast up, beautiful for the
                            feet of those who would walk in Wisdom's ways of pleasantness, and all things are ready for
                            a soul birth right in the Paradise of God, to all who choose to be born anew ! Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple gospel of Christ" TEIform="index"/>THE SIMPLE GOSPEL OF CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. LOMAS</byline><p TEIform="p">The most singular feature of so-called Christian theology-the one which strikes with greatest
                            surprise the so-called heathen-is the multiform presentation of it from
                            multiplyingpersuasions or churches. Nor this only ; but the most consummate ingenuity is
                            demanded of him who preaches, that the gospel of Christ may be made significant, according
                            to this or that peculiar persuasion. The question here presents itself forcibly : Why any
                            more differe::ces of opinion concerning what Christianity really is, than there ia regarding
                            Buddhism, Mosaim, or Mohammedanism? But concerning these last mentioned, there are no
                            differences worth mentioning among the professors of those peculiar doctrines. Judaism is
                            identical the world ov?r—it has but one churchal exponent ; and so with the followers of and
                            believers in Buddha and Mohamet. Why is this thus ? Why should Christianity be the prey of
                            so many and much contentions? Why, when there is only "one Lord, one faith and one baptism,"
                            should there be almost numberless division:of opinions as to what genuine Christianity
                            really is? Why, in the face of the reasonable facts, that Christianity is so simple as to be
                            un- derstood by a child; and "the wayfaring man, though a fool (to any worldly logic or
                            theological ingenuity,) needs not err therein," should there be such demands for Colleges,
                            Universities, etc., for the training of the young, by the most skilled theologians and
                            ingenious scholars, simply that they may know and teach what some ignorant, unpretentious
                            fishermen learned from the lips and observed in the life-walks of the Master? These
                            Universities and Colleges are not for the learning of the simple religion of Jesus. It may
                            seem harsh ; it may be deemed severe to assert of them, that the peculiar teachings given
                            and learned therein, are devices that obscure the really simple life, char- acter and
                            religion of Jesus, and are intended for the upbuilding of peculiar theories, that really
                            teach the full cross of Christ unnecessary, and a great deal of the woridly life not only
                            admissable m the Church of Christ, but so harmonious as to become sacraments therein ! We
                            are not antagonistic to the most iberal educations ; but we consider any education that
                            obstructs the truthful )resentation of the most vital and important subject—soul religion—to
                            be a )erversity and a villainous perversity oo, of God given talents for obtaining wisdom.
                            We asseverate, that there is no need of any extraordinary education, nor ingenious
                            renderings of the scriptures 3 <pb n="4" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. that any one may be the
                            better Christian. The minister who has been trained for the pulpit, taught to expatiate upon
                            this that and all texts in agreement with the Alma Mater—the persuasion of the College at
                            which he was taught—is none the better Christian for his training in ingenuity. The gospel
                            of Jesus Christ is the same today as ever in the past—demands the s*me and only the same
                            credentials for discipleship—and an exceedingly holy life—a life like Christ's is demanded
                            by Christ's gospel. And the rural farmer, the unlettered mechanic, the simple laymen and
                            women, all, whether learned or unlearned, can know what Christianity really is, can learii
                            it from the beautiful self-denying life of Christ, and decide for themselves how much they
                            are Christians, how much they are willing to be Christians, by the nearness they approach
                            the life example of the Christ. Wherefore, then any need of skillful training or ingenious
                            legerdemain, that any may teach, preach or live the Christian life? Wherefore the need of
                            the Babylon of Churches, each proclaiming this is the way, while each is just so far from
                            genuine Christianity as the lives of its Communicants differ from the life of Jesus Christ ?
                            Is there any doubt in the minds of any professors of Christianity, or of those who do not
                            profess it, as to what kind of a life Jesus lived? There is a oneness of knowledge, oneness
                            of feeling in this respect. Let us have one Christian Church that will absorb all the
                            previous Babylonyish professions—a Church that will be the universally acknowledged
                            Christian Church, embracing all sensible men and women, who are not led by the ingenious
                            evasions of the priests ; but one that will be accepted, because it teaches that Christ's
                            life was His religion aud His Christianity ; and as Christians that life must be ours.
                            Appropos of the foregoing remarks we conclude with the sensible paragraphs upon the same
                            subject, of the venerable Oliver Johnston, in a sermon on " God's way of Saving Men." "This
                            is not an age when men should be content to live in the basement story of their being, half
                            under ground, but when they should ascend to the upper chambers, and even to the high towers
                            of observation in pursuit of truth." "In conclusion, let me say that man may pile his creeds
                            as high as heaven, charging them with deepest mysteries and accepting them all without
                            question; he may adopt and practice any number of forms and ceremonies, but they will amount
                            to nothing unless he heartily and sincerely confesses and forsakes his sins, and thus lays
                            the foundations of a noble character on the eternal rock. How glibly men recite their
                            beliefs, and practice their rituals, as if they had in them some saving grace, while at the
                            same time their lives are selfish and groveling, and marred by sins which are a daily
                            offense to God and man ! But neither their beliefs, not their baptisms, nor their
                            sacraments, will avail them as substitutes for penitence and right living." Watervliet, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man without a purpose is like a ship without a  rudder..." TEIform="index"/>The man without a purpose is like a ship without a  rudder...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carlyle" TEIform="persName"/>Carlyle: </byline><p TEIform="p">The man without a purpose is like a ship without a rudder ; a waif, a nothing, a no man. Have
                            a purpose in life, if it is only to kill and divide and sell oxen well, but have a purpose;
                            and having it, throw such strength of mind and muscle into your work as God has given
                        you.</p></div2><pb n="5" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In remembrance of Eldress Polly J. Reed" TEIform="index"/>IN REMEMBRANCE, Of Eldress Polly J.
                            Reed</head><p TEIform="p">Down to the river of tears, In grief are we led, For one light of our household, Now sleeps
                            with the dead ; With a spirit perfected Through suffering and prayer, Here, she closes her
                            labor, Her burden and care. In the cause of salvation, So loyal and brave, A leader
                            undaunted, By danger's dark wave. The land of soul liberty, She has defended, Where man's
                            equal rights Are in purity blended. Loved by dearest of kindred, In life's opening day ; The
                            lone star of their circle, Called early away From the altar, where human Affections entwine,
                            To her mission of sacrifice, Pure and divine. No selfishness cold, in her heart Found a
                            place, For the beautiful spirit Of true Christian grace, Sat enthroned in the temple Of her
                            loving soul, And held o'er the wild sea Of passion control. Through life's wearisome march
                            Fraught with hopes and with fears, "No shadow of turning" In her purpose appears ; But the
                            pure hallowed law Of the truth and the right, Has guided her home To the City of Light.
                            Humanity's good was the theme Of her fervor, The triumph of right Claimed her every
                            endeavor, That the bond of affection, Uniting us now, Should be sealed, as eternity's
                            Unbroken vow. No murmurings could rise, Like a cloud o'er the way, For the mandates of
                            justice, Will reason obey ; And the strength of her word Was the work of her life, Where
                            meekness and truth, In each action were rife. As she lived, so she died, A heroine rare ;
                            Drinking deeply of suffering For others welfare, Yea those unto wThom she A pilot would be,
                            To the rock unmolested By life's troubled sea. O why should our sister, Our pattern and
                            guide, In the day of her usefulness, Fall by our side ; A prey to disease That no skill can
                            arrest, 'Till she reaches her home, In the land of the blest. Now the veil drops between us
                            And vision doth cease, And no longer we hear Her sweet echoes of peace ; But patiently
                            trusting Wh£n free from earth's care, We shall meet our beloved, In the '•'Home Over There."
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspired by the spirit of loving kindness..." TEIform="index"/>Inspired by the spirit of loving kindness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Inspired by the spirit of loving kindness, we could not avoid writing and speaking of God's
                            love to man.</p></div2><pb n="6" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God,—dual" TEIform="index"/>GOD-DUAL</head><p TEIform="p">And God said, "Let us make man in our image, after our likeness ; so God created man in 34s
                            own image, in the image of God created lie Him ; male and female created He them, and called
                            their name Adam." Here in simple Bible language we are told what God is : at least as much
                            as man can know ; for, study and reason as we may, we cannot comprehend the In- finite.
                            "Canst thou by searching find out God ? Therefore beyond a certain point necessary to
                            understand our relation and duty to Him, it is foolish speculation and waste of time. "Say
                            first of God above, or man below, What can we reason but from what we know." Man's natural
                            intuitions of theDiety, even those of the children of the forest and desert, seem more
                            correct than the theories and conclusions of theologians ; for they, the theologians,
                            suppress the soul's prompting, and substitute therefor vagueness and mystery,-creations of
                            their own distorted imaginations. "Let us make man in our likeness." Let us make man male
                            and female like ourself. Let us also endow him with godlike reason and intelligence. "So God
                            created man in his own image, male and female created He them." If we interpret the biblical
                            account literally, as Christian sects usually do, we must believe that man was an exact copy
                            of God in miniature, in form and in structure : and if man is fnale and female, God must
                            also be male and female. If, again, we give a spiritual construction thereto, making due
                            allowance for the figurative language of the ancients, we must believe that great prin-
                            ciples were involved instead of mere physical formation, and that man's anatomy represents
                            the male and female principle in Deity. W? do not attempt the presumptuous folly of proving
                            two persons in the Godhead. This would be as absurd as to assert that there are three. We
                            cannot, like the Buddhist, make 2ods to order ; and as Warwick made English Kings ; neither
                            does our system of arithmetic teach us that one is three and three is one. Our God does not
                            compel us to believe inconsistencies of himself; nor does our religion consist of mystery.
                            Common sense and the yearning of our souls for parents, teach us of a Heavenly Father and
                            Mother too. We are not reconciled to the idea of being half orphans. We claim a legitimate
                            birth from a full and perfect parentage. Do we believe in Jesus, the Son of God? Most
                            certainly, and we also believe in Ann the Daughter of God. Why not have a daughter as well
                            as a son ? We believe He has many sons and daughters. The bible tells us that He had sons
                            six thousand years ago. The apostle Paul, unquestioned authority, says: "For the invisible
                            things from the creation of the world arc clearly seen, being understood by the things that
                            are made, even his Eternal Power and Godhead. Throughout creation we find manifest the dual
                            principle,—in the mineral, vegetable and animal kingdoms. This triple Diety has no
                            illustration in the world of ours. The idea originated in the abnormal brain of some
                            visionary monk. The arguments adduced to sustain such a theory are fallacious and have no
                            shadow of scriptural foundation even, save the occurrence a few times in the New Testament,
                            of the words 6 <pb n="7" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. Holy Ghost, and which only means Holy
                            Spirit. The male—God idea, the manGod idea, the idea of the corporal death of a God, and a
                            trinity of personal Gods, is a rel:c of a barbarous age, and was cotemporary with the
                            erroneous supposition that the earth was flat and supported by a huge turtle ; the sun small
                            and revolving around the earth, &amp;c, &amp;c. All these absurdities should, ere
                            this, have ceased to exist. The maleGod idea is boon companion for the doctrine of election
                            of an implacable God and eternal damnation ;—is consistent with the belief that woman was
                            made of a piece of man, and consequently is his natural appendage and legitimately his tool
                            and his slave. The emancipation of woman from a worse than feudal or African slavery, the
                            assertion of her just rights in domestic life, are yet in the future. The agitation for
                            woman's equal rights in educational f.nd political life,-the right of franchise, of
                            participation in govern- ment, her demand for equal pay for labor when equal quantity and
                            quality are rendered,—this is just what ought to be, but when obtained is but an
                            introduction to the real rights of woman. Woman herself does not yet sufficiently understand
                            her glorious possibilities ;-she even now ignorantly strives to be content to remain in
                            bondage, under the mistaken notion that God has made her so ; and to this fact are due, to a
                            great extent, the social miseries and prostitutions that curse our marital relations. These
                            are the unhappy conditions that make households miserable, and the fruits thereof fill our
                            cities with crime, glut our prisons and insane asylums, people our pauper institutions and
                            fill our cemeteries with premature deaths. From these homes come the Josie Mansfields, the
                            Jennie Cranmers, and the host of wantons of both sexes. These conditions are condoned by our
                            legislatures and ministers of the gospel silently pass them by as unpopular subjects for
                            discussion. The true reason of this cowardly reticence, this shameful neglect of imperative
                            duty by cur public teachers ; we will not now discuss ; but if the test were given, do we
                            think it would now be easier to find one sufficiently guiltless to cast the first stone,
                            than it was when the poor woman was brought by her accusers to Jesus ? Is there a remedy for
                            this moral leprosy of society ? Is there power 014 earth or in heaven to probe and heal
                            these festering sores of sensualism? God of our fathers ! Hear our prayer for deliverance
                            from this spiritual death. Our petition has been graciously received and woman is sent to
                            the rescue. Man's noble helpmeet, in no sense his inferior ; co-equal with man possessing
                            her full share of divinity in man, and representing her share of God's image. Hitherto she
                            has been ignored ; we have not known her. She has been merely a piece of property, a toy for
                            pastime or a baser use. Now by a more enlightened dispensation which in God's good
                            providence lias begun its unfoldment to a few at least, this incongruous one-sidedness is
                            changed. Woman comes to the front, stands side by side with man ; we greet her as a
                            companion, an adviser, a skillful manipulator of the destinies of life, able and willing to
                            sustain her full share in all its relations. Man's supremacy has been tried for more than
                            six thousand years, and it may be, six times six thousand years, and it has failed. Now
                            then, let us be 1 <pb n="8" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. honest and admit the fact, let us
                            attest an experiment, and not a doubtful one either. The Shakers have tested the equality of
                            the sexes in government, in religious service, and in domestic life for a period of one
                            hundred years. Worshiping God as Father and Mother, we recogni;e a complete family of sons
                            and daughters, and we love and respect each other in mutual rights as brothers and sisters—
                            a perfect and harmonious household. For one hundred years this Society hat proved to the
                            world that men and women can and do live in holy fraternal relations. Scoffers have not been
                            wanting, who, having no confidence in their own ability to exemplfy the virgin life, have
                            derided the possibility of the sexes living purely together and so closely socially
                            connected as we are. But we can afford to wait for our complete vindication from all
                            calumny. The truth will ultimately triumph ; and even now our cause is being championed by
                            the best minds and the most influential men. We declare unto you that we do live as we
                            pi-ofess. That we are able and really do bear our crosses against the lusts of the flesh ;
                            and in our relations with woman we do not find her a puny sickly thing, we do not find her
                            the weaker sex. We find in our sisters true companions, able and ready to stem with us the
                            tide of nature, to bear their full share of crucifixion, and oftentimes the stronger and
                            braver ; generally the more patient and enduring. We cannot speak of ou« sisters as the
                            women, nor do we hear them mention their brethren as the men. That is clearly the best
                            religion which evolves most fully our divinity. That is the safest theology, which, when
                            practically illustrated, produces the best result. Our conception of God as dual, and his
                            reproduction in man as male and female, two parts of a perfect whole, each different but
                            equal, gives us a broad and stable foundation, a solid hope, and humble trust in the Author
                            of our being. We no more worship Him in fear, in doubt, in mystery ; but as a full parent,
                            Father and Mother. He has indeed been wonderfully good to us his children. Let us worship
                            Him devotedly, with reason and intelligence. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be not faithless" TEIform="index"/>BE NOT FAITHLESS</head><byline TEIform="byline">From the spirit of ELDER <persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD BUSHNELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Bo faithless nevermore In the promises of God, He who hath declared,— Will in truth perfect
                            his word. Shall Zion's beauty fade, Or her glorious light go out? Not while the Sun and Moon
                            Shall shine. Never, never doubt. Shall this Sacred Temple rear'd, E'er crumble into dust;
                            Shall the Altar Fires cease, In which so many trust? Where in penetential tears, Great
                            Sacrifice is made For sin, and for transgression, 'Till ev'ry farthings paid? Shall the
                            consecrated labors Of Sainted Pioneers, Whose hands laid these foundations Baptized in
                            prayers and tears? Shall all these off'rings perish,— Be lost to needy souls? Not while the
                            Stars pursue their course Or wave of Ocean rolls. What though a few faint-hearted, Turn back
                            with scorn and spite :— Deride thy peaceful tenure, 'Gainst truth and justice fight? Lured
                            by elements of nature, For worldly paltry pelf; 8 <pb n="9" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. To
                            find no greater pleasure. Than merely pleasing self. Traitors at the nation's birth, But
                            nerved the Patriot's arm; Though in the direst trial, Fled cowards in alarm. Yet loyal Sons
                            of freedom With faith in God stood firm; Jehovah these delivered,—¦ From them a lesson
                            learn. Their names are high emblazoned On parchments, nations read; And yet shall unborn
                            millions Praise each heroic deed. While scorn shall point her finger, And hiss to very shame
                            ; The Traitor and the Coward Who've lost an honored name. God bless this land of freedom,
                            Which guards our Zion home; Thrice blest art thou, Mount Zion ! Where God has placed his
                            name. Blest is the crystal fountain Whose waters cleanse and heal; Blest the Ark and
                            Mercy-Seat Where God his Laws reveal. Raise high the gospel banner, Higher and still higher
                            ¦ Breast every opposition,— Burn up with gospel fire,— The lust of vain ambition, The pride
                            of sinful man, The unclean beast cast out,— Curs'd since the world began. Come blend your
                            hearts together, Ye trusting, honored few; The heavens have prepared Their richest gifts for
                            you. In songs of praises, tongues of fire, The word of God proclaim ; In Prophecies and
                            Visions True inspiration's flame. Listening hosts shall hear thee And hasten to the call,—
                            To the Altar of confession In gladness prostrate fall. From sea to sea o'er Oceans broad,—
                            To distant lands 'twill spread; From rivers to the ends of earth, To wake the sleeping dead.
                            Renew your faith and courage, Keep innocent and pure :— And set your house in order, God's
                            promises are sure This the Way the Truth the Life It never, never'll fail, 'Gainst all the
                            powers of darkness ; It surely will prevail Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker view of marriage" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER VIEW OF MARRIAGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Tn the Christian Union some time ago, under head of ''The Marriage Te.«t," appeared the
                            following statement, which needs correcting : "If a new system or scheme of life tampers
                            with marriage, it is always bad, and can by no possibility be good. The Shakers form a
                            community built on this rotten foundation. They destroy the family, root and branch. They
                            have no place for love, and enter into a determined fight with the God of nature, who, by
                            the strongest passions and impulses he has ever implanted in the human soul, has commanded
                            them to establish families and homes. Shakerism is good for nothing if it is not good
                            universally,—if it ought not to be adopted universally. But universal adoption would be the
                            suicide of the race, and a race has no more right to commit suicide than a man," etc.
                            Shakers do not tamper with marriage, but deem it a worldly institution with which the
                            genuine disciples of Christ have nothing directly to do. Nor can they have1 any interest
                            whatever in weakening its obligations on those who choose to populate the world. Ann Lee
                            taught, "Do not go and report that we forbid to marry, for we do not. But all that cannot or
                            will not take up their cross for the Kingdom of Christ's sake, and that only, I would advise
                            them to marry and live after the flesh in a lawful manner, ind be servants to their families
                            ; for that is natural and less sinful in the sight 9 <pb n="10" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 10 SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO.. of God than any other way of gratifying that nature." Shakers deem marriage
                            honorable in all who honorably use it for companionship or offspring only, and no for
                            unfruitful works of which it is ; shame to speak except in terms of con- demnation. Lawfully
                            used, it is gooc for those who own no higher purpose in life, and is far better than
                            licentiousness. Inasmuch as it brings the parties into responsibility absorbs and directs to
                            useful ends their superabundant energies, it improves them, and upholds their latent powers,
                            and subjects them to a degree of order, law and discipline. Nevertheless, it is written of
                            such, "They twain shall be one flesh," hence they are not spiritual, are not children of the
                            resurrection, who neither marry nor are given in marriage, but are of the earth, earthy,
                            like the first Adam, whose image they bear and whose works they do, and are bound by carnal
                            ties and worldly interests from which nothing can redeem them but the love and the cross of
                            Christ, faithfully borne. For not until they are prepared to forsake that order and its
                            carnal works, and live consecrated in brotherly and sisterly love, in perpetual chastity for
                            Christ's sake and his gospel, can they be lawfully released from the obligations incurred by
                            wedlock, and then only by changing an inferior for a superior relation. If this destroys the
                            family, root and branch, it evidently is not the work of man, for it is opposed alike to the
                            dictates of worldly wisdom, and the perverted desires of a depraved nature. Nor is it of
                            Shakers, but of God, for none can accomplish it without that faith and understanding which
                            is freely given of God to such as earnestly desire, above everything else, to know his will
                            that they may do it. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In union there is strength" TEIform="index"/>IN UNION THERE IS STRENGTH</head><p TEIform="p">The points made in November S. M., under the title "Bridegroom and Bride," so well accord
                            with my own understanding and experience, that it seems I ought not to with-hold an
                            expression of warm approbation. With the genuine hearted Shaker, nothing can supersede the
                            necessity of fulfilling the law of Christ, in all its bearings, which, as there remarked,
                            lias not to do with any part of the works of generation. Although it takes cognizance of all
                            the duties of the household, spiritual or temporal, not omitting any needful improvements,
                            in dress, diet, or any other branch of daily life, these may prove to be, not improvements,
                            but delusive snares, to any who seek, to introduce them in opposition to established
                            authority, or even without full and free sanction. In regard to dietary reforms, I consider
                            that the most desirable object to seek is a mind to partake of what is placed before us,
                            piously and gratefully. In good time any needed reform, will, we may trust, in this, or any
                            other department of life, be achieved by an easy, natural process. Mean-while there is no
                            better way than to adhere to customs, which, however objectionable to some, to others are
                            hallowed by age. A project may be canvassed, and differing views freely expressed, but the
                            introduction of new ways and things, at variance with the leading counsel, is a certain
                            occasion of anarchy, and of dearth in spiritual gifts. Great weakness is betrayed by those
                            who, thinking that the body moves too slowly—is too tardy in adopting new customs which may
                            be desirable—take their departure independently of the example and advice of those who are
                            in the van. These do not help the cause of srogress ; for though they succeed in forcing
                            their plans, in this irregular manner, they idmit more than enough weakness and disorder to
                            overbalance the advantages to be ooked for from their innovations. It is not the too
                            conservative, probably, vho retard progress, and postpone improvements, so much as the ultra
                            radical. While he former may be clinging too much to old forms, the latter, paying little
                            regard to these n their eagerness for variations step^aside <pb n="11" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. 11 from the safe, narrow track of obedience, and loss ensues, with poverty of
                            spirit The former class, seeing these evil results, are thereby made more cautious, and
                            tenacious of time honored institutions. Thus the day is deferred when the desired
                            alterations may be adopted with full accord and harmony. It may be better to submit to
                            conditions and customs, which, abstractly considered, do not commend themselves to our
                            understanding as hygienic or physiological, than to forego the discipline of implicit
                            obedience, and seek to crowd out prematurely, that which does not accord with one's private
                            judgement. The immense advantage of being in full union with our gospel parents, might seem
                            sufficient to induce one to accept many inconveniences of a minor and temporary character.
                            Moreover, that condition of perfect harmony, and unity of feeling, which ought to be
                            sustained, whatever our differences of opinion, is the condition most favorable to all that
                            is truly progressive. This discipline of yielding a childlike submission to those whose
                            function it is to direct appears to be of vital importance. It is so salutary in its effects
                            upon the soul who renders it, and so efficient a part of that system of education which
                            alone can ever qualify us for the kingdom which Christ says we may receive by becoming like
                            little children, that I have often thought it more profitable, and more conducive to true
                            manly dignity and independence, to render this fealty without reserve or limitation, even
                            though the requirement itself were trivial, or seemingly unjust. Childlike submission in us
                            is not a service given with all the blind trustfulness of childhood,—though it should be as
                            free and complete—but as being aware of th^ final result of such self-sacrifice, and the
                            result, on the other hand, of standing aloof, and choosing to maintain the rights of sham
                            dignity, and individuality of the man as he is in Adam, untouched, unscathed by the inner
                            warfare of Christ. Instead of abating from true manliness, the humility enjoined by the
                            gospel plan adds to it; and everywhere, at all times, we find real grandeur of character
                            allied with meekness and a simple deportment. But every meanness, every contemptible trait,
                            goes hand in hand with an arrogant, aggressive egotism, ever jealous of its own rights,
                            whether fancied or real, and ever forgetful of the fact that if we wish to be useful in
                            society, the most efficient means is not a clamorous, boisterous self assertion, but an
                            unassuming, quiet manner, resting ourselves upon our works, or upon the inherent truth of
                            our position, as our sole recommend. These will most effectually engage the consideration of
                            others, and their esteem. The rankest egotism is sometimes found under a false guise of
                            meekness, and patient endurance of slights and indignities, which have no existence, save in
                            the morbid imagination of the self afflicted person, who broods over them until he becomes
                            persuaded that he is being made a martyr. This conduct is owing, perhaps, to a deep seated
                            feeling, or sense, of the weight and importance of a quiet manner. But this is even more
                            despicable than an extremely demonstrative one. I suppose there are as many grades of
                            progress on the gospel journey as there are travelers. One will advance to a certain
                            position, another to a stage farther on, and still another takes a degree beyond this. Not-
                            withstanding it is said that we cannot be stationary, I think that by yielding to
                            indifference, we are exposed to the danger of becoming fixed, and fossilized; and a fossil
                            Shaker is not a very attractive character To me the gospel of Christ's second advent would
                            be pretty much a dead letter without that active, practical mortification of the old man
                            which brings all his being into subjection to some will besides his own, or to the supposed
                            will of a God afar off. This discipline, which to our own selves is so unwelcome, is the
                            source of great comfort to those who seek it. In common life how prone we are to shun every
                            occasion for this sort of experience, which if properly valued would be earnestly sought. It
                            stings a selfish pride to be brought under circumstances where we fancy we are making an
                            unfavorable impression upon others. If it be in doing an act, or saying a word which
                            actually raises us in the estimation of others, <pb n="12" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 12 SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            and involves the practice of humility, we ar apt to be ashamed of ourselves, while w would
                            not in doing an unworthy thing, i done in a striking, pompous manner. I certainly would not
                            be exempted fron this wholesome tuition, while all these inferi or motives lurk within.
                            Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of Eldress Polly J. Reed" TEIform="index"/>IN MEMORY OF ELDRESS POLLY J. REED</head><p TEIform="p">Though many voices join in praise, Too much cannot be given For one who spent her youthful
                            days, And all her life for heaven Not for a Heaven of peace and rest In which she would
                            repose With those, the justified and blest, When here the life doth close; But heaven for
                            every one she met While toiling o'er the road, . By kindness they could not forget, Which
                            lightened every load. She gave her all,— not small to give, Inheritance was great, In
                            virtues staunch by which to live And conquer fear and fate. A Christian's shield was hers,
                            the Truth Her motto and her dress; Disarmed by nothing of the earth, She moved to love and
                            bless. Not proud of talents, which were rare, But humble as a child To do her best, and
                            equal share, Content and reconciled. Parental love was rent, to give This Isaac of their
                            fold To God, for Christ's pure cause to live; Be their's a peace untold. And may all others
                            near akin Feel blest, and not in vain Their sacrificing unto Him, Their own, for Zion's
                            gain. Farewell, dear sister, in the Lord, Farewell in sweetest peace; On earth, "Well done,"
                            and thy reward Is joy to never cease. Canterbury, N. H. God and not self.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Circular letter" TEIform="index"/>CIRCULAR LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">Shaker Village, N. H. Dec. 20, 1881. Beloved Ministry :— On receiving the Dec. No. of the
                            "Manifesto ;" you will notice that the duties connected with the little paper have been
                            transferred from Witervliet to Canterbury. The acceptance of this burden has been only by
                            the urgent request of our Beloved Ministry of Mount Lebanon, through whom we expect to
                            receive the blessing of our God. This family would have preferred to have been excused from
                            an immediate connection with the paper, honestly thinking that the several societies would
                            be better pleased if it was under the direct management of Mt. Lebanon. In accepting this
                            onerous burden we shall ask the kind remembrance of all our beloved gospel friends, and
                            solicit your aid in assisting us to make the paper what Believers in general, would have it
                            to be. The positive value of the Manifesto must necessarily depend upon the value of the
                            contributions. They may be written upon Theology, Practical Religion, our Social Life, or
                            take any form of expression that meets the demands of the day, only allow them to be used as
                            the representatives of the several Societies. We are well aware that the paper must be
                            maintained by a careful cultivation of union, and shall hold ourselves as the ready
                            dispensers of any gifts that may be presented for publication. It has been the general
                            feeling among Believers to publish in each number a piece of Music. We would suggest that
                            this department also, shall represent every Society. As it is prefered that the hymns be set
                            to har- mony, we should wish to receive them in that form, carefully analyzed and corrected
                            for ;he press. Should it so happen, however, that any family having a hymn of good and
                            beautiful words, and finding themselves unable to arrange a harmony for the same, if they
                            will send the hymn to the—Editor of the Manifesto—we will, for the present, see that the
                            music is arranged and the contribution pubished. <pb n="13" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 13
                            We also propose to publish some of our best marches and select pieces, which are written
                            only as melodies. If our dear friends cannot furnish a hymn, they may be able to send us
                            some little gem of a march which will be sung with an inspiration wherever it is known. In
                            order to make the Manifesto interesting and instructive to the thousands of aged and
                            youthful readers, its contributions must appeal to their minds. This will be nothing new in
                            the order of its arrangement, as the several departments could not be changed for the
                            better. Elder Giles remarks :-—"It is suggested, to let the young people write very short
                            items of from one to eight and ten lines ; write and rewrite them, and show them to their
                            friends to be criticised and revised," and then send them to the Manifesto. With this
                            brotherly and sisterly considera" tion we hope to present a paper which will afford a
                            measure of satisfaction to those who so liberally help to sustain it, both with
                            contributions of matter, and with that of money. Remember us in your prayers, dear friends,
                            before God and before his angels. Accept our kindest love, Your brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>Henry C. Blinn</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good morning" TEIform="index"/>GOOD MORNING</head><p TEIform="p">Don't forget to say "Good-morning!'' Say it to your parents, your brothers and sisters, your
                            schoolmates, your teachers— and say it cheerfully, and with a smile; it will do you good,
                            and do your friends good. There's a kind inspiration in every "Good morning" heartily
                            spoken, that helps to make hope fresher and work lighter. It seems really to make the
                            morning good, and to be a prophecy of a good day to come after it. And if this be true of
                            the "good-morning,'' it is also of kind, heartsome greetings ; they cheer the discouraged,
                            rest the tired one, somehow make the wheels of life run more smoothly. Be liberal with them,
                            then, and let no morning pass, however dark and gloomy it may be, that you do not help at
                            least to brighten by your smiles and cheerful words.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Science Advocate contains the following excellent maxims" TEIform="index"/>The Science Advocate contains the following excellent maxims
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Science Advocate contains the following excellent maxims, alphabetically
                                    arranged, to facilitate their being memorized and being easily remembered. The world
                                    would be much better if both old and young would faithfully aim to follow these wise
                                    rules and regulate their conduct and intercourse with their fellow creatures
                                    accordingly. Attend carefully to the details of your business. Be prompt in all
                                    things. Consider well, then decide positively. Dare to do right; fear to do wrong.
                                    Endure trials patiently. Fight life's battles bravely and manfully. Go not into the
                                    society of the vicious. Hold integrity sacred. Injure not another's reputation or
                                    business. Join hands with the virtuous. Keep your mind free from evil thoughts. Lie
                                    not for any consideration. Make few intimate acquaintances. Never try to appear what
                                    you are not. Observe good manners. Pay your debts promptly. Question not the
                                    veracity of a friend. Respect the counsel of your parents. Sacrifice money rather
                                    than principle. Touch not, taste not. handle not intoxica- ting drinks. Use your
                                    leisure time for improvement. Yield not to discouragement. Zealously labor for the
                                    right. &amp; success will attend your faithful efforts. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Science advocate" TEIform="index"/>Science Advocate</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is to be regretted that singers, both in public and private..." TEIform="index"/>It is to be regretted that singers, both in public and private...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is to be regretted that singers, both in public and private, attend 140 little to that
                            most powerful letter of recommendation— the countenance ; for many who, in conversation, are
                            agreeable and animated, no sooner begin to sing than they resemble figures whose mouths,
                            pulled open at pleasure by a string, emit sounds, which, though ever so mellifluous, lose
                            their effect by issuing from such automaton organs. Others, on the contrary, in their desire
                            to avoid the charge of insipidity, so painfully distort their features that they render
                            themselves objects of ridicule or pity. However charmed we may be by a good voice, the eye,
                            as well as the ear, requires to be pleased; and we insensibly become fatigued and
                            discontented when the countenance and demeanor do not in some degree accord with the subject
                            to which we may be listening.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guilmette, C. A." TEIform="persName"/>C. A. Guilmette</byline></div2><pb n="14" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker manifesto. Change of Office of Publication..." TEIform="index"/>SHAKER, MANIFESTO
                            Change of Office of Publication</head><p TEIform="p">The "Shaker Manifesto" for the presen will be published at Shaker Village, N. tl All business
                            matters connected with the fi nancial department of the paper will be di rected to the,—
                            Publisher of Manifesto, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. All other communications may be ad
                            dressed, Editor of Manifesto, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., K". H. One Copy per. year, Postage
                            paid, .60 " " six months, " " .35 Enclose a two cent stamp for a specimen copy. To avoid
                            mistakes, those who send money, should write the name of their Post Office, County and
                            State. TO ADVERTISERS. One inch, one insertion $ 1.00 " " three " each .75 " " six " " .65 "
                            " twelve " " .50 " column ----- --------6.00 Larger spaces, in proportion, at same
                        rates.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year" TEIform="index"/>The New Year</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Beloved Friends :—With the present number of the Manifesto, commences Volume twelve. To all
                            of its readers, to those who may contribute to its columns, as well as t:. that great
                            company who have never seen nor even heard of it, we wish a happy, peaceful and prosperous
                            new year. Many dear friends who are richly rown,ed with years of gospel experience, The
                            mission of the paper from its beginning to this date has been fully presented to its readers
                            by those who have made themselves interested in its publication . As the Manifesto is
                            expected to be a fair exponent of the spirit of the several communities of Believers, we
                            shall solicit, in all kindness, a continuance of interest on every subject worthy of a place
                            in its columns. The paper is for the better advancement of truth as understood by the
                            Shakers and to this end we write or speak to those who are not of our order. The practical
                            manifestation of this, ultimately, must be through our very life purposes, if it is expected
                            to work for the salvation of one or more individuals. In this age of free thought, free
                            speech and independent action, every church and every phase of church discipline must pass
                            through the ordeal of a critical examination. This crucial test will place before the world
                            the beauties, as well as the ad- vantages of a life of self-denial, or better a life of
                            Christ. The principle which worked such wonders in a past age for the Christians, when it
                            was generally conceded that "might is right," las been pretty thoroughly exploded. Whoever
                            wins the confidence and respect of his fpllow man at the present day, must stand
                            pre-eminently above his ellows in the representation of practical ighteousness. If we pray,
                            let the prayer carry our inspirations up to God, and if we preach, et us watch over our own
                            lives and see f we practice as we preach. <pb n="15" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 15 suggest
                            that every number should have one or two articles bearing directly upon the Covenantal and
                            spiritual life of the order. The subject is as beautiful as is that of the wells of
                            salvation "whose waters are springing up unto everlasting life." We hope to be the happy
                            recipients of these papers as our covenantal relations should occupy an exalted place in our
                            minds, and a growing interest should be manifested in its sacred maintainance. Those who are
                            gifted with this divine blessing will no doubt contribute liberally to this department. In
                            making preparations for the issue of this first No. of the Manifesto, we cast about,
                            somewhat, as prudent calculators may do by taking account of stock on hand. This enables us
                            to draw reli- able conclusions as to what we may safely carry forward into the New Year, and
                            what must be left behind. To brighten our hopes for the future, comes, appreciated among our
                            valuables, the brotherly love of our former Editor, in expressions of kind regards. One
                            writer remarks that words, in the place of works, are as leaves, dry, tasteless and
                            meaningless. Fortunately, we are not left to know this fruitless condition as the article
                            which so kindly came, in due season, will most readily attest. All this is God's blessing to
                            us and we ask its continuance through time. We gratefully acknowledge the receipt of Ten
                            Dollars, from our friend HERMAN Mullek of Cincinnati, Ohio,—as an aid in publishing the
                            "Manifesto." May those who read this, be induced to go and do likewise.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Basseterre, St. Kitts,  B. West Indies, September 29,                                     1881" TEIform="index"/>Basseterre, St. Kitts, B. West Indies, Sept. 29, 1881</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Brails, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Eespected Friend :—I offer no apology for
                                troubling you with a letter, as I think the subject will interest you, and, it may be,
                                give hope of better days for your principles Some ten years ago I left Glasgow for
                                health. Came here, as I had an interest in a brother's business, General Store. I was a
                                member of the society of Friends, or Quakers, in Scotland. I knew from books that George
                                Fox and other early Friends, had made extensive tours in all these Islands. So, one day
                                when in the neighboring island of Nevis. I was told of a sect called "Xoahites," or
                                Shakers, or Quakers. They were everywhere spoken against, railed at and despised. I
                                found that their meeting was the last vestige of Friends in the West Indies. After some
                                trouble I learned that somewhere about 1665, three persons of the sect called Quakers
                                came to Nevis, where they found a friendly reception in the house of one, Humphrey
                                Highwood, who, not long after was cited to appear before the Governor for breaking a
                                law, enjoining formal notice of the arrival of all strangers after a given time. For
                                this undesigned omission flighwood was committed to prison; but eventually the Quakers
                                managed to obtain a firm footing in that part of the island called the Lowlands. There
                                is found evidence of their last resting place in some few stones on which is marked name
                                and date of death. A daughter of the then Governor Lake is interred in the same place.
                                So they had made converts. I rode out to Colton Grounds, but could not see any of thje
                                men connected with the meeting, but I went out the next First Day, and found the
                                leaderHe was only known as Captain Frederick; from him I learned that the meeting had
                                been a long, long time held. He said he had been a slave, as all his people had been ;
                                they had always belonged to the meeting, but the meeting was almost dead—no life, no
                                nothing. He was an old man, fully 75 years of age. So that 1 am only giving you an
                                outline of what he said. About 1838, a man named Noah, who had been brought up in <pb n="16" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. meeting, came back from America, where he had
                                been for some years, and with joy, old Fred said, he brought life to the meeting. He
                                brought marching, singing, dancing and clapping of hands, and the meeting began to live.
                                My visit was early in 72. I found the Meeting House had been swept away by the hurricane
                                of the previous August. I may say in passing, it ruined nearly all these islands.
                                However, they met in the house of one of the members—the largest house in the place. As
                                meeting did not begin until 3 p. m., I called at the house of the manager of the estate
                                where the meeting was to be held, had dinner, and heard some strange stories of the
                                Noahites. As he had never been at their meetings, he came with me When we got to the
                                place, I found that everything had been taken out of the cabin, or hut, except one chair
                                for Frederick. He took his place and around the walls the women ranged themselves ;
                                before them, all round a second row, low enough to let the back see over them. Frederick
                                engaged in prayer, and all joined in repeating the Lord's Prayer. Many hymns were
                                sung—time being kept by all clapping hands and also beating with their feet, until, by
                                and bye, they got excited, and their springs and jumping, all in good time, became
                                general. There were fully one hundred joining in the worship outside. This continued for
                                fully two hours, when I had to tell Captain Fred, 1 had to ride into town and must go.
                                They stopped and I had a few words to say to them. I said I had no doubt the meeting had
                                once been a Quaker's but how strangely changed, when the old man touched me on the
                                shoulder, saying: same spirit, Massa, different manifestation. What could I say against
                                that? and if the new manifestation brought life and joy to them, it was not given to me
                                to speak against it. I parted with them in much love I am prepared to say, that,
                                although spoken against they are the best people in Nevis. Their creed consists of very
                                few articles : 1. No pay for preach. I give it in their own words. 2. No debt—owe no man
                                anything. 3. No smoking; no strong drink; no perfume. 4. No gaudy dress, no going to
                                law; live in peace. I asked Captain Fred, how the young people kept the laws. He said,
                                better than expected. Some did smoke. He thought on the whole that the old times and
                                folks were better than the present. I made inquiry all round but could find no proof of
                                immorality among them. I arrived in this island a few weeks ago. My old friends in Nevis
                                heard of my arrival, and Josiah Lawrence, the present head of the meeting, came over to
                                see me. From him I learned that old Captain Frederick died in 1875, aged about 90; that
                                the meeting is growing, having now fully two hundred people attending. Not all members,
                                but all worshipers or inquirers. I found they are in sad straits for want of a meeting
                                house. As few of them can read and fewer still write, I am at a loss what to do for
                                them. To send them a lot of Quaker tracts is out of the question. So, dear friend, as
                                everyone is my friend who has a kindly word for his neighbor, if you, or any of the
                                brethren should see the way clear to send a few tracts—the plainer the better—I do think
                                some good might be done. I say honestly that the reason why they are everywhere spoken
                                against is because they won't "pay for preach." The Methodists and Moravians, indeed
                                all, must live by their trade, and if the poor people refuse to "pay for preach," as
                                they expressively put it, then the preaching business is done. Josiah Lawrence, Colton
                                Grounds, Lowlands, Nevis, B. West Indies, will reach him, but he bitterly complained
                                that some works which I sent him were never delivered to them. You can form no idea of
                                the state of matters in these islands. The black, or colored man is looked upon as a
                                beast, and let me say, by beasts. Strong drink and lust are the two curses of the world,
                                but here, immorality reigns triumphant. Base things are no longer base, or vile things
                                vile. I admit that a morality easy enough in a cold country, is to the great mass
                                impossible here. Good rum (if any of it can be called good) is 12 cents per bottle, so
                                that people can get the worse for liquor on one cent. If the end of this age does not
                                soon 16 <pb n="17" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 17 come, then this fair portion of God's
                                earth will be the Devil's, as this is Hell. Thy friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McNish, James" TEIform="persName"/>James McNish</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brookline, December 1881" TEIform="index"/>Brookline, Dec—1881</head><p TEIform="p">Elder H.— Dear Friend :— Herewith the Book on the "History, Doctrine and Discipline" of
                                your Community is returned with my hearty thanks. It has been read with much interest
                                and sympathy; and a most sincere respect for the pure heartedness, spiritual elevation,
                                earnest devotedness, fidelity and consecration of the chief Foundress of your Order,
                                "Mother Ann" was assuredly, in the best sense, a saint of singular truthfulness,
                                integrity and zeal. It seems to me that your body of Christian s have a great work of
                                Reform still to do, in the teaching, illustrating and exemplifying these three Grand
                                Truths. I. That every human being should be a Holy Temple for the Divine Indwelling; and
                                that every form and degree of Impurity unfits us to be worthy dwelling places for the
                                spirit of Holiness. With this grand Central Truth are connected two others :—First, That
                                life is a sacred gift from the Living God; and that the act of transmitting life,
                                through Parentage can never be desecrated by any mode of impurity, without outraging the
                                Holiness of God,—and Second, That the laws of Perfect Purity is precisely the same and
                                equally binding for man as for woman. II. The Second Truth entrusted to your keeping,
                                for you to expound and explain is that the True Law of life for every Christian
                                community, is the fraternal and sisterly law of co-operation, self-sacrifice, mutual
                                honor and humane helpfulness. Your work has but begun in that direction ; and the on
                                looking world will rejoice in your success, so far as you can prove the soundness of
                                your principle, by your enlarged prosperity. III. The Third Truth committed to your
                                charge and of which you should be the missionaries is ; that every Church of the Beloved
                                Son, which took little children in his arms and blessed them, saying "if such is the
                                kingdom of Heaven"—should stand in the place of parent to all the Towns around it,— in
                                the spirit of Universal Adoption. Your Homes, your Schools, your Societies, should give
                                models to the world of the highest possible training, discipline and culture, physical,
                                industrial, social, moral, intellectual and spiritual. Your Villages should be, each of
                                them a true Paradise regained, the abode of Purity, Harmony, Love, Peace and Joy, for
                                all its young people, thus help to spread the reign of Heaven upon Earth. It gave me
                                great pleasure to meet you and your sisters and brother, and the interview will be long
                                remembered. With hearty benedictions, I am your friend.— </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. C.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DEATHS</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sears, Chauncy" TEIform="index"/>Chauncy Sears
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Sears, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>, sen. at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
                                    Oct. 22, 1881. Age, 79 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reed, Polly J." TEIform="index"/>Eldress Polly J. Reed
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Reed, Polly J." TEIform="persName">Eldress Polly J. Reed</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon, N.
                                    Y. Nov. 25, 1881. Age, 63 yrs, 10 mo. and 23 days. (See pp. 5 &amp; 12.)</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lane, Phebe" TEIform="index"/>Phebe Lane
                                </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Lane, Phebe" TEIform="persName">Phebe Lane</persName>, (colored,) at Shakers, N. Y. Dec.
                                    10, 1881. Age 93 years. She had been a Shaker for 73 years,—and a good one too.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>Juvenile</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Catching sunshine" TEIform="index"/>CATCHKG Sl'XSHKE</head><p TEIform="p">My next door neighbor's little girl, A cunning two-year old, Wondered one day why drooped
                                her flowers, And pleaded to be told. Then said her mamma :—"Here-in-doors The sunshine
                                does n't come To warm and bless and gladden them And drive away their gloom. And so they
                                droop, as children do Who get no tender love To cheer them on that upward way Whereon we
                                all must move." <pb n="18" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 18 SHAKER MANIFESTO. Next day, when mamma went to
                                seek Her darling at her play, She found her standing in the sun In just the queerest way
                                : For there she held aloft a cup Above her pretty head, 'What are you doing, LuLu dear?"
                                Mamma, astonished, said. And she, her cup still held aloft— Bless her, ye heavenly
                                powers ! "I'm catching sunshine, mamma dear, To give my 'ittle f'owers." Type of all
                                children there was she; Who in life's garden stand, Still holding patiently aloft Their
                                life cups in their hand. And so the world is kept alive, And freshened every minute, By
                                the dear grace that overflows The children who are in it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anon" TEIform="persName"/>Anon</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boys we need" TEIform="index"/>THE BOYS WE NEED</head><p TEIform="p">Here's to the boy who's not afraid To do his share of work; Who never is by toil
                                dismayed, And never tries to shirk. The boy whose heart is brave to meet The lions in
                                the way; Who's not discouraged by defeat, But tries another day. The boy who always
                                means to do The very best he can; Who always keeps the right in view, And aims to be a
                                man. Such boys as these will grow to be The men whose hands will guide The future of our
                                land; and we Shall speak their names with pride. All honor to the boy who is A man at
                                heart, I say; Whose legend on his shield is this : "Right always wins the day."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rexford, E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. Rexford</byline></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little mouse saw a fine piece  of cheese in a trap..." TEIform="index"/>A little mouse saw a fine piece  of cheese in a trap...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little mouse saw a fine piece of cheese in a trap. "How good it looks !" he said. "I
                                guess I'll just taste it, and take the rest home to my sick little sister." Just then,
                                his eldest brother ran into the room. "It's mine," cried he, running toward the trap.
                                "You shall not have any of it. I want it all for myself " He took a bite, the trap
                                snapped, and he was killed. Moral—Selfish little boys and girls don't get caught in
                                traps, but they often get into a great deal of trouble.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Churchman" TEIform="persName"/>Churchman. </byline></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><p TEIform="p">As the youth and children in our several Societies are occasionally -writing and
                                receiving letters, we propose to insert some of those deemed most suitable in this
                                department, for the benefit and encouragement of all interested.</p><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Canaan, N. Y. December 1881" TEIform="index"/>Canaan, N. Y. Dec. 1881</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Sister L. ;—I received your little missive on the 14th. inst. which was very
                                    acceptable. You speak of its being a task for you to discipline yourself to a
                                    perfection in penmanship and letter writing. I agree with you in this, although as I
                                    practice I find that it becomes much easier. This afternoon a large number of the
                                    brethren and sisters are attending the funeral of an aged sister at another family,
                                    one whose death impressed my mind with the importance of so living, that I shall not
                                    fear to meet my reward when the angel Reaper shall call my spirit to its final home.
                                    She was well beloved by all who knew her, for she had been a faithful Christian for
                                    many years and was fully prepared to make the change. I rejoice that m\ lot has been
                                    cast with the faithful followers of Christ, and I am resolved to stand flrm in the
                                    faith that calls me to a life of purity and self-denial, to sacrifice selfish
                                    inclinations for the good and happiness of others. — There is a high wind today and
                                    it is exceedingly cold. But what matters the weather without? If true Christian love
                                    reigns in <pb n="19" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER MANIFESTO. 19 our hearts it will be all
                                    cheerful and pleasant within. Please accept my love with that of all my dear
                                    companions, and thank Sister A. for the proposition she made for you to address me.
                                    I should be pleased to hear from you again. Affectionately, Your Sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., E. E." TEIform="persName"/>E. E. H.</byline></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, December 1881" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, Dec. 1881</head><p TEIform="p">Our Precious H :— My mind was drawn to you this morning while thinking of my dear
                                    young brethren and sisters, in whose midst memory lingers as 'mid a garden of
                                    beautiful flowers, the tiniest of which bears marks of the careful cultivator. Ah
                                    H.,—let us bear in mind that it is the discipline and pruning of the Christian work
                                    which makes good manners, good morals, and the symetrical character. So be encoured
                                    my dear sister, aim high, we will climb together the rugged hill of life, and enjoy
                                    together the sweet peace and happiness which flows from a pure well disciplined
                                    mind. When we feel dissatisfied with our gains, or think we are making slow progress
                                    toward the heavenly kingdom, let us turn our minds to doing something for others,
                                    loving and preferring them to ourselves; thus by scattering joy and sunshine on all
                                    around us, we shall increase our own treasure. Though the gain may be imperceptible
                                    for a long time, it is nevertheless, sure. What we sow, we shall reap. This reminds
                                    me of beloved Eldress A's word,—that we must "never begin anything that we shall
                                    have to leave otf." What an excellent text for the New Year! What an amount of
                                    unnecessary trouble and work we should save ourselves, did we but bear it in mind.
                                    You see I take the liberty to write freely, and why not, since love prompts the act.
                                    To wish you a "Merry Christmas," or a "Happy New Year," seems like the repetition of
                                    a time worn phrase, or an echo of the real happiness which I trust may be yours. I
                                    covet for you the best gifts,—the cheerfulness which wells up continually from a
                                    pure spirit, like the ripples of the laughing brook, reflecting the radiance of
                                    virgin sweetness on all within the circle of your influence. May the happiness be
                                    yours which obedience to faith and conviction are sure to bring. Finally, be true to
                                    your own soul, and to God ; and your cup of blessing will be filled to overflowing.
                                    You will feel the love and companionship of the good and true, which is, really, all
                                    the friendship worth having. Now H.,—as an older sister, let me advise you to be
                                    careful of your health, you have a kind heart, but once deprived of this blessing,
                                    you may know a sorrow you cannot now imagine. In all your gains, your joys, or your
                                    sorrows I am with you, and whatever tends to your prosperity, adds to my happiness.
                                    With this assurance, I remain, Your loving sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="C., M. M." TEIform="persName"/>M. M. C.</byline></div4><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, Mer. County, N. H." TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, Mer. County, N.
                                    H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Sister S. ;—I shall be very happy while I am writing to you. I would like you to
                                    please answer this letter. I have a good deal to do today. I am going to meeting,
                                    and I am going to study my Scripture lesson. I love the Sabbath day. I mean to be a
                                    good, obedient girl. I kindly thank you for taking care of me. I have been to
                                    meeting and it was very nice. I did not speak, but I wish I .had. What should you
                                    think to have a little girl eight years old speak in meeting? Shall I tell you I
                                    have just looked at the Time Table? I am going to have a nice time tomorrow if I am
                                    a good girl. My teacher says so. I hope I will. I shall tell you all about it
                                    sometime. Most all of the girls are writing today. I am sorry I did not help you
                                    wash the dishes this morning, I will next time, so good bye. From your little girl,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., L" TEIform="persName"/>L. D.</byline></div4></div3></div2><pb n="20" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House-hold</head><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things to be remembered" TEIform="index"/>THINGS TO BE REMEMBERED</head><p TEIform="p">Remember that tea should not be infused for more than seven minutes. Have the water
                                boiling and use a teaspoonful of tea for each person and one over. Put the tea in the
                                pot and pour the boiling water over it, and let it stand for seven minutes. If it is
                                allowed to stand the tannin in the tea is drawn out and dyspepsia is the result.
                                Remember that mirrors should never be hung where the sun shines directly upon them. They
                                soon look misty, grow rough or granulated, and no longer give back a correct picture.
                                The amalgam or union of tinfoil with mercury, which is spread on glass to form a
                                looking-glass, is easily ruined by the direct, continuous exposure to the solar rays.
                                Remember that lemons can be kept sweet and fresh lor months by putting them into a
                                tight, clean cask or jar, and covering with cold water. The water must be changed as
                                often as once every other day, and the cask kept in a cool place. Remember that a
                                teaspoonful of black pepper will prevent grey or buff linen from spotting, if stirred
                                into the first water in which they are washed. It will also prevent the colors running,
                                when washing black or colored cambrics or muslins, and the water is not injured by it,
                                but just as soft as before the pepper was put in. Remember that one can have the hands
                                in soapsuds with soft soap without injury to the skin if the hands are dipped in vinegar
                                or lemon juice immediately after. The acids destroy the corrosive effects of the alkali
                                and make the hands soft and white. Indian meal and vinegar or lemon juice used on hands
                                when roughed by cold or labor, will heal and soften them. Rub the hands in this; then
                                wash off throughly and rub in glycerine. Those who suffer from chapped hands will find
                                this comforting.—Maiden Mirror.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you want to retain a healthy voice..." TEIform="index"/>If you want to retain a healthy voice...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If you want to retain a healthy voice, never keep the neck tightly and closely covered.
                                Let the air circulate freely around it, in or- der that the skin may become as hard as
                                possible ; for such is the natural effect of exposing even delicate tissues to the air,
                                as might be illustrated by numerous cases in surgery.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guilmette, C. A." TEIform="persName"/>C. A. Guilmette, M. D.</byline></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pork versus ethics" TEIform="index"/>Pork versus ethics
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hanaford, J. H." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">From Dr. Foot's Health Monthly. PORK versus ETHICS. By Dr. J. H. Haxaford. Is
                                        it right to eat and drink as a depraved appetite may suggest? I claim that no
                                        Christian, certainly, has a right to be a glutton, or a winebibber, eating pork,
                                        or any article forbidden in the scriptures, any more than he has to lie, swear,
                                        or steal. This will seem evident from the command; "Whether ye eat or drink, or
                                        whatsoever ye do, do all to the glory of God." This is a good illustration of
                                        the "higher law" and must seem strange to those who disregard Lev. II, 7,
                                        &amp; 8, and other similar passages. Is it said that such were intended for
                                        the Jews? I suppose so, but not for them only, any more than the ten
                                        commandments, or any more than the epistle to the Romans was intended for the
                                        disciples at Rome only. I suppose that the whole Bible was intended for the
                                        whole world, and equally obligatory on Jews and Gentiles. I suppose that the
                                        moral laws relating to the diet, cleanliness &amp;c, had sanitary
                                        applications and relations, on the principle that the soul is reached through
                                        the body, measurably, that physical soundness and purity are necessary
                                        conditions and aids to the moral growth. That pork is among the most corrupt and
                                        diseased of all meats, no intelligent person will deny, and that it is so
                                        difficult of digestion that few, if any, can use it with impuni- ty, is equally
                                        certain. As such, it is unfit for human food, while the wild beast scavengers,
                                        unless driven almost to desperation by hunger, will not devour the dead hog! The
                                        Jew, as a part of his religion, avoids pork as we do profanity and falsehood,
                                        and this fact we should infer from his personal appearance and physical purity.
                                        He is free from the taint of scrofula, cancer, and "hu- mors" in general, while
                                        the female is as "fair as a Jewess." These are significant facts, and give force
                                        to the Divine command, and well illustrate its moral appropriateness. <pb n="21" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> Dr. Gibson, of England, medical officer, states "there is no
                                        doubt that a Jew's life in London is worth twice as many years as a
                                        Christian's." The medical officer of one of their large schools has remarked
                                        that their children do not die in any thing like the ratio as the Gentile
                                        children; and, in the district of White Chapel, the officer has reported that on
                                        the north side of High St., occupied by the Jews, the death rate is 20 per,
                                        cent, while on the south side, occupied by English and Irish, it is 45, per
                                        cent, per 1,000." This startling fact must find its explanation in the physical
                                        condition and habits of these people.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Dr. Foot's health monthly" TEIform="index"/>Dr. Foot's health monthly
                                    </bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Death in iced drinks" TEIform="index"/>DEATH IN ICED DRINKS</head><p TEIform="p">The story of the sudden death in Canton, O., of the "healthy young tinner" who drank
                                ice-cold beer, is a warning to men, women and children who swallow tumblerfuls of
                                ice-water on every occasion. No one who reflects for a moment can but believe that the
                                introduction of zero frost into the body is dangerous as well as unhealthy. It was not
                                the beer that killed; it was the ice that paralyzed the stomach, and before the beer
                                became of a proper temperature for absorption into the system it fermented, causing a
                                gas that overpowered the heart, lungs and brain and produced death. People drinking
                                ice-cold water, or rapidly eating anything of an ice-cold nature, must be careful that
                                they have not eaten just be- fore material capable, of fermentation. Our candid opinion
                                is that the general habit among Americans of drinking ice-cold fluids is the cause of
                                dyspepsia and other diseases that so generally prevail in this country. We know that
                                until this habit was introduced into Paris by Americans living there dyspepsia was
                                unknown to Frenchmen. New York Commercial.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you cannot lay the foundation, it is something to pull down error..." TEIform="index"/>If you cannot lay the foundation, it is something to pull down error...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If you cannot lay the foundation, it is something to pull down error. ... If I am in the
                                wrong, my errors may set the minds of men to work, and may be the means of bringing both
                                them and me to acknowledge the truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Macaulay" TEIform="persName"/>Macaulay</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Milking machines" TEIform="index"/>MILKING MACHINES</head><p TEIform="p">In answer to an inquiry, the American Cultivator replies that many attempts have been
                                made to construct machines by which the milk could be drawn from the cow's bag with the
                                same facility and completeness as it could be drawn by hand; but so far as our knoAvl-
                                edge and observation extend, without any practical success. It is supposed by many that
                                the milk is retained in the cow's bag through atmospheric pressure alone ; which,
                                however, is not true, since the cow is able to control this flow to a great extent. If
                                the cow dislikes the person employed milking, or his manner of drawing the milk, she
                                will not only refuse to let down the fluid, but by per- sisting in the effort, will soon
                                dry up the supply. The udder of the cow is composed not only of a bundle of milk veins,
                                but also of nerves. The aperture in the teat of the cow varies in size with each animal
                                milked. In the case of some cows this aperture is large and the milk can be drawn away
                                very rapidly, while in other cows the aperture was small, and any attempt to draw the
                                milk from this latter class of cows as rapidly as from the former will be attended with
                                much pain on the part of the abused animal, and a determination on her part to hold back
                                the milk. This defect in the size of the aperture of the cow's teat is one which no
                                machine can detect, but one which the human hand readily observes. Immediately upon its
                                discovery the humane milker relaxes his efforts in forcing away the milk. It is the
                                smallness of this aperture which stamps the cow as a hard milker. The observant dairyman
                                soon learns that when he draws too hard the milk passes back to the bag. In such a case
                                his efforts must be so relaxed that the milk will come away easily though slowly. Again,
                                when there is inflamation in the cow's udder, the careful milker readily detects it, and
                                as quickly sets about with measures to reduce the inflamation and relieve the cow. By
                                the use of no machine could such a difficulty be detected and serious consequences might
                                be the result of machine milking. A great many bags would be per<pb n="22" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 22
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. manently ruined and many cows die of milk fever, which would be saved
                                to the owner where milking by hand prevails. It is observed that men have not become
                                better artisans since the introduction of machinery. Managers and overseers may now
                                under- stand better the nature of the article manufactured, the raw material used and
                                the nature of the machine employed than was the case formerly, but the rank and file—the
                                class of men who to-day operate the machines, and who, before machines were invented,
                                did the work by hand—these men understood the nature of the material upon which they
                                worked better in former times than they do now. And so, in this connection, he who has
                                to milk a cow, and do it well and properly, should know at least the character and
                                construction of the cow's bag.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Handle dairy stock kindly" TEIform="index"/>HANDLE DAIRY STOCK KINDLY</head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Parcell, in the report of the New Jersey Agricultural Society, says : It is important
                                that dairy stock, from the young calf to the old cow, that is being fed for beef, should
                                be handled and treated kindly. If a calf is handled roughly and becomes wild and vicious
                                thereby, when it becomes a cow you may expect the same, but if handled carefully and
                                treated with kindness, when grown up she will be mild and gentle. It may not always be
                                so, but in general it is. There have always been many cows spoiled by the person having
                                the care of and milking them, by whipping or frightening them whenever they come in his
                                way, or if when milking, a cow hoists her foot or kicks (which is generally caused by
                                pain,) such a fellow stops milking and commences whipping, or worse, kicking the cow,
                                and she becoming enraged, holds up her milk, kicks back, and is finally ruined. Never
                                whip a cow for kicking, if she does kick the milk-pail out of your hand and sometimes
                                upset and knock you over ; but be kind and gentle with her, and milk her out with as
                                little excitement as possible, and if she gets over her kicking propensity, it will be
                                by mild not harsh treatment Never whip a cow because she kicks, for it will do no good,
                                but will do a great deal of harm.—Exchange.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A grape vine growing upon a ranch near San Diego, California..." TEIform="index"/>A grape vine growing upon a ranch near San Diego, California...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A grape vine growing upon a ranch near San Diego, Cal., has attained to such gigantic
                                proportions that it has prostrated an oak tree to which it clung. The tree was perfectly
                                sound and measured two and a-half feet in diameter and sixty feet in height, yet the
                                vine has torn it bodily from the ground. This immense creeper covers several hundred
                                square yards and the yield of fruit is prodigious. The owner declares that from the part
                                of the vine which ruined the tree fully five tons of grapes were gathered.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Select</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every one pleased" TEIform="index"/>EVERY ONE PLEASED</head><p TEIform="p">Some time since, Parson M—of Mass, (then a British colony,) being at Boston, bought him a
                                wig, and returning home, wore it at church the next sabbath. As a wig of such a size and
                                shape was quite a novelty in that obscure place, it gave offence to almost the whole
                                congregation, who, both men and women, repaired the next day to their minister's house,
                                and stated their complaint, the burden of which was, that the wig was one of the Boston
                                notions, and had the look of fashion and pride. The good natured minister, thereupon,
                                brought it forth, and bade them fashion it to their own liking. This task they set about
                                in good earnest, and with the help of scissors, chopped off lock after lock, till at
                                last they all declared themselves satisfied—save one,—who alleged that wearing a wig at
                                all, was in his opinion, a breach of the commandment, which saith, "Thou shalt not make
                                unto thee any graven image, or any likeness of anything that is in heaven above, or that
                                is in the earth be- neath." This last objector was soon silenced by convincing him that
                                the wig in its present condition, did not resemble anything either above or below. Even
                                so fares it with the characters that make it their aim to please everybody. Slashed on
                                this side and on that, and twisted into every shape, and out of all shape, they finally
                                come to the condition of his reverence's wig.—Brief Remarker.</p></div3><pb n="23" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angels' visits" TEIform="index"/>ANGELS' VISITS</head><p TEIform="p">Robert Collyer says that Angels' visits are neither few nor far between, and tells how
                                the death of his mother, who was far away, was told to him abont the time of its
                                occurrence. "Men laugh," he says, "and say that we live in a prosy, railroad world, in
                                which the telegraph outflies the old-fashioned angel. But it is not true that angels
                                don't care for us—it's we who do not look for them after they have come to visit us. All
                                the angel that we care to look for is a Michael Angelo angel. But all common human
                                agencies are touched with angelic power, while we are like children, who breathe on the
                                window pane and shut the beautiful landscape out behind a dull cloud. The angels are all
                                about us, though, and they ascend and descend upon humanity. Bad as any man may be, he
                                has angels to minister to him. And when a bad man sinks down and down, and will not
                                listen to the sweeter voices of ascending angels, then come the terrible shapes of
                                descending angels, that do save him in the end." Golden Era.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some travelers in South America..." TEIform="index"/>Some travelers in South America...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Some travelers in South America, in traveling an arid and desolate tract of country, were
                                struck with a strange contrast. On one side there was a barren desert, on the other a
                                rich and luxuriant vegetation. The French consul at Loreto, Mexico, says that this
                                remarkable contrast is due to the presence of the Tamai caspi, or the rain tree. This
                                tree grows to the height of sixty feet with a diameter of three feet at its base, and
                                possesses the power of strongly attracting, absorbing and condensing the humidity of the
                                atmosphere. Water is always to be seen dripping form its trunk in such quantity as to
                                convert the surrounding soil into a veritable marsh. It is in the summer especially,
                                when the rivers are nearly dried up, that the tree is most active. If this admirable
                                quality of the rain tree were utilized in the arid regions near the equator, the people
                                there, living in misery on account of the unproductive soil, would derive great
                                advantages from its introduction, as well of the people of more favored countries where
                                the climate is dry and drouths frequent.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Did the prophet Isaiah ever eat at a railroad  station?..." TEIform="index"/>Did the prophet Isaiah ever eat at a railroad  station?...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Did the prophet Isaiah ever eat at a railroad station? It certainly looks so,
                                        for how could he have described it so liberally if he had not? "And he shall
                                        snatch on the right hand and be hungry; and he shall eat on the left hand, and
                                        they shall not be satisfied."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Congregationalist" TEIform="index"/>Congregationalist</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A brother arose in a weekly prayer meeting in New Jersey and said..." TEIform="index"/>A brother arose in a weekly prayer meeting in New Jersey and said...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A brother arose in a weekly prayer meeting in New Jersey and said: "Brethren,
                                        when I consider the shortness of life, I feel as if I might be taken away
                                        suddenly, like a thief in the night."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York star" TEIform="index"/>New York Star</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Now,' said the teacher in a primary class to one of  his pupils..." TEIform="index"/>Now,' said the teacher in a primary class to one of  his pupils...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Now," said the teacher in a primary class to one of his pupils, to whom he was trying to
                                impart a knowledge of division, but with little success, "if you had a pie, and I should
                                ask you for a quarter of it, and you should give me what I wanted, how much would you
                                have left?" "I wouldn't have any left!" quickly responded the little girl, who seemed to
                                think that the teacher's wants were by no means small.Yonkers Statesman.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is said that a respectable tradesman of the name of 'G. Sharp'..." TEIform="index"/>It is said that a respectable tradesman of the name of 'G. Sharp'...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is said that a respectable tradesman of the name of "G. Sharp" was astonished one
                                morning to find that some one had added to his name the words, "is A flat" which,
                                however, correct in a musical sense, was certainly far from complimentary to the worthy
                                tradesman. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man who talks everlastingly and promiscuously..." TEIform="index"/>The man who talks everlastingly and promiscuously...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The man who talks everlastingly and promiscuously, who seems to have an exhaustless
                                magazine of sound, crowds so many words into his thoughts that he always obscures and
                                frequently conceals them. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Irving, Washington" TEIform="persName"/>Washington Irving. </byline></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lying is like trying to hide in a fog..." TEIform="index"/>Lying is like trying to hide in a fog...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Lying is like trying to hide in a fog; If you move about you are in danger of bumping
                                your head against the truth ; as soon as the fog blows up, you are gone anyhow.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who have few affairs..." TEIform="index"/>Those who have few affairs...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Those who have few affairs to attend to are great speakers. The less men think the more
                                they talk.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Montesquieu" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3></div2><pb n="24" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">Canterbury, N. H. 1. O, Father, to Thy throne we come, In attitude of prayer, 2. O,
                            bless us with a fervent zeal, To know and do thy will; Our hearts petitioning Thy grace,
                            Thy With more abundant righteousness Our care, fill: We That ask for pow er to
                            control The elements of earth; we may walk with purpose fix'd The path way of the pure
                            ; For wisdom, to expand the soul Unto the higher birth. Fulfilling all the law of
                            grace, Thy favor to insure. guidance, love, and under standings</p></div2><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>