<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0502" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18750201" TEIform="date">February 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">9-16</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="9" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. No. 2. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. ~r~,™~ Sixty Cents Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co.. N. Y. February, 187o.
                        PERANNUM.</p><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorial correspondence" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL CORRESPONDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Tribune : Will you publish a paper in response to two remarkable editorials, " Katie King," of the
                            Tribune, and " How to investigate Spiritualism," in the Scientific American, of even date ? The Shaker Order has
                            " business relations with the outlying world, with which your Railroads, Steamboats and Telegraphs do not
                            connect."—Will you give the (Shakers a voice ? Spiritualism and Geology are Sciences— Not Religions. The Shakers
                            have studied Spiritualism, for a century, and put it to the practical uses of life. We have been patiently
                            waiting for your over-wise people, to become scientific enough to hear and investigate its facts — to prove all
                            things, Spiritualism included. We came to New York, to help you, and the press received us liberally — gave good
                            notice of our Stein way Hall Meetings, of Nov. 22. But the Reporters, with the exception of the Tribune and
                            Republic, utterly failed to tell the truth, or to refrain from gross misrepresentation. If the Editors and the
                            Eddys are no more honestly dealt by, through the Reporters, than are the Shakers, Editors may learn that they
                            know nothing yet, as they ought to know it, about either Spiritualism, or Shakerism. I will send a corrected,
                            printed proof slip of the article. Please reply,</p><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Yes.' We will not undertake to publish all manner of crazy reports..." TEIform="index"/>'Yes.' We will not undertake to publish all manner of crazy reports...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"Yes." We will not undertake to publish all manner of crazy reports from credulous people who
                                        fancy that they have seen Ghosts. But we recognize Elder Evans as a man of ability, and shall be
                                        glad to give him any reasonable hearing.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ed. tribune" TEIform="index"/>Ed. Tribune</bibl></cit></p></div3><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribune and shakers" TEIform="index"/>THE TRIBUNE AND SHAKERS</head><p TEIform="p">The Tribune was established, originally, in the interests of the common people, like the Roman Tribune — a
                            magistrate chosen by the people, to protect the people from oppression by patricians or nobles — to defend their
                            liberties against any infraction by Senate and Consuls. Is not our modern Tribune a little too patrician in its
                            tendencies on the subject of spiritualism ? No sooner are its patrons, and even its founder landed on immortal
                            shores of the spirit world, than all interest in their welfare is at an end. I have sometimes thought, perhaps
                            hastily, that the Tribune was an organ to defend the people of the United States, who are in the body, against
                            all attempts of the people of the United States, and any other States, who are out of the body, from
                            establishing a scientific communication and friendly intercourse through which they might seek to destroy that
                            which destroys—war, poverty, sexual incontinence, solid and fluid intemperance, together with the abnormal
                            desires of mind and body, that engender diseases, which are excuses for medication and drug doctoring. When the
                            Fox girls were first in New York as mediums, I had a tilt with my friend Horace, in which he accused me of "
                            having an axe to grind " — Spiritualism favored Shakerism. I replied, " Henceforth, Spiritualism is an
                            Institution of America." Am I not justified by subsequent facts ? KATIE KING. " We have received, recently,
                            divers letters of inquiry, principally from the inland and agricultural portions of the country, referring to
                            what the anxious writers are courteous enough to call the " recent spiritual manifestations." We must refer all
                            such seekers after truth to those of our cotemporaries who have established connection with out-lying ghostly
                            quarters: The Tribune only undertakes to deliver news from tracts accessible to railway trains, telegraphs, or
                            at least, not to put too coarse a point on it, balloons." As an order of people, we, the Shakers, do have
                            established connections " with the outlying ghostly world " — business connections too. Among this people,
                            Spiritualism, which is showing so much power — see Rev. 18 — originated. From here, Spiritualism went forth to
                            humanity outside of this order. Do you ask what good it has done? It claims to have released the thirty millions
                            of Serfs, of the Russian Empire. If true, is not that glory enough ? A friend from Albany, who went with the
                            Palestine company, of seventy Americans, was present at a dinner given by the Emperor and Empress, at which the
                            Empress, speaking of Home — the American Medium — states that it was by direction of Spirits, through Home, that
                            the Emperor issued the Ukase, freeing the Serfs, and to this the Emperor assented. That Slavery in America was
                            destroyed by Spirit agency, I have never doubted. " John Brown's soul went marching on," as really as did the
                            army, and he went not alone. Stanton was a confirmed Spiritualist, and his statements, to us, that Lincoln was
                            equally so, were most explicit. Will the Tribune, as the friend of the common people, of the two conjoined
                            worlds, let these important facts go forth to humanity ? In the editorial " Katie King," there is a " break in
                            the wall." The satire is designed to make a clean separation between the real and the fictitious — the honest
                            and dishonest. It is keen enough for the purpose ; but do you not close the door, to the inner world, a little
                            too tight ? Why not leave the gates, at least, ajar? When you put it on this wise : " This materialization must
                            be either spirits, assuming visible shape, or a skillful trick of clever knaves—there is no half way ground," I
                            like it. That is just the truth of the case. Just stick to that point, and we will get out of the fog. We can
                            solve this problem, as we would solve any other scientific problem. I was the first person, so far as I know,
                            who defined spiritualism as a science, not a religion ; placing it with agriculture, astronomy, geology and
                            chemistry, to be dealt with accordingly. By spiritualism, 1 would be understood the acknowledged existence of
                            the spirit world—Human Immortality—the possibility of intercommunication between those in and those out of the
                            body, and nothing more. The morality or immorality of the mediums—the occurring facts, whether important or
                            puerile —the truth or falsity of communications, have no more bearing upon simple spiritualism, than similar
                            things have upon electricity and electricians, or upon farming. Science is an orderly arrangement of facts. Give
                            us the facts. The use or no use, the sense or no sense, we will attend to hereafter. In an editorial of even
                            date in the Scientific American, are the following tremendous utterances. They may correspond with your "
                            Innocent Earthquake : " "HOW TO INVESTIGATE SPIRITUALISM. " There has been lately an extraordinary revival of
                            spiritualism, and it again challenges the general attention. Nearly all the newspapers, and some of the most
                            respected of the literary magazines, without reservation or protest, lend their columns to its advocates. " This
                            revival of spiritualism is probably due to the new phase which the spiritual manifestations have taken on :
                            Materialization, in place of raps, tips, trumpet blowing, tying, levitations, ponderations, etc., performed by
                            or through the medium, we now have the spirits appearing in propria persona, with bodies apparently of flesh and
                            blood, and nicely dressed in such clothes as they wore when they dwelt in the mortal coil. "Now these things
                            seem to justify us in recurring to the subject of spiritualism, and in improving the opportunity to point out
                            some things which Science has to do with it. And to make the matter short, we will limit our remarks to the
                            alleged physical phenomena, the movements or changes of matter. We leave out of view, of course, the religious
                            aspects of spiritualism; and for its bearings on psychology and physiology, we refer to what Faraday, Carpenter,
                            Tyndall and others have written. "In the first place, then, we can find no F. W. EVANS, Editor. <pb n="10" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 1O words wherewith adequately to express our sense of the magnitude of its importance to Science
                            if it be true. Such words as profound, vast, stupendous, would need to be strengthened a thousand fold to be
                            fitted for such a use. If true, it will become the one grand event of the world's history ; it will give an
                            imperishable lustre of glory to the nineteenth century. Its discoverer will have no rival in renown, and his or
                            her name will be written high above any other. For spiritualism involves a stultification of what are considered
                            the most certain and fundamental conclusions of Science. It denies the conservation of matter and force; it
                            demands a reconstruction of our chemistry and physics, and even our mathematics. It professes to create matter
                            and force apparently out of nothing, and to annihilate them when created. If the pretensions of spiritualism
                            have a rational foundation, no more important work has been offered to men of Science than their verification. A
                            realization of the dreams of the elixir vitoz, the philosopher's stone, and the perpetual motion, is of less
                            importance to mankind than the verification of spiritualism." Having, for the last forty years, studied this
                            science of Spiritualism—by it Iwas converted to Shakerism—with our own mediums, who have no motive, either of
                            poverty or vanity, to practice fraud, I visited the Eddys, who knew not of my coming, determined to know of the
                            facts there existing — I went, as to one of Tyndall's experimental lectures. After an unprejudiced examination,
                            I pronounce the materialization that I witnessed, of some fifteen spirits, of men and women, to be as true and
                            real — as genuine — as are any facts in agriculture or chemistry that I have ever witnessed. I fully realize the
                            responsibility I assume by this statement. I do it as a duty to my fellows, who may not have the opportunities,
                            I have had, in forming a union with disembodied men and women. " Two theories only, are tenable, regarding most
                            of the Spirit manifestations. They are real and true and honest, or they are a culpable fraud." So says the
                            Scientific American. That is the pin to hang all doubts upon, until removed therefrom by facts —evidence. But
                            when, to this, he adds, " the media, in these cases, are either the most worship-worthy of mortals," I demur
                            entirely. We, too, fell into that trap. The facts may be real and the materializations true, and yet the mediums
                            be as great cheats and liars, as were some of the Reporters — not the Tribune's — who professed to give, the
                            public, the facts of our Steinway Hall Meetings, on the 22d November, and as somebody must be, in the great
                            scandal suits. Even when media are entirely truthful, it no more constitutes them worship-worthy, than is a
                            pipe, that conveys precious or vile fluid—than is an electric machine. Again says the Editor, " Concerning raps
                            and materializations, there is a question of fraud or no fraud, and this is a question of such fundamental
                            character, that the answer to it is conclusive of the whole matter." Then come the tests, to settle the
                            important question — A gun is suggested, to shoot the apparition. This, the Editor is afraid of, and warns the
                            investigator that an action, for murder, would lie, should the fraudulent medium be killed. Of the fifteen male
                            and female figures of different sizes, ages and proportions, that I saw, any one of them might have been
                            subjected to that test. But I too, would give a caution. While any kind of a test, that a sincere enquirer might
                            honestly require, as evidence, or to detect fraud, would pass harmlessly ; should the tester be a fraud, the
                            missile might rebound and kill the sender. Then we have the "Lasso" suggested, " a dark lantern, some ink "—then
                            " a strong grasp upon the materialization," Any thing, friends, if you bear "in mind, that haply contending with
                            something real, you may kick against pricks. If " the peace of society is disturbed, and something must be done
                            for quiet, or many good friends will go to Bedlam," I trust that all those Editors, who 'gave such liberal
                            advance notice of our Shaker Meetings, will happily escape.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine, September 22, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me., Sept. 22,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Elder Frederick : But for circumstances beyond my control, I would sooner have responded to your friendly
                            greeting. Your fatherly commendation of our efforts in Lynn, cheered me not a little. The encouraging truths, in
                            your letter, strengthen me anew for further effort. The Comforter, Jesus promised, was the Spirit of Truth.
                            While it acts as comforter, to those ready to receive it, it will cause all to mourn, who rely upon other power
                            for safety, or protection. How many high wrought schemes have come to naught through its power ! How many Idols
                            have fallen from their high position, like Dagon before the Ark ! From Aaron's Calf to the Pet Idol of to-day,
                            men have been ready to worship their own creations of hand, or brain. Philistines are not sole mourners for the
                            destruction of their Gods. May we be so self-disciplined, that we can say, and speak advisedly — Let Truth
                            Prevail, tho' every man be a liar — or mistaken in some things. While able to see some things, to-day, hid from
                            our view yesterday, let the thought of to-morrow's light enable us to receive the knowledge of to-day with
                            humility. Evidence, rapidly accumulates, of work, going on in the minds of men and women, causing the scales to
                            fall from their eyes. They are no longer willing, even at the bidding of a hireling Priesthood, to bow the knee
                            to a God, who could predestine the majority of his creatures to endless misery, and demand the ignominious death
                            of his only begotten Sosr, to appease his wrath against the remainder. That so many are unwilling to see through
                            the eyes of others, or put on the spectacles of past opinions — that some, at least, have the moral courage to
                            use the reason God has given them — fills my soul with rejoicing. I feel with you, that the beginning of the end
                            has come — the old dam of superstition must give way before the accumulating waters of Truth. Among the many
                            Instruments God has employed to inaugurate this great work, I recognize those Radical Materialists, to whom you
                            refer, and of whom you were one. They were inspired by a class of Spirits, who — however blind to many truths,
                            since opened to you — saw with clearness, the false foundation on which the Dam was builded, and the deformity
                            of the Idols, worshipped by the world ycleped Christian. You and your compeers were ready instruments in the
                            hands of those spirits. They so filled you with the tear down idea, that it remains with you today, in its
                            pristine vigor — tempered, no doubt, with the wisdom of greater knowledge and broader experience. While
                            influenced by this Spirit, to strip, from this mythical Jesus, the- robes with which Priests have clothed their
                            Idol; is it not possible, you would, sometimes, take away what, of right, belongs to the real Jesus ? Heartily
                            agreeing with you in your first, second, third and fourth positions — when I read in your fifth, that Jesus,
                            like all good Jews, believed in physical resurrection, and headed a general movement in the spirit world, to
                            effect it — that he believed in war, expecting spirit assistance to overthrow the powers that were, and make him
                            King —I am constrained to say — Not yet do I so read history. That the Apostles, for a time at least, did
                            believe in a physical resurrection, I agree with you. Their so believing has been a stumblingblock in the way of
                            educating the masses, that the Christ Resurrection is spiritual. Events of to-day, to some extent, obviate the
                            difficulty. From the Apostolic record, I fail to discover that Jesus so believed. His raising Lazarus is no more
                            to the point than Elijah's or Elisha's doing a similar thing. When he said to Martha, I am the resurrection and
                            the life — lie that believeth in me, tho' he were dead, yet shall he live — he referred to quite a different
                            death from that of Lazarus, or the Ruler's daughter. That Jesus came back into his old body, and other Saints
                            did so too, the Apostles, no doubt, believed at the time. We can excuse people, of even a hundred years ago, for
                            thinking it the only sensible construction of the story. But now we have evidence in our very midst, both in
                            England and America, that Spirits can, under certain conditions, clothe themselves with material form, which can
                            be seen, talked with and handled, as really as was Jesus, or any of the old saints. Is it not more in keeping
                            with the Spirit of the age to conclude, that no Spirit can come back into its body, after animal life had
                            entirely left it—that Lazarus, as well as others, was in that condition which might have ultimated in death, but
                            was no more really dead, at the time, than many others, in these days of hasty funerals ? As to Jesus and the
                            swords, let Materialists read Mathew's report of the sermon on the Mount, and then tell, under what conditions,
                            a man, believing those divine principles, could take, or believe in the swords. That his zeal for God's house,
                            may, for the moment, have led him away from these divine truths, when he drove out the money changers, I will
                            not attempt to deny. But, that he ordered the purchase of swords with the idea of thereby saving his life, or
                            becoming King, is not, to my mind, consistent with the record. That he may have been so tempted, during his
                            forty days in the wilderness, is quite probable. That he resisted, thus setting us an example which the Apostle
                            plainly declares. At the time swords were spoken of, he evidently expected death, and could not, consistently,
                            have anticipated deliverance by men, or Angels. His rebuke of the disciple who, 8HAKEE A.ND <pb n="11" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                            with the sword essayed to protect him, was consistent with his teachings at all times, and plausibly explains
                            his wishing them to have a sword, at the time, that he might give his dying testimony against it. So, too, when
                            disciples would that he make use of the higher form of war, by calling down fire from Heaven, to consume his
                            enemies, even as did Elias -— he rebuked them as emphatically, as could even Elder Frederick, that they knew not
                            what manner of spirit they were of. Thus, Beloved Elder Frederick, I dissent from your conclusions, not because
                            I believe. Jesiis was a God, and therefore could not err, but because I believe him to be a Godly man, entitled
                            to the full benefit of his recorded words and acts. Differing from your conclusions, while pateruing your
                            freedom of opinion, is prima facie evidence that I believe every one should form his and her own opinion,
                            according to his and her own best judgment. Be assured, Beloved Elder, I love and revere your earnest, fearless
                            spirit, in opposing all error, wherever found. May I imitate your example, by accepting the increasing light
                            each day brings. In Gospel Love, I am your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vance, John B." TEIform="persName"/>John B. Vance</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New standpoint" TEIform="index"/>A NEW STANDPOINT</head><p TEIform="p">Among the emigrants from this world to the next — of such as have figured largely in the affairs of men — I fail
                            to find the first individual, who, if a mere wish would obtain it, would not have a sponge drawn over his past
                            record. Underlying his patriotism, he finds, on retrospection, a large substratum of Ego, hiding, for the time
                            being, from Ms own eyes only, the absurdity of his "fantastic tricks before high heaven," the absurdity of
                            inferring, from his accidental, temporary elevation, that he was born to command ad infinitum. He now sees that
                            some, who were unknown to fame, are largely his superiors. He sees there is a Power that over-rules in the
                            affairs of man. He sees that, from the material lying around loose, such instruments are selected as will best
                            subserve the present purpose. When that purpose is accomplished, or the tool becomes dull, that tool is dropped
                            and another is picked up. In the instrumentalities selected, no new springs to action are created. The springs
                            already there are put in motion. The reward is measured, not so much by the end accomplished, as by the motive
                            of the instrument.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribune editorial" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUNE EDITORIAL</head><p TEIform="p">The Tribune is courteous and generous. It can also afford to be scrupulously j ust. Let us understand each other,
                            and answer to a proposition, definitely, when we have stated it accurately. The Tribune says, '' "We are
                            compelled to say, that neither Owen nor Evans has said a word in arrest of the general judgment upon the mummery
                            practiced at Philadelphia and at the home of the Eddys, in Vermont. Both of them seem to think the word of a
                            Spirit is as good as that of any one else, if not better. Elder Evans expressly says, that the personal honesty
                            or dishonesty of the medium has nothing to do with the faith to be given to his utterances." This is a serious
                            mistake. The point at issue, is the fact of mediumship of the man or woman, and the materialization of the
                            Spirit — not the '' word," or utterance, or character of either of them. Do the Spirits exist? Does the
                            mediumship of the man or woman exist? And is the materialization fact — or fraud? This is what I do say. It will
                            bear repeating — for very important interests are involved in the scientific solution of this problem. Upon it I
                            have staked my reputation, as a practical man — a lover of my kind, whether they be in their first or second
                            physical body. '' By Spiritualism, I would be understood, the acknowledged existence of the Spirit world — Human
                            Immortality — the possibility of inter-communication between those in the body, and those out of the body, and
                            nothing more. The morality or immorality of the mediums — the occurring facts, whether important or puerile —
                            the truth or falsity of communications, have no more bearing upon simple Spiritualism as thus defined, than
                            similar things have upon any other science—upon Chemistry or Farming. Science is an orderly arrangement of
                            facts. Give us the facts. The use, or no use —the sense, or no sense, we will attend to hereafter." And is it
                            not "in arrest of the general judgment of mummery " of materialization, when I state, point blank, after an
                            unprejudiced examination, I pronounce the materialization, that i witnessed, of some fifteen Spirits of men and
                            women, to be as true and real — as genuine — as are any facts in Agriculture or Chemistry, that I have ever
                            witnessed ? I fully realize the responsibility I assume, by this statement. I stand by that to the public, both
                            of my own Order, and of the outside world. Are we not all disposed to strain at gnats, and swallow camels ? How
                            the theologians, to whom the Bible is the word of God materialized, can disbelieve in the principle of Spiritual
                            manifestation, is, to me, a logical enigma. When food, for a million of people — more or less — was, for forty
                            years materialized — when Nadab and Abin, and seventy Elders, saw the God of Israel materialized— and did eat
                            and drink. Ex. 24: 9. And when Jesus and his disciples materialized bread and fish, for thousands of men and
                            women, to eat — just as I saw Honto materialize cloth in plain sight of twentyfive people — and finally when
                            Jesus was transfigured, and Moses and Elias were materialized, so that James and John proposed to build tents
                            for them to live in —I marvel, either at the gullibility, or the incredulity of Christians. After the soul of
                            Jesus was out of his body, he either returned and reanimated it, for forty days: or he materialized a body that
                            talked — saying, "A spirit hath not flesh and bones, as ye see me have." Why then should not the same Law be
                            operative among so progressive a people as the readers of the New York Tribune?</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The true social desideratum at last is, not that women, equally with men, assume..." TEIform="index"/>The true social desideratum at last is, not that women, equally with men, assume...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The true social desideratum at last is, not that women, equally with men, assume the exercise of authority ; but
                            that men, equally with women forego the exercise of authority The genuine perfection of humanity instead of
                            being the enforced obedience of one-half to the other half, is the spontaneous obedience of both halves to the
                            law of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Mill" TEIform="persName"/>Mill.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There never  was a great man unless through divine inspiration" TEIform="index"/>There never  was a great man unless through divine inspiration
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There never was a great man unless through divine inspiration.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cicero" TEIform="persName"/>Cicero</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Winouski, Vermont, October 25, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Winouski, Vt., Oct. 25,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Respected Friend and Brother, F. W. Evans: I was truly gratified by your 10th October favor. You are so good as
                            to send us the quotations from the Revised Statutes of New York, and I appreciate. I am constrained to say, your
                            letter is a diamond — I shall ever so regard it—full of superb ideas. You are, in the fullest sense, liberal and
                            tolerant. I would rejoice to see so noble and worthy a letter printed ; it would be a source of joy to many a
                            weary and progressive heart, to comprehend its beauty. Your Shaker and Shakeress of November is at hand. Mrs.
                            Shipman, a most excellent woman of great energy and enterprise, my son DeLion, my daughter Portia and I — all of
                            us — count it a feast of fat things. For myself, I feel akin to you — I seem to gravitate to you, and to the
                            celestial light I see all around you and yours. I am assured we are spiritually drawn together. I want to find
                            men and women with great hearts ; I want to attain to the highest good, no matter at what sacrifice ; I want a
                            revolution from the wrecks all around us, and would hail with delight the coming of the Reconstructing Angel of
                            Truth. By the blessing of the angel world, may we be won to you, you to us. " Legal Marriage" is enforced
                            maternity — sexual slavery. Free Lust is a covenant with Hell! — an agreement with Death. Free Love, by the aid
                            of Science, Culture and Refinement, leads to Purity, to Self-denial, Self-abnegation. And this is a Law of
                            Right. Spirit life tells us, you, as a people, are nearer to us than any of our race. So, for the good of
                            humanity, let us form an alliance. Is it not the biggest thing to lead blessed men and women up to a higher
                            plane of life ? Let me hold a place in your heart. Ever yours, Owen Shipman. Evening. — Several of our members,
                            previous to receiving your good letter, anxious to go over to Valcour, being impatient to organize, went on to
                            Plattsburg, and effected an organization. I will try to send you printed copy soon, with circular No. 2. Accept
                            the assurance of my heart, overflowing with gratitude for your generous and brotherly offer of books ; please do
                            not send just now. Will rejoice to avail ourselves of your goodness in time to come. We have several noble
                            brothers and sisters, more spiritually progressive than others — for some lack these attainments. They, with me,
                            desire to live on the self-denying, intellectual plane ; so we have joy in loving our celibate brothers and
                            sisters, and we are not aliens, nor antagonists to you. We want order, science, harmony and energy, with economy
                            ; also, your efficiency to revolutionize chaotic elements. The rock on which we are most likely to split, is
                            Treachery and Anarchy. Now, if we wreck, I invite the noblest and best of you to come to our rescue.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shipman, Owen" TEIform="persName"/>Owen Shipman</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hints to writers" TEIform="index"/>HINTS TO WRITERS</head><p TEIform="p">" Most writers not accustomed to the press imagine that a newspaper article, like an oration, should have an
                            exordium, an argument, and conclusion. Not at all. The argument is all that is wanted. That is state your case,
                            say your say, and stop. Do not take time and space to get into the subject, and more to get out of it; but come
                            to it instantly, and stop when you are done. " Be short. The time is short, the world is very fast now, and
                            readers of newspapers do not want long articles. Pack your thoughts into short words, short sentences and short
                            essays. If you never do a great thing never do a long thing. " Come to the point. If you have no point, lay down
                            the pen and do something else, rather than write. It is not every one who can write for edification' and you may
                            not be one who can. '• Write the article two or three times over carefully, making it shorter each time. Write
                            on one side only of the paper. Write legibly. Keep a copy of what you send to the press. Editors do not return
                            manuscripts. We cannot undertake to, and we so state every week, but are every week asked to. It is impossible
                            to make the reasons plain to writers ; but it is out of the question. " Be very modest in your estimate of your
                            own productions, and do not fret if others esteem them even less than you do."— N. Y. Observer. Each is the
                            proper guardian of his and her own health, whether bodily, mental or spiritual — is his or her own
                        physician.</p></div2><pb n="12" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel travail" TEIform="index"/>GOSPEL TRAVAIL</head><p TEIform="p">Many practical experiences of others have I read and heard related with evident advantage and benefit to myself.
                            Some were encouragements to perseverance in righteousness, and some were solemn warnings to " avoid the very
                            appearance of evil." Now, after a long term of years in the holy discipline of virtue, I quite frequently
                            retrospect the ground over which I have gone, and try to discover the principles, practices and habits, which
                            have proved elements of success in reaching the goal for which I started. In hours of serene meditation in the
                            solemn afternoon of life, one grand principle comes to my memory, which was early in active operation in my
                            mind, and from which I have scarcely swerved a single time in half a century, i. e., never to allow any discount
                            on an honest fulfillment of obligations imposed by conscience, whether suggested by my own mind or furnished by
                            the rules of piety, order and Christian decorum, adopted by Believers as means of safety, protection, and
                            salutary discipline in righteousness. I have known persons to fall away from a very fruitful travail in virtue
                            and piety, in so gradual a manner, that the several steps in the process were scarcely distinguishable by
                            others, and, apparently, not at all by themselves. The little foxes were eating away at the tendrils of the
                            vines and insidiously severing them more and more from the great and noble tree round which they had so long
                            clung for shelter and support. I have dreaded an indefinite, lukewarm condition of conscience more than any
                            dangers to which a Christian pilgrim is exposed. I will illustrate a little. About thirty years ago, it was
                            required of us young converts to avoid placing our feet upon the rounds of the chairs when sitting therein, and
                            thereby save the paint on them. Some older and better men than myself would ignore and trample upon this little
                            regulation, yet I never dared to do so. And why ? Not because I thought there was any great degree of moral
                            turpitude in the act itself, but because I felt that a departure from any rule I had once adopted would
                            inevitably be a starting-point of incipient backsliding, and where it would end who could divine ? I was taught
                            to pick up pins, and strings, and bits of iron, and save them ; and to this very day I dare not relax my zeal,
                            even in this small matter, for fear my conscience might be demoralized, and my living impressions of practical
                            righteousness in matters of weightier concern might begin to wane. So of keeping the Sabbath. I saw to my
                            surprise some who would not scruple to depart from the holy service and sacred usages of the Sabbath as
                            established by Believers. I never could afford to do it, not even so much as to walk or ride out for mere
                            recreation, although I felt no hesitation in milking the cows, or caring for the horses, or performing any other
                            necessary duty. I could see plainly that a little relaxing here would soon fritter away my earnest feelings and
                            spiritual inspirations ; I should lose the blessings of the day and institution, appropriated to religious
                            meditation. In all matters pertaining to life, the pabulum of my mental and spiritual being consisted of that
                            which the best and highest and most earnest efforts on my part could procure from the sweetest, purest sources
                            at my command. I could not afford to lower the standard of sincerity in my conscience. Will any one say it is
                            superstition not to walk over a pin, a string, or bit of iron, without picking it up and saving it? Not at all.
                            It gives strength and tone to the moral nature more than a bitter discussion of theology a hundred years long.
                            Hear this pretty story: Mother Lucy once visited a family of Believers who had just harvested their bean crop.
                            She noticed that they had not taken them carefully from the vines but had left too many to waste, and she
                            directed a brother to pick them over again. The brother went as directed and saved quite a quantity. But this
                            was not all, nor the best. While he was gathering the beans, he was entirely overpowered by the goodness of God
                            and the presence of angels, and cried for very joy the whole time. That day would remain a green spot in his
                            memory forever. From this we may learn that what, to an undisciplined worldly spirit, is trifling or
                            superstitious, may be the essence of high and holy inspiration. I have written this, not for the benefit of
                            Believers of long experience. Such have already patiently traveled quite through this low ground " To reign with
                            the bridegroom and bride." But unto the inexperienced in Zion, this is inscribed in all kindness and humility,
                            and my kind regards and affectionate love-greeting go with it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton, Union Village, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Happy new year" TEIform="index"/>A HAPPY NEW YEAR</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Youth in Zion: The first day of the year should be regarded, by you, as a marked day in the history of
                            your lives ; for it is the starting point of a new era in life's journey. The new date of the year, like the
                            number on the milestone, will remind you that a defined portion of your earthly journey is finished, and that
                            you are entering upon a new and untried portion. In wishing you a Happy New Year, I would impress on your minds
                            the important truth, that in the stern battle for eternal Life, if you would win, you must work. You must
                            commence the year with self-denial and self-discipline, if you would end it with spiritual prosperity. Be not
                            afraid to form new resolutions, at the beginning of each year, such as will restrain from vicious habits and
                            tendencies ; now is the time to discard evil practices, and commence the cultivation of good ones. Be careful
                            that the thousand poisonous weeds of vice do not choke the lovely expanding blossoms of virtue. Open a new
                            account with conscience, and heed its timely admonitions, that you may not have, at the year's end, a heavy debt
                            and nought but remorse to pay it. You are not living wisely, nor well, unless you make each coming year better
                            than the past one — better for yourself and for others. A good life keeps the conscience clear, and a clear
                            conscience makes its possessor happy. The youth who lives a good life — and why should any live a bad one?
                            —strictly obeys God's requirements, as they are made known through His appointed leaders. Truth is the glory of
                            youth, and is essential to their happiness in this world and also in the next; therefore make truth your motto,
                            for " Truth alone will stand." " Lord, who shall abide in Thy tabernacle? He that speaketh truth in his heart."
                            Youthful readers of the S. and S.: besetting sins of every name and nature should be at once uprooted and
                            destroyed, never to grow again. If all who read this will make the effort, earnestly and hopefully, they will be
                            able to say — This is indeed a Happy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Calais, Vermont, June 7, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Calais, Vermont, June 7, 1874</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Shaker and Shakeress : I have, at last, found a paper which teaches C%m£-religion. I have had the privilege
                            of reading several numbers of your paper, of late, and am pleased with them. I am almost a Shaker. My Heavenly
                            Father has given me light of what is to be in the future: THE FUTURE. There is a time, not far ahead, When all
                            intemperance is dead, When holy angels will descend, and every knee to God will bend, His righteous judgment be
                            confessed, And all true Christians will be blessed—The Lion, by the Wolf caressed, and with them, will the Lamb
                            be blessed, And little children lead the throng, With Hallelujah their best song—Peace—sweet peace, to man be
                            given, Withnever a war, in Earth, nor Heaven—A cleaned up Earth, unmarred by vice—With one new Church all sweet
                            and nice —By Love to God, in man inspired. No man-made laws will be required —Behind old creeds, there'll be no
                            hiding-^No need, when all are law abiding—When, in God's image, all complete, Is man—including Helper meet—Then
                            all the Stars may skip and play, and spread the tidings far away.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pierce, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>Joseph Pierce</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steinway hall meetings" TEIform="index"/>STEINWAY HALL MEETINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Expenditures. $470.95. Receipts, $430.05. Deficit, $40.90.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Kisco, New York, December 19, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Mount Kisco, N. Y., Dec. 19,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Frederick Evans: Yours, of the 12th, came to hand. You say you are willing I should come and prove rayself by
                            your Order. I am aware I could not unite myself to your Order, with any degree of satisfaction, to myself or
                            others, without an experience, essentially different from the outside world. I see the beauty and desirableness
                            of the community system, wherein none act on selfish principles. All laboring for, and loving their neighbor as
                            themselves. This, to my perception, is the Incarnation of Heaven upon Earth. I was delighted with my visit among
                            you. It made an impression upon my mind, never to be effaced. How pleasant to recognize the Elders among you, as
                            Fathers, with their long, varied and valuable experience. The younger men, as Brothers or Sons. The elder women,
                            as Mothers — the younger as Sisters — a relation purely spiritual, noble, pure, holy and exalted — where the
                            constant endeavor is to do the will of God, as is done by angels in Heaven — where intemperance, in eating, as
                            well as in drinking, is carefully avoided. Where disease — the effect of law's infraction—is banished. Where
                            sin, in its multiform manifestations, desolating humanity, in the outer world, is studiously left behind. Where
                            the so called benefactors of the world, including lawyers, doctors and clergy, have a privilege to earn their
                            bread by honest industry. Well may your worthy correspondent, A. B. B., regard your Institution as a " Beacon
                            Light, hung up in these western heavens, to teach mankind what sublime achievements humanity can attain, for a
                            religious principle." The fact, that your Institution has, for so many years, stood the strain of the surging,
                            tumultuous waves, of an adulterous generation, is, to my mind, conclusive proof that the Institution is founded
                            on the Bock — that It has a great mission to perform — and that God, in his own good time, will show how
                            powerful are these silent influences, for the liberation of the anxious throng, who are now praying to be
                            delivered from the thrall of the debris of a shipwrecked generation, with groanings unutterable. I am looking
                            for light and direction. I have been pointed to Mount Lebanon, by an influence, which I am sure is from above.
                            But I have been in doubt whether the friends could bear with my infirmities. I have, as I told you, been
                            troubled with periodical turns of what doctors call neuralgia in. the head, which; I am satisfied comes from a
                            disordered stomach, the result of improper food, improperly cooked. I would like to live on grain and
                            vegetables. I expect you could prescribe a system of hygiene, which, if carefully carried out, might, in time,
                            relieve me of the difficulty. People, in general, you are aware, live on pork, beef, hot buckwheat cakes, cooked
                            in grease, pickles, mince-pies, tea, coffee, rich cakes, fine flour and the like, bolted down without
                            mastication. Then follow patent medicines—doctors, with blue pills, quinine, mercury, etc. — then the
                            undertaker. Have you any employment in which I could make myself useful ? I would come as a learner, divested of
                            disagreeableness, bigotry, over self-esteem — all bad qualities which would shut me out from that kingdom, which
                            is righteousness and peace, joy, in angelic purity. I desire an eye single to the glory of God, that I may dwell
                            in the light of eternal day — to know and do the will of God, in all things, at any and all costs. Please write
                            me soon. Yours Truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hubbell, Gilbert" TEIform="persName"/>Gilbert Hubbell</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The general average of mankind..." TEIform="index"/>The general average of mankind...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The general average of mankind are not only moderate in intellect but also moderate in inclinations ; they have
                            no tastes nor wishes strong enough to incline them to do any thing unusual, and they consequently do not
                            understand those who have, and class all such with the wild and intemperate whom they persecuted, and then
                            worshipped. Food or drink should never be taken into the mouth either hot or cold, but near the temperature of
                            the blood.</p></div2><pb n="13" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: many mansions" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: MANY MANSIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">If a photographic view of a village, or of a commodious building, should be taken at the same time from different
                            standpoints,would not every view thus taken be dissimilar ? Would it be just, or wise, to assert that all the
                            others, except the one taken from our standpoint, were false and unreal ? All would agree that such village or
                            building did actually exist. Then, would it not better accord with reason, and show more of the love of truth,
                            to seek to know of what material the building is composed — whether its foundations are laid deep and strong,
                            and if it be really capable of sheltering and protecting those who seek refuge from storms and tempests that may
                            arise without 1 While thus testing its strength, and seeking to find out whether any of its parts can be shaken
                            by the increasing winds of truth, that there may be a timely removal of the error, we would say, as did the
                            apostle, "Let brotherly and sisterly love continue, and let patience have her perfect work." Theology is viewed
                            differently by persons occupying diverse positions, rendering discussion and investigation necessary and
                            profitable, if conducted with a view to elicit truth instead of producing controversy. Eeligion is the vital
                            element of the soul — its life. Theology is the outward form, to embody and clothe the real spiritual part. When
                            the body is moved by the vitalizing principle within, then all will be harmonious. Science and religion will
                            thus act in concert and a desire to get at the true — will be the ruling motive, while all differences of
                            opinions, honestly expressed, will be treated with kindness and respect. Neither bigotry, conservatism, nor
                            pride of opinion, should ever block the wheels of progress, nor draw the curtains of superstition over the
                            windows of the soul, to shut out the increasing light of truth. " In my Father's house are many mansions," said
                            Jesus. When were those mansions built, and for what purpose ? Were they all constructed at one time ? If the
                            soul's destiny is fully determined at the expiration of mortal existence, and all go direct to heaven or hell,
                            why so many mansions ? Shall we presuppose an aristocracy there — a Plymouth and Trinity Church for the high,
                            and other churches for the colored people and the lowly, bearing distinctive marks of caste ? Or, shall we
                            understand that those mansions to which Jesus referred, were built in different ages and cycles, and were shaped
                            according to the degrees of knowledge and progress of the people at the time? Their conceptions of God, the
                            primordial cause of all causes, may have been vague and limited; yet they used the best material that they could
                            command, and the mansions which they built were adapted to the conditions of the people, and were accepted, as
                            forming a part of the Father's house. There have been many builders all down through the ages, who have worked
                            according to the pattern given to them. Moses was shown a pattern in Mount Sinai, and was instructed to build a
                            tabernacle that would serve the needs of the people at that time. However symbolical it may have been of the
                            tabernacle to which the ringer of prophecy pointed, that would eventually be built in such perfect consonance
                            with truth, and so strongly fortified therewith, that " not one stake would ever be removed, neither any of the
                            cords thereof be broken," it was evidently not the one design for all succeeding builders. Solomon and Ezra were
                            commanded to build ; they had their patterns ; those were also included as belonging to the Father's house.
                            Jesus laid the foundation of a new structure, and left his followers to build upon it. It was not his mission to
                            destroy the law ; neither to condemn the doers of the law ; but to show a more perfect way, reveal a higher law.
                            He called those who were prepared to leave the old covenant of types and shadows, which had served a good
                            purpose and done its work, to enter into a new covenant, which was more spiritual. The unprogressed Jews
                            persecuted those who accepted the new covenant, and, like unconverted Saul, " verily thought they were doing God
                            service." The spirit of controversy, and bitter railing, have never been productive of good fruits, in any age
                            of the world's history. Tens of thousands have honestly entertained opinions at one time, that they have as
                            honestly changed for other opinions, at another time. From a variety of standpoints and degrees of altitude, we
                            catch different views; but " Charity suffereth long, and is kind. Charity envieth not." Had there never been any
                            aggressive movers — iconoclasts in the world — where would have been the progress of the race? We are naturally
                            all idolators, have our gods to worship, either of wood and stone, the low forms of animal life; or through
                            tradition and blind zeal we make gods of human beings and worship them. Whatever or whoever they may be, they
                            are sacred to us ; and if any one takes the axe of truth to break those idols in pieces, it ia hard to convince
                            us that they have been sent of God to do it. No living, inspirational soul, will be heard to say that we have
                            already attained unto the highest degree of truth that is for the race. The keys of revelation, through some
                            human agency, will yet unlock doors that have hitherto been closed. New sacrifices will be required, and new
                            glories will open to our spiritual vision. Whoever are called to this work, should look well before they strike,
                            lest " they hurt the oil and the wine," and mar the seal which God has placed in the foreheads of his
                        servants.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence of kindness" TEIform="index"/>INFLUENCE OF KINDNESS</head><p TEIform="p">I have been led to observe how, in a thousand instances, little services and kind words rendered in time of need,
                            which indeed should never be withheld, drew from observers expressions of praise, and they always leave a bright
                            mark on the characters of those upon whom they fall. As we pass the rounds of daily life in all its various
                            employments, how characteristically do the motive powers of each one portray themselves, whether meritorious or
                            otherwise; and we, whom providence, or destiny has placed together, how important it is thai we scan the motives
                            which lead to actions Thus it is that we really learn to know ourselves, and the bearing with which we impress
                            others toward us. We see those whose talent and philanthropic nature raise them above the common level of
                            mankind. Such are destined ;o become glorious workers in the vineyard of "'hrist; and their works of love and
                            benevolence find no broader field for efficient exercise than in our own localities. And we observe that the
                            benevolent, those who are always kind and pleasant, cheerful and hopeful, radiate light; they are as bright
                            stars shining with effulgence wherever they go, causing clouds to disappear, as mists are overpowered by the
                            bright rays of the sun. But always to keep and command this beautiful harmonious condition of mind, requires
                            vigilance and self-sacrifice in many ways, which only add greater lustre and help to form a beautiful character.
                            There are many who have the germs of noble men and women at their birth; but who for the lack of self
                            discipline, a little exercise on those points, never really attain to that place in the scale of being that they
                            otherwise would. There are many opportunities wherein we may show a kind heart, by speaking pleasant words,
                            which drop as dew on thirsty plants. Had we the power to see the soothing effects they produced on sorrowful
                            hearts, perhaps already bruised and sore, almost beyond endurance, we would make it a constant study to select
                            careful and prudent language, that we may not, in any unguarded moment, let pass from our lips words which would
                            drop as lead in the already depressed spirit of our brother or our sister. Are there any who have not in some
                            period of their lives felt themselves so bereft of true friendship — the affections that sweeten life's bitter
                            woes — and also the crush of disappointed hopes, that have so far blasted the past and darkened the future, that
                            courage had almost failed ? Then how sweet is sympathy, a kind word or a favor, if even coming from a child; a
                            heart, thus humiliated, is able to appreciate kindness ; and we should never forget that all need kind words and
                            sympathy, when under trial, no matter from what cause ; we are all the better for having rendered, and for
                            having received them. Our greatest enjoyments are in our own beloved homes. Our nearest associates are those
                            with whom we mingle daily— the inmates of our own household. And living so nearly connected as we do, we have
                            need to bring into requisition those little civilities which tend so much to refinement, and produce harmonious
                            condition.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brady, Susanna M." TEIform="persName"/>Susanna M. Brady, Union Village, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contribution" TEIform="index"/>CONTRIBUTION</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Eldress Antoinette: Our little " Monthly," the " Shaker and Shakeress," is very dear to me. I always welcome
                            it. Its pages are well filled; and I take useful lessons and derive much comfort and happiness therefrom. I
                            would gladly contribute something to its columns, were I able to do so, and thus indicate practically my faith
                            in, and love for, Community life and principle. When I feel my inability to present anything new, that would
                            interest and instruct the readers, contributors and supporters of the clean little sheet, I am reminded of a
                            certain person of olden time who cast two mites into the Lord's treasury, and was commended for so doing. It was
                            not the amount given, but the motive which prompted the act, that attested the donor's sincerity — that elicited
                            approval. I am not unmindful of the labors of those who strive to make the paper so good and useful ; and it
                            would be a mark of selfishness, if I should remain silent and not give expression to feelings of gratitude for
                            favors thus received. The beautiful sentiments so clearly expressed by the young sisters with whom I have often
                            fraternized, and for whom I entertain a deep love, fill my spirit with joy. My sincerest desires are for their
                            prosperity and growth in spiritual life and light. They give evidence that they are living for a higher purpose
                            than merely self-pleasing, and earth's alluring charms, or to dwell in idleness, and slothfully spend their
                            time, destitute of soul aspirations, and lofty aims. Seneca, a philosopher, said, " We complain of the shortness
                            of time, and yet have more than we know what to do with. Our lives are spent either in doing nothing at all, or
                            doing nothing to the purpose — nothing which <pb n="14" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 14= A.ISTD we ought to do—complaining that our
                            days are few, and acting as if they would never end." Among the ancient Indians, there was a tribe called "
                            Gymnosophists." They had great aversion to sloth and indolence. It is said of them, that when the table was
                            spread for their repast, the assembled youths were asked by their chiefs how they had spent their time since the
                            rising of the sun. Whether they had been engaged in some useful employment. If upon investigation it was found
                            they had been idle— done nothing to deserve a dinner — they were rejected, while the others who had been
                            industrious, enjoyed the fruits of their own labors. They seemed to entertain the same opinion that the Apostle
                            Paul did, when he gave commandment, " That if any would not work, neither should they eat." It should not be our
                            purpose to eat the bread of idleness, either in a temporal or spiritual point of view. They who feel the worth
                            of immortal souls, will not cease to struggle in spirit, and pray earnestly to God that the convicting power of
                            truth may be felt throughout the length and breadth of our land, that will cause souls to feel the necessity of
                            living virtuous and godly lives. It has been said truly, " virtue is the foundation of all honor, and the source
                            of all beauty, order and happiness." It enhances the value of all the natural endowments of the human mind, and
                            to it every faculty should be subservient. The more eminent a person becomes, the more prominent will appear
                            their deformities, if virtue be not the controlling influence and guiding star of their lives. Virtue will give
                            dignity to character, and will ornament the soul, when we shall have put off the mortal. Beauty and wit may fade
                            and die. Many things which we learn that are applicable to the earth-life, will pass from memory with their
                            disuse. But virtue, innocence and love, will remain the soul's guardians and companions forever. Superior
                            beings, in all worlds, are bound by virtue's strong cords, and one law governs the whole of God's universe.
                            Those who are wise will search diligently to find the pearl of great price, and when found, will not hesitate to
                            " sell all to obtain it." As the poet says : " Go, thou in life's fair morning, go in the bloom of youth, And
                            buy for thine adorning, the iprecious pearl of truth. Secure this heavenly treasure, and bind it on thy heart,
                            And let no worldly pleasure, e'er cause it to depart. " Go while the day star shineth, go, while the heart is
                            light; Go, ere thy strength declineth, while every sense is bright, Sell all thou hast and buy it, 'tis worth
                            all earthly things; Rubies, and gold, and diamonds, sceptres and crowns of kings. " Go, ere the cloud of sorrow
                            steal o'er the bloom of youth. Defer not till to-morrow, go now and buy the truth ; Go seek thy Great Creator,
                            learn early to be wise, Go, place upon his altar, a morning sacrifice."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Van Houten, Phebe" TEIform="persName"/>Phebe Van Houten, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the shaker and shakeress:" TEIform="index"/>For the Shaker and Shakeress :</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doobeney, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Doobeney's farewell to the Community, after a Sabbath day's
                            enjoyment, of their worship and repose at Mt. Lebanon.</byline><p TEIform="p">BROTHERHOOD. Brother I know thee not in name, But feel thy future home is mine! Our loving father is the same—
                            And my heart is knit to thine. SISTERHOOD. Sister, I know that in thine eyes, And in thy accents soft and sweet
                            A Saviour reigns without disguise, Where all the Christian virtues meet. ADIEU, The moment, though a fleeting
                            one, In which I've felt thy sympathy, Shall, while these eyes behold the sun, Rest graven on my memory.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect" TEIform="index"/>CAUSE AND EFFECT</head><p TEIform="p">Op all the " many inventions mankind have sought out," none seem so little fraught with good to him, spiritually,
                            as those which offer him immunity from the effects of sin. Why ? Because, the one thought now is to avoid the
                            penalty, not considering that the cause is the wrong to be avoided, and that the penalty is nothing more nor
                            less than the consequence which must follow certain causes. Cause and effect are inseparable, and must succeed
                            each other, as certainly as the ebbing and flowing of tide, or the oscillations of the pendulum. " The soul that
                            sinneth (against the laws of its being) shall die," was fulfilled, though the mortal body might not then have
                            perished. Its spiritual perceptions and life were so paralyzed that the true and higher life was sacrificed for
                            the time, and has thus continued, until one came with power enough over the body to fulfill the law of
                            obedience, put it in subjection to the spirit, and show how it could be done. The Adamic Parents waited not
                            until the time when they could generate rightly. The result was a murderer, instead of a being on as high a
                            plane as themselves. Though becoming as gods, through the creative function, they sunk from the innocent and
                            guileless, till now, the fig-leaf covering has become the most engrossing thought, instead of the cause that
                            produced its necessity. The primeval innocence is gone, and nothing can restore it but the avoidance of what has
                            so long destroyed it, and filled earth with wantonness. Let us draw a figure as did the Master, to illustrate
                            from common life. In your house you have an ice closet which was constructed to run its waste water into a
                            vessel beneath it. But lately it leaks and the pan does not receive it, and your floor is wet and you are
                            annoyed. " That can be remedied says one, have a platform made as large as can be put under, with a border
                            around it, and run the water from that." Well, you try it and it keeps most of the water from the floor. But
                            suppose you could look into the refrigerator and see the floor beneath that zinc, soaked and decaying, the
                            charcoal saturated with water, and the under floor almost ready to drop out. Would you think your refrigerator
                            was saved ? Would you not say, What a fool I was to doctor effects instead of searching for the cause ? All I
                            needed was something to reach the cause. A little skill and solder, and sense, seasonably and suitably served,
                            would have sufficed. But in this tabernacle of the body, we ignore the laws of its construction, and into its
                            fine delicate membranes we crowd any thing we happen to, without regard to its needs or capabilities, and then
                            feel surprised if it cannot keep doing, and the machinery all run smoothly while the vital forces are wearing
                            out, prematurely, in an outlay which is at the same time defrauding the mind and soul of their life and
                            inspiration. Or perhaps, we dress so tightly that the thin delicate texture of the lung cells cannot resist the
                            pressure, and they consequently are not inflated and thus lose their life element and become diseased locally.
                            Then, by not performing their functional work the white blood or chyle, fails to become charged with the oxygen
                            it should receive through the lungs to change it into the healthy vitalizing fluid, and the individual becomes
                            pale and wasted, or burnt up with the fever nature intensifies to assert once more her healthy poise of
                            function. We will speak of another fruitful cause of mischief, for whatever interferes with health of body, has
                            its reflex on the spirit and causes unhappiness and waste. We perhaps bring the delicate valves of the skin
                            almost in contact with the chill or frosty earth, and thus close up the gates nature has provided for the
                            ejection of a large amount of exhausted and impure matter, and then call it disease, when nature opens one of
                            her more apparent relief gates to preserve the life. We have made life so full of inventions, so artificial and
                            complicated with fashion, parade and sham, that there is one continual strain on body and nerve. Although any
                            quantity of labor-saving machines have been tried, yet the ornaments and complications increase in greater ratio
                            and there is no time left for rest of spirit, or for introspection. Many a tired and harassed house-keeper must
                            look longingly forward to the rest of the grave. So far removed are mankind, from simplicity that the greatest
                            boon now is, a resort to the wilderness, the mountains, or the ocean; where man's inventive genius has not yet
                            robbed them of the simple grandeur and charm of nature's works. There they find healing and invigoration. Though
                            all animal, and plant life seeks the light and sunshine, except in its highest meridian, still humanity, with
                            similar internal organs and mechanism, shut themselves up in dark and dingy rooms, and bar out each ray of
                            sunshine that would force itself in, lest carpets be faded, or flies flourish, for even they cannot live in the
                            dark, except in a dormant condition. We exclude life and health conditions, and wonder that we ache, and groan,
                            and die palsied, wonder that life is deteriorating ; wonder that the daughters are not equal to the mothers.
                            Verily the Fathers builded better than they knew, when they thoroughly cleared the land of trees when preparing
                            a location. And the utility of blinds must certainly be questioned, if the glorious Autumnal Sun or blessed
                            warmth of his Winter shining must be excluded, " He maketh his sun to rise on the evil and on the good," and
                            none are so far removed from the Father's loving providence, that this is not their right. Truly said the wise
                            Teacher. " The light is sweet and a pleasant thing it is for the eyes to behold the Sun." "The people that
                            walked in darkness have seen a great light." Why spoken of so exultingly, if light is not blessing, and darkness
                            and anguish almost synonymous curses ? Or, why the promise ? " Moreover the light of the moon, shall be as the
                            light of the sun, and the light of the sun, seven fold, in the day when my people are healed of their wounds and
                            bruises. " Or, why say of those who oppress the helpless that " their sun shall go down at noon, and the earth
                            be darkened in a clear day "? As light, and the opening of the interiors, are in correspondence spiritually, so
                            are sunlight and health in the natural. But one more figure. There stands a house. It is not old and is nicely
                            painted, but there is some defect, or sickness on one of its sides. " Oh, well," you say, " it is made of poor
                            material." But are you sure that is the trouble ? Away upon the roof there is a hole where there should be a
                            shingle. Not near the defect, it is true,but in range with it, and much of the leakage has obeyed the laws of
                            hydrostatics and quietly glided down on the rafters, and has found an outlet through the finish which once made
                            the building a thing of beauty. And that is only an effect which it is proper and right to expect of such a
                            cause. Can you blame nature, or aught but your own neglect, if the building should crumble ? You would have too
                            good an understanding of cause and effect to say that the builder, or his work was the cause of the mischief.
                            You can only say the aperture in the roof should have been attended to. But of the wonderful house which the
                            spirit occupies, the entrances are guarded by sentinels, who are free agents, enlightened by reason and
                            instruction, and though they say, Withhold ! and try to stop the door, inclination and carnal security say, "
                            Leave it open! If a leak start I can mend it. There is pain killer, just the thing." Or if the mechanism gets
                            over-worked and under-fed with the bracing air, or sunlight, use a little liniment, or start it up with a dose
                            of something which is so repulsive that it is in labor till it expels it. And that you call cure. How long can
                            the mortal tenement endure such treatment? Strange that a Harp of thousand strings should keep in tune so long.
                            But we started with the sickness of sin ; and now ask, if the same principles, of common sense we would apply to
                            other things, are not in order here ? Shall we keep on sinning, because Christ died for sinners? or because sin
                            8HAKEE <pb n="15" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> can be confessed ? Does that stop the sin and its consequences which are, physical
                            and spiritual deterioration, any more than the platform saved the refrigerator ? " Mankind were created
                            upright," manly and nobly as lords of lesser creations ; but, " they have sought out many inventions,"— depraved
                            and perverted habits, have named, and classified the effects, and called them inherited evils and disease;
                            whereas, if we viewed them as consequences of our own, perhaps, ignorant transgression, and sought their
                            antidote in avoidance of producing causes, would we not be more consistent ? Can we wonder that Jesus said, "
                            Except a man deny himself and take up his cross daily he cannot be my disciple " ? Not only subdue the passions
                            but the appetites. The leakage which is ruining manhood, is unbridled appetite; and the deceptive invention,
                            that there is a way to avoid its consequences, and thus divorce cause and effect.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lafayette, Indiana, December 6, 1874" TEIform="index"/>Lafayette, Ind., Dec. 6,1874</head><p TEIform="p">Highly Esteemed Editors : In the multiplicity of life's duties, I have neglected one, that to me, is very
                                important, — the renewal of my subscription for your valuable, ah ! priceless little monthly — twenty of
                                which are taken in our great, fashionable and rapidly growing city. I am fully convinced that you have
                                entered into the great and final work of redemption, designed by our Lord and Saviour for the elevation and
                                salvation of man. Your communities are certainly paradisiacal abodes, for the care-worn and sin-sick soul. I
                                believe in an overruling power — a rewarder of all souls, according to their works; and that you will ere
                                long reap an abundant harvest from the precious seeds of truth you are sowing, through the " Shaker and
                                Shakeress." The temperance ladies here read extracts, and sometimes whole documents from your paper. We
                                believe, with yourselves, that gluttony is twin brother to strong drink ; and we highly approve your
                                sentiments on the subject. May the Lord in wisdom direct both you and us in the great work of reform.
                                Inclosed please find one dollar for two copies of S. and S., and much oblige a true friend and sister in the
                                work of reform. I see a great spiritual revelation just at the door. Yours for Progression,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Nagle, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>Sarah A. Nagle</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eating between meals" TEIform="index"/>EATING BETWEEN MEALS</head><p TEIform="p">Half of all ordinary diseases, says Dr. Hall, in his Journal of Health, would be banished from civilized life,and
                            dyspepsia become almost unknown,if every body would eat but.thrice a day at regular times, and not an atom
                            between meals, the interval being not less than five hours, that being the time required to digest a full meal,
                            and pass it out of the stomach. If a person eats between meals, the process of digestion of the food already in
                            the stomach is arrested, until the last which has been eaten is brought into the condition of the former meal;
                            just as, if water is boiling and ice is put in, the whole ceases to boil until the ice is melted and brought to
                            a boiling point, and then the whole boils together. But it is a law of nature that ai: food begins to decay
                            after exposure to heat and moisture for a certain time. If a meal is eaten and in two hours another, the whole
                            remains undigested for seven hours, before which time the rottening process commences, and the man has his
                            stomach full of carbon—the very idea of which is horribly disgusting.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping meals waiting" TEIform="index"/>Keeping Meals Waiting.</head><p TEIform="p">Little things often interfere with our comfort very much, and one small annoyance is for men to delay coming to
                            dinner when called. Sometimes they have an hour or more of work which they will do before quitting and then they
                            go to the house to find the dinner cold, and the cook discouraged. Nothing is more disheartening to a tired
                            woman than a table f ul of dirty dishes ornamenting the table an hour and a half later in the day than usual.
                            Punctuality is a virtue, that men should learn, if they are in the habit of being uncertain about coming to
                            their meals. Any woman worthy the name of housekeeper will be regular with her meals, if it lies within her
                            power to have them so.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Motherland" TEIform="index"/>MOTHERLAND</head><p TEIform="p">Daughters of the nation listen ! Liberty to you appeals! Tearful eyes around you glisten, While she supplicating
                            kneels. To their homes your fathers brought her Through the flood and fire of war; Through the thunderstorm and
                            slaughter Boiled her fair triumphal car. And they said, "All men are equal, With inalienable rights;" Little
                            dreaming of the sequel, That has filled the land with blights. For a while their sons defended That great
                            heritage with power ; Sought the good that was intended, For the country's lasting dower. But the demon,
                            slavery, flourished ; Half approved and half ignored ; At her founts his life was nourish'd, Till he grew to be
                            her lord. Boldly took not heavy duty On such articles as tea; His, not taxes, but rich booty; Even pearls of
                            liberty. Then a lofty manhood" crumbled, Like a soulless mass of clay; For its spirit had been humbled, And its
                            honor swept away. Droop'd the flag, the stars were broken As by clouds of inky hue ! And the stripes disclosed
                            in token, Blood and tears that bondage drew. When, at length, its folds were lifted, By the soldier's dying
                            breath, Was the nation's harvest sifted, From the bitter seeds of death ? Do not intrigue, sloth and plunder
                            Still destroy her ripening grain, While the world is struck with wonder At her turmoil, loss and pain? Is there
                            yet no hope for nations ? Must all constitutions fail, And the heart's uplifted patience, Sink and let despair
                            prevail ? Safe between two veiling oceans, God had kept a land to show, When the Church and State commotions,
                            Blacken'd earth with crushing woe. When the hells that priests created Lit the inquisition's flame, And the
                            flesh was satiated In the Holy Spirit's name. From Republican Genoa To the tortured Spanish land, Came a man,
                            impress'd like Noah, With the rescue God had plan'd. Europe had no aid to furnish ; Tyrants heard no pleading
                            tone ; They had thrones and arms to burnish, Schemes for prowess, all their own. But a woman heard the story Of
                            a land beyond the sea ; And bright visions of its glory, Gifted were her eyes to see. She the jewel treasure
                            offer'd, That adorned her as a queen ; And the gems thus freely proffer'd Bridged the waves to shores unseen,
                            Where shall be a declaration, That will make all women free ! Where our eyes shall see a nation, That is fit for
                            liberty I Where the rights, divine and human, Shall forever be secure, In the land first bought by women, And by
                            her made good and pure. For a government parental Soon will bring true order forth : Place whate'er is
                            accidental, Build "new heaven and new earth." Heavy is the task before us; But it takes no winding course,
                            Cloudless light is shining o'er us, In this day of vital force. Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Blest is the
                            sacred tie that binds In sweet communion kindred minds, Whose hopes, and hearts, and aims are one, To live for
                            truth and that alone. Thus sharing union, comfort, care, With Christian zeal unite in prayer, That perfect love
                            and peace may reign, Throughout the whole of Zion's plain. We all must of this love partake To comprehend how
                            Christ can make Our earthly home a type of heaven, Where death is banished, life is given. Here we behold the
                            Gospel light Which shineth from the mountain's height, Where truth and justice bear the sway, And every sin is
                            cast away.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Think before you speak what you shall speak..." TEIform="index"/>Think before you speak what you shall speak...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Think before you speak what you shall speak, why you should speak, about whom you are to speak, what will come
                            from what you may speak, what may be the benefit from what you may speak, and lastly, who may be listening to
                            what you may speak. Turn your speech seven ways, and there will never come any harm from what you have spoken. "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The religion of a nation ought to be the embodiment of its highest intelligence..." TEIform="index"/>The religion of a nation ought to be the embodiment of its highest intelligence...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The religion of a nation ought to be the embodiment of its highest intelligence in the most solemn moments of
                            that intelligence." But that is not the fact to-day in any country.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual aspiration" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL ASPIRATION</head><p TEIform="p">Our Zion home is lovely, secluded, and secure, And precious our relations, so peaceful, and so pure; Not all
                            earth's fading pleasures, or wealth it has to give, Shall lure me from these treasures, for these alone I live.
                            More fervently 111 labor to make the gospel mine, That all its ties more firmly around my heart may twine; Be
                            mine the true affections, which from the earth are riven, Which cling to Saints and Angels, to Christ and God,
                            in heaven. Be mine the Christian crosses, the sorrow and the love, The daily prayers and watchings, that lift
                            the soul above, And lead the spirit onward, to seek the higher life, Away from earth's corruption, confusion,
                            care and strife. Be mine to hold communion with mortals robed in white, To rise with them in triumph to realms
                            of endless light; Where Jesus and blest Mother, receive their faithful band Of souls, who braved all trial to
                            gain the summer land. With searching beams unclouded, roll on thou perfect day, When shade, and storm, and
                            tempest, shall all have passed away. Flow on thou crystal river, thy broad and swelling tide Will bear the weary
                            pilgrim, to life's immortal side. With heart attuned to gladness, I hear the chants above, And feel the Angels
                            wafting their sweet redeeming love; And well I know my Saviors, will pilot me safe o'er, To rest in peaceful
                            triumph, and glory evermore.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifestations in New York, Dr. Slade" TEIform="index"/>MANIFESTATIONS IN NEW YORK CITY, DR. SLADE</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Banner: Gotham is being stirred to its very centre by Spiritualism. The following is taken from the Daily
                            Graphic: " The interest in so-called 'Spiritual manifestations ' which has been developed by the course of the
                            Daily Graphic in regard to the matter is rapidly growing. The Herald, following, as it is wont to do, the
                            example of the Daily Graphic, recently sent a reporter to Chittenden, whom the Eddys, however, declined to admit
                            to their seances. The Sun has lately been publishing a large quantity of letters on the subject; and at Elder
                            Evans' Shalier Conventionlast night, the greater part of the conversation was on the subject of Spiritualism.
                            The matter is in a fair way to be thoroughly investigated at last, and we are sincerely sorry that, so far asthe
                            Chittenden manifestations are concerned, the Herald has been deprived of an opportunity to test their
                            genuineness." Elder Evans also gave the allopathic doctors grape and canister, and ventilated class-legislating,
                            quack doctor, no diploma, ecclesiastical medical inquisitional bill, and the Albany Legislature for having
                            passed the star chamber act. He held his immense audience at Steinway Hall spell-bound for nearly two hours. God
                            and good spirits bless Elder Evans for his brave words, say I. "Eternal vigilance is the price of liberty."
                            Principles and not men, universality, not individuality. This is not Dr. Dake's nor mediums' funeral, it is the
                            people's. And. if such innovations upon civil liberty are not frowned down by the people, we will sooner or
                            later have cause to regret our indifference and "masterly inactivity.''—Banner.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Way to Avoid Calumny" TEIform="index"/>The Way to Avoid Calumny</head><p TEIform="p"> "If any one speaks ill of thee," said Epictetus, " consider whether he hath truth on his side; and if so reform
                            thyself, that his censures may not affect thee." When Anaximander was told that the very boys laughed at his
                            singing, "Ay," said he, "then I must learn to sing better." Plato being told that he had many enemies who spoke
                            ill of him, said : "It is no matter: I will live so that none shall believe them." Hearing, at another time,
                            that an intimate friend of his had spoken detractingly of him, he said : " I am sure he would not do it if he
                            had not some reason for it." This is the surest, as well as the noblest way of drawing the sting out of a
                            reproach, and the true method of preparing a man for that great and only relief against the pains of calumny —a
                            good conscience.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those principles which lift the soul..." TEIform="index"/>Those principles which lift the soul...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Those principles which lift the soul, From nature's plane to heaven's height, Consume the dross, but leave the
                            gold, A shining metal, pure and bright."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Smith</byline></div2><pb n="16" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of peace" TEIform="index"/>VOICE OF PEACE</head><p TEIform="p">1. O'er sea and strand and peopled land, The voice of Peace is heard, It speaks with sweet inspiring tones, And
                            many souls are stirred. It lifts the vail where wrongs prevail, Which long were covered o'er, Revealing harvests
                            of life's fruit Despoiled by cruel war. 2. O, sad'ning sight of death and blight, Of mis'ry, want and woe, The
                            waste of manhood's noble life, Whence cultured wealth should flow; The homes and lands which mourn the hands
                            That bore the deadly steel, Whose skill was turned to matchless strife, Instead of human weal. 3. For throbbing
                            hearts have felt the darts, And borne the curse of war, And nations perished in the scourge, Beneath the battle
                            star. God speed the time, when peace divine On earth shall bear the sway, When Love shall twine her laurel
                            wreath To crown the perfect day. 4. The bards of old in song foretold A time when wars should (tease, When earth
                            would bloom a paradise, Beneath the reign of peace. That golden age on hist'ry's page Shall gleam in truthful
                            lines, For even now its dawn appears, Through bright prophetic signs.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To sustain shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>TO SUSTAIN SHAKER AID SHAKERESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Let Believers contribute eighty cents to each individual, and receive, in bulk, as many papers as individuals —
                            if they wish. Can have an equal number mailed to outside subscribers, by sending ten cents postage for each
                            subscriber. For subscribers, in excess of the above, canvassers will remit fifty cents. Canvassers are to
                            receive, of outsiders, sixty cents. Give subscribers' names in full. The three volumes '73, '74, '75, may be had
                            for fl.10. By Believers for $1.00.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Merry Christmas" TEIform="index"/>A MERRY CHRISTMAS</head><p TEIform="p">December 25,1874. Elder Frederick — Beloved Father in Christ —Permit me, on this, my first Christmas with you, to
                            acknowledge, while I gratefully remember your many acts and words of kindness to me, during my residence with
                            you. The labors of your pen have been to me like water to the traveler on the barren desert — like refreshing
                            showers from heaven to the parched earth. And now, on this recurring festival, let me congratulate you on the
                            peace and happiness enjoyed by your flock. May you long be spared to minister to an ever-increasing family — to
                            witness many returns of this joyous and happy season. Such is the prayer of Yours truly in the Gospel,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gill, David" TEIform="persName"/>David Gill, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hollister, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Hollister
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Hollister, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Hollister</persName>, Nov. 17, 1874, aged 66 years. Canaan, N.
                            Y.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McComb, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary McComb
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="McComb, Mary" TEIform="persName">Mary McComb</persName>, Dec. 17,1874, aged 80 years. South Union, Ky.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ostrom, Emiline" TEIform="index"/>Emiline Ostrom
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Ostrom, Emiline" TEIform="persName">Emiline Ostrom</persName>, Dec. 19,1874, aged 55 years. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gates, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Anna Gates
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Gates, Anna" TEIform="persName">Anna Gates</persName>, Dec. 25,1874, aged 83 years. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Receipts and expenditures for S. and S. 1873" TEIform="index"/>RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR S. AND S. 1873</head><p TEIform="p">Received, $2,148.75— Expended, $2,061.48. 1874— " $1,807.02— " $1,678.15. Leaving $215.75 for editing, folding,
                            directing and other services, for the two past years.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear editor and editress:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Editor and Editress :</head><p TEIform="p">I have been much edified in reading your editorials, the year past, likewise many of the articles in both
                            departments. They were rare specimens of literary merit, sound, logical, argumentative, scriptural, full of
                            pith, pathos and the fire of God's Truth. That is what the world and many among Believers, need, and must have.
                            Jesus "made himself of no repute" — not by immoral conduct, but by bearing witness to the Truth. He put forth
                            Ideas, far in advance of the age. They were rejected by many, especially the Jewish orthodoxy. To them He was an
                            "Infidel." That the Good Samaritan, whom Jesus approved, was an Infidel, we have no doubt. He showed his faith
                            by his works. To this class of Infidels in the world, who make no profession of Christianity—who gain Heaven by
                            being honest in their dealings with their fellow men — our little paper meets with acceptance. Blessed are such
                            Infidels ! I am willing to stake my all with this class, be they in what part of the world -— in what "world
                            they may. It was this class of Infidels, in its highest types, that framed our United States Constitution — who,
                            in their wisdom, and far-seeing Statesmanship, took the necessary precaution forever to exclude the possibility
                            of introducing the Jewish War-God, or any other God or Christ, or Bible into that Sacred Instrument. Again, we
                            say, Blessed are such Infidels! We unite with all such, for the preservation of the Constitution of these United
                            States — as it was—as it is—as it shall be. It was made for man — for all men and all women—of all nations,
                            kindred, tongues and peoples, under the Heavens — for all Religions — subject to no eclesiastical tinkering. So
                            we say Hands off.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Prescott, North Union, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Katie King exposed" TEIform="index"/>KATIE KING EXPOSED</head><p TEIform="p">It is said that a young woman personated Katie, when the real Katie was not forthcoming. The Truth Seeker thus
                            discourses: "It was found she had made her entrance and exit into and from the cabinet by means of a panel or
                            secret drawTer in the partition, and with her artful representations, she had succeeded in " deceiving the very
                            elect." The philosopher and close observer, R. D. Owen, had faithfully attended upon Katy's seances, and has he
                            not detailed the whole "wonderful affair" in the Atlantic Monthly, and characterized the same as the most
                            remarkable representations of spirit power? Now, however, since the fraud is exposed, the good man is compelled
                            to acknowledge himself deceived by dishonest mediums. A lesson is to be learned from all this. If Mr. and Mrs.
                            Holmes have been frauds, it does not prove that all others are. Chaff does not disprove the existence of wheat,
                            and all the lies in the world do not falsify one truth. But so long as money is to be made in the roll of
                            mediums, it is not strange, perhaps, that dishonesty is resorted to. The public must be chary, and not believe
                            too readily all representations made. ' Try the spirits, that ye be not deceived.' " Words of wisdom, like
                            apples of gold in basins of silver.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Biter bit" TEIform="index"/>THE BITER BIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Train, George F." TEIform="persName"/>George F. Train thus writes me :</byline><p TEIform="p">Miller's Bath Hotel, 41 W. 26 st., New York, Dec. 29. Dear Elder Evans: Shakerism continues to shake
                            Christianity, and Spiritualism continues to demoralize Christians. After breaking up Gordon, the Hugh Boy at
                            Apollo Hall, medium Wassen at Tammany, after exposing Katie King at Philadelphia, after fighting the
                            Spiritualists at their meetings and through the press for years, Dr. Miller, who went to Chittenden to capture
                            the Eddys, has himself been captured ! The biter has been bit at last; he has gone over, bait, line, hook and
                            sinker 1 His last postal card reads : " Prepare to meet thy God, for he is up here among the mountains."</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Surrendered" TEIform="index"/>SURRENDERED</head><p TEIform="p">Thus runs a postal card from Dr. Miller: Chittenden, Dec. 28,1874. Dear Elder Evans : Your article on
                            Spiritualism in Tribune, Dec. 26, is just at hand. You are all sound on the genuineness of some of these
                            manifestations ; I have been through it — have been with the Eddys ten days. They are as true as steel: the
                            truth about them has not half been told. I differ with you on the subject that Spiritualism is not a Jleligion,
                            but a Science. I think it is the Science of Religion. The Eddys have captured me, soul, body, and spirit; old
                            things have passed away, and all things have become new. Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, Eli" TEIform="persName"/>Eli Miller</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Steady I' is the word..." TEIform="index"/>Steady I' is the word...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Steady I" is the word, in the English military service, in times of trial — in the crisis of a battle — when
                            defeat and victory balance each other. So say we — Steady, friends, steady! keep cool and collected, if you
                            expect to ride the whirlwind of Spiritualism and direct the storm of Materialization to ends useful to humanity.
                            Ed. of 8. &amp; 8.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>