<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0301" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18730101" TEIform="date">January 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-8</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                     <p>Vol. III. No. 1. F. W. EVANS, Editor. MONTHLY. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Mt. Lebanon, Ool. Co.N. Y.Y.
                        January, 1873. Fifty Cents per annum.</p>
--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salutatory" TEIform="index"/>SALUTATORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">As Eighteen hundred and seventythree (1873) is to be our date for the next twelve months, we desire for you a
                            joyful, Happy New Year. In accepting the chief editorship of our little paper, the burden is much lightened by
                            the fact that I shall be supported by the experience of my " well done" predecessor, Elder G. Albert Lomas, who
                            has kindly consented to continue his contributions, and, also, to otherwise help in the publication and
                            management of the Shaker and Shakeress. His partial withdrawal is due to the heavy and afflicting losses by
                            incendiary fires in the beautiful village of Watervliet, where he resides. We would that those who have so
                            ruthlessly inflicted these losses upon a quiet and peaceable people were possessed of a different spirit, and
                            impelled by better motives. "But the wicked will do wickedly," and " one sinner destroyeth much good." As one
                            agency in saving and redeeming ourselves and our race from these existing and latent evils, from the antagonisms
                            and animosities, envyings and divisions of interest in the present so- cial system, we issue this, our Monthly.
                            We can sincerely and understanding^ pray for those who seek our destruction, as we also labor and pray for " the
                            peace of the city " and nation where our lot is cast. Our all of character, life, and property is embarked in
                            and devoted to the work of human redemption. We intend, in our whole lives, to return good for evil, and to do
                            nothing but good to poor, suffering humanity. NEW PLAN. Agreeable to our fundamental idea of a diiality in the
                            Divine government of the universe, and also in our own Society organizations, the Shaker will henceforth contain
                            a department edited by Eldress Antoinette Doolittle, open to contributions from the Sisterhood of our Order; and
                            to her such contributions, and other communications from females, both within and without the Shaker fraternity,
                            may be addressed. It is confidently expected that this arrangement will meet not only the warm approval of our
                            own people, but also of our friends in the outer world, where woman's rights, duties, and privileges are being
                            so intelligently discussed both in Europe and America. The very interested attention which Shakerism, as a
                            system of ideas, has hitherto attracted from the friends of co-operation and community, and which it is now
                            attracting from Spiritualists, it is also destined to receive from the advocates of peace, of temperance, of
                            hygiene and physiology, and from the woman's suffragists and land reformers. Indeed, we invite all progressive
                            minds and classes, all truth-loving, religious persons, from the most scientific rationalist to the revivalist,
                            to take the Shaker and Shakeress, and thereby help us to inaugurate the blessed era of universal virtue, wherein
                            civil governments and all society organizations shall, by their organic laws, do as we would individually be
                            done by. The Shaker Communities are but as the seeds of the future, or as a handfull of grapes on the topmost
                            branches of the " vine of the earth," to show what the full crop will yet be, when the fullness of the Gentiles
                            shall have been gathered in, and humanity be harvested by the great reapers, Time and Truth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Man's duty" TEIform="index"/>MAN'S DUTY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Elder Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">Man's duty consists simply in his being true to himself. With all the obligations he may be under to others, with
                            all the cares, interest and regard to any living creature — to any earthly object coming under his observation,
                            with all his indebtedness and responsi- bility to God and high heaven, if found unfaithful in any respect, then
                            he is untrue to himself. That his cares and affections may become universal and unselfish, not circum- scribed
                            and confined to himself, his family, or special friends, his interests should be as broad as the Universe, and
                            should reach the heavens, that he may be able to bless G-od and His work, and thus find his relation with the
                            Angels. Indeed, his cares and affections should extend down into the lower parts of the earth, to be able to
                            meet his fellow-man in earthly conditions, and express a sympathy and love that would touch his soul. They
                            should penetrate prisons of darkness where the ignorant, the vile and the lowest elements of humanity may be
                            taken hold of; where minds may be enlightened, educated, developed, and so elevated that man can live in God.
                            Thus he would be able to comprehend his requirements, and become qualified to co-operate with Him, thereby
                            becoming a saviour, to aid in the regeneration of the human race. For, through man's agency, G-od has always
                            worked to elevate human conditions, introduce reforms, reveal light, and open dispensations. And He has, by his
                            Spirit, always prepared the way, by raising up individuals filled with knowledge, and baptized with power,
                            sufficient to capacitate other souls to be equal to his requirements; to give progress in teaching, leading,
                            protecting, and bringing mankind nearer to Him. Thus deputized, man becomes God's vicegerent upon earth, and
                            opens the way for " Saviours to come up on Mount Zion " to judge the earth. " Know ye not that ye shall judge
                            even angels?" In all ages, from the days of God's everlasting covenant made with Abraham, to the giving of the
                            Law, through Moses, and the delivering of Israel from captivity, through Deborah, to the preaching of repentance
                            through John the Baptist, who opened the way for a still greater work — that of salvation from sin — through
                            Jesus, who, by his anointing, became "the Messiah, which is, being interpreted, the Christ; " and still fur-
                            ther down to the days of Ann Lee, the female Messiah, or Christ, whose testimony is before the world to-day a
                            protecting, saving power unto those who accept and live it. Ye seekers after a redeeming Gospel, ye who would
                            know its practical operations, examine critically the life and doctrines of the Churches of to-day; and, when
                            you have found the body whose members are "saviours," as was Jesus, mark such Church as the Church of God, and
                            there make your offerings. And let that Church which is not able to bear this investigation, no more name the
                            name of Christ. And let the individual who is unable to endure this searching light of heaven, no more claim the
                            appellation of Christian. Truth will prevail, despite the obloquy and revilings of man, and despite the dishonor
                            brought upon the cause of Justice, of true <pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEE A-ISTD and undefiled religion, by weak and
                            cowardly pretenders of the Christian faith. And though, for a season, truth be crushed, yet "Zion will arise and
                            shine," and souls under its protection will alone triumph in glory.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of prayer" TEIform="index"/>THE SPIRIT OF PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham</byline><p TEIform="p">To illustrate the true spirit of prayer and private devotion, we will consider the subject in the following
                            light: A child that has pure love and affection for its father, runs to him with simple joy and delight at every
                            opportunity ; it holds him by the hand as long as the occasion lasts; is always rejoiced to meet him, and sorry
                            when duty requires a temporary separation. In these joyful interviews, it prattles forth, in simple confidence,
                            all its sorrows and all its joys. It receives all the caresses and commands of its father with equal delight,
                            and enters cheerfully into all his designs and wishes, having no desire but to please and do the will of its
                            father. This represents the state of a soul, whose devotion is nothing less than his whole life given to God,
                            and who embraces every opportunity of holding holy intercourse with the Father of spirits. In contrast with
                            this, we may suppose a child full of self-love, self-will, and pursuits of its own, which, though it fears, does
                            not love its father. It is taught that it must go, at stated times every day, and bow and perform certain other
                            acts of reverence to its father, and that if it neglect, the father will punish it with the greatest severity.
                            The same selfishness which prompts this child to pursue its own sports and mischief, may induce it to be very
                            punctual in attending to these times and forms of reverence, not because it loves its father, but because its
                            selfishness makes it dread the threatened punishment. Hence, though it has no love for these acts of reverence,
                            nor for its father who requires them, yet it will carefully perform them for its own sake. These acts of
                            reverence form no part of its happiness, but are only per- formed to escape the misery of chastisement. For this
                            reason it always feels as if these requirements were a drawback from its happiness — a hindrance of so much of
                            its time from pursuing its own ends. Consequently it is always cramped, hurried, and confused when in the
                            presence of its father; is sorry when the time of reverence has arrived, and glad when it is over. To set this
                            in still another light, Ave may suppose a third child, which is not driven to these acts of reverence by threats
                            and dread of punishment, but by promises of reward in apples, cakes and toys; such things as it loves. Now, as
                            the father is not the object of its love, but the objects of reward which he has offered, though the child may
                            be very punctual in attendance, and have the appearance of love and zeal, perhaps equal to the first-mentioned
                            child, yet, as its motives are purely mercenary and selfish, this external show of respect to its father, though
                            specious, is unreal. Self is the idol of the child's heart. As a proof of this, let the father withhold his
                            wonted rewards, and, though he be otherwise kind, you will see a sudden change in the zeal of the child. It is
                            disappointed of its mercenary expectations, and is full of murmuring and discontent. As soon, therefore, as it
                            gives over all expectations of receiving any more rewards, having nothing to hope, and never having been taught
                            to fear, it will throw off all restraint and wholly neglect to reverence its father. Thus will it be with
                            mercenary worshippers of God, who serve him for reward and not from love. While the child which truly loves its
                            father will forget its cakes and toys, and forsaking them will run to his father and be wholly satisfied with
                            his company, hearing his counsel and doing his will. "Verily, except ye become as this little child, ye can in
                            nowise enter into the Kingdom of God."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel of life" TEIform="index"/>THE ANGEL OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>Elder H. L. Eades</byline><p TEIform="p">It is certainly true, that the angel life is one of innocence and freedom from sin. But, as " all have sinned and
                            come short of the glory of God," the possibility of a sinless state, in this life, is questioned, doubted,
                            disbelieved, by the world, professor and profane; they say, " the child must make crooked marks before it can
                            make straight lines;" "the girl must thrum discords, before she can produce harmonies," etc. This is true; but,
                            if the child always makes the straightest lines possible, it is all the time doing right; hence, sinless. The
                            same with the music. But, should the child wilfully make crooked lines, which is not a necessity, this would be
                            sin, but it does not follow therefrom, that straight lines and har- monies are an after impossibility. The first
                            difficulty says Cardaillac is this : " The first part of our life is fled before we have the capacity of
                            reflection and observation ; while the impressions which we receive from earliest infancy, are from material
                            objects. The wants of our animal nature, and the prior development of the external senses, all con- tribute to
                            concentrate, even from the first breath of life, our attention to the world with- out. " The second, passes
                            without our caring to observe ourselves. The outer life is too agreeable to allow the soul to tear itself from
                            its gratifications., and return frequently upon itself. At the period when the material world has at length
                            palled upon the senses (which it invariably does at some period of life), when the taste and desire of
                            reflection gradually become predominant, we find ourselves, in a certain sense, already made up, and it is
                            impossible for us to resume our life from its commencement, and to discover how we have become what we now are."
                            " Hitherto," says Ancillon, " external objects have exclusively riveted our attention (not necessarily so), but
                            let us recoil upon ourselves ; the scene changes, the charm is gone, difficulties accumulate, in a word, every
                            thing within repels, every thing without attracts, and thus it is our life runs like water through our
                            fingers—carried along, lost; whelmed in our life, and the reflective Ego which distinguishes self from its
                            transitory modifications is never developed in the majority of mankind at all." Now it seems that the
                            possibility of obviating the foregoing difficulties to the angel life had not occurred to these philosophers. "
                            I thank thee, 0 Father, Lord of heaven and earth, thatthou hast hid these things from the wise and prudent, and
                            hast revealed them unto babes." How much superior was the exalted and inspired wisdom of Mother Ann, who fairly
                            cut this gordian knot by her teaching that all children should be taught to turn their thoughts within, on
                            spiritual things, by the time they were four years old, and thus grow in favor of God as well as men, and retain
                            their angelhood, that when the second stage spoken of should arrive, they would have a balance wheel to steady
                            their action, thus entering into greater harmonies instead of beginning at this late day to thrum discords. All
                            who have neglected her advice have wofully witnessed the truths enunciated by these philosophers, and can fully
                            sympathize with the feelings of a conscientious world's schoolmaster who writes as follows: " There is
                            considerable enjoyment in teaching these boys. But oh ! what a bitter grief it is to watch the gradual course of
                            their corruption. Nothing seems to drive the angel out of them so fast as sexual vulgarity. There are boys here
                            who were really cherubic when I first came among them. With what yearning tenderness I used to lean over them.
                            They also have eaten of the tree of knowledge of good and evil — have become as gods — have discovered their
                            nakedness, and so have begun to adjust the fig leaves." . At this stage we must admit the difficulties to be
                            great, though not absolutely insurmountable. The spiritual neglected; the cerebrum put to bed and sound asleep.
                            The cry comes up " Is there no balm in Gilead ? Is there no physician there ?" A skillful one is now in demand,
                            and if the spirti brain cannot be roused into action, the case is, at present, hopeless. We must see the poor
                            victims, one after another, prostrate before the god of this world, and lead for a season a life of sin, until
                            the third stage spoken of arrives and reflection and reason return, when, if they have suffered enough, they may
                            now take the Father's advice, and begin to become as little children, and by confessing, repenting of, and
                            forsaking all sin, may yet be one of that innumerable number which was seen, besides the 144,000 virgins who
                            followed the Lamb, etc. But the danger is, that the mass of them will be swallowed up in some of the popular
                            sects of whom a certain writer says: " The popular religions north and south are but devilish counterfeits of
                            Christianity ; they have ceased to be the light of the world. Instead of being a terror to evil doers, they have
                            become their safest hiding places," etc. Hence, knowing and confessing themselves to be sinners, priests and
                            people, they resort to a vicarious atonement, of which, Gregg, in his u Creed of Christendom," thus pertinently
                            discourseth: " Sin contains its own retribution and pen- alty, as surely as the acorn contains the oak. Its
                            consequence is its punishment. It needs no other, and can have no heavier. Its conse2 <pb n="3" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>
                            SHAKERES8. 3 quence is involved in its commission, and cannot be separated from it. Punishment (let us fix this
                            in our mind) is not the execution of a sentence, but the occurrence of an effect. It is ordained of God to
                            follow guilt. This conviction, once settled in our understandings, will wonderfully clear up our views on the
                            subject of pardon and redemption. Eedemption becomes then a regenerating process. We can be redeemed from the
                            punishment of sin only by being redeemed from its commission. Neither can there be any such thing as vicarious
                            atonement, which is a relic of heathen conceptions of an angered Deity, to be propitiated by offerings and
                            sacrifices. Punishment, being the result of sin, cannot be borne by other than the sinner. It is for orthodox
                            dialectics to explain how divine justice can be impugned by pardoning the guilty,and yet vindicatedbj punishing
                            the innocent. The sin which has absorbed our soul may be repented of — may be turned from ; but in the case of a
                            sin of which you have induced another to partake, you may repent of, you may, after agonizing struggles, regain
                            the path of virtue, pour spirit may re-achieve its purity through much anguish, and after .many stripes; but the
                            weaker one whom you led astray, whom you made sharer in your guilt, but whom you cannot make sharer in your
                            repentance and amendment, whose downward course (the first step of which you taught), which you cannot check,
                            you are compelled to witness. What forgiveness of sin can avail you there ? There is your perpetual, your
                            inevitable punishment." It must be admitted that the sin here commented on, is, above all others, the most
                            heinious, probably the last to be forgiven, but even this must sometime in vast eternity have an end, else the
                            appalling doctrine of endless hell torments would be true, which is revolting when we remember God is good as
                            well as just. Our good parent, Father James Whittaker, took a lively sense of its enormity when he publicly
                            remarked that it was a " great consolation to him to know that no human beings could lift their eyes in hell and
                            point to him as the cause of their misery," and happy are all who can in truth say likewise. After all, friend
                            Gregg to the contrary notwithstanding, there is such a thing as pardon. If thy brother trespass against thee, if
                            he repent, forgive him, pardon him. So can a merciful God lift the sufferings from a soul that has repented and
                            made all amends in his power. If he could not, then the attribute of mercy were unnecessary. " Whosoever sins
                            you (my successors), remit — pardon — they are remitted unto them." Jno. 20, 23.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dual government" TEIform="index"/>DUAL GOVERNMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Leonard, W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder W. Leonard</byline><p TEIform="p">" In the beginning God created man, and called their name Adam." Thus the race was started under generative law;
                            and this law they were to bind upon their children. Their order was complete, and God blessed them, and said to
                            them, " Multiply and have dominion over every living thing which moveth on the earth." If they stood upright the
                            government would stand ; if they fell, it would be broken. They did fall, and sorrowful have been and are the
                            consequences to the race. By this fall, and their posterity "sinning after the similitude of their
                            transgression," we were all brought under the curse of broken law. Consequently man seized the power to rule
                            over woman, and she lost her standing by his side, and all rights pertaining thereto. Reasoning from these
                            premises, it is plain that it was not intended that the earth should stand exclusively under male power. The
                            Patriarchal rule, the Law, the first Gospel Age, the Witnesses, in both sexes, all point to a steady struggle to
                            reproduce a dual government in these last days. The Church, brought in by Jesus, was still under male rule,
                            which rendered it imperfect. Its founders and leaders saw and preached but in part. Jesus, reasoning from the
                            past, upon what was yet to come, predicted a falling away. He foresaw that Christ's second coming would be like
                            unto a marriage; or would produce a Church governed jointly by man and woman, corresponding to the first Adam,
                            the figure. This government, as was predicted, commenced with the Latter-day Church. Ann Lee, a great
                            revelationist, received from the Christ Spirit the same light and principles that were lived out by Jesus. She
                            established a Church strictly under male and female government, which has existed nearly a century, restoring
                            woman to her place, which she lost by the fall. Ann Lee, and the best seers in her Order, predicted that dual
                            governments would become universal; and the best evidence of the truth of their revelations are the changes
                            which have come over spiritual and earthly governments during the last half century. Then, to suffer not a woman
                            to speak in public, especially the churches, was the rule and not the exception. Many leading minds have seen
                            and acknowledged the principles of this Church, but have stumbled at this dual government. They have hesitated,
                            doubted, and stood back; and the Church has sadly felt the effects of such hesitation; but, like an army with
                            banners, onward moves this new governmental idea in the civil and ecclesiastical world of thought. Half a
                            century since, women could find no place as teachers, as public lecturers, critics on political matters, voters,
                            or preachers, as they now do. All this has a significant meaning, and the question is, what will it grow to and
                            end in ? Who would have thought, in the days when John Endicott hung women in Boston for daring to speak in
                            public after he commanded them not, and found support from men taught in the old school theology, that, in less
                            than two centuries after, halls and pulpits would be opened to them by the hundred; or that scientific and
                            legislative bodies would give them public hearing ? Who would then have dreamed that, in the councils of this
                            nation and from every quarter, a host of strong-minded men would speak out and demand for women the right of
                            suffrage ? Evidently such a condition of things is upon us; and who, in view of this can say there has not been
                            a steady advance, toward a dual government, since God established it in this Church and Order? For ages past, a
                            period of universal peace has been predicted, from which innumerable blessings would flow to nations and
                            peoples. Be it remembered that this was to come in the latter days. Appealing to universal history, are we to
                            expect this millennial state to result from the rule of man alone ? When political troubles have arisen among
                            disagreeing rulers, men have furnished swordsmen by regiments, and have always been ready to turn out their
                            warriors instead of peacemakers. Men suffer greatly in war by their barbarity; but women have been by far the
                            greatest sufferers. Millions of them have lost fathers, husbands, sons and friends who have been sacrificed upon
                            the battle fields of the various nations of the earth. Besieging armies have indiscriminately slain untold
                            numbers of mothers and infants. Mothers and daughters have been worse than murdered, and left to starve; they
                            have been carried into captivity and sold as slaves, or left to perish by thousands in barren and desolate
                            places of the earth. If noble women find their places in national councils, will they not look back on these
                            bloody pages of history and strive to turn the weapons of cruelty into plow-shares ? Will they not labor to have
                            the prophecies of the ancient sons of God fulfilled? Is not God pressing on this movement, in order to bring
                            about this universal brotherhood for which the world, through the instrumentality of dual governments, seems
                            stirred up to work and look ? Man first invented the still, and from it he has poured out the liquid fire that
                            has scourged and consumed large portions of the race. It has proved a curse to both sexes, and a moral
                            desolation to all nations, filling prisons, lunatic asylums, and pauper houses, and turning the feet of many
                            into the paths of sin and sorrow. No pen can paint the sufferings that have been brought upon our world by this
                            terrible evil, and upon women in particular. Accordingly, we see her rising up in society, striving to banish
                            the pest, and lift the curse from herself and children. Temperance reforms have not proved a perfect success:
                            popularity and pride have required large revenues for support. Statesmen, to collect these, have worked against
                            these reforms. Their laws so encourage distillation and importation remain in full force. Thus, those men who
                            sit at the helm of power by law crush out all temperance experiments, and drunkenness still continues among all
                            classes, statesmen themselves setting the example. Would this be if Woman had the ballot, and a place in the
                            councils of the nation ? Judging from their past example in temperance and other reforms, we think not. As long
                            as navies and standing armies exist, and intemperance is thus supported by law-makers, it is impossible to
                            uproot prostitution. From the day that woman receives her political rights, which the age will surely grant,
                            better laws and morals may be hoped for. The reform will pass through both Church and State. <pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>
                            8HAKEE A.ND For nearly a century the Shaker Church has stood under this form of dual government, and proved its
                            blessings. Their spiritual and temporal government both stand in this Order, and they have never ceased to pray
                            that, under the law of progress, it may yet find its place in every land and nation upon earth. Whenever this
                            takes place, society will begin to realize the ruling power of this Church, what it is, and where it originated;
                            and, though it may be new to the age, they will find it as old as the heavens; that it began in the morning of
                            creation, and, instead of opposing, the rational, thinking classes will advocate it. From their own political
                            plane they will cast their eyes upward, and see that, while they enjoy it on earth, the dual order exists in the
                            mansions of the blessed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful extract" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL EXTRACT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Robertson, Frederick W." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The following extract from Frederick W. Robertson, expresses the laboring thoughts of my mind better than I could
                            find words to do it with. The Bible and Inspiration are subjects of investigation fully in order at this present
                            time. " The Inspiration of the Bible is a large subject. I hold it to be inspired, not dictated. It is the Word
                            of God — the words of man; as the former, perfect; as the latter, imperfect. God the Spirit, as the Sanctifier,
                            does not produce absolute perfection of human character. God the Spirit, as an Inspirer, does not produce
                            absolute perfection of human knowledge ; and for the same reason in both cases — the human element which is
                            mixed up with the Divine element—else there could have been no progressive dispensations. Let us take the case,
                            the history of the creation. I hold that a spiritual revelation from God must involve scientific incorrectness :
                            it could not be from God unless it did. Suppose that the cosmogany had been given in terms which would satisfy
                            our present scientific knowledge, or say rather, the terms of absolute scientific truth. It is plain that, in
                            this case, the men of that day would have rejected its authority; they would have said ' Here is a man who tells
                            us the earth goes round the sun, and the sky which we see to be a steroma fixed and not far up, is infinite
                            space, with no firmament at all/ and so on. ' Can we trust one in matters unseen who is manifestly in error in
                            things seen and level to the senses ? Can we accept his revelation about God's nature and man's duty, when he is
                            wrong in things like these?' Thus, the faith of this and subsequent ages must have been purchased at the expense
                            of the unbelief of all previous ages. I hold it, therefore, as a proof of the inspiration of the Bible, and
                            divinely wise, to have given a spiritual revelation, i. e. a revelation concerning the truths of the soul, and
                            its relation to God, in popular and incorrect language. Do not mistake that word incorrect; incorrect is one
                            thing; false, another. It is scientifically incorrect to say that the sun rose this morning, but it is not
                            false, because it conveys all that is required, for the nonce, to be known about the fact, time, etc. And if God
                            were giving a revelation in this present day, He would give it in modern phraseology, and the men He inspired
                            would talk of sunrise, sunset, etc. Men of science smile at the futile attempts to reconcile Moses and geology.
                            I give up the attempt at once, and say, the inspiration of the Bible remains intact for all that — nay, it would
                            not have been inspired, except on this condition of incorrectness. " Neologianism is a large word, and embraces
                            an almost endless variety of views ; but, to be candid, I look upon Bibliolatry with quite as much dislike as
                            Arnold did — as pernicious, dangerous to true views of God and His revelation to the human race, and the cause
                            of much bitter Protestant Popery, or claims to infallibility of interpretation, which nearly every party puts
                            forth. I believe Bibliolatry to be as superstitious, as false, and almost as dangerous as Romanism." I think
                            quite so; they are mother and daughter.— Ed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy" TEIform="index"/>CELIBACY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Frazer</byline><p TEIform="p">" What are the effects of abstinence from exercising the generative functions ? " Freedom from all diseases of
                            those functions. " What does your eighty years' experience contribute to physiological science ? " It
                            contributes the above important fact. '' What forms of disorder arise from such abstinence ? " No specific form
                            of disease is incident to a virgin life — the life we live. We enjoy better health than do those outside our
                            body. '' How does it affect length of days ? " Favorably. The writer is seventy years of age; was thirty when he
                            came here, and indorses the above answers in all their details. To philosophers and physiologists we say, form
                            your theories according to the above facts, and we will abide the result. We assume that man is in possession of
                            and manifests a two-fold life. The lower, represented by the baser propensities ; the higher, by the attributes
                            of goodness, truth, mercy, and all aspirations God-ward. In view of this assumption, the above questions may be
                            summed up by one inquiry : " Can men and women live, in the exercise of the higher, divine life, to the
                            exclusion of the exercise of the generative functions ? " We take the affirmative of this question, and it is
                            for philosophers, medical men and others, to show — give evidence — that the position we have taken is
                            untenable; when they do, we will meet them with an experience of nearly a hundred years. And this experience is
                            barely a drop to the bucket of the experience of past ages. In Thibet, celibate institutions have flour- ished
                            for thousands of years. The Brahmans and Ascetics of India can speak of their ex- perience also. To-day, China
                            and Japan have their celibate orders. There, existence in these stereotyped civilizations is an inverted
                            prophecy — that celibacy has existed in these countries for untold ages. The Therapeutae of Egypt present their
                            experience. The Essenes of Judea had their celibate communities. The order of the Vestal Priestesses in ancient
                            Rome lasted about one thousand years; and the monastic orders of Europe, down to the present day, about two
                            thousand years. And, strange to say, before Columbus touched these shores, Mexico and Peru had each their own
                            civilization, and celibacy was found in them both. From every quarter of the globe we have concurring evidence
                            that, whenever man has made any progress beyond being a mere animal, the law of the higher life has broken forth
                            from celibate institutions. First in history, and foremost in the field, is Asia; next is Africa Europe responds
                            for more than two thousands of years in similar manifestations. Ancient America adds her quota of experience to
                            the practicability of a virgin life. And lastly, the Shakers of modern America, in the sunlight of physiological
                            law, and in all the well-understood relationships of social life, add their testimony to that of past ages, that
                            a celibate life is not only practicable, but favorable to health and longevity. And it is a condition necessary
                            to their wants— an essential preliminary to their happiness— the manifestation of the divine element in their
                            spirits. Because of this life was Christ manifested in Jesus, to gather all into one fold, who progress above
                            and beyond the procreative law. The idea that a virgin life is a contravention of the Creator's plan, seems to
                            me to be one-sided, and certainly is a low estimate of man's ultimate destiny ; and is not sustained by man's
                            nature, nor by the analogy of other created things. Human beings are as really subject to be reaped, as is the
                            grain they sow. On this subject Jesus said: "Cannot ye discern the signs of the times ? the harvest is the end
                            of the world ; the angels are the reapers, and ye are they on whom the ends of the world have come " — the ends
                            of the generative life. In harvesting grain, the reapers gather the elements of their own bodies. So, in the
                            harvest of the world, the angels gather those in whom the elements of angelic life are quickened. These, when
                            gathered, will manifest the Divine civilization, in which are neither war nor want. "Their bread and water shall
                            be blest, and sickness taken from their midst." The Shakers, as a people, are in the full realization of the
                            former, and to the latter, freedom from disease, we are surely and steadily approaching. We take a prac- tical
                            view (as did Jesus), that all are not prepared, as yet, for this life. But we think that humanity needs our
                            example, to which, if they do not attain, they may approximate. From the wide-spread action of Spiritualism we
                            anticipate greater results; its mission thus far has been to disintegrate old organizations and ideas ; all
                            their attempts to organize, heretofore, have made bad worse. "When its present phase is accomplished, we trust,
                            as a wave of spiritual light has reached rudimental humanity, that it may be succeeded by a wave of light and
                            warmth combined, necessarily convicting and organizing in its results. If the Spiritualists organize a higher,
                            civilization on the generative plane, and, if the more advanced portion realize a higher ideal than we present,
                            we shall be most happy. Outside of our Order there is a growing desire for a permanent amelioration of human
                            conditions. Governments, which rule by brute force, as do lions, are not acceptable. The diseases that afflict
                            humanity, especially those referable to the generative functions, are appalling. In the midst of plenty, and in
                            the possession of the most productive agencies the world ever beheld, it is supposed that nearly twenty millions
                            of persons in the British empire alone, have, during the present century, perished from lack of food. The power
                            to possess wealth and to increase See eighth page.</p></div2><pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: appeal to the sisterhood" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: APPEAL TO THE SISTERHOOD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">The Shakers, who, as a people, were but little known or understood by the outside world (except through business
                            transactions), were prompted by a sense of duty and the solicitations of friends to fit up, on the first of
                            January, 1871, a small vessel called " The Shaker" and release it from its moorings where it had been securely
                            anchored in a quiet harbor through the storms of nearly a century, and trim up its tiny sails, and send it forth
                            over the great waters on a mission of love. It contained, as they believed, many treasures, which might be a
                            blessing to others of earth's inhabitants, as they had been to them. The plain truths which this little craft
                            contained were unpalatable to some, while others hailed with gladness any medium of truth, though small in the
                            beginning, as a harbinger of a good time coming. Truth is potent in removing error and in breaking down idol
                            worship in the form of churchal creeds and lifeless ceremonies. Those who had been famishing on the dry husks of
                            theology, and whose souls were longing for living, spiritual bread, said: " Send, Lord, by whom thou wilt." Such
                            were prepared to read, consider, and understand. At the end of twelve months, the little voyager came back
                            bearing good tidings. It had made many friends while sailing to distant ports; and, although the waters were
                            whitened with the sails of many large and powerful vessels laden with all kinds of wares, yet there seemed to be
                            room enough for " The Shaker" and all had treated it with kindness and respect. Thousands were heard to say
                            "Send out 'The Shaker' again; it has done us good." Again it went forth, and, at the close of the year 1872, it
                            returns (like Noah's dove) to the ark, bearing an olive leaf. The meed that it brings is not praise merely, but
                            the sound "It has been a blessing to us; we cannot do without it. Long live The Shaker! — 'It must not die.' "
                            And now, in behalf of the Sisterhood of the Shaker fraternity, I would greet all the readers of our little sheet
                            with " A Happy New Year." This is not merely a compliment, a meaningless sound passing the lips, but is
                            heartfelt; and we pray that the light of truth may illume your pathway, and that holy influences from angel
                            spheres may surround you, and lift your thoughts and affections to things of enduring worth. This would augment
                            the happiness of all. And, my dear sisters of the Shaker Community, let me ask you all, as one, to unite, with
                            renewed efforts, the coming year, to advance the good cause. Truth and virtue have always been maintained
                            through individual self-sacrifice. Let us be thankful to be counted worthy to suffer, if thereby truth may be
                            promoted. There is work to be done; a cross to be borne, and a crown to be secured; and woman must act her part.
                            Let us be as angels in our own home; strew fadeless flowers— innocence, purity and love — in life's pathway.
                            This will attract angels from higher spheres, and they will commune with us. We shall, also, feel the blessing
                            of our good brethren, who have resolved to eat the fruit of honest toil. When they go forth to plow the field
                            and sow the seed, they will return to their peaceful home with gladsome hearts, knowing full well that they will
                            meet kind-hearted, Grod-fearing sisters, who will welcome them, and administer to all their necessities. How
                            many magnificent dwellings there are at the present time, in our own country, with beauteous surroundings of
                            shrubbery, choice fruits, and flowers of varied hue, and frescoed walls, and floors overlaid with costly
                            tapestry within, that are destitute of all those essentials which make home desirable and pleasant. Luxury is
                            there; but the white-robed angel of peace does not find shelter. Better and more to be desired is the humble
                            cottage, with a scanty morsel, where peace dwells, than a king's palace where envy and strife bear rule. And 0,
                            how many men there are at the present time who, by the unreasonable demands of their wives and daughters, in the
                            eager pursuit of the goddess Fashion, are compelled to resort to unjust measures to procure means for such
                            extravagance ! Ah, woman, how art thou fallen ! Instead of being an angel-friend to lift man up in the scale of
                            moral purity, your mediumistic pow- ers are turned to demoralize him. Let this be a lesson for the daughters of
                            Zion to study. By it let us learn to regard the law of use, and not be content to live upon the labors of our
                            brethren, and eat the bread of idleness; but toil with them ; aid them in all the duties of life; rejoice with
                            them in prosperity, and suffer with them in adversity. Do any of our outside fripnds ask What are the social
                            conditions and spiritual enjoyments among the Shakers? We answer: True friendship; brotherly and sisterly
                            affection; devoid of sensuality in our domestic relations ; and, in our religious associations, we, in concert,
                            raise our hearts and voices in prayer and praise; and feel that the heavens bow down while we become lifted up
                            in spirit to meet loving messengers from higher spheres, who feed the spiritual part, (which cannot subsist upon
                            gross, material things,) with immortal food. This, to us, is real joy.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-discipline" TEIform="index"/>SELF-DISCIPLINE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bullard, H." TEIform="persName"/>H. Bullard</byline><p TEIform="p">Conversion of heart, to my mind, is the correction of one's life; and this is the result of conviction of one's
                            sins — a conviction deep and heartfelt. Were there more of this con- viction in the Churches and in the schools;
                            if, in every family, each individual were en- joined to carry into life, moral principles and religious truths,
                            would not society be more benefited, than in all or any belief in preaching, that alludes to some righteous
                            being, but requires no righteousness in our own lives ? In my Shaker home, in which I have en- joyed peace and
                            plenty for more than thirty years, purit}r and righteousness are enjoined; while good works are the rule and not
                            the exception required of the members; and these are taught as requisite to a Christian character, in a
                            Christian community. The early training of the child is quickly apparent in the human character. The physical
                            constitution of the child is the foundation of the physical man or woman. Proper food, cleanliness, and a good,
                            moral training for the correction and direction of the child, creating activity in virtuous ways, greatly add to
                            its future character and happiness. Discipline should not be outgrown with childhood; but, as the primary
                            branches of education are to the collegiate course, so should be the discipline of the child to the adult in
                            riper years. Self-government should be more severe than was the paternal; the moral and spiritual faculties
                            should rule the animal passions; thus proving that individual improvement is the basis of general reform. "He
                            that ruleth his spirit is greater than he who taketh a city; " and those who are able to bring every thought,
                            word and action into submission to the law of Christ, stand forth noble specimens of humanity, a praise in the
                            earth. From childhood to mature age, life should be a continuous unfolding of better existence, of superior
                            principles, " progressing from faith unto faith;" as one position is gained, we should be prepared for another
                            and advanced movement. A progress is called for from Christian professors, from the plane of Adam and Moses, up
                            to the life of Christ. The discipline will consist of thoroughly dropping the generative practices of humanity,
                            and adopting the life of the heavens — heaven on earth. Passion subdued, peace ensues; the earthly or natural
                            exercise of the passions abandoned, the spiritual or heavenly element is given the full control. This is a work
                            all must per- form for themselves; this is self-discipline for an eternal existence. Said Jesus : " I indeed lay
                            down my life of myself, no man taketh it from me." This was his discipline, self-discipline, and of him, as our
                            exemplar, let us " learn ; for he was meek and lowly in heart " — disciplined for the heavenly life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True estimation" TEIform="index"/>TRUE ESTIMATION</head><p TEIform="p">If is often said that knowledge is power, and this is true. Skill or faculty of any kind carries with it
                            superiority. So, to a great extent, wealth is power, and genius has a transcendent gift of mastery over man. But
                            higher, purer, better than all these, more constant in its influence, more lasting in its sway, is the power of
                            character — that power which emanates from a pure and lofty mind. Take any community, who is the man of most
                            influence ? To whom do all look up with reverence ? Not to the " smartest" man (physically), not to the
                            cleverest politician nor the most brilliant talker, but to him, who in a long course of years, tried by the
                            extremes of prosperity and adversity, has approved himself to the judgment of those around him — of all who have
                            seen his life as worthy to be called wise and good.</p></div2><pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mission" TEIform="index"/>MISSION</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Cowan, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Cowan</byline><p TEIform="p">In perusing the columns of The Shaker, as it reaches our midst, on its Gospel mission, I am forcibly reminded
                            that we need such influences as it brings to bear, to awaken in our minds those latent aspirations for spiritual
                            food which appear to slumber in our breasts, without fully considering, as we should, the great necessity of
                            seeking enjoyments, in a spiritual point of view, and rejecting the fitful pleasures of time, which will perish.
                            Not that the teachings heralded by that paper are wholly or in part different from the faith heretofore taught,
                            and by the faithful lived, in the different Shaker Societies, for a goodly number of years; but I trust the time
                            has now come that light and knowledge will become more widespread, and that, through the columns of this
                            much-cherished paper, many will learn where to look for truth and righteousness, who are walking in darkness
                            without knowing the way of life, or the requirements of God to mankind. Seeing there is a strong desire on the
                            part of the contributors to our paper, to disseminate true G-ospel principles, and not suffer their hands to
                            beoome slack, or their hearts to wax cold, with regard to spiritual things, so, in this light and in this hope,
                            we rejoice that the way which God has marked out to be a " savor of life unto life, or of death unto death :) to
                            all, may be handed down as an immaculate treasure to those who have not been so favored as ourselves, but who
                            might perchance receive the Gospel, believe and be saved; I concluded, though yery weak the effort, to throw in
                            my mite to uphold, so far as may be, the cause we are struggling to maintain. In casting my eyes around to see
                            the necessity of aspiring for and looking beyond earthly and transitory things, I see those who have walked in a
                            humble, Christ-like manner; in short, have lived simple Shaker lives, and denied themselves of all earthly
                            enjoyments, and have lived pure and chaste before God; their shining examples and virtuous deeds irradiate their
                            countenances, until they seem like diamonds of light in our midst, and reassure us that we too may become the
                            worthy recipients of God's favor, being harvested from the earth by our own virtues and godly life. So, with
                            these views on what does and will bring true happiness to the sojourner here in time, we are much pleased to see
                            the efforts made, on the part of Believers, through The Shaker, to enlighten the minds of mankind as to what
                            constitutes a true Christian; and how nearty the requirements of Believers comport with the life and teachings
                            of the Saviour, who are able to say, "We are the way, the truth and the life; follow us as we follow Christ."
                            God's chosen people have ever been called upon to sacrifice their earthly desires and propensities ;
                            consequently, if we reach the goal they reached, less effort by us than they made cannot secure our eternal
                            happiness. Then, how comforting the thought that the way of life is made plain, and that, in addition to the
                            life and example of Jesus, we have the way also marked out by Mother Ann which consummates the way of life, and
                            confirms our faith in the plan of salvation as taught in this our day. There is a fullness of light and peace,
                            beyond which we have no aspirations; but with it our souls can rest secure, feeling sure that, although the
                            number may be small who will become true heirs of heaven, yet feeling conscious that there will always be a
                            remnant who will retain the testimony, and consequently maintain the principles of the Gospel through all
                            succeeding ages. Who then, but an ingrate, can reject so high and holy a calling, to work out salvation here in
                            time, and endeavor with their might to be eyes to the blind, and ears to the deaf, and a light to souls dead in
                            trespasses and sin ? this is certainly the duty of Zion's children; hence it is plain that all our endeavors
                            should tend .to elevate the human race, by ever pressing onward and upward, and in this way be a light to
                            earth's weary pilgrims on their heavenly journey.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I want to be a savior" TEIform="index"/>I WANT TO BE A SAVIOR</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Dodgson, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Dodgson</byline><p TEIform="p">How often we are cheered by the sweet sound of the little chant, "I want to be an angel, and with the angels
                            stand," as it comes from the lips of bright-eyed, juvenile innocence. And who is so hardened that her soul, upon
                            reflection, does not affirmatively respond to the desired want? But I am thinking that for mature years, where
                            furrowed brow, dimmed eyes, and whitened locks bespeak experience in this world of ours, we might with propriety
                            sing of wanting to be, or becoming, saviors. O, how our world needs practical salvation ! And is there not
                            already a call for saviors to arise and stand on Mount Zion ? I want to be a savior and on Mount Zion stand,
                            With self-denial for my shield, and sword of truth in hand; To live a life that's sinless, in innocence and
                            love, With wisdom of a seraph, and meekness of a dove. I want to be a savior: then saved I first must be From
                            selfishness and envy; from worldly pride be free; From base, low, groveling passion, I must have wings to rise,
                            Not seeking worldly glory, but reaching for the prize. Like Jesus Christ our Pattern, the lowly Nazarene,
                            Performing acts of mercy, each savior must be seen, And boldly chiding error, with stripes, if needs should be,
                            Completes a savior's mission, as by the word we see. We have two holy Patterns — Christ Jesus and Christ Ann,
                            Who've taught us to be saviors, and form'd and laid " a plan,' By which each human creature who ceases from all
                            sins Becomes a Christ or Savior, whose mission here begins. Then come, O come, ye saviors, and stand on Zion's
                            hill; There boldly rear your standard, your mission to fulfill, To save from sin and sorrow all who will hear
                            the call, Be resurrected, born again, and freely give up all. A practical salvation, in thought, in word and
                            deed, Brought forth by self-denial, is what our world does need; And many a blessed savior now on Mount Zion
                            stands, With crowns upon their heads, and harps within their hands. </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Henry Vincent on the shakers" TEIform="index"/>HENRY VINCENT ON THE SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Vincent, Henry" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">* * * "I contented myself with the results I saw before me, and thought them sufficiently remarkable to command
                            the respectful and thoughtful attention of the Church and the world. "I saw a community of men and women of all
                            ages living a pure celibate life, under the same roof, full of sweetness, love, and gentleness — a happy family
                            of brothers and sisters. I knew that many of them had been married men and women before they were led, by a
                            religious principle and motive, to 'crucify all worldly lusts,' and enter into what they regard as the
                            millennial state. I know that this life had been lived by monks and nuns, who were excluded from each other with
                            a prison-like rigor, under lock and key, and bolts and bars; but here I saw a spiritual family — the once
                            husband and wife entering upon a new life in the daily presence of each other — and that this chaste community
                            had tested this life of purity for seventy years, without any cloud arising to dim the lustre of its chastity. "
                            Of course we all exclaim, ' How can these things be ? ' And the profligate and the base raise the yell of
                            laughter; but the Shakers' modestly reply, 'Not unto us, but unto God be all the glory.' The world laughs again,
                            and slanders; but the answer is the fact of this life, which this people lay open to the gaze of all the world.
                            I saw, moreover, a people who will not hold private property -—¦ a people who rest securely and in perfect
                            harmony and prosperity, upon a community of goods. The dream of Utopia is here realized. They work hard ; they
                            enjoy the fruits of their industry; they live simply and frugally. For ten years they have ceased to eat swine,
                            or to drink alcoholic drinks, except under medical advice. " I saw that this community of goods sprung from a
                            deeper motive than a social or economical truth. Indeed, in one of their publications I found this paragraph: '
                            They could not understand how so-called Christians (brethren and sisters) could be members of the same religious
                            body or Church, and be divided into rich and poor in the things of this temporary world, but who are vainly
                            expecting that in the world to come they will all be willing to have eternal things in common.' Thus their
                            communistic idea springs from a religious motive, and such a fact is worthy the contemplation of thoughtful men.
                            " I inquired into the internal working of the Community, as to how disputes or misunderstandings were settled,
                            if they unfortu- nately arose. I was told that here again they adopted the Christian plan, speaking to the
                            brother or sister alone, and, if that failed, ' tell it unto the Church;' and that so far all had moved on with
                            harmony, and no serious difficulties had disturbed them. Another thing I have also seen in relation to the
                            Shakers : Every one in America with whom I have spoken speaks highly of their moral character, of their
                            truthfulness, of their honesty in their dealings with their fellow men. All bear this testimony, with the
                            exception of those degraded people who believe there 8HAKEE .A.ISTD 6 <pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEE8S. are no such
                            things as virtue and truth on the earth. " Surely the success of this community must have a cause. What is that
                            cause ? I do not pretend to ansAver the question. But it is a question worthy of an answer. Many similar
                            experiments have totally failed. Why has this succeeded? Within the past forty years, the Owenite experiments in
                            England and America have failed; but ShaJcerism is a living and triumphant fact. Let me urge upon divines and
                            scholars, in their rambles through America, to visit the Shaker Community at Mount Lebanon, and if they are
                            disposed to inquire, ' How can these things be ? ' my answer is, ' Come and see.' "</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Novitiate" TEIform="index"/>A NOVITIATE</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Shaker.—Ever since I first saw you, I loved you, and ever will. Every time you have appeared to me you have
                            awakened earnest thoughts in my mind, and sweet feelings in my heart. I have looked upon you as an expression of
                            the condition and spirit of our people; the people among whom I am happy to be counted. You go out into the
                            world to tell its children what we are, what we think, how we feel; and I am thankful to you for that. You try
                            to let them see our character as a people; you try to make them understand our ideas about God and our duties to
                            him, about life generally, and more especially about the beautiful relations we are called to hold to one
                            another in our peculiar sphere; you try to have them appreciate our feelings of sympathy for our fellow-men, of
                            pure and true love to one another, of deep reverence for our Divine Parentage, whose will, revealed to us
                            through worthy mediums on earth, is the rule of our lives. Thus, always finding you engaged in this noble work
                            of enlightening the minds of men, in regard to these things, do you wonder that your monthly visits to me have
                            been seasons oi great pleasure ? And still there is one thing that I have felt, and that I would like to say,
                            through you, to my young companions with whom I love to be united in every good work. The beautiful life that we
                            are called into, inspires the mind continually with new thoughts and ideas. Not one step can be taken, not one
                            word spoken, not even a feeling can enter the heart of a true Believer, without his faith taking hold of it, and
                            judging whether it be for God or for self. This is a great work. To youthful minds whose powers and energies
                            have not been wasted in a worldly life, and for its selfish relations, it shows every moment higher and better
                            ends to aim at; such youthful minds it accepts as virgin soil to till — grounds that have been but too long
                            neglected. I feel exceedingly interested in these labors to reclaim the realms of nature in the human heart to
                            their Lord, and it gives me great joy and courage to know that there are so many who have turned their attention
                            in this direction; that I have so many youngcompanions fervent in their feelings and earnest in their
                            resolutions to carry on the work of God in their own souls, cost what it may. I have often felt the power of
                            love and symputhy flowing from heart to heart among those who are being redeemed. By being a little more willing
                            to express our thoughts and feelings, we might do one another some more good, stimulate one another to new
                            exertions, to gain gifts that are worth possessing, gifts of heart and mind, the power to feel truly and deeply,
                            to think soundly, and to express ourselves simply and acceptably. Being now near the beginning of a new year, I
                            feel a de- sire to enter a covenant with my young brethren and sisters, to pay more attention to these things,
                            to devote more time and labor to studying the laws of our Order, which are as important to us as are the laws of
                            the natural order to those who adhere to it. And if ever we should be called upon to communicate the fruits of
                            our labors to one another, we should be as willing to give as we are to receive, and we should find fully as
                            much blessing in the former as we are finding in the latter.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bretzner, Emil" TEIform="persName"/>Emil Bretzner</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Outrage at the Watervliet Shakers Settlement" TEIform="index"/>Outrage at the Watervliet Shakers Settlement
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The following letter, written by one of the sisters of the Watervliet Society of Shakers, to a sister at New
                            Lebanon, describing the situation of affairs at the former place, will be read with interest: Shakers (Albany
                            County), November, 1872. [From the Albany Express.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Outrage at the Watervliet Shakers SettlementDear Eldress Antoinette: In a recent letter you sent
                                    to me, you thought it would be some time before you wrote again. We feel no claim on your precious time
                                    in that direction, yet we do beg your love and sympathy, in these trying times for soul and body. To be
                                    aroused from our beds by two extensive fires ir. one week's time, and then the insecurity which we
                                    constantly feel, has so unnerved us, that it is impossible to get a good night's rest, although the
                                    brethren keep a constant watch; and again, the burden and wear upon the strength of the brethren, with
                                    so much upon them, make our hearts ache. The barns and sheds for our oxen, cows, and young stock, with
                                    all that we had to keep them through the winter, gone, together with all the oats, which we had for the
                                    horses, was there stored for threshing. The oat crop has been a failure for several years past, and the
                                    brethren have had to buy. This season it was good; had enough to have carried through to another
                                    harvest. We can courageously endure privation, and labor hard, but, when night comes, it brings with it
                                    such a feeling of horror that we long for an eternal day. If we sleep, we are only frightened that we
                                    have been to sleep. When the bell strikes it is the knell of fear; and still feel that all that has been
                                    is unaccounted for. We know of no personal enmity, no rivalry in business, or any thing unusual on the
                                    part of Believers; but we do know that there is a very low state of morals at the present time;
                                    robberies are committed very frequently; men are seen masked; henroosts are robbed, and various places
                                    pillaged. This has been going on until it has grown into a regular organized band of desperadoes, who,
                                    seemingly, have no other object than to rob and secure money. On the morning of the fire at our place,
                                    two men were seen and sent away from the Church Family's office; two men were also met running toward
                                    the Second Family. On the evening of the fire, two men tried to get into the office at the Second Order,
                                    which leads us to think that the object of firing the barns was to draw the brethren away from those
                                    places, and leave them unprotected. We know no other way than to be faithful in duty, and fervent in
                                    prayer, looking to the higher powers for protection. Now, perhaps, your motherly spirit would like to
                                    know how we shall make out, as we depend so much upon the dairy for the sup- port and comfort of the
                                    family. I will tell you : As we have, late years, kept more milch cows through the winter, we have not
                                    laid down our winter supply of butter, as formerly ; therefore, under our present affliction, not being
                                    able to keep but a few cows, we have agreed to have one-third of our meals without butter, and to
                                    lengthen out our shortning for pies, to do with one-third less pie. As we have a good supply of apples
                                    and potatoes, we can live comfortably. Even a piece of bread and a cup of cold water would be a
                                    sumptuous meal, if we could only banish our fears for the future, and go to our rest in safety. Do not
                                    forget us in your prayers, nor withhold some of those strong spirits which encamp around about you, to
                                    come to us, to inspire us with strength and courage. We have no less thankfulness for the Gospel of
                                    salvation, and the privilege to be Believers, on account of our recent affliction, but will toil on to
                                    the end of life's journey. Yours, in affliction, Harriet</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany express" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Harriet" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Waste basket" TEIform="index"/>WASTE BASKET</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">"Write and educate yourself and others. No wellmeant effort in mental discipline is lost; it is even as in
                            spiritual things, " where no labor in the Lord is ever in vain." Words are mediums through which to convey ideas
                            ; the knowledge and use of them is often termed education. But what if a person should know how to speak and
                            write with all the tongues of men and angels, and yet lack ideas, would they not be learnedly ignorant? as when
                            possessing the gift of tongues, of healing, of knowledge, and all spiritual gifts, yet lacking the gift of
                            charity, or love, they are nothing when judged by the standard of true Gospel travel of soul. Write, therefore,
                            for the Shaker and Shakeress. The contents of the "Waste Basket" will rise up and claim its due share of honor
                            in its support. At any race of half a dozen men or horses, do each one win the prize ? or can only one win at a
                            given time? Write, therefore, and keep the Waste Basket full, and The Shaker well supplied with good matter. "
                            What is the chaff to the wheat?" saiththe Lord. Why, without the chaff there could be no wheat; it is as
                            necessary as a Waste Basket. Therefore write, meditate ; and re-write on one side of the sheet only ; after
                            preparing as best you can, and it having passed the ordeal of the society's local editor, send it neatly folded,
                            ready for the Waste Basket, for we must have plenty of matter for our Shaker and Shakeress, as we could not make
                            even a world out of nothing.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We" TEIform="index"/>"WE."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The usual editorial term of '• we " is no longer a subject of doubt. But the world has waited long for the Shaker
                            and Shakeress to illustrate the point by giving it a dual signification. </p></div2><pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful shore" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL SHORE</head><p TEIform="p">Andante. 1. Time's dark billows and tempests may roar, Yet will I sing of that beautiful shore, Where the
                            chill winter of life shall be o'er, Ne'er to return to the soul. 2. Gladsome the spring of that fair happy
                            land, Blossom and fruitage in glory expand, While the soft breeze from its emerald strand, Scent-laden float
                            to us here. 3. Pilgrims who tarry, your time yet abide, Slowly receding is life's ebbing tide: Over its
                            surges your spirits shall glide Safe to that beautiful shore. Blest summer land, free from sorrow and gloom,
                            In fadeless beauty our spirits shall bloom, While the earth casket In-her its the tomb, Seasons supernal will
                            roll. Love builds its mansion all pearly and bright, Rising in grandeur in rose-tinted light: 'Tis for the
                            blessed, whose robes are made white, Heavenly homes have been rear'd. Happy the tho't I If our hearts are made
                            pure, We an inheritance there shall secure. Hope still confides in the promises sure, When here our journey
                            is o'er. rit. [if. F.Mt. Lebanon.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibacy" TEIform="index"/>CELIBACY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Frazer</byline><p TEIform="p">( Continued from fourth page.) it, without creating any, the antagonism between the accumulative products of
                            labor and the laborer, the condition of the productive class, particularly the agricultural portion, reveal a
                            state of things too awful to contemplate. A war establishment to kill and to destroy, is at the same time
                            associated with extensive missionary efforts to preach a gospel of peace which they do not possess. We must be
                            borne with, when we designate such a civilization a Satanic form of human life, the organic law of which is "
                            the love of self at the expense and neglect of the neighbor." To bring about a distant approximation to our form
                            of human society, we ask for the elevation of humanity to the practice of the law— " the love of self, and the
                            neighbor as self." The organic law of our Order is: "He that is greatest, shall be the servant /" To those who
                            wish to enjoy a Divine form of social life, we say, "Come and see" whether such operates among us or not.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little Quail" TEIform="index"/>THE LITTLE QUAIL</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="McNemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard McNemar</byline><p TEIform="p">Traveling once along the way, Thinking of this latter dayHow much progress we can make, Since our lives are not
                            at stake. Ancient saints could little gain, Still by persecutors slain; Now protected from the foe, Saints can
                            have full time to grow. Next I thought, If sinners knew That we thus our safety view, Would they not yet try to
                            kill ? Could they not our vitals spill? Through my mind this thought I cast, While a log I closely passed, Where
                            a little quail did sit Fair and easy to be hit. Instantly I made a stand, With a stick I raised my hand ; Thrice
                            I struck with all my skill, Rut no vitals did I spill. (. noe my stick just grazed his tail, But the
                            well-protected quail, Sound and nimble took its flight Through the forest, out of sight. Instantly the spirit
                            spoke, " As this quail escaped thy stroke, So the wicked strike in vain In the great Messiah's reign." O, what
                            wonders I did view As the little creature flew! Every flutter of its wing Seemed to cry, " The Lord is King."
                            Had I then an army seen, Full of rage and cruel spleen, I should felt no more surprise Than amidst a host of
                            flies. While the cross of Christ I bear, Under his protecting care, Every danger I shall shun, Till my work is
                            fully done. He who gave this striking sign Hasstretch'd out his meas'ring line : Persecution's at an end ; Now
                            we may with Christ ascend. Blessed day how bright and clear! O what fruits the saints can bear! Righteousness
                            through every stage, Now can grace this Golden Age.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Churches of our land" TEIform="index"/>THE CHURCHES OF OUR LAND</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr</byline><p TEIform="p">Loud ring their bells, and loud their organ tones Pour the grand anthems that by art were given. Wealth,
                            learning, eloquence, their proud dominion hold: But what of God, of Life, of Love, of Heaven? A seeming fitness
                            blends all outward thingsConcordant sounds and softly mellowed light; We almost list the rush of angel's wings,
                            And watch for saints in radiant robes of white. Can heap'd-up shams the Infinite allure ; Or flatt'ry charm the
                            all-embracing mind ? Can systems that oppress and spurn the poor Be brought to God, and His acceptance find ? Is
                            He deceived by fashion, pomp, and show ? Can grandeur hide disease, deceit and sin ? May every wickedness the
                            heart can know Come to these temples and gain entrance in ? If stern, misguided hearts go forth no more, The
                            Martyr's unrelenting fire to light; If ruthless persecutions cease to pour Their venom'd darts with wild inhuman
                            might. Does there abound that precious gift of God— Faith in the good that is, and that which yet may be? Is
                            Christ-like charity their basis broad? And is tht-"r focus — Truth — unmarr'd and free? When youthful manhood,
                            full of noble zeal, An offering makes of his unfolding life, Is there an inspiration he can feel. To meet his
                            ardor and award his strife? And does the soul of woman bear no fruit, Nor spread its branches like the olive
                            tree ? Beneath the ban that bade her to be mute Must her expanding powers forever be? Alas ! alas! the altar's
                            fire is dead ; God's Spirit meets the soul no longer there: But canting mockery gives stones for bread, And
                            scorpion answers to the cry for care. Our prayer ascends, O be it thus no more; Come, sweet refreshing from the
                            Source Divine, And spread true Brotherhood "the wide world o'er," Which poet-prophets saw in "auld lang syne."
                            Let Truth reveal to science Nature's laws, Let faith not die 'mid superstitions dim ; For truth and science both
                            shall seek the Cause, That gave all souls one universal hymn. Write God, write Goodness, on the nation's heart,
                            Not with a legal pen by man's decree ; But let iniquity the land depart, And make the young Republic pure and
                            free.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and Shakeress. Addresses of the Local Editors and Publishers..." TEIform="index"/>SHAKER AND SHAKERESS.
                            Addresses of the Local Editors and Publishers</head><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W". Evans, Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. .. G. A. Lomas, Albany, N. Y. Shakers. Calvin G. Reed, Sonyea,
                            Livlng'n Co. N. Y. Simon Mabee, West Pittsfield, Mass. .. H. S. Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn. Shakers. Albert
                            Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co. Mass. Wm. Leonard, Ayer, Mass. Shakers. Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village,
                            Middlesex Co. Mass. B. H. Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co. N. H. Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co. N. H.
                            John B. Vance, Alfred, York Co. Maine Shakers. Nehemiah Trull, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co. Me. Shakers.
                            Charles Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co. O. Shakers. Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co. Ohio. Shakers. Stephen
                            Ball, Dayton, Ohio Shakers. Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co. Ky. J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co. Ky. J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>