<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1112" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18811201" TEIform="date">December 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">265- 288</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                                        <p> DECEMBER, 1881. { 60 Cents Per Annum MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United
                        Societies. OUR HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony: " 'Go preach the Kingdom of God!"
                        ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XI. No. 12.
                        The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="265" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blighted" TEIform="index"/>BLIGHTED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Just in a night they withered, Touched by a blighting frost, Their delicate nerves were
                            shivered And all their glory was lost. Those beautiful flowers that bloomed Through spring
                            and summer hours, And the balmy air perfumed, At the call of dews and showers. They are
                            gone, our bright hopes perished And close to the eartli they lie, The sweet things that we
                            cherished So quickly doomed to die. Oh! thus on our spirits' flowers May come some chilling
                            blight, Though the germs, by heavenly powers, Were matured and brought to light. Sometime
                            when the sun's fair shining Promises setting clear, And the clouds with golden lining Above
                            life's hills appear. There may lurk in the coming darkness Some cold and icy breath, That
                            swift in the sable darkness May hurl the shafts of death. It may be the frost of sorrow Will
                            fall on the nightly air, To bring us a sad to-morrow And rob us of treasures rare. Or a
                            sudden chill of feeling May pass over hearts once warm, A sadder wreck revealing Than comes
                            of the passing storm. Of the coming days we speak not, Of the future who can know, Over our
                            greenest earth spot Palleth the drifting snow. Where our choicest hopes are blasted, May
                            some new life take wing, And the souls of flowers wasted Bloom in perennial spring. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> Commemorative of this notable day of Christendom, many are the manifestations betokening
                            appreciation of the birth and mission of Jesus into the world. But how singularly varied are
                            the grateful memorials characterizing the mass of professing Christians ! Eager to
                            commemorate this eventful epoch, the abilities of professed discipleship are brought into
                            wonderful requisition. The advent of our Saviour into the world was " to create a new order
                            of things, the old of which shall not be remembered nor brought into mind." Does this
                            necessitate the external display of pomp, the decorations of halls of wealth, the sumptuous
                            repasts of the wealthy at the expense and exclusion of the poor? " Inasmuch as ye have done
                            it unto the least of these my breth- <pb n="266" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 266 THE SHAKEft MANIFESTO. ren,
                            ye have done it unto me.'' How then does this divine injunction accord with the life
                            practice of the so-called Christian world? And upon this day especially, designed as
                            requisite for practical proof of faith in the mission of the Messiah, do the lovers thereof
                            work in harmony with the spirit of Him whom they profess to follow ? " If ye love me, ye
                            will keep my commandments. Go sell what thou hast and give to the poor ; so shalt thou have
                            treasures in Heaven." Can our divine exemplar look with an approving smile upon that which
                            forms ho part of his heavenly kingdom ? The rich, becoming richer through the sufferings of
                            the poor, and, upon this day above all others, lavishing their wealth in a manner pampering
                            to innate selfishness, tending more or less to most prevalent passions, among which are the
                            unsuppressed longings of the stomach—a God before whose shrine all other considerations must
                            bow ! Was Jesus thus morbidly affected ? If healingphysical diseases were a conspicuous part
                            of His mission, would the pampering of morbid appetite seem pleasing in His sight ? And yet
                            this is the record which is read upon debilitated humanity—a continuous chain of ignorant or
                            willful transgression of physical laws all along the pathway of life, even "from the cradle
                            to the grave." Infants, in many cases, receive their first lesson of intemperance by
                            indulgent parents through the administration of dainties, which, in the end, only tend to
                            sicken opening thereby another channel through which to administer poisonous drugs for the
                            blind purpose of undoing evils which never should have occurred. Likewise, in this receptive
                            period of life they are taught to look forward to the anniversary of the " dear Jesus" with
                            love and admiration— not so much of the heavenly characteristics of the man, as of the
                            sweetmeats and presents generally, which characterize the day. Indeed, it might be a query
                            to which of the two personages, Jesus or Santaclause their love is the stronger. May the
                            good time hasten when a befitting display of Christmas may be made practical throughout
                            Christendom, which will result in a growing love and admiration of the beautiful principles
                            of Christianity to the exclusion of much that only tends to pamper the taste, dwarf the
                            mind, and disease both physical and spiritual organization. Then will the children come up
                            through the tender period of dependence, imbibing true principles of love to the Saviour,
                            their countenances beaming with genuine delight, while their promising futurity will bespeak
                            not only prosperity and happiness for themselves, but unparalleled blessing and honor to the
                            race. Enfield, N. H</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibate Shaker life" TEIform="index"/>THE CELIBATE SHAKER LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p"> Man is a series of ascending developments through the law of evolution. The union of the
                            sexes is fundamental, designed to be eternal ; "what God hath joined together." " They twain
                            shall be one flesh," in the generative order. The "rib" beautifully symbolizes the
                            semi-circurnference of one whole. "Their name was called Adam." " In Adam all die ;" the
                            physical, generative relations cease. The body of Jesus, and all divine men and women die.
                            In Christ (the spiritual relations) shall all be made alive, they are eternal. The '"' new
                            commandment to love one another," is an elimination from the exclusive family tie,
                            broadening, and transferring all the senses, loves, affections and sympathies, to higher and
                            diviner uses. Forsaking, applies to the primary uses, the inferior affections, which
                            constitute father, mother, wife, children, etc., not to the innate principle planted in the
                            human soul by the finger of God, to be raised and sublimated. Did Jesus discover less depth
                            of love and affection when He recognized those who did the divine will, lived the virgin
                            life as His relation above all others ? Had Mother Ann less " affection and benevolence when
                            she said, " if I possessed the whole world I would turn it all into joyf ulness ?" Such are
                            our examples, fulfilling the " new commandment to love one another ;" all who live the
                            divine angelic life without <pb n="267" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 267 distinction of
                            family tie. Such have been taken from the rudimental—the wild olive, and grafted into the j
                            tame olive.jthe more progressed, elevated and refined. They inherit the legacy of love,
                            broader than the world can give, and purer than it can appropriate. Man has acted upon the
                            false idea that the earth, the elements, and man in particular were perfected—had reached
                            the summit of all progress, when they are only at the base, or at best, on a terrace of
                            their own ideal forming. The prophets who in every age have praised the clouds that shrouded
                            the mountain, and were " lifted up " in obedience to their heavenly visions, and would fain
                            have drawed other men thither, have been beaten back, persecuted and oft crucified. And it
                            is still heroic to fight a single new truth rather than a score of old sins. " The salt of
                            the earth" are such as put a check on over-population. Who can tell the whole truth without
                            cutting their own fingers ; who do not destroy, but save men's lives ; who " have no
                            fellowship with the unfruitful works of darkness, but reprove them? " The sticklers for the
                            first great command, by their practice, render " multiply and replenish," as if it read
                            destroy, and lay waste instead of to fill up, the true definitionIt is equally consistent to
                            use all the vegetable kingdom for the purpose of reproduction, because of its inherent law
                            of germination, as to assume the same prerogative for the human species, without check or
                            balance. And how reads the remainder of the command ? " And subdue it (the earth) and have
                            dominion over every living thing that moveth upon the earth." But alas ! what a fatal
                            failure over the animal in man! Let those who are under the law keep the law ; and those who
                            become an end of the law, by living above all its requirements, live the divine virgin life.
                            And then the song of Moses, and the Lamb, will blend in sweet harmony. The fourth beast, the
                            symbol of the spiritual epoch, was a flying eagle, in the act of soaring above the earth.
                            Blessed are the prophets, who can discern the signs of the times. Ayer, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>TO LEBANON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gale, G. N. P." TEIform="persName"/>G. N. P. GALE</byline><p TEIform="p"> In that remote, secluded glen, Far from the restless world, My spirit joys to find itself
                            With pinions wide unfurled. To revel 'mid fair nature's charms, And from her boundless store
                            Cull flowers of beauty whose perfume Inspires me more and more. Pure are the lessons she
                            imparts, Affectionate and kind ; Sweet peace and thankfulness her joys, In greatful hearts
                            enshrined. Vast, solemn, silent mountains round, In pompous grandeur rise, To kiss and woo
                            the fleecy clouds, And commune with the skies. Their graceful blooming slopes display Rich
                            gorse and purple heath,— Save where the golden wheat waves high In smiling fields beneath.
                            And far below, deep in the glen, Are stalwart lab'ring hands Gathering the precious fragrant
                            herbs, Among the Shaker bands. Their voices borne on zephyr's wing, Ring up the steep hill
                            sides, And tell how many a Shaker suit A noble spirit hides. O active toilers, that unbar
                            Earth's undeveloped store; May you unfailing harvest reap Of heaven's yet richer ore.
                            Believe not that the worldly rich Are happier than you, Their wants are legion, and their
                            cares ; Your wants and cares are few. Heaven help all willing, working hands, And aye, will
                            aid and cheer All who strive well to aid themselves, Whate'er their station here. Let each
                            his duties on life's stage Industriously fulfill; In love and labor trust, and wait,
                            Obedient to His will. Then in this calm enchanting glen, As in the city's glare, All may be
                            happier if they will But seek Heaven's love to share. St. Catharines, Ont.</p></div2><pb n="268" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soul travel, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>SOUL TRAVEL, NO. 4</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Although, for untold ages, the human family has been like the restless ocean, lashed by the
                            winds of passion into waves and tempests of sorrow and despair, striving to live without
                            soul-food, without God, then, anon, feeling bereft of the great boon of human existence,
                            soul-happiness and her interest in the soul's treasure of heavenly things, thus alternately
                            flowing and ebbing, and the ocean of Divine Wisdom, aparently like the cup of tantalus, ever
                            just beneath her lips, but, apparently, seldom permitted to drink therefrom, still, it is
                            not an eternal necessity that she should continue to repeat past experiences of
                            reciprocating progress and backslidings. There is a millennial baptism for the race into the
                            light and love of Heaven. A possible and needful wave of sincere repentance, turning her
                            into "wisdom's ways of pleasantness " to go no more out forever. But, in reviewing the
                            present religious world (so called), it manifests what is termed "religion in the capacity
                            of a business consideration," offering prospective confidence and trust as a temporal
                            advantage, in a mercenary sense, rather than as presenting a means of happiness for the
                            soul, as the fruit of a life thereby saved from evil, and purified by the fruits of its
                            profession and true possession. If a person has a name on the church-record, and contributes
                            to keep the meeting-house in repair, pays for a pew, and helps to pay the preacher, the
                            chances for honorable position in society are multiplied; these are the advantages looked
                            for by the world, in embracing religious faith (so called). Creeds of faith numbered by
                            hundreds are presented to the multitudes for acceptance, embracing some truths and many
                            ideas accommodating to the individual, social or national vanity, folly or pride of the
                            same. But, in proportion as the various and multitudinous creeds present different paths of
                            life, each professing to be the only one leading to Heaven, the juvenile mind is often
                            embarrassed to decide which is right, and, eventually, ofttimes, for a season, doubt them
                            all. Besides this^unhappy effect, the creedal bias — a pride of opinion united to worldly
                            ambition and personal vanity — produces contentions and conflicts between the professed
                            religionists of different sects; this destroys Christian love, peace and confidence in
                            religions, professions generally ; hence, the growing generation incline, very largely, to
                            be unreligious. It must be admitted that conflicting interests, and collisions of
                            multitudinous creeds and forms of religion (so called), contribute to destroy individual
                            faith in such religion, and introduce and diffuse the deadly bane of atheism'—a soulless,
                            godless state of society. These creedal walls that bar the union, peace and fellowship of
                            one religious devotee and worshiper from another of a different creed are just as fast
                            vanishing as the light of Divine truth and the power of Christian love moves upon the human
                            soul, and overcomes its prejudices, and links it into the one united chain of wisdom's
                            revelations. And so fast is this work in operation, that, at present, ministers of
                            magnanimous spirits and advanced minds frequently worship at one and the same shrine though
                            trained in the theology of diverse creeds, or often exchange pulpits with each other. Easy
                            and quick transit by railroads, and instantaneous communication by telegraph and telephone,
                            is beginning in a marvelous degree to conscociate the nations, harmonize their ideas of
                            science, art, political and social economy; and, as is now beginning to be manifest, must,
                            eventually, uproot also polytheism and polycreedism, and introduce the millennium of
                            religious truth and its fruits of united graces. Possessed of powers and faculties which, if
                            kept tuned in harmony with the Divine mind, would make him almost a demi-god, man's normal
                            state is to be a co-worker with God, as His servant, in producing such conditions for
                            humanity and for all inferior creation. Did man live in harmony with all the laws of God for
                            his well-being, both of body and soul, as in the ideal Edenic state, the ear of his spirit
                            would ever be unstopped to hear the instructions of his Creator, enabling him to proceed in
                            all the <pb n="269" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 269 duties of life, so as to secure the
                            blessings of Divine Providence without a failure. From the organization of the soul of man
                            it is demonstrably certain, that, in his normal condition, he is so amnitively united to his
                            Creator as to be, at all times, conscious of His Divine will, and as a dutiful child ever
                            ready to yield explicit obedience to His behests, thus to dwell in the sunshine of His
                            paternal affection and love continually, and drink at the well-springs of His superior
                            wisdom and power. In this relation all possible benefits relative to the health, protection,
                            development and perfection of the physical, mental and spiritual being of man, would be his
                            legitimate and constant inheritance. That man as now known in human society is,
                            comparatively, but a very limited recipient of these Divine favors, is proof, as true as the
                            source of light, that, at present, he is in an abnormal relation to his Creator, to the
                            inhabitants of the higher spheres and to his fellow-man; indeed the chasm is so deep and
                            wide between man and his God, that with untold millions the query arises, is there a God?
                            And, if so, have we any means of access to Him ? Is He the hearer of our prayers? Does He
                            hold us in the arms of His protection, or is man the product of unfathomable nature — the
                            accident or incident of chance — the measure of mere imaginative quantity and quality ?
                            Consequently the question is pressing, how shall man regain his normal relations to his
                            Creator, so that His ear may be attentive to man's plaintive cries for aid, and his soul
                            feel itself the recipient of God's benefactions ? As preliminary to a reply it would seem
                            proper to inquire how man has lost his true relation to his God ? This perceived, it would
                            appear a plain fact that the way to regain it would be to retrace his steps. Man has lost
                            this relation by seeking, in all the avenues of life, to please himself, though at the
                            expense of the pleasure of his God; wherefore, his road to the land of his true inheritance
                            is to crucify his selfish, independent nature and strive to know and do the pleasure of his
                            God. This is crossing man's adopted evil nature even unto death. The experience of the human
                            race illustrates the fact, that, to be able to attain unto the Divine wisdom and grasp the
                            treasures of the heavenly home, a considerable degree of rational asceticism must be
                            practiced in order to disengage the soul from the earth bond shackles of time and sense;
                            for, inasmuch as it is unharnessed from these, it is free to soar to heavenly realms in the
                            paradisian fields of wisdom, glory and godliness; but, while bound by those shackles, it
                            never can rise to heavenly mansions. The soul, freed from the enthrallments of animal,
                            earthly sensualism, is at liberty to walk and talk with God, and often privileged to see,
                            with the prophetic telescope, future prospects and liabilities ; at liberty to roam with
                            angels 'mid groves of the trees^of life, bearing the fruits of the spirit of such luscious
                            flavor as to spoil all relish, in those who partake thereof, for mortal fruits that only
                            minister to the earthly senses of the worldly man and perish in the using. All of God's
                            noble vicegerents who have been the great and immortally-honored benefactors of the human
                            race have been, invariably, self-denying, self-sacrificing souls, who, in their
                            philanthropy, rejoiced in giving their lives to God. The human family have had many seasons
                            of spiritual plentitude, these have been the harvests' home-fruits of the labors of the
                            faithful prayerful benefactors of our race, both those in tenements of clay and those
                            inhabiting the supernal worlds above earth. Many seasons of spiritual famine and moral
                            desolation; long planes of desert, and dreary and fruitless soul-fields have also been
                            trodden by the human race; seasons when angel visits were few and far between, and God's
                            blessing, showers of spirit-life, seemed only as a distant horoscopic picture of what once
                            was man's heavenly inheritance. But never, even in these most desolate fields of soultravel,
                            has any soul broken away from these moorings of soul-bondage ; the tethers of the human race
                            to the world of sin and sorrow, and in self-abnegating devotion, in agonizing prayer and
                            unabating spirit-toil, sought God, His wisdom to know, and His will to do, but, to such
                            laboring soul, the angels have been sent to minister the bless- <pb n="270" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 270
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. ings of the heavenly world, and have upheld their hands to pluck
                            gorgeous heavenly flowers and luscious fruits of the spirit from the evergreen tree of life.
                            Let thirsty, hungering, starving Zion so live and so labor, and they will have the key to
                            unlock the heavens, and draw from her sacred fountains blessings to the satisfaction of
                            every heaven-born soul.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progressive redemption" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESSIVE REDEMPTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Elder, Frederick Evans : I can never express my appreciation of one of your
                            excellent articles in a recent SHAKER Manifesto. It is the voice of the living present ; the
                            testimony of truth ; the breath of life, the respiration of which would develop a " living
                            soul." Finality is a good anchor if we would remain stationary forever, standing in the
                            footprints of our ancestors. Should not "progressive redemption" from a false theology be
                            complemented with a " life-long desire and effort," for " progressive redemption " from
                            worldly fashions ? It seems to me that simplicity, utility, comfort, [convenience, health
                            and economy should be the " desire and effort," in all changes and improvements in fashion.
                            To seek the popular fabric, cut and color — the fashions of the world which pass away —
                            change from the ridiculous to the idiotic, is not a very comforting " redemption "— it is
                            not present salvation. It is the spirit of the world out on exhibition. When the sisters
                            wore high-heeled shoes, they were ridiculed. When they discovered that nature did not
                            require them to stand on their toes, they ceased to wear them — a sensible act. Now, idiocy
                            and fashion seek this as a means of elevation. We may honor our profession -— separation
                            from the world — and give an external proof of our " desire and effort," for the best in
                            fashion, and hold to it because it is best, until there is a reasonable show of improvement,
                            and not merely an excuse to ape worldly fashions. There is a sort of awkward embarrassment,
                            when you chance to meet a brother with such an index that you are in doubt, and approach him
                            with the question : '' Are you acquainted with the Shakers? " It was my pleasure not long
                            since to be in a city with four sisters, and it was a source of laudable pride to be in
                            company with the best dressed females in the city. And I have all reason for believing the
                            fashionables envied them their comfort! Let our seeming and being, be one — be Shakers,
                            square and plain." Our motto: "Progressive redemption," from the spirit of the world. As
                            ever your brother,Ayer, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Squaw's lament: original" TEIform="index"/>Squaw's lament: original
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wanetta" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE SQUAW'S LAMENT: ORIGINAL. Wanetta. Where the green fringes fall on the banks
                                    of the soft lake, Lay all still the red man's canoe, And the fire burned high on the
                                    face of the hunting ground, And sent o'er the waters its glow. It was praise to the
                                    Great Spirit Maninee Waninee, Who gave him the word and the flame, Who gave him the
                                    bright leaves to shelter his wigwam, And hide him when the dark curtain came. He was
                                    brave of the bravest, and chief of the chiefest, The Great Spirit often him bless,
                                    He wrong not his people with any cold war, .Nor even the squaw did oppress. High
                                    over his wigwam, Kanchee the wild bird, Sing songs that makes his heart glad, And
                                    unto his hunting ground comes oft the gone ones, Who make him, 0 make him not sad!
                                    When o'er the still lake sailed forth the red man, He speak not a word down the
                                    tide, Then the Wanitee help him, the Wanitee keep him, And from the dark tempest him
                                    guide. But the red man have eyes that can look far away, And he see coming down to
                                    the shore, What make him with sad heart turn the fringed bank, There the peace of
                                    his fathers implore. <pb n="271" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 271 For t'was
                                    coming so strong o'er the face of the still lake What Indian knew a bad sign, A wild
                                    whirl, a strong whirl that roll to the hunting ground, And mutter so dark, this is
                                    mine. Then he know there shall come from afar a great many, Who take what the Great
                                    Spirit gave And Kanchee sings not in the top of the wild tree And hushed is the
                                    voice of the brave. He give up the beads that the wild forest brought him And take
                                    down the rings from his ears, But they not so much as the Peace of his people That
                                    his fathers kept many long years. Oh! over the hunting ground Esquaw is angry, The
                                    tomahawk glistens anew, And the squaw hides her little one under her mantle, And
                                    pray to the Great One, help through. 0 wicked war! cruel war! go away, far away,
                                    From the fringed bank and the glad shore, O wicked war! cruel war! go away, far
                                    away, Darken not the land any more. O good people! help the Great Spirit of
                                    kindness, To soften the hearts of all men : Till he sing song of peace and the
                                    Kanchee shall hear it, And sing it forth over again. Then all will clasp hands, the
                                    red ones and white ones, Be children of the Great Spirit, Love, And unto each home
                                    will much peace and plenty Come down from the bright world above. Definitions :
                                    Maninee, Waninee, Spirit of the wild woods. Kanchee, Wild bird of the forest.
                                    Esquaw, Guardian of the prosperity of the red man. Wanitee, Guardian of the Lodge.
                                    Evil-speaking and evil-thinking about others are kindred evils. They usually go
                                    together. And they who practice them stand condemned before the first great
                                    principle of Christian character. The heart that thinketh and speaketh evil is
                                    devoid of love, for love " thinketh no evil, and rejoiceth not in iniquity, but
                                    rejoiceth in the truth."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religious telescope" TEIform="index"/>Religious Telescope.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentissiana: In Union there is strength" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA: "In Union there is
                            strength."</head><p TEIform="p"> " By this shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one for another."
                            When, on the 6th of April, 1820, I accidentally or providentially found the Shakers, at
                            Watervliet, Albany county, N. Y., and, in answer to questions, they told me how they lived—a
                            life of virginity and community, as sister and brother, I said, where do you get the power.
                            Other folks can't live so. They replied, " In union there is strength; where many minds
                            combine together, for a certain purpose, they form a strong current and are a support to
                            each other." Community is society in its most compact form. As members of community, of our
                            own volition, self-respect requires that we make some sacrifice of selfishness, to the
                            better feelings of the community—especially the better half. " Love must govern the world,"
                            so said the little shepherdess. " I believe in the communion of .saints." In each sister and
                            brother, I]find a saint ; with the saint, I commune. If, in any case, ego, or something
                            lower down, be lurking about—if I have not the self-respect to let the naughty thing alone,
                            I ought to have a Crusoedom, where I can be " monarch of all I survey." " Blow ye the
                            Trumpet in Zion." In accord and concord the outside world, under divine influences, are this
                            day an example for our beloved Zion. Let accord, concord, love and good-will permeate all
                            branches of Zion; and truth-loving souls, under divine influence, will fill the waste places
                            of Zion and extend her borders. Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The man who indulges in evil surmisings about his brethren..." TEIform="index"/>The man who indulges in evil surmisings about his brethren...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The man who indulges in evil surmisings about his brethren or neighbors ought to know that he
                            is serving the devil quite as well as if he were a highway robber.</p></div2><pb n="272" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="84 Russell St., Melbourne" TEIform="index"/>84 Russell St., Melbourne</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Terry, W. H." TEIform="persName"/>W. H. Terry</byline><p TEIform="p"> 84 Russell St., Melbourne October, 4, 1881. My Dear Elder Lomas : I read with some
                                concern your brief article in the August Manifesto " can we afford to suspend ? " and my
                                reply is a solid no. The gems with which the magazine is so thickly stud ded are
                                infinitely more valuable than the dollars that represent the subscription money, and the
                                world would be poorer for their loss. The only transmittable money I have by me is a two
                                dollar note which I inclose as a small help to pay expenses. I understood from your
                                letter a few months since that my last remittance would pay my subscription to the end
                                of current year. If the Manifesto goes on, as I sincerely hope it will, I will at that
                                time send twenty dollars toward next issue, taking whatever copies it is convenient to
                                send. I know what a thankless office the editorship of a religious paper is, having had
                                twelve years' experience of it, and can therefore sympathize with you as a brother, but
                                hold on just a little longer, my friend, till some one capable of bearing the burden
                                takes it from your shoulders. Yours fraternally, </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, York Co., Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, York Co., Me.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>Otis Sawyer</byline><p TEIform="p">Alfred, York Co., Me. November 12, 1881. Dear Brother Albert: The Manifesto must live ;
                                it is indispensable. Every number comes to us laden with rich offerings and
                                contributions from those who live the Christ-life and know whereof they speak ; added to
                                these are choice selections and gems of thought, while the editorials are " meat of the
                                nut." These are combined in attractive form so as to make the monthly visitor a most
                                welcome guest. At home it is an educator, while it is diffusing a broad knowledge of the
                                truth as the waters cover the sea. Taking "the sense of the meetings," at Alfred and New
                                Gloucester, it was the unanimous expression that the Manifesto was ably and
                                satisfactorily edited, that it must be continued, and that the'present talented editor
                                be requested to continue his services. Now if it be that " the voice of the people is
                                the voice of God," then we are sure that Brother Albert will continue as in times past
                                to do the will of God. Both the editor and publisher are deserving and do receive the
                                thanks and share the gratitude of all Zion for their unwearied labor and pains in making
                                the Manifesto one of the best periodicals of the day. Receive freely the love and
                                blessing of your gospel friends in Alfred and West Gloucester. Yours in the cause
                                forever,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South Union, Ky.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. Eads</byline><p TEIform="p">South Union, Ky. November 9, 1881. \ My Dear Brother G. A. L.: I must write a line to
                                tell you how much I am pleased with Excelsior in the present number of our little craft,
                                just received— words so true, so clear, so direct and withal so modest. More it seems
                                could not be crowded in less compass. All Shaker theology in about two hundred words !
                                It has been thought by some that to stick to Christ is not keeping up with the
                                progressive age in which we live. Hence they are seeking to find what they call new ruts
                                or grooves to move in ; but why should we want any thing more than the " highest and
                                best ? " Excelsior will be hard to excel by the editor or others. Very lovingly
                            thine,</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No heretic" TEIform="index"/>NO HERETIC</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier" TEIform="persName"/>Whittier</byline><p TEIform="p">Call him not heretic whose works attest His faith in goodness, by no creed confessed.
                            Whatever in love's name is truly done To free the bound and lift the fallen one Is done in
                            Christ. Whoso, indeed and word, Is not against Him, labors for our Lord. When he who, sad
                            and weary, longing sore For love's sweet service, sought the sister's door; One saw the
                            heavenly, one the human guest. But who shall say which loved the Master best?</p></div2><pb n="273" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Valedictory" TEIform="index"/>VALEDICTORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With this issue of The Manifesto —the closing of Vol. XL—the present management of Editor
                                and Publisher ceases. It gives us extreme pleasure to announce that The Manifesto WILL
                                CONTINUE TO LIVE AND FLOURISH captained by earnest hearts and perhaps abler influences.
                                We feel warranted in saying, that in regard to our Shaker testimony, The Manifesto will,
                                in the future, even more so than in the past, give forth no uncertain sound. The record
                                of its past is so well known to our readers, that modesty forbids that we do other than
                                to leave judgment upon it with them. We leave it with considerable satisfaction,
                                acknowledging that we have enjoyed much satisfaction in our past labors upon it. It has
                                not been a sinecure, but invariably the reverse of such. We cannot envy bur successors,
                                but make them welcome to every aid and comfort that any can bestow. We appeal to the
                                generous for their continued subscriptions; and hope that, by the aid of tangible funds
                                and gospel encouragement, the hearts of the future management will be made many times
                                glad. We thank the contemporary press for many kind words and valuable exchange list. We
                                call the especial attention of all to. the future address of our monthly.— The Shaker
                                Manifesto, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who are the heretics" TEIform="index"/>WHO ARE THE HERETICS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The strangest and most condemnable feature observable in the arena of the so-called
                                Christian religious world to-day is the hue and cry of " Heretic " of one or more,
                                against one or more, who may choose to differ from established, churchal, world-bound
                                creeds, to favor a belief in a manner of teaching and of life, more in accord with what
                                Christ taught, with what Christ lived ! But little reflection is called into operation
                                that any may decide, that the creed of any church nearest resembling the immediate,
                                practical teachings and life of Christ, is indeed the most truly Christian creed and
                                Church. Therefore, when any individuals, sick of the scortative, worldly life of the
                                flesh, and of creeds which sustain the elements of a life, unchanged from the old,
                                Adamic career, hearken to the higher inspirations, and put on more of the Christly
                                self-denying elements, and yield to these in practice, the cry of " Hereticts" is
                                sounded world-wide from those who have embraced the profession of Christianity, but who
                                hate in their very hearts the self-denying practice of Christ's simple life. Never,
                                since the light of true Christianity blazed on the world, as resplendently as it is
                                found to do, through the exemplary life of Jesus, have men been left with better
                                evidences of the senses of what Christ taught and lived, than can be, and is almost
                                universally known, by those who think to-day. The comeouters are not the heretics ; the
                                standbys of the old, false creeds, who make faith and a profession answer the ends of
                                conscience, instead of headlights to a genuine following of Christ's life, are the
                                genuine heretics ; who are without the pale of a present salvation from sin, and with
                                only the semblance fPitreial. <pb n="274" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 274 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. of hope
                                in the future, which such profession and faith, without the practice of Christ's life,
                                can give them. Poor hope — hopeless. The so-called infidels have an unerring aim in
                                destroying the erection of creeds which are not built upon deeds,—lives that are not
                                like Christ's. " As long as heaven is the reward of creed instead of deed," says
                                Ingersoll, " just so long will every orthodox church be a bastile, every member a
                                prisoner, and every priest a turnkey! " And Ingersoll is correct. Let professedly
                                Christian people live what they profess — the Christian life — a life modeled after,
                                that of Jesus — and so-called infidels will not only be left without their abundant
                                ammunition of accusation, but the world will glisten with myriads of constellations of
                                present salvations never experienced before, through all who will Jive like unto such
                                profession. Christians are those who, regardless of the excessive self-denials practiced
                                by Jesus, do accept such as the straight and narrow way, and walk therein by adaily and
                                continuous practice. None others are Christians, no matter what or how much they pray or
                                profess. |fj" The foolishness of preaching" never was more apparent than is
                                almosfuniversally seen among professedly Christian denominations, holding on to creeds
                                of Atonement, Baptism, Communions, and the many foolish fashions of the typical, while
                                their lives are so far from being like that of Christ Jesus as to be almost unworthy to
                                be brought in contrast, because they are living the reverse of Christ's life. Look once
                                at the purity of Christ's virginity, all through his life! If it is heresy to disbelieve
                                that Christ's virginity can make of ns virgins if we live not so, then blessed be
                                heresy! If heresy embraces all who deny, that Christ's life of equality with his
                                brethren, and denial to individual possessions, establishes the same Christianity in us,
                                then glorious is such heresy ! If any cannot believe that the peacefulness,
                                unretaliation, and unworldliness of Christ immolates us into similar Christian
                                conditions, without our similar, personal self-denials, blessed be such heretics! The
                                heavens bid for more heretics, who will shun the profession, rather than fail of the
                                possession of the elements that made np Christ's life. These elements are essentially,
                                wholly and truly, Christianity. Any one-sided issue from that of following in the
                                footsteps of the living Christ, who lived the Christian life, who said: " I am the way ;
                                Follow me ;" such side issue is rank heresy, and it advocates glaring evidences of
                                heresy, inasmuch as they are not saved from the commission of sins to day—are indeed
                                "miserable sinners" and have none other but an imaginary hope of any salvation from sin,
                                nor possession of heaven hereafter. ¦A</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Welcome progress" TEIform="index"/>WELCOME PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is more than one hundred years since the founders of the Shaker Church, arriving in
                                America, preached the good news of a present salvation from sin, and consequently from
                                the punishments of sin through a life of self-denial, similar to 'that lived by Jesus,
                                and which saved Jesus. Pur- <pb n="275" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 275 ity, Peace,
                                Equality and Unworldly ambitions ranked first, a most worthy of attainment. For the
                                possession of these any, and every necessary self-denial was endured. Closely allied to
                                these, but secondary in importance were theological beliefs, which,however unorthodox
                                and heretical at the time, have since become the popular beliefs of the millions. Ann
                                Lee taught that "Hell" was the torments of conscience; not a literal "fire and brimstone
                                ;" and though she taught more than a century since, this idea is now generally accepted
                                as most true. Ann Lee rejected with abhorrence the theory of a physical resurrection,
                                which only a few years since was the popular belief; therefore, the Shakers were ready
                                for the advent of spiritualism, and able to interpret its manifold phenomena. The Second
                                Advent having already occurred among the Shakers, they welcomed the progress of the
                                idea, when it sprung upon a startled world. The equality of the sexes before the law and
                                before God has been peculiarly and originally Shaker ever since their rise, and every
                                new ray is hailed with especial delight. To the Shakers, God is Male and Female — Father
                                and Mother. The earliest testimony of the Shakers was accompanied by a protest against
                                slavery, white or black. The Shakers, having been communists since their origin, welcome
                                the dawn of the grand anti-monopoly theory and practice. By their invariable testimony
                                against national wars and family contentions, they were and are ready for the past and
                                future settlements of difficulties by arbitration. There have been no forward movement
                                yet made by Church nor State but were anticipated and longed for by the little, obscure
                                people, called Shakes. We would welcome more progress, particularly in the churches; we
                                would welcome the relinquishment of the unstable hope, dreamed of in the atonement
                                doctrine, and the substitution of the real life of Christ, which will save, and make us
                                at-onement with Christ. We look for this consummation with positive certainty, and
                                welcome its dawning from any circumstance and from every quarter. The Shakers have very
                                much to gain before they assert their proficiency as a Christian people; but they have
                                thus far been in the van of all the dghteous demonstrations that have reformed Church
                                and State for the better; and yet stand ready to welcome more, and an eternal increase
                                of morality, justice and true religion. These forward movements have been made at the
                                expense of proneness to selfish considerations; and extreme self-denial in the
                                foundation of the Shaker life and Church. ¦</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Polly J. Reed" TEIform="index"/>ELDRESS POLLY J. REED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Ere these lines are read by our readers, the above noble woman will have passed on to her
                                spiritual home. In all our land " none knew her but to love her, none named her but to
                                praise." From earliest childhood she has been a bright star in the Shaker firmament,
                                ripening to a most glorious planet amid gospel constellations. Hers has been a life of
                                most willing consecration and obedience to what she believed to be right, and it can be
                                truthfully said, that she was completely <pb n="276" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 276 THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. worn out in the service of her God. She was a woman of most excelleni and
                                ingenious faculties; a finished scholar; a beautiful speaker, and a most loveable
                                associate. • She was a great worker with her hands, and her heart bore evidences of
                                continuous services in the arena of spiritual labors and official capacity. She dies at
                                the age of 66 years, crowned with the highest honors, won by bearing the greatest
                                burdens of society. Her successor at this writing is not yet selected. Eldress Polly,
                                Farewell; and may your illustrious example shine down the future lapses of ages, to
                                illuminate and cheer us all. [Deceased Nov. 25, 1881.J</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-conceit" TEIform="index"/>SELF-CONCEIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES This ugly feature is found very prevalent among those who are ardently
                                inclined to religion. There is really as much, if not more, need of a crucifixion of
                                self-conceit among professors of religion than anywhere else. When individuals get to be
                                so good as to consider themselves especially cared for by Providence, and do not show
                                the effects of this special notice by self-abasement that longs for and works for the
                                good of others, all forgetful of themselves — even of their goodness and their physical
                                comforts — we are reminded of the truth of the wise man : " Seest thou a man wise in his
                                own conceit, there is more hope of a fool than of him." "Let another praise thee, and
                                not thy own mouth ; a stranger and not thine own lips." It is commonly observed, that as
                                persons become really better, they become less boastful and boasterous of themselves;
                                and a calm, sweet temper controls them, which prompts them, unlike their former selves,
                                to seek how they may do good unto others, their foes perhaps, and are hence no longer
                                wrapped up in considerations peculiarly selfish, and ostentatiously so. If any are
                                really better than others, they will show it by their increased Christian demeanor; and
                                unless it is so manifested, none will accept it as a fact from their own mouths.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Emulation" TEIform="index"/>EMULATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is not because we would restrain any from emulating and exceeding the characteristics
                                of Jesus, that we call so much attention to his life as a pattern, and condemn the
                                theory of his death as an atonement. But we find such an almost universal passing by, or
                                passing over Jesus' example, to get into heaven byan easier road than through the same
                                acts of self-denial endured by him, that we feel called upon to continue the clarion cry
                                of Follow Christ." Not simply believe in some creed which Jesus never uttered nor
                                thought of, but to do something — live the same spiritual, self-denying life; the same
                                unworldly, unfleshly, simply Christian life, from which so many world-loving individuals
                                flee.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two sermons" TEIform="index"/>TWO SERMONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Recently, Sir Garnet Wolseley, of the British army, has made himself more renowned than
                                ever, by giving his testimony in favor of total abstinence by soldiers from in;oxicating
                                beverages, either in camp or on the battle-field. Thus endeth <pb n="277" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 277 sermon first, as testimony- against intemperance. Our illustrious
                                contemporary — the New York Commercial Advertiser— commenting on the above, thinks, that
                                so far as camp-life goes, the absence of intoxicants is best; but on the battle-field, a
                                man needs all the whisky he can drink to put sufficient devil into Mm to make him
                                willing to massacre his unprovoked fellow-beings. Thus endeth sermon two.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eldress Polly's successor" TEIform="index"/>ELDRESS POLLY'S SUCCESSOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The decease of Eldress Polly J. Reed necessitated the filling of the extensive vacuum
                                occasioned in the ranks of the Central Bishoprick, of which the deceased has been so
                                competent and honorable a member Eldress Harriet M. Btjllard, for several years the
                                senior of the Novitiate order at Shakers, N. Y., has been chosen to occupy the
                                burdensome, responsible, and honored position. Those of us who have been intimately
                                acquainted with her for many years, know her to be altogether competent, worthy, and an
                                unexcelled champion of our faith. We are safe in assuring all that the interests of the
                                faith and organization will only improve under her administration, in company with her
                                senior companions ; and the original force and determination of her character for the
                                right will be ever and righteously administered. The mantle has undoubted fallen
                                properly. Those who would be pleased with an article from her pen, we refer them to
                                closing chapter in " Plain Talks ; or AVhat must I do to be a Shaker ? "</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received from" TEIform="index"/>RECEIVED FROM</head><p TEIform="p"> : George Wilcox.................. $40 00 Philip Smith.................... 20 00 Isaac
                                Auger.................. ... 12 00 B. B. Dunlavy.................... 40 00</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DECEASED</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Starbird, Sally" TEIform="index"/>Sally Starbird</head><p TEIform="p">, died on Poland, July 4, aged 76.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Donovan, Richard" TEIform="index"/>Richard Donovan</head><p TEIform="p">, died at Alfred, Nov30, aged 68.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Davis, Evan" TEIform="index"/>Evan Davis</head><p TEIform="p">, at Enfield, N. H., July 26, aged 67 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Special notice" TEIform="index"/>SPECIAL NOTICE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline><p TEIform="p">The little pamphlet entitled: "Plain Talks upon Practical Religion ; also answering the
                                question : " What must I do to be a Shaker ? " has been out of print for some time. We
                                have received $12.00 from two parties toward issuing a new edition. Parties desirous of
                                getting them at cost price may send us at the rate of $4.00 per hundred. Address,
                                Shakers, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good resolutions" TEIform="index"/>GOOD RESOLUTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> Form and re-form good resolutions. If some are not kept, that constitutes no reason for
                                not making them. " Gird on the heavenly armor" for good works more earnestly than ever.
                                Good resolutions are the spirit's safeguard. Some persons are always intending to do
                                better but never find time to begin. Now is your opportunity, don't miss it. Keep the
                                good resolves now that you should have kept last year. The year 1882 will be as fresh
                                and new as any preceding it; so live that it shall be the best. Make your own heaven and
                                you will be sure to have it. You have the solid benefit of one more year's experience ;
                                profit by it. Never give up ; it is unmanly. If you stumble, do not stop there ; avoid
                                the same error again. Try, and if you fail once, a hundred times, struggle on, the
                                reward will be sure. It is only those who "look back " that come to grief. " Victory
                                comes only through repeated struggles and failures." Onward and upward steps wins the
                                Christian's crown. " Experience is a great teacher," and lessons of experience are often
                                profitable, though not always pleasant. " Learn from the past to profit by the present,
                                and from the present to live for the future." Shrink not before adverse gatUty 9^cmtf.
                                    <pb n="278" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 278 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. circumstances — it shows weakness.
                                Persevere. Jesus was unflinching in courage, unwavering in the right. ' Imitate his
                                example. If bad habits and vicious courses hold you in their fell grip, don't despair:
                                grapple manfully with them and you can work wonders. What others have done by their own
                                efforts, and God's help, you can'do. No other one can perform your self denying work,
                                and if you fail, what you should have done will be greatly missed. It is the
                                self-denying struggles that save. There is joy in the thought that you have conquered
                                temptation. Never exchange the blessings of virtue, for the burning fires of vice. " A
                                sinful life stains clear through." Virtue confers present joys ; secure them now. Let
                                virtue be the mainspring animating your whole life, and your future is safe, Enfield,
                                Gonn.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our parentage" TEIform="index"/>OUR PARENTAGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> Is the erratic idea of no fathers and no mothers in the gospel logical? If so, how can
                                we acknowledge the fatherhood and motherhood of God, or claim to be children of a Divine
                                Parentage, or, indeed, how can we be brothers and sisters ? If we renounce the first
                                relation why not disclaim the other ? Be monks and nuns; but, even these in their
                                separate communion, claim their leaders respectively as parents, styling them the father
                                or mother-superior, as the case may be, and yielding to them implicit child-like
                                obedience. A true natural household is Father and Mother, brothers and sisters; all
                                other connections by ties of consanguinity are outside of the family circle, not
                                necessarily a part of it. Progenital names and relationships do not at all apply to, nor
                                will they ever be likely to become a part of, our spiritual unioh, which is organized on
                                the basis of parental government ; and only as the father and mother elements harmonize
                                mutually, for the welfare and happiness of the children of their adoption, can there be
                                a happy, flourishing and well-ordered household. It requires all the faculties of the
                                natural man and woman, purified, refined and turned into the channel of spiritual life,
                                to fit them for the high trust of paternal and maternal government in Zion. Those who
                                are deficient in the qualities that would make them proper heads of families in the
                                order of nature will be found wanting in the elements that would gather, nurture and
                                bear with souls until they come fortli unto the birth of the regeneration. Wisdom and
                                love combine to bring forth perfection. All hail to those full-orbed souls that shine as
                                suns amid the lesser stars in God's grand universe of life. These are my fathers and
                                mothers in the new creation, and their obedient children are my brothers and sisters,
                                the hundred-fold relation of promise ; the only kindred I claim. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some signs" TEIform="index"/>SOME SIGNS</head><p TEIform="p">Solomon said, many centuries ago: " Even a child is known by his doings, whether his work
                                be pure, and whether it be right.' Some people seem to think that children have no
                                character at all. On the contrary, an observing eye sees in these young creatures the
                                signs of what they are likely to be for life. When I see a little boy slow to go to
                                school and glad of every excuse to neglect his book, I think it a sign that he will be a
                                dunce. When I see a boy in haste to spend every penny as soon as he gets it, I think it
                                a sign that he will be a spendthrift. When I see a boy hoarding up his penniesl and
                                unwilling to part with them for any good purpose, I think it a sign that he wil, be a
                                miser. When I see a boy or girl looking out for themselves and dislike to share good
                                things with others, I think it a sign that the child will grow up a very selfish person.
                                When I see boys and girls often quarrelling, I think it a sign that they will be violent
                                and hateful men and women. When I see a little boy willing to take strong drink, I think
                                it a sign that he will be a drunkard. <pb n="279" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 279
                                When I see a boy smoking or chewing tobacco, I think it a sign that he will soon be
                                guilty of other filthy habits. When I see a boy who never prays, I think it a sign that
                                he will be a profane and profligate man. When I see a'chlld obedient to its parents, I
                                think it a sign of great future blessings from Almighty God. When I see a boy fond of
                                the Bible, and well acquainted with it, I think it a sign that he will be a pious and
                                happy man. And though great changes sometimes take place in the character, yet, as a
                                general rule, these signs do not fail.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Applied theology" TEIform="index"/>APPLIED THEOLOGY</head><p TEIform="p">One Sunday morning, while a certain deacon was preparing for church, a wandering
                                wayfarer, or, in modern parlance, a tramp, appeared at his door, pleaded his hunger, and
                                begged for something to eat. The deacon looked solemn and frowningly, but reluctantly
                                got a loaf of bread and began to cut it ; but while doing so, took occasion to admonish
                                the beggar concerning the error of his ways. After reminding him that it was the holy
                                Sabbath which he was desecrating, he asked him if he knew how to pray ? " No," was the
                                reply. " Then," said the deacon, " I'll learn you," and he commenced to repeat the
                                Lord's Prayer. But just as he uttered the first words, " Our Father," the beggar
                                interrupted him with the question, " What, is He your Father and mine too ?" " Yes," the
                                deacon replied, "Why," exclaimed the beggar, " we are brothers then, ain't we ? Can't
                                you cut that slice a little thicker ?"</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miss Alice who has just finished..." TEIform="index"/>Miss Alice who has just finished...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Miss Alice who has just finished saying her prayers with her little brother: " Mamma,
                                Ally wasn't thinking about God at all. He was thinking about his sled." Master Alfred,
                                indignantly : " How do you know, miss? You can't see down my stomach."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For corns" TEIform="index"/>For Corns</head><p TEIform="p">.—Tie a bit of black silk cloth around the toe, or fasten it inside the stocking if the
                                corn is on the bottom of the foot. It seems a simple remedy, but is very efficient. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A stiff whisp broom is better..." TEIform="index"/>A stiff whisp broom is better...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A stiff whisp broom is better to remove the dust and dirt from a horse's legs than a
                                currycomb. Many horses with thin skin are exceedingly nervous and restive in the hands
                                of a careless groom, and this nervousness often degenerates into viciousness.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove mildew" TEIform="index"/>To Remove Mildew</head><p TEIform="p">.—Take one ounce of chloride of lime and dissolve in a stone vessel. Turn off the clear
                                water, but none of the sediment. Rinse the article mildewed in clear water, and lay into
                                this solution; stir often until the spots disappear; then rinse thoroughly to remove
                                every trace of the lime, which will rot the goods. Or take one ounce of oxalic acid ;
                                dissolve, and lay the article into the solution for three minutes ; then wring out and
                                lay in the sunshine. If the spots do not readily disappear, repeat,the process, and
                                afterward rinse very thoroughly.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To keep mice out of seeds..." TEIform="index"/>To keep mice out of seeds...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To keep mice out of seeds, the Druggists' Circular recommends mixing a few lumps of gum
                                camphor with the seeds, in the boxes where they are stored.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sacrament" TEIform="index"/>THE SACRAMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doten, Lizzie" TEIform="persName"/>LIZZIE DOTEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> The aged pastor broke the bread — With trembling hand he poured the wine, "Eat, drink" — in
                            earnest tones he said__ These emblems of a life divine — His body, broken for our sins ; His
                            blood for our salvation shed; The priceless sacrifice that wins Life and redemption from the
                            dead. " See how with tender love He stands, And calls you to His faithful heart; Lo ! from
                            His wounded side and hands, Again the crimson life drops start. 0 sinner! wherefore will you
                            stay, Regardless of your lost estate 1 Come at your Saviour's call to-day, Before, alas ! it
                            is too late." Forth from his lowly seat apart, A dark-browed Ethiopian came, Htfms Qopits.
                                <pb n="280" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 280 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. As if ngw life had stirred his heart,
                            That beat within his manly frame. " O, give to me,'" he meekly said, A portion of that
                            heavenly food ; I too would eat the living bread, And find salvation through His blood." The
                            pastor turned with wondering eyes ; But when he saw the dusky brow, He answered, with a
                            quick surprise, " Ho ! bold intruder ; who art thou ? The master's table is not free To give
                            the low-born servant place ; Such privilege can only be, For his accepted sons of grace."
                            Upon the dusky brow there glowed A flush that was not wrath nor pride, As forward he
                            majestic strode, And stood close by the altar side. The broken bread his left hand spurned,
                            With sudden movement to the floor; While with his right, he quickly turned The consecrated
                            chalice oe'r. One instant, for the tempest cloud To gather on each pallid face ; And then
                            uprose the angry crowd, To thrust him from the sacred place. With conscious might he raised
                            his hand — A being of resistless will — And uttered the sublime command, That hushed the
                            tempest—'/Peace,be still!' The waves of wrath and human pride Rolled back, without the power
                            to harm ; The angry murmurs surged and died, And lo! there was a breathless calm. The dusky
                            brow, to dazzling white, Had in one fleeting instant turned ; And round his head a halo
                            bright Of heaven's resplendent glory burned. " I do reject," he calmly said, " These outward
                            forms — this bread, this wine ; Lo! at my table all are fed, Made welcome by a love divine.
                            The high, the low, the rich, the poor, The black, the white, the bond, the free, The sinful
                            soul, the heart impure, Forbid not them to come to me. " Too long, too long have faithless
                            creeds Shut out the sunshine from above ; While human hearts, with human needs, Have
                            perished from the lack of love. O break for them truth's living bread ; Let love, like wine,
                            unhindered flow ; Thus would I have the hungry fed, And let these outward emblems go." Then
                            from the altar side there rose A cloud with matchless.glory bright, As when at evening's
                            calm repose The sun withdraws his radiant light; But though so far removed from all, He
                            seemed in presence to depart, The seed of living truth let fall, Took root in many a
                            thoughtful heart.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All hail the manifesto" TEIform="index"/>ALL HAIL THE MANIFESTO</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas</byline><p TEIform="p">Elsewhere, our readers will be made aware that our loved monthly—The Manifesto—is not to
                            suspend, but will continue its manifestations with renewed vigor., and be hailed by very
                            many glad hearts by an increased devotion. It is a fact worthy to be mentioned, never to be
                            forgotten, that our Manifesto is a favorite with hundreds and thousands not of the immediate
                            societies, called Shakers. This fact will bear much reflection. It is one of the
                            impossibilities for any to make a distasteful testimony agreeable. There is nothing in the
                            Shaker testimony, as put forth in The Manifesto, but is a disturbing element to a carnal
                            worldly mind and life. That so many should have a respect and even love and admiration,
                            genuine and unfeigned, for those who live the Shaker life, and for its most out-spoken,
                            monthly advocate, will ever be an occasion of fruitful thought, and very pleasant
                            congratulation. The Manifesto is the only offspring from our heart, towards which we can
                            look with unfeigned pleasure and an admissible pride. That it has done much valuable work of
                            keeping the faith as fully represented to thousands, in our own land; and in foreign
                            countries where English is spoken, it has introduced the faith, where perhaps it would have
                            been heard of and learned many years in the future. The Manifesto has the <pb n="281" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 281 respect of all its contemporary periodicals ; not
                            only for its generally beautiful typographical make-up, but for its good theology and
                            directions to a good, religious, superior life. We fear not the future course of our child.
                            That it will keep up the manifestations of growth as its years increase, in all the
                            testimony necessary to enable souls to become full fledged Christians, and thus to elevate
                            them in a resurrection of soul-life not exceeded outside of the heavens, we have no doubts
                            whatever. We again ask for our successors the kindest sympathy—sympathy that has hands to
                            help, legs to travel, prompt MONEY TO MAKE THE GOSPEL fly abroad—and in every way let theirs
                            be made an easier task than has been ours. Thanking all, from a heart full of gratitude, we
                            are yours truly, .</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weed, Parsons and company" TEIform="index"/>WEED, PARSONS AND COMPANY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> ¦------------------?------------------.. We cannot afford to come to a full close of our
                            labors, without acknowledging deep and lasting respect and gratitude, to Weed, Parsons and
                            Co., Albany, N. Y.,—our printers. Much of the beauty of art of typography, freedom from
                            errors, etc., is due to their credit. We would speak for them the patronage of the entire
                            world; and whoever desires their printing, binding, lithographing, electro typing, and press
                            work done by a most careful and painstaking firm, at most moderate rates—they have done The
                            Manifesto work at cost, or less—apply for the estimates of such work of our noble patrons—
                            Weed, Parsons and Co., Albany, N. Y. #</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Asking a blessing" TEIform="index"/>ASKING A BLESSING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="D., M. A." TEIform="persName"/>M. A. D.</byline><p TEIform="p">He asked a blessing on all set before him With kindly, modest grace,and then began To carve
                            the meat; just then a cloud came o'er him, Which made him look and act another man. " Mutton
                            again ! and almost raw, confound it! How can one eat this stuff with temper meek ? And these
                            potatoes, just half-baked, around it! Oh, for a decent dinner once a week !" " Some tea, my
                            love? " " No love — no tea I thank you— I'm sick of things diluted and undone ; Charles
                            Henry, if you don't behave, I'll spank you! Good heavens ! a careless wife, a graceless son
                            ! " The bread is sour! the butter—that is dirty ; I vow I find no food or comfort here. When
                            will you learn, Maria, you're over thirty, « To cook ! I'll dine on ginger snaps and beer.
                            The man meant nothing wrong—he asked a blessing. With gentle thoughts of food not mean or
                            sparse, His words were always kindly and caressing Till disappointment made his prayer a
                            farce. A little less of self and more of duty— A little care, God's bounties to disburse,
                            Are things fare nobler than mere grace and beauty— These bring a blessing—those provoke a
                            curse.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Methodist society in Mendon, Vermont..." TEIform="index"/>A Methodist society in Mendon, Vermont...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A Methodist society in Mendon, Vt,, has put up about a dozen good horse-sheds at
                                    the church. That is practical religion, and worth a dozen exhortations on "falling
                                    from grace " or sanctification. A man who will hitch his horse to a fence on a cold
                                    winter day, and do it for years, while he goes inside the meeting-house to talk
                                    aboiit "faith" and "love" "sanctification" and "election," lacks some essential
                                    feature of the fgospel of Christ. The world wants ¦more of the Christianity which
                                    builds horse-sheds, pays one hundred cents on the dollar, treats the horses kindly,
                                    cares for the stock, and is not domineering in the family. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Vermont tribune" TEIform="index"/>Vermont Tribune.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="282" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to begin the day" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO BEGIN THE DAY</head><p TEIform="p">Begin the morning by saying to thyself, I shall meet with the busybody, the ungrateful,
                            arrogant, deceitful, envious, unsocial. All these things happen to them by reason of their
                            ignorance of what is good and evil. But I, who have seen the nature of the good that it is
                            beautiful, and of the bad that it is ugly, and the nature of him who does wrong that it is
                            akin to me, not only of the same blood or seed, but that it participates in the same
                            intelligence and the same por tion of the divinity, I can neither be injured by any of them
                            ; for no one can fix on me what is ugly, nor can I be angry with my kinsman, nor hate him.
                            For we were made for co-operation, like feet, like hands, like eyelids, like the rows of the
                            upper and lower teeth. To act against one another, then, is contrary to nature ; and it is
                            acting against one another to be vexed and to turn away. These wise words were uttered by
                            Marcus Aurelius many centuries since, and they have a bearing on the conduct and happiness
                            of life to-day as well as when first spoken.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Witchcraft in Germany" TEIform="index"/>WITCHCRAFT IN GERMANY</head><p TEIform="p">Accusations of witchcraft and maltreatment of supposed witches by the illiterate country
                            people are still things of frequent occurrence in Germany. A recent number of the Danziger
                            Zeitung tells of an incident of this kind in the village of Stangenwalde, where an old lone
                            woman was accused of having bewitched an invalid widow, because, as the latter was driving
                            past the other's hut, her horse suddenly came to a stop. This was assumed to be owing to the
                            old woman's occult influence, and to prove that the widow's illness had been caused by her.
                            The old creature, frightened out of her senses, was dragged to the widow's bedside and
                            subjected to various torments to coerce her into expelling the devil from her victim. This
                            mode of procedure failing, she was compelled to inflict cuts in three of her fingers and
                            permit the widow to suck her blood, after which the invalid immediately began to feel
                            better. It was then proposed to hang the witch, and a rope was fastened around her neck,
                            while the crowd beat her about the head and face with slippers and shoemaker's lasts. She
                            was finally rescued, but in a dangerously injured condition.</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Value of ammonia" TEIform="index"/>VALUE OF AMMONIA</head><p TEIform="p">Ammonia will remove finger marks from paint, where there would otherwise have to be a good
                            deal of scrubbing with soap, which takes the paint oft too. Ammonia is useful to wash all
                            the brushes that are used in a household. Nothing will cleanse greasy sinks, pans or
                            scrubbing brushes so well. A teaspoonful in a basin of water will make hair brushes
                            beautifully white. Take care not to let the back of brushes dip below the surface ; rinse
                            them with clear, warm water, and put them in a sunny window to dry. A small bottle of
                            ammonia is also useful for the wardrobe. Wet a little sponge with it and you can take out
                            most any spot.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Where our forests are going" TEIform="index"/>WHERE OUR FORESTS ARE GOING</head><p TEIform="p">To make shoe pegs enough for American use consumes annually 100,000 cords of timber ; and to
                            make our lucifer matches, 300,000 cubic feet of the best pine are required every year. Lasts
                            and boot-trees take 500,000 cords of birch, beech and maple, and the handles of tools
                            500,000 more. The baking of our bricks consumes 24,000,000 cords of wood, or what would
                            cover with forest about 50,000 acres of land. Telegraph poles already up represent 800,000
                            trees, and their annual repairs consume 300,000 more. The ties of our railroads consume
                            annually thirty years' growth of 75,000 acres; and to fence all our railroads would cost
                            $45,000,000, with a yearly expenditure of $15,000,000 for repairs. These are some of the
                            ways in which American forests are going. There are others: our packing boxes, for instance,
                            cost in 1874, $22,000,000; while the timber used each year in making wagons and agricultural
                            implements is valued at more than $100,000,000.</p></div2><pb n="283" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New sticking plaster" TEIform="index"/>A NEW STICKING PLASTER</head><p TEIform="p">The Scientific American tells us, that at a recent session of the Massachusetts State Board
                            of Agriculture, Prof. E. S. Morse gave the following curious particulars about ants: " The
                            ant belongs to a family of insects such as wasps, bees and hornets, but is the superior of
                            them all, as are the elephant, the horse, the dog, etc., in other lines of animal life.
                            Their mouth is for biting and swallowing food only, not for breathing. Their bite is so .
                            determined and lasting that they are used in some countries for confining the edges of
                            wounds and cuts. Ants' heads are presented to the cut surface, which they grasp with their
                            nippers, when their bodies are cut off, leaving a whole row of them to hold the flesh. They
                            are cheaper than sticking plaster in some countries.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature's undertakers" TEIform="index"/>Nature's undertakers
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">NATURE'S UNDERTAKERS. How often do we hear the query, " What becomes of all the
                                    dead birds?" The secret of their mysterious disappearance was but just now half told
                                    by the buzz of those brown wings, and the other half is welcome to any one who will
                                    take the trouble to follow them. The beetle is one of man's incalculable
                                    benefactors. It is his mission to keep fresh and pure the air we breathe. He is the
                                    sexton that takes beneath the mold not only the fallen sparrow, but the mice, the
                                    squirrels, and even much larger creatures that die in our woods and fields. Beneath
                                    that clump of yarrow I found just what I had expected — a small dead bird — and the
                                    grave-diggers were in the midst of their work. Already the rampart of fresh earth
                                    was raised around the body, and the cavity was growing deeper with every moment, as
                                    the busy diggers excavated the turf beneath. Now and then one would emerge on a tour
                                    of inspection, even rummage among the feathers of that silent throat, and climbing
                                    upon the plumy breast to press down the little body into the deepening grave. These
                                    nature-burials are by no means rare, and where the listless eye fails to discover
                                    them the nostril will often indicate the way, and to any one desirous of witnessing
                                    the operation, without the trouble of search, it is only necessary to place in some
                                    convenient spot of loose earth the car cass of some small animal. The most casual
                                    observer could not fail soon to be attracted by the orange-spotted beetles.
                                    Entomologists assert that these insects are attracted by the odor of decay ; but
                                    from my own humble investigations I have never been able to fully reconcile myself
                                    to this theory. If it were the question of odor alone in this dead bird, for
                                    instance, it would be difficult to explain the beeline flight of these humming
                                    beetles, two of which came swiftly toward me even from the direction of the wind,
                                    and dropping quickly upon these feathers hidden from sight among the grass Perhaps
                                    in such an instance we might imagine that they had been there before, and knew the
                                    way ; that they had noted this clump of yarrow, may be; but I have observed theia-ct
                                    before when there was every reason to believe that no such previous visit had been
                                    made.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Harper's monthly" TEIform="index"/>Harper's Monthly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sponges" TEIform="index"/>SPONGES</head><p TEIform="p">Dr. Bowerbank, in his work on British sponges, describes nearly two hundred varieties, and
                            many species have since been discovered. They are found presenting an endless diversity of
                            size and outward configuration—many of them small, others of immense size and of varied
                            colors. Some of the most beautiful specimens secrete a silicious substance which takes very
                            beautiful forms, but is easily broken, and crumbles when dry. One of the prettiest of these
                            is called the Glass sponge, and another is called Venus Flower Basket. Sponges are found to
                            bear the forms of fans, globes, branches of trees, funnels and trumpets. Others are divided
                            into lobes, like great fingers, such as "Neptune's Glove." One variety produces regular
                            sponge monuments, which grow from three inches to six and a half feet on the submarine
                            rocks. They have a narrow stalk, which at a certain height expands and gives the structure
                            the look of an immense drinking goblet. To such a colossal vase the imagination of the
                            sailor could give but one name, that of "Neptune's Cup."</p></div2><pb n="284" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sermon in rhyme" TEIform="index"/>A SERMON IN RHYME</head><p TEIform="p">If you have a friend worth loving, Love him. Yes and let him know That you love him, ere
                            life's evening Tinge his brow with sunset glow. Why should good words ne'er be said Of a
                            friend—till he is dead ? If you hear a song that thrills you, Sung by any child of song,
                            Praise it. Do not let the singer Wait deserved praises long. Why should one who thrills your
                            heart Lack the joy you may impart? If you hear a prayer that moves you, By its humble,
                            pleading tone, Join it. Do not let the seeker Bow before his God alone. Why should not your
                            brother share The strength of " two or three " in prayer ? If you see the hot tears falling
                            From a brother's weeping eyes, Share them. And, by kindly sharing, Own your kinship with the
                            skies. Why should any one be glad When a brother's heart is sad ? If a silvery laugh goes
                            rippling Through the sunshine on his face, Share it. "Pis the wise man's saying — For both
                            grief and joy a place. There's health and goodness in the mirth In which an honest laugh has
                            birth. If your work is made more easy By a friendly, helping hand, Say so. Speak out brave
                            and truly, Ere the darkness veil the land. Should a brother workman dear Falter for a word
                            of cheer ? Scatter thus your seeds of kindness, All enriching as you go — Leave them. Trust
                            the Harvest Giver, His rewards are sure you know.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dangerous" TEIform="index"/>Dangerous</head><p TEIform="p">.—It is dangerous to eat or drink any thing that has remained in the room of a person who is
                            ill with fever or contagious disease ; the germs in the air may have fallen on the food, and
                            any one who eats it may thus take the complaint.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fresh air" TEIform="index"/>Fresh Air</head><p TEIform="p">.—Every person spoils a gallon of air every minute. If you were shut up in a room seven feet
                            long, seven feet broad and seven feet high, the doors and windows fitting so tightly that no
                            fresh air could enter, you would die, poisoned by your own breath, in a few hours.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Old knickerbocker justice" TEIform="index"/>OLD KNICKERBOCKER JUSTICE</head><p TEIform="p">Governor Wouter Van Twiller's mode of administering jnstice in the action of account between
                            Wandle Van Schoonoven and Barent Bleecker: "The two parties being confronted before him,
                            each produced a book of accounts, written in a language and character that wTould have
                            puzzled any but a High-Dutch commentator, or a learned decipherer of Egyptian obelisks. The
                            sage Wouter took them one after the other, and having poised them in his hands, and
                            attentively counted over the leaves, fell straightway into a very great doubt, and smoked
                            for half an hour without saying a word; at length, laying his finger beside his nose, and
                            shutting his eyes for a moment, with the air of a man who has just caught a subtle idea by
                            the tail, he slowly took his pipe from his mouth, puffed forth a column of tobacco-smoke,
                            and with a marvelous gravity and solemnity pronounced, that having carefully counted over
                            the leaves and weighed the books, it was found that one was just as heavy and as thick as
                            the other; therefore it was the final opinion of the court, that the accounts were equally
                            balanced; therefore Wandle should give Barent a receipt, and Barent should give Wandle a
                            receipt, and the constable should pay the costs. This decision being straightway made known,
                            diffused general joy throughout New Amsterdam, for the people immediately perceived that
                            they had a very wise and equitable magistrate to rule over them. But its happiest effect was
                            that not another lawsuit took place throughout the whole of his administration; and the
                            office of constable fell into such decay, that there was not one of those lousel scouts
                            known in the province for many years." — Irving.</p></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fasting" TEIform="index"/>Fasting</head><p TEIform="p">.—" Rigid abstinence," says an eminent English medical writer, " is a most powerful remedy in
                            all acute diseases. In diseases of the stomach, to withdraw food nearly altogether for [a
                            time, would be to employ an actual and powerful remedy."</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pure food" TEIform="index"/>Pure Food</head><p TEIform="p">—Pure food makes pure blood; pure blood makes pure nerves ; pure nerves build up a pure,
                            sound, healthy body.</p></div2><pb n="285" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Snake stories" TEIform="index"/>SNAKE STORIES</head><p TEIform="p">A farmer in Devonshire once told me that he caught a viper, partially disabling it from a
                            blow from a stout stick, and with the assistance of his men bound it, still living, in the
                            fork of a tree. (He was a kind-hearted and fairly intelligent man, who would not have
                            tolerated any ill-treatment of a horse or dog — far less have been guilty of such a thing
                            himself — but he saw no cruelty in thus punishing the poor reptile.) There they left it,
                            striking with its fangs on all sides in its rage and agony. When they returned next day the
                            viper had escaped, but the limb of the tree was dry and dead as though blasted with
                            lightning ! I was young and hopeful at the time I heard this tale and unwise enough to do
                            all in my power to dissuade the narrator from the belief he held, or, at any rate, to try to
                            convince him that he wrongly connected cause and effect in the case, but, as he said, he "
                            see'd it himself," and he went down to the grave in that faith. That he honestly believed it
                            there could be no doubt, for he had not enough poetry in him to invent such a romance. It
                            reminds one of the Yankee who told how he had killed a snake with a hoe, and the handle of
                            which the " varmint" turned and bit several times before receiving its coup de grace. " You
                            mayn't believe it, Squire," said he ; " but, jest as trew as you stand theer, in less than
                            three minutes that hoe handle was swelled up bigger than my leg ! " Have you ever heard of
                            the hoop snake? They abound, according to several accounts I have been favored with, in
                            India and Australia, and derive their name from the peculiarity of their mode of
                            progression, taking their tails in their mouths they bowl along like a hoop! Fact, so an old
                            Indian officer informed me, who had often seen the native soldiers chasing them with short
                            bamboo sticks (he was fearfully circumstantial) around the pounds or along the roads. What
                            an acquisition a couple of these would be to our Zoological Gardens, in an iuclosure of
                            their own, with a Sepoy or two to run round after them with bamboos at stated hours ! The
                            following nice little anecdote was gleaned from an English colonial newspaper, where it was
                            published as an actual occurrence in the immediate neighborhood during the week, with much
                            local and collateral detail. A boa-constrictor woke up hungry from a three months' nap and
                            caught a rabbit, which he bolted whole in the usual way. This did not satisfy the cravings
                            of his capacious stomach, so he went afield in search of further victuals, and presently
                            came to a fence, which he essayed to get through. But the lump caused by the defunct though
                            undigested bunny stopped him when his head and a few feet only of his body had passed
                            between the rails ; and lying in this attitude, he caught and swallowed another rabbit which
                            had incautiously ventured within his narrow sphere of action. Now, what was the state of
                            affairs ? He could neither go ahead nor astern through the fence, being jammed by his fore
                            and aft inside passengers, and in this embarrassing position he was slain with ease. —
                            London Field.</p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wonderful machine" TEIform="index"/>A WONDERFUL MACHINE</head><p TEIform="p">The enormous capacity and lightning-like rapidity of the Hoe printing press for doing work
                            are almost incredible. It turns off in first-class shape 24,000 papers, sometimes 27,000,
                            and has done as high as 30,000, in an hour, or at the marvelous rate of six, seven, and
                            eight papers in one second. These papers too, it must be remembered, are divided by it
                            uniformly and accurately into pages, put in book form, the backs glued, the edges cut, and
                            the last of all are folded in the nicest possible manner, ready for delivery</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Humility is the source of all true greatness..." TEIform="index"/>Humility is the source of all true greatness...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Humility is 1he source of all true great ness; pride is ever impatient, ready to be offended.
                            He who thinks nothing is due to him, never thinks himself ill-treated; true meekness is not
                            mere temperament, for this is only softness or weakness. Some men make you feel as though
                            the warm sun had just broken through the clouds, while others make you feel as if a sudden
                            east wind, with its arms full of cold fog, had caught you with too thin clothing</p></div2><pb n="286" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hygiene of the teeth" TEIform="index"/>HYGIENE OF THE TEETH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Oswald, Felix L." TEIform="persName"/>Felix L. Oswald</byline><p TEIform="p">A hard crust is the best possible dentrifice. I never could get myself to believe in the
                            natural necessity of a tooth-brush. The African nations, the Hindoos, the natives of
                            Southern Europe, the South Sea Islanders, the Arabs, the South American vegetarians— in
                            short, three-fourths of our fellow men, besides our next relatives, the frugiverous animals,
                            have splendid teeth without sozodont. L really believe that ours decay from sheer disuse;
                            the boarding-house home lives chiefly on pap—wants all his meats soft-boiled and growls at
                            cold biscuit or an undone potato ; in other words, he delegates to the cook the proper
                            functions of his teeth. We hear occasionally of old men getting a second, Or rather third
                            set of teeth. I met one of them in Northern Guatemala, and ascertained that he had become
                            toothless during a twelve years' sojourn in a seaport town, and that he got his new set upon
                            his return to his native village, where circumstances obliged him to resume the hard
                            corn-cake diet of his boyhood years. His teeth had reappeared as soon as their services were
                            called for, and would probably never have absented them, selves if a pap diet had not made
                            them superfluous. An artificial dentifrice will certainly keep the teeth white, but that
                            does not prevent any premature decay ; disuse gradually softens their substance, till one
                            fine day the hash-eater snaps his best incisor upon an unexpected piece of bone. Every old
                            dentist knows hundreds of city customers whom the daily use of the tooth-brush did not save
                            from the necessity of applying, before the end of the fortieth year, for a complete
                            "celluloid set." I do not say that a soft tooth-brush and such dentifrices as oatmeal or
                            burned arrow-root can do any harm, but, for sanitary purposes, such precautions must be
                            supplemented by dental exercise. Let a child invigorate its teeth by chewing a hard crust,
                            or better yet, a handful of "St. John's bread," or carob-beans, the edible pod of the Mimosa
                            siliqua. Chil. dren and whole tribes of the northern races seem to feel an instinctive
                            desire to exercise their teeth upon some solid substance, as pet squirrels will gnaw the
                            furniture if you give them nut kernels instead of nuts. Thus Kohl tells us that the natives
                            of Southern Russia are addicted to the practice of chewing a vegetable product, which he at
                            first supposed to be pumpkin or melon seeds, but found to be the much harder seed of the
                            Turkish sun-flower {Helianthus perennis). Their natural diet consists of milk, kukuruz,
                            (hominy, with butter, etc.), and boiled mutton, and they seem to feel that their Turkoman
                            jaws need something more substantial. The schoolboy habit of gnawing penholders,
                            finger-nails, etc., may have a similar significance. The Mimosa siliqua would yield
                            abundantly in our Southern States, and its sweet pods would make an excellent substitute for
                            chewing-gum. Our practice of sipping ice cold and steaming-hot drinks, turn about, has also
                            a very injurious effect upon the brittle substance that forms the euamei of our teeth; no
                            porcelain glass would stand such abuse for any length of time, and experience has taught
                            hunters and dogfanciers that it destroys even the bonecrushing fangs of the animal from
                            which our canine teeth derive their name.—Dr. , in the Popular Science Monthly for
                        November.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No snoring" TEIform="index"/>NO SNORING</head><p TEIform="p">One of the most eccentric clergymen of Scotland of the latter part of the last century was
                            the Rev. Peter Glass, minister of Crail. His pulpit language was broad Scotch, and his
                            expressions, even in devotion, were particularly simple. Many of his parishioners being
                            fishermen, he usually prayed specially for their welfare. One day, using the expression "May
                            the boats be filled wi' herrin' clear up to the tow-holes " (spaces for the oars), a
                            fisherman lustily called out, " Na, na, that far, sir, or wud a' be sunken." A farmer in the
                            parish had been in the habit of sleeping in church, much to Mr. Glass's annoyance. Mr. Glass
                            reproved him privately, and the farmer excused himself on the ground of his arduous labors
                            during the week. He expressed a hope that the minister would extend to him a little
                            indulgence, adding that he would drive two cart</p></div2><pb n="287" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Forgiving love" TEIform="index"/> FORGIVING LOVE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schultz, Maria L." TEIform="persName"/>Maria L. Schultz</byline><p TEIform="p"> Dolce. Canaan, N. Y. There are hearts around us God who sits in judgment Let not all thy
                            feeling O forge thy brother! Oh! in all the moments Human as our own, On the mercy seat,
                            Circle round a few, As forgiven thou ait, Of our silent prayer, Hearts by sorrow broken,
                            Left to walk alone; Sending forth His angels On their missions sweet; Give to all thy
                            blessing, Liberal and true; Pour the oil of healing In the contrite heart; When on Avings
                            of mercy, Poised in holy air, Hearts that love can sof Chideth our repin Like the blessed
                            sun Charity's fair man Angels tarry Avith ten By her tender Avords, ings, But His blessing
                            gives, shine, Like the gentle rain, ¦ tie, Beautifid and white, us, And around us move, In a
                            voice whos To the soul who Falling on the Hides the little We may learn the music meekly
                            millions frailties lessons Is sweet as song of birds. In Christian loATe forgives. So let
                            thy loATe remain. Of erring life from sight. Of SAveet forgiA'ing</p></div2><pb n="288" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curious advertisements" TEIform="index"/>CURIOUS ADVERTISEMENTS</head><p TEIform="p">'' I would like this advertisement translated into French," said an American in Paris,
                            handing to a clerk in the American Register office the following curious advertisement:
                            "Twenty francs reward will be paid for the recovery of a cameo brooch which represents Venus
                            and Adonis lost on the Boulevard des Italiens about 10 o'clock last evening." But the
                            literary pr®ductions of advertisers who have axes to grind, and who pay liberally for the
                            privilege of occupying space, have before now proved very interesting bits of reading in the
                            columns of a well-edited paper. H H. Brown &amp; Co.. of No. 1 Centre street kept
                            standing for several weeks in a leading New York daily : " Soldiers who have lost their
                            discharges, and those who did not receive pension from the date of their discharge or death,
                            please apply." In the "' Wants" department of a country exchange, a resident advertises for
                            "a woman to wash, iron and milk one or two cows." A wine merchant asks for bids for " sixty
                            dozen of prime port, lately the property of a gentleman forty years of age, full in body and
                            of a high bouquet." A livery-stable keeper offers cheap " a mail phaeton, the property of a
                            gentleman with a movable head as good as new,"' and " a splendid gray horse, calculated for
                            a charger, or would carry a lady with a switch tail and warranted kind." It is easier for
                            some people to determine what they want than to ask for it. Words are bugbears to them, and
                            language takes terrible shapes. "To be sold—an Erard piano, the property of a lady about to
                            travel in a walnut case with carved legs," was humorously commented upon by the Saturday
                            Review a few months ago. The Irish World copies an item : " Purse lost by a poor widow woman
                            who has a sick child containing 13s. and a letter." No wonder the child was unwell. The next
                            item in the column is the World's own, and is as follows : " Robert Taylor, aged
                            eighty-three years, is the father of twenty-five children by three wives, seventeen of whom
                            are living." Robert should be tried for bigamy. The Chicago Tribune, not long since, copied
                            the advertisement of a widow who intended to succeed her husband in the management of a
                            hotel: "The hotel will be kept by the widow of the former landlord, Mr. Brown, who died last
                            Summer on a new and improved plan. She will be aided by other stockholders." Such a
                            corporation would not deserve to have a soul. A Coroner's verdict reads thus : " The
                            deceased came to his death by excessive drinking, producing apoplexy in the minds of the
                            jury." A country paper says -"A child was run over by a wagon three years old, and
                            crosseyed, with pantalets on."</p></div2><div2 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The first printed newspaper..." TEIform="index"/>The first printed newspaper...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The first printed newspaper was issued in England in 1622.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Strong language utterly fails to bolster a weak argument" TEIform="index"/>Strong language utterly fails to bolster a weak argument
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Strong language utterly fails to bolster a weak argument.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When you face a difficulty never let it stare you out of countenance" TEIform="index"/>When you face a difficulty never let it stare you out of countenance
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When you face a difficulty never let it stare you out of countenance. "</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Always pay as you go, 'said an old man to his nephew.' But..." TEIform="index"/>Always pay as you go, 'said an old man to his nephew.' But...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Always pay as you go," said an old man to his nephew. " But, uncle, suppose I
                                    have nothing to pay with ? " " Then don't go."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="London times" TEIform="index"/>London Times</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earnestness is the path to immortality..." TEIform="index"/>Earnestness is the path to immortality...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Earnestness is the path to immortality, thoughtlessness the path to death. Those who are in
                            earnest do not die. Those who are thoughtless are as dead already.</p></div2><pb id="p29" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>