<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0805" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18780501" TEIform="date">May 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">103-126</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--               <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. VIII. NO. 5. MAY 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED
                        SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT "WATERVLIET, W. Y. "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD." 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINT-ED AT SHAKER
                        VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. MANIFESTO. <pb id="p2"/> Separation from the World 103 Echoes from the Voice
                        of Peace 113 Substance better than Shadows 104 Correspondence in Christian Culture No. 11 105 Shaker Courtesy 115
                        The Future 106 Is the Shaker System best 11(5 Mind vs Matter 109 Editorial Notes 117 Moral Reform 109 Book Table 118
                        Set the house in Order 110 Obitua ry 119 People of the other World 110 For the Children 120 Thoughts 110 Mind and
                        Man 121 Shaker Manifesto 111 Home Topics 122 Fear of the Lord 111 Farm & Garden 123 An Address to Leaders
                        112 Music 124 TERMS OF ADVERTISING. For one inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column, " $ 3. 00 one " " " $ 6.
                        00 page, " " $12.00 Continued insertion for three months, 20 per ct. discount. " six " 25 " " " one year, 33 1/3 " "
                        Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription will begin
                        when order is received.—No back numbers. CONTENTS.</p>*/
                    --><pb n="103" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER MAIIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL. VIII.— MAY.
                        1878.—No. V.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Separation from the world" TEIform="index"/>SEPARATION FROM THE WORLD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName">ELIJAH MYRICK</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> This separation is not a recluse life 01 pious devotion to sect or creed, labelec "holier
                            than thou ;" it is not the fruits of divine life laid away in a napkin white though it be.
                            Nor is it in the cut and color of apparel, nor the nay and yea of speech. Neither is it
                            exclusiveness from our fellow beings. Jesus breaking away from the exclusiveness of the
                            Essenes, rose on the tidal wave of John's mission of baptism and repentance, and became an
                            active exponent of their faith, their commu- nism, celibacy, peace, healing power, and
                            spiritual gifts : declaring that he came "to bring fire on the earth"—a separation from the
                            world—a consuming of the worldly elements. (Luke, 12, 53.) "A new commandment I give unto
                            you, that ye love one-another"—differing from the old, that "they twain should be one
                            flesh." The new the divine, the old the earthly, for "the children ol this world." As with
                            the heavenly kingdom ; so with the kingdom of this world; it is within. Would we come out of
                            the world we must get the world out of ourselves. "The lust of the flesh the lust of the eye
                            and the pride of life," declared to be "of the world," find their counterpart in the second,
                            Christ advent. "Put away your selfishness your lust and your fllthiness and be prepared for
                            the gospel increase." "They spare no idol great nor small, But pass one sentence on them
                            all." The second advent of Christ is a renewal of the war upon the world ; and for this
                            purpose "came not to bring peace but a sword"— "the sword which proceedeth out of the
                            mouth"—the testimony of truth ; the sundering of worldly ties, centering all the life, love,
                            and affection on a new relation, paying all just debts, restoring what has been unjustly
                            taken, confessing and forsaking all sin, and living a pure virgin life, keeping unspotted
                            from the world. Is not this the Christ? It is a self-imposed fraud to assume a show of
                            outward conformity and let the world usurp the control of the heart's affections,
                            substituting semi-lusts, fancy affections, and perverted loves, as a compromise between the
                            natural, and the divine. Mother Ann Lee said, ' "this is no lalf-way work; we do not daub
                            with <pb n="104" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> XO4 THE SHAKER M-AJSTEEPESTO. untempered mortar," "God requires
                            the whole soul in his service." She was a rue prophetess ; her testimony grew out of her
                            life. False prophets there are, having unclean spirits like frogs (amphibious) who say it is
                            possible to live in both elements, the flesh and the spirit. Rightly named, "spirits of
                            devils," heed them not. Rather heed, and pattern those who have borne the world's odium for
                            Christ's sake ; whose very presence is a testimony that the baptism of fire has consumed the
                            world within. Let us make our record like theirs ; while reproving the world of sin, win the
                            sin-sick soul by love to repentance, and obedience to divine laws ; causing the earth to be
                            a paradise of joyfulness. May the practice of every Christian precept, evince our separation
                            from the world. Harvard, Mass. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Substance better than shadows" TEIform="index"/>Substance Better Than Shadows</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName">ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The dispensation of types and shadows, is now superseded by the real. In the ages past,
                            seers,—through faith-—pierced the clouds and shadows, and with prophetic lens saw the Christ
                            of the coming years who would reveal the substance of things which they awaited and hoped
                            for, but did not realize until they had passed the boundaries of the earth sphere. The law
                            given through Moses to the ancient Jews, that required sacrifices of beasts and birds, for
                            the expiation of sins, was symbolical of the final crucifixion of the animal nature of man
                            and woman, when in the fullness of times an offering should be made of the sensual life
                            "once for all" upon the altar of truth which God would erect; whereon sin offerings would be
                            laid, and an effectual cleansing of the transgressor be made by confession and repentance :
                            and the injunction be, "Go and sin no more." Neither the blood of animals, the hyssop branch
                            nor running stream could effect the cleansing of souls in that day ; but a recurrence of
                            those sins for which oblation had been made, showed the weakness of the law, and marked the
                            course of its subjects; but it was a pledge given to be redeemed by something better in the
                            coming future. The law, with its ceremonial appendages was not given as a redeemer, only
                            designed to guide, guard and protect. It was the best that the people of that day were
                            prepared to receive. Minis- ters who stood in the ancient Jewish temples, though clad in
                            sacerdotal robes, could not administer saving power ; they did not possess it. By the varied
                            offerings presented to the Priests, the people stood confessed for thereby the nature of the
                            transgression was marked and understood which, in a degree, brought humiliation of spirit,
                            and a restraining influence upon those passions which the law pointed out as unclean. Had
                            the people of that day kept the law of their God in regard to procreation—been orderly and
                            timely in the work of reproduction—those restraints and constraints, would have been need-
                            less ; for the principle of right use would have prevailed, and seed time would have been
                            blest, and a normal growth of the race from the natural towards the spiritual been produced.
                            Then the harvesting anaels could have done their <pb n="105" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> work of reaping and
                            gathering souls, u to a higher plane of spiritual life, anc holier loves, without inharmony
                            or jar ring of the general plan. But the Jewish law was disregarded broken—by pi-ophets,
                            priests and people Priests fattened upon the offerings mac by the people, and transgression
                            wa not rebuked by them ; idolatrous deec were tolerated, while they (the priests) surfeited
                            upon the fat of beasts and birds. Hence the prophet Hosea said, "The Lord condemned and
                            rejected them as unworthy the priesthood, seeing they had forgotten the law of their God,
                            and eaten up the sin of his people, and set their hearts on iniquity." Thus the an- imal
                            passional nature gained the ascendency even in the Order of the priesthood—the highest and
                            holiest sanctuary of that dispensation. Henceforth may it be truthfully said that there is a
                            sanctuary—a holy temple established on the earth where God dwells,—where conscience
                            rules,—and the law of Purity which produces peace and love remains unsullied and unbroken.
                            Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 11" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN CULTURE. No. 11</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName">WM. H. BUSSELL</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">The Consummation : The ultimate of all Christian culture must he perfection of character
                            socially, intellectually and morally, as well as perfect happiness. Longfellow, it is true,
                            in his Psalm of Life, declares— "Not enjoyment, and not sorrow Is our destined end or way."
                            He doubtless has reference only to the present life, during which we are "To act that each
                            to-morrow Finds us farther than to-day." Pope expresses the universal desire— "O, happinessJ
                            our being's end and aim." Happiness is the attendant of sound physical health; of the
                            acquisition of every kind of useful knowledge, when the mind has become sufficiently
                            developed to appreciate it rightly; of virtuous associations and the performance of all
                            beneficent acts ; of every effort made to become wiser and better ourselves and to make
                            others so. But all along through the present life the ingredients in its cup are of a mixed
                            nature-—bitter and sweet. Yet the aspirations for perfect happiness never cease, and the
                            assurance of finally reaching the goal of perfection becomes stronger and stronger with
                            every onward step. These aspirations continuing even to the latest period of the earthly
                            life are evidences of a life beyond the present in which they shall have their complete
                            realization. Those who have made the greatest advancements in culture of every kind while
                            upon the earth feel the most strongly the need of further opportunities for growth. Not that
                            they are dissatisfied with what they have acquired, but that, compared with the immense
                            treasures yet lying before their view, what they have gained seems but the mere alphabet of
                            truth. These treasures they are eager to make their own, but their present opportunities and
                            facilities are altogether inadequate to that end. Divine love may have commenced its growth
                            within them, developing the social powers, but how few the means and brief the time upon
                            earth for their gratification! Eternity is needed for that purpose, for eternity alone can
                            satisfy the wants that exist in the intellectually and socially developed being. This is the
                            end of all Christian culture, the grand truth of the Christian doctrine. The self-denial it
                            requires is for the purpose of fitting its subjects for the perpetual enjoyment of a life
                            that cannot be gained without it. The humility it teaches is of a character that makes each
                            disciple the equal associate of every other, without which true friendship cannot be
                            perpetuated, and with which it may be made eternal. Christian self-denial and humility are
                            compatible with the highest social ife. They are a preparatory step to it, and when that is
                            fully gained, the resurrection to ternal life or the life of Divine Love is comleted. The
                            drift of all these remarks upon chrisMANIFESTO. <pb n="106" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> ioo THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. tian culture is to the effect that the heaven of the Christian, though,
                            externally, containing the most beautiful things of which the thoroughly developed mind can
                            conceive, yet is by no means limited to these. Its essential nature is the perfection of all
                            the iowers of the soul, so that they shall be in conplete harmony with each other, and so
                            that each individual person who possesses it shall be in perfect accord with every other.
                            This agrees with the words of Jesus—"the kingdom of heaven is within you;" and with those of
                            Paul—"the kingdom of God is righteousness, peace and joy in the Holy Spirit." The tendency
                            of these remarks is also, that this heaven in its perfection is gained only after passing
                            through a course of discipline and development in which there is constant growth from the
                            lowest conditions of life to the very highest. It is "to those who by patient continuance in
                            well doing seek for glory, honor, and im- mortality that God will render eternal life."
                            Every disciple of Jesus not only "learns of him," but is also a subject of the same
                            discipline to which he submitted. He has from the first the kingdom of heaven within him in
                            its various stages of manifestation and development, and no one can come into possession of
                            the perfect heaven without passing through these several stages. The idea, then, of passing
                            from earth whether an infant or a person of mature years, and entering immediately into a
                            perfect heaven without having passed through the preliminary discipline necessary to make
                            the perfect Christian is one of the greatest absurdities ever promulgated. If a regular
                            course of discipline is necessary for one, it is necessary for all; and if any have not had
                            an opportunity for this upon the earth, the simplest dictates of reason teach that they must
                            and will have that opportunity after departure from the earth. Groveland, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Future" TEIform="index"/>THE FUTURE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">ELDER F. W. EVANS</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">From correspondence of E. J. Meigs, of Washington, D. C. with the Shakers at Canterbury, N.
                            H. we make quotations. After a visit to Canterbury, he writes : "I saw that a Community may
                            be so constituted as to absolutely secure material well being to every one of its members.
                            In the social organization called the State, how few of its constituents, in comparison to
                            the mass, enjoy the blessings of adequate food, raiment and shelter! In Washington, fast
                            becoming the most pleasant city on the continent, a large majority of its people suffer the
                            keenest misery from unavoidable cold and hunger, while no Shaker is destitute of fuel, food
                            or clothing. In the State, the life, liberty and property of its members are secured by
                            enormous perpetual exertion and expenditure of never ending contributions that leave the
                            mass in utter destitution, victims of ignorance and disease, with no refuge but death."
                            Here, the practical results of the two systems are contrasted. The "Shaker system" presents
                            some sixty companies of human beings, located in different states, in possession of present
                            and prospective necessary comforts of life for all. The State, not only fails to do this,
                            but allows the minority to accumulate and hold property so far beyond their normal wants,
                            that vices, detrimental to all classes, are engendered by its possession. Does not this
                            condition of things evince ignorance, on the part of the non-possessors, and wickedness on
                            the part of all who assent and submit to the operation of such principles? The Slave, who
                            assents to the principle of slavery, is as wicked as the slave-holder. And the man, who
                            votes—consents— to appoint to Office, men, to the exclusion of women, or the rich and the
                            learned, to the exclusion of men fit to sit on a jury, is an unconverted man, unconverted to
                            the eternal law of right, truth and virtue—he is not an American—does not understand the
                            principles underlying the Declaration of American Freedom. Let true Americans blow the
                            Jubilee trumpet, asserting Human Rights, irrespective of existing vested rights, declare the
                            Law of God, of Nature, of Humanity, that each Child, legally begotten, has a right to be
                            born, that each child, legally born, has a right to life, and all which that right implies.
                            Declare, in tones of thunder, and embody it <pb n="107" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE .SHAKBE in Law, that
                            no man and woman shall bring into existence another human being, to be a constituent member
                            of the State, without consent of the State by duly appointed Committee composed of select
                            men and women of the town where they reside, under the pen" alty of extinction, in the
                            parents, of the pow" er to repeat the offence, and in the offspring' if allowed to survive,
                            of the procreative power. Present forms of death penalty might then be abolished, the
                            reproduction of criminals, by criminals, being rendered impossible. The American Revolution
                            caused changes of property relations between England and America. Why may there not be other
                            changes? "Vote yourself a farm," was the cry, forty years ago, of a few unselfish men. The
                            property holders were terribly alarmed, but the result was, Freedom of public lands,
                            Homesteads, and the Abolition of Slavery. If the people can vote themselves homes, they can
                            vote homes for all the tramps and poor in the land. Who shall limit the Sovereign People in
                            their power to do good? Let Right and Power coalesce and Vox PopvM be Vox Dei' Voters can
                            depopulate the Cities, spread the people over the broad acres in the country, dissolve
                            Poorhouses, State Prisons and all penal institutions. Have Quakers need of these inventions
                            of ungodly men? Do they have, or patronize, Army or Navy, take oaths, pay tithes, preach or
                            sing for hire? They have no tramps, no paupers. With them, marriage and children are not
                            haphazard affairs, but subjects of legislation by duly appointed committees of male and
                            female wisdom. No criminals, for they have no poor. No poor, for children are not begotten
                            unintentionally, nor without permission. They are birthright members. Nor has this been done
                            in a corner. Prove all things, hold fast the good—adopt the true of all peoples, and
                            denominations, Christians, Mahometans, Jews, Pagans, Infidels, even if it lead to the
                            endorsement of their true principles. Orthodoxy begins with belief, dogma—I quote from
                            Agent's Journal. "There is, in the whole dark catalogue of crime, sin and disobedience, but
                            one that God will not, in a twinkling, forever forgive and forget, to wit—rejecting
                            salvation through Christ." What is this terrible crime, rejecting Christ, or rather Jesus? I
                            confess I do not know. "Willfully rejecting Christ is the most criminally guilty act that
                            ever stained and blemished a human soul." "Not for a perverse life, mingled with darkening
                            crimes and deeds of infamy, is it, that the soul is to be subjected to eternal death," but
                            because it does not believe some abstract tenet, that makes a fool, for superstition's sake,
                            of the person believing it? Is not this simply horrible? Does not this irrational theology
                            underlie the putrefaction of our state morals? Let us begin with fruits, rejecting all
                            theologies that do not make men and women cease inflicting hunger, cold, nakedness and war,
                            creating Doctor-craft, Lawyer-craft, Priestcraft, rich, and poor landless human beings. For
                            the present distress, put Quaker Men into the House, and Quaker Women into the Senate, until
                            a class of intellectual celibates come up, who rise above propagation altogether, to relieve
                            the husbands and wives, that they may go home and attend to raising the best types of
                            humanity they are capable of propagating. "Land is absolutely the heritage of the human
                            race—the gift of Clod to man. The State is, at present, so constituted as to be incapable of
                            preventing its monopoly by the few, whose exclusive right it is even pledged to maintain.
                            "Is this state of things to be perpetuated? God forbid",—and Let Man forbid. "The race is
                            waiting for deliverance. Where is it to come from? By community of property?" Not at all,
                            but by two Orders, a Spiritual, having Community of goods, and a Natural, having a system of
                            Co-operation, under which the land is held for the lives of the people, and the products of
                            labor as the property of all, so far as life and life necessaries are involved. When the
                            Natural Order settles it, that each member of the State must live comfortably, it will be
                            settled that the State shall settle who and how many shall become members of the State. The
                            Spiritual Order does now determine who and how many shall become members of Communities.
                            These primaries being admitted, the combined wisM .AJSrrF'ICSTO. 1O71 <pb n="108" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>
                            1O8 THE SHAKBE dom of man and woman, under God and Nature, will soon devise laws, rules and
                            regulations to render such primaries practical. The Truth being born, its father and mother
                            will soon learn how to care for it. Mbigs' Correspondence Concluded. "May not men and women
                            marry and hope, in that state, to enjoy the profound prosperity and tranquility of Shaker
                            Villages? If not, why not?" This is the point at issue between Shakers and generating
                            communities. I answer, Nay. Except a man forsake all he hath as a generative man, he cannot
                            become a true Community member. When a man and woman becomes husband and wife, they found a
                            little State—the State in its germinal form. It is all the world to them, and all the world
                            they want. Having raised children, acquired property and gone the length of their chain,
                            they seek association. They may co-operate with other propagating families, for protection,
                            for working land by machinery, build and operate factories, organize Government, by becoming
                            members of it, subject to its laws— may thus enjoy, in their order, the necessaries and
                            comforts of life. In concluding his first letter, Friend Meigs says, Elder Evans, in
                            Manifesto No. 1. says :—"I want to see the redemption of the stomach, the redemption of the
                            land and the redemption of the creative forces of men and women." He continues—"On the first
                            of these points, he has shown us the way, but the other two redemptions are waiting to be
                            dealt with. I am not without hope we shall hear from him, in an early No. of your beautiful
                            little Magazine, how the land is to be redeemed from the curses of mal-appropriatio.n, and
                            how deftly he will put the creative forces on their best behavior, for I do verily believe
                            he is not far from the Kingdom of God. "It is also suggested by Elder F. W. E., in his
                            "Shaker System," that inalienable homesteads maybe reasonably hoped for and would make a
                            vantage ground fruitful of other ameliorations—I have received the Randolph Lecture, "Pure
                            vs. adulterated Christianity," and "Oriental Spiritualism" tracts. The advice of Mother Ann,
                            to give little heed to familiar spirits, who, while really of the world, stand behind a
                            screen and delight in much speaking, etc. is, to my understanding, practically valuable and
                            well put. "The whole is exceedingly curious, and I would fain know whether you all trust
                            those things implicitly." We do not "trust those things implicitly." Neither the Bible, nor
                            Spiritualism is, to us, authority for truth We must see it for ourselves. If the Almighty
                            comes to us as a teacher, He, above all others, should be plain to our understanding,
                            consistent with our reason. Will not the Judge of all the earth do right—act rationally?
                            Land Redemption. I suggest that Land limitation be one of the first steps. Fix a limit to
                            the quantity of land one person may hereafter own. Death will do the rest, and no
                            disturbance will ensue. When a landlord dies, compel the heirs to divide and sell all beyond
                            the legal limit. All parties will be satisfied, because all will be benefited. Death and
                            time would abolish land monopoly, as they abolished Slavery in the State of New York, half a
                            century ago. Marriage should be restricted to the production of offspring. No unfruitful
                            works of darkness. And the whole matter be subjected to law as above stated. Inalienable
                            homesteads and the abolition of all laws for the collection of debts can, at once, become
                            accomplished facts. "Elder Evans' outgivings are I think, entitled to deliberate
                            consideration. "Under a natural law of evolution," he says, "hitherto overlooked,
                            disregarded or ruinously vio- lated, when a people have progressed beyond a patriarchal
                            family relation, they should develop a class of intellectual celibates, who do not marry
                            individually, but who marry the State. "I understand him to mean this class of intellectual
                            celibates.should shoulder the cares of State, to the exclusion of Congress, President,
                            Courts and all that paraphernalia, leaving the other class of husbands and wives, to the
                            care of their families, they not assuming to care for, or rule the national family. But how
                            is this class to be assembled? By whom are the cares of state to be devolved upon them? Not,
                            I suppose by the husbands and wives ; they are to have no voice in the election of their
                            rulers, or share in celebratingthe nuptials between those celibates and the M^JsrrexE sto .
                                <pb n="109" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 1O9 State. How is this to be explained to
                            American educated people, who from Magna Charta down to the last constitution in the Union,
                            have had voice, if not a vote?" Friend Meigs has not quite caught my meaning. Leaving the
                            governmental machinery as it is, I would have the whole population, male and female, vote
                            Quaker men into the House and Quaker women into the Senate, to occupy until supplanted by
                            celibate rulers exclusively devoted to intellectual and moral pursuits. Redemption of the
                            stomach would prevent the generation of Pagan plagues and Christ- ian diseases. Supervision
                            of procreation, forestall the inherited ills that flesh is heir to. And property redemption,
                            would save from property evils and the causes of war. The present checks upon population,
                            perverted generation, pestilence and war, being gone, population would rapidly increase ;
                            but wisdom, holding the helm of state, fostering celibacy as a virtue—the highest form of
                            evolution—the celibate rulers would limit the population to the quantity of land and the re-
                            sources of food in the national kitchen. A Seer, a Reformer, may announce an abstract
                            principle, and predict the result when carried out; as does John the Revelator, who
                            proclaimed the passing away of the "former earth and heavens," and the substitution of a new
                            earth in which right ruled; and a new heaven, so spiritually true, that there was in it
                            neither pain, sorrow, nor sighing, and all tears were wiped away by the hand of love. Yet,
                            neither John nor any spirit can give the minutiae of means to effect results. The workers
                            only can do this, and they, not by a cut and dried formula, but by the living spirit erf
                            wisdom, like the soul in the body. By the Spirit, will the temple of God of humanity be
                            built. We hope for a national religious revival—rational and scientific—creating individual
                            characters, fitting each person for ei- ther the new earthly, or the new heavenly Order. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A humorous apothecary in Boston exposes a case of soap in his show window... " TEIform="index"/>A humorous apothecary in Boston exposes a case of soap in his show window...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A humorous apothecary in Boston exposes a case of soap in his show window with the pertinent
                            inscription, "Cheaper than dirt."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mind vs. matter" TEIform="index"/>MIND vs. MATTER</head><p TEIform="p">Matter is composed of earth; Mind of God's eternal breath. Matter yields to form and word;
                            Mind alone, can worship God. Mind is master of the man. Matter, servant of his plan. Mind
                            retains its vigor long, Matter fails e'er mind is strong. Mind can scale the Universe ;
                            Matter, law confines, to earth. Mind retains its vernal bloom When matter lieth in the tomb.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moral Reform" TEIform="index"/>MORAL REFORM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">JAMES S. PRESCOTT</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">There is a work of moral reform going on in Cleveland, O. which appears to be in the right
                            direction. The "Temperance Movement" is beginning to assume gigantic proportions. One man by
                            the name of Doan has built a Tabernacle at his own expense which cost $9000.00, capable of
                            seating 5,400 people, in stationary chairs, besides a room adjoining, where prayer meetings
                            are held every day at noon, one hour, and in the even- ing before the general Lecture. This
                            Tabernacle was built expressly for the '•'"Temperance Movement," and was dedicated on
                            Thanksgiving Day, by calling in fifteen hundreds of the poor of the city—outcasts, reformed
                            inebriates, who had signed the pledge, and all the repenting prodigals they could find who
                            wish to reform, and live higher, nobler, and better lives. It was for this class that a
                            feast was prepared; the fatted calf was killed; the tables were spread, and loaded with all
                            kinds of good things, and these were the guests invited to come in and partake of the feast!
                                <pb n="110" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER One of the Leaders in this revival is a Lawyer, by the
                            name of Wm. E. Preston ^ an infidel to the orthodox faith, is doing more in my opinion to
                            help this class than any clergyman in the cityhe throws open his parlor doors, and invites
                            in the poor, not the rich, to partake with him at his own table—he goes from the court room
                            from pleading a civil case, to the prayer meeting, and there pleads the case of the
                            prodigal, with all the eloquence and pathos of an apostle. Another Leader by the name of
                            Camp, is fully his equal. North Union., 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Set the house in order" TEIform="index"/>SET THE HOUSE IN ORDER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName">MARIA WHEELER</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> With the opening of the present year I felt earnestly invited by a higher aspiration to "set
                            my house in order," by burying ill-feelings, and cultivating more largely love and
                            good-will. As I regard truthful, the beautiful sentiment of the Poet who wrote that "Every
                            inmost aspiration is God's Angel%undefiled;" so I accept this invitation as coming from the
                            heaven of heavens. I believe it is a beautiful condition to have the "house set in order" to
                            live on earth, as beyond the earth, I am earnestly engaged in this work. What helps we all
                            may have from the good words and works of those who have long secured to themselves a
                            welcome in that "home not made with hands, eternal in the heavens;" and also what mutual aid
                            and encouragement among dear companions likewise engaged! When we are prepared to receive
                            heaven's blessings how often will the golden gates be left ajar, and sweet and holy
                            inspirations flow into our souls from sacred fountains of strength and consolation beyond
                            our human comprehension. And I would not exchange the balmy fragrant breath of inspiration
                            for all the cold philosophy the world has ever known. And I would share with kind readers,
                            this little germ of truth, which has been wafted to me this calm Sabbath morning. One grain
                            of ill-will entertained within our hearts toward any human being, if it be not larger than a
                            mustard seed, will bar our entrance to the heavenly fields of peace and lasting happiness.
                            Union Village, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="People of the other world" TEIform="index"/>PEOPLE OF THE OTHER WORLD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName">CHAUNCY DIBBLE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">We are pleased to know that some of our esteemed friends are interested in regard to the
                            conditions of spirits who have departed out of the body froix these shores, since time has
                            rolled, up to the present. We are .all being swiftly transported into their society ;
                            therefore, tell us ye men of deep research into spiritual philosophy, are those of the other
                            sphere still rational, free agents? Do they live in each other's society ? Is there
                            government, law and protection ? Are there associations and enterprises? Does justice
                            prevail? Is innocence a shield? Is there progress in virtue? growth in wisdom? expansion of
                            faculties? Does each individual wear the impress of their former life and acts, whether
                            virtuous or vicious, innocent or guilty? Is reformation possible for those who have deeply
                            degraded themselves in this earth life? Will those who have tyrannized over, and oppressed
                            others, and by their influence willfully caused them to stumble from the path of innocence
                            and rectitude in this life, there feel the just recompense of their guilt? Reasoning from
                            what we know of God's progressive laws, is there not a no , M^ISTXET'ESTO <pb n="111" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEJR Ill superior condition of perfection and happiness attainable
                            there ? These are questions that invite reflective answers. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts, upon my 24th birthday" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS, Upon my 24th birthday</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah F." TEIform="persName">ELVAH F. COLLINS</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">0 flowing years! Where are your many dreams ? Aback I turn to find they all have flown; The
                            thoughts, the deeds, the imagery of life, Have chased each other into the unknown. No more
                            can I possess the infant mind— That formed each day its happy round of life— That laughed
                            away the sorrows and the cares Which ever brood o'er the increasing strife. Unconscious of a
                            mother's anxious heart— To keep the little hands from dangers near, And little feet from
                            straying into wrong, With prayers that they in future rightly steer. Gone! gone those sunny
                            days of childish bliss; Pursued by the increscent years of time, That turned my heart from
                            childhood's playful hours, To thoughts of what should blossom on my prime. Tori have heard
                            the sweet-voiced angels' call To come away from shadow and from shade; To sow, and reap a
                            life of purity, And dwell mid flowers that time can never fade. Here let my soul be met, by
                            weal or woe, Joy, or affliction, as I greet the years, No grief nor sorrow I could ever
                            know, But would be joy to sin's embittered tears. Each day its lesson brings; and so I learn
                            More wisely on the morrow to pursue, The threaded winding paths of life below, Therein to
                            spurn the false, and bless the true. O! angel mother, place upon my head, The hand of
                            blessing for my future course; And with thy finger write upon my heart Those principles of
                            glowing vital force. And I will read with faith's unfailing eye, And walk with willing feet
                            the path to thee; For thro' thy blessing and thy life of prayer A.re Zion's sin-forsaking
                            children free. And here I sit today; not like the throng Of suffering sisters, steeped in
                            bitter tears O'er steps unwisely taken, mid the thorns That seem to thicken with the coming
                            years— Not like the thousands bowed in servitude— To lustful fires that burn the human heart
                            Of him who shows no mercy to his prey— Who longs each day for life to soon depart; Or
                            backward turns to days of innocence, And yearns to live those hours o'er again, Because the
                            castles ot her youthful mind Have crumbled into dust of shame and pain. I have no need to
                            summon up the years, That silently have left me, one by one, Nor does my heart shrink back
                            with shuddering fears From the great future I have but begun. The morning light of fadeless
                            golden hue, Has streamed across the everlasting hills; And Zion's city flooded with its
                            beams My heart with peace and holy gladness fills. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto, our standard bearer" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKER MANIFESTO, OUR STANDARD
                            BEARER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles. B." TEIform="persName">G. B. AVERY</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">1. The making of "all things new, and all things of God." 2. The inauguration of the Kingdom
                            of Heaven upon Earth. 3. The Manifestation of God—a heavenlyFather and Mother. 4. The
                            Manifestation of Christ's Second Appearing in the female. 5. The co-equality of man and
                            woman in Christ's Kingdom. 6. Christian Salvation, positive—from sin; not negative—merely
                            from the consequences of sin. 7. The dissolution of creedal bondage; Institution of the
                            Christ life as criterion of religious duty. 8. Continuous revelation of light, truth,
                            wisdom, power, will and love of God, the fountain of eternal soul-life. 9. Communism,
                            proper, the fruit of Virgin Celibacy, a heavenly, not a worldly institu- tion.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fear of the Lord" TEIform="index"/>THE FEAR OF THE LORD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName">DANIEL ORCUTT</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">"Come, ye children, hearken unto me; I will teach you the fear of the Lord." Children, this
                            call is to you. It is the language of maternal solicitude and love. It is what every wise
                            parent, guardian or teacher, would say to you. "Hearken unto me;" that is, hearken to the
                            voice of Wisdom. Children are apt to <pb n="112" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 113 THE SHAEER MANIFESTO.
                            hearken to the voice of mere pleasure, or passion ; their minds are unstable ; they dislike
                            restraint, and often hearken to those who advise them to do evil. But Wisdom says, "hearken
                            unto—me." Perhaps you may ask, why should we hearken to Wisdom? Because She will teach you
                            righteousness,—-the fear of the Lord. Be assured, that the true fear of the Lord, is not to
                            be understood in the sense of slavish dread, nor terror. Bad people have not the true fear
                            of the Lord, while the good, possess it. The worst consequences are attributed to the
                            absence of it, while everything that is good, is ascribed to its existence in the soul. The
                            true fear of God, is perfectly consistent with true love ; we can cherish this fear, and yet
                            love God, as did Jesus and the Apostles. "By the fear of the Lord, men depart from evil.''
                            Solomon says, "The fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom." It is the highest kind of
                            wisdom, Job's language agrees precisely with this : ' 'Behold, the fear of the Lord, that is
                            wisdom ; and to depart from evil, is understanding." "The fear of the Lord is to hate evil;"
                            to reverence God's character, and love His law; and those who do this, will have great
                            spiritual prosperity. The season of youth is the best time for learning the fear of the
                            Lord. We have not room to quote all that the Bible says on this subject; it is summed up in
                            the following words. '' Though a sinner do evil a ' hundred times, and his days be
                            prolonged, (were such a case to happen,) yet surely I know that it shall be well with them
                            that fear God ; but it shall not be well with the wicked, neither shall he prolong his days,
                            which are as a shadow, because he feareth not God." We hope our young readers will meditate
                            deeply on this subject, and let its principles be engraven on their youthful hearts.
                            Enfield, Ct. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address to leaders, copied from a community record" TEIform="index"/>Address to leaders, copied from a community record
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">AN ADDRESS TO LEADERS COPIED FROM A COMMUNITY RECORD. We find that office is a
                                    very dangerous place ; persons are so liable to grow arbitrary and oppressive,
                                    jealous of opposition, disturbed if folks say a word against their proceedings,
                                    irritated by parties who watch for their infirmities and defects. I warn you not to
                                    think of yourselves as officers in the usual sense. Christ said his officers should
                                    be ministers and servants. That is the only true conception of your function. If you
                                    have any other conception than that, you will be a center of attraction for devils.
                                    Christ said to his disciples, "Ye know that they which are accounted to rule over
                                    the Gentiles exercise lordship over them, and their great ones exercise authority
                                    upon them. But so shall it not be among you; but whosoever will be great among you
                                    shall be your minister, and whosoever of you will be the chiefest shall be servant
                                    of all." That was the principle on which our early leaders started, and we must keep
                                    it bright. It must be understood that we have no officers in the usual sense. It
                                    must be understood that a true officer is the first to set an example of humility
                                    and service—the first to submit to criticism—the first to want to know his faults
                                    that he may be cured of them. There is a spiritualistic truth of very great
                                    importance concerned in this mat<pb n="113" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 113 ter, at which
                                    I have already hinted, and that is, that a leading position has a peculiar power for
                                    attracting evil spirits. There is the danger. Even the lowest in office, if they are
                                    not wide-awake, will find bad spirits stealing into them which will make them
                                    arbitrary and jealous of any interference with their proceedings. The spirit of
                                    diotrephiasis, the spirit which we call officiality, the spirit of lordship and
                                    arbitrary power, the spirit of embezzlement, self-seeking and selfindulgence, and
                                    many other bad spirits, gather to office as flies to a honey-pot; and you must be
                                    aware of the danger. The moral question, What is right and wrong? is even less
                                    important than the spiritual question, What will attract good or evil spirits ?
                                    Overcome evil with good. That is the motto for leaders. Perhaps persons are watching
                                    you with an evil eye, ready to find fault with your official management ; if you are
                                    conscious of doing right never mind ; wait and watch, and trust God to justify you.
                                    He will do it. Trust him tq take care of your reputation, and don't quarrel with
                                    folks about it. Set it before you as your ambition to govern by grace and not by
                                    law, and study Paul to find out how to do it. Renounce all compulsion, all governing
                                    by crushing people. Keep yourselves child-like and simple, loving and merciful. If
                                    you do that, you will be just the officers the heavens want, and they will take care
                                    of you and save you from evil spirits on the one hand, and evileyed criticism on the
                                    other.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American socialist" TEIform="index"/>Am. Socialist</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A bell rung under the water..." TEIform="index"/>A bell rung under the water...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A bell rung under the water returns a tone as distinctly as if rung in the air.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Echoes from the voice of peace" TEIform="index"/>ECHOES FROM THE VOICE OF PEACE</head><p TEIform="p"> E. M. Coats said, at a Convention in Dutchess Co., N. Y. that there are in the United States
                            Treasury $500,000, the accumulated interest and principal of pension money uncalled for, by
                            such as became members of the Shaker Community. There are said to be in the United States
                            60.000 Ministers claiming to preach the Gospel. I beg you friends, to hold these to a
                            literal fulfillment of their profession. I used to dread to- call myself a Christian the
                            term seemed so synonymous with persecution and war. Z. C. Whipple. The Beneficent Father
                            never made war ; man was its author. War is a monstrosity and the wonder is that Christians
                            ever studied it, legalized it, paid for it, gloried in it. A. H. Love. Advertisement of a
                            Military Academy in its true meaning : Send here your sons to have the pure spirit of truth
                            trained out of them, and a demon of military cunning and deceit, called strategy, put in its
                            place. We will teach them that Christ's precepts are nonsense and cowardice. A. M. PoweL
                            Effects of our Civil War. A debt of $3,000,000,000 ! Millions of paupers ! ! 500.000 widows
                            and three times that number of orphans ! ! ! B. A. Lockwood. Some still open their eyes in
                            wonderr when a minister of Jesus ignores war! We rejoice to know that the question of
                            arbitration is claiming the attention of the best minds of the world. H. T. Child. Let us
                            march up from the plane of M^NTIIPEISTO. <pb n="114" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER brute force. Give
                            universal suffrage, before the law, for women.—J. M. Troth. Why, with the most fruitful
                            harvest known in a century are our people begging for bread ? Why, when millions of acres of
                            land are waiting for cultivation are bands of idle men straggling over the country like
                            beasts of prey ? Why are our manufactories idle, and our prisons and alms-houses full ?
                            These are the legitimate train of evils which follow war. As a remedy, organize compulsory
                            education for children, and compulsory labor for the able-bodied idler. Do away with dram
                            shops, and threefourths of our prisons and alms-houses wall be empty. Make less haste to get
                            rich and less still, to seem rich. Dignify labor and let it be understood that he who does
                            nothing is nothing. E. M. Coats. Let us have one more Indian war, and then, no more Indians
                            ! !—General Ouster's Advice to the Government. Can the Turks cherish a more deadly feeling ?
                            We are told that the Republic of Switzerland is the only spot on the continent of Europe
                            where the friends of peace and liberty are permitted to hold public meetings, and speak out
                            freely by the sentiments of their souls. Voice of Peace. In the town of Chester,
                            Pennsylvania, there is a military school on the soil of William Penn, and the head of that
                            institution is a minister ! A. H. Love. I well remember of the ministers seceding from the
                            American Anti-slavery Society in New York in 1840, and forming a new society for the reason
                            that Abbie Kelley was elected one of the business committee ! What vast sums of money are
                            taken from the poor, to support priests who uphold the gallows, war, and try to prevent
                            women from exercising their God-given rights! but with all their bigotry they cannot stop
                            the onward march of free thought. B. H. Ober. The late Uncivil War cost the United States
                            1.000.000 horses! </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Bro. Albert, Be assured of my grateful appreciation of your efforts to..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Bro. Albert, Be assured of my grateful appreciation of your efforts to...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, March 24, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass. Mar. 24, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Bro. Albert, Be assured of my grateful appreciation of your efforts to make the
                                Shaker Manifesto an honorable representative in both contents and execution. And (if you
                                are in need) I have a little sympathy for you. Doubtless, Paul and Stanley were both
                                honest men. One embraced Christ and modified it to suit such as would not take it
                                unmixed; the other received Christ and denied it—went back to his "mire." In your
                                analysis, preserve all the good metal; whatever cannot bear examination through the lens
                                of truth must go the way of all chaff. The incubus of all false doctrines must be shaken
                                off. Can we do better than to observe Jefferson's motto : "Equal and exact justice to
                                all men?" When books and men accredited with infallibility speak to us with discordant
                                tongues, are we to pay royalty on reason, and revelation, or accept the mixture?
                                Physicians do not prescribe the mixture of a whole apothecary inventory for their
                                patients. They are wiser than the spiritual physicians, who repeat Paul: 114
                                M-AJSTimiESTO. <pb n="115" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 115 "Marriage is honorable in all, and
                                the bed undefiled." Is this the teaching of Jesus ? Whose disciples are we ? Jesus the
                                recognized pattern of the Christian ministry, was both healer, and preacher. Do Doctors
                                and Ministers inhabit one skin now-a-days in healing disease and in giving warning
                                against the fatal relapse of repeating the sin ? Or does one live by preaching Paul,
                                while the other lives on the effects of such preaching? Go on my brother, the verdict
                                will be in order at the close of the trial. As ever affectionately,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName">Elijah Myrick</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Young Sister L.— How nearly like a pure white lily your name sounds!..." TEIform="index"/>My Young Sister L.— How nearly like a pure white lily your name sounds!...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, Aprril 16, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Village, N. H.
                                Apr. 16, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Young Sister L.— How nearly like a pure white lily your name sounds! Just so pure
                                would I have my Lily in spirit. Earthly flowers afford great pleasure ; their beauty
                                gratifies the sense of vision, their sweet perfume the sense of smell, and how pleasant
                                to hold in our grasp a bouquet of lovely and fragrant flowers,—these are emblematic of
                                heavenly graces and Christian virtues; but how much more beautiful and really
                                significant, is the embodiment of these graces in the mind of an individual, and that
                                one in the bloom of life,—dedicated to the service of the Lord,—transplanted in the
                                beautiful garden of God ! My young Christian friend, grant to those you love, the
                                pleasure of seeing your youthful life bloom in loveliness, and more than this—giving the
                                promise of golden fruit. Nothing can be more lovely than a virgin soul! Believe me, a
                                pure, clean, disciplined spirit, is holy; and the promise of becoming the "Glory of
                                Heaven and the Flowers of Paradise," is given unto such only. You have made the attempt
                                to walk in the Christian path-way, and it is indeed, more glorious, and wiser to choose
                                the "better part," to sacrifice the selfish will, and thusfind the joys of eternal life,
                                rather than yield to the tempter—enjoy the pleasures of sin fora season and then have to
                                pay the penalty for indulgence against light, through intense sufferings. The gilded
                                pleasures which the world holds forth to the mental vision of youth, are not real; they
                                are never enjoyed, save at the expense of virtue, confidence, and a life of true
                                pleasure. There is no real happiness only in the Christian path of true self-denial; the
                                knowledge that we subordinate the lower desires, to the claims of the higher, spiritual
                                aspirations. I hope never to see my Lily a crushed flower, resolving again into the
                                elements of the earth, having lost the beauty and fragrance of her life. Never, never
                                listen to the unholy whisperings of the adversary, "Who goeth about like a roaring lion
                                seeking whom he may devour." Avoid his grasp! Flee from vain imaginings! Seek shelter in
                                the hearts of your spiritual guides, through the door of humble obedience, and you will
                                find the love of God equal to your needs ; the winds will all be tempered as you can
                                bear, and according to your day, so will be your strength. In conquering your own
                                passions, you will find that all things will be clad in new beauty ; you will see lovely
                                graces in your friends, and find ability to climb every rugged place; with gratitude for
                                an access so easy to the heavenly kingdom. Now having chosen the best gift—a pure
                                spirit,—may the angels of God guard, and guide you forever. Affectionately, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName">Your Sister E. M.</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker courtesy" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER COURTESY</head><p TEIform="p">One of the "true blue," aged brethren of Mt. Lebanon, made to his kind, young sister in
                                the gospel— Ann Offord—the present of a beautiful box, so ar" ranged internally, as to
                                be a practical present. In re turn, she poured forth her gratitude in poetical song
                                inscribed to her venerable friend. Now, listen to his thoughtful, practical reply :
                                Beloved Sister Ann: Your New Year's salutation is very acceptable. That which comes from
                                the heart, reaches the affections. On this commemorative occasion, I congratulate you,
                                and myself, that we are called MAlKmnESTO. <pb n="116" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> to the practical
                                manifestations of "Peace on earth, and good-will to all Humanity"—a weighty
                                responsibility—to embody, in ou every day lives, Divine Wisdom and Love The time has
                                fully come for the Law to be written on our affections. Indeed, to be the music of our
                                lives. 'Tis ours, to "sing the song of 31oses and the Lamb!"—to include in our lives,
                                the harmonies of Natural and Divine Law. While the propagative man and woman shrink from
                                the cross we bear, it is ours to sing of the triumphs, and the glories of the Higher
                                Life. Dearly beloved Sister : Go on your way rejoicing; and when we get through with the
                                fleeting shadows of earthly conditions, may it be said of you, of me, and of the whole
                                household of faith: "These are they, who keep the commandments of God, and the faith of
                                Jesus." In gospel love, your aged brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shaw, John" TEIform="persName">John Shaw</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Your religion may be hung with damask..." TEIform="index"/>Your religion may be hung with damask...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Your religion may be hung with damask and perfumed with lavender on Sunday if
                                        you wish, but on Monday the world wants a homespun religion whose color won't
                                        wash out and whose threads will stand the wear and tear of temptation</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York herald" TEIform="index"/>New York Herald</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is the Shaker system best?" TEIform="index"/>IS THE SHAKER SYSTEM BEST?</head><p TEIform="p"> In our plain advocacy of Shaker principles, we ever have endeavored to be so liberal, as to
                            be open to correction, whether or not the Shaker system is the best for the purposes it
                            intends. We have endeavored to do only simple justice to the various denominations of the
                            professedly Christian faith, even when we have charged some of them, so far from being
                            followers of the celibate, peaceful, unselfish Jesus, that they had not the smell of
                            Christianity about them; but, that for selfish considerations alone, they had reversed the
                            rules of his life, and had made sacraments of those very practices which he purposely
                            abjured, and which abjuration, was the distinguishing feature between Christianity and
                            Judaism. The intents of our system are salvation and redemption from the good and bad of the
                            world ; a rising superior to the world, in its very best estate. Can it render these? Does
                            it do so best? We have given the Methodists credit for their zeal, while condemning their
                            mixture of good faith and bad, as unchristian works ; we have credited the baptisms of the
                            Baptists as very good so far as the water is concerned; we have admitted the underlying
                            truths of the theories forming the Presbyterian faith; and have been particularly favorable
                            to th'at conspicuous feature of the Roman Catholics, which makes celibacy an enforcement on
                            their clergy, monks and nuns. Wherever we have seen evidences of a following of the Master
                            in churches or individuals, we have been most active to give credit and record the fact.
                            Yet, n the face of this unequaled liberality, we are unjustly charged with egotism,
                            superstition and bigotry. The principles that guided the life of Tesus, the Christ, are
                            Christianity to us ; and we have espoused Christianity from a love of these principles ;
                            with a full understanding what they would cross off rom our practices and what they would
                            approve. We do not practice Christianty because Jesus did ; neither because any one else
                            than Jesus did so. We so ive from a love of the principles ; and because the fruits of these
                            principles are <pb n="117" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MA.NTF'EISTO. salvation and redemption from
                            what we would cease to be subjects. We disclaim being copyists in the sense of idolaters. We
                            admit there is a good in marriage ; and there is a plane of human ex- istence, where it is
                            properly practiced, that it may be termed very good—where it gives to the earth sound minds
                            in healthy bodies. But in its very best forms we pronounce marriage a worldly, unchristian
                            institution, that never was, never will be practiced by a follower of the Master—a child of
                            the resurrection. We want salvation from even the good of marriage, and therefore find, by
                            following the Christ, we obtain what we want. We admit that Paul permitted its practice, by
                            those who would do worse without it; but we claim that he knew that it was not following the
                            Master so to engage, and that inasmuch as the people married, they so far failed of
                            experiencing the salvations and resurrec- tions of the Christ. "Marriage should people the
                            earth: Celibacy populates the heavens," said St. Jerome. If marriage is ever proper, and we
                            admit that it is, then "the children of the world"—Jews, etc. are the proper parties to
                            engage in it. But let no Christian attempt it, nor its following of reproductions. Is not
                            the Shaker system best, in its rendering salvation from the good and bad of marriage ? If
                            not, show us the better way. With marriages, naturally follow children, aggregation of
                            property etc. Are not these selfish considerations that find no parallel in the Christ? And
                            does not our system best meet them with a remedy? The lusts of the flesh and pride of life
                            are of the world ; and these seek indulgences in and out of marriage. We want to be elevated
                            to Christ's life and above these ; and our system guides to the elevation. From these same
                            lusts and pride spring all the wars of households and of nations—from which we seek complete
                            salvation. Put- ting away the causes, through activity of the Shaker system, these effects
                            cease with us. Is there a better way? We do not deny the crosses our system imposes upon us;
                            these are many, and sometimes irksome ; but are they not salutary, even to saving us as
                            Jesus was saved ? Therefore, while we claim that our system is capable of an exceeding
                            progress, this will be in a heavenly direction, not earthward ; and that while it is not yet
                            a finality unto perfection, does it not approach nearer to Jesus' life than any other
                            system? Let us reflect: Jesus lived above Marriage, reproductions, houses, landsall selfish
                            property; thus our system teaches ; do the popular Churches so teach? Jesus was a
                            peacemaker— "prince of peace"—and our system evolves none others. Is it so with the popular
                            Churches? "Whoso names the name of Christ," or Christian, let them depart from all practices
                            not found in the life of the Christ; and to them will appear which system is best unto
                            salvation.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker sermon" TEIform="index"/> A SHAKER SERMON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Henry Ward Beecher, in our hearing, preached a full-toned Shaker sermon in one complete
                                sentence: "As followers of Christ, we have no right to do that 117 <pb n="118" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 118 THIG SHAKEE MIAJNTEFESTO. which the Master never did." This is as well as we
                                could preach ourselves, and we therefore say liAmen!" to it; asking all professors of
                                Christianity to examine themselves, and see, if they are engaging in any practice in
                                life, that finds no sanction in the life practices oi Jesus—the master.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and state" TEIform="index"/> CHURCH AND STATE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We object to the apparent junction oi Church and State, illustrated on the new silver
                                dollar in the words : "In God we trust." The name of no one's religious God should be so
                                desecrated. We propose an amendment that would answer more truthfully, and aid in
                                keeping the Church superior to State control ; Let that word '' God" be made to read
                                "Gold;" and then let "Silver" be added. We think the gods of gold and silver have
                                immense congregations of devotees—idolaters. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To all nations" TEIform="index"/> "TO ALL NATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> There is one feature of the gospel of Christ, we are almost invariably inclined to evade
                                ; and this is the universal application of the gospel to every sinsick soul, no matter
                                of what color or nation he or she may be. There will be people of various colors,
                                desirous of the gospel given us to preach; and what right have we to interdict, by
                                deciding that "their day has not yet come?" Let us be careful to feed hungering souls,
                                regardless of their color or nationality ; else there may be chargeable to our account a
                                loss to souls, much inhumanity, and a mournful want of Christianity. Let them come, and
                                when they arrive, asking a share in our cross, testimony, and life, do not let there be
                                heard from our habitations queries as to nationalities, or "what is the color of your
                                skin?" May heaven preserve us from such prejudices ; and from becoming unwilling sharers
                                of gospel comforts with any and all who want to be good. The reminder and rebuke,
                                applies equally well in the East, as in the West. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and state" TEIform="index"/> BUDDHIST MISSIONARIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We hail with joy, the fact that Bro. J. M. Peebles has made arrangements with some
                                Buddhists, well versed in the English tongue, to come to America and compare their isms
                                with the Christianity sent them by Missionaries from America. Such hybrid, perverted,
                                polluted Christianity as some missionaries make current in foreign fields, is a disgrace
                                to barbarism. If we mistake not, these Brahmins will ask and demand an answer, as to
                                what and wherein Christianity, as taught by the general Churches is an improvement on
                                what preceded it—Judaism; and unless more radical Christianity finds practice in these
                                Churches, they will be unable to render a favorable showing.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The fourth Paper on Ann Lee etc. is crowded over into June No.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/> BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American communities" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hinds, William A." TEIform="persName"/>William A. Hinds</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual scientist" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Yates company chronicle" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Family herald and weekly star" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communication from the spirit of Mother Ann Lee" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Views of our heavenly home" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davis, A. J." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">American Communities : by William A. Binds, American Socialist, Oneida, N. Y. Such is the
                                title of a large, octavo pamphlet of nearly two hundred pages, written in the most
                                happy, as well as most correct style sossible, or imaginable. There have been arger
                                works written upon this subject; but none of them can be as desirable to the larger
                                number of people as is this. It is replete with all subjects which most people are
                                desirous of knowing about Com<pb n="119" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> munal life and "Communities." It is
                                critical, very kindly so; and suggestive of very many reasonable improvements in
                                existing communities, and will prove a harbinger of valuable thought to those
                                contemplating community life, or of starting co-operative associations. But it is the
                                very kindly spirit, manifested towards that phase of communism known as Shakerism, that
                                we wish particularly to refer to. The author, while not believing Shakerism to be the ne
                                plus ultra for humanity, finds, nevertheless, very much therein that attracts his
                                admiration; so much so, that apart from other divisions of the hook, the reader will
                                think of him as one "almost persuaded to be a Shaker!" Our personal acquaintance with
                                the author is of a high order; and while we do not believe he could purposely
                                misrepresent any community, we would express both gratitude and fears for the almost
                                flattering . .apter on each and all of the Shaker Societies, The Shaker Manifesto
                                institution included. Let all bear in mind, it is not an expensive treat; but within the
                                reach of the poor. Its price is Sixty Cents. Ordered through this office, it may be had,
                                with The Manifesto one year, for One Dollar ! Tiie Spiritual Scientist is again on its
                                wings, well, hearty, and as enterprising, happy and hopeful as its illustrious editor,
                                E. Gerry Brown, can make it. Its address is Boston, Mass, and may it flourish with true
                                spirituality. The Yates Co. Chronicle : Penn Yan, N. Y. We have been the recipient of so
                                many tributes from this noble weekly, we wish our readers by the thousands would secure
                                a copy of it, and judge for themselves what a noble paper it is. The Family Herald and
                                Weekly Star: Montreal, Canada. We have befjre spoken of this most enterprising weekly;
                                and we now, unsolicited, inform our readers, that fora weekly that contains so much, we
                                do not think its equal exists for $1.25. Human Nature, (London, Eng.) for January,
                                copied the entire "Communication from the spirit of Mother Ann Lee, "as printed in Nov.
                                1877 Shaker. We have perceived, that elsewhere, the answers therein to Bro. Peebles'
                                questions, have attracted unusual attention. We feel assured, lhat those answers will
                                yet be used extensively by the better class of spiritualists. Another edition of "Plain
                                Talks upon Practical Religion," is now ready. As a means of answering hundreds of
                                questions, naturally arising, concerning Believers, called Shakers, Elder Henry Cumings
                                says : "It is the very best work that we have ever issued." We will send it to any
                                address for five cents—postage one cent—less than cost. Direct to either Editor or
                                Publisher of The Manifesto. Received: Catalogue of Live Stock at Oneida Community Farm.
                                It is an excellent exhibit. Religio-Philosophical Tracts : This beautiful pamphlet
                                published by the R. P. Journal Publishing House contains seven articles upon very
                                important subjects, and is sent postpaid for ten cents. Views of our Heavenly Home: By
                                A. J. Davis. Colby and Rich, Publishers, Boston Mass. For many years the writer of this
                                book has obtained desired seclusion from publicity: yet in the meantime has been
                                handsomely visited by tangible public approval. In this book the noble writer is made
                                the medium of relating most beautiful and happifying possibilities in the future life of
                                our spirits. Every line is consistent with the truism that effects there, follow their
                                causes here; and while illuminating, apparently to an exaggeration, the inexpressible
                                beauties of the future life, there is not a line that excuses the vicious from the
                                rewards of vice, nor aught but magnifies, beyond comprehension, the harvests of those
                                who live virtuously. It is a most wonderful book, written by a person of a very lovable
                                disposition and high-toned character. We take this occasion, in noticing this great
                                book, to thank Bro. Davis, far taking no part, nor entering, even to a shade of
                                fellowship, with that class of spiritualists, who seek and are satis- fied with merely
                                the phenomenal; or who would use Spiritualism as a cloak to their sexual lusts.</p></div3><pb n="120" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks</head><p TEIform="p">To whom these presents shall come : We commend the little work "Plain Talks upon
                                Practical Religion" to the consideration of all who are anxious for information
                                concerning our faith and principles. We deem it unpretentious, concise and plain; yet
                                considerably illustrating the subjects commonly arising as questions in the minds of
                                most people concerning Shakers and their principles. We recommend Novitiate Elders, and
                                any others interested, to aid in its extensive circulation.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ministry of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y." TEIform="persName">Ministry of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> We are under the necessity of deferring comments until June No. upon "Buddhism and
                                Christianity, Face to Face"—a work not yet arrived for sale in this country, but bearing
                                the unmistakable evidences of being the work by Bro. J. M. Peebles. Look for it; obtain
                                it.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Starbuck, Benjamin" TEIform="index"/>Benjamin Starbuck
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Troy, N. Y. March 15, <persName reg="Starbuck, Benjamin" TEIform="persName">Benjamin Starbuck</persName>,
                                aged 73. He was a near and dear friend of the Shakers, and a most upright, honorable
                                citizen.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hopkins, Nancy" TEIform="index"/>Nancy Hopkins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield Conn. <persName reg="Hopkins, Nancy" TEIform="persName">Nancy Hopkins</persName>, departed this
                                life March 11, 1878 aged 78 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earl, Permilla" TEIform="index"/>Permilla Earl
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At Shakers, N. Y. March 18, 18.78 <persName reg="Earl, Permilla" TEIform="persName">Permilla
                                Earl</persName>, aged 76. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dutton, Lueretia" TEIform="index"/>Lueretia Dutton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At West Gloucester, Me., March 23, <persName reg="Dutton, Lueretia,                                     Eldress" TEIform="persName">Eldress Lueretia
                                    Dutton </persName>aged 61 years and 6 months.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stebbins, Olive" TEIform="index"/>Olive Stebbins
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> At Enfield, Conn. Feb. 8, <persName reg="Stebbins, Olive" TEIform="persName">Eldress Olive
                                Stebbins</persName>, aged 79 years, and for 64 years a treasure of countless worth to
                                her Enfield friends who deeply mourn their loss. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter IV" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName">WILLIAM G. LIBBEY</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">CHAP. IV. Although we suffered some from sore feet and fatigue, our rest at night was
                                very refreshing, there being no mosquitoes nor fleas —those pests of most tropical
                                countries—to trouble us. We found plenty of good fish in all parts of the lagoon, and
                                very easily taken; with a short line held in the hand we could catch enough for a meal
                                in a few minutes. Cocoa-nuts were abundant wherever we went. If we tired of fish and
                                cocoa-nuts, we could easily knock down a young booby, a kind of pelican bird the'flesh
                                of which is tolerably good food. Those we roasted wero very fat, being fed every day
                                with abundance of flying fish, by the parent birds, who are very attentive to their
                                young before they are able to fly. These young birds on remaining quietly in their nests
                                until they are fledged, become a mass of fat, which they soon lose when able to fish for
                                themselves, and never regain; for all of the full grown birds we caught were rather poor
                                in flesh. One incident of our journey around the island I will relate, as it gave us an
                                extra feast, and was quite an event in our island life. I think it was the second day of
                                our journey, in the afternoon, we came suddenly up- on a large terrapin; and wanting a
                                change of diet we cut off the head, opened the shell, and prepared for a feast like any
                                hungry na- tives ; and having kindled a fire near the ocean beach we went to the water's
                                edge to wash our terrapin meat, and eggs. While thus engaged flocks of birds hovered
                                over our heads ready to devour any piece that chanced to escape from our hands, that is,
                                if the sharks did not get it first, for we could see their great blunt heads within a
                                few feet of us, watching greedily for a share <pb n="121" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> •of our meat; but
                                we had none to spare them. Building a good fire from the wreck of a small vessel which
                                we found on the beach, we roasted and ate of our terrapin, until the stars appeared;
                                while we no doubt ate very heartily, it should be remembered that our cooking process
                                was quite primitive and slow. for when I retired to our hut for the night, my brother
                                was by the fire roasting and eating. How long his feast continued I know not, as sleep
                                overpowered me and kept me in its grasp, until day-light. We made our breakfast from
                                terrapin meat, and had some of the eggs left to take along with us on our journey; we
                                also saved some of the oil in a cocoa-nut shell, to take with us for our feet, which
                                were badly lacerated, by walking on the coral. About the fourth day of our journey, we
                                came suddenly upon a wide passage of water, from the lagoon to the open ocean, and the
                                tide being high the water between us and the opposite shore looked rath't forbidding.
                                Not that we were at all afraid of salt water, for we could easily have swam across had
                                there been no sharks in the way; hut seeing their fins cut through the surface of the
                                water, we dared not trust ourselves to swim in their company. Going back to a beautiful
                                grove of cocoanut trees, we built a shelter hut, made a fire, and obtaining a good
                                supply of fish from the tidal passage, satiated our hunger by cooking and eating, as
                                previously described. With all our experience as sailors and fishermen, we never saw so
                                good a place for fishing before. There were holes in the branching coral from two to
                                five feet deep, into which we could drop our hooks, with only a short piece of line, and
                                quickly take out a nice white fish weighing four or five pounds. While waiting the turn
                                of the tide we improved the time reading our little Bible, the only book we had, and
                                mending our clothes. We also made a case for the sun-glass, as it occurred to us here,
                                that if we should break it, we could not make a fire, and of necessity be compelled to
                                eat our fish and fowls raw; therefore putting our ingenuity to a test, we managed with
                                the help of an old dull axe, to make a case; which, although rude, was good protection
                                for o.ur precious treasure. We remained at this place about a day and a half, observing
                                the rise and fall of the tide ; and found to our joy that at low water wo could cross to
                                the opposite side of the passage, without being forced to swim. On the morning of the
                                second day we left our beautiful grove, and carefully picking our way over the highest
                                parts of the coral, we reached the opposite shore in safety. There we saw a place where
                                the small shrubby trees of the island were covered with some kind of a wild vine, the
                                only vines we saw; and if I may be allowed a small speculation in geology, I should give
                                it as my belief, that the place where the vines grew was the oldest part of the island,
                                not only from the presence of the vines, but also from its being the windward side of
                                the island, and the trade wind having blown in one direction for many ages, causing the
                                roll of the ocean to take the same course, the island must have been formed, beginning
                                at this point. The vegetables and marine waste from the newly formed land, must have
                                gone with the roll of the sea to leeward, or westward; thus changing a coral reef
                                dangerous to the future navigator, into a beautiful island covered with verdure, and
                                abounding with trees, prominent and towering, while above them all, is seen the queen of
                                tropical trees—the cocoa-nut palm. The day we crossed the tidal passage we walked faster
                                and farther than on either of the previous days, and arrived at our destination a little
                                past noon. On reaching the huts we found them in ruins, but selecting the best one, and
                                taking parts of the others to repair it, we managed to make a comfortable shel- ter for
                                a warm climate. The most useful and valuable thing we found at the old huts, was a part
                                of one side of a large cast iron pot, broken in the shape of a skimmer, and capable of
                                holding three or four gallons. To us it was a whole kitchen department, for we could now
                                have boiled fish, fowl soup, and chowder. Our pot was in place ready for use, set on
                                bricks that doubtless came ashore with the pot, and were, no doubt, a part of the
                                try-works of a whaler, wrecked in the lagoon twelve years before. She belonged to
                                Sydney, Australia, and had several hundred barrels of SHAKBE : <pb n="122" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/>
                                122 THE SHAKER 6perm oil which was saved, and the ship's crew with their effects were
                                rescued by another vessel, after a residence of several months on this island. This
                                information we obtained from a boat steerer, a half breed Pequot Indian, belonging to
                                the old ship Phenix, of New London, Conn., the vessel in which we made our first voyage
                                to the Pacific ocean. But to return to our domestic life : we now thought ourselves very
                                well provided for. having found means for so great an improvement in our diet. One
                                little incident that occurred when we came in sight of these huts, I will mention, as it
                                caused a little controversy with the inhabitants of the island! My brother objected to
                                the place as a residence, because there were no cocoa-nut trees within five minutes walk
                                of the huts : you see lie loved the trees, and said it was not a pretty place; this the
                                writer was willing to admit, as we had been pitching our camps in much prettier places,
                                during our march, yet while this was not the most pleasant spot we might have selected,
                                it was the best place to see the passing vessels ; or should they call at the island,
                                this was the only place a boat could land in safety ; and should we fix our home farther
                                in_ land, vessels could come and go, and not be seen by us, and thus we should miss
                                obtaining from them some articles of which we were then beginning to feel the need; such
                                as fish-hooks, lines, a small iron pot that we could carry with us any where ; we wanted
                                a few carpenter's tools with which to build a boat, or a house. So by thus reasoning we
                                became reconciled where to fix our port of entry; my brother very kindly yielding the
                                point when convinced it was for the best interest of our little community of two. (to be
                                continued.) </p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mind and man" TEIform="index"/>MIND and MAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doyle, Alfred E." TEIform="persName">ALFRED E. DOYLE</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> In looking o'er this world so wide— A seeming maze without a plan— We e'er should seek
                                the brighter side, To help the mind and bless the man. Though Satan's hosts may oft
                                engage us, Combined in passions war-ike clan ; And fiercer though the conflict rages,
                                These nerve the mind to make the man. And in this life whate'er our chances, Our
                                fellows' joys or ills to scan ; Remember 'tis oft the circumstances, That mould the mind
                                and rule the man. So may we all at calls of need, Da what so e'er we find we can, By
                                kindly looks or words or deed, To aid the mind—in blessing man. And in conclusion—let
                                all reflect Since life is but a simple span, What e'er the lot—we should respect, The
                                noble mind of an honest man. Watervliet, O. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to keep bouquets fresh" TEIform="index"/>How To Keep Bouquets Fresh</head><p TEIform="p">There are various recipes for keeping bouquets fresh. Some people stick them in moist
                                sand; some salt the water in the vases, and others warm it; others, again, use a few
                                drops of ammonia. My rule is to cool the flowers thoroughly at night. When the long day
                                of furnace heat has made the roses droop and their stems limp and lifeless, I clip them
                                a little, and set them to float in a marble basin fall of very cold water. In the
                                morning they come out made over into crisp beauty, as fresh and blooming as if just
                                gathered. All flowers, however, will not stand this water-cure. Heliotrope blackens and
                                falls to pieces under it, azaleas drop from their stems, and mignonette soaks away from
                                its fragrance. For these I use dry cold air. I wrap them in cotton wool and set them on
                                a shelf in the ice-chest. I can almost hear you laugh; but really I am not joking.
                                Flowers thus treated keep perfectly for a week with me, and often longer.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="St. Nicholas" TEIform="persName"/>St. Nicholas</byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sundry useful receipts" TEIform="index"/>Sundry Useful Receipts</head><p TEIform="p">A hot shovel held over varnished furniture, will take out white spots. m: AJNrrEPESTO.
                                    <pb n="123" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> A bit of glue dissolved in skim milk and water, will restore
                                old crape. Ribbons of any kind should be washed in cold soap suds, and not rinsed. If
                                your flat-irons are rough, rub them well with fine salt, and it will make them smooth.
                                Oat straw is the best for filling beds. It should be changed once a year. If you are
                                buying a carpet for durability, choose small figures. A bit of soap rubbed on the hinges
                                of doors, will prevent their creaking. Scotch snuff put on the holes where crickets come
                                out, will destroy them. A gallon of strong lye put in a barrel of water, will make it as
                                soft as rain water. Half a cranberry bound on a corn, will soon kill it. In winter set
                                the handle of your pump as high as possible at night, or throw a blanket over it.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dyspepsia is cured by muscular exercise..." TEIform="index"/>Dyspepsia is cured by muscular exercise...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Dyspepsia is cured by muscular exercise, voluntary or involuntary, and cannot be cured
                                in any other way, because nothing can create or collect gastric juice except exercise;
                                it is a product of the human machine. Nature only can make it.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep borax in the house" TEIform="index"/>Keep Borax in the House</head><p TEIform="p"> In the laundry it is economical, as it saves both labor and soap, and is really cheaper
                                than the latter. For blankets and other large articles it is especially valuable, and in
                                all cases the use of a little borax will save half the labor when articles are much
                                soiled. It is perfectly effectual in driving away red ants, cockroaches, etc., if
                                sprinkled around on pantry shelves, or put in small quantities on paper and placed in
                                the runways of the insects. Borax is also of great value for toilet uses. For removing
                                dandruff and cleansing the hair it is unequaled. It is also a good remedy for rough face
                                and chapped hands. Its application to wounds, sores, bruises, sprains, etc., proves very
                                salutary and is often the only remedy required, even in severe cases. Indeed, borax is
                                one of the best remedies for many ailments in our whole hygiene, and for that reason
                                alone it should be kept ready for use when wanted. There are many other uses for borax
                                which I need not specify, but those I have mentioned aro alone enough to satisfy any
                                family of the value of the article.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="The people" TEIform="persName">The People</persName></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping poultry" TEIform="index"/>Keeping poultry
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Keeping Poultry.—Our domestic animals, derived as they are from wild ancestors, require
                                a certain amount of exercise to keep them in vigorous health. Poultry cannot be kept in
                                large numbers in confined areas without detriment to their constitution. Colonel
                                Taggart, of Pennsylvania, provides food and exercise for fowls at the same time. In his
                                poultry yard are several beds about thirty feet square each, in which Colonel Taggart
                                buries oats, several bushels to the bed. The grains begin, of course, at once to swell
                                and germinate, and the fowls have free access, scratching and eating the tender sprouts
                                to their hearts' content. While the fowls are thus busy on one bed, a new one is
                                prepared, which is in readiness for them by the time it is required. The idea is a good
                                one. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A single pound of bone-dust..." TEIform="index"/>A single pound of bone-dust...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A single pound of bone-dust contains, ac- cording to our illustrious chemist, Liebig, as
                                much phosphoric acid as one hundred pounds of wheat. Hence the economy of utilizing
                                every scrap of bone to be found on the farm. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Root crops for cattle" TEIform="index"/>Root crops for cattle
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Root Crops for Cattle.—The value of roots as feed for cattle, particularly for those
                                giving milk, is receiving large consideration by the agriculturists and stock men of all
                                the more enlightened countries. Not only are they of more value as multiplying the
                                lacteal fluid, but they are more nutritious than other feed, excepting grains, and their
                                manurial value is a very important consideration, as being second only to grain-fed
                                animals. We advise stock men to sow The Yellow Ovoid Beet, which though a recent
                                importation, has the last season yielded under favorable conditions 5000 bushels on
                                three acres ; and at another place more than fifty-nine tons were grown on an acre! We
                                shall sow Ovoid extensively.</p></div3><pb n="124" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Weary not o Christian pilgrim" TEIform="index"/>WEARY NOT O CHRISTIAN PILGRIM</head><byline TEIform="byline">FROM <persName reg="The sisterhood" TEIform="persName">THE SISTERHOOD</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">ENFIELD, N. H. 1. Weary not O christian pilgrim, in thy journey 2. Shun the mists
                                of gloom and sorrow, thatch scure thy weary not, Tho the way of life be fore '' thee
                                seems gospel light, Let thy polar star be duty and with many dangers fraught, Thro'
                                the valley of thy mot to truth and right, Then the Savior's love the shadow you in
                                safety shall be brought, shall guide thee to thy home in glory bright. <pb n="125" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 135 For the promise of the Father will not fail,
                                will not fail. Weary not, in the weary not strife For a home in the heavens weary
                                not, is secure, is secure.</p></div3><pb n="126" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To ascertain the weight of live cattle" TEIform="index"/>To ascertain the weight of live cattle
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To Ascertain the weight of Live Cattle. Take a string, put it around the
                                        breast, stand square, just behind the shoulder blade; measure on a foot rule the
                                        feet and inches the animal is in circumference; this is called the girth; then,
                                        with the string, measure from the bone of the tail which plumbs the line with
                                        the hinder part of the buttock; direct the line along the back to the fore part
                                        of the shoulder blade; ta*ke the dimensions on the foot rule as before, which is
                                        the length; and work the figures in the following manner: Girth of the bullock,
                                        say six feet four inches; length, five feet three inches; which multiplied
                                        together, make 31 square superficial feet; and that multiplied by 23 (the number
                                        of pounds allowed to each superficial foot of cattle measuring less than seven
                                        and more than five feet in girth,) makes 713 pounds. Where the animal measures
                                        less than nine and more than seven in girth, 31 is the number of pounds to each
                                        superficial foot. Again, suppose a pig or any small beast should measure two
                                        feet in girth, and two along the back, which multiplied together, make four
                                        square feet; that multiplied by 11, the number of pounds allowed each square
                                        foot of cattle measuring less than three feet in girth, makes 44 pounds. Again,
                                        suppose a calf, a sheep, &amp;c, should measure four feet six inches in
                                        girth, and three feet nine inches in length, which multiplied together, make 15
                                        one fourth square feet; that rcmltiplied by 16, the number of pounds allowed to
                                        all cattle measuring less than five feet and more than three in girth, makes 265
                                        pounds. The dimensions of the girth and length of back cattle, sheep, calves, or
                                        hogs may bo as exactly taken this way as it is at all necessary for any
                                        computation or any valuation of stock, and will answer exactly to the four
                                        quarters, sinking the offal, a sum which every man who can get even a bit of
                                        chalk can easily figure.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Rural new yorker" TEIform="index"/>Rural New Yorker</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saltpetre for lice" TEIform="index"/>Saltpetre For Lice</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Livermore, S. G." TEIform="persName">S. G. Livermore</persName></byline><p TEIform="p">, a practical farmer, states that he has found saltpetre a never-failing preventive of
                                lice. It should be given with salt in the proportion of one pound of saltpetre to a
                                bushel of salt. If you can save the numberless scrubbings with tobacco water and grease
                                and kerosene, &amp;c, &amp;c, it will be an item of no small consequence.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>SELECTED</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Now and then" TEIform="index"/>Now And Then</head><p TEIform="p">Learn impatient soul, Heaven's profound decree, Wise the firm control That restraineth
                                thee. Impulse is but blind, Mad is strong desire, God to thee is kind Plucking from the
                                fire. Justice beareth sway, Love uplifts the hand; Now thou must obey, Then shalt
                                understand. Vain to rage and fret, Weak to wish and pine, Dare not question yet Higher
                                will than thine. Wouldst thou stand at ease? Hear the bugle play! Forward! victories
                                Crown the closing fray ! Wouldst thou choose thy post? One surveys the field, Where he
                                needs thee most, Patient service yield. Wouldst thou lead apart From the sounds of
                                strife With thy books and heart Self-communing life? Up, and self forget! Forth! to gain
                                and give Payment of the debt Due to all who live. Work, submit, obey, Smile, and be
                                content, Cast thy will away, Take the burden sent, To thy sentence bow, Badge of fealty
                                wear, Child and servant now Then the lord and heir.</p></div3></div2><pb id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!-- 
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [advertisements deleted] </p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>