<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2604" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">22</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18960401" TEIform="date">April 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-72</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1896.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
with large type   and  on  excellent  paper.
It  contains  130 pages and has
ILL US TEA TIONS
of the Shakers and their
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
The  work  gives  quite an extended account  of  the  Several SOCIETIES, their
organization and general management.
Price,  50 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OB
"United   Society    of    Believers"
It treats of the Bise and Progress of the
Society, together with the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
Price 50 cts.
LLOYD H. CHANDLER.U. S. W
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
AUTHORIZED RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER   (COMMUNITY,
The religious'Jbasis of the Oeder must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the  individ
ual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
APRIL,
MILLENNIAL
BY
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
The Testimony of History to the Truth
of Scripture. "This is number 33 of the AntiInfidel Library. With a carefully written introduction by the Editor of the Christian,
H. L. Hastings, and the body of the work from
the pen of the Rev. George Rawlinson, M. A.
should be sufficient to warrant any reader of
the great value of the 240 pages of Historical
Illustrations.
The small price of thirty-five cents should
be a great inducement for all to obtain this
Historical Work, who ure at all interested in
Biblical knowledge or in the curiosities of an.
cient History.
Published bj H. L. Hastings 47 Cornhill,
Boston, Mass.
As state after state comes into line in the
matter of abolishing, by legislation, the apparently useless form of "three days of grace"
the question has been raised in many a mind
as to the origin and supposed meaning of a
custom which is now dying out in the march
of social progress. The Editor of The Sunday
School Times takes up this subject editorially, in his issue of February 15, and shows that
the custom dates back not only to early English days, but to the very infancy of the world,
and the time of primeval man.
JOHN D. WATTLES & CO.
1031 Walnut St., Philadelphia, Pa.
In none of his papers upon "This Country of
Ours" has ex-President Harrison delivered
himself with such vehemence and emphasis
as he has in the one in the March Ladies' Home
Journal. "The President's Duties." Besides
commending one of Mr. Cleveland's acts, and
censuring Ambassadors for making political
speeches, he talks of Presidential appointments in a most feeling and an almost pathetic way. Upon the latter theme, in giving en
dorsement to Civil Service Reform, he says:
"In spite of all the difficulties that beset the
question of removals and appointments it
must be conceded that much progress in the
direction of a betterment of the service has
been made. The Civil Service Rules have removed a large number of minor offices in the
departments at Washington, and in the postal
and other services, from the scramble of politics, and have given the President, the Cabinet officers and the Members of Congress
great relief; but it still remains true that in
the power of appointment to office the President finds the most exacting, unrelenting and
distracting of his duties. In the nature of
things he begins to make enemies from the
start, and has no wray of escapeit is fate;
and to a sensitive man involves much distress
of mind. His only support is in the good
opinion of those who chiefly care that the public business shall be well done, and are not
disturbed by the consideration whether this
man or that man is doing it; but he hears very
little directly from this class. No President
can conduct a successful administration without the support of Congress, and this matter
of appointments, do what he will, often weakens that support. It is for him always a sort
of compromise between his ideal and the best
attainable thing."
The great "Leo of Virginia" series, in Frank
Leslie's Popular Monthly, is continued in
the March number with a picturesque and superbly illustrated paper devoted to Major
General Henry Lee, of Revolutionary fame.
This is "the dashing dragoon and orator, the
chosen of Patrick Henry and the beloved of
Washington, classic scholar and impassioned
patriot, brilliant scion of a long-distinguished
race, Governor of his native State, and perfect
type of the Virginia gentleman, rearing his
sons in religion, morality and learning, sclicitous above all that they should be taught to
ride, shoot and tell the truthGeneral Henry
Lee, the 'Light Horse Harry' of his soldier
contemporaries, and the father of General
Robert E. Lee." Other illustrated articles in
the March Frank Leslie's are : "The New South,"
by the Hon. John Y. Foster; "In Old Virginia," by Rate Mason Rowland; "A Winter in
Lombardy," by Lena L. Pepper; "Woman's
Work and Ministration," by Alvin S. Southwrorth; "The Memory of Robert Burns," by
Margaret E. Leicester Addis; "Society Plays
Golf," by Diana Crossways; and "A Winter
Vagary," by William Potts, of "Underledge."
Among the contributors of fiction and poetry
are Anna Katharine Green, Cleveland Moffett, Frances Swann Williams, Charles Edwardes, Henry Tyrrell and Georgia Roberts.
The first of a series of articles on "The
Young People of the White House," by Joanna
R. Nicholls, is given, with numerous illustrations, in the March number of Frank Leslie's
Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls. This
number has many other good things that will
delight its youthful readers, among them a
short boating story by James Otis; a very
pretty cat-show story by Rosalie M. Jonas; a
thrilling account of "A Wild Whirl Down the
Loops," by J. Macdonald Oxley; the second
paper of Frank Lee FarnellSs interesting series on "The Favorite Story-writers for Young
People," in which are portraits of Horatio
Alger, Jr., James Otis and Sophie Swett; an
article on "Dainty Work for Girls," by Lila
Graham Alliger; abright little story by Helen
Corinne Bergen; the conclusion of the two
serials by Edward S. Ellis and Jeannette H.
Wai worth; some illustrated poems; two new
games; a chat on juvenile literature by the
editor; and a number of prize puzzles.
Word and Works for March opens with an
illustrated chapter on the Sun, Moon and
Planets. A great many persons are especially interested in the Moon, and are anxious to
visit it while in the body, and may be to take
up their abode with their friends in the Moon,
after their journey has closed on the earth.
The Rev. Irl. Hicks, in the March number of
Word and Works, will with pleasure accom--><pb n="57" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of Chas. D. Hampton of Union Village, Ohio, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF CHAS. D. HAMPTON OF UNION VILLAGE, O. NO. 3.</head><p TEIform="p">.You have felt the blessing of peace and experienced the reward of obedience. Your soul has
                            been warmed by the tranquilizing influence of conscious rectitude according to the degree of
                            spiritual light which has illuminated your understanding, but you have more to do. You have
                            never thought to acknowledge God as the author of your felicity, or prayed to Him for a
                            continuation of his blessing. You have done well for a beginning, but those who find access
                            to the door of heaven, must knock, and if they would have the blessing must ask for it.
                            Without prayer and a living sense of dependence on superior principles, your soul will
                            become lean and barren. The manna you gathered yesterday will not support you to-day. If you
                            expect to realize eternal happiness, you must prepare your soul for eternal progression. I
                            listened to these remarks with surprise and answered with reverence,I have been obedient to
                            your ministrations and believe them to be sent of God. It is true I have not prayed to God
                            because I do not know Him. I have asked of you because you have proved to me that you have a
                            desire for my good. Mentor.What you say is true and for that reason I have ventured to
                            instruct you. I am, like yourself, an agent of instruction and subject to being taught. My
                            ability to do good comes from God, and in order to obtain it I am constrained to ask for it
                            and my strength is perfected in obedience and sincere prayer. APRIL, <pb n="58" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 58
                            THE MANIFESTO. I continued to plead,"I do not know how to pray or foi1 what to ask, seeing
                            all my reasonable wants are amply provided." Mentor.My time of ministering to you is drawing
                            to a close, and I desire that you may do your work and find future needful support and
                            protection from the fullness of a more abundant fountain. At this announcement I felt
                            distressed; I could not now feel his presence. The requirement seemed reasonable, but I was
                            unprepared for it. I retired to the unfrequented woods and took a seat on a log, and
                            deliberately went into an analysis of my condition. Deeply sensible of my ignorance of the
                            being whom I was about to address and also aware of my own natural levity of character,
                            doubt and unbelief and want of confidence overcame my previous determination. Being really
                            weak in faith, but honest and sincere, I promised fervently that if in my present
                            undertaking any kind being would give a response to my prayer that I could understand and
                            realize an answer to my supplication, I would obey without regard to consequences. I queried
                            in what manner and for what I should pray but could come upon no form of words. Finally,
                            remembering that Jesus told his disciples, ''after this manner, therefore, pray ye. Our
                            Father, who art in heaven," etc.,I commenced the Lord's prayer in the most serious manner of
                            which I was capable, speaking the words slowly and deliberately, intending to say and to do,
                            understandingly. At this time, I heard a clear, distinct voice saying, "stop ! Do you pray
                            for the will of God to be done in earth as it is in heaven?" After a short pause I answered,
                            "I do." Mentor.Are you willing to do it? Answer.I am. Mentor.Then know that the business you
                            are following is not according to the will of God. Answer.What must I do, my family must be
                            supported ? Mentor.Did you not promise that you would obey the counsel you received, and now
                            you are reasoning about your family, as though God could not provide for you and your
                            family, if you have confidence in Him to trust them to his keeping. Answer.Yes, I did so
                            promise and I will perform accordingly, and from this moment myself and my family are
                            delivered over to his care, and as long as I feel as I do now, I will forever do so without
                            regard to consequences. I felt sure that this was the answer to my prayer, and have never
                            doubted it. I arose and went to my office and told a student to attend to all calls as I
                            should do no more business in that place. He purchased all of my drugs and medicines and
                            took the business, and from that day to the present, I have never practiced my profession.
                            After this unconditional surrender of myself and all I possessed unto God, my peace began to
                            flow again like a <pb n="59" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 59 river. I looked to God with a new
                            and pleasing confidence to which I had before been a stranger. I continued to enjoy the
                            association of my guardian spirit. Every day added to my stock of intelligence in regard to
                            my duties and the prospects of united association and intimate connections of men and women
                            under different modes of operation than those common in the habits and customs of general
                            society, opened before my mind with surprising clearness. I saw the many advantages and was
                            imprest to comprehend and appreciate the blessings which would ultimately flow from
                            well-ordered organizations until my mind would be wholly absorbed in the pleasing reverie.
                            My sphere of spiritual illumination was very much enlarged after my renunciation of my
                            business profession. I was enabled to see man as he was intended to be when the finishing
                            hand of Providence had taken off his inequalities so that he might become mild and docile.
                            He then looked as another kind of creature. His body became a combination of materialized
                            organs, the delight of which was in the use, and his mind resembled an individualized
                            element of good and formed to find delight in blessing others. The human family looked to me
                            as if in the good day coming it would fill up the measure of its pilgrimage in learning to
                            gain its ultimate destiny in filling its original character as the children of heaven and as
                            images of God. In this and similar modes of thinking time moved on for weeks and months, in
                            which I had no doubt nor uneasiness in respect to myself or family, although there was not
                            at that time the first sign of rational exertion to provide for our necessities, beyond that
                            which was already obtained. At this stage of my probationary travel I was strongly imprest
                            to visit a remarkable people who resided about forty miles distant from my home. The
                            impression was intense, but whether coming from my unseen instructor or not I never knew,
                            but felt his entire union with it. My intention was to visit them and learn for myself their
                            true character, and was determined to investigate their principles and practice with close
                            and critical attention. From the current reports in circulation in regard to the people in
                            question, there seemed no reason to expect much good, and I should maintain my religious
                            opinions with ease. I had no doubt on that subject and expected our labors to terminate in a
                            liberal use of words. However, being fully bent on going and having nothing on hand of
                            importance, I made the journey and arrived at the village a stranger to the people and to
                            their faith. As it was in the evening I found the family engaged in their religious service.
                            I was generously provided for through the night and had an excellent breakfast in the
                            morning. After the repast was over I was introduced to an aged man with a mild and placid
                            countenance. He received me with easy and marked politeness as one who knew the world and
                            was at home. I informed him of the cause of my visit, that I had called to investigate their
                                <pb n="60" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 60 THE MANIFESTO. principles and practice as they might deem it
                            advisable to communicate them. After the introductory preliminaries had been dispensed with
                            and our business before us, but a short time was required to open my eyes to the true state
                            of the case. The aged Brother with a mild, almost child-like gentleness opened more simple
                            truth in the knowledge of substantial good than I had ever heard in my whole life. Suffice
                            it to say that as the importance of his subject increased, his whole being assumed a fire
                            and intelligence I hardly ever saw equalled. It was in vain that I labored to neutralize his
                            reasoning, and contested step by step the propriety of his premises and the justness of his
                            conclusions. With mildness and the most prompt decision he showed the errors of my
                            sentiments and proved the correctness of his own. I soon found that there was more good
                            sense in listening than by presuming to call in question the beauty and moral excellence of
                            his convincing testimony. After becoming thoroughly acquainted with this important fact I
                            confined myself to asking questions. When I became completely satisfied and ever}7 objection
                            was removed, I addressed my venerable friend in this manner:My father, you have fully
                            satisfied my mind. I am convinced of the truth of your testimony and am thoroughly convicted
                            that you have kindly opened to my view the true and living way of life eternal. I henceforth
                            subject myself to your counsel and will abide by it. I beg your prayers for my spiritual
                            strength to increase, and I will strive honestly to learn the way of life and abide in it
                            forever. My aged friend replied,To love God above all things, and our neighbor as ourself
                            fulfills the whole requirement of both the Law and the Gospel. But we have no way to show
                            our love to God only as we show it to our fellow man, so that finally every gospel
                            requirement would be obeyed when we learned to do to others as we would wish them to do to
                            us. When this important principle of moral truth is gained, all the evils of existence will
                            be supplanted. Wars will cease, fraud and deception will be useless and the human family
                            will dwell together as harmless lambs in their Father's fold. The promises of the prophets
                            will be fulfilled and the long expected day of joy and gladness will spread abroad over the
                            earth. Have you counted the cost of the move you are making ? Are you prepared to encounter
                            the scorn and derision and even hatred of all the world. All of your friends and relatives
                            may consider you insane. They may be disposed to wrong you in your interest and spurn you
                            from their presence. All this you must expect and be prepared to meet, and in meeting it to
                            stand as firm as a mountain. All this you must take into account and consider and assure
                            yourself that you are man enough to face all of this or you had better never attempt it. You
                            may remember this, that although you have the whole world against you, yet you will have all
                            heaven to support you. I answered him with deep sincerity,If your testimony is true, and I
                            sol- <pb n="61" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 61 emnly believe it is, I am prepared to defy the
                            injustice of the world, and I will obey my conscience at all risks. He smiled approvingly
                            and then remarkt,Remember you must overcome the world in yourself by the "blood of the Lamb
                            and the word of your testimony." Remember that the blood of the Lamb is the life of the
                            Lamb. This harmless, peaceful life you must always live, according to the example of Jesus,
                            for he came as an example that we should follow. You are not called in bearing your
                            testimony to "cast your pearls before swine" as this would do no good, but if you can be
                            useful to a fellow creature by being a witness of the Truth do it fearlessly and fully. Let
                            no man alarm nor daunt you in the discharge of this duty. If you are faithful in your life
                            and consistent in your testimony, the God of Heaven will sustain you and will continue to
                            protect you through all time. When you know your duty, clear and full, you must do it. I
                            received into my soul the last lingering splendor of his setting sun. The rays made a sure
                            entrance, and there is no consideration within the scope of my knowledge that could prompt
                            me to forfeit my claim to his love and blessing by acting contrary to the spirit of this
                            divine precept. At this visit my destiny was fixt. I have never retraced my steps nor
                            faultered in my resolution, although I have met with all I was promist, the blessings of
                            heaven together with the persecution of friends and kindred. On my returning home I finisht
                            settling my business affairs, cancelled all claims and was gathered into the Lord's
                            vineyard, where I have resided in peace and quietness and had the satisfaction to see my
                            family gathered to the fold of Zion. And now, farewell, may the blessing of an indulgent
                            heaven be ever shining on your pathway through time, and may the pleasing smiles of an
                            approving conscience introduce you when the lamp of life is going out, into a spirit world
                            of harmony and peace. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What constitutes civilization?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT CONSTITUTES CIVILIZATION?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE gradations of human society ranging from the savage to the barbaric and upward to the
                            so-called civilized nations, are only comparisons illustrating the truth of the evolution of
                            man from types of life lower than any now existing. That he was created perfect and by
                            violating the laws of that perfect life, he fell from the estate bequeathed to him through
                            no effort of his own is absurd ; for if perfection had been attained which is only
                            comparative, retrogression would have been impossible. Superficially observed, our question
                            may appear absurd, but in the light of the events of the closing decade of the nineteenth
                            century when the struggle <pb n="62" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 62 THE MANIFESTO. to break away from certain
                            social and religious conditions transmitted from the past is nearing a climax, and the
                            allegorical conflict between the archangel and the dragon is preparing to be enacted in
                            human society on a scale far transcending any ever experienced, the perfect propriety of the
                            question must be admitted. The inventive genius of man is a powerful auxiliary to assist him
                            in his advancement towards a true civilization if rightly used ; ah, there is the rub; but
                            if not a powerful engine used for his own destruction. The art of print ing, the development
                            of the latent forces of steam and the electric power, and the many devices by which the
                            intellect has conquered the material world and compelled it to do homage are only a means to
                            an end, and not the final result. To those who are enjoying the political and religious
                            freedom of the present day, who would be willing to go back to the times of the Spanish
                            Inquisition and consider them civilized? When we read in military reports the expression,
                            "civilized warfare" we are led to exclaim "O consistency thou art a jewel" and the propriety
                            of our question becomes more apparent. That the past has transmitted to us conditions that
                            are fixed and eternal because founded upon truth is admitted. That the so-called
                            civilizations of to-day have attained to that development where they can claim a monopoly of
                            the truth over the older, we deny. The one-sided development that has been going on for ages
                            has had the tendency to make human character angular ; but thanks to the more civilized
                            methods in vogue the discordant tones are becoming less. We boast of our "modern
                            civilization.'' Hear what Emerson says,"Beware when the great God lets loose a thinker on
                            this planet." Then all things are at a risk. There is not a piece of sciencp but its flank
                            may be turned to-morrow ; there is not any literary reparation, not the so-called eternal
                            names of fame, that may not be revised and condemned. The very hopes of man, the thoughts of
                            his heart, the religion of nations, the names and morals of mankind are all at the mercy of
                            a new generalization. The artificial gradations of human society are transmitted from the
                            past, when physical force was the dominant factor that produced the apparent superiority
                            over the weaker, the stronger asserting the right to rule. The term artificial is used in
                            contradistinction of the normal faculties, the development in different individuals being
                            widely divergent. As the intellectual and moral faculties became more developed, wealth
                            which many times is accumulated through brute force or the ability to outwit his neighbor
                            became the cause that produced class distinction, with the different developments of the
                            intellectual powers, which it is the destiny of a true civilization to remove by eliminating
                            the conditions that make it possible for these artificial barriers to exist. The question
                            will be asked how will we proceed to remove those conditions that have existed so long that
                            the very fiber of human life is permeated with them? By efforts being made to educate the
                            lower types <pb n="63" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 63 and elevate them to the standard of the
                            highest. This is not a Utopian dream, but a condition of life that is capable of, and will
                            be realized to a greater extent as the race advances toward a true civilization. The
                            instinct of the race that caused it to care for its own exclusively, was probably necessary
                            in the lower phases of development. In that primitive state of society the social faculties
                            had not manifested themselves, but when the social instincts began to develop and take their
                            proper place as one of normal faculties, showing to man that he can not live for himself
                            alone ; that his individual interests are so closely associated with those of his fellows
                            that if one suffers the whole body feels the pain. Such examples as the reign of terror in
                            France should be evidence enough to prove that however high the intellectual and material
                            culture may be, that it is not civilization; and the enormous fortunes that have been
                            accumulated in a short time in America, giving a power to the aristocracy of wealth that is
                            causing combinations antagonistic to them; which is the logical result as the law of
                            self-preservation must be used to protect society against itself but contrary to the highest
                            feelings of a civilized life. While we have exercised adverse criticism in replying to
                            claims made by those who hold that civilization consists merely in the subjugation and
                            development of the material forces, we will now show on what lines an advancement is being
                            made toward that much desired goal. The settlement of the question regarding the right of
                            one human being to make a chattel of another, on the basis of the divine right of all
                            regardless of race or color, to life liberty and the pursuit of happiness which the nations
                            of the earth claiming the most advanced culture have succeeded in doing, removing a barrier
                            that prevented their onward march to a still higher unfoldment; has given evidence that
                            though at times temporarily retarded, they are moving along on the lines that will
                            eventually evolve a true civilization. The humanitarian principle, or the duty that devolves
                            upon human society to minister to and properly care for those whom nature has not endowed
                            with faculties enabling them to stand as equals with their fellow beings, or accident has
                            deprived of those powers, is organizing methods that go far to show that under the coarse
                            exterior there is a fountain fed from the eternal springs, that proves the divine unity of
                            humanity. Every hospital or asylum built and endowed where the wayfarer or traveler on
                            life's journey can find relief, is a beacon light illuminating the pathway which we are
                            traveling, toward that condition where the Divine commandment "to love the Lord thy God with
                            all thy heart and soul and thy neighbor as thyself," is practically demonstrated in human
                            life. This is Civilization. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pray for patience..." TEIform="index"/>Pray for patience...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Pray for patience; every day will bring something to call for its exercise.</p></div2><pb n="64" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder John B. Vance" TEIform="index"/>ELDER JOHN B. VANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>By Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p">THE sudden death of Elder John Bell Vance, of Alfred, Me., has reached us at an unexpected
                            moment. For many years he has been actively engaged in the financial and spiritual duties of
                            the Societies of Alfred and Gloucester. He held the office of a Trustee of the Community,
                            and was also a member of the order of Ministry, and through these several responsible duties
                            was known both to the Shakers and to those with whom lie held his business relations as an
                            upright and honorable man. While the friends in his religious home lose a very dear and
                            beloved brother, the town of Alfred also loses an honest and honorable citizen. His death
                            occurred on the 13th of March, at his own home, surrounded by his nearest and dear friends.
                            He was confined to the house but a few days when the best medical aid learned that
                            strangulation of the intestines would prove fatal in a few hours. Elder John was born in
                            Baileyville, Me., May 9, 1838, and came to the Community at Alfred, Sept. 14, 1838. At the
                            age of 16 he commenced the keeping of a District school in the Society, and has followed
                            that occupation more or less, to the present date. At the age of 20 years he was appointed
                            an Elder in the Novitiate Order, and in Jan. 1872 he entered the Order of Elders in the
                            Church family, and earned the endearing appellation of a father and a friend by all who came
                            under his kindly ministration. On the 19th of March 1884, at the death of our beloved Elder
                            Otis Sawyer, he was appointed to the Order of Ministry and occupied that office at the time
                            of his death. The funeral was held on Monday the 17th inst, at 2 o'clock p. m., in the
                            family dwelling of the Church. The services were under the direction of Br. Henry G. Green,
                            and were very pleasantly and satisfactorily conducted. Br. Henry made an appropriate
                            introduction to the Believers and to the many friends of Elder John who had come by
                            invitation to attend the last, loving duties that could be given on such an occasion. All
                            the Brethren and Sisters of the Society were present, also Elder Joseph Holden, of Mt.
                            Lebanon; Elder John Whiteley, of Shirley, Mass; Elder Henry C. Blinn, of East Canterbury ;
                            Elder William Dumont, Eldress Lizzie Noyes and Sr. Prudie Stickney, of Sabbathday Lake,
                            Maine. After the singing of the first hymn the twenty-third Psalm was read which produced a
                            very pleasant impression. Following this a few remarks were made by Elder H. C. Blinn, after
                            which several hymns were sung and remarks made by Elder Joseph Holden and the other
                            visitors, and also by many of the Brethren and Sisters. Two or three articles, especially,
                            written for the occasion were read very distinctly before the meeting, and kindly
                            appreciated by all who were so fortunate as to be the privileged hearers. <pb n="65" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 65 These interesting services continued for about one and one
                            half hours, when the assembly was dismissed, and all were invited to step into another
                            building and see the dear Elder in his prettily arranged casket. Most of those who attended
                            the funeral service, accepted this invitation, and were deeply interested in the neatness
                            and care that was exercised in its preparation. A near and dear friend of Elder John by the
                            name of Goodall of Sanford, sent a variety of very choice flowers from his conservatory, and
                            these were all tastefully arranged in and around the casket. A writer in the "Daily Eastern
                            Argus" makes this pleasant reference, "In the death of Elder Vance, the Society loses a
                            member that makes a vacancy that can not be filled, and the entire Community mourn with us.
                            His removal deprives Alfred of a townsman whom everybody loved and respected, and the state
                            of a citizen who did everything in his power to promote the peace of the commonwealth." East
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks of mother Lucy Wright, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS OF MOTHER LUCY WRIGHT. NO.
                            1.</head><p TEIform="p">WE find that when there is much hand labor to be performed, there is a liability to exercise
                            less of the spirit of true thankfulness, as the mind appears to be absorbed largely in
                            temporal duties. When we meet that which seems a cross, we may feel that there is less cause
                            for thankfulness; but when we realize to what blessings we have been called, it is easy to
                            feel thankful. We should ever feel grateful that we have health and strength of body, to do
                            our daily duty. When it conies the close of the week, or nearing the Sabbath, temporal
                            duties should become secondary, giving only the needful attention that all things may be
                            done well, thus preparing the mind for the worship of God. We are blest with the greatest
                            privilege that can be bestowed upon the children of earth. We have a knowledge of the way of
                            God, and how to obtain victory over a sinful nature. We are called by the gospel to be
                            simple and meek; to live in love and in union with the spirit of Christ, and lay aside all
                            evil speaking and all unkindness, and learn to bless each other. Those who bless will be
                            blest. Those who harbor a party spirit, mar the house of God. They do harm to the Church of
                            Christ. "A party or partial spirit is forever rejected by the gospel of Christ." The sense
                            of man seems to be so absorbed in temporal things that there can be but little room or
                            desire for the gifts of God. So long as the mind craves so much of the earth, it may be all
                            right that we should be hurried and have as much, and even at times more than we find time
                            to accomplish. <pb n="66" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 66 THE MANIFESTO. We can not feel that the true spirit
                            of thankfulness is gained that should be, if there are any who would not thankfully lay down
                            their natural lives rather than give up their precious faith in the gospel of Christ. This
                            kind of spirit will cause us to labor for the good of each other and not find pleasure in
                            another's faults, distresses and mistakes. We would rather possess a spirit of sympathy,
                            desiring all to be restored in the spirit of meekness. After a lengthy discourse on various
                            matters that seemed to burden the spirit of Mother Lucy, she said, "Father Joseph often
                            taught us that all who were gathered into this Order, were called to be exemplary in all
                            things, temporal and spiritual. We are sometimes fearful this may be forgotten. We should do
                            right, let others do as they may. The use they make of our example will not justify or
                            condemn us. Addressing the youth and children she said, "You must not expect to please
                            yourselves with every fancy. You have a privilege to learn the way of God, and if you are
                            obedient and retain your minds in their innocency, you will be far more beautiful than the
                            loveliest flowers of the earth. The number will always be small who will choose the narrow
                            way, but there will always be enough to condemn the world. We had rather be with the few who
                            are pure in heart, than with the great majority who are of the earth, earthy. Numbers are
                            not the object in which to glory, but purity and holiness of heart. We do not feel a lack in
                            numbers; but the great lack we realize is of gospel grace. We are only strong as God is with
                            us. The gospel is equal to the demand of this day : all will receive according to their
                            labor and desire. Those who are faithful to take up their cross, will be glorious in their
                            generation. Each one will receive according to his works, both good and evil. If it were not
                            so we should have more reason to complain that the gospel is not just. If any one feels a
                            lack, we know the cause is in himself, for the gospel is sure and true. If one half of those
                            who are present are not faithful to their knowledge of the way of God this need not weaken
                            our trust in the gospel. Who can want to save the nature of the flesh, or even would desire
                            to have it sanctified? "To be carnally minded is death." That which is unholy can not enter
                            the kingdom of heaven. We desire that all seek for a baptism of divine truth, lest we become
                            so absorbed in the things of this world that they spring up and choke the Word of God in our
                            hearts and it becometh unfruitful. {To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who advises or encourages..." TEIform="index"/>He who advises or encourages...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He who advises or encourages young persons to use tobacco, whiskey, opium or beer is sowing
                            to the wind, and will inevitably reap the whirl-wind.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contrition often knocks..." TEIform="index"/>Contrition often knocks...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Contrition often knocks at the door of the heart, but, like an undesired guest, receives no
                            welcome.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. S.</byline></div2><pb n="67" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. APRIL, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the "United
                            Society op Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued regularly by
                            the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the religious
                            views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all communications
                            to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. February. Thermometer. Bain. Snow. 1895. 20.18 0 in.
                                24 in. 1896. 24.69 2.75 " 25 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 50 above 0 Lowest " " " "
                                20 " " Number of rainy days '' " 2 " " snowy " " " 12 " " clear " " " 4 " cloudy" " " 11
                                C. Q. Reed. Center family. March, 1896. Some time has elapsed since we have offered the
                                least contribution to the Manifesto, and now we have but a few items. While I write a
                                furious storm is raging without, giving a reminder that March does not promise an early
                                spring; we hope however for better weather when this month shall have passed. I am much
                                pleased with the last Manifesto; some of the articles are very interesting, not the
                                least of which is the one by Sr. Aurelia G. Mace. Others are good but I was especially
                                pleased with this as it gives voice to the testimony of Jesus the Christ and Ann the
                                Christ. It is absolutely necessary for us as a people that we keep this testimony before
                                the world and in our own homes, otherwise the spirit of the world will overshadow ns.
                                There is danger of our laying down the weapons of our warfare. "Let your light so shine,
                                that others seeing your good works may glorify your Father which is in heaven." Light is
                                shining all over the civilized world, not only spiritual light but scientific and all
                                that relates to man in the whole physical domain and we need to keep abreast of all
                                truth whether natural or spiritual. Light is sown for the righteous, and joy for the
                                upright in heart. The redemption of man can be brought about by the cross of self-denial
                                only; this will make us strong and powerful for good and whether there be few or many
                                living as Jesus Christ and Mother Ann taught and lived, such will be a mighty power for
                                good in the earth. Timothy D. Ray son.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. March, 1896. "Stormy March has come at last." Whether it will be a month
                                that represents the character given it by the poet, time will tell; but the promise that
                                was given of old of "seed-time and harvest," is true as the lengthening days announce
                                approaching seed-time. February closed its record with a heavy rain flooding the ponds
                                and creeks and covering the adjacent lowlands with water. To all the lovers of flowers
                                the beautifully illustrated catalogues of the seedsmen with their varied collections,
                                furnish an abundant source from which to supply those wants and satisfy the taste for
                                the beautiful that every normally developed TERMS. <pb n="68" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 68 THE
                                MANIFESTO. human being is endowed with, and of those who come to our table none exceed
                                in their collections the publication of James Vick's Sons, Rochester, N. Y. How truly
                                the poet illustrates the love for the beautiful in the following lines. 'And with
                                child-like credulous affection We behold their tender buds expand ; Emblems of our own
                                great resurrection, Emblems of the bright and better land." We think that the sick man
                                had the best of the Deacon, and was justified in not accepting the offer for prayers,
                                hope the testimony will go forth so strong against the filthy habit of tobacco using
                                that it will become obsolete. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 189G. Hakd colds, accompanied with long, tiresome coughs have been in market all
                                winter and many have had occasion to regret unwise bargains made in that line, but
                                winter has not always shown its gloomy side; just enough clouding to make the light
                                spots brighter and give more pleasing contrast to the picture. Three times the large
                                double sleigh, headed by two wide awake horses, held in check by Br. Ira's skillful
                                hands, has taken a company out to test the merits of the glistening, white snow. Perhaps
                                it is too late to talk about the holidays, but it is one of the bright spots in our
                                memory. On Christmas evening, a brief Entertainment was given, followed by a magic
                                lantern exhibition, and last, but not least, the famous tree presentation. This
                                resembled a captive queen, as one and another of its pretty ornaments were bestowed on
                                eager waiters until, left entirely destitute, its skelelon fingers shamed all partakers
                                of so cruel a plot. Some two weeks ago we enjoyed a day of social and mental profit,
                                with our North family friends who visited us, after which we would place the time worn
                                phrase, "To be continued next month." Our family dwelling has been improved by the
                                addition of cypress wood doors at the main entrance and at the meeting room. So through
                                the coming years we shall have no trouble in welcoming friends to our house and home, as
                                they will swing easily on their new hinges. From the busy hum of the saw and tho
                                appearance of the wood yard, we infer that a whole tribe of our mountain hermits have
                                been taken from their homes and are rapidly being changed into forms of usefulness. A
                                few days of warm weather thawed the ice and snow, and then a severe cold blast froze its
                                smooth surface until the yard is a path too smooth for mortal feet to tread. To look
                                downward we see nothing but the dangers of the ice, but raise our eyes and we discern
                                many forms of marvelous beauty. Every twig glistens with tiny jewels and each branch is
                                encircled with diamonds, while the depending icycles look like silvery fringes in the
                                sunlight. So it often is. If our eyes be continually fixed on the realities of life, we
                                grow unconscious of the beauty around us. The thoughts become engrossed with care, while
                                just above us, and beautifying all around are the jewels of mercy depending for our
                                comfort and benefit. Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1896. "To be carnally minded is death, but to be spiritually minded is life and
                                peace." If we keep our hearts pure, our aspirations holy, our thoughts mild and humble,
                                our souls ever opened heavenward, we shall be enriched with the fruits of the Spirit,
                                which are peace, joy and love. Let us breathe more of the pure air of heaven, and be
                                strengthened by the sweet songs of peace the angels sing. Denying self makes peace. Let
                                us hope on though we meet with discouragement. We have the same God and heaven and
                                truth; the same duties and the same helpers. Let us hope in God. Let us be courageous
                                and noble- <pb n="69" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 69 minded; our own heart, and not other
                                men's opinions of us form our true honor. Duty can not be neglected without harm to
                                those who practice as well as to those who suffer the neglect. "The Cathedrals of
                                England were many years in building. Bristol Cathedral surpasses all others, 522 years
                                having elapsed between its commencement in 1306, and its completion in 1888. ****** *
                                Time intelligently given to poultry will pay equally well with that given to any other
                                kind of farm work, and where too many are not kept it may be done at such times as not
                                to interfere with other important work. Outside of any pecuniary benefit it pays well in
                                furnishing fresh eggs for the family. Daniel Orcuit. South Family. March, 1896. We have
                                experienced a remarkable winter, in that we have had some of the coldest and warmest
                                weather known in any one winter. It will be a very hard season on new seeded land, for
                                which the worst condition is this constant freezing and thawing; which is also bad for
                                the sick. We note the absence of snow; the warm heavy rains we had lately caused the
                                Connecticut to rise higher than in thirty years. We hear at times several song birds
                                whose notes gladden our hearts at the sound of prospective spring. Experience has
                                demonstrated that such a winter is often followed by a late spring. An Ornithologist
                                informs us that some rare birds have been seen in this neighborhood lately;notably, two
                                Lapland longspurs or Greenland Nightingales, a bird which breeds near the shores of the
                                Arctic ocean and sings on the wing. These birds were seen in February; Savannah, and
                                tree sparrows, Eed-winged blackbird, kSnow Bunting, Red-poll Downy wood-pecker, Brown
                                creeper, White bellied nuthatch, Eed-tailed and rough-legged hawks, Murgauser,
                                Chickadee, and Butcher birds. Now a very interesting question presents itself to the
                                bird lovers, namely, Will the Bluebirds return in strong force this spring? Last winter
                                thousands were destroyed by the unusually severe winter in the south. We would ever be
                                thankful for the blessings we enjoy. Maria Witham.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1896. The wheels of time have whirled us along through zero's cold, blinding
                                stoims till we now have the "windy month" attended by all its disagreeableness; yet
                                Nature is not only grand, but beautiful in all her moods. With what interest we watch
                                the snowflakes descend; how varied their crystal forms. When meteoric conditions
                                fluctuate between rain and freezing, and both try for the ascendency, then every tree
                                and shrub is encased in glittering armor that when the sun's rays fall upon them they
                                sparkle as though hung with diamonds. Winter and spring are now contestants, each
                                striving for the ascendancy. Our wood is nearly housed and preparations are being made
                                to secure some of the sweets from our beautiful maples. Br. Ezra Newton, our centenarian
                                is very feeble in health and may not remain with us much longer. Occasionally an
                                inquirer calls for a few days and then goes his way. We hold ourselves in readiness for
                                whatever God has in store for us. Marcia M. Bvllard.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossa, Florida" TEIform="index"/>Narcoossa, Florida</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1896. We have been much strengthened by the presence of Elder Joseph and Elder
                                Isaac for three weeks past. During their sojourn Elder Joseph broke up the first four
                                acres at our central station on the lakes, and worked with us three or four days
                                clearing the high and dry hammock on the lake which includes about twelve acres. We tore
                                up trees, and roots, and <pb n="70" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 70 TK E MAN I FES TO. piled for the fire,
                                over a surface of about three acres. Elder Isaac returned to help us and drove our mules
                                the last day we were blest with their able help. Our garden filled with all northern
                                productions is in thriving condition, collards, raddishes and lettuce for the table, and
                                sometime before this meets your eye we shall have new potatoes and sti'ing-beans. We
                                have a beautiful green pasture of rye for our cows. Our 130 peach trees planted Dec. 24,
                                have made six inches growth and look healthy. The 1C65 pine-apples as a whole look
                                wholesome, but are partly quiescent in cool weather. Our tomatoes have been, and are yet
                                to be; the winter crop is past. Corn and melons planted since the Brethren's sojourn
                                with us are putting forth briskly since we were blest with about an inch of rain, Friday
                                the 2*7th ult. Meadow-larks take the whole if they can get it. We are in better hope and
                                experience from this winter's work. I think it is as good a country and land, as lies
                                upon the globe, when we learn to adapt ourselves to it. Every tiling raised in the north
                                can be raised here in the winter, and melons, peaches and oranges will produce without
                                fail. The cross, the cross is just as hard to bear to those who do not want it here as
                                in a more northern climate, but the yoke of Christ is easy and his burden light
                                everywhere. Henry Hollister.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">March, 1896. While we are aware that the time draws near for Home Notes, we can think of
                                nothing but the happenings of the past week, and these every newspaper in New England
                                has described, therefore all there is left for us to tell is,"The rains descended and
                                the floods came and the winds blew," and beat upon our home and it fell not for it was
                                founded upon a rock. During the eight days of fearful storm we were saved from
                                disaster,held, as it were, in the hollow of God's hand. Indeed, we feel grateful for his
                                Omnipotent power that so kindly shielded us through danger. Who was not glad to see the
                                brave "Toil On" which the Feb. Manifesto announced to its readers? Your efforts are
                                appreciated, beloved Editor, and we in t!;e east, have all concluded to "Toil On" with
                                you, thanking God that the Believers are still able to publish our paper. Our aged
                                Sister, Mary Jane Jones has happily passed to Spirit life. She had been feeble for a
                                long time and one morning when we little thought of death, took her departure. The fear
                                of death she did not know, The grave had lost its sting! Triumphant now, o'er all below,
                                With the redeemed she'll sing. Ada S. Cummings.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Sister A---:--You are welcome..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Sister A---:--You are welcome...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Florida, Narcoossa, May 1896" TEIform="index"/>[All of our readers will be interested
                            to hear from the dear friends in Florida, who are zealously engaged in that land of flowers
                            in building a religious home. Ed.] Nakcoossa, Fla. Mae. 1896.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Sistek A- - - - -:You are welcome to our home and hearts. How good of you to come and
                            see us in spirit. I hope you may not forget to come often. Now we will step out on the
                            veranda and have a little chat. What do we see? Six large banana trees throwing out their
                            great leaves, four feet long and twenty-one inches wide. From these we may expect a crop the
                            coming year. The lawn is covered with Bermuda grass. Our flower garden has a sparce
                            sprinkling of verbenas, pinks, lilies and roses, and all these are in bloom. At our right
                            are two strawberry beds, in bearing, and a small patch of sweet potatoes. Just south of this
                            is a pine grove. It is sown to rye and is now beautifully green. Our two milch cows enjoy
                            feeding there some hours, daily. You will observe our pineapple orchard contains not less
                            than 1000 plants. We anticipate a crop some time next year. All our Florida friends who have
                            visited the place say that "the old growers can't <pb n="71" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 71
                            beat it." By this we feel quite encouraged. We have a small section for sugarcane, one for
                            cabbages, one for raspberries, and one hundred banana trees in good condition, some may bear
                            fruit next year, others the year following. Here is a field of Irish potatoes in bloom and
                            by and by we expect a supply of Florida grown Irish potatoes. A section is devoted to the
                            growing of Cassava. It is up and looks well. It is very much like the white yam so largely
                            raised in the West Indies. It is considered good for table use. Our peach orchard contains
                            130 trees. Less than one year since, this ground was covered with a grove of tall pines.
                            These have been cut down and their roots taken from the ground. Our garden has a variety of
                            vegetables, and we are now having a supply of radishes, lettuce, greens, etc. We will now
                            pass into the house. The dining-room occupies a central position. The sleeping apartments
                            are on the west side and a sitting room on the east. Our room for cooking is so arranged
                            that we do not have the heat and smoke in the dwelling. We have a well and a pump attached,
                            also a good water tank. As we have no cellar, our milk and various other things share the
                            cool breeze. Our yard is covered largely with Bermuda grass. In the flower beds we have
                            gladiolas, tulips, hyacinths, lantavas and hybiscus. Some of these are in full bloom. We
                            have also in another section orange, plum and persimon trees, twenty-five of each variety.
                            We have a new barn with sheds attached, also a yard for the hens, and all about these are
                            groves of pine. We are anticipating a permanent residence at a future date, some two and one
                            half miles distant from our present home, on the shore of Alligator Lake. It is a beautiful
                            place. Lovingly Your Sister</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, M. L." TEIform="persName"/>M. L. Reynolds.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who loveth most..." TEIform="index"/>Who loveth most...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Who loveth most is nearest kin to God?</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of Elder John Vance" TEIform="index"/>In Memory of Elder JOHN VANCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, Eva M." TEIform="persName"/>By Eva M. Libbey.</byline><p TEIform="p">Lo, an angelic reaper, Hath borne from earth away, The spirit of our father, To dwell in
                            endless day; Where hosts of shining angels Await with outstretched hands, To welcome our
                            dear Elder To that bright and happy land. His life was one of blessing While journeying here
                            below; He was loving and forgiving, And did to each one, show A spirit of true patience, Of
                            charity and love; He was blessed with holy wisdom That cometh from above. He gave his life
                            for others, Nor did one moment spare For selfish ease or pleasure, But every thought and
                            care Was for his gospel kindred, That they might safely be Guided through all dangers, On
                            life's tempestuous sea. A life of self-denial He taught from day to day, And on from simple
                            childhood He walked the narrow way. O may his pure example Be our guide while dwelling here,
                            As the upward path we travel May we feel his presence near. And now beloved father, Thy
                            blessing o'er us spread As a mantle of protection, And as our daily bread. Farewell, we all
                            shall miss you, Grief and sorrow fills each heart; May we meet again in heaven Never more
                            from peace to part. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God measures souls..." TEIform="index"/>God measures souls...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">God measures souls by their capacity for entertaining his best angel, love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilcox, Ella Wheeler" TEIform="persName"/>Ella Wheeler Wilcox.</byline></div2><pb n="72" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No one will deny..." TEIform="index"/>No one will deny...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"No one will deny that eating animal flesh stimulates the passions, and gives vigor to
                                that kind of life which finds gratification in sensual indulgence, and in asserting the
                                power of brute force.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bradbury, H. A." TEIform="persName"/>If. A. Bradbury in World's Advance
                            Thought.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spinal difficulties" TEIform="index"/>SPINAL DIFFICULTIES.</head><p TEIform="p">Few things are more common among the young of modern times. Dr. Warren of Boston thinks
                                about one half the young women, whom he called "well educated,1' but he should have said
                                fashionably educated, are affected with some degree of distortion of the spine. Their
                                minds are filled with learned lore as a bottle is filled with liquid. The deformity is
                                not wholly unknown even among boys. Those who have round shoulders, frequently have
                                crooked spines.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Alcott" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Alcott.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pure air and hearty foods" TEIform="index"/> PURE AIR AND HEARTY FOODS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Those attacked with and suffering from acute diseases should be allowed
                                        little or no food. Tanner fasted forty days. A thousand die of gluttony to every
                                        one of starvation. Feed the fevers of the young with water only. But not so with
                                        consumption or any of the wasting diseases. These require pure, dry ail-, and
                                        hearty nourishing, yet easily digested foods. The breathing of pure air remarks
                                        Oswald: "The breathing of pure, cold air may come to be a luxury, like the
                                        drinking of pure, cold spring water. 'I might as well try to sleep in a sack,'
                                        said my little boy in the stifling atmosphere of a Pullman sleeper, 'let's tell
                                        the crazy nigger we can't live without air, and go back to a car where we can
                                        open a window.' " Lung curing fat and grease need, indeed, not be derived from
                                        slaughtered animals, and a Hindoo consumptive would probably as soon lie down
                                        and die as to try the plan of an emaciated young lady ' whom I once saw drink
                                        two pints of oxblood at a Cincinnati slaughter-house. She assured me that the
                                        ghastly specific had snatched her from the brink of the grave, but good cream,
                                        rich milk, fresh butter or olive oil would have served her purpose as well, if
                                        not better. Drinking the blood of slaughtered animals is a barbarous, beastly
                                        business. There is already enough of the animal in the human.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Mackintoshes and Rubber Clothing large commissions can be earned by retailing to users.
                            Sample free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1871 New York.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Watch in the night" TEIform="index"/>A WATCH IN THE
                            NIGHT.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by A. G. Hollister.] Oppressed by something in my troubled sleep I, with a moan, awoke in deep
                                    despair; Was it some daytime duty left undone, Or was it some forgotten kiss or
                                    prayer? ] Something it was that made my pillow hard, Something my heart around or
                                    soul within; I rose and looked across a night as dark, Yes, darker than the fearful
                                    face of sin! Close, clo: e at hand a midnight taper burned, L knew it as the lamp of
                                    my fierce foe; I leaned far outhe could not help but hear 'Friend,' forgive thee
                                    every hurt and blow! " Down on my knees I fell and prayed for him Who wrong had done
                                    me many times and oft; And as a star shone through a rifted cloud, I sought my couch
                                    and found the pillow soft!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Independent" TEIform="index"/>Independent.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brooks, Lucinda" TEIform="index"/>Lucinda Brooks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Lucinda Brooks, at Enfield Conn. Jan. 10, 1896. Age 58 years and 9 mo. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jones, Mary Jane" TEIform="index"/>Mary Jane Jones
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Jane Jones,
                                at Sabbathday Lake, Me. Jan. 21, 1896. Age 84 years, 7 mo. and 20 days. Sr. Mary has
                                been a faithful, toiling Sister. A. G. M.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vance, John B." TEIform="index"/>Elder John B. Vance
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Elder John B. Vance, at Alfred, Maine. March
                                13, 1896. Age 62 years, 10 mo. and 4 days.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
pany any one on a visit to the Moon, to its
mountains, its rivers, its lakes and then introduce you to the good people who reside there.
Every month a storm diagram is published
in Word and Works and the reader can study
at his leisure what may be expected to happen during that term of days. An abundance
of interesting articles may also be .found in
the paper, telling us of the heavens and the
earth, and of our duty to God and man.
Published by Word and Works Co. 2201 Locust Street, St.Louis, Mo.
The Journal of Hygeio Therapy. February. Contents. The Science of Life; Nerve
Harmony; Songs; Tobacco; New Testimonies
against Drugs; Medical Science; Wm. Tebb
(portrait;) The Antitoxin Remedy; An Ap.
peal for money; Phenology, etc., etc.
Dr. T. V. Gifford & Co., Kokomo, Incl.
The Phrenological Journal of March
comes out in a new and enlarged form. It is
now under the Editorial management of Edgar
C. Beall, M. D.
The Magazine will still'be published by the
Fowler and wells Co., 27 East 21st St. New
York City.
The subscription price will be $1.00 per annum. Under this change of management the
Phrenological Journal anticipates an increase in circulation. "The well known members of the old Company, while relinquishing
certain official duties in the business administration, will continue in their professional
capacity as heretofore."
The new Magazine abounds in interesting
and instructive articles, as have I.he former
numbers, and is liberally and beautifully illustrated for the clearer elucidation of the
many subjects that are presented.
Address Fowler & Wells Co., New i'ork City.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title of a neat little pamphlet ol
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Holljsteb of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearl
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
m sum cquuit.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS    OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
he same  time, afford instruction to all  inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
HUMAN NATURE
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per    year,    devoted   to   PHEEN0L0GY,
PHYSIOGNOMY, HEALTH, MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEP0EM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, Cal.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OB1   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
Largest circulation of any scientific paper fn the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it.    Weekly, $3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address, AfTTNN & CO.,
Publishers, Uiil Broadway, New York City.
A cream of  tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Eoyal Baking Powder Co.
106 Wall St., N. Y.
Popular Science
NEWS
Nature, Invention,
Botany, Electricity,
Chemistry, Medicine,
Hygiene
HEALTH
formerly BOSTON JOURNAL OF CHEMISTRY
Enlarged and Improved
MI
Good reliable men, to sell
our Choice ami Hardy
Xursery Stock such as Fruit
Frees, Roses Shrubs ami OrContains a large number of Short, Easy,
Practical, Interesting and Popular, Scientific
articles, that can be Appreciated find Enjoyed
by any intelligent rea ier, even though he
knew little or nothing of Science.
Profusely  illustrated  and  Free
from Technicalities
nauientals. Toadies make this business a success. JTCasy work, pleasant, light and profitable. Outfit Free. Apply at once, with references, and secure choice of territory.
F.  1ST.  M.A.Y   COMAPANY,
Nurserymen  and   Seedsmen,   Roches,
ter. 3ST. Y.
Newsdealers, 10 cts.   $1.00 per year
4g~Mention this paper for a sample copy.
Largest Circulation of any
Scientific Paper in the World.
PUBLISHED  MONTHLY  BY
BBNJ. LILAKD, New York.
POUR
By Pressing the lid.
SKETCHES OF SHAKERS
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society   of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.   .Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avert.
Price,  15cts.
Tea and Coffee Pots tiuu pour by the lid without lifting or tipping.     Simple beyond belief.
Practical and artistic.   Send for pr.mplilet.
THE ASBU1?Y=PAFNE MFG. CO., Phila., Pa.
This is a good tiuinjlid.
<pb n="" id="p21"/>
The Old Rocking-Chair.
BY T. C. HARBAUGH.
It stands over there in the corner alone,
The varnish is cracked and one rocker is gone;
What's left of its tidy is dusty and brown,
And scattered and silent its fringes hang down;
No songster appeareth to warble its praise,
When we were but children it saw its best days,
And many a face that was rosy and fair
Eeposed after play in the old rocking-chair.
How often from it in the Winter nights cold
The tale of the fairies by nurses was told!
How often we listened with kiss-bedewed brow
To a lullaby strain which I hear even now;
Aye, back from the past with its sunshine and
shade
I hear the sweet sound that the old rockers made;
And now while I listen I willingly share
The loves of the years with the old rocking-chair.
She rests where the roses their love-vigils keep,
Who fondly and tenderly rocked me to sleep;
But still when I look in the corner, I trace
Within the old rocker a well-cherished face;
The years that have vanished no more to return
But deeper the joys of a childhood in urn;
And thus doth the past, with a halo most fair,
Re-crown with its beauty the old rocking-chair.
No longer to music, now fast and now slow,
At morning and evening it rocks to and fro;
No more from its depths where sweet memories
throng
With an angelic touch comes a lullaby song;
It is covered with dust, but the dust cannot hide
The prints of the hands that will ever abide
Upon the old arms so reposeful and fair,
When memory turns to the old rocking-chair.
<pb n="" id="p22"/>
SOMEBODY'S MOTHER.
AS RECITED BY ADOLP'H J. JACKSON'.
The woman was old, and rugged and gray.
And bent with the chill of a Winter's day :
The streets were white with a recent snow.
And the woman's leet with age were slow.
At the crowded crossing she waited long,
Tostled aside by the careless throng
Of human beings who passed her by.
Unheeding the glance of her anxious eye.
Down the street, with laughter and shout,
Glad in the freedom of "school let out,"
Come happy boys, like a flock of sheep.
Hailing the snow piled white and deep ;
Past the woman, so old and gray,
Hastened the children on their way.
None offered a helping hand to her,
So weak and timid, afraid to stir,
Lest the carriage wheels or the horses feet
Should trample her down in the slippery street
At last came out of the merry troop
The gayest boy of all the group ;
He paused beside her, and whispered low,
"I'll help you across, if you wish to go !"
Her aged hand on his strong young arm
She placed, and so without hurt or harm,
He guided the trembling feet along,
Proud that his own were young and strong ;
Then back again to his friends he went.
His young heart happy and well content.
She's somebody's mother, boys, you know.
For all she's aged, and poor and slow ;
And some one, some time, may lend a hand
To help my motheryou understand ?
If ever she's poor, and old and gray.
And her own dear boy is far away."
"Somebody's mother," bowed low her head,
In her home that night, and the prayer she said
Was :   "God be kind to that noble boy,
 Who is somebody's son and pride and joy."
Faint was the voice, and worn and weak,
 But heaven lists when its chosen speak ;
 Angels caught the faltering word,
 And "Somebody's Mother's" prayer was heard.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>