<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0508" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><date value="187508601" TEIform="date">August 1875</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">57-64</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="57" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">Vol. V. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. Editor. Mt* Lebail-O:o- Ool. Co. N. Y. August, 1875 No. 8. Sixty Cents per
                        annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jewish history" TEIform="index"/>JEWISH HISTORY</head><p TEIform="p">"In Christ are hid all the treasures of Wisdom and Kuovvledge." These things were written for the admonition of
                            us, upon whom the ends of the world have come. The history of external Israel is as a shadow or chart of the
                            history of the New Creation, or Spiritual Israel. The first class of Israelites, born in Egypt, carried with
                            them Egyptian proclivities — old habits, appetites and passions, inherited and acquired. By the marvelously
                            wonderful Spiritual phenomena witnessed in Egypt, through the rnediumship of Moses and Aaron, those proclivities
                            were suspended, and afterward held in check by continued exhibitions of Divine power, throughout the forty years
                            travel in the Wilderness. The cloud by day, and the pillar of fire by night, went before them, from their
                            passage of the Red Sea, to their passage, dry shod, over Jordan. In both instances the waters stood in heaps,
                            ready to overflow them the moment the power was withdrawn; that first appeared to Moses in the burning bush,
                            that was not burned ; in a stick that became a serpent, but was not a serpent, that swallowed other serpents
                            that were nothing but sticks in the hands of the Egyptian Media. The ten plagues were Spiritual phenomena. The
                            two spheres touched each other and interblended. As were the Egyptian Media, so were Moses and Aaron, with this
                            important difference : Higher and purer Spiritual Beings — Gods — inspired Moses and Aaron, than were those
                            inspiring the Egyptian Magi. They had objects to accomplish — plans to carry out — in relation to Israel, as a
                            nation, and through Israel, as a medium, in relation to the whole race of man upon earth. Time was an element in
                            their programme ; and Numbers were used by the succeeding Prophets of Israel as evidence of the existence of
                            such general plan, or design, framed by some thinking, calculating, intelligent being, or beings. The whole
                            Jewish and Christian world acknowledge this element of time, however much they differ about the day and hour, or
                            the manner of accomplishing the promises, and of fulfilling the prophecies. The first class of Israelites, who
                            came out of Egypt, all died in the Wilderness, except two, Joshua and Caleb. These received the revelation of
                            the Second Coming Degree of the Jewish System, and they led the generation, born in the Wilderness, into the
                            Land of Promise. The Spirit — God of Israel — had two visions of that first class. One was, that they were a
                            chosen and peculiar people — Saints of the Most High — a Royal Priesthood to all coming generations of the Jews.
                            The other, that they were a rebellious, murmuring, unbelieving, stiff-necked, wicked generation, with whom God
                            was not well pleased. And this, from the day that Moses and Aaron knew them, until Joshua and Caleb finished
                            burying their carcasses, in the Wilderness, that had fallen according to the curse pronounced upon them by their
                            God, whom they had wearied by their importunities, and grieved by their everlasting back-sliding toward the
                            Egypt from which they were only externally delivered. Their old habits and propensities were like the Leopard's
                            spots. Yet, what a change they underwent in their diet and manner of life! It was from one great extreme to
                            another. In Egypt, their labor w«,s excessive, and their food, its fleshpots. Now, their food is Manna —light
                            food — that their souls loathed, and drink corresponding — pure water — nothing more. The change that awaited
                            them, when over Jordan, was equally unexpected and trying to their Spiritual Faith and physical systems. Instead
                            of the land in common, their food in common, and their clothing unwearoutable, and shoes that would not wax old,
                            the Manna ceased to fall, the shoes and garments did wax old, and henceforth, if they did not work, neither
                            could they eat. To this end, in Canaan, the land was divided, to each a portion, and only by industry and
                            economy, could they eat the fat thereof. Two orders of people were founded — the generating Jews, and the
                            Essenes, who held their land in common, did not marry, would not fight, and ate no flesh of animals, clean or
                            unclean. The product of this order was the Son of Man — Jesus — the ultimate fruit of the Essene tree. He became
                            the cornerstone of the first temple — the Primitive Church — of which the Temple of Solomon was a type. The
                            other order — the generating Jews — progressed on, down the ages, until incorporated in the Roman Empire. Church
                            and State were then combined, like Adam and Eve, when first created — the Spiritual and temporal— generation and
                            regeneration—the whole race evoluting toward the second appearing of the Christ-Spirit, when the mystery of God
                            would be finished by the final separation of Church and State, and the founding of a true order of generation,
                            having a civil government, free from theology, based upon the first principles of the Mosaic law of holiness in
                            earthly things — the rulers, male and female — the land, held for all to work and live from — their diet, the
                            fruit of the soil, free from blood-shed — the relation of the sexes, free from the unfruitful works of darkness.
                            Thus are the two orders now started. The United States, and the United Societies. The Spiritual will ultimately
                            separate from the natural, and the natural will be entirely separated from the Church, in the United States
                            government. The First Degree of Seven, was a Wilderness state. That first generation are nearly all gone. A few
                            of them, like Joshua, have the revelation of the New, or Second Degree. The Canaanites, to be driven out, are
                            the anti-christian sects, who have monopolized the land, which must yet be divided unto the people of the
                            country. They have raised fat Jiogs, rather than fine men and women. They live upon the lives of other
                            creatures. In their generating — their sexual relations — they are lower than the animals they slaughter for
                            food, and who, in turn, slaughter them, by diseases that they generate in their physical bodies. Eternal
                            warfare, with Amalekites, was the law of Israel, external. And eternal hatred of the carnal mind, with all its
                            lusts of the flesh and spirit, is the privilege and duty of members of this Zion of God. It is their right to be
                            in continual communion with the saints and prophets of all ages and races — to be baptized with the Christ of
                            God — the Rock of Ages, which always responds when struck by the wand of truth, sending forth the living faith
                            of the redeemed, in the Heavens, to the struggling saints on earth. Better to be in communion with the true
                            actors of the scenes of the past, now in the Spirit World, than to depend entirely upon the history that
                            imperfectly describes those scenes.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and the world" TEIform="index"/>THE CHURCH AND THE WORLD</head><p TEIform="p">As members of the great family of man, we have one common ancestry, are imperfect and have need of boundless
                            charity, and of improvement in every righteous direction. WTherein, then, do members of the true Church of
                            Christ differ from the unchristianized citizens of the world ? Just here — The former, having been baptized with
                            the Christ-Spirit, have had their intuitions quickened and inspired and possess a consciousness of a divine call
                            to higher, purer and more spiritual condition, and to the necessity of attaining it by every facility vouchsafed
                            to them through the power of God. They are fortunate in having the invitation before others perhaps equally
                            worthy. There is, therefore, no reason why such should arrogate, to themselves, superiority over others not thus
                            favored, except by obeying their superior calling and conforming to a higher standard of righteousness. The
                            followers of Christ are commanded to be separate from the world. This enjoining does not refer to external
                            habitations only. Some may have availed themselves of this external isolation for sordid purposes, continued in
                            iniquity, and been a curse to themselves and to society. All members of Christ's Church are under <pb n="58" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 58 SHAKER A.ISTI3 sacred obligation to a life of righteousness, purity and charity, surpassing
                            those who are not favored with like facilities. This is an interior work—a discipline which church members must
                            keep in vital activity in all places and under all circumstances. Souls are not worthy of the name of Christians
                            — Shakers — unless they live such life all the time and everywhere. Although I incessantly and earnestly bear
                            the Cross of Christ, and thank God for the great salvation from sin that I enjoy, I do not thank him in the
                            sense of a pharisaical righteousness that I am not as outside publicans. On close examination I find I have not
                            yet attained that high standard of purity and righteousness — that redemption of soul from the nature of sin —
                            which the spirit of progression is continually pointing me to. Professed members of Christ's Church, who feed
                            their sensual appetites and passions with narcotics — opium, tobacco in any form, beer, wine, cider, any
                            stimulating or stupefying beverages— should not arrogate, to themselves, great perfection of separation from the
                            world. It is precisely on this physiological platform of self-denial that the Church of Christ, as an
                            institution of progression, should cease to blend with the world. To mingle with outside society for the purpose
                            of ministering the Christian testimony, or to transact necessary business, may be consistent with that
                            separation from the world which characterizes the true Church of Christ. Neither Jesus nor Ann was afraid thus
                            to mingle with the publicans, sinners and magdalens of their day, and break to them the bread of life. A soul,
                            who lives in purity and charity, and moves in obedience to his or her spiritual directors, cannot be injured by
                            the society of the world. Such are able to minister virtue and avoid contamination. There is suffering in the
                            Church of Christ for want of laborers to disseminate its principles in the field of human society. For still the
                            harvest is truly great, and the laborers are few. Should they not, even now, be passing and repassing over the
                            great harvest field of the world, reaping where angel hands have sown ? The Shaker and Shakeress is doing what
                            it can, and is evidently instant in season in its efforts to reach the popular heart and conscience. Let us not
                            cease to pray the Lord of the harvest field to send forth more laborers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton, UnwiiVillage, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Public materialization" TEIform="index"/>PUBLIC MATERIALIZATION</head><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, June 15,1875. Horatio Eddy &amp; Co. — Esteemed Friends : I have been impressed that the time
                            has arrived when Spiritualism should begin to do to Humanity the good designed by the Powers Above.
                            Materialization is the second step in Spiritualism— the second Degree. There will be seven Degrees. A public
                            meeting, in some great city, where the speakers — part of them — were materialized, would begin a Religious
                            Revival as much exceeding that got up by Moody and Sankey, in England, as Truth exceeds Error, or substance its
                            shadow. Will you co-operate with me to bring this about? If so, on what terms, and under what conditions 1
                            Please confer together, and, if at all disposed to entertain my proposition, consult the Ruling Spirits. As
                            educational preparation for the great undertaking of meeting the American Public, how would you feel about
                            coming to M't Lebanon and holding some seances here, in conjunction with our people ? Would not the influences
                            here be in every respect favorable ? Could we not form a battery, composed of your natural Mediumship, the
                            Shakers' acquired practical Spirituality, and those controlling Spirits, in the other world, who have the whole
                            movement in charge ? In this work, should you, as Media, the Ruling Spirits, as Motors, and the Shakers, as
                            Substrata, or working force, all concur and agree 'to confer together, and work together, ] suggest that we
                            invite some of the leading minds, in the Spiritual movement, to join with us in the public meeting. I address
                            you first, upon the subject, as 3eing, in my estimation, the first Media in the known world. You may lay this
                            letter before such of the Spirits as you recognize as the highest — most divine — authority, with whom you
                            associate. In kind, respectful regard to yourself and Spiritual household, I am your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chittenden, Vermont, June 20, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Chittenden, Vt., June 20, 1875</head><p TEIform="p">Friend Evans, This is our location at present. We are held here, by the bands that control in our seances, for a
                            purpose known only to the Powers that control us. We shall wait their bidding. Should they desire us to go to
                            Mt. Lebanon, or anywhere else, we are ready. We trust in all their movements, knowing full well they will do all
                            things right, and keep us where they can get the most power, and do the most good. Let the Spirits make their
                            own conditions, and the world will be convinced of the power of Immortality, as fast as they are prepared to be
                            convinced. Should we, on this side of the Spiritual or Spirit world, make conditions for the Spirits, there
                            might be many pull-backs. We are not permitted to make any arrangements to go away from here, at present. Best
                            wishes from your friend, in the cause of truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eddy, H. G." TEIform="persName"/>H. G. Eddy</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Letter from the editor of 'the Sun'" TEIform="index"/>LETTER FROM THE EDITOR OF "THE SUN"</head><p TEIform="p">New York, June 14,1875. Friend Evans, I don't know that I have ever expressed the sentiment to you, but it is
                            proper that I should say frankly, that I have no personal conviction that materialization is a true thing.
                            Neither do I care very much whether it is true or not. I have no idea whatever that witnesses from beyond the
                            grave are of any value as teachers of Spiritual Truth. T*ruth must stand on its own merits, and if it were
                            uttered by ten thousand spirits, it would not be a whit more true than when uttered by one man in the flesh.
                            Having said this, I will say that such a meeting as you propose would be immensely interesting and important. If
                            it is really possible to produce a spirit from the other world in the appearance of an ordinary human body, and
                            to have this spirit address an audience, the fact would produce an extraordinary excitement. Nothing that could
                            occur, I suppose, would so deeply impress the minds of people in general; and, if it is practicable, I can see
                            no objection to undertaking it. As for defraying the expenses, there would not be the slightest difficulty in
                            having that done over and over again, by charging a small fee for admission ; but a considerable force of police
                            would probably be necessary to preserve order. Yours sincerely,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dana, Charles A." TEIform="persName"/>Charles A. Dana</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, June 16, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, June 16,1875</head><p TEIform="p">Charles A. Dana — Esteemed Friend : Your note of 14th instant, is to the point. I did not suppose that,
                            individually, you believed materialization a verity, or that to you, Truth would be more valuable for being
                            uttered by a Spirit. You are a sensible man. Are not old men for wisdom and history? If Moses and Elias were
                            materialized to Jesus and Apostles, two points were made — First, that they did exist, and could prove it;
                            Second, being older, by many hundred years, than any earthly man, they were more valuable, for history, than two
                            new books. To me, the natural law of materialization is an interesting scientific fact. I expect to instruct
                            materialized spirits, not to be instructed by them. But the materialized spirits may be inspired by spirits
                            superior to themselves. Should we hold a meeting, as I propose, I hope to accomplish two objects. First, by the
                            Mediums we will bring with us, to materialize Spirits from the other world, who will appear as ordinary men and
                            women, and speak to the audiences. Second, by the Spirits we will bring with us, to inspire the speakers thus
                            materialized, so that they shall utter truths of great importance and of the highest order — truths that will be
                            of practical use to society and to the attendants of said meeting. A smith may work cold metals — he prefers
                            working them at red heat. Excitement with human beings is as heat or fire to metals. To be baptized with fire
                            and with the Spirit of Truth, is to receive Truth — Spiritual Truth — under excitement. Will not Wisdom be
                            justified of her children, if materialization be a means to a good end ? Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Father Evans:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Father Evans :</head><p TEIform="p">I have read your Autobiography through with a great deal of interest. It has given me a better idea of your life
                            and work, and of many things connected with the Shakers than I ever had before. Your conversion to Shakerism and
                            your labors for the good of humanity, in various reforms, will be better appreciated when many of your ideas on
                            other matters are better understood by the mass of the people. I never heard the Book of Revelations so
                            satisfactorily explained as you have explained it. Whether your views be correct, or not, I have seen no
                            explanation so applicable. Although many years of my early life were spent within a few miles of the Sonyea
                            Shakers, I never knew much of their belief, nor of what they were aiming to do. Your religion is practical — not
                            theoretical. It goes to the bottom of things. It is calculated to revolutionize every thing in society. The
                            present system of Marriage would be changed — the present system of Laws would be changed -— Society would be
                            reorganized — Churches, Schools, every thing, would be revolutionized. In fact, it seems to me, you would make
                            one grand smash-up of things in general. And what is the object of all this? Would the Shaker programme make the
                            world better and happier ? Would it rid the world of disease, crime and sinners ? Would it do away with
                            premature death, poverty and other evils, to which the human family are subject, under existing conditions ? I
                            always supposed, that if the Shaker programme was fully carried out — the sexes not allowed to come together for
                            procreative purposes — that the earth would, in one or two generations, be depopulated entirely. I could see no
                            way in which human life could be prolonged, unless you show that Shakerism would bring physical immortality to
                            those who adopt it. If, by joining the Shakers, physical immortality could be secured — the last enemy, death,
                            be destroyed, or overcome — I could see strong attraction to Shaker society. Could you demonstrate the
                            possibility of such result, you would soon convert the whole world to Shakerism. But thus far, Shakers die as
                            well as other people, and I am not aware that the average of human life is much greater, with them, than with
                            the gentile world. The New Cycle, which I learn from you, the Shakers are about to enter upon, will offer
                            something of a very important character for the consideration of thoughtful minds. The division of the human
                            family into three or four orders, in which all, but the most robust, live celibate lives, will prevent the
                            propagation of sin, disease and misery. Such propagation has gone on long enough. 'Tis high time sinners,
                            criminals, diseased and deformed persons stop reproducing their kind. We have, already, more than enough of that
                            kind of humanity on the earth. Has not society the right to compel the criminal, the diseased and deformed, to a
                            life of continence —if need be, to take from them the power to reproduce their likeness ? 'Twould be better for
                            them, and better for society. They have no right to curse the world with marred types of humanity. It is a
                            legitimate subject for governmental supervision. The first thing required is a class of men, for Rulers, who are
                            masters of themselves — men and women in whose organization the in- <pb n="59" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKERESS. 59
                            tellectual and moral forces are paramount, controlling all lower law influences. No man nor woman is fit to make
                            Laws, administer them, or in any waf govern or control others, who has not sovereign control of his and her own
                            spirit and passions, so as to do right for the love of right. When our public offices are filled with the right
                            material — Law makers and Law administrators whose lives are devoted to Humanity's Elevation — Society's wrongs
                            will be righted. I see much in Shakerism that commends itself to my judgment. The intellectual and social life
                            of communities could be made very pleasant. 1 never could see the use of the uniformity and monotony in your
                            style of dress. Why not give to each a certain amount of money and let them dress to suit their own tastes ?
                            Nature loves variety. She never tries to duplicate herself. As your Drugfactory has burned down, why not use
                            that force to cultivate flowers and fruits for market, and to beautify your homes — making them so attractive
                            that every body will want to live with you ? God has made flowers, birds and fruits, in such variety of beauty,
                            color, plumage, flavor and odor, that it seems to me we should cultivate, use and enjoy them See what beauty and
                            grandeur are in the sunlit clouds ! in the variegated landscape ! in the mountains ! in the forests, and in the
                            rainbow ! Why not adorn your homes with copies of these also, and make those homes the Paradise the whole earth
                            is to become in the Millennial Age ? You have the germs of that happy time. With perfect bodily health, the
                            right kind of mental, moral and social surroundings, I fail to see why Shakers cannot begin the Millenial Age.
                            Yours with great respect,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Miller, E. P." TEIform="persName"/>Dr. E. P. Miller</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, June 17, 1875" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, June 17,1875</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend Miller : Your highly valued letter of the 14th is at hand. Let me get an article out of it for the
                            Shaker and Shakeress. It is too good to lie idle in my desk. I shall use it, unless you say nay. About the
                            flowers and all that, there is no difference in principle. But about dress, you are intoxicated with the wine of
                            Babylon. Your world's women are horridly ugly — no beauty about them — while Shaker women are the glory of the
                            earth, and when materialized, at the Eddys, as they are, are admitted by all to be beauty incarnated. Your sense
                            of beauty is perverted. It will come right, if you have a care of your diet. Beauty rests upon utility. Also, we
                            are only in our First Degree of the Seven. Let us alone until we grow up to the Ornamental. We want first to "
                            clean escape the corruptions that are in the world through lust." Then, in this our Second Degree, we want to be
                            freed from all physical diseases. We shall then have occasion for flowers, instrumental music, and cause for
                            Ornamentation. Sin, painted, is one of the most detestable of sights. When I look at world's women, bedecked
                            with jewels and loaded down with dry goods, I keep thinking of the ills that female flesh is heir to, in this
                            day. They should dress in " sack cloth and ashes," so that the inner and outer might agree. Am always pleased to
                            hear from you. Kind regards to your family, to friend Train, and to all friends.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you are well, let yourself alone..." TEIform="index"/>If you are well, let yourself alone...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If you are well, let yourself alone. One of the great errors of the age Is, that we medicate the body too much.
                            More persons are destroyed by eating too much than by drinking too much. Gluttony kills more than drunkenness in
                            civilized society. The best gymnasium is a wood yard, a clearing, a corn field. A hearty laugh is known the
                            world over to be a health promoter; it elevates the spirits, enlivens the circulation, and is marvelously
                            contagious in a good sense. Bodily activity and bodily health are inseparable. If the bowels are loose, lie down
                            in bed, remain there and eat nothing till you are well. The best medicines in the world are, warmth, abstinence,
                            and repose.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Telegraph" TEIform="index"/>THE TELEGRAPH</head><p TEIform="p">In 1837, a year or two before Morse's discovery of the magnetic telegraph, two of the girls in the Second Family
                            of Shakers at Watervliet, N. Y., were in Vision, as it was called. Unconscious of mortal surroundings, they lay
                            on a bed in the east end of a long room, called the T room. The room was literally packed with standing
                            spectators, witnessing the thrillingly interesting phenomena. The door of entrance was at the opposite end of
                            the room. I came in late and seated myself near the door. The girls could not possibly have seen me, had their
                            eyes been open. They had gone to a far distant city, in the Spirit World, where they met Mother Ann, with whom
                            they had, in their Spirit World excursion, frequently met and become familiar. They were now conversing as if
                            all girls together. I spoke not a word, but simply thought, how can they make their todies talk, when so far
                            away as they claim to be ? The girls ceased talking, as if listening. Presently one of them said : " Mother,
                            some of the folks at home wonder how we can make our bodies talk when we are so far away." After apparently
                            listening to the response, she said: " Mother says, it is not we that make our bodies talk. It is our Guardian
                            Spirits, who remain with our bodies, to keep the vital action, while we are gone." I thought, how can their
                            Guardian Spirits get their words so readily ? The girl seemed to listen, then said: " Mother, the folks at home
                            wonder how our Guardian Spirits can get our words so readily." After apparently listening, the girl said — or
                            the Guardian Spirit said: "Mother says she don't know that she can make you understand that. It is by a kind of
                            telegraph that we have in this world. You have nothing like it in your world now, but will have before long." At
                            the date aforesaid — 1837 — Telegraph meant an agreed upon flag, or other signal. We were subsequently informed,
                            in manner aforesaid, that Dr. Franklin, whose favorite amusement, here, was halter-breaking lightning, when in
                            the next world, succeeded in harnessing a similar power, to the mailstage there, and that the facilities by
                            which we are now enabled to talk around the world, in almost less than no time, are the materialization of what
                            had pre-existence in the Spirit World. It may be so with all our modern inventions — the inventor being the
                            medium of transmission. Some inventions may be the re-materialization of lost arts.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., O." TEIform="persName"/>O. P., Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialization vs. materialism" TEIform="index"/>MATERIALIZATION v. MATERIALISM</head><p TEIform="p">The star of " materialization" is in the ascendant just now, and thoughtful people are gazing heavenward with
                            wonderstruck eye. And well they may, for this new constellation, glorious and bright, bids fair to eclipse with
                            its splendor all the lesser lights that surround it; and the boasted inventions, discoveries and achievements of
                            this steam and iron age, compared with this latest marvel, sink into insignificance. Faith in the hereafter is
                            the very basis of religion ; and joyfully 1 hail "materialization," because I believe it is a weapon which, in
                            the hands of the angels, will destroy that soulstunting materialism that now rules a cold intellectual age. Even
                            skeptics must accept the evidence of their senses, and worshippers at the shrine of reason dare not deny logical
                            conclusions. If spirits can be handled, and weighed, and recognized, and can give conclusive proof of their
                            identity, the inference is plain : — the spirit world exists, and communication between it and the earth is a
                            possibility — truths which are indeed needed to warm and cheer the fainting hearts of the sons of men. I have no
                            theory to advance upon the subject. I have not, as yet, accurately determined the limits of spiritual forces,
                            and admit that, to me, the accretion by a spirit of a physical body is no whit more wonderful than the growth of
                            the tiniest plant. That which is unfamiliar we are apt to consider marvelous. I think it was Bishop Berkeley who
                            taught the subjectiveness of all phenomena, and the impossibility of proving the existence of any thing outside
                            of our consciousness. I am at no pains to dispute this position, because the vast majority of people do believe
                            in the material substantiality of their surroundings. When they see a man they are content to believe it is a
                            man, and when they meet a mad bull, they carefully get out of his way, for fear of the very forcible and
                            disagreeable fancy of being tossed on his horns. To such, I say, the evidence is strong that many spirits do
                            appear in bodies as real, material and substantial as our own. But I anticipate the skeptic's sneering and
                            ironical assent. It does, indeed, seem to be incontestible that mediums do occasionally deceive, and that
                            manifestations are sometimes simulated. But a hundred frauds can never annihilate one genuine manifestation,
                            occurring under rigid test conditions ; whereas one genuine manifestation is a complete offset to a thousand
                            bogus Katie Kings. The fact that Brother Thomas Smith and Brother Daniel Sizer, at the Eddy homestead, did
                            actually see and recognize departed friends — materialized forms that were visible to all present — is worth
                            more than volumes of erudition and finished essays proving "materialization" a fraud and a delusion. To me, it
                            is a comfort to feel that the spirit-world is near, and that spirits are concerned for the welfare of humanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Hewson" TEIform="persName"/>Hewson Brown, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Visit to the Eddys" TEIform="index"/>VISIT TO THE EDDYS</head><p TEIform="p">Kind Editor Shaker and Shakeress : Thursday, April 22d, found Brother Daniel Sizer and your correspondent at
                            Chittenden, Rutland county, Vt., the home of the much talked of Eddy brothers, mediums for spirit
                            materializations. Presuming a short sketch of the facts seen, heard and felt would be of interest to many
                            readers of your paper, I herewith tender the following account. Chittenden, like many old settled New England
                            townships, consists of a few straggling farm-houses, built near the most fertile spots of rough looking hills.
                            The particular house, made notorious by these materializations, is a plain one, standing a few feet back from
                            the road, with some claims to modern additions in the shape of an Ell, running back from its center some 40 ft.
                            with width of 20 ft., two stories high. The upper room of this addition being devoted to the spirits, is entered
                            by a door in the back center of the old house. Its one large room is entirely unfurnished, with the exception of
                            a stove, three or four common chairs, two long rough benches, a common table with leaves 4x2 ft., on which are
                            placed various common musical instruments — violin, accordion, harmonicon, tin horns, bells, etc. At farther end
                            of this room the floor is raised 2 ft., forming a platform 4 ft. wide by 2 ft. high, running the width of the
                            room, and inclosed by a low railing, except at south end, where are steps. The cabinet is on this platform, and
                            is formed by taking the space from the chimney (which stands in the center of back wall) to north side of
                            building, inclosed with lath and plaster partition, leaving door space next to chimney, forming a room 8x2 ft.
                            The doorway is covered by an old blanket, hung on hooks at upper end. This evening, April 22d, there are
                            eighteen persons present from various portions of this country and Canada. We assemble in the seance room at
                            7-J- p. m., taking seats on the benches, the majority being on front bench, they joining hands. Wm. Eddy now
                            enters the cabinet, while his brother, Horatio, takes a seat among the audience and plays upon a violin,
                            accompanied by any one who can sing the various melodies — old religious hymns, spiritualist songs, ballads,
                            negro melodies and sentimental songs. <pb n="60" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 60 8HAKEE In the course of five or ten minutes the
                            curtain moves aside and there stands a spirit, so called. Presently the spirits step out on the platform, walk
                            around, dance, speak, rap, materialize pieces of cloth out of nothing visible, call up some of the audience to
                            feel of them, dance with them, etc. The light in the room, in the meantime, being a common kerosene lamp,
                            burning at half light, then again turned up to full blaze, and held within 10 ft. of cabinet door, showing every
                            feature as plain as daylight, color of hair, eyes, skin, clothing, every thing indicative of one's personality.
                            Our first seance lasted fifty minutes, during which time my watch lay at my side, face open, and with pencil I
                            noted the appearance of each spirit, time out, and length of time between their retiring into the cabinet and
                            the appearance of another spirit. The shortest time being one and a half minutes. Fifceen different forms, of
                            various sizes, appear this evening, some Indians, characteristically dressed in colored bead-work, belts, caps,
                            leggings, etc., and a large proportion of the others recognized by different parties present as relations, etc.
                            We attended four of these seances, with audiences varying from eight to twenty-four persons present, some
                            constantly coming and going. In these four seances, forty-five different spirits made their appearance, all of
                            whom were recognized by some one or other present. Some were able to speak ; those seemed to be the most
                            successful in doing so who had been materialized a number of times. Among the many occurrences interesting to
                            the spectators, because of some personal peculiarity, deformity, or circumstance connected with them, allow me
                            to mention a few. A woman and her husband, of high social position and liberal means, form part of the audience
                            before whom a spirit shows himself, a young man of twenty-five or thirty, with beard on lower part of face,
                            dressed in black, whom they recognize as a nephew, called Charles. He waiks back and forth on tlie platform,
                            showing peculiarities of gait, build and dress, answers questions by raps and speech. At second appearance, he
                            moves forward to railing and reaches his right hand out, beckoning to the woman to come forward, which she
                            timidly does, extending her right hand, which he grasps with his right, and while shaking her hand, pats the
                            back of her right hand with his left hand. This is in plain sight and audible to the whole company. Again, a
                            woman appears who is recognized as Ellen, a niece. Inquiry is made if her little child of three years is
                            present, and can materialize. Affirmative response, and she retires into cabinet, to again appear in a few
                            minutes, leading a little child at her side, whom she turns around, lifts up in her arms, bends down and kisses
                            three times in a motherly fashion. Each person present receives tokens of recognition. Aside from the
                            materializations, we attended one each of the light and dark seances. In the light circle a curtain is drawn
                            across the corner of room, behind which a table is placed, covered with the various musical instruments. The
                            medium sits in a chair placed in front of curtain, some one selected from the audience sits beside him, with one
                            arm bared to the shoulder, which the medium grasps with his hands. A blanket is now pinned around them both,
                            leaving only their heads in view. The man's free hand is now thrust out of the blanket and held by some one of
                            the audience. Immediately music begins, bells ring, horns blow, a guitar is thrust beyond the curtain in full
                            view and played upon, horns are thrown over the curtain, hands appear and stroke the faces of those present,
                            patting them, pulling their beards, etc. A pencil is taken by the spirit-hand and various signatures and
                            messages written out upon cards, which are thrown out, together ¦with various instruments, among the audience.
                            Two one-quarter inch iron rings, of diameter sufficient to slip easily on upper arm, are next taken by the
                            spirit-hand, and instantly the man next to medium finds them on his bare arm, without the medium moving his
                            hands ; all this while the large kerosene lamp stands at full blaze between the aiidience and medium. In the
                            dark circle things are somewhat different. The medium, occupies a chair in the center of the floor, some six
                            feet from the audience, one of whom ties his hands behind him with a rope, which is again secured to back of
                            chair in which he sits ; this is done as firm as ingenuity can do it. A man now takes his seat in the medium's
                            lap, at the same time holding the hands of another person, who sits in front of him, but who might be supposed
                            to be an interested party to the performance. The light is now extinguished. Then begins a medley of sounds,
                            table moving and thumping, bells ring, voices speaking through trumpets, and finally playing upon instruments
                            tunes descriptive, of a storm at sea. Suddenly the instruments seem to be in all parts of the room, flying
                            through the air, performing in concert the only music, worthy the name, which we have heard. This is very
                            harmonious and pleasing, purporting to be a welcome of some parties to Spirit-land. In the midst of it comes a
                            crash, and all is still as death for a moment, when some one remarks, " You have broken the circle, by releasing
                            hands," which proves incorrect. A noise now commences as of a number of men running around the room, dancing,
                            whistling, whooping, stamping, playing rough music, which continues ten minutes, when the spirits, speaking
                            through the trumpet, say that a company of wild Indians had taken possession of the place and drove away those
                            who were performing. The lamp is now relit, and the musical instruments found in different parts of the room,
                            with mediums tied as at first, and in same place. Cord examined and found all right. Light extinguished, when
                            the spirit welcome is finished — verses are improvised by spirit voices, on any subject selected by those
                            present. A short lecture delivered, various questions answered, and seance concludes. Among the spirits who
                            materialize is a woman, whom they all seem to venerate, known as the Witch of the Mountains. She comes upon the
                            platform with a quiet dignity, speaks in a clear incisive tone, pointedly and to the purpose, rising to
                            eloquence in her language and delivery, teaching the highest moral lessons, and always making a deep impression
                            on her hearers. On one of these occasions, when we were present, she spoke for ten minutes in a voice loud
                            enough to be heard two hundred feet, by a large audience. She made the statement, that within five years it
                            would be a common occurrence for spirits to speak from the rostrum, to meet friends in their homes and in the
                            street, and be as familiar as mortals. She has made the assertion that it will be done at Chittenden, in broad
                            daylight, in 1875. An incident of our last seance may be of interest to many. There appeared a Shaker sister,
                            whom the audience recognized as a Quakeress, while we knew her as one of our sisterhood, who departed many years
                            since. She answered many questions, and was succeeded by another sister, who had deceased only a few months, who
                            also answered questions. They were both unmistakably dressed in full Shaker costume, even to cap and
                            handkerchief. This of course was very satisfactory to us — their names, Mary Ann Patterson and Martha Poole —
                            special friends. I have met many, since our visit, who were anxious in their inquiries, and all evidently
                            interested in some form or other. To those, who have not seen or heard, queries numberless present themselves,
                            as to the reality and meaning of it all. I unhesitatedly pronounce the materialization genuine — a reality. Its
                            morality does not seem to be a point in the case at present. It is an open avenue through which comes a stream
                            of human souls, vividly suggestive of society here good, bad and indifferent, without any, at present, apparent
                            object in view, but the satisfaction arising from a re-union with earthly friends. As to the meaning or
                            possibilities in the case, I hazard no opinion, for they seem illimitable. Here is a new force developed, unique
                            and without precedent in the realms of science — a force evidently capable of changing the whole face of
                            society. New channels of thought open, and new modes of revealing to human beings the hidden secrets of God and
                            nature by means of which the creation of new heavens and a new earth — a re-organization of all mundane
                            institutions—-is reduced to a mere matter of time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Smith. Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to eat" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO EAT</head><p TEIform="p">BEFOivEaman becomes hungry, watchful nature has calculated, in her way, how much nutriment the body needs, and
                            provides as much of a liquid substance as will be necessary to prepare from the food which may be eaten, that
                            amount of sustenance which the system may require. When this is stored up and all is ready, the sensation of
                            hunger commences, and increases with the steadily increasing amount of the digesting material just referred to,
                            and the very instant the first mouthful of food is swallowed, this "gastric juico" is poured out into the
                            stomach through a thousand sluices; but no more has been prepared than was necessary, for nature does nothing in
                            vain ; so that if a single mouthful more of food has been swallowed than the untempted or unstimulated appetite
                            would have called for, there is no gastric juice for its solution, and it remains but to fret and worry and
                            irritate for hours together. If the amount eaten is much in excess, the stomach, as if in utter discouragement
                            at the magnitude of its task, ceases its attempts at digestion, and forthwith commences the process of ejecting
                            the unnatural load by means of nausea and vomiting in some cases; in others, it remains for an hour or more like
                            a weight, a hard round ball, or a lump of lead, an uneasy heaviness; then it begins to " sour," that is, to
                            decompose, to rot, and the disgusting gas or liquid comes up into the throat, causing more or less of a scalding
                            sensation from the pit of the stomach to the throat; this is called " heart-burn." At length the half-rotten
                            mixture is forced out of the mouth by the outraged stomach with that horrible odor and taste with which every
                            glutton is familiar. In some cases the stenchy mass is passed out of the stomach downwards, causing, in its
                            progress, a gush of liquid from all parts of the intestinal canal to wash it with a flood out of the system;
                            this is the "diarrhoea" which surprises the gourmand at midnight, or in the early morning hours, when a late or
                            overhearty meal has been eaten. When sufficient food has been taken for the amount of gastric juice supplied,
                            hunger ceases, and every mouthful swallowed after that, no gastric juice having been prepared for its
                            dissolution, remains without any healthful change, inflaming, and irritating, and exhausting the stomach by its
                            efforts to get rid of it, and this is the first step toward forming "dyspepsia," which becomes more and more
                            deeply fixed by every repeated outrage, until at length it remains a life-time worry to the mind, filling it
                            with horrible imaginings, and a weary wasting torture to the body, until it passes into the grave. The moral of
                            this article is, that the man who forces his food, he who eats without an inclination, and he who strives by
                            tonics, or bitters, or wine, or other alcoholic liquors, to get up an appetite, is a sinner against body and
                            soul —a virtual suicide! — Hall's Journal of Health.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>HEALTH</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Shaker and Shakeress : Much might be said and written on the subject of health. We should consider the
                            health of the soul as well, or even more, than the health of the body. If we transgress the laws of nature the
                            body has to pay the penalty, and it is just that it should. If we transgress the laws of God the soul must pay
                            the penalty. It behooves us, therefore, to watch; be careful what we eat and drink, that our bodies may be a
                            healthy abode for a righteous soul to dwell in, as the body and soul are so closely connected now, until this
                            body shall have ended its course; then let us think how are matters with the soul. The soul that sinneth shall
                            die, was, and is and forever will be the irrevocable decree of the Almighty. All men have sinned and fallen
                            short of their duty ; and the 144,000 who stood on Mt. Zion with the Lamb had all been sinners, but now are
                            without fault, etc. O, what a happy and cheering thought that the way is now opened that sinners may return, for
                            now is come salvation and strength and the kingdom of our God and the power of his Christ. Then let us begin the
                            reform now, to-day if ye will; let us have a healthy soul and body ; let us cut off all that is offensive to
                            either ; let us cut off all unnatural stimulants, should it even be as dear to us as the right eye or arm, or
                            even no matter how long we have been accustomed to them ; let us all be new creatures in Christ, and let the
                            time past suffice to have lived after the course of the world; but now let us come out and be separate. I am
                            ready, willing and anxious for a step forward, upward and onward for ever.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kulp, Jacob S." TEIform="persName"/>Jacob S. Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><pb n="61" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: persecution, idolatry, infidelity" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: PERSECUTION, IDOLATRY, INFIDELITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">It may be much easier to define Persecution — to portray its spirit and animus — if not to fix its boundaries —
                            than to decide what is real Idolatry or Infidelity, when adjudged at the high court, where Justice and Truth are
                            the arbiters. Persecution has its root in the wild raging passions of men, in the war spirit, —under the guise
                            of religious zeal—and is fed from the same source, vain ambition, bigotry, superstition and the lust of power
                            and dominion. The heathen nations, and the ancient Jews, were great warriors; and although the Jews sought the
                            aid, and claimed the protection of their God in their battles, they were not as intolerant in regard to
                            religious opinions as their descendants. Pagans, Mohammedans, and the great variety of Christians (so called),
                            have all their peculiar gods to worship, each pitted against the other, who, like Saul of olden time, have
                            thought they were doing God service in persecuting and torturing one another for opinion's sake. Religious wars,
                            of all others, have been the most ruthless and unrelenting. The bloodstained pages of history reveal the sad
                            fact, that millions of human beings have been subjected to physical and mental anguish, to force them to accept
                            opinions repugnant to them, and when that did not effect their purpose, death, in its most cruel form, was
                            inflicted by those who had the power. Such the fruit of Church and State synthesis. Constantine, the first
                            Christian emperor, made it a penal offense for a Christian to become a Jew, and forbade Pagan worship in any
                            form. He razed their temples to the ground, and the Fathers of the Church eulogized him for bis edicts against
                            Pagan worshipers. He held the balance of power in his hand, and made the sword his arbiter. Augustine claimed
                            the sanction of the Old Testament scriptures, when he passed sentence of death upon those who celebrated certain
                            rites, which, but a short time previous, had been tolerated. Multitudes were branded as heretics, and suffered
                            death in its most agonizing forms, under the pretense of defending the Christian religion ! It is recorded that
                            the worship of images cost five hundred thousand lives. The doctrine of Transubstantiation four hundred thousand
                            more. The persecution of the Manicheans, instigated by Theodora, resulted in the sacrifice of one million lives
                            in Greece alone. Their great crime consisted in believing there are two eternal principles. One, light,
                            representing good ; the other, darkness, representing evil. The great loss of life by Crusaders is estimated at
                            five millions. Moshein says, that the " European nations were deprived of the greatest part of their
                            inhabitants. For centuries, the fairest portions of earth were reddened with human blood, and strewn with human
                            skulls." Pagans, Catholics, Heterodox, Schismatics and Protestants, all, when they have had the power, were sure
                            to use the sword, the gibbet, the dungeon and the rack, in the name of God. We learn from history that the
                            Catholics slew thirty thousand in one day, and when the leaders of the massacre could no longer discern their
                            own people from the heretics, the Pope's legate cried with a loud voice, " Kill on; God will know His own."
                            Buckle states, that about one million of the most industrious inhabitants of Spain were hunted like wild beasts,
                            and thousands were butchered on the road to Africa. How many thousands of Jews have been robbed, plundered,
                            hanged, head downward between dogs, burned and impaled, while priests, directly or indirectly, have conducted
                            the slaughter, will probably never be known until the recording angels shall open the great Book laid up in the
                            archives in the unseen land of light, where all false coverings are removed, and things are called by their real
                            names, and made to appear just as they are. Queen Isabella banished hundreds of thousands from Spain, and tens
                            of thousands were killed, and vast numbers perished from famine and pestilence. Eighty thousand besides, were
                            baptized by force, and their children coerced from them to be educated in the Christian faith ! The famous
                            schism that preceded the burning of Huss, and the wars consequent, cost one hundred and fifty thousand lives ;
                            and millions of the Aborigines in America were sasfcrified on the altar of the Catholic faith by the priesthood
                            and their abettors. The massacre of St. Bartholomew, it is said, cost fifty thousand lives. One writer states
                            that the whole religious influence of Spain was exerted to hasten the cafastrophe which deprived twelve millions
                            innocent individuals of life and happiness, to add to the glory of a merciful God. In the reign of Charles V.
                            from fifty to one hundred thousand were immolated for their faith, and many thousands more in the reign of his
                            son. A mandate went forth from the Church in the fifteenth century which condemned all the inhabitants of the
                            Netherlands to death, who were deemed guilty of heresy, and the king confirmed the decree. Three millions of
                            people, men, women and children, says Motley, were sent to the scaffold in three lines. In Spain, three hundred
                            and twenty thousand were burned, and subjected to various kinds of torture by the Inquisition. Need we go
                            farther to define what Persecution is ? or to show its origin other than by the effects produced? Where is the
                            "Lamb of God that taketh away the sins of the world" (errors in belief or practice)? who said: "Love your
                            enemies." "My servants will not fight ? " Protestant Christianity has lighted the fires of persecution—whenever
                            opportunity has offered — which have contained as much caloric, and whose flames have risen as high as have
                            either Pagan or Catholic. Scotch bishops and the English church united in their fiendish plans to brand the
                            Dissenters, as they were called, with hot irons, and tear their ears from their roots, and whip women through
                            the streets, because they dared to dissent from the ritualism of the church. The Scotch Presbyterians exercised
                            the cruel spirit of persecution to the extent of their power. The burning of Servetus was approved by
                            Protestants, and Calvin gloried that he had revenged the blasphemies of Servetus, by burning his physical body.
                            Malanthon showed his approval of the diabolical deed, when he wrote to Calvin that "the Church owed him a debt
                            of gratitude for so doing, and that his magistrate acted justly in thus suppressing heresy." His chief offense
                            was, that he claimed that Jesus Christ was not the Son of God from all eternity, but only since His incarnation.
                            On that point he was heterodox ; other than that it seems he was orthodox — a Protestant Christian. The
                            Anabaptists were greatly persecuted for their notions concerning infant baptism. The persecutions in regard to
                            witchcraft and sorcery have been equally balanced between Catholics and Protestants, according to the power
                            possessed by each. Luther, in theory and practice, advocated vindictive measures to suppress heresy. He said, "
                            I would show no mercy — have no compassion on those witches." Puritanism, in effect, was no better — was the
                            same in spirit, if not in degree. New England eclipsed the glory of American history by her bloody deeds and
                            intolerant spirit toward the Quakers, and by hanging witches. Think of it, in New England thirteen women and six
                            men were hanged for witchcraft, and one man, eighty years old, was crushed to death under a board loaded with
                            stones. Quakers had their ears cut off, were whipped and hanged ; women were tied to cart-tails in the dead of
                            winter, in a half nude state, and whipped through towns. Dark indeed is the cloud that rests over that sad
                            chapter in the history of New England ! But to the honor of New England it must be said, that much has been done
                            to wipe out the foul stains stamped upon her pages of history. Thousands of heinous cruelties and crimes might
                            be cited, to show how far a blind zeal, instigated by an ambitious bigoted priesthood, will carry its subjects.
                            The tear spirit, whatever form it may assume, or name it may bear, proceeds from beastly passions. In all ages
                            the lust of power is fed from the hells, while it usurps the authority to bind the consciences of men and women,
                            and kill the prophets. Let us inquire, " Who among all the orthodox and heterodox sects have been the Idolaters,
                            and who have worshiped the true and living God ? " Can we marvel that so many thousands should ask, " What is
                            Christianity ? Where and what its fruits ?" Can Paganism, Mahommedanism or Judaism present more atrocious crimes
                            than are found in the annals of what is called sacred history? Who will decide and point out with precision, the
                            Heretics, the Idolaters, or the Infidels in the past, or at the present time ? God sees and judges differently
                            from men. He looks at the heart — j udges the motives by the fruits produced. The important subject now
                            agitating the minds of deep and free-thinkers in Europe and America is, " Shall the beastly powers again ascend
                            the throne and rule the consciences of the people as in the past, either through Papal supremacy, making a god
                            of the pope, by giving him unlimited sway, or by placing the Protestant's God in the constitution of the
                            American government ?" Who wants to bend their necks to receive the usurper's yoke? Will America's sons and
                            daughters consent to have their consciences bound to creedal forms of belief and worship, by church and State
                            power, or to be branded and punished as heretics ? As well might we sing, "Carry me back to the dark ages—to the
                            Inquisition, the faggot and flame," instead <pb n="62" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER A.ND of struggling to roll forward the
                            car of progress, and talk of religious liberty. Clouds tliat portend a storm are gathering, they are ominous.
                            Mutterings which were at first but faintly heard in the distance grow louder and draw nearer. It would be well
                            for us all to remember, that " God is not a respecter of persons," of names, sects nor professions. But they who
                            seek to know, understand and do the truth, regardless of what it may cost, are His elect.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living waters" TEIform="index"/>"LIVING WATERS."</head><p TEIform="p">Jesus, while upon earth, uttered the following memorable words : " Whosoever drinketh of the water that I shall
                            give him, shall never thirst." The spiritual signification of water, throughout the scriptures, seems to be a
                            continual inspiration of Truth ; something vitally necessary to spiritual growth, and health — moving — Living
                            waters — nothing stale and dead. The very best and clearest water, as it bubbles up from its source on the
                            mountain side, or taken from the running streamlet in the valley — if allowed to remain for a long time, even in
                            the purest and most costly vessel — will gather, from the surrounding atmosphere, those noxious gases, which
                            living things are continually giving off in the different processes of growth, transformation and decay, and
                            become dead — unfit for use. They are no longer living waters, containing the inspiration and vigor which are
                            derived from them, when drank from the spring, or the flowing stream ; but are a prolific source of disease and
                            danger. On the contrary, the living waters of which Christ spake are continually springing up unto eternal life.
                            They have the elements of life in them, which keep them constantly in motion. Their principle of life, like that
                            of every thing in nature, is in constant activity. Still, pentup waters grow foul, and stagnant, and will not
                            support animal life, unless it be the lowest forms. The vital significant truths, which it was the mission of
                            Jesus to reveal, possess lifegiving elements, and are as living waters to souls. There is power in them,
                            evincing that they come from, and keep their connection and communion with the Fountain Head — the source whence
                            they came. Those who profess to drink of the waters of life, unless they manifest inspirational life, and have
                            that life to bestow on the thirsty famishing children of earth, how can they claim to constitute the Body of
                            Christ — his Church ? Have they, in their keeping, the testimony, the sound of which is as the "voice of many
                            waters," which proclaims them to be the living servants of Christ ? " By their fruits ye shall know them." A
                            living, breathing pulsation from the great Fountain Head, and manifesting itself in stainlessness of life, and
                            through consecration to good and holy uses, toward all with whom they come in contact, especially the "
                            household of faith," is proof that they have drank of those living waters; for by their acts, they show that
                            they are vitalized by the pure and glowing love of the Divine Parentage, and have bathed in the waters of
                            repentance. If they follow their exemplar, in that repentance, which is unto life, will they not, like him, be
                            willing to come to any " John the Baptist," who may be in order as a witness for God, and confess their sins —
                            reveal the history of their lives ? The Scripture record of him is, " He was tempted in all points as we are,
                            but without sin." Also, that " He learned obedience by the things he suffered." However that may be, it seems
                            that he cheerfully submitted to the olden time rite, for the cleansing of the people; and in a child-like
                            spirit, as was his wont, he said to his external Baptizer, " Suffer it" etc. That Jesus was a chosen medium to
                            receive a baptism of the Christ-Spirit, there need be no doubt. And that he was attended from his childhood days
                            with a guardian Spirit, who instructed, and prepared him for that event, we have strong evidence. At the early
                            age of twelve years, when he said to his sorrowing earthly parents, who had diligently sought him three days, "
                            Wist ye not that I must be about my Father's business ?" he seemed to be impressed that he had some important
                            mission to perform. We are left in the dark concerning many years of his history; are only informed that " He
                            grew in stature, and in favor with God and man." His season of temptation, which was painfully trying and severe
                            — of which it is stated he fasted forty days and forty nights — was succeeded by beautiful ministrations from
                            Angels; and thenceforward, his life seemed pervaded with a continual influx of good, which he ministered to his
                            disciples and all who were willing to receive. In that noble, generous heart, there was no shrinking from duty.
                            Through self-renunciation, and holy consecration, he endured and suffered, that he might benefit others, until
                            his mission on earth was fulfilled. He said, " he would send the Comforter " to his little Band; and promised,
                            that those who would drink of his cup and be baptized with his baptism of fire and the Holy Ghost, should do
                            greater works than he had done. Which promise was verified.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. Webster, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do good" TEIform="index"/>DO GOOD</head><p TEIform="p">" Do good and cast it into the sea; if the fishes do not regard it, God will." This, though an ancient Arab
                            saying, strengthens the belief that no good deed goes unrewarded, however indifferent the receiver of such an
                            act may appear. Do good and bless life by your existence. Make better the place where you hold a right; let no
                            opportunity pass unimproved. The way to increase our own happiness is to make others happy ; it being " more
                            blessed to give than to receive." In how many little ways we could, by an unselfish spirit, light'en the burdens
                            of the overborne, and cheer the drooping spirit of a friend, or companion, if our aim be to assist othei's and
                            be always doing good. " Be kindly affectioned one to another, in honor preferring one another," are the words of
                            the Apostle; which, if lived out, would lead to acts of self denial and care, lest we mar the happiness of
                            another. " Life is made up of atoms ;" and if they all tend to promote goodness, how blest the reward ! " What
                            we sow we must surely reap;" and who would not prefer a harvest of good deeds, kind words and affectionate
                            regards, to that of wrongdoing, unkindness and hatred 1 We were intended as blessings, having power to be angels
                            of love to each other. We have read that satan can appear as an angel of light, and misguide the unwary who are
                            not wakeful in duty; but he never can be transformed into an angel of love, which we have the privilege of
                            becoming. We can make life pleasant, by improving the opportunities for doing good ; or unpleasant, by counting
                            all the disagreeables of life as insurmountable obstacles, and continually looking on the dark side ; thus not
                            only robbing ourselves of peace and quiet, but casting over others a chilling and blighting influence. Do good;
                            rise in the morning with this determination in your heart, renew it every hour; and bless society by your
                            associations. "Little acts of kindness, little words of love, Make this earth an Eden like the Heavens above."
                            The principle of preferring others to ourselves opens a way for all to receive acts of love and care. If our aim
                            be to do good and make happy our sister and brother, who toil with us, and tr y, in turn, are governed by the
                            same spirit to do good to us, then are we all made better by our unselfish aims. Let us do good, for large is
                            the field in which to labor, and we shall be more than compensated for all the self-sacrifice that such a course
                            requires.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johns, Harriet A." TEIform="persName"/>Harriet A. Johns, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To believers" TEIform="index"/>TO BELIEVERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Money orders are an affliction. Please close up all accounts with S. &amp; S. immediately, by drafts, on New
                            York.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good intentions" TEIform="index"/>GOOD INTENTIONS</head><p TEIform="p">How many there are who begin life's varied pursuits with good intentions, looking to the future with bright and
                            sanguine hopes for success ; and yet how many fail, sadly fail, of realizing those anticipations. Meaning to do
                            well they become, in a measure, satisfied with their intentions, instead of actual good works. Thus they pass
                            along till overtaken by misfortune, or the accumulation of neglected duties, while many of the most valuable
                            years of health and vigor are squandered, and golden opportunities lost. We have never heard of the individual
                            who became accomplished mentally or morally without a constant effort and application, meeting trials and
                            disappointments withal. Let us learn endurance, and though we often fail of reaching the desired object, what
                            has been accomplished may be again, with the same patience and unflinching courage. Each failure should serve to
                            stimulate the mind and renew the energies for greater action. If "All real good is on the mountain top," then we
                            must go up there to get it; and our trials and failures may prove, in the end, to be the very stepping-stones or
                            means of our ascent to its summit. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Conversation" TEIform="index"/>CONVERSATION</head><p TEIform="p">Among the pleasant hours of entertainment, recreation and rest, are those of good solid conversation, wherein
                            minds, through reciprocity of ideas, become enlightened, educated and possessors of others' thoughts. There is
                            great beauty in, and profit derived from proper conversation; but they are not found in the surface talk which
                            readily flows from superficial thinkers, who seek to entertain with the sheer nothings that pass and repass upon
                            the stage of human existence. When we come in contact with minds sensibly alive to great vital principles, with
                            treasured items of useful knowledge which they are willing to impart, who take note of passing events, study
                            causes and their results, by which they are able to discern the future, we are instructed; we intuitively feel
                            that they drink deeply from the inspirational fount of learning — the Universe. If our feelings are consonant
                            with theirs, we take pleasure while, in conference with them, and toe also a.re inspired with the noble theme of
                            living to do and to acquire good. Conversational powers are enhanced and sustained by individual effort, for
                            information and improvement. " Genius unexerted is like the moth that flutters around a candle until it is
                            scorched to death." Genius properly exerted, made active by being brought into service, is an educator, whether
                            in a moral, intellectual or spiritual point of view, and is principally, at our own option, our own work. We are
                            surrounded with the means of education, and it remains with us whether we will employ the agencies placed within
                            our reach, or not. Continued industry and close thought are requisite to reveal the lustre of pure Truth. Reason
                            is applicable to all Truth, whether Natural, Scientific or Religious. Nature itself is a never-ending volume,
                            from which a great variety of lessons may be learned. , The varied incidents of life through which we pass make
                            diversified impressions upon different minds. Exchanging the various thoughts and views impressed upon minds of
                            different cast from our own, augments our store of knowledge, intensifies thought, elucidates the power of
                            perception, and lengthens the radius of meditation. The exchange of thought by fitting conversation is like
                            genial rays of sunshine to warm and vivify the heart, strengthen and give activity to the brain, and chase away
                            the clouds of doubt and uncertainty that gather around and prevent the free exercise of the intellectual powers.
                            By culture vre grow in intelligence, and become useful members of society here, and by the same means we must
                            prepare ourselves for the companionship of immortals, and to ornament the courts of heaven. If all, in early
                            life, would devote their minds to subjects both useful and interesting, that would demand the application of the
                            faculties 62 <pb n="63" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEES8. 63 according to their age, they would learn that happiness
                            increases as knowledge and industry increase; and they would erect a fortress against temptation. Instead of
                            pursuing selfgratification with eagerness and seeking happiness in vanity and romance, which lead to dissolute
                            habits, there would be a calm and settled purpose of mind and a growing thirst for substantial knowledge and
                            wisdom that would elevate and refine. If woman would detach herself from the artificial and vain, and devote her
                            powers of mind to the substantial and true, what an influence she would wield over the destiny of our race! The
                            love and gentleness of her nature need not be diminished thereby; but all the true womanly qualifications,
                            devoid of voluptuous delicacy, would be retained, and she would arise as a power for good, to educate the lowly,
                            and in all her words and acts bear aloft the standard of moral purity, and make the world better, politically,
                            morally and spiritually.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Emblems of spring" TEIform="index"/>EMBLEMS OF SPRING</head><p TEIform="p">Beneath the long despotic reign Of Winter's icy hand, How manifold the forms of life That sleep within the land.
                            His frigid fingers touch the trees, The grass, and flowers bright, His chilling breath the waters close In
                            slumbers of the night. But ever on the earth revolves Around the orb of light, And each gyration nearer brings
                            The morning of delight,— When 'neath the warm and genial raya That fall to bless the land, The germs of life in
                            seed and bud. In loveliness expand. And sparkling waters burst the crust That hushed their murmurous flow, The
                            tender grasses pierce the sod, To feel the sunbeam's glow. In rainbow tints and sweet perfume, Are robed the
                            smiling flowers ; By force unseen, their beauty's wrought From sunlight and from showers. The leafy tongues of
                            forest trees Unite each happy note With light winged birds, whose mingled songs Upon the breezes float. And o'er
                            us bend the graceful boughs, All wreathed in blossoms fair, A prophecy of ripened fruit,— A recompense for care.
                            When selfishness and sin possess Dominion in the heart. They sternly hold a frigid power That chills the spirit
                            part. But if we turn to seek the light That cometh from above, We'll feel the warmth of angel life In sunny
                            beams of love. They will the icy coverings melt, Of envy, hate, and fear, And joyously will Spring's bright morn
                            Within the soul appear. The plants of virtue then will grow, Life's fountains be unsealed, And latent energies
                            awake, That long have been concealed. Affections pure like early flowers From wintry slu?nbers start, 'Mid
                            verdancy of good desires Upspringing in the heart. The tree of endless spirit life Unfolds its fragrant bloom,
                            In token of the precious fruit That never finds the tomb. We see that this exterior sphere Is clothing for the
                            soul, Which is the vitalizing force That animates the whole. The glorious sun that giveth life To all material
                            things, That from a dark chaotic state, Such wondrous beauty brings,— Is but an emblem of the Truth, The motive
                            power—Love, The element in which our souls Have being, live and move.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>Catherine Allen, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Diet" TEIform="index"/>DIET</head><p TEIform="p">We read that Felix listened to Paul, while he reasoned of Righteousness, Temperance and Judgment. If the Apostles
                            of Jesus, eighteen centuries ago, reasoned upon righteousness and temperance, What is the duty of the advocates
                            of the Christian religion, after the growth and development of reason and science, for so many ages ? There are
                            many preachers of righteousness at the present time, who are doing a good work in staying the flood of
                            intemperance in drinking. But to be temperate in all things is a duty that intelligent beings owe to others, and
                            to their own well-being. The subject of proper diet has occupied my thoughts from time to time ; but I must
                            confess that / have been a transgressor of the laws of hygiene ; some times through ignorance, at other times,
                            through weakness and force of circumstances. How unstable and irresolute are poor mortals, many times, when
                            placed in the way of temptation; and how easily drawn aside from the path of rectitude ! It is lamentable to see
                            how large the number of people, in the nineteenth century, who profess to be free, and still are slaves to
                            abnormal appetites. Intemperance in eating is as pernicious, if indulged to the same extent, as intemperance in
                            drinking. Eating improper food, and at irregular hours, deranges the stomach, poisons the system, produces
                            dyspepsia, that vexatious infliction upon human beings, and is a destroyer of peace and happiness, resulting in
                            misery and premature death. The life of a real dyspeptic is fraught with pain and sorrow. The path which he or
                            she travels is oftentimes despondent and gloomy ! Dark caverns appear before them and they are filled with
                            fearful forebodings of the future ! Again, hopes brighten, and the spirits are exhilerant; signs and scenes are
                            fitful and changing. We cannot violate the laws of health, without paying the penalty. We may flatter ourselves
                            with the delusive hope that we shall pass unharmed if we indulge in all the tempting luxuries of life in meats
                            and drinks. The same deceptive spirit, that ages ago said " Thou shalt not surely die," to-day walks in our
                            midst, says the same things and lures thousands to commit sins against their bodies and souls. Stimulating
                            drinks,hot cakes — all nice and white — rich mince pies, pastry and sweetmeats— made delicate and palatable —
                            are disease-producing causes. How much time and strength are unwisely spent in the preparation of unhealthy
                            food; thus aiding the weak to continue their unphysiological selfindulging habits and appetites. Dwelling in
                            illy-ventilated rooms, which are warmed by tight stoves, accompanied with stimulating drinks and unwholesome
                            diet, is a prolific source of disease, sorrow and death. Hence, of the millions of human beings born of diseased
                            parents, every year, only a fractional part reach maturity ; and especially in our own country, at the present
                            time, we see a generation of weak, puny youth and children, upon whom, in a few years, must rest the burden and
                            responsibility of framing laws, and of sustaining the republican institutions, in what is called free America.
                            To the same source, Believers in Christ's Second Appearing must also look for members to replenish their ranks.
                            And they who are called to constitute the highest Spiritual Church on earth — by living a pure, virgin life, a
                            life of consecration in all things—should be saviors from physiological sins, as well as the sins which relate
                            more particularly to the soul. To eat and drink for strength — for use — and not for gratification and gluttony,
                            should be the law of God's house. We may speak as with the tongue of Angels, and make loud professions of Faith;
                            but by our tcorks we shall be known — by the fruits brought forth we shall be judged. If we are transgressors of
                            the laws of life and health, relating to body or soul, how can we become saviors — helpers-to others in like
                            condition ? Instead of unbosoming their sorrows and showing the causes of their infirmities, as the sick patient
                            would confidentially approach a skillful physician, would they not say," Physician, first heal thyself? " There
                            are multitudes of people in our day, who profess the healing art, and point out a panacea for all the ills of
                            soul and body, and are prepared to reform every body but themselves. When we see reformers who have first
                            reformed themselves, who will practically demonstrate how they have done it, then we have confidence that they
                            understand how to administer the healing balm to others. When I cast my eyes over society, and reflect how many
                            friends — near and dear companions — have gone down to premature graves, my heart bleeds, and my spirit is
                            pained ! I yearn for a higher state of things, when sickness, pain and untimely death will not bear rule as in
                            the past. I pray for the ushering in of new earthly conditions, to prepare the way, and make room for greater
                            spiritual, heavenly truths ; that the kingdom of heaven may come so perfectly on earth, that God's will may be
                            done by healthy souls in healthy bodies ; and that all who profess to belong in that kingdom, will have learned
                            the all important lesson, " Eat to live, and not live to eat." The " Shaker and Shakeress" is a small sheet, but
                            contains many weighty truths, and is doing a good work. Indeed, there are inspirational effusions from almost
                            every article comprised therein, which are instructive and strengthening. Its deep tones sound aloud, and
                            continuously call to higher action. May its voice, as a spiritual messenger, be heard far and near, even to the
                            remotest isles. The millennial truth must go forth from Zion, and the time is hastening when it will be said. "
                            The law of use is the law inscribed on every vessel in the Lord's house, and nothing shall hurt nor harm in all
                            His holy mountains." Slaughtering dumb animals for food will be among the things of the past, and there will be
                            no more use for poisonous drugs to counteract the poison taken in the human system by unhealthful food and
                            drink. We see cause of rejoicing, that the downy beds, which a few years ago were held in high esteem throughout
                            the country, and were used quite extensively, are now considered disease generators, and have gone into
                            disrepute and disuse. It is a hopeful sign. Let all of Zion's children be of one heart and mind, and bless every
                            effort at true reformation, strengthen others who are weak, by being strong in the truth, and thus lead on to
                            victory.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Nancy L." TEIform="persName"/>Nancy L. Rupe., Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Female voting" TEIform="index"/>FEMALE VOTING</head><p TEIform="p">A decision has been reached in the United States Supreme Court, which seems to settle the status of women as
                            qualified voters. In the case of Miner v. Hoppersatt, the decision, while conceding that women are citizens of
                            the United States, and of the State where they reside, fails to make them voters by virtue of such residence.
                            The court were unanimous in the opinion that the Constitution of the United States does not confer the right of
                            suffrage upon any one. That right is made one of the attainable privileges of a citizen and is not an absolute
                            one. The United States possesses no voters. Their officers are chosen directly or indirectly by the voters of
                            States. To vote for Federal officers, one must be first competent to vote for State officers. Women cannot
                            become voters, therefore, until authorized by the respective States in which they reside. Victor Hugo has taken
                            his stand in favor of Woman's Bights. In a recent letter to the French Society for the Amelioration of the
                            Position of Women, he said that all the efforts of his life had been to secure a better lot for women, and added
                            " Man has been the problem of the eighteenth century, woman is the problem of the nineteenth; and to say woman
                            is to say child, that is to say the future. The question thus put appears in all its gravity. It is in its
                            solution that lies the supreme social appeasal. Woman can do all for man — nothing for herself. The laws are
                            imprudent to make her so feeble when she is so powerful. Let us recognize that feebleness and protect it; let us
                            recognize that power and direct it. There lies the duty of man ; there lies also his interest. I do not tire of
                            saying the problem is put; it must be solved. Whoever bears a part of the burden ought to have a part of the
                            privileges. Half of the human race is outside equality; it must be made to re-enter. It will be one of the great
                            glories of our great century to give the rights of the woman as a counterbalance to the rights of the man — that
                            is to say, to put the laws in equilibrium with the customs."</p></div2><pb n="64" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Germs of truth" TEIform="index"/>GERMS OF TRUTH</head><p TEIform="p">Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1. There are germs of truth upon the earth. That never have been known, And seeds of grace in
                            ev'ry heart That angels there have sown; 2. The type of many unborn flowers, Are placed before our eyes; We
                            catch a hope they yet will bloom, And then the vision dies; They struggle 'neath the heavy soil That shrouds the
                            land today, The seeds of error check their growth, Impede their upward way. But when the magic spirit power Of
                            angel ministry, Shall rule the elements of earth, All life the good will see. 3. And we who 'neath God's holy
                            light Sad winter little know, May lend a summer's warmth to aid The soul in grace to grow. And we will pierce
                            the threatening clouds 'Till sunshine floods the earth, 'Till it reveals the mighty strength And depth of angel
                            worth. 4. And we will seek in every heart To find the germs of truth, And breathe thereon the holy life Of
                            everlasting youth; Then, when the eventide of years Around our spirits close, No lingering fear or sad regret
                            Shall mark the last repose.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gift of love" TEIform="index"/>GIFT OF LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">I. My heart nurs'd wishes for a gift, But somehow dared not to express them ; In silence only, and when left
                            Alone, 'twould fondle and caress them. I knew it could not be for gold, For that is worthless to the spirit, Who
                            toil'd for years in mother's fold Heaven's inner kingdom to inherit. Nor could it care to wish for fame; O, nay
                            — for who could wish to find it ? Nor even less for titled name — All these were things long left behind it. And
                            so what could it be but Love — That gentle spirit, guiding many? Some angel did my doubts remove ; It was the
                            gift of Love, if any 1 And season went and season came, And wonder'd at a world so funny; And still my wishes
                            were the same, And still the skieslooked bright and sunny 1 II. One afternoon I plowed the sod With steady hand
                            and quiet feeling, When lo ! I felt the Love of God On snowy wings around me stealing. And then I knew my heart
                            had dared To give expression to its wishes, And God in His great Love prepared Not only loaves, but also fishes
                            I And since that hour this gift of love Hath left my heart not for a minute; What'er befall, where e'er I move,
                            This heav'nly gift is always in it. 'Tis there ! I feel it when I kneel At eve with those beloved in heaven. Or
                            when I rise at morn I feel The gift I wished for, God hath given 1</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fickeyson, C. A. Emil" TEIform="persName"/>C. A. Emil Fickeyson White Water, January 17,1875.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To me, it is not a matter of dispute..." TEIform="index"/>To me, it is not a matter of dispute...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To me, it is not a matter of dispute whether in Jesus, the first Christ was manifested to men, or not. I accept
                            him as typical of said Order, in the distant past, as in the coming future. If Jesus was not the first unearthed
                            man, I shall be happy in knowing that of Clirists there are millions, seeing I can partake of their spirits and
                            powers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Twenty impolite things" TEIform="index"/>TWENTY IMPOLITE THINGS</head><p TEIform="p">1. Loud and boisterous laughing. 2. Reading when others are talking. 3. Reading aloud in company without being
                            asked. 4. Talking when others are reading. 5. Spitting about the house, smoking or chewing. 6. Cutting finger
                            nails in company. 7. Leaving church before worship is closed. 8. Whispering or laughing in the house of God. 9.
                            Gazing rudely at strangers. 10. Leaving a stranger without a seat. 11. A want of respect and reverence for
                            seniors. 12. Correcting older persons, especially parents. 13. Receiving a present without an expression of
                            gratitude. 14. Making yourself hero of your own history. 15. Laughing at the mistakes of other people. 16.
                            Commencing talking before others have finished speaking. 17. Answering questions that have been put to others.
                            18. Commencing to eat as soon as you get to the table. 19. Not listening to what one is saying in company ; and
                            20. Whistling and loud talking in a printing office.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Question — what does the shaker and shakeress do?" TEIform="index"/>Question — What does the Shaker and Shakeress
                            do ?</head><p TEIform="p">Answer — It stops one of the gaps in the wall of the world's complaints—that we never go out to proclaim our
                            principles and give to seekers of the truth, a reason for the faith that is in us. It bears witness, to the
                            world, of the reality of physical — Spirit — manifestations — but not of the truthfulness of supermundane
                            communications from the lower spheres. As a medium of present revelations, from the higher spheres, it is
                            edifying to the saints.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>James S. Prescott, North Union, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The history of the past and the experience of the present show that the best men and womens..." TEIform="index"/>"The history of the past and the experience of the present show that the best men and women...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The history of the past and the experience of the present show that the best men and women have suffered most
                            severely In their reputations; have been reviled, persecuted and crucified. It would seem as if these revilings
                            and persecutions were proportioned to the purity and goodness of the individual. " A decent respect for the
                            opinions of others, and a proper love of approbation, stimulate us to do right; but at the same time, there is a
                            true and noble independence which results from right actions, that lifts us above the influence of malice and
                            slander, and the well-poised mind is not moved by these, except with feelings of pity for those who indulge in
                            them."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Child, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>Henry T. Child, M. D.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfection" TEIform="index"/>PERFECTION</head><p TEIform="p">My God, my home, my precious call, Ideal grace unfold ; I see that glory in them all, Which ancient seers
                            foretold. My God is perfect, true and wise, And while this God is mine, Perfection will alone- suffice In life
                            that is divine. IIow much salvation do we ask ? For it a price we give, If only from the grosser ills, From
                            these remote we live. If we desire the saving power, From every thought of sin, We give our all, from hour to
                            hour, 'Till we perfection win.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cremation" TEIform="index"/>CREMATION</head><p TEIform="p">Cremation, in India, is the cause of the Asiatic cholera. Let Americans, who have plenty of land, bury their
                            dead, far enough apart, to plant a tree by each grave—have all funeral ceremonies as simple and inexpensive as
                            possible. When Catholics enter church, Rich and Poor are on a level. When Protestants come into their sick
                            rooms, and burial grounds — let them then, if nowhere else, be on a dead level Quaker equality. The following
                            address was recently delivered at the funeral of a San Francisco type-setter : " Our brother, Mr. John Harlan,
                            is dead. His last letter is distributed, his case is emptied, his stick is full, the last line is spaced out,
                            and the clicking of the type is no more heard as stuck by his hand. A paragraph is made, a period put in! his
                            last proof is taken, his galley cleared. His form is made up, and lies upon the cold imposing stone of death,
                            silent, lifeless. His faults are set in diamond and pied, so that no more pi oof can be taken. His virtues are
                            set in six-line pica, colored, framed and hung on the walls of memory, never to be forgotten. Be warned and be
                            ready. Correct your proof."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Campbell, Dana" TEIform="index"/>Dana Campbell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Campbell, Dana" TEIform="persName">Dana Campbell</persName>, 73, May, 1875.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Edwards, Paulina" TEIform="index"/>Paulina Edwards
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Edwards, Paulina" TEIform="persName">Paulina Edwards</persName>, 40, May, 1875, South Union, Ky.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Darram, James" TEIform="index"/>James Darram
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Darram, James" TEIform="persName">James Darram</persName>, aged 86, Union "Village, Ohio. Was a vegetarian for
                                fifty years; his last words were " The way I have lived is right. It was never designed of God that his
                                people should cut throats</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>