<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1012" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18801201" TEIform="date">December 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">242-288</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
<p> MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. "And
                        they shall turn to you for a testimony:" "Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO G. B. AVERY,
                        PUBLISHER. 1880. "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." The Shaker DECEMBER, 1880. Vol. X. No. 12. 60 Cents Per
                        Annum.</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
--><pb n="265" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sweet consolation" TEIform="index"/>SWEET CONSOLATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher</byline><p TEIform="p">. 0 God, nay heavenly father, How can I e'er repine, So truly blest and happy In this, the
                            lot that's mine ! My heart expands anew To praise thee all the day; Again, at eventide, 1
                            would resume my lay. No urging do I need, To meet thy call of grace ; Permit me only here To
                            earn and hold a place ; Why was I blest of thee, To leave the fallen course Of nature,
                            stained and lost, And so perverse? And what would 1 have been, Hadst thou permitted me, The
                            worldly life, as seen, The best yet known to be? A slave to pride and sin, To passion and to
                            lust; With conscience stirred within, But naught of earth to trust. Long, long would be the
                            road To travel back to thee— My Saviour, and my God, My home of purity. Could I desire all
                            this, To make my song of praise For highest, heavenly bliss, As shared from childhood days?
                            Nay, Father, I am glad, Blest Mother, I rejoice ; Not once the feeling sad, I follow named
                            by choice, And joyful give the whole, In gratitude each day, For blessings to the good,
                            Found in thy narrow way. Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New year's resolves" TEIform="index"/>NEW YEAR'S RESOLVES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">A Suggestion. The beginning of a new year is a starting point, with many people, for the
                            discarding of bad habits and the formation of good ones. If any of our readers are inclined
                            to charge themselves with being too selfish, with having too long lived without endeavors to
                            benefit themselves and others, we hope they will begin the new year by trying to do better.
                            We would suggest one direction in which efforts in this respect will give satisfaction. Let
                            them select from their circle of friends the names of such as would be likely to be
                            benefited by reading The Manifesto, and send the addresses to our office, with sixty cents
                            each for a year's subscription. New year's gifts of this kind would be, to many persons, not
                            only acceptable, but in the highest degree beneficial. Many people have had occasion to be
                            deeply thankful <pb n="266" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 266 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. that The Manifesto ever came
                            in their way. Either they have been directly benefited by something observed in its pages,
                            or it has set in motion new trains of thought, or inspired new impulses; the results have
                            been seen in successes of a moral and spiritual character. There are thousands of people who
                            would be profited by the regular reading of our journal, for it has a direct tendency to
                            draw the mind from sinful pleasures, and attract it toward that which is elevating and pure.
                            Those who are not subscribers should now enroll their names; those who already enjoy the
                            privilege should forthwith extend the same to their friends. Let us commence the new year
                            with the endeavor to do all the good we can, every day, and if we do not grow weary in well
                            doing, the year 1881 will bring forth an abundant harvest of heavenly treasures. Enfield,
                            Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's plan of your life" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S PLAN OF YOUR LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell" TEIform="persName"/>DR. BUSHNELL</byline><p TEIform="p">. Never complain of your birth, your training, your employment, your hardships ; never fancy
                            that you could be something if you had a different lot and sphere assigned you. God
                            understands his own plan and he knows what you want a great deal better than you do. The
                            very things that you most deprecate as fatal limitations or obstructions are probably what
                            you most need. What you call hindrances, obstacles, and discouragements, are probably God's
                            opportunities : and it is nothing new that the patient should dislike his medicine, nor any
                            certain proof that they are poisons. Check that foolish envy which knaws at your heart
                            because you are not in the same lot with others ; bring down your soul, or rather, bring it
                            up to receive God's will, and do His work in your sphere, under your cloud of obscurity
                            against your temptations; and then you shall find that your condition is never opposed to
                            your good, but really consistent with it. No man preaches well to others if he does not
                            preach to his own heart.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Don't stand on the track" TEIform="index"/>DON'T STAND ON THE TRACK</head><p TEIform="p">EASTERN SHAKERS. A thought fills my soul with a feeling of awe, That life is a railway whose
                            engine is law ; Which knoweth no rest and never turns back, While it shrieks out its
                            warning, " Don't stand on the track." The iron horse, progress, forever rolls on, Old
                            principles die out, and new ones are born ; We must go with the engine that never turns
                            back, Then hark to the warning, "Don't stand on the track" There are laws for the body and
                            laws for the soul, By yielding obedience their force we control; They know no exemption for
                            white nor for black, Then hark to the warning, " Don't stand on the track." Young man! keep
                            awake, on the journey of life! Your pathway with terrible danger is rife ; The speed of the
                            iron horse never grows slack, For the love of your life, then, " Don't stand on the track."
                            Shun the fumes of the cup as a rattlesnake's breath ; You are playing with fire that will
                            burn you to death ! Yield not to temptation, though fierce the attack ; Remember the
                            warning, " Don't stand on the track." With eye never closing your watch you must keep, For
                            our passions are often like wild beasts asleep ; Sin takes from the soul what it never gives
                            back, For the sweet hope of heaven, " Don't stand on the track."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is truth?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS TRUTH?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> Was the question put to Jesus by Pilate. It is seldom appropriately answered, to our
                            understanding. Truth is the manifestation of those principles, the issues of which eventuate
                            in the evolution, development and perfection of humanity, and which consummate in the glory
                            of God.</p></div2><pb n="267" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall we do with the Indians?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT SHALL WE DO WITH THE INDIANS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pool, J. B." TEIform="persName"/>J. B. POOL</byline><p TEIform="p"> [While we do not entirely agree with the following suggestions of our brother at West
                            Pittsfield', Mass., we present his article as certainly original and characteristic ; while
                            we know the writer is not without much of the milk of human kindness, and a large respect
                            for human brotherhood.—Ed.] . This is one of the great questions of the day, and has
                            received a variety of solutions. It has been suggested by some that the Indians ought to be
                            annihilated! This exhibits a very ungenerous feeling. The Indian has a place in nature as
                            well as the white man ; and it is the duty of the superior race to ascertain the positions
                            the lower races should occupy. In taking a view of the processes of nature, we are led to
                            believe that the genus homo commenced its existence on the earth from the lowest type —
                            lower than anything now on the earth — and that the higher species came along one after
                            another, till at last the Caucasian species, the highest of all, was introduced. The species
                            immediately below the Caucasian is undoubtedly the Mongolian. The latter species claim a
                            priority of existence as regards the white race, and it is probable that this claim is a
                            just one. It was a Mongolian female, no doubt, that first received the Spirit-germs of the
                            first pair of whites that came on the earth. Consequently the whites got their first tuition
                            and instruction from the Mongolians. When the white race became sufficiently developed to
                            take care of themselves, a separation took place — the white leaving the Mongols and seeking
                            their fortunes in distant lands. Now the whites are able to teach the Mongols, and the
                            latter, by being influenced by the Caucasians, are capable of further development. , The
                            Chinese, in consequence of their seclusiveness, have remained stationary for many centuries
                            ; but now, on account of more frequent contact with the superior race, they are catching the
                            inspiration and are going ahead. The race immediately below the Mongols appear to be the
                            Indians. It is quite probable that the Mongolians were introduced to the scenes of time
                            through the medium of the Indians. Consequently the Indians must now look to the Mongols for
                            help and instruction. The chasm between the whites and the Indians appears to be too great
                            for practical purposes. The Indians, feeling their inferiority, cannot learn or be
                            influenced by the whites. It is probably owing to this that our government has had such poor
                            success in treating with the aboriginals, From the Chinese no doubt the red man would catch
                            the spirit of improvement and go on in the line of progression. The race below the Indians
                            is the Negro, and the red-man received his birth, perhaps, from the black race; and now the
                            negro must look for instruction from the Indian. According to the view herein given, our
                            government ought to send a tribe or two of Indians to Africa, within a few years, and the
                            procedure should be kept up till the Indians are transferred to that country.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker reminiscences" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER REMINISCENCES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Severance, G." TEIform="persName"/>G. SEVERANCE</byline><p TEIform="p"> At the age of nine years, my father, who was by occupation a farmer, moved from Lempster, N.
                            H., where I was born, to the neighboring town of Claremont, where I lived mostly till the
                            age of twenty-five. In Claremont, my father was a deacon of the Congregational Church of
                            that place. In that faith, when I was a youth, I was carefully trained, though I was never a
                            communicant in that connection. At about the age of sixteen I became much interested in
                            subjects of religious controversy, and very soon espoused the doctrine of Universalism.
                            While in my teens I thought myself quite an adept in encountering the Orthodoxy of the time
                            from the Universalist point of view. A little previous to this period a paternal uncle had
                            joined the Shakers at Enfield, N. H. A few years before a Universalist clergyman, by the
                            name of Fayette Mace, had joined the Shakers and published a small work in defense of Shaker
                            theology, and in the preface paid a very high compliment to Elder John Lyon, as a champion
                            of the <pb n="268" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 268 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. principles advocated by the Shakers.
                            He represented himself as most sorely discomfited by this unpretending advocate of the
                            Shaker faith. Universalists were bold and sanguine in matters pertaining to religious
                            controversy. They asked no odds at the hands of believers in the eternity of punishment. In
                            learning of the Shakers through the instrumentality of Fayette Mace, my curiosity increased
                            to become more intimately acquainted with this people. In the winter of 1838, a young man, a
                            favorite cousin, concluded with me to make a journey to the Shakers. We made the journey of
                            nearly twenty miles on foot. About four o'clock p. m., on a pleasant January day, found us
                            in the to us unique Shaker village of Enfield, N. H. Had I planted my feet on a European or
                            South American city, the surprise at my surroundings could not have been greater. Such order
                            and tidiness, out doors and in, had never before met my eyes; every thing was a wonder. The
                            gentle and modest suavity of the people captivated me. I had never seen any thing of this
                            nature to be compared with the social order and harmony of this beautiful village. It was
                            Saturday night, and we were invited to attend the evening worship. We were quietly seated
                            before the worshipers appeared, the males entering one door, and the females another,
                            forming in plattoons preparatory for worship. Then, suddenly all knelt, preserving solemn
                            silence for a few moments, "when all at once they rose to their feet and the singers took
                            their place in the middle of the hall, while the others engaged in a springy march to
                            enlivening singing. Singular as it may seem to the uninitiated, I was almost spell bound.
                            Were I to attend a spiritual seance, and were the room all at once to be filled with
                            spirit-materialized forms, the effect on me would not be more striking. That evening meeting
                            made an impression on me time will never efface. I was then in my eighteenth year. The next
                            day being Sunday, we repaired to the church at the usual hour. The number of worshipers was
                            much larger than the previous evening ; and the services were highly interesting. It was
                            about this time the revival of 1837-43 had become a marked phase. For the first time I saw
                            the movements of those who were known as conspicuous instruments in the strange developments
                            then going on. To me the sight was solemn and serious, as they moved about with the
                            worshipers seemingly insensible to their surroundings. The pallor of their countenances gave
                            them a celestial look. There was no deception here, and I was reminded of pentecostal times.
                            At a proper time I had an introduction to Elder John Lyon, then about sixty years of age,
                            not above medium height, rather full faced, and slow of speech. I was young and zealous in
                            presenting my Universalist views ; but I was not long in discovering I was in the presence
                            of a man of superior abilities, who was perfectly at home in dealing with polemical
                            subjects. I was very soon lead into a different department of the ological controversy from
                            any which was familiar to me. At this period textual controversies were rife in all
                            directions. I soon concluded that John Lyon's abilities had not been overestimated. Any
                            reasonable thinker would have been astounded to see with what ease he would dispose of
                            vaunting clergymen who sought to drive him from the position in which he had intrenched
                            himself. Often did I think that our promising young divinity students after graduating would
                            do well to spend a month or so with this most worthy and able elder of the Shaker faith. It
                            is now nearly twenty years since he left his earthly form. I have often said he knew me
                            better than my own father did. Well did he serve his day and generation. When he died I
                            wrote an obituary of him which was published in a Universalist paper. I have often thought
                            the Shaker fraternity hardly knew how strong and representative a man it had in the person
                            of John Lyon ; and I think I can say whoever has traveled extensively and seen much of the
                            world, will find there is much to be seen and learned from a Shaker community. If a rational
                            piety and devout consecration place a people in nearness to God, then the position occupied
                            by this people places them in the front rank. <pb n="269" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            2G9 To the outside world, Shakerism has the appearance of rigidity. It is extremely rigid in
                            the emphasis it gives to a virgin life. Beyond this point as a community no sect has more
                            flexibility. It does not war with scientific discoveries. It does not set up claims for the
                            Bible, which it does not set up for itself. If our liberalists and secularists deny what is
                            denominated the Fall of Man, the Shaker will take them on their own ground and prove
                            scientifically that the human species are, and have been in an abnormal condition for untold
                            ages as respects the laws of sexualism. Sexually our race is fallen and degraded to an
                            extent unknown in any other department of the animal kingdom. And the Shaker will tell you,
                            could he but lift the race up as high as the properly natural plane of life, Shaker
                            societies would increase, and multitudes who now stand aloof would flock to them as doves to
                            their windows. Reluctant as the world is to concede it, Shakerism aims its blows at the real
                            root of all evil. During those periods, when the nations of the earth have most rioted in
                            wickedness, then licentiousness has been most rampant. How little is the world conscious
                            that its most terrible woes have arisen from this source. What a singular episode in history
                            was the advent of Ann Lee. Unlettered in the extreme, as the world phrases it, unacquainted
                            with even the rudiments of an education, the founder of a community that has now reached a
                            longevity to which all other modern communal systems are and have been strangers, requiring
                            her devotees to bear a cross against which there is almost universal rebellion, and still
                            the greatest of communal victories. Were the Shakers to disband and disappear to-morrow,
                            they have had a mission and have borne a sad testimony to the world's wrongs. In my younger
                            days Ann Lee was spoken of in the most contemptuous terms. No intelligent modern writer thus
                            treats her memory now. Kven the elite of Harvard University, with all their wisdom in the
                            experiment at Brook Farm, most notably failed in their trial of communism. We can only
                            explain the success of Mother Ann on the ground she was the instrument of the invisible
                            world in her superior achievements. I have borne this testimony as a token of respect for a
                            people who are and ever have been since my first acquaintance most highly esteemed for their
                            superior excellence. Tunbridye, Vt.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Father, forgive them!" TEIform="index"/>FATHER, FORGIVE THEM!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., L. L." TEIform="persName"/>L. L. B.</byline><p TEIform="p">BY "Father, forgive them!" if these words were oftener breathed From the tried heart—from the
                            weird mind with torture wreathed, From the deep soul, when pierced with selfish, vengeful
                            wrong, Breathed those words divine in whispers, or in sweet song, They'd reach each sinning
                            child, and turn to good ere long. "Father, forgive them!" the power these words contain To
                            reach the vilest heart—the darkest soul reclaim From imbred sin and crime—from deepest,
                            poignant woe, To teach the erring truth—could saint and sinner know Their depth, their
                            height, their worth, 'twould be the prayer below. "Father, forgive them!" with His latest
                            breath, he said ; With arms outstretched, and meekly, nobly bowing head : "Oh, Father,
                            forgive them, they know noc what they do!" While thorns were on His brow, His hands and feet
                            pierced through,— In sorrow for Bis son, the Father God withdrew. "Father, forgive them!"
                            whether near or far away,— Those who have wronged us be it in our hearts to say, "For they
                            know not what they do," whether good or ill, Only the Father knoweth whom He chasteneth
                            still. "Father, forgive them!"—'tis Thine it shall be our will.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="At best, life is not very long..." TEIform="index"/>At best, life is not very long...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">At best, life is not very long. A few more smiles, a few more tears, some pleasure, much
                            pain, sunshine and song, clouds and darkness, hasty greetings, abrupt farewells, then our
                            little play will close and the injurer and injured will pass away. Is it worth while to hate
                            each other?</p></div2><pb n="270" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Creed-Christ" TEIform="index"/>CREED - CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> " For modes of faith let graceless zealots fight, His can't be wrong whose life is in the
                            right." The zealots, whose zeal originates in a desire to sustain a mere party with which
                            they may happen to be connected will fight. In this regard, Brahma has nothing of which to
                            boast over Buddha, nor Buddha over Brahma. Christianity in its historical phase exhibits
                            nothing superior to the religion of Mohammed, nor has the actual life of Moslem risen above
                            that of Christianity. Why ? Because the adherents of each have been mostly the bigots of a
                            creed rather than persons actuated by Divine love. If we can accept the record, this advice
                            was once given by an apostle: "Earnestly contend for the faith once delivered to the
                            Saints." Whatever the apostle had in mind it is certain that the exhortation to '' contend
                            for the faith " has been carried out to the very letter, not by Saints, indeed, but by
                            thousands ©f those who were "filled with all unrighteousness." Hence the history of mankind
                            exhibits no blacker crimes than those committed by such as claimed to be the successors of
                            apostles. It is unnecessary to give examples ; they are familiar to the minds of all who are
                            acquainted with history. The bigoted creedist very naturally arouses the contentious spirit
                            which he possesses in the minds of those who will not accept his creed. The language of the
                            latter is : " I will not bow with patient knees To worn out laws or bigot creeds ; My
                            Tiature hnows its wants and needs, And scorns all cant hypocrisies Of hollow words and empty
                            deeds. I worship what is true to me ; Have faith in what is just and right; No cloak shall
                            hide from my clear sight Those bigots of idolatry That hide the blessedness of light." And
                            so the contest begins and is carried on until not harsh and cutting words merely but the
                            most cruel of bloody deeds are the consequence. This is the record of history for centuries.
                            Is the present " enlightened age " different from the past ? If so, what has caused the
                            difference ? There are still conflicts among the creedists, but they are not of the same
                            fierce character as formerly. To what is this to be ascribed ? Partly, no doubt, to the
                            diffusion of knowledge among all classes. "Knowledge is power." "Light is that which makes
                            manifest." The bigots have in a measure been shamed out of their former senseless conduct.
                            If they still have the inclination they have not the power of the olden times. One is
                            reminded of Bunyan's old and enfeebled giant sitting in his cave while the pilgrims were
                            passing by. He is in age and feebleness extreme, and his former bitter and bigoted spirit
                            becomes weaker and weaker with the passing years. But not only is there greater light to see
                            the wrong, there is greater strength of judgment and conscience. The prophecy of old time
                            has not been forgotten by him who uttered it through human lips; " 1 will pour out my spirit
                            upon all flesh." The Divine life, which is Divine love, is to take the place ultimately of
                            the mere animal in human nature. In the language of Tennyson men will " Move upwards,
                            working out the beast, And let the ape and tiger die ; Rise on stepping stones of their dead
                            selves To higher things."' All truth must commend itself to us by its power to raise the
                            individual and society to higher things. It matters not through whom it may come as special
                            teacher. If it effect this necessary work, it proves itself of God, whatever name the
                            individual teacher may bear. Such is the Christ of God, and this is the language uttered by
                            the Christ to the Divine Father and in respect to all who are "partakers of the Divine
                            Nature." " Thou, Father, art in me and I in thee ; I in them and thou in me, that they may
                            be made perfect in one." When this is accomplished, the mere wild beast dies; the creedist
                            that was has nothing more to contend about; his creed, his ceremonies, his self-conceit that
                            elevated him to the throne of dignity, have all been blown to the winds, and his whole life,
                            whether physical, mental or moral, is divine, for it is the life of Divine Love. Most
                            Christians consider the Bible more precious than gold. But they lock up their silverware and
                            jewels at night and allow the Word to remain on the parlor table.</p></div2><pb n="271" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="English preacher proposes a new confession of faith and the abolition of sectarian lines" TEIform="index"/>AN ENGLISH PREACHER PROPOSES A NEW CONFESSION OF FAITH AND THE ABOLITION OF SECTARIAN
                            LINES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Joseph Parker</byline><p TEIform="p">[In a note appended in our November issue, we commented upon the growing and glowing
                            prospects of the rise and growth of a purer and broader Christianity. We copy from an
                            exchange some of these prospects, as proposed by one who is at least the second most popular
                            minister on the other side of the water.—Ed.] , pastor of the City Temple, and a
                            Congregational minister of some prominence in England, sends the following letter to the
                            London Times: " The boldness of the proposal I am about to submit warrants me in seeking for
                            it a place in columns no less distinguished than your own. You have recently published
                            reports of the primate's visitation addresses, and a day or to ago you commented upon them
                            in a tone with which my proposal will distinctly harmonize. I cannot but express very deep
                            dissatisfaction with the authoritative addresses which are delivered from many of our
                            ecclesiastical chairs from time to time. As sectarian or denominational addresses they are
                            admirable, and are justly applauded by the companies for which they were prepared ; but,
                            viewed in their larger relations, I cannot but feel that they are often wholly outside the
                            thinking of one section of the community, and the immediate need of another. Has not the
                            time come when the points of union should be magnified and the points of differences be
                            reduced to minimum 1 My own impression is that there are thousands of Christians in England
                            who have no connection with the sects, and who, strange as it may appear, are not aware of
                            their own Christianity. This anomaly is to be accounted for by the fact that in the hands of
                            the sects Christianity has become a set of theological opinions and definitions, instead of
                            being left as the spirit of selfsacrifice for the good of others. Christianity is not a
                            form, it is a spirit, it knows nothing of articles, catechisms, standards, and subscriptions
                            to tests or creeds. All these are merely human arrangements or conveniences, and if not kept
                            in their proper places they will do more mischief than it is in the power of atheism to
                            effect. I do not hesitate to say that sectarian theology is the most mischievous influence
                            of the age. Men who think carefully and broadly will never be united on this basis ; it is
                            too narrow, too vague, and too controvertible. Is it not possible to find a point at which
                            all reverent thinkers will unite in cordial fellowship ? In my opinion it is quite possible,
                            and if possible it must be infinitely desirable. Whoever adopts and practices the principle
                            of self-sacrifice for the good of others is, in my view, a living Christian, whatever he may
                            think of any point in socalled dogmatic theology. He may not even be a theologian at all;
                            and if not, so much the better, unless he be a man of very exceptional intellectual and
                            moral capacity. I make the broadest possible distinction between Christianity and theology,
                            and my proposal is to operate upon that distinction by encouraging the formation of an
                            inclusive alliance, whose one principle of union shall be that self-sacrifice for the good
                            of others is the true law of life. Christians most come to the rescue of Christianity when
                            it is disfigured by sectarian badges and compelled to speak the alien language of sectarian
                            definitions and orthodoxies. I do not propose to interfere with aDy thing that is legitimate
                            in denominationalism. As long as the world endures men who think alike will unite for the
                            propagation of their opinions, and this is most wise and proper ; but my inquiry is, whether
                            there is not below and above all denominational formalities a principle which can unite and
                            inspire men of the most diverse theological convictions, and whether that principle ought
                            not to be primarily recognized so as to set all differences in their just relationship and
                            perspective. I cannot but believe that there is a nobler word than Pan-Anglican,
                            Pan-Presbyterian, or Pan-Methodism, and that nobler word is Pan-Christian. The Trinitarian
                            and the Unitarian are both Christians, so are the Calvanist and the Arminian ; but when do
                            they ever meet on the broad ground of Christianity and make a common declaration that their
                            religion is deeper than their theology ? I leave my proposal of an inclusive alliance or
                            association to make its own im- <pb n="272" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 272 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. pression on
                            your readers, and I hope his grace, the archbishop of Canterbury, will not regard the
                            suggestion as out of harmony with his broad and generous addresses."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="G. B. Avery, Shakers, N. Y. : Dear Sir : Enclosed, please find 60 cts. in stamps..." TEIform="index"/>G. B. Avery, Shakers, N. Y. : Dear Sir : Enclosed, please find 60 cts. in stamps...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Minnesota, Wyoming, November 10, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Wyoming Chicago Co., Minn.
                                Nov. 10, '80</dateline><p TEIform="p">G. B. Avery, Shakers, N. Y. : Dear Sir : Enclosed, please find 60 cts. in stamps, for
                                which please send the Manifesto one year. I have examined the copies sent, and although
                                I am not prepared to indorse quite all contained therein, yet there is so much that is
                                good and true that I want to be a regular reader of it. I am a Methodist and heartily
                                wish they might all adopt the unselfish living of the Shakers and the communism of
                                property practiced by the Apostles. Yours very truly,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Davis, Nathan" TEIform="persName"/>NATHAN DAVIS</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor : Inclosed, please find one dollar to purchase..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Editor : Inclosed, please find one dollar to purchase...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Alfred, November 13, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me., Nov. 13,1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor : Inclosed, please find one dollar to purchase five boxes of your "Shaker Eye
                                and Ear Balsam," which I suppose can be sent by mail. Please send at once and oblige
                                Your brother in love, . " The Shaker Manifesto " grows monthly more interesting and in
                                favor with all Godly men and women. God bless your every effort to prepare for your
                                readers a monthly feast.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>OTIS SAWYER</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bro. G. A. Lomas: If you will allow me some space in the Manifesto I will..." TEIform="index"/>Bro. G. A. Lomas: If you will allow me some space in the Manifesto I will...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Pennsylvania, Pawling, October 30, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Pawling, Chester Co.,
                                Pa., Oct. 30,1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Bro. G. A. Lomas: If you will allow me some space in the Manifesto I will present a few
                                thoughts in regard to the society of Shakers I have recently spent some time with at Mt.
                                Le. banon, and from what information I have gained, I have realized that in utilizing
                                nature's resources to the comforts and conveniences of those who are readyand willing to
                                live the celibate life in a unitary home, that the society has proven a grand success;
                                has kept pace with the age of progress in agriculture, horticulture, fruit growing,
                                improved implements, machinery, buildings, etc, also in hygiene and the best methods oi'
                                attaining to, and preserving healthy bodies with all the appliances for cleanliness,
                                plenty of pure water applied inwardly and outwardly; also a system of drainage and
                                ventilation to insure breathing pure air, practical industry is also habitual, and with
                                all of these my sentiments agree. The religious forms to my mind are not in keeping wiih
                                the age of progress in which we now live, as religion is progressive as well as the
                                moral and intellectual states are progressive; and any system of worship, adopted one
                                hundred years ago, would necessarily be tainted more or less with the prejudices and
                                teachings of that day. Pure and unadulterated religion is the spontaneous outflow of the
                                emotional nature, and is as varied in expression as mankind differ in stature and
                                appearance. Whenever you undertake to formulate the emotional nature, the substance
                                vanishes and leaves only the shadows. To formulate religion is purely an individual
                                matter ; it cannot be confined or its qualities measured by any forms or ceremonial
                                worship ; it is only by the results shown in our lives. That individual who lives the
                                purest, noblest and best life, has the best religion, although he takes no part in any
                                forms or ceremonies of worship. The universe of matter is governed by fixed laws, and
                                man is a free agent, subject to those immutable laws. God has no arbitrary laws,
                                therefore mankind are at liberty to use the resources of nature to elevate and raise up
                                man in all his faculties both physically, morally and intellectually. Those are my
                                convictions after thirty or forty years of unprejudiced study and investigation into the
                                economy of nature, which is the word of God, as God has never spoken to mankind in any
                                other way than through natural law. We may have converse with advanced spirits or
                                angels, but can only talk with God through the phenomena of nature. Now as you can only
                                receive accessions from those without, and as the world of matter and all things are
                                progressing, you will necessarily have to take in those of advanced thought or confine
                                your additions to the illiterate or ig- <pb n="273" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 273
                                norant. I am an applicant for admission but do not wish to put on any straight jacket.
                                In regard to religion I want to keep my mind or reason unfettered. I want to keep
                                constantly on the outlook for the highest gifts or knowledge. (Truth is my motto and
                                reason my interpreter.) .</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Madden, D." TEIform="persName"/>D. Madden</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="D. Madden—Esteemed Friend: Yours of 80th inst., to the editor of Manifesto, was received..." TEIform="index"/>D. Madden—Esteemed Friend: Yours of 80th inst., to the editor of Manifesto, was received...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, October 31, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon October 31, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">D. Madden—Esteemed Friend: Yours of 80th inst., to the editor of Manifesto, was received
                                and considered. How shall I answer your reasoning ? "All ye are brethren." Jesus said: "
                                One is your master." Was that republicanism ? Is there, on earth, a republic? The United
                                States government is no more a republic now than before the war; this was a free
                                country. We are on the way towards a free government. "If the truth make you free, ye
                                shall be free indeed." When the truth is applied to us, individually, that is our day of
                                judgment. God, only, can apply the truth, and God can apply it only by some man whom he
                                appoints. The people are the fountain of power in the United States. The people can
                                exercise that power, only by some one man whom they appoint. You may call him by any
                                term you please. This being an infidel people, they appoint an infidel man to rule over
                                them, making it an infidel government — no church and state union. The Shaker order is
                                the church. The two are the new earth and new heavens that are being created. They will
                                move toward perfection. There will then be a perfect republic, composed of men and
                                women, whose rulers will do the will of the people. There will be a perfect monarchy,
                                paternal and maternal, with subjects who will do, not their own will, nor yet the will
                                of sovereign people, but the will of God — their Heavenly Spiritual Father and Mother.
                                In this kingdom God will be the fountain of power. The Christ Spirit will be the bread
                                coming down from heaven to feed the people — a minister of pure abstract truth, that
                                will convict the world of sin, rightousness and judgment, until God's truth becomes all
                                in all, in temporal and spiritual things. Hitherto, all governments have been a mixture
                                of church and State ; because the people are in a mixed condition—they are neither
                                natural nor spiritual—neither Christian nor infidel. It is the scriptural Babylon.
                                Shakers, being Christians, are infidel to all church and State theology, as are all true
                                American people. The mission of the angel of spiritualism is to disintegrate church and
                                State people, and their civil and ecclesiastical institutions. The angel went out from
                                the Shaker order to break in pieces the captain and his soldiers—the priests and their
                                people—the horse and his rider—the lawyer and his client—the doctor and his patient—the
                                capitalists and producer—man and woman. All this is being rapidly accomplished
                                throughout Christendom. "Yet once more (the second coming of Christ), and I shake, not
                                only the earth, but the heavens also—they are being shaken." Drops of water and globules
                                of mercury unite, being homogenious. How can individual men and women unite, unless they
                                become of one heart and mind—and how can they become of one heart and mind, unless they
                                subdue the lusts of flesh and mind? The mission of the Shaker system is to efiect this.
                                Except a man deny himself, and bear a daily cross against bad habits, will he ever
                                travel out of them ? A successful community indicates successful travel of the persons
                                composing it. A Christian community can't be composed of worldly people. After accepting
                                the celibate life, I wonder at your" straining at any thing else. A company of English
                                people write me from Boston, who wish to unite, but hesitate un. less we yield the point
                                of celibacy. You must not wonder if we think of the children in the market place—nor be
                                surprised if we conclude to hold fast the good we have secured, and wait patiently and
                                hopefully for the harvest to grow a little riper, before she, who sitteth upon the white
                                cloud of Shaker societies, receives the command. " Trust in thy sickle and reap, for the
                                time has come for thee to reap, for the harvest of the earth is fully ripe." <pb n="274" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 274 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. From the spirit and tone of your letter, I
                                conclude you have fully decided that the Shaker system will not suit you, or meet your
                                case. Asa general thing, when people are willing to live celibate lives, they easily
                                make the other sacrifices necessary to the existence of a Shaker community. Ghriftt is
                                not a human being, but an intermediate sphere of spiritual existence, me diatorial
                                between deity and the inhabitants of all material worlds. Its first appearance was in
                                the male—its second, in the female of humanity. The Pentecostal community was the fruit
                                of the Christ spirit, in its first, as in its second appearing. We shall feel much
                                interest in the progress of any attempt you and your friends may make to establish a
                                better system than this we are living under. I think there may be a successful
                                cooperative movement among men, on the basis of marriage—of great benefit to all
                                concerned. But a successful community must be built upon the foundation of Christian
                                celibacy. In much love, .</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust" TEIform="index"/>TRUST</head><p TEIform="p">"The clouds hang heavy round my way, I cannot see; But through the darkness I believe God
                            leadeth me. 'Tis sweet to keep my hand in his While ail is dim ; To close my weary, aching
                            eyes, And follow him. Through many a thorny path he leads My tired feet; Through many a path
                            of tears I go, But it is sweet T© know that he is close to me, My God, my guide. He leadeth
                            me, and so I walk , quite satisfied. To my blind eyes he may reveal No light at all ; But
                            while I lean on his strong arm I cannot fall."</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Philosophers say that shutting the eyes..." TEIform="index"/>Philosophers say that shutting the eyes...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Philosophers say that shutting the eyes makes the sense of hearing more acute. A wag says
                            that this accounts for the many closed eyes that are seen in church.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Real Christianity" TEIform="index"/>REAL CHRISTIANITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">If Christianity is superior as a religion to any thing previously presented to humanity,
                                and we claim that it is, the superiority consists in that it will make its adherents
                                really better ; not by the simple profession of an adherence to something claiming
                                superiority, but by an actual life that will bear the closer inspection of the wise of
                                this world, and meet even their approval and decision. That this Christianity is best,
                                because its adherents are happiest; not altogether because of its self-denials and
                                renunciations, but because general results make up the really better men and women —
                                those most truly filled with the love of humanity ; those most ready to suffer for the
                                safety of virtue; for the dispensations of equal comfort; for the blessings of peace ;
                                for non-conformity with the world, because such conformity tends to lessen the greater
                                blessings, and makes Babylon of valuable material. Eeal Christianity will never ask any
                                one to forsake any thing until it not only presents a better thing, but gives actual,
                                living evidences that by the renunciation, superior conditions are attained. Away then
                                with all the " will o' the wisp " and " bopeep " persuasiveness ! The true Christianity
                                is being judged by what it bears; and the Shaker Christianity of to-day is no exception
                                to this rule. Age, self-denials, special devotions, this, that, or the other specialty,
                                cannot condone for continued selfishness, want of charity and the milk of human kindness
                                — the love of self and ease, at the ex <pb n="275" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 275
                                pense of others' labors — inharmony, undeveloped virtues, in places of that genuine,
                                Christian, overflowing consecration to the gospel, that saves humanity from its selfish,
                                corruptions, by removing their cause. We claim for Shakerism, superiority only on the
                                ground, that by its superlative self-denials it presents better individuals— more
                                perfect specimens of what the heavens are peopled with; heavenly individuals, living on
                                earth—than any other persuasion does or can present! This is a great boast; but if we
                                can prove,by actual,living experiences,that Shakerism causes an incomparable increase of
                                purity, brotherly and sisterly affections; loss of selfishness, with an expansion of the
                                whole individual from the narrowness of self to the love of the race universal, we are
                                enabled to present a gospel to the world that very much resembles the Christianity of
                                Jesus, and a gospel very much needed to become very universal, before " thy kingdom "
                                can come. True, we, as Shakers, need the lash of parental whips to stir up our great
                                profession, into active, real Christianity. The lull of religious agitation and the
                                prevalence of worldly prosperity are apt to dull the keenness of our grand profession
                                and demands of Christian life—apt to cause a drifting with the current, and cessation
                                and forgetfulness of active endeavor to present a real, living Christianity to our
                                fellows—better than they have got by utmost endeavors to please themselves —and this to
                                be proved by renunciations of worldliness, selfishness and the lesser good, for the
                                acquisition of self-forgetful ness and superior manhoods and womanhoods. In vain do we
                                profess, if we cannot present a superior humanity—a better love than worldly poets sing
                                of, and merely animal men and women are crazy to enjoy. Eeal Christianity is rife with
                                renunciations; but it is also rife with exaltations of real manhood and womanhood, which
                                quite obscure the cross that did the elevating. "Folloiv me" meant actual following ;
                                actual life ; actual renunciation of the sins of selfishness and personal
                                considerations, for and in behalf of the greatest good to the greatest number. Real
                                Christianity and Shakerism ought to be one—ought to present a superior religion to the
                                blind, led by blind leaders; so that feeling and seeing and the hearing of the
                                testimonies, will create believers in and doers of actual, real Christian works. Let
                                Shakers present superior lives —those most redundant with Christian loves and graces ;
                                fuller of salvations and redemptions; and thus proclaim theirs the religion of real
                                Christianity.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the influential Christian clergy" TEIform="index"/>TO THE INFLUENTIAL CHRISTIAN
                                CLERGY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We the Shakers, wish to be presented properly, and to you : You are the invested
                                parties—invested by the constituted authorities of religious bodies, outside of
                                Shakerdom—to reveal to the people the most solemn and consequential errand that in our
                                day has been presented to the people. Your flocks look to you for the instruction that
                                will lead them to those.pastures, here and hereafter, that will be ever green and
                                positively satisfactory. <pb n="276" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 276 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. We ask you to
                                consider the primary principles that the gospel of Jesus intended : We hold, that it
                                intended a revolutionary, but peaceful change of the Mosaic dispensation; and to embrace
                                the radical, changeful views of the old to the new. This change would demand
                                acknowledgment on your part, the essential principles which we, the Shakers, are
                                endeavoring to present and press upon the whole world. 1. That Jesus, the Christ, while
                                acknowledging the good of the past, did present as superior life, Virginity ; not to
                                oppose, but to elevate the conditions which the civil contract of marriage would imply
                                and impose. Is virginity a necessity of Christian faith and practice? Then where are
                                you? Did Jesus teach the Christian practice of Peace ? How do you teach upon this
                                subject, pertaining to the family and to the nations ? Are your deliberations joro or
                                con to the constitution of an equality of the entire Christian family—and if pro how is
                                this to be accomplished under your teachings ? We ask you to consider the teachings and
                                practice of the earliest, Christian, Pentecostal Church upon this subject, and to teach
                                accordingly, and with no evasion. How shall you follow your divinely appointed master in
                                teaching, if you do not teach as the Shakers do, that Separation prom the World, and
                                from tuorldly practices is a Christian necessity ? And what is marriage ? What is
                                Private Property ? AVhat are War and Family Contentions ? What are Politics and the
                                general worldly commingling ? Are any of these of Christ Jesus ? However any of these
                                are pleasing to you, or to your would-be Christian teachings, will you not reform and be
                                honest in deeds, and teach Christ, and not self nor selfishness? Let us reflect. We ask
                                you kindly, dispassionately and without partisan and theological bias, to teach Jesus
                                Christ, and his simple, unpopular, Christian life. Will you do it ? ft</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Please" TEIform="index"/>PLEASE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">If any of our friends have a spare number or two of June, 1880, send as a favor to the
                                beloved, Mary Whitcher, Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our account" TEIform="index"/>OUR ACCOUNT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We invite special attention to our Debit and Credit for 1880. And then we ask for the
                                kindly help of every man and woman who loves Christ, to aid us in publishing the
                                testimony, if in the judgment of such, it is Christ's.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It will occur to some..." TEIform="index"/>It will occur to some...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It will occur to some of our valued readers, that they have been the recipients of The
                                Manifesto through the favor of a certain party known to us, free of cost to them. We
                                would be pleased, if they would notify this office whether the same is agreeable, and
                                how much so ; also, if they would be pleased to have the same party con- <pb n="277" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 277 tinue the gift another year. We need the help
                                of all who feel to help us; and would be pleased to append to our list of honorable
                                names, the great increase of all the names of the honorable men and women living. Hoping
                                we are deserving of such aid, we will, however, be glad to continue sending The
                                Manifesto to those who are worthy, yet perhaps unable to spare even the small sum we ask
                                for it as a subscription. Send for a sample copy, friends, free to you.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communistic" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNISTIC</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The attempt of Thomas Hughes, of Rugby fame, to establish a grand communistic settlement
                                in Tennessee is meeting cordial sympathy and hopeful anticipations. This communistic
                                relation is one of the features of a genuine, brotherly, Christian love. Even though
                                this feature may be inferior to other features of genuine Christianity, it is none the
                                less essential in making men and women of Christ. In the selfish relations of ordinary
                                life, marriage, private property, etc., there is a greed for ease and comforts — a
                                strife for the most and the best for me and mine — that occasions a war of households
                                which extends to a war of nations. All wars have their origin in the strife for more
                                than an unselfish part of the lands or enjoyments which should be universally enjoyed
                                and equally so. Hence, we glory in this new attempt at organizing a better, truer
                                brotherhood than commonly exists.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The soul of man..." TEIform="index"/>The soul of man...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The soul of man (let man in homage bow Who names his soul), a native of the skies!
                                High-born, free,her freedom should maintain, Unsold, unmortgaged for life's little
                                bribes.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Young" TEIform="persName"/>Young</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deceased</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clark, Polly" TEIform="index"/>Polly Clark</head><p TEIform="p">November 2, 1880, at Union Village, O., aged 82 years, .</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Caswell, Hattie Ann" TEIform="index"/>Hattie Ann Caswell</head><p TEIform="p">At Canterbury, N. H., Nov. 26, , aged 24 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Shakeress, living in the United Society of Believers at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y...." TEIform="index"/>A Shakeress, living in the United Society of Believers at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y....
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A Shakeress, living in the United Society of Believers at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.,
                                        and known as "Aunt Dolly Saxton," has attained the remarkable age of 104 years.
                                        She was born in Columbia county, of American parents, on the 6th of May, 1776,
                                        fifty-nine days before the Declaration of American Independence. Her parents
                                        were converted to the doctrine of Mother Ann Lee, and joined her church when
                                        their child was five years old, and she has always remained an honored member of
                                        the order.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Brethren's advocate" TEIform="index"/>Brethren's Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="[Autobiography of Antoinette Doolittle]" TEIform="index"/>[Autobiography of Antoinette Doolittle]
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It may not be known to the public generally, but there has been published, very quietly,
                                and perhaps too modestly, an autobiography of the leading Eldress of the Novitiate
                                Orders of Shakers, Antoinette Doolittle. We are not aware whether this gem is in the
                                market or not ; but we venture to give her address (Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.) while we will
                                have more to say of this little work hereafter.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Granger" TEIform="index"/>Granger
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The grangers must look well to their laurels, or certain Shakers, if not all of the fifty
                                families, will accomplish grander results than grangers commonly have done. Who so would
                                be a Granger after Shaker style let such send ten cents and get membership, addressing
                                Polly Reed, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. No objection to one individual getting several
                                memberships. We suppose it to be a very worthy institution.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pier, Helmes" TEIform="index"/>A SAD ACCIDENT</head><p TEIform="p">Helmes Pier, a worthy employe of twenty years or more, of the South Family of Shakers, N.
                                Y., was suddenly called from his existence in this world, by reason of a runaway team,
                                on Nov. 23, 1880, leaving an interesting family, as well as his employers, to mourn his
                                sudden and terrible absence.</p></div3><pb n="278" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sorry" TEIform="index"/>Sorry</head><p TEIform="p">We sorrow for the accident of a fire at North Family, Enfield, N. H., wherewith they met
                                with nearly a thousand dollar loss, losing their valuable drying house, roots, etc.</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Congrautlatory" TEIform="index"/>Congratulatory</head><p TEIform="p">We congratulate a certain eastern bishopric, that the ministry have new headquarters and
                                home at Enfield, N. H. Elder Nicholas A. Briggs, Canterbury, N. H., our dear old chum,
                                we salute you !</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Financial" TEIform="index"/>Financial</head><p TEIform="p">Cash received by us beginning Jan. 1, 1879................. $1,115 35 To printing
                                Manifesto, etc., 1880, 1,153 87 Postage on Manifesto, etc., 1880, 75 00 Extra on
                                wrapping paper, Music, etc.......................... 55 00 Due the Manifesto, from
                                various parties....................... 125 90 Friends of the Manifesto, due us, please
                                be prompt G. B. AVERY. Publisher.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Somebody's mother" TEIform="index"/>SOMEBODY'S MOTHER</head><p TEIform="p">The woman was old and ragged and gray, And bent with the chill of the winter's day ; The
                                street was wet with a recent snow, And the women's feet were aged and slow She stood at
                                the crossing, and waited long, Alone, uncared for, amid the throng Of human beings who
                                passed her by, Nor heeded the glance of her anxious eye. Down the street, with laughter
                                and shout, Glad in the freedom of " school let out," Came the boys, like a flock of
                                sheep Hailing the snow piled white and deep. Past the woman so old and gray Hastened the
                                children on their way. Nor offered a helping hand to her, So meek, so timid, afraid to
                                stir Least the carriage wheels or the horses' feet Should crowd her down in the slippery
                                street. At last came one of the merry troop- The gayest laddie of all the group; He
                                paused beside her and whispered low, "I'll help you across, if you wish to go." Her aged
                                hand on his strong young arm She placed, and so, without hurt or harm, He guided the
                                trembling feet along, Proud that his own were firm and strong. Then back again to his
                                friends he went, His young heart happy and well content. " She's somebody's mother,
                                boys, you know, For all she's aged and poor and slow ; And I hope some fellow will lend
                                a hand To help my mother, you understand, If ever she's poor and old and gray, When her
                                own dear boy is far away." Aud ' somebody's mother " bowed low her head In her home that
                                night, and the prayer she said Was, "God, be kind to the noble boy, Who is somebody's
                                sou and pride and joy!"</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doing good" TEIform="index"/>DOING GOOD</head><p TEIform="p">" We all might do good, When we often do ill, There is always the way, If we have but the
                                will; Though it be but a word Kindly breathed or suppressed, It may guard ofi some pain,
                                Or give peace to some breast." We all might do good In a thousand small ways, In
                                forbearing to flatter. Yet yielding due praise— In spurning ill humor, Reproving wrong
                                done, And treating but kindly Each heart we have won. We all might do good, Whether
                                lowly or great, For the deed is not gauged By the purse or estate ; If it be but a cup
                                Of cold water that's given, Like " the widow's two mites," It is something for
                            heaven."</p></div3></div2><pb n="279" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spurgeon's life and work" TEIform="index"/>Spurgeon's life and work
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We wish our space would permit of our doing justice to the most worthy firm of I. K.
                                Funk, No. 10 and 12 Dey St., New York, but it will not. We beg of our friends to address
                                the firm for a catalogue of their wonderfully cheap, but valuable publications. The last
                                one received was " Spurgeori's Life and Work," price 20 cents ! and how such books can
                                be sent for the money passes our comprehension, and at the same time meets our
                                approbation ; for all their intentions are of a noble and nobler type, than simply the
                                acquisition of money, for instruction of the valuable in literature is the special
                                intention of these parties. Write for their catalogue.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="North American review" TEIform="index"/>North American review
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The North American Review.— D. Ap pleton &amp; Co., New York, contains in its last
                                number, Dec, a valuable article by an old friend, Ex-Secretary of the IT. S. Treasury,
                                Boutwell, upon " The Future of the Republican Parti/." We would call attention to the
                                value of the publication itself, which invariably contains deep digests of prevailing
                                thoughts of the day.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious telescope" TEIform="index"/>Religious telescope
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Religious Telescope, of Dayton, 0., comes to us now in quarto form, like Christian
                                Union, Christian at Work, Independent, etc. We are pleased very much with it, and with
                                this change. We would suggest to all such an increase in their value, by cutting their
                                edges, which can be done by small extra cost.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good religion" TEIform="index"/>Good Religion</head><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A few prominent gentlemen of New York are supporting a mis sionary among the poor of
                                the city who first feeds and then preaches to the needy. An eye-witness of a recent
                                meeting along the river,front says: " There was nothing highflown about the preaching,
                                there were no dogmas brought up or assailed, and there were no Greek or Latin quotations
                                to be explained. The audience were of the humblest class; out at the knees and elbows,
                                with battered hats and worn-out, shoes. There were women as well as men in the crowd,
                                and not a few little children were among the grown people. All kept excellent order. The
                                tenderly spoken words were such as were adapted to raise the poor listener above himself
                                ; to excite in him an ambition to better his condition ; to be somebody ; to drop his
                                vices and put virtue in their places; to stop despairing and begin to hope; to cease
                                quarrelling with others, and to cultivate kindness, forbearance, and charity instead.
                                But the meeting was not all sermon. A handsome little wagon was brought up, with a tall
                                coffee-urn and a large hamper of bread. Men from the crowd were selected by the speaker
                                to fill and pass around cups of steaming hot coffee and slices of the fresh, light
                                bread. " I tell you, this is the kind of religion a man can take stock in," said a man
                                who had taken his cup of coffee and a bit of bread. " There is nothing of the priest in
                                this, who charges us for a seat in church and pokes us back in a dark corner where our
                                rags won't make the rich people hold their noses and keep as far away from us as they
                                can. There is no collection taken up here, and we ain't told we'll go to hell if we
                                don't pay to be kept out. This is the religion I want in mine ! " Others spoke in the
                                same way, and it was plain that the earnest worker held the affections of the people.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religious telescope" TEIform="index"/>Religious Telescope</bibl></cit></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A good life is the best philosophy..." TEIform="index"/>A good life is the best philosophy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A good life is the best philosophy, a clear conscience the law, honesty the best policy, and
                            temperance the best medicine. One riiay gather a harvest of knowledge by reading, but
                            thought is the winnowing machine. As we must render account of every idle word, so must we
                            likewise render of our idle silence.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="O, make thy life all pure and true..." TEIform="index"/>O, make thy life all pure and true...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">0, make thy life all pure and true, Fill it with deeds of high endeavor, Be brave to dare, be
                            strong to do That which thy God approveth ever. Let patience, gentleness and love, Crown
                            e'en thy name with thoughts of sweetness. So shalt thou walk all fears above, Man — woman in
                            thy rich completeness.</p></div2><pb n="280" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salt mackerel" TEIform="index"/>Salt Mackerel</head><p TEIform="p">. — Soak salt mackerel over night, after washing them carefully in plenty of cold water;
                                lay them in a dripping-pan, cover with hot water, and bake till tender ; drain from the
                                water, and serve hot with butter gravy.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Recently patented German process" TEIform="index"/>Recently patented German process
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A recently patented German process for making rancid butter sweet is to knead it with
                                perfectly clear lime water. After a few minutes' kneading the lime water is poured off,
                                and the butter is thoroughly washed with water. The rancidity is caused by the presence
                                of certain free acids, which are neutralized by the lime.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For welding iron and steel..." TEIform="index"/>For welding iron and steel...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">For welding iron and steel a composition has lately been patented in Europe, consisting
                                of iron filings forty parts, borax twenty parts, balsam of copaiba or some other
                                resinous oil two parts, and sal-ammoniac three parts. They are mixed, heated and
                                pulverixed. The process of welding proceeds as usual, the surfaces to be welded are
                                powdered with the composition, and then brought to a cherry-red heat, at which the
                                powder melts, when the portions to be united are taken from the fire and joined.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Care of clothing" TEIform="index"/>The Care of Clothing</head><p TEIform="p">. — A clothes brush, a wisp broom, a bottle of ammonia, a sponge, a hand brush, a cake of
                                erasivesoap, a viol of alcohol, should form a part of every toilet. After all dust has
                                been removed from clothing, spots may be taken out of black cloth with the hand brush
                                dipped in a mixture of equal parts of ammonia, alcohol and water. This will brighten as
                                well as cleanse. Benzine is useful in removing grease spots. Spots of grease may be
                                removed from colored silks by putting on them raw starch made into a paste with water.
                                Dust is best removed from silk by a soft flannel, from velvet with a brush made
                                specially for the purpose. If hats and bonnets when taken from the head are brushed and
                                put away in boxes and covered up instead of being laid down anywhere, they will last a
                                long time. Shawls and all articles that may be folded should be folded when taken from
                                the person in their original creases and laid away. Cloaks should be hung up in place,
                                gloves pulled out lengthwise, wrapped in tissue paper, and laid away, laces smoothed out
                                nicely and folded, if requisite, so that they will come out of the box new and fresh
                                when needed again. A strip of old black broadcloth,four or five inches wide, rolled up
                                tightly and sewed to keep the roll in place, is better than a sponge or a cloth for
                                cleansing black and dark-colored clothes. Whatever lint comes from it in rubbing is
                                black and does not show. When black clothes are washed, as they may often be previous to
                                making over, fresh clean water should be used, and they should be pressed on the wrong
                                side before being quite dry If washed in water previously used for white clothing they
                                will be covered with lint.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curious way to deaden pain" TEIform="index"/>A Curious Way to Deaden Pain</head><p TEIform="p">.— The Medical Record contains a notice of a new and curious method of deadening pain
                                which is of striking simplicity. It was discovered by Dr. Bonwill, a dentist of
                                Philadelphia, in 1875. In 1876 Dr. A. Hewson made a favorable report of his experience
                                with it to the International Medical Congress, and at a recent meeting of the
                                Philadelphia County Medical Society several papers were read on the subject, and much
                                discussion followed. In using the method, the operator merely requests the patient to
                                breathe rapidly, making about 100 respirations per minute, ending in rapid puffing
                                expirations. At the end of from two to five minutes an entire or partial absence of pain
                                results for half a minute or more, and during that time teeth may be drawn or incisions
                                made. The patient may be in any position, but that recommended is lying on the side, and
                                it is generally best to throw a handkerchief over the face to prevent distraction of the
                                patient's attention. When the rapid breathing is first begun the patient may feel some
                                exhilaration ; following this comes a sensation of fullness in the head, or dizziness.
                                The face is at first flushed, and afterward pale or even bluish, the heart beats rather
                                feebly and fast, but the sense of touch is not affected, nor is consciousness lost. The
                                effect is produced in females more readily than in males, and in the middle-aged more
                                easily <pb n="281" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 281 than in the old ; children can
                                hardly be made to breathe properly. It is denied that there is any possible danger.
                                Several minor operations, other than frequent dental ones have been successfully made by
                                this method, and it is claimed that in dentistry, minor surgery and obstetrics it may
                                supplant the common anaesthetics. Dr. Hewson's explanation is that rapid breathing
                                diminishes the oxygenation of the blood, and that the resultant excess of carbonic acid
                                temporarily poisons the nerve centers. Dr. Bonwill gives several explanations, one being
                                the specific effect of carbonic acid, another the diversion of will force produced by
                                rapid voluntary muscular action, and third, the damming up the blood in the brain, due
                                to the excessive amount of air passing into the lungs. The Record is not satisfied with
                                the theories, but considers it well proved that pain may be deadened by the method,
                                which it commends to the profession for the exact experimental determination of its
                                precise value.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to prevent the ravages of moths" TEIform="index"/>How to Prevent the Ravages of
                                Moths</head><p TEIform="p"> .— The destruction caused by these little pests can only be counted by millions yearly,
                                and they are the plague of every housekeeper. Unless you hermetically seal a cask or
                                box, you can scarcely keep the miller out, as she will crawl through a goodsized
                                pin-hole. Therefore we must use something offensive. Nothing is so effective and cheap
                                as petroleum paper, or even the common tar-roofing paper will answer. Buy the paper in
                                rolls, cut ii into sections long enough to cover inside, the bottom and the sides, and
                                lap over on the top of the box. All of the inside of the box must be covered, and on the
                                inside of this again place wrapping paper, so as to prevent contact of the nice clothing
                                with the petroleum paper. Use a large box— no matter about being very tight, as the
                                paper will cover the holes—and pack in all your woollen, and furs, filling it full.
                                Bring the paper up which has been hanging over the sides of the box and let it cover the
                                whole, so that the miller cannot enter the box without crawling over the petroleum
                                kpaper, which she will never do. Nail on the cover of the box and your clothing is safe
                                for three years if you want to leave it that long. This is a specific against the
                                ravages of the moth ; it is much cheaper and does not evaporate like camphor, and the
                                carbolic acid in it seems to act like an antiseptic on the animal fibre of the wool to
                                preserve it and make it healthful. In securing clothing against moths, if linen is used
                                for wrappings, no moth will molest. Paper bags are equally good if they are perfectly
                                tight, and so are trunks and boxes closed so tightly that no crevice is left open for
                                the entrance of the moth fly. As the moth loves darkness, it will not molest even furs
                                hung up in light rooms open to air and sunshine.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cold bath" TEIform="index"/>The Cold Bath</head><p TEIform="p">.— Although the daily cold bath is healthful and reviving, it must not alone be depended
                                upon as a cleansing agent. A man may bathe daily and use his towel even roughly, but
                                remain as dirty to all practical intents as though he eschewed cleanliness; indeed the
                                physical evil of dirt is more likely to ensue, because if wholly neglected the skin
                                would cast off the refuse matter by periodical perspirations. NothiDg but frequent
                                washings in water of at least equal temperature with the skin, and soap, can insure a
                                free and healthy surface. The feet require especial care, and it is too much the
                                practice to neglect the omission of daily washing with water; and the wearing of foot
                                coverings so tight as to compress the blood vessels and retard the circulation of the
                                blood through the extremities are the most common causes of cold feet. The remedy is
                                obvious ; dress loosely and wash frequently. The skin plays an important part in the
                                preservation of bodily health.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Apple jelly" TEIform="index"/>Apple Jelly</head><p TEIform="p">.—;Tomake the finest quality of apple jelly, the apples must be good and fully ripe; the
                                temperature cool, never higher than 60 to 70 degrees is preferred. slightest
                                fermentation of the juice spoils the jelly ; hence the whole process must be confined to
                                three or four hours, and with the mercury at 60 degrees to one hour. A copper evaporator
                                is used; it must be washed every day thoroughly.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do not keep your good manners for company, but be equally polite at home and abroad" TEIform="index"/>Do not keep your good manners for company, but be equally polite at home and abroad
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Do not keep your good manners for company, but be equally polite at home and abroad.</p></div3></div2><pb n="282" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every year" TEIform="index"/>EVERY YEAR</head><p TEIform="p">The Spring has less of brightness Every year, And the snow a ghastlier whiteness Every year;
                            Nor do Summer's flowers quicken, Nor Autumn's fruitage thicken As they once did, for we
                            sicken Every year. It is growing darker, colder, Every year; As the heart and soul grow
                            older, Every year. I care not now for dancing, Or for eyes with passion glancing, Love is
                            less and less entrancing Every year. Of the loves and sorrows blended Every year; Of the
                            joys of friendship ended Every year ; Of the ties that still might bind me Until time to
                            death resigned me, My infirmities remind me, Every year. Oh ! how sad to look before us,
                            Every year, While the cloud grows darker o'er us, Every year ! When we see the blossoms
                            faded That to bloom we might have aided, And immortal garlands braided, Every year. To the
                            past go more dead faces Every year ; Come on new ones in their places Every year. Everywhere
                            the sad eyes meet us, In the evening's dusk they greet us, And to come to them entreat us, _
                            Every year. " You are growing old," they tell us, " Every year; You are more alone," they
                            tell us, " Every year. You can win no new affection, You have only recollection, Deeper
                            sorrow and dejection, Every year." Thank God ! no clouds are shifting, Every year, O'er the
                            land to which we're drifting, Every year. No losses there will grieve us, Nor loving faces
                            leave us, Nor death of friends bereaves us, Every year.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light in the house" TEIform="index"/>LIGHT IN THE HOUSE</head><p TEIform="p">WHAT DR. RICHARDSON, THE AUTHOR OF " THE HYGIENIC CITY," SAYS ABOUT IT. Dr. Richardson, whose
                            articles on health have been cited so much, in a recent English pubJication produces an
                            article called " Health at Home," which is replete with wisdom. A most important point, and
                            one on which he dwells, is the fact that so many people are afraid of the light. " In a dark
                            and gloomy house you never can see the dirt that pollutes it. Dirt accumulates on dirt, and
                            the mind soon learns to apologize for this condition because the gloom conceals it."
                            Accordingly, when a house is dark and dingy, the air becomes impure, not only on account of
                            the absence of light, but from the impurities which are accumulated. Now, as Dr. Kichardson
                            cleverly puts it, we place flowers in our windows that they may have the light. If this be
                            the case, why should we deprive ourselves of the sunshine and expect to gain health and
                            vigor? Light, and plenty of it, is not only a purifier of things inanimate, but it
                            absolutely stimulates our brains. It is in regard to sick rooms that this excellent
                            authority is particularly impressive. It used to be the habit of physicians in old times to
                            sedulously darken the rooms, and this practice continues to some extent even to-day. In
                            certain very acute cases of nervous diseases where light, the least ray of it, disturbs in
                            over-exciting the visual organs, this darkening of the room may be permitted, but ordinarily
                            to keep light out of the room is to deprive the patient of one of the vital forces. Children
                            or old people condemned to live in darkness are pale and wan, exactly like those plants
                            which, deprived of light, grow white. Darkness in the daytime undoubtedly makes the blood
                            flow less strongly, and checks the beating of the heart, and these conditions are precisely
                            such as bring constitutional suffering and disease. The suppression of the light of day
                            actually increases those contagious maladies which feed on uncleanliness. Dr. Richardson
                            states : "I once found by experiment that certain organic poisons, analogous to the poisons
                                <pb n="283" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 283 which propagate these diseases, are
                            rendered inocuous by exposure to light." Once in England there was a tax placed ©n windows,
                            but this was driven out by English legislation after a while, never to be brought up again,
                            because it was a tax on human health. This leading authority on hygiene has a great deal of
                            fault to find with some of the architectural dementia of to-day. A fashion introduced in
                            England, and which has some feeble imitations in this country, is to reproduce the styles of
                            the Queen Anne houses. This peculiar method indulges in small panes of glass, overhanging
                            windows, sharp, long roofs, with tiny openings. It is a relic of ancient perversity,
                            picturesque, if you please, but perfectly at variance with the dictates of common sense. If
                            you have big windows, which say admit too much light, the glare of which is uncomfortable, a
                            shade or curtain will keep out the sun ; but have small windows, barely admitting the
                            invigorating air and light, do what you please, you cannot increase either air or light.
                            Such cramped windows interfere with the great work God gave to the sun. Architectural
                            elegance ought always to be subsidiary to the necessities of health. In the United States,
                            though with a climate differing materially from that of England, the laws of health are the
                            same. Our August glare heats our houses, but still it should be admitted at times. A house
                            darkened and kept darkened from the middle of June to the first of September is an
                            unwholesome house. Its coolness may apparently be refreshing, but the air of the rooms,
                            which stagnates, con. tains undoubtedly germs of disease, which are not the less dangerous,
                            because they are unappreciable. As it is, then, only the windows of the house, with panes of
                            glass which admit the light, the precautions to keep them clean and bright are not so much
                            measures of tidiness as absolutely hygienic necessities. As regards windows and their
                            construction, American invention has in this respect not advanced any thing like in
                            proportion to other things. The usual window, with its counterpoise weight, presents unusual
                            difficulties as to cleansing it. You can get inside of it, but the outside presents great
                            difficulties. Save in the lower stories, it may be pretty generally asserted that the upper
                            windows of a house, the most important of all which give light to the sleeping rooms, the
                            glass is rarely bright and clean. There seems to be a decided reluctance on the part of
                            builders to put in houses either the French window, which simply works like a door, or those
                            windows which, hung in the middle, revolve on the center. For ventilation alone, such
                            windows have great advantages over the old styles, and they can be cleaned with perfect
                            ease.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress of theology" TEIform="index"/>PROGRESS OF THEOLOGY</head><p TEIform="p">[We find the following item in the New Jerusalem Meszenger. It contains some wholesome
                            truths, and some pretty, discreet philosophy. If we permit that " subtle influence " to
                            appear constantly as a working reality, the imputed part of the philosophy will well deserve
                            another signification —one that will better agree with the injunction: " Work out your own
                            salvation." The whole, however, portends a better theology than is usual.— Ed.] Times are
                            changing, as the following very interesting experience, related in a letter from a
                            correspondent, will show : " I must tell you ione thing further. Dr. Kobinson, President of
                            Brown University, was preaching here last Sunday evening, and he said some things which
                            surprised and delighted me. For instance, he said we might talk and pray andsing psalms ever
                            so much and so earnestly, and it would all avail us nothing without character —
                            distinguishing this from reputation. He also said that that faith which is not completed in
                            works is no faith. Also, that by a true faith we are so brought into contact with Christ
                            that by a subtle influence the qualities of his character pass over to us, and He also draws
                            from us the evils of our nature, and this is what is meant by his righteousness being
                            imputed to us and his bearing our infirmities."</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unanticipated answer" TEIform="index"/>Unanticipated Answer</head><p TEIform="p">. — Teacher — " Charles, can you name a certain act which Job did about the close of his life
                            ?" Charles — " Oh, certainly; he died 1"</p></div2><pb n="284" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kingdom of glory" TEIform="index"/>KINGDOM OF GLORY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p"> Enfield, N. H. V 1. To the clime, the bright home of my fathers, My soul is attractivly
                            drawn; 2 Away, not so far in that region, In vision I view it at hand; 3. They tell me that
                            no voice of slander, No hardness of feeling is there; 4. That if we would have an alliance
                            With them in the bright world above, I would dwell in the midst of those arbors, Where
                            angels harmoniously roam, And fain would I pluck those bright flowers, That wave on that
                            beautiful strand. No tempest, no war cloud, no danger, But heaven, all peaceful and pure,
                            Our lives must be peaceful and pure, Our element, union and love, Away on those evergreen
                            shores, Whose banks are enchantingly dressed A glimpse of the angels before" me Gives
                            courage; they beckon me on; They teach me the beauty of order, The power of heaven's first
                            law, Pray ope heaven's portals still wider, Its influence more fully impart, M With
                            beautiful Paradise flowers, O there let my spirit rest. Hark! list to their clarion voices
                            Triumphing in victory's song. That all who aspire for that kingdom, From carnal affections
                            withdraw. That we may a closer communion Enjoy with the pure in hear*.</p></div2><pb n="285" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Crucifixion — a vision" TEIform="index"/>Crucifixion — a vision
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the Press and Knickerbocker. ] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">CRUCIFIXION-A VISIONNot with the deed upon Calvary's hill, When the Saviour hung
                                    bleeding, his life pulses still, Crucifixion was ended. The cross that stood there
                                    In His last solemn warning, that all must prepare, By true crucifixion, Salvation to
                                    share. Crucifixion of Hatred, and Malice and Pride — Of Uncharity, Selfishness — all
                                    sins beside That darken the soul and bind it to the Earth That hold it from rising
                                    toward Heavenly birth. Sorrow may crucify, misfortune and pain, The evil of
                                    others—their harm, if our gain— But here or hereafter Crucifixion must come, Ere the
                                    peace and the joy of Heaven are won. And woe to the spirit that passes throueh life,
                                    Gathering darkness — turning from light. A vision appears to my awe-stricken gaze ;
                                    A vision that fills my rapt soul with amaze. I see a steep mount, for earth's
                                    children to climb ; At its summit, a cross that stands through all time, And in the
                                    far heavens that open above Are circles of angels, bearing pity and love. Up the
                                    face of the mount stream the spirits of men — A vast, endless concourse that Death's
                                    minions send ; Each clothed with a garnment, self-woven through life — Of many dark
                                    colors — some black, and some white. External justice the cross stands beside, To
                                    each spirit that mounts it, his lance is applied — All that have woven their
                                    life-garments bright Suffer not on the cross, but ascend from the sight. While to
                                    every dark spirit, for each shade or hue, Retributive sufferings from Jesus issue,
                                    And such as grow pure by the pains from that hand, Are borne upward by angels that
                                    waiting there stand. But see ! On the cross hangs a soul black as night, 'NeatlTthe
                                    tortures of Justice it struggles with might; The venom of Evil pours forth from each
                                    wound, And its poisonous stain seems to darken the ground. And now 'neath the cross,
                                    through the heart of the mount, Deep ! deep ! below reach of all vision or thought —
                                    A black abyss sinks. This soul torn from the cross, Is plunged therein, for Hell's
                                    gain and Heaven's loss. Yet, not forever ! E'en now do I hear That voice through the
                                    ages, still echoing clear — That pleading appeal to the Mercy on high— "Father,
                                    forgive them" — all souls—ere they die. And now through the ranks of the angels
                                    above, Pours a sweet, holy light—the light of God's love, The blackness thai covers
                                    the realms of the lost, By that pure beam from Heaven is riven and tost — And the
                                    souls that are touched by one ray of its light, Start up from these depths, amazed
                                    with new sight — And moans of Repentance float up to the sky, As they painfully
                                    climb toward the Glory on High. While a voice like a trumpet sounds over the earth.
                                    So ends the vision. What lesson, if any, is shown ? Truth, meekness and goodness the
                                    spirit must own — And sin of all shades be .expelled from, the heart, Ere the soul
                                    on his Heavenward journey can start.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Press and knickerbocker" TEIform="index"/>Press and knickerbocker
                                </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warning to biblical scholars" TEIform="index"/>WARNING TO BIBLICAL SCHOLARS</head><p TEIform="p">Biblical scholars are sometimes sadly entrapped. In a little town of Bavaria, the other day,
                            sat an aged fraulein and her father confessor, who was, at least supposed to know the bible
                            by heart. The fraulein enjoyed a practical joke iu spite of her age, and and the reverened
                            father, although a thoroughly pious man, was not a whit behind her. Our fraulein said:
                            "Father, you may have heard that some of the persistent explorers in the Holy Land have just
                            discovered a huge heap of bones which are supposed, on pretty good authority, to be those of
                            the children which Herod killed." "Ah, indeed ! "replied the pater, thoroughly interested. "
                            Yes, I had heard of it," continued the fraulein, <pb n="286" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 286 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. " and, strange to say, nearly half the bones were white as the snow of the Alps,
                            while the rest were almost black as ebony." "Well, well," exclaimed the good priest, "that
                            is certainly very remarkable." "And the problem to be solved is," continued the fraulein, "
                            whether the white belonged to the girls and black ones to the boys, or vice versa. The
                            explorers were greatly vexed by the matter, and could arrive at no satisfactory conclusion.
                            Now, what do you think Father?" " Oh," wittily rejoined the priest, "of course the black
                            ones belonged to the girl babies, and the white ones to the boy babies." We ask the same
                            question of our readers, and they had better guess several times before they read the rest
                            of this paragraph. When they have settled the matter they can refer to the answer of the
                            fraulein, who, with a merry twinkle in her eye, said: " Father, you must have read your
                            Bible to very little purpose, for the account tells us that only boy babies were killed by
                            Herod."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be content" TEIform="index"/>BE CONTENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whittier, John G." TEIform="persName"/>JOHN G. WHITTTER</byline><p TEIform="p">. It may not be our lot to wield The sickle in the ripened field ; Nor ours to hear, on
                            Summer eves, The reaper's song among the sheaves. Yet where our duty's task is wrought In
                            unison with God's great theught, The near and future blend in one, And whatsoe'er is willed
                            is done. And ours the grateful service whence Comes, day by day, the recompense ; The hope,
                            the trust, the purpose stayed, The fountain, and the noonday shade. And were this life the
                            utmost span, The only end and aim of man, Better the toil of fields like these Then waking
                            dreams and slothful ease. But life, though falling like our grain, Like that, revives and
                            springs again ; And, early called, how blest are they Who wait in heaven their harvest day !
                            Hannah More says that there is one single fact that one may oppose to all the wit and
                            argument of infidelity, that no man ever repented of Christianity on his death-bed.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rise above them" TEIform="index"/>Rise above them
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">RISE ABOVE THEMWhen friends (?) assail, and try to put thee down, Or foes deride,
                                    and ridicule or frown, Unless they boast a Caesar's bloody crown, Or other
                                    awe-inspiring renown, Rise above them. Make sure thine aims and purposes are right,
                                    Then girt thyself with courage for the fight, Clad in the well-proved mail of honor
                                    bright, The victory shall be thine—in manhood's might, Rise above them. Seek not to
                                    put them down—but be thine aim, With mild forbearance, to awaken shame, Show that
                                    you will not cringe to wealth or fame, Won at the cost of honor or good name, Rise
                                    above them. Be not disheartened by their envious jest, Measure thyself with them by
                                    inward test, With noble emulation, do your best— By making thyself greater—not them
                                    less. Rise above them. Hold up thine head and show thy kingly face, Worth,
                                    intellect, and energy I trace; These coins, well used, will purchase name and place
                                    Worth all the phantom honors many chase, Rise above them. Above them—not in petty
                                    influence, bought With filthy lucre—by the vain mass sought; But in the glory of
                                    great, god-like thought, By high integrity and culture taught, Rise above them.
                                    [From the </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany argus" TEIform="index"/>Albany Argus.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not a bad story" TEIform="index"/>NOT A BAD STORY</head><p TEIform="p">The building committee of a church recently finished in New Jersey, wanted a stone slab over
                            the door, with the name of the church and a scriptural motto. It occurred to them that
                            nothing could be neater than "My house shall be called the house of prayer." So one of the
                            committeemen, who was in a great hurry, told the stonecutter to chisel on the slab the
                            thirteenth verse of the twenty-first chapter of Matthew. He thought the verse ended with the
                            words he wanted to use. The stonecutter took the whole verse from the Bible, and faithfully
                            copied it to the end. Imagine the horror of the committeemen when the stone was delivered [
                            It read: " My house shall be called the house <pb n="287" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            287 of prayer; but ye have made it a den of thieves." The stonecutter insisted that he had
                            obeyed orders. But the committeemen insisted that the motto he had inscribed was not what
                            they wanted, and that it would be of no particular use to them. That slab is now in the
                            stonecutter's yard, and any body who wants it for a tombstone can probably buy it cheap.
                            —New York Catholic.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="St. John the aged" TEIform="index"/>ST. JOHN THE AGED</head><p TEIform="p">I'm growing very old. This weary head That hath so often leaned on Jesus' breast, In days
                            long past that seem almost a dream, Is bent and hoary with the weight of years. These limbs
                            that followed him—my master oft, Fram Gallilee to Judah ; yea, that stood Beneath the cross
                            and trembled with his groans, Refuse to bear me even through the streets To preach unto my
                            children. E'en my lips Refuse to form the words my heart sends forth ! My ears are dull;
                            they scarcely hear the sobs Of my own children gathered round my couch; God lays his hand on
                            me—yea, his hand, And not his rod—the gentle hand, that I Felt, those three years, so often
                            pressed in mine In friendship such as passeth woman's love. I'm old ; so old I cannot
                            recollect The faces of my friends ; and I forget The words and deeds that make up daily
                            life; But that dear face, and every word he spoke, Grow more distinct as others fade away,
                            So that I live with him and holy dead More than with the living. Some seventy years ago I
                            was a fisher by the sacred sea. It was at sunset. How the tranquil tide Bathed dreamily the
                            pebbles ! How the light Crept up the distant hills, and in its wake Soft, purple shadows
                            wrapped the dewey fields ! And then he came and called me. Then I gazed, For the first time,
                            on that sweet face. Those eyes, From out of which as from a window, shone Divinity, looked
                            on my inmost soul, And lighted it forever. Then his words Broke on the silence of my heart,
                            and made The whole world musical. Incarnate Love Took hold of me and claimed me for his own.
                            I followed in the twilight, holding fast His mantle. Oh! what holy walks we had, Through
                            harvest fields, and desolate, dreary wastes ! And oftentimes he leaned upon my arm, Wearied
                            and wayworn. I was young and strong, And so upbore him. Lord now I am weak, And old and
                            feeble ! Let me rest on thee ! So, put thine arm around me. Closer still! How strong thou
                            art! The twilight draws apace. Come let us leave these noisy streets, and take The path to
                            Bethany; for Mary's smile Awaits us at the gate, and Martha's hands Have long prepared the
                            cheerful evening meal. Come, James, the Master waits ; and Peter, see, Has gone some steps
                            before. What say you, friends! That this is Ephesus, and Chrisfe has gone Back to his
                            kingdom ? Aye, 'tis so, 'tis so. 1 know it all; and yet, just now, I seemed To stand once
                            more upon my native hills. And touch my Master. Oh ! how oft I've seen The touching of his
                            garments bring back strength To palsied limbs ! I feel it has to mine. Up! bear me once more
                            to my church ! Once more There let me tell them of a Savior's love ; For, by the sweetness
                            of my Master's voice Just now, I think he must be very near— Coming I trust to break the
                            vail, which time Has worn so thin that I can see beyond, And watch his footsteps. So, raise
                            up my head. How dark it is ! I cannot seem to see The faces of my flock. Is that the sea
                            That murmurs so, or is it weeping ? Hush, My little children ! God so loved the world He
                            gave his Son. So love ye one another. Love God and man. Amen. Now bear me back. My legacy
                            unto and angry world is this : I feel my work is finished. Are the streets so full ? What,
                            call the folk my name ? The holy John. Nay, write me rather, Jesus Christ beloved, And lover
                            of my children. Lay me down Once more upon my couch, and open wide The eastern window. See !
                            there comes a light Like that which broke upon my soul at eve, When, in the dreary Isle of
                            Patmos, Gabrial came And touched me on the shoulder. See, it grow, As when he mounted toward
                            the pearly gates. <pb n="288" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> 288 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. I know the way. I trod it
                            once before. And hark ! It is the song the ransomed sang, Of glory to the Lamb ! How loud it
                            sounds ! And that unwritten one ! Methinks my soul Can join it now. But who are these that
                            crowd. The shining way ? Say!—joy'tis the eleven, With Peter first ! How eagerly he looks?
                            How bright the smiles are beaming on James' face ! I am the last. Once more we are complete
                            To gather round the Paschal feast. My place Is next my Master. O my Lord, my Lord ! How
                            bright thou art ! and yet the very same •&gt; I loved in Galilee, 'Tis worth the hundred years
                            To feel this bliss ! So lift me up dear Lord, Unto thy bosom. There shall I abide.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Select readings" TEIform="index"/>SELECT READINGS</head><p TEIform="p">" Dying in poverty/' says a modern moralist, " is nothing. It is living in poverty that comes
                            hard on a fellow." A religion that never suffices to govern man, will never suffice to save
                            him. That which does not distinguish him from that sinful world, will never distinguish him
                            from a perishing world .—John Howe. There is this difference between happiness and wisdom:
                            he that thinks himself the happiest man, really is good ; but he who thinks himself the
                            wisest man, is generally the greatest fool. Blessed be he who gives to the poor, albeit only
                            a penny ; doubly blessed be he who adds kind words to his gift. Say not, because thou canst
                            not do every thing, " I will do nothing."— Jewish Sayinys. Money, unsanctified, makes nobody
                            happy, neither do big houses, big barns, large acquaintances, power, fame, but he only is
                            happy that enjoys religion — he that knows his sins are forgiven, he and he alone is at
                            peace. The perfect man is the one who has a deliberate purpose to do the will of God in all
                            things, under all circumstances, and at all times, never resting in this or that point of
                            obedience, but going on, fixing Ms eyes on his high calling.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Serious selections" TEIform="index"/>SERIOUS SELECTIONS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A man rose in one of Mr. Moody's meetings and gave his experience. "I have been
                                    for five years on the Mount of Transfiguration." ' 'How many souls have you led to
                                    Christ last year?" was the sharp question that came from Mr. Moody in an instant.
                                    "Well, I don't know," was the astonished reply. "Have you saved any ?" persisted Mr.
                                    Moody. "I don't know that I have," answered the man. "Well, we .don't want that kind
                                    of mountain-top experience. When a man gets so high that he can't reach down and
                                    save poor sinners, there is something wrong." When the saintly Payson was dying lie
                                    exclaimed, "I long to hand a full cup of happiness to every human being." This was
                                    the language of a heart thoroughly purged of all selfish affection, and filled with
                                    the spirit of that love which led our adorable Jesus to give his life for human
                                    redemption. If every Christian would go out daily among men, filled with such
                                    longing for human happiness, what marvelous changes would soon be wrought in human
                                    society! The selfish element would be eliminated from the dealings of the Christian
                                    business man. Not justice merely, but benevolence, would enter into every act of
                                    trade. The same spirit would rule his home and churchlife. He would become an
                                    incarnation of good-will toward all, and would so preach the gospel by his deds that
                                    the man would see his good works and glorify his heavenly Father. The spirit of
                                    Payson is worthy of every man's imitation. Happy he who can truthfully say, " I long
                                    to hand a full cup of happiness to every human being."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Zions herald" TEIform="index"/>Zions Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer of Socrates" TEIform="index"/>The Prayer of Socrates</head><p TEIform="p"> .— O ! beloved Pan, and all ye other gods of this place, grant me to become beautiful in the
                            inner man, and whatever outward things I have may be at peace with those within. May^I deem
                            the wise man rich, and may I have such a portion of gold as none but a prudent man can
                            either bear or employ. Do we need any thing else, Phaedrus ? For myself I have prayed
                            enough.—Plato (Phcedrus).</p></div2><!--
    				<pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>