<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1105" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">5</biblScope><date value="18810501" TEIform="date">May 1881</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97- 120</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> MANIFESTO. G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT SHAKERS, N. Y. And
                        they shall turn to you for a testimony:'* ''Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO " The
                        Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1881. Vol. XI. ) No. 5. \ MAY, 1881. 60 Cents Per Annum.
                        The Shaker</p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="97" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plod on" TEIform="index"/>PLOD ON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Schultz, Maria L." TEIform="persName"/>MARIA L. SHULTZ</byline><p TEIform="p"> Plod on, brave soul, to thee as to all others Will come the final, promised rest at last;
                            Thy life-toil over, and thy journey ended, Its dangers narrowly, but safely passed. Plod on,
                            brave soul, on thee as on all others Will shine the gen'rous sun of God's good will ; What
                            though thou ploddest slowly, they are wisest Who walk with care, nor try to run up bill.
                            Plod on, brave soul, for thee as for all others The blessed rains of Heaven's love will
                            fall; Then do not faint and fear, but be all mindful Of Him whose loving care is over all.
                            Plod on, brave soul, 'round thee as 'round all others Will close the shadows of a dull
                            despair ; Yet cast not down thine eyes, but lift them skyward, The bright Hope-star is
                            beaming out somewhere. Plod on, brave soul, 'bove thee as 'bove all others Will flash the
                            lightning, will the thunders roar; But, afterward the sweet and gentle windharp Of Peace,
                            will tell thee that the storm is o'er. Plod on, brave sonl, o'er thee as o'er all others
                            Will burst the Golden light of Heaven's day ; Ah ! then be hopeful, steady in thy climbing,
                            From doubt apart, and from the night away. Plod on, brave soul —¦ nor weary in thy plodding—
                            On thee will rest as much of God's true grace As upon him whose feet unwary runneth. The
                            swiftest in this life's uncertain race. Plod on, brave soul, what if thou gainst the summit
                            Not all at once, nor first doth reach the God will not care as long as thou'st walked truly,
                            Hast climbed in Faith, and kept a patient soul. Plod on, brave soul, to thee as to all
                            others Will come the final, promised rest at last; Thy plodding over, and thy life march
                            ended, Its dangers narrowly, but safely passed. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Better and better" TEIform="index"/>BETTER AND BETTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Let knowledge grow from more to more, But more of reverence in us dwell; That mind and
                            soul according well, May make one music as before, But vaster." Tennyson. Eternal life, in
                            the Christian sense, means not merely endless existence, but perpetual growth in knowledge,
                            in wisdom, in grace <pb n="98" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> both external and internal, and in love, which
                            includes reverence to the infinite Creator and to all who are formed in His likeness.
                            Education in its full sense means nothing less than this. Like the gospel of Christ, it is
                            for all human beings without distinction of sex or color. Opinions may differ, as they have
                            differed, whether a monarchy, an aristocracy, or a democracy is best adapted to human social
                            needs; whether this class or that class, this person or that person should exercise the
                            elective franchise or not; but no individual man or set of men, whether styled the
                            aristocracy or the democracy, has the right to lay a straw in the way of human progress or,
                            in other words, the attainment of eternal life. Absolute right lies in the Divine intention,
                            and that, according to the Christian doctrine, must accord with Infinite love. But human
                            intentions and human acts, whether expressed in the form of law or otherwise, do not always
                            accord with this. Not even the democracy, that has often been so clamorous for rights, has
                            had regard for the absolute right. This name of democracy has seemed to serve a good purpose
                            for awhile, until many who had fonnded their ideas of human rights on the teachings of Jesus
                            began to suspect that it was used only as another term for slavery of the very worst kind.
                            One needs not go back a century of European and American history to prove the truth of this
                            statement. Names become perverted from their original meaning and sometimes come to signify
                            its very opposite. The Christian name has been obliged to bear that very disgrace; obliged,
                            because many of those who bore it displayed a character and conduct the very reverse of what
                            was borne by those who first assumed it. So Voltaire, referring to Jesus Christ, could
                            exclaim — " crush the wretch ! " In his estimation the name was synonymous with bigotry and
                            fanaticism. But why attempt to confound ideas that are naturally and necessarily distinct
                            from each other? "Each thing in its place is best." Intellectual conceptions are one thing,
                            the inspirations of spiritual life are another. Ideas, if in accordance with truth, are good
                            in their several places. A conception cannot take the place of a life, but it may lead to a
                            life. The conception of God, however feeble at first, may lead, by prayer, to the very life
                            of God. Cherish the beginnings of all good ; no matter if they are feeble, they will
                            ultimate in perfection after a sufficient time Clearness of the eye-sight is good — the
                            clearer the better. So is the faculty of hearing; so are all the human faculties. It is
                            better that each one should have his own eye-sight than be dependent on. that of another. It
                            is far better that each one should be able to exercise all his own faculties than be
                            dependent on those of others. This is a mere truism, but it lies at the foundation of all
                            mental, moral and spiritual growth. The young are entitled to the sound possession of all
                            the faculties, whether external or internal, that appertain to human beings. But human
                            ignorance, the parent of human vice, often deprives the young, in the very outset of life,
                            of the use of some one or more of the senses or of the mental faculties so necessary in this
                            the first stage of their existence. Doubtless the infinitely Wise and Good has methods of
                            compensation in "the better land," but oh, the pity that so many should be shut out from the
                            blessed light for many a dreary year, and that so many should be unable to listen to the
                            sweet sounds that fall so delightfully upon other ears! It is true, human benevolence has
                            done much to mitigate these misfortunes; but if a hundred years of existence upon the earth
                            properly belongs to each one of us, then it is well deserving the attention of the
                            philanthropist and the scientist to ascertain how this may be effected, and effected in such
                            a manner that life may be regarded by each as a blessing rather than a wearisome burden.
                            This may, indeed, be regarded as a task beyond human capacity. If it is beyond present
                            capacity, yet it is not beyond that to be developed hereafter. Years are often consumed in
                            the development of things intended for mere material convenience. How much better is man
                            than a machine 1 But the old adages will apply here—"Preventive is better than cure." "
                            Begin at the fountain to purify the stream.'" Will it be said that it cannot be accomplished
                            ? That these are <pb n="99" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 99 mysteries which belong to God
                            alone? They belong to Him no more than all departures from rectitude, whether physical or
                            moral. Those who have the faith .of Jesu*who bids his disciples pray — " Thy will be done on
                            earth as it is done in Heaven will not say it cannot be accomplished. If sufficient faith to
                            effect this is not now upon the earth, then it is time to renew the prayer, with more fervor
                            than ever,—"Lord, increase our faith " Divine power can effect this and infinitely more, but
                            the human must cooperate with the Divine ; and when the co-operation is continuous, the
                            knowledge will " grow from more to more," and what have heretofore been regarded as miracles
                            will be the common experience of life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harmony of God's universe" TEIform="index"/>HARMONY OF GOD'S UNIVERSE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Men and women of brilliant intellect are not always the most profound in wisdom It is
                            important that large talents be well poised, equally balanced, lest those who possess such
                            gifts, if they perchance to rise to a high eminence, either through vain ambition or want of
                            sound principle and fixedness of purpose, miss their aim and fall; and the higher the
                            ascent, the greater the fall. Hence it is far better, and safer, to seek to be just, than to
                            be reputed great, and ob'ain honor through wealth, position or fame. Knowledge, under the
                            guidance of true wisdom, is safe, pleasant, and profitable ; and enables its possessor to
                            avoid much of the misery that is the product of ignorance and want of discipline and
                            self-culture. But human life, in its best cast, is unavoidably fraught with many dangers,
                            vicissitudes, pains,disappointments,and sorrows; and they who are the most strongly allied
                            to earthly idols feel those conditions the most keenly; and such persons are apt to think
                            that material substances, which are the most tangible to the outward senses, are the most
                            real; while those things accessible only to the inner soul senses are vague and unreliable.
                            One of olden time, when he saw the iniquity, injustice and inequality existing among men,
                            and that " the race was not to the swift nor the battle to the strong, neither bread to the
                            wise, nor riches to men of skill," came to the conclusion that " Time and chance happen unto
                            all," and that there was no arbiter above or beyond. Others who reason more and have
                            brighter glimpses of an interior, far-reaching soul life, conclude that all existences in
                            the rudimental sphere have a destiny to fill, according to an overruling Providence that
                            shapes and guides, however we may will it. Others, again, believe that the power of choice
                            is given to every intelligent human being, and by the power of that choice, we mark out our
                            own pathway, and decide our own destiny. One point is quite evident: — the strongest,
                            brightest intellect, .and largest powers of receptivity ever given to any mortal being would
                            amount to very little without the added knowledge of personal experience and the experience
                            of others. Thus we all find ourselves debtors to the wise and unwise. The power of choice,
                            to a very marked degree, is given to every one; and we may learn by observation how to make
                            a wise application of the good and virtuous examples of others, and also how to avoid the
                            misdoings of the vicious and ignorant; and by thus doing, to a large extent, we shape our
                            own destinies. It is true that more or less we are creatures of circumstances. Some,
                            however, have the intuition and will force to control circumstances, and act somewhat
                            independently of them, instead of being controlled by them. Hence it is that what are called
                            self-made men and women are generally esteemed in society as worthy of honor and trust; and
                            when elevated to positions in National councils, more confidence is reposed in them, as a
                            general rule, for the reason that they have been able to guard their own honor, and maintain
                            their personal integrity through adverse circumstances; and have evidenced strength of
                            character, and firmness of purpose, quite beyond those who are born to a fortune and reared
                            in the lap of luxury, and tenderly fed and nursed, without feeling the stern hand of
                            necessity <pb n="100" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 100 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. and want laid upon them, and being
                            disciplined thereby. How true it is that " God never made an independent soul !" that is,
                            absolutely independent. All through the realms of Hi vast creation we find the laws of
                            dependence operative; and taken as a whole, productive of life, health and growth; while
                            abstractly considered, there could be no healthy result; but disintegration and decay would
                            speedily follow. The seas could not be navigated without the aid of canvas, steam, or other
                            propelling force. The soil could not be tilled without some kind of utensils adapted thereto
                            ; neither could artificers perform their work without instruments of proper shape and form.
                            The rolling ages that are numbered with the past are all witnesses of God's excellence, His
                            wisdom, majesty, and power, and how perfectly He has impressed His autograph even upon the
                            smallest leaf and flower, so that the whole creation is as one musical harp, attuned to His
                            praise and honor, and in harmonial accord with the great heart of humanity. Even the
                            prophets and sages of the past — who struggled through dark days and long nights of bitter
                            persecution, when ignorance and idolatry formed thick clouds which lingered in the minds of
                            cruel oppressors, and nerved them to strike deadly blows — found solace and peace, in the
                            dungeon and on the rock, through the voices of angels who touched the golden lyre and caused
                            them to hear triumphal songs that lifted their spirits above mortal pains and sorrows, and
                            made them able to render praise in the midst of devouring flames. Those days are past,
                            although some of the shadows, like specters, still appear upon the walls of the temples in
                            Babylon; but are powerless to act in this enlightened age of progress and liberal ideas.
                            Would Solomon, if he were with us today, attired in his kingly robes, with all his
                            accumulated knowledge of men and things, be heard to say that " Time and chance happen to
                            all alike !" If, guided by the light of science and the spiritual and divine revelation of
                            the nineteenth century, would he not be led to the conclusion that life in this rudimental
                            sphere is but a prelude to the life beyond, one step as it were in the grand scale of Being
                            ? And that although justice and judgment are not speedily executed, according to our
                            perceptions, still in the coming future all things will be weighed and measured according to
                            merit or demerit ? Science, whose home is in the brain, when alone, is cold, and tends to
                            criticism ; but when consociated with true religion of the heart, and harmonious and just
                            relations are established between the two, then there is a genial warmth produced,
                            beneficial to soul and body, and humanity at large reap the fruits; and the forces created
                            and brought into active operation by the united effort of conscience and intellect combined,
                            although unseen by mortal eyes, cause growth and development, and are rich in results.
                            Science, to a large extent, at the present time, seems to work unaided by the religion of
                            the heart. Its mission appears to be to break down and demolish old structures, and show the
                            crudities and absurdities of lone-established creeds of doctrine, and how flimsily they are
                            constructed. It is much easier to be an iconoclast, even if one is forced to strike hard
                            blows to accomplish the purpose, than to he an effectual builder.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Call of the spirit" TEIform="index"/>CALL OF THE SPIRIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>OTIS SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Let me treasure joys eternal, Let me drink of waters pure ; Let my love in God be boundless,
                            Build upon foundations sure. More in earnest, be devoted, Consecrated heart and soul, Ev'ry
                            moment rilled with breathing, That God's power may through me roll. Never period more
                            momentous,— Louder ne'er the spirits' call — Lo a voice is heard from heaven: " Zion rise
                            both great and small, Shake yourselves from sloth and slumber, Shake from selfishness and
                            pride ; Talents which the Lord has given, No more in a napkin hide. "Let the self-exalted
                            spirit Pall before the throne of God ; Let the doubting, double minded, Cleanse their hands,
                            and with God's word <pb n="101" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 101 Cut asunder flesh and
                            spirit, That a piercing light of truth May reveal their false position, And in honesty come
                            forth. " Fleeting, fading, evanescent, Are the alluring scenes of time ; Carnal joys in
                            pangs resulting, Sink the soul in sin and crime. 0, for strength to lift the fallen— O, for
                            balm to heal each wound— O, for faith by which to waken, That they hear the gospel sound.
                            Feigned your love to God in heaven, If you fail the least to love, Of your hrothers or your
                            sisters, With a pure angelic love. O, let earnest prayers be offered, That conviction, like
                            a wave, May roll on and touch each conscience, Sure to quicken, strong to save. West
                            Gloucester, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unsatisfied needs and cravings" TEIform="index"/>UNSATISFIED NEEDS AND CRAVINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Birdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BIRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p"> The unjust system of society has produced caste and class, depriving many of the rights and
                            needs of life, and bestowing upon others more than their equal share. The laboring,
                            producing classes are the most depressed by those conditions, and are rendered unable to
                            obtain the physical necessities of life sufficient to give them strength to perform their
                            daily task, and are forced by circumstances which they cannot change to plod on their weary
                            way year after year with a scanty pittance of food and clothing, barely enough to sustain
                            life, sometimes striving to accept with reconciliation what seems inevitable, and at other
                            times despairing and despising their lot, and even cursing their existence. Painful are the
                            tales of human suffering caused by poverty and unmet needs, which engender disease, and
                            produce premature death. They touch the cords of the heart that can feel and awaken
                            sympathy, and call forth compassion. From children we hear the sad story, " Oh, we were so
                            poor! Mother had to sell her shawl to buy a loaf of bread. Father had to pawn his coat to
                            get some supper for us !" And parents are heard to say : " We were obliged to work nearly
                            all night to support our family, and but little time to rest." Others have so much of
                            material wealth that they live without labor and luxuriously spend time and money. But we
                            rind that human beings, as at present, are a curious compound, made up, in a large degree,
                            of- inconsistencies. Some of the poorer classes, such as above referred to, are so
                            accustomed to a certain routine in life that it is difficult to change their condition in
                            society with profit to them, or satisfaction to those who would seek to benefit them.
                            Uneducated, and unused to mingling in social relations with others on a higher plane of
                            life, they do not know how to appreciate blessings that may be offered to them. If we
                            undertake to introduce them to community life, where all toil together for the benefit of
                            each and all, and in common, share the fruits of that consecrated labor, many soon forget
                            their former condition of servitude and want, and show a lack of appreciation by
                            complaining. They become so refined in their appetites and cravings^ that they are not
                            satisfied with common food and clothing ; and they look with jealous eyes, and murmur if
                            they are not soon made equal with those who have consecrated all their powers, for many
                            years, to lay a foundation, and build the home which they are invited to enjoy without money
                            or price. Such are quite ready to say .- " Oh, I thought Shakers were just, and believed in
                            equality!" Thus many times our efforts to do good prove ineffectual. We cannot censure
                            individuals alone for this condition of things. Society has fostered the worm that gnaws at
                            the vitals, and destroys the life-germ, and lowered the standard of justice, and generated
                            imperfect ideas, which produce their legitimate fruit. It is easier to depict the ills of
                            humanity, than to remedy them, we frankly acknowledge. Indeed we fail to see a remedy except
                            through Divine agency. We need an outpouring of the Holy Spirit that will take effect upon
                            all classes, the rich and the poor, to convict them of sin, of righteousness and of
                            judgment, a rekindling of pentecostal fires that will cleanse souls from sin and burn up the
                            lusts of the flesh and mind, and create a new and [fill the hearts of the <pb n="102" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 102 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. children of men with longing for spiritual food and
                            clothing ; the real instead of so much of the artificial. Now, as in times past, just in
                            proportion as we place our affections upon earthly objects, and fill the mind with those
                            things which please the senses merely for the present, we close the door of the heart
                            against the inflowings of the divine and heavenly, and are spiritually poor and destitute.
                            The pages of the past bear record, that whenever those who were called and chosen to bear
                            witness for God began to descend earthward, instead of looking upward and trusting in Him
                            for aid, they lost their power and became as fallen stars. Let Zion unite as one in the
                            prayer of faith and ask for living bread to supply the soul's needs.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law: prentissiana" TEIform="index"/>LAW: PRENTISSIANA</head><p TEIform="p">" Law is a rule of action prescribed by a superior, and which an inferior is bound to obey."—
                            Blackstone. So far, so good — but who is the superior, and who the inferior ? In barbarous
                            ages and countries, the biggest fighter, the conqueror, is the superior, the conquered are
                            the inferior. In half civilized ages and countries, the few, who by some kind of
                            7ioeuspocus, grasp the land and the learning, are the superior ; the many are the inferior,
                            in. the eye of the law. When humanity so ascends the progressive grade that the many are
                            disposed to do right, because it is right, the many are the superior ; the few not so
                            disposed are the inferior. As nnita of a nation, or state, it is our duty and right to be
                            subject to the laws of that nation and state. It will do us good. In a religious community,
                            the constituted authority, spiritual and temporal, acting in harmony, each in its order, are
                            the superior; we don't need an inferior. Entering the community, not by compulsion, but of
                            our own volition, it is our highest privilege, as well as duty, voluntarily to square our
                            lives by the rules of the order. It takes the conceit out of us ; fits and prepares us for
                            the Holy Eternal Father and Mother's Mansions of Eternal Brightness. We'll bless our saints;
                            and who has a better right to 1</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious sentiment" TEIform="index"/>RELIGIOUS SENTIMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> We are living in an age of activity. The force that acts upon mind and matter is electric;
                            thought, permeated by this subtle element, is destined to move the world to higher planes of
                            existence. The increasing liberality of the present time is a happy promise of the near
                            future when sectarian bigotry—the bane of religion—shall have been swept away by the tide of
                            intellectual expansion and true Christian faith, resulting in brotherly love. Christianity,
                            misinterpreted, has failed to meet the needs and aspirations of man's interior spiritual
                            nature. While ecclesiastical councils have spent centuries in contending over abstruse
                            doctrines, engendering hatred, strife and bloodshed, they have shut out from their
                            sacramental communion the living, loving Christ, in all the simplicity and heavenly beauty
                            of his life example; leaving poor hungry souls to starve on husks of theologic creeds,
                            devoid of the spirit that giveth light and understanding even to the most simple. Religious
                            sentiment is changing, evolving new forms, wherein shall dwell a nobler spirit and a higher
                            law than has as yet found expression among professed Christians. The great heart of humanity
                            begius to pulsate to the dictates of reason, justice, and benevolence. Dying, beyond
                            resuscitation, is that power that has molded mind in the narrow limits of soulless systems
                            of dogmatic belief. Great men and true women are clasping hands, and standing side by side,
                            in work that pertains to the common interests of society and civil government, without
                            questioning each other's differences on religious points- Acting out the genuine spirit of
                            religion, they rind that it needs no formulas of expression; it is that element of good- <pb n="103" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 103 ness, God-given and inherent in every human
                            heart, that wells up and flows out in sympathy, charity, forgiveness, and love. It is a
                            divine emotion, or principle, which, set in action, is sure to bless the world. Declining
                            faith in the mere externals of religion speaks of a broadening basis in the intellectual, as
                            a support for the spiritual structure, that shall meet the growing demands of the race.
                            Ordained ministers, preaching less of theologic mystery, and more of practical truth, are
                            awakening to an acknowledgment of the good that is being done by so-called infidels, who
                            speak plainly and pointedly against the great evils that are the outgrowth of the coercive
                            spirit of sectarian bigotry. Editors send' good sermons through the secular press,
                            commenting wisely on social, civil and moral obligations in all the transactions of life.
                            The noble work of the illustrious Thomas Paine is being better comprehended ; harsh
                            opprobrious words of slander and obloquy are softening to truthful and appreciative
                            utterances. The living spirit filled with the glowing inspiration of truth must prove
                            iconoclastic when its battery opens on ecclesiastical fortresses, which are now tottering to
                            their very foundations. But let us not mourn their dissolution. " I kill, and I make alive ;
                            I wound, and I heal," is the work of the Good Spirit acting through appointed agencies for
                            the uplifting of humanity. Disintegration and reorganization is a law of nature; change is
                            inevitable as a sequence of action. Reverential tendencies cling to old forms, and souls
                            whose limited vision and devo tional feelings prescribe a certain bound, look with sadness
                            upon what they deem modern innovation of materialistic philosophy, which they fear is going
                            to turn their cherished institutions upside down, and leave them no ark of safety, or city
                            of refuge, but send them adrift, on a sea of confusion and doubt; such do not see aright.
                            Fossilized and incrusted forms of belief are giving way by reason of internal pressure, and
                            burst just as naturally as does the crysalis or shell when the butterfly or bird are fledged
                            for a loftier flight. No great truth, whether enunciated by Confucius, Buddha, Zoroaster, or
                            Jesus, will ever be lost. The grandeur and stability of moral principles outlive all forms,
                            ceremonies and traditions, only on them as a basis can mankind hope to successfully build
                            any structure that shall stand the crucial test of analytical science, and in which all
                            peoples shall harmoniously blend in the worship of the good, the heavenly and divine.
                            Religion and science, handmaids of the Eternal Prototype of man, shall go together; and with
                            living, loving hearts, teach the higher laws of life in things natural and spiritual; 'till
                            a fullness of God's blessing shall crown the earth, with the new age of peace, prosperity
                            and universal love. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus betrayed" TEIform="index"/>JESUS BETRAYED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy S. Bowers</byline><p TEIform="p"> ''If there be a crime Of deeper dye than all the guilty train Of human vices, 'tis
                            ingratitude." And again, " To thine own self be true And it must follow, as the night the
                            day Thou canst not then be false to any one." From what we can learn through scriptural
                            record of the life of Jesus, and the time in which he lived, we can but sorrow at the
                            sufferings^ he endured, and wonder at the depravity of a race which could not produce even
                            twelve individuals who would be true to the trust, or to human liberty. It would seem that
                            at the time of the feast of unleavened bread, Jesus endured his severest trial. Judas
                            Iscariot was claimed as one among the number held sacred and dear, through ties of faith and
                            holy friendship ; but being led away by his own passions, and perhaps by outside
                            circumstances, he became darkened in his understanding, and rebelled against God and his own
                            soul, and sought through various means to betray his spiritual guide and Master. He was
                            tempted, as were many others, and sold himself for money. We conclude it was somewhere about
                            the niiddlejof the month of March, thatJJesus and his disciples seated themselves at a table
                            supplied with bread and water only; but <pb n="104" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 104 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO.
                            sufficient for him who had endured hunger, trial and hardship, without home, or even where
                            to lay his head, and felt the darkness around, and the perils impending over him ; he
                            refused to eat, but divided the substance among the guests, at the same time not only
                            intimating his forebodings, but actually stating his impressions in these startling words. "
                            Behold, the hand of him who betrayeth me is upon this table ; and truly the son of man goeth
                            as it was determined ; but woe unto that man by whom he is betrayed." We can hardly imagine
                            the condition of Judas' mind when those words were uttered; but vice is always added to vice
                            ; and here with the rest began to inquire, which of them should be guilty; they were
                            contentious and highly agitated, whereupon Jesus exemplified his Christian character, and
                            calmly remonstrated with them. He sympathized especially with Simon, and predicted Peter's
                            denial of Him, of which Peter was perhaps himself at that time unconscious. Soon after he
                            and his band repaired to the Garden of Gethsemane, which was at the foot of the Mount of
                            Olives, as was his wont. And in his awful, yet tranquil condition of mind, which quite
                            compared with the twilight darkness of the hour, he exhorted them to pray that temptation
                            might flee from them ! How traitorous and unworthy to bear the name of disciple were they
                            who thus hardened their hearts, and could harbor within their breasts such inhuman and
                            treacherous feelings! While yet upon his knees, he supplicated his Heavenly Father to let
                            the cup pass by, at the same time acknowledging his entire submission to his fate, or what
                            seemed to be his Father's will. He realized the presence of comforting ministering spirits
                            around him, and his agony so operated upon his physical tissues, that it produced bloody
                            sweat, which is said to have fallen to the ground. We know not how he became informed of his
                            imminent danger; unless'through his clairvoyant faculty or other mediumistic gift, he was
                            enabled to perceive the near future, or to discern through the conduct of his disciples,
                            their gradual fall from true integrity. " Little by little the sinner f alleth ; " which may
                            have been very apparent in that instance. And again, as the time advanced we are still more
                            deeply impressed with the fearful recklessness of the carnal mind. When Jesus, amid his
                            tribulation, so plainly manifested, paused between life and death, and observed those around
                            him, who seemingly with consciences benumbed, and hearts devoid of human affection, were
                            overtaken with sleep, still possessed of the same Christ-like spirit, he kindly warned them
                            against evil temptations; while at the same time the betrayer drew near to embrace him,
                            which, being feigned friendship, was worse than the strike of a deadly foe. He was not
                            deceived, but perceived the meaning of the action, which was understood by those'around. It
                            was the signal to be given when the multitude should have gathered, and it accomplished the
                            plan. He was subsequently led away captive; and soon after Peter verified the prophecy in
                            his false and willful denial. He seemed to have been convicted of his wroflg, and wept
                            bitterly upon recollecting the words spoken at the table some time previous, which we must
                            conclude he did not understand, or was blind as to its real meaning. From that time the
                            persecution of Jesus increased, which terminated his earthly career, by his crucifixion upon
                            the cross. We ask: Is it any wonder that Judas sought death, when he felt the stings of a
                            guilty conscience which must have followed him night and day ? Jesus is not the only man who
                            has suffered martyrdom for truth's sake ; but his meek and humble deportment commends itself
                            as worthy a great leader in the spiritual work of God on earth for coming cycles of time,
                            and also of our admiration and praise. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is fashionable in some localities..." TEIform="index"/>It is fashionable in some localities...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is fashionable in some localities to be very proud of ignorance, as if ignorance were one
                            of the virtues. Some one said to John Wesley, " Ah, Mr. Wesley, God has no need of any man's
                            learning." Mr. Wesley replied, " No, friend, and he has far less need of his ignorance."</p></div2><pb n="105" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fraternal sympathy" TEIform="index"/>FRATERNAL SYMPATHY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="persName"/>Mary A. Gillispie</byline><p TEIform="p">West Gloucester, Cum. Co., Me., ) April 1, 1881. J My Dear Stster Edith : Your sister
                            correspondent in this place with much kindness of heart asks me to write you a word of
                            sympathy, and so I will. It seems that you, with others, have been called to make a
                            sacrifice of one who was very dear to you by the ties of nature as well as by Christian love
                            and friendship; but as your faith is so well grounded in gospel soil, and your feet planted
                            in the sure way, this trial will be far easier for you to bear than if you were thus left in
                            the Earthly Order; this is one of the blessings which our community life gives. I very well
                            remember when I was a little girl, the parting scene between my oldest sister and myself and
                            brother. She entered upon spirit life; we were left to walk life's rugged paths with our
                            faithful sister Fannie considerably older than myself, whom I shall always love and bless
                            for her kind sisterly care. Well, my sister, what I wish to impress upon your mind is this:
                            When your younger sister was called away by the angels to her final home, you did not have
                            to bear this sorrow alone; but you were encircled by kind, loving mothers and angel sisters,
                            who not only met you face to face, but walked with you and talked with you, and each word of
                            comfort was a dew drop of gospel affection. You loved her and so did they. She was your
                            sister by the ties of consanguinity, and theirs and yours by the stronger ties of virgin
                            purity and love. She may have been doubly dear to you as a sister, because you had each
                            taken the yoke and cross, and had promised to be true; this was beautiful indeed ; that
                            pledge was witnessed by virgin souls in the other life as well as this. And let me say, my
                            precious sister, you must never lose sight of that pledge. You and your companions will
                            undoubtedly have as severe struggles with the enemy as those who have gone on before. You
                            will hear the same old story about the pleasures of a worldly life, its wonderful charms and
                            great and glorious privileges; but you must remember this very same story has been told to
                            hundreds and to thousands before either you or I ever heard it. If you have never ascended
                            that high mountain, with the tempter just ahead of you, drawing you upward by smooth words
                            and self-pleasing promises, you will be taken there, for there was never a soul who started
                            in the straight and narrow path but has climbed that mountain, and from its topmost rock
                            looked out upon the glories of the world and heard that voice charmingly say, "All these
                            things will I give thee if thou wilt fall down and worship me " etc., etc. But if you are
                            only able to say as Jesus said, "Get thee behind me Satan; for it is written thou shalt
                            worship the Lord thy God, and Him only shalt thou serve," then and only then will you have
                            achieved a great victory worth more than all the honor and applause of this world. You, as
                            one of a band of young sisters, are wonderfully blessed with beautiful examples of peace and
                            purity; and it seems that you cannot be otherwise than good. My love to yourself, your
                            loving Elders, and all the dear ones in your home. I always call Canterbury my home,, the
                            home of my early youth. Affectionately, Edith Caswell, Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Ct., April 3, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct., April 3, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shaker Station, Ct., April 3, 1881. My Good'Sister Edith: Once more I yield to my
                            corresponding proclivities. To-night as I sit writing I listen to the winds singing as a
                            requiem to a dying year. So swiftly the months have fled I can scarcely believe another year
                            gone. Yet so it is, and all in vain we question, whither? Silently the days came, and as
                            silently they went again. Each day brought its joys, its sorrows, its temptations and its
                            victories. If some were darkened by errors or passions, others were bright and golden with
                            good deeds, and angels must have sung a gladder song because of them. But whether dark or
                            whether bright, all are gone now. I would remember the past not for idle grieving nor
                            repining, but that I may make the present and future better. To-night, while all without is
                            wrapped in <pb n="106" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 106 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. silent darkness, I think of the
                            treasures the year has taken from us. Some are gone whom we held dear, and vainly do we
                            watch for their coming. It seems but yesterday, though it was in July, that we did the last
                            sad work for our worthy elder, Thomas Damon. For long years he had stood in "front of
                            battle." We knew he was growing old, yet so hale and hearty he seemed we had hardly realized
                            he had reached three score years, and fain would we have kept him longer. We love to think
                            of the life he lived here, so quiet and unostentatious, but so potent for good. If every
                            good deed and kindly thought here formed a flower in the pathway beyond, how beautiful, how
                            rich in sweet perfumes, must be the way along up the hill to God for all such as he. Better
                            than earthly fame or riches, better than the high-sounding praise of men, are the treasures
                            in heaven, and rich indeed is he who may claim such a heritage. How could we bear the heavy
                            trial and bereavement but for the comfort, consolation and hope God has given in the past,
                            and still so constantly gives in the present? But whoever is taken from us our duty is plain
                            before us and must not be put aside. There is no time for murmuring. We must work while the
                            day lasts, for the night cometh on ere we are aware, and we would not it should find us with
                            empty hands. We must not put off until to-morrow what should be done to-day. We feel that
                            the past year has been good to us; so we let the old go into the great silence of the past,
                            and welcome another year with thankfulness and trust. O how swiftly our time flies! and how
                            precious it is. God^who is most liberal in all other things, is exceedingly frugal in
                            dispensing this, for He never gives two moments together, nor grants us a second moment till
                            He has withdrawn the first, still keeping the third in His hand, so that we are uncertain
                            whether we shall have it or not. Wise indeed is he who can take the little moment as it
                            comes, and make it brighter ere 'tis gone. What need there is of constantly watching and
                            working. It is what we do with the little moments that determine our lives; according as
                            they are spent, usefully or selfishly, will the account stand. The sheaves we are gathering
                            moment by moment are those we must bear home when the call comes for us. With just the
                            graces and virtues that grow in us here must we begin life there in Heaven — nay, we may
                            begin that life here if we will, for time and eternity are one, and the Kingdom of Heaven is
                            within. Let me try in ery truth so to live that each to-morrow finds me farther advanced
                            than to-day. This is true living ; this alone will bear the perfect fruits of our Father's
                            and Mother's kingdom. I would unite in firmer faith, in all that is good, beautiful and
                            pure, and seek anew for the sure upbuilding of the self-denying work in the year untried
                            awaiting us. Still would I be your struggling, crossbearing brother,</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Is Christ your saviour?" TEIform="index"/>IS CHRIST YOUR SAVIOUR?</head><p TEIform="p">The question of importance to you is not, are you a Christian, but is Jesus Christ your
                            Saviour ? These two questions may seem to aim at the same point, but they involve very
                            different processes of mind, and therein consists the superiority of the latter over the
                            former. Your salvation must not rest on what you are, but on what your Saviour is and does.
                            If you look at .your self to find the ground of hope, you will never be satisfied unless you
                            are deceived. But if you look at Jesus, you can see reason enough for hope. Jesus Christ
                            came into the world to save sinners ; not Christians, but sinners. If you are a sinner you
                            may be sure you are one of the very class Jesus Christ came to save. The question, Am I a
                            Christian ? has troubled many an anxious mind for weary years; and the more the inquirer has
                            pondered it, the less hope there seemed of its settling. But there need be no such trouble
                            in settling the question. Is Jesus Christ my Saviour ? Whom did Jesus Christ come to save ?
                            Are you one ©f that class? Do you want him to save you ? Is he able to do so ? Is he
                            willing? These are the questions for you. The more you look away from yourself, and the <pb n="107" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 107 more you fix your gaze on Jesus, the firmer
                            your ground of hope will be. There is a great deal of time wickedly wasted on
                            self-examination, that might be profitably given to the contemplation of the Saviour.— 8. S.
                            Times. Comments : We copy the above, not with any approval of its sentiments, but to correct
                            all who have for years been led by such blinding sentiments. It makes all difference what we
                            are personally. True, Jesus Christ came to save sinners, by teaching repentance and
                            reformation from sin. Jesus proposes, nowhere, to save any in their sins; but to teach by
                            example a way out of sin.where the former sinner needs sin no more. This leaving the saving
                            work for Jesus to perform for us is a wicked and disappointing doctrine, even though it be
                            very hoary with years. Jesus seems to say with all good reason : " Sinner, do you want
                            salvation ? Then look at my life ; follow in my footsteps ; and as I am saved, so you may be
                            by the same process." It is high time that the deleterious, lying phantom of the past, which
                            held out that " Jesus paid it all— All the debt I oweNothing, neither great nor small,
                            Remains for me to do." should be rent into nothingness. And the very sensible opposite, be
                            learned and adopted as the truth : " Must Jesus bear the cross alone, And all the world go
                            free ? Nay, there's a cross for every one, And there's a cross for me "— and fully as big a
                            cross, and fully as active a work of self-examination and discipline as were presented in
                            Jesus.' life. Look upon Jesus' life ; and by a strict following thereof, find the salvations
                            of Jesus; not otherwise.—Ed. Manifesto.] [Remarks on the same, by C. Dibble.] How strange it
                            seems that men of professed enlightenment should give utterance to such shallow sentiments
                            as above unless it be on the principle that they choose to shut the entrance to the kingdom,
                            and neither go in themselves nor suffer others to enter. Our Saviour gave as the certain
                            criterion of discipleship and of the hope of salvation : " If any man will be my disciple,
                            let him deny himself, take up his cross and follow me." Therefore the question : " Am I a
                            Christian ? is the one of vital importance which should constantly exercise the mind of
                            every Christian traveller. Upon the settlement of this rests the hope of our salvation, each
                            one for one. And our souls can never look to Jesus with confidence, nor feel sure of eternal
                            safety, only by becoming practical Christians. And the more we study to invent some project
                            to be saved in our sins, the less hope will shine upon us. He is able to save us, and more
                            than willing, if we by self-examination, prayer and true obedience to the life which he
                            lived, become transformed into his likeness from day to day.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Experience and blessing of a veteran father in Israel" TEIform="index"/>EXPERIENCE AND
                                BLESSING OF A VETERAN FATHER IN ISRAEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brackett, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>JOSEPH BRACKETT</byline><p TEIform="p">ELDER . Dear Bro. Albert — Ed. Manifesto : Having been deeply interested in our beautiful
                                and instructive Periodical since the issue of the first number ten years ago, I have
                                long felt that it was duty as well as privilege to express my thanks for your faithful
                                and arduous labors in preparing such a rich, monthly feast for my eager soul. I more
                                than once read through every number, soon as received, until my sight became dim, and
                                for a few months past have depended upon kind brothers and sisters to read the
                                soul-inspiring effusions from the able pens of devoted fellow-laborers, who, from all
                                parts of our beautiful Zion, contribute to its columns, and from my heart breathe
                                blessings upon every one of them, for their love of the principles of the gospel of
                                Christ, revived by Mother Ann Lee and so clearly expressed, and for the beautiful life
                                of her virgin followers. My soul is enwrapped in love to this pure, virgin life, and I
                                have devotedly spent a <pb n="108" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 108 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. long life in
                                faithful service in the house of God; and my service to Him has been in strengthening
                                the foundations, building up and beautifying my Zion home, in being good, and doing good
                                to others; in strengthening the weak, comforting the strong, lifting up the faltering,
                                and trying to make the pathway of others pleasant. By these acts is my love measured to
                                my Heavenly Parents, and to the way which leads to eternal life ; and I have found
                                exquisite and abiding pleasure in crucifying self and selfish ambition, thus to serve
                                the Living and true God. I may be pardoned in making a brief allusion to my past
                                experience : In consideration of my advanced age this may be the last word I shall be
                                permitted to address you while I remain upon the shores of time, and, Jacob-like, I want
                                to bless the whole household of the Sons and Daughters of Zion, yea, and every soul
                                throughout the land who loves truth and purity. My father received faith in the Second
                                Manifestation of Christ when I was four years old, and moved with his family to Gorbam,
                                Me., and was one of the founders of that flourishing little Society numbering between
                                fifty and sixty souls, which in the year 1819 moved to Poland Hill to form an integral
                                part of the Society at New Gloucester. I was born May 6, 1797, thus I was brought up and
                                nurtured in the way of God, and at an early age wholly consecrated my soul and body,
                                time and talents, to this most glorious work which God ever revealed. to man, of
                                salvation and redemption from the nature and power of evil; and have lived a pure and
                                chaste life according to the best of my understanding, from my childhood to the present
                                day ; and my soul has tasted the good word of God, and powers of the world to come, and
                                I daily partake of the food of angels, and drink the celestial waters of life which flow
                                from the fountain of God. Having tested the wTork, by implicit obedience, I know whereof
                                I affirm, that living as Jesus and Mother Ann lived and taught, is the only way for
                                souls to find redemption from sin, and obtain an inheritance in their pure and heavenly
                                kingdom. I now find my reward more than the hundred fold promised in this life, with the
                                full assurance of eternal life in the near world to come, when I expect to complete my
                                redemptions, and travel on to greater degrees of glory. I do not claim that my pathway
                                has always been through flowery meads; like my Saviour and Mother Ann, deep tribulation
                                has been my portion very many times. Not quite eighteen years old when placed in a
                                responsible position in society, burdens increased as I grew in years, a portion still
                                resting upon me; my duties brought me in contact with a great variety of dispositions;
                                and heartfelt pleadings with the stubborn and willfully erring has wrung anguish from my
                                soul, especially when they turned a deaf ear to all entreaties, and forfeited their holy
                                birthright; and whatever the pretensions, no soul ever did, or ever will, separate
                                themselves from the Society of the true followers of Christ for the purpose of living a
                                higher, holier, and purer life than they are required, and may live in this sacred
                                Institution. But, amid all the perils through which I have been compelled to pass, I can
                                say, with St. Paul, that perils with false brethren has been the most cruel and hardest
                                to bear. Feeling that my days on earth are few, I would entreat all into whose care is
                                confided the consecrated property accumulated by the labors of innocent and confiding
                                Brethren and Sisters, to be true to their trusts, and use it as not abusing it,
                                remembering that sooner or later they will be called to render a just account of their
                                stewardship. I thank God that now in my old age I am associated with a few long and
                                well-tried friends, who have not faltered by the way ; yea, and surrounded by talented
                                young Brethren and Sisters, who treat me with every degree of filial aff'ction,
                                ministering every thing needful for my comfort, and I bless them every day. They are
                                growing in strength, and already many of them are trusty burden-bearers, destined to
                                become pillars in Society, whom I bless with every feeling of my soul, and my mantle of
                                true devotion and entire consecration I leave to abide with them forever; and the fruits
                                of years of consecrated labors is their just inheritance. They are all my jewels ; and I
                                    <pb n="109" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 109 shall never cease to watch over
                                them for good when divested of this earthly form. Be of good cheer, the Lord has heard
                                your prayers, and you shall yet see the bright glory of God shining round about you,
                                with sipiritual increase, which shall gladden your spirits and cause your hearts to leap
                                with joy. I will prophesy good to the Zion of Gfod. West Gloucester, Me., April,
                            1881.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, April 23, 1881" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, April 23, 1881</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">Union Village, April 23, 1881. Dear Albert — I send you a letter I lately received from
                                one Daniel Stewart, who lived at Union Village during the years of his boyhood. It seems
                                to contain ideas so much ahead of the average individual outside, that Bro. Chas. Clapp
                                thought you would appreciate the sentiments therein sufficiently to publish them.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Walla Walla, Washington Ter" TEIform="index"/>Walla Walla, Washington Ter</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Stewart</byline><p TEIform="p">Walla Walla, Washington Ter., ) April 23, 1881. f Friend Oliver — It is now nearly
                                eighteen months since I was at your pleasant village, where I whiled away some eleven
                                years of my childhood and youth. It was after the lapse of some thirty-eight years, that
                                I carried out the long-cherished plan of making a short visit to the home and the scenes
                                of my childhood, and to see some of the faces of those familiar to me in the morning of
                                my recollections. Most of those who gave me those moral lessons to guide my feet from
                                the snares of vice and sin, and inculcated in my youthful mind those lessons of virtue
                                and uprightness, both by precept and example, which have been a guide to me in after
                                life, and .for which I have ever held your people in grateful remembrance, had gone to
                                that bourne from whence none return; namely: James Smith, William N. Redmon, Henry
                                Valentine, James Hodge, Jas. Amphlet, etc. They were all men who were moved by the sole
                                desire to benefit others by their example and precepts. The appearance of your village
                                had materially changed from my youthful impressions. The fields, pastures and woodlots
                                had shrunken more than half their original size, and the different family houses were in
                                more neighborly distance of each other. There were other things, however, which age had
                                not altered and time had not dimmed. Those principles of order, harmony and fellowship
                                which pervaded every thing.and seemed to be the governing principles, made themselves
                                evident. The noblest principles of humanity rule your society and community. I felt that
                                selfishness, envy and the baser impulses of the human family had no home in your
                                Society. I have sometimes thought that a people who practice and teach such a rigid code
                                of moral ethics—whose only and highest aim is to elevate all to a higher plane of life,
                                and to make this existence more tolerable and worth living for; to reduce crime and
                                misery in this world, and be a model to those who wish to live better and purer
                                lives—could do more and better service in the cause of humanity by diffusing your
                                principles and practices more prominently before the thoughtful and inquiring people of
                                our country. The first object of all philanthropists is to elevate humanity, and make
                                man better for the part they have acted and the principles they have promulgated. When I
                                take an unbiased view of man and see the vice and sin and misery on every hand, and find
                                none able to offer a practical antidote against the sorrows and afflictions that beset
                                us on every side, I have sometimes despaired of any efficient remedy. I see in your
                                Society a way that would lessen the vice and misery complained of. When we come,
                                however, to apply those principles to the ruling of this selfish world as society is at
                                present organized, I fear all efforts in that direction would prove futile. We have not
                                arrived at that plane where selfishness will be subservient to the well-being of
                                society. I confess I look with a pyrrhonistic vision on the future of our race. But I am
                                glad to see the people of this country agitating the one-man monopoly of the broad
                                acres, that our common Parent gave to man as a common heritage, that should not be used
                                by any one to enslave his fellow-man. The God-given gifts, water, air and land, ought
                                not to be monopolized by any one man to the exclusion of his fellow-man. I own,
                                according to the laws of the country, some <pb n="110" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 110 THE SHAKEE
                                MANIFESTO. 3,000 acres of good land, which, I hold, I have no moral right to. I think
                                like William H. Seward, that there is a law higher than the Constitution. When we look
                                in every direction, and see the dictation of corporations and capital to Congress, with
                                no one to raise his voice in favor of the poor, the future looks gloomy indeed. If you
                                will send me a few lines on receipt of this I will feel much obliged. Give my kind
                                regards to all who knew me in the days of my youth, and my best wishes to all. My wife
                                often expresses to me her respect and admiration for your Society, and their kindness
                                which was apparent on every side. Yours truly,</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Albert:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Albert</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline><p TEIform="p">— You see, our friend speaks out pretty plainly concerning the present villainy of
                                moneyed corporations and monopolies, but it is from a standpoint of experience in the
                                practical chicanery by which government has been,is and will be more and more
                                manipulated by and in the interest of these infernal institutions; for he was for eight
                                years a member of the Oregon Legislature, much of the time entirely against his own will
                                or inclination. However, I submit all to the judgment of the Ed. S. M. whether to
                                publish this or a part of it, or none, as may seem best.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I know not any pleasures of sense more exquisite than..." TEIform="index"/>I know not any pleasures of sense more exquisite than...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Arnot, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Arnot</byline><p TEIform="p">I know not any pleasures of sense more exquisite than a draught of cool, clear water when you
                            are thirsty; but, few things are more insipid than water when there is no thirst. It is thus
                            that Christ and His salva" tion are very sweet to one, and very tasteless to another.— .</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The smallest crust may save a human life..." TEIform="index"/>The smallest crust may save a human life...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The smallest crust may save a human life; The smallest act may lead to human strife; The
                            smallest touch may cause the body pain; The smallest spark may fire a field of grain; The
                            simplest deed may tell the truly brave ; The smallest skill may serve a life to save; The
                            smallest drop the thirsty may relieve; The slightest look may make a heart to grieve; Nought
                            is so small but that it may contain The rose of pleasure or the thorn of pain.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism vs. it's modern interpretation" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN
                                COMMUNISM vs. ITS MODERN INTERPRETATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Volumes have been, and are being written by gentle, thoughtful men and women, in
                                opposition to the craze of late years, upon the subject of Communism. The majority of
                                the sentiments can bo very cordially accepted ; but where the destruction of Communism
                                as a principle is proposed, none who are believers in Christianity can acquiesce
                                therewith. The rampant, forcible determination to divide the accumulations of the
                                inordinately wealthy, at the risk of life and the peaceable foundations of society,
                                should be frowned upon, deplored and verily prevented. This measure of force is a very
                                weak one — it will never work. Let us say to those who would pattern after the
                                discipleshipof what is known as " French Communism"— revolutionizing, by force and
                                bloodshed, features in society which seem unbearable to the poor and depressed : these
                                features can be supplanted, by time, and reasonable persuasiveness ; but they never can
                                be suppressed as you propose. Apostles of liberty, of charity, of benevolent bequests on
                                most magnificent scales, were never so many, powerful nor effective as now. The Age of
                                Reason and reasonable comity between the wealthy and the poorer classes has dawned, and
                                will gradually cover the whole world with the most generous, human diplomacy. As the
                                rising of the sun and stars is gradual, yet eventually effective over the whole earth,
                                so is all the economy of grand<pb n="111" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Ill good
                                deeds slow, but inevitable in their coming and conquering. Christian Communism has been
                                badly mixed with that of the modern interpretation ; but no two things or systems could
                                hardly stand more widely apart. In Pentecostal day of old, " they were together " — came
                                together voluntarily —" sold their possessions and goods, and parted them to each that
                                needed ; and no man possessed aught he called his own ! " Under the civil rules of
                                modern society, the above is simply impossible of accomplishment. Be it remembered, that
                                the members of the above church in making it a model for the genuine Christian churches
                                that might follow, previously passed upon themselves certain resolutions which alone
                                could or can make such a life and system possible: Before parting their individual
                                possessions for the benefit of those in need, they renounced the acquisitive title of
                                husbands and wives and their partial blood relationships ; they bound themselves by the
                                most solemn vows neither to give nor to take offense; they renounced all the carnal
                                proclivities and vain fashions of the world, and like Him, whose disciples they claimed
                                to be, theirs were unselfish, pure, peaceable, unworldly, virgin lives. Now, we propose
                                to the world at large the reasonable reflection of true Christian Communism; and of the
                                positive, primary requirements that can alone make Communism successful or possible. We
                                propose to supplant the old system of husbands and wives; of individual possessions ; of
                                war and jealousies, and envyings and family feuds ; of the corrupting expensiveness of
                                gaudy fashions, by the simple rules which guided the Communism of the first Pentecostal
                                Community, knowing that like causes can alone produce identical results. As the "old
                                creation" cannot be suppressed, let us supplant it with the " new creation " of Christ,
                                having the Christ-life as our guide unto perfect, heavenly communism. And only as we
                                approach this life voluntarily, can a reasonable, endurable Communism be possible.
                            ft</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Physical resurrection" TEIform="index"/>PHYSICAL RESURRECTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are loth to quote the familiar, but unpretty expression, " the fools are not all dead
                                yet I " but so it seems; for we have lately received a neatly printed little book on the
                                above ridiculous theme. The intent of the author is to reassure his readers that the
                                same body that is put into the grave or cremation pot will, in God's own time and way,
                                rise up in perfected form, because the Bible says so. The Bible tells of a great many
                                things which happened once; as instanced in the speaking by Balaam's ass; and we have
                                confidently believed that circumstance never would occur again ; but must now, and hence
                                own being mistaken, when any individual attempts to force upon us the distasteful,
                                idiotic subject of Physical Resurrection. " Who ate Roger Sherman's body ? " You often
                                hear men of the world say of this or that professing Christian's acts, " Well, if that
                                is religion, I do not want it." That is not religion, and no one knows it better than
                                the faulty Christian ; but religion is the same, notwithstanding the imperfections of
                                those who profess it.</p></div3><pb n="112" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This number" TEIform="index"/>This Number</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">EDITORIAL NOTES. Of The Manifesto contains some very excellent thoughts by our excellent
                                contributors. One feature — that of the correspondent department, is worthy of special
                                notice. We would also call attention to the gentle sympathy of gospel friends for one
                                who recently lost a dear sister by the hand of the great leveler, death : and to the
                                realization of how the harshness of the circumstance is stolen away, almost unawares.
                                Our music is unfortunately omitted by reason of an accident unpremeditated, and by us
                                sorrowed. It will not occur again, we intend. Once more: we ask the kindly, good sense
                                to our appeal to "friends and neighbors."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children's music" TEIform="index"/>Children's music
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE CHILDREN'S MUSIC. We asked were the music came from That made her so
                                        wondrous fair, As she stood with the sunlight touching Her gloss of golden hair,
                                        And her blue eyes looked toward heaven As though they could see God there. "
                                        Hush," said the child, " can't you hear it, The music that's everywhere ? " God
                                        help us ! we could not hear it, Are hearts were heavy with pain, We heard men
                                        toiling and wrangling ; We heard the whole world complain ; And the sound of a
                                        mocking laughter We heard again and again, But we had lost all faith in the
                                        music ; We had listend so long in vain. "Can't you hear it?" the young child
                                        whispered, And sadly we answered " No." We might have fancied we heard it In the
                                        days of long ago ; But the music is all a delusion, Our reason has told us so;
                                        And you will forget that you heard it When you knew the sound of woe. Then one
                                        spoke out from among us Who had nothing left to fear; Who had given his life for
                                        others, And been repaid with a sneer. And his face was lit with a glory, And his
                                        voice was calm and clear And he said, " I can hear the music Which the little
                                        children hear."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Good words" TEIform="index"/>Good Words</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing and reaping" TEIform="index"/>SOWING AND REAPING</head><p TEIform="p">I saw the farmer toil On rough and rugged soil ; From early morn 'till night, He worked
                                with mind and might. ¦• The year rolled on ; and then I viewed his lands again, 1 found
                                the ground well-tilled, His spacious barns well filled. His was a rich revvai'd; And yet
                                I know, dear Lord, He must have toiled in vain, Without Thy sun and rain. I thought of
                                other soil On which Thy children toil, To root out weeds of sin, And plant Thy grace
                                within. There is a little spot There Thou hast cast my lot; Thou hast consigned to me
                                Young hearts from sorrow free. I've sought by toil and prayer To reap a harvest there;
                                When will that precious field, A plenteous harvest yield ? I've tried to sow Thy truth
                                Through many years of youth; I've marked the tender shoot And hoped for early fruit. But
                                human hearts, we find,' Like mother-earth inclined To nourish thorns and weeds Instead
                                of precious seeds.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Camel and the miller" TEIform="index"/>THE CAMEL AND THE MILLER</head><p TEIform="p">This, it seems, is an Arab fable. Read it, and see if you can tell what it means. Once
                                upon a time a miller, shortly after he had lain down for an afternoon's nap, was
                                startled by a camel's nose being thrust in at the door of his house"It is very cold
                                outside," said the camel, "I only wish to get my nose in." The mil <pb n="113" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 113 ler was an easy kind of man, so the nose was let in. "The
                                wind is very sharp," sighed the camel, "pray allow me to get my neck inside," This
                                request was also allowed, and the neck was thrust in. "How fast the rain begins to fall.
                                I shall get wet throngh. Will you let me place my shoulders under cover ? " This, too,
                                was granted; and so the camel asked for a little, and a little more, until he had pushed
                                his whole body inside the house. The miller soon began to be put to much trouble by the
                                rude companion he had got in his room, which was not large enough for both, and, as the
                                rain was over, civilly asked him to depart. "If you do not like it, you may leave,"
                                saucily replied the beast. "As for myself, I know when I am well off, and shall stay
                                where I am." This may show the meanness of unthankfulness, and the folly of giving up
                                too much to bad folks. And the camel may also represent habit. A bad habit almost always
                                begins with a little pleasant indulgence, then more and more, until at last the habit is
                                master. Keep the camel's nose out. Stop your bad habits in the very beginning. Then you
                                can fill the place God has given you in the world.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Never killed a bird" TEIform="index"/>NEVER KILLED A BIRD</head><p TEIform="p">"Thanks that I can say that I have never killed a bird. I would not crush the meanest
                                insect that crawls upon the ground. They have the same right to life that I have ; they
                                received it from the same Father, and I will not mar the works of God by wanton cruelty.
                                "I can remember an incident in my childhood which has given a turn to my whole life and
                                character. I found a nest of birds in my father's field, which held four young ones.
                                They had no down when I first discovered them. They opened their little mouths as if
                                they were hungry, and I gave them some crumbs which were innrv pocket. Every day I
                                returned to feed them. As soon as school was done, I would run home for some bread, and
                                sit by the nest to see them eat, for an hour at a time. They were now feathered and
                                almost ready to fly. When I came one morning I found them all cut up into quarters. The
                                grass round the nest was red with blood. Their little limbs were raw and bloody. The
                                mother was on a tree,and the father on the wall, mourning for their young. I cried
                                myself, for I was a child, I thought, too, that the parents looked on me as the author
                                of their miseries, and this made me still more unhappy. I wanted to undeceive them, I
                                wanted to sympathize with and comfort them. When Heft the field they followed me with
                                their eyes and with mournful reproaches. I was too young and too sincere in my grief to
                                make any apostrophies. But I can never forget my feelings. The impression will never be
                                worn away, nor can I ever cease to abhor every species of inhumanity toward inferior
                                animals."— Memoirs of Ghanning. And Cowper beautifully chimes in here : '' Let us love
                                mercy, And teach our sons to love it, too ; Remembering, that he who shows none, Being
                                ripe in years, and conscious Of the outrage he commits, Shall seek it, and not find it
                                In his turn." And again ; " Mei'cy to him who shows it, Is the rule and righteous
                                limitation Of its act, by which heaven moves In pardoning guilty man !"</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Effective retaliation" TEIform="index"/>EFFECTIVE RETALIATION</head><p TEIform="p">A Quaker had a quarrelsome neighbor, whose cow being suffered to go at large* often broke
                                into the Quaker's well-cultivated garden. One morning, having driven the cow from his
                                premises to her owner's house, he said to him : "Friend T——, I have driven thy cow home
                                once more, and if I find her in my garden again—" "Suppose you do ?" his neighbor
                                angrily exclaimed, "what will you do?" "Why," said the Quaker, ' 'I'll drive her home to
                                thee again, friend T-----." The cow never again troubled the Quaker.</p></div3><pb n="114" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My friend" TEIform="index"/>MY FRIEND</head><p TEIform="p">Here is a pretty piece of true philosophy, which our children could learn and declaim
                                with profit to themselves and those who hear them. . Who is my friend ? he who doth in
                                me see Nought but the good I do and fain attempt? Who all my work doth praise as grand
                                and good, And says that better man can ne'er be found ? Who sees no paradox in all I am,
                                No room to criticise the what I do ? Who deems my inmost thoughts have never been Less
                                white or spotless than the driven snow? Who says no lines by poet ever penned Are
                                tenderer and sweeter than are mine? Who to my name and self would add but fame To make
                                me equal and above the best ? Who thinks the eminence by me attained As high as
                                mountain's crest 'bove lowly vales; As eagle's flight above the tiny wren's? Who to my
                                every fault or sin is blind And thus to flatter me is but inclined ? Is he my friend ? I
                                answer "no!" My friend Is one who sees me as 1 am at heart ; My faults, my weaknesses,
                                the all that mars That mooted character—a perfect man— Or doth prevent my being what my
                                soul In high ecstatic state doth long to be ; Who is not blind to my defects, but who
                                Doth lovingly and kindly point them out That I may overcome and master them ; Who when 1
                                stumble on life's rugged road— As all frail mortals are full apt to do— Doth say to me :
                                "Arise ! press on again, Ne'er grieving o'er the fall or pain received, But with renewed
                                ambition onward press, Avoiding rocks you've stumbled o'er before, Save but to point
                                them out to other souls, Perhaps less able to outlive a fall." He is my friend who when
                                the ones I've loved Have turned their backs on me in cold disdain, Who when my
                                staunchest friends—or rather those Who've known me long, and I had counted such— Do pity
                                me and greet me with a sigh, In feigned regret that I have missed success, Doth greet me
                                with a smile and heartiness That proves he knew I had deserved success, And given time
                                would yet success achieve. He is my friend who when the earnings haTd Of many years doth
                                melt away as snow, And I from wealth to penury am hurled, And toil from morn till night
                                to earn my bread, Doth still extend to me the hand of love ; Who tells me of the trials
                                he has had, And how by patient toil he conquered them; Who tells me of the patriots and
                                those Who fought their way through difficulties soreYes, insurmountable to common minds—
                                And proudly feels that I will onward march To grand success and its attendant joys ;
                                Yet, though he feels all this, and gives it voice, He does not think my life perfection
                                is, But scans it closely and doth here and there Point out where I may work and better
                                it. He is my friend, and though in after years— When on the scroll of fame my name is
                                carved Or he 'neath cruel want or scorn may bend—¦ The world may laugh that I should
                                call him such, Still will I prove to him as true a friend As he, in my sore need, has
                                been to me.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sailor boy in a storm" TEIform="index"/>THE SAILOR BOY IN A STORM</head><p TEIform="p">A young sailor boy was in a storm. He was indeed a little boy, far better fitted for
                                thumbing a spelling-book than furling a sail in a storm. But his mother was a widow, and
                                there was no other way for the boy to earn a living for himself and mother than at sea.
                                The ship was rolling sadly ; and some of the rigging got foul at the mainmast-head, so
                                that some one must go up to set it straight. But it was a task of peril. The mate told
                                the boy to climb to the mast-head. He lifted his cap and glanced at the swinging mast
                                and the boiling sea. He stood for a moment in silence ; then rushed across the deck, and
                                ran down into the cabin. He was there about two minutes, when he returned and laid his
                                hands on the ropes, and went up with a cheerful and brave will. "My eyes," says a
                                passenger, "followed him till my head grew dizzy, when I turned and asked the mate why
                                he sent the boy aloft, saying he could not come down alive " 'Why did you send him?' "
                                'I did it,' replied the mate, 'to save life. We have sometimes lost men overboard, but
                                never lost a boy. See how he holds like a squirrel. He is careful : he will come down
                                safe!' "Again I looked till a tear dimmed my eye, and I was compelled to turn away,
                                expecting every moment to hear his last fall. In about fifteen or twenty minutes,
                                however, he came down ; and raising himself up with <pb n="115" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. 115 a sense of having performed a manly act, he walked away with a smile on
                                his face. "In the course of the day I spoke to him, and asked him why he paused when he
                                was ordered up aloft. " 'I went, sir,' said the boy, 'to pray.' '' 'Do you pray ?' "
                                'Yes, sir ; I thought that I might not come down alive, and I went to commit my soul to
                                God.' " 'Where did you learn to pray ?' " 'At home ; my mother wished me to go to the
                                Sabbath school, and my teacher urged me to pray to God to keep me, and I do,' " 'What
                                was that which you had in your jacket pocket ? ' " 'My Testament, which my teacher gave
                                me. I thought that if I did perish, I would have the Word of God close to my heart.' "
                                Who that reads this account acts like the sailor boy at sea ? Do we pray ? And when do
                                we pray ?</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the living" TEIform="index"/>TRIBUTE TO THE LIVING</head><p TEIform="p">If our dearly beloved Sister Dolly Saxton will be so good as to live until this number of
                                The Manifesto reaches her at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.., we will congratulate her upon
                                reaching her 106 complete years, and a good life of years too, on May G, 1881. We hear
                                her health is still fairly good ! Ed.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received" TEIform="index"/>Received</head><p TEIform="p"> : As a gift for Tub Manifesto, from J. W. Randolph, Shakers, N. Y., $5.00. [There are
                                some good folks living, and generously mindful .of The Manifesto's interest.]</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Friends and neighbors" TEIform="index"/>FRIENDS AND NEIGHBORS</head><p TEIform="p">While we would not presume to use our prerogative for the animadversion of any who so
                                kindly love us, and sustain oar Manifesto as they would and do ; yet, we are constrained
                                to offer, in explanation, the reasons for the absence of seven very nicely written, and
                                most respectful mementoes, of as many lately and dearly departed. The publication of
                                these would occupy more than eleven pages of our Manifesto. If agreeable to the majority
                                of our readers, we could make up one whole number as a literal Mausoleum, just to see
                                how it would appear. Having declined several long notices of very eminent individuals,
                                it is only fair and impartial that we hold to this decision — one which we deem would be
                                an agreeable one to those deceased, were they now living — to accept, for publication,
                                no long mortuary notices. We hope for the union and sympathy of all our good folks in
                                the same. Ed.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>DECEASED</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chaffin, Chloe" TEIform="index"/>Chloe Chaffin</head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, N. H., March 24,1881, aged 85 years</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tucker, Sallie Ann" TEIform="index"/>Sallie Ann Tucker</head><p TEIform="p">Also, suddenly, , April 4, aged 6.4 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dring, Mercy" TEIform="index"/>Mercy Dring</head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Mass., April 9, , aged 76 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peterson, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Peterson</head><p TEIform="p">At West Gloucester, Me., April 8, , aged 60 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Giles, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Thomas Giles</head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, 0., March 17, , aged 83.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whiteley, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Whiteley</head><p TEIform="p">In the United Society, Shirley, Mass., on the 23d March, , a native of Huddersfield,
                                    Yorkshire, England, aged 80.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sharp, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Sharp</head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, March 31, , aged 84 years. [This noble woman was sister to that most
                                    dearly loved Eldress Sally Sharp, of Western fame, and who once lived in the Central
                                    Western Society.]</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bates, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Bates</head><p TEIform="p">Also, April 9, (sister to the late, most highly honored, Eldkess Betsy Bates), aged
                                    88 years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following from an exchange hits the nail on the head..." TEIform="index"/>The following from an exchange hits the nail on the head...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The following from an exchange hits the nail on the head : " Intelligence means thrift,
                                honesty and rational enjoyment. Ignorance means vice, poverty,crirne,wretchedness. Money
                                spent in educating the people will save ten fold the expense in jails, almshouses and
                                criminal courts. It is the duty of every one to encourage education in every possible
                                way." A horse cannot say yea, but he can neigh.</p></div3></div2><pb n="116" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Commercial Advertiser of New York" TEIform="index"/>Commercial Advertiser of New York
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Commercial Advertiser of New York, lately enlarged, and with new dress, is certainly
                                the best newspaper that hails from the metropolis. Besides being as enterprising as any
                                of its contemporaries in the line of news, its editorials are surpassingly valuable and
                                instructive. Our old and kind friend, H. J. Hastings, is editor and proprietor, and is
                                one of the wisest of nature's noblemen. Send for a sample copy.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our little ones" TEIform="index"/>Our Little Ones</head><p TEIform="p">Published by the Rus. sell Publishing Company, 149 A Tremont street, Boston, Mass. This
                                magazine is a monthly ; and for children of ten years or younger, we think it the very
                                best periodical extant. Its illustrations are very numerous and fine. We invite our
                                readers to get copies on trial. Its subscription price is $1.50 per year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dyspepsia" TEIform="index"/>Dyspepsia</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="L., G. A." TEIform="persName"/> G. A. L.</byline><p TEIform="p"> — We get this remedy for the above distressing complaint from one who cured himself, and
                                is now curing doctors of medicine, who have no faith in their own nostrums, yet who are
                                afflicted — and the success has been simply marvelous : Get two ounces essence
                                wintergreenTake after each meal, one teaspoonful, in a little water or milk. When
                                relieved, stop taking the dose ; but pass the recipe to your nearest afflicted neighbor.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure of dandruff" TEIform="index"/>Cure for Dandruff</head><p TEIform="p">.—The Journal of Pharmacy asserts that a preparation of one ounce of sulphur and one
                                quart of water, repeatedly agitated during intervals of a few hours,will, in a few week,
                                remove every trace of dandruif from the scalp, and the hair will become soft and glossy.
                                The head should be saturated every morning with the clear liquid. He says, " I do not
                                pretend to explain the modus operandi of the treatment, for it is well known that
                                sublimed sulphur is almost or wholly insoluble, and the liquid used was destitute of
                                taste, color or smell. The effect speaks for itself."</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beef tea" TEIform="index"/>Beef Tea</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Boston journal of chemistry" TEIform="index"/>Boston journal of chemistry
                                    </bibl><quote TEIform="quote">We find in the Boston Journal of Chemistry—most excellent authority by the
                                        way—the following directions: Beef tea is too well known to need any special
                                        recommendation, but it is too often spoiled in the making. One ounce of beef to
                                        six tablespoonfuls of water is a fair proportion for a good article. Cut the
                                        meat into dice, put it into a stew-pan and add the water cold. Certain
                                        components of the beef are soluble in cold water ; therefore let it stand ten
                                        minutes. Chicken for broth should be boiled for six hours in a covered stone jar
                                        set into a pan of boiling water. Gelatine (which was for a long time considered
                                        as absolutely innutritious, but is now recognized by the best authorities, as
                                        valuable food) renders beef tea or chicken broth more nourishing, and, as a
                                        change, more acceptable to the patient. Soak a quarter of an ounce of gelatine
                                        in a quarter of a pint of cold water, add to it a cupful of the tea or broth,
                                        and stir it over the fire till the gelatine is dissolved, when cold it will be a
                                        firm jelly.</quote></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Boston Transcript insists that 'in the house of the future the bedroom will..." TEIform="index"/>The Boston Transcript insists that 'in the house of the future the bedroom will...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Boston Transcript insists that "in the house of the future the bedroom will be
                                dedicated to sleep, and the bed, with perhaps a chair or two, will be the only
                                furniture. There will be no hangings, no papered walls, no carpets, no nothing to catch
                                and hold the dust, and the bed will stand in the middle of the room, where the air can
                                circulate freely around it. The result will be health."</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paste for paper" TEIform="index"/>Paste for Paper</head><p TEIform="p">. — To ten parts by weight of gum arabic add three parts of sugar in order to prevent the
                                gum from cracking; then add water until the desired consistency is obtained. If a very
                                strong paste is required add a quantity of flour equal in weight to the gum, without
                                boiling the mixture. The paste improves in strength when it begins to ferment.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Toughened lamp chimneys" TEIform="index"/>Toughened Lamp Chimneys</head><p TEIform="p">.—The following recipe is from a Leipsig journal devoted to the glass interest: Place
                                your tumblers, chimneys, or vessels which you wish to keep from cracking in a pot filled
                                with cold water, add a little cooking salt, allow the mixture to boil well over a fire,
                                and then cool slowly. Glass treated in this way is said not to crack even if exposed to
                                    very<pb n="117" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. 117 sudden changes of temperature.
                                Chimneys are said to become very durable by this process, which may also be extended to
                                crockery, stoneware, porcelain, etc. The process is simply one of annealing, and the
                                slower the process especially the cooling portion of it, the more effective will be the
                                work.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corns on the feet" TEIform="index"/>Corns on the Feet</head><p TEIform="p">. — To cure corns, take one measure of coal or gas tar, one of saltpetre, and one of
                                brown sugar; mix well. Take a piece of an old kid glove and spread a plaster on it the
                                size of the corn and apply to the part affected; bind on and leave two or three days and
                                then remove, and the corn will come with it.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The London medical journal insists..." TEIform="index"/>The London medical journal insists...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The London Medical Journal insists that Bright's disease is the result of the immoderate
                                use of iced drinks, and seeks to prove this with figures showing that the disease
                                prevails in any country in proportion with the amount of ice consumed there. We of the
                                United States use 90 per cent more ice than any European country, and the disease is 75
                                per cent worse than in Europe. England comes next, while in the wine-drinking countries
                                the disease is very seldom seen, and in semi-civilized nations, where ice is not used,
                                it is wholly unknown.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To get rid of cockroaches" TEIform="index"/>To Get Rid of Cockroaches</head><p TEIform="p">.—A correspondent writes as follows: " I beg to forward you an easy, clean and certain
                                method of eradicating these loathsome insects from dwelling-houses. A few years ago my
                                house was infested with cockroaches, or ' clocks,' as they are called here, and I was
                                recommended to try cucumber peeling as a remedy. I accordingly, immediately before bed
                                time, strewed tlxe floor of those parts of the house most infested with the vermin with
                                the green peel, cut not very thin, from the cucumber, and sat up half an hour later than
                                usual to watch the effect. Before the expiration of that time the floor where the peel
                                lay was completely covered with cock roaches, so much so that the vegetable could not be
                                seen, so voraciously were they engaged in sucking the poisonous moisture from it. I
                                adopted the same plan the following night, but my visitors were not near as numerous — I
                                should think not more than a fourth of the previous night. On the third night I did not
                                discover one ; but, anxious to ascertain whether the house was quite clear of them, I
                                examined the peel after I had laid it down half an hour, and perceived that it was
                                covered with myriads of minute cockroaches, about the size of a flea. I therefore
                                allowed the peel to remain till morning, and from that moment 1 have not seen a
                                cockroach in the*house. It is a very old building, and I can assure you that the above
                                remedy only requires to be persevered in for three or four nights to completely
                                eradicate the pest. Of course it should be fresh cucumber peel every night."—People
                                &amp; Patriot, Concord, N. H. [Perhaps Croton bugs had better be fed on cucumber
                                rinds?—Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for the epizooty" TEIform="index"/>A Cure for the Epizooty</head><p TEIform="p">.—As this disease is becoming quite prevalent in many parts of the country, remedies are
                                in order. An old veterinary surgeon of the United States army furnishes the following as
                                a sure cure for the epizooty : " Take one pound of gum assaf cetida, mix it with one
                                gallon of boil ing water; stir the mixture constantly until the assaf oetida is all
                                dissolved. Let the mixture cool Strain and give the horse half a pint every three hours.
                                This will relieve the horse inside of twelve hours, and give a good appetite."</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Graham custard pie" TEIform="index"/>Graham Custard Pie</head><p TEIform="p">. — One quart of milk, two eggs, half a cup of sugar, half a cup of graham flour. Beat
                                the eggs and stir all together. The graham flour sinks to the bottom of the pie dish as
                                the custard bakes and forms a good crust. It may appear to be soaked, as custard pie
                                crust often is, but it is not in the least " clammy." It dissolves easily in the mouth
                                and is entirely digestible. A pleasant cream pie is made from the same recipe, leaving
                                out the eggs and using creamy milk or thin cream.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To remove old paint" TEIform="index"/>To Remove Old Paint</head><p TEIform="p">. — Slack three pounds of stone quicklime in water, and add one pound American pearl-ash,
                                making the whole into the consistency of paint. Lay over the old work with a brush, and
                                let it re main from twelve to fourteen hours, when the paint is easily scraped off.</p></div3></div2><pb n="118" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Futurity" TEIform="index"/>FUTURITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Grosvenor, Lorenzo D." TEIform="persName"/>LORENZO D. GROSVENOR</byline><p TEIform="p"> The scenes of this earth are not man's destination ; Life is not a bubble of time's
                            transient wave ; The spirit, designed for immortal duration, Fears not the dark shadow of
                            death, nor the grave. Our ardent desires for the endless fruition Of hopes and of pleasures
                            that earth cannot give, The soul's aspirations and keen mental vision Declare that our
                            spirit shall not cease to live; — Else why do the clouds and the rainbows come o'er us With
                            beauty and lustre which none can define, Then leave us to muse on the picture before us, And
                            trace the fair semblance to regions divine ? Or why do the stars in the heavens suspended,
                            That range through immensity, smile in our view; (Their movement, their origin,
                            uncomprehended) And teach us that death will our spring-time renew. We are formed for a
                            destiny bright and unshaded. Unlike to the transient enjoyments of time ; Where strays the
                            bright rainbow, with lustre unfaded. Reflecting the rays of that beautiful clime | Where the
                            stars are spread out like the isles of the ocean, Presenting unchangeable worlds to our
                            sight; Where those who here vanish rejoin our devotion , Remaining forever our constant
                            delight.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Success in practical life" TEIform="index"/>SUCCESS IN PRACTICAL LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">If you speak the right word at the right time; if you are careful to leave people with a good
                            impression ; if you do not trespass upon the rights of others; if you always think of others
                            as well as yourself ; if you do not forget the courtesies which belong to your position, you
                            are quite sure to accomplish much in life which others with equal ability fail to do. This
                            is where the race is not to the swift nor the battle to the strong. It is where you make
                            people feel that you are unselfish and honorable, and truthful and sincere. This is what
                            society is looking for in men ; and it is astonishing how much men are able to win for
                            self-respect and success and usefulness who possess these qualities or good breeding. It is
                            almost the turning point of success in practical life.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ's disciple" TEIform="index"/>CHRIST'S DISCIPLE</head><p TEIform="p">" If any man will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross daily, and
                            follow me." (Luke ix, 23.) Would you be my disciple? Consider again. Can ye follow my
                            footsteps thro' trial and pain? ('an you throw away pleasure and glory and fame. And live
                            but to honor my cause and my name?" . Can ye turn from the glitter of fashion and mirth, And
                            dwell like a pilgrim and stranger on earth. Despising your riches, and living to bless ? Can
                            you follow the feet of the shelterless? Can ye ask from your heart the forgiveness of men?
                            Can ye list to reproaches nor answer again? Can ye pray that repentance in life may be
                            theirs. Who've watched for you falling, who've set for you snares? When ye hear I am coming,
                            oh, say, can you rise, The joy of your heart springing up in your eyes ? Can ye come out to
                            meet me, where'er I may be, Though ye come on the waves of the storm crested sea? When I
                            call can ye turn, and in gladness depart From the home of your sunshine, the friends of your
                            heart? With nought but my promise in which to rely, Afar from your loved can ve lie down and
                            die? Can ye take up the cross that was heavy for me, The scoffing and scorn my discipline to
                            be ? Blest saviour, thou knowest the weakness of man ; With strength that thou givest we
                            answer, we can.</p></div2><pb n="119" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ninety and nine" TEIform="index"/>NINETY AND NINE</head><p TEIform="p">There are ninety and nine that live and die, In want, and hunger and cold ; That one may
                            revel in luxury, And be lapped in its silken fold, And ninety and nine in their hovels bare,
                            And one in a palace with riches rare. ***** Prom the sweat of their brows the desert blooms,
                            And the forest before them falls ; Their labor has builded humble homes, And cities with
                            lofty halls. And the one owns cities and homes and lands And the ninety and nine have empty
                            hands But the night, so dreary, and dark and long, At last shall the morning bring ; And
                            over the land the victor's song, Of the ninety and nine shall ring, And echo afar, from zone
                            to zone, " Rejoice ! for labor shall have its own."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Select readings" TEIform="index"/>SELECT READINGS</head><p TEIform="p">The Bishop of Manchester said the other ' day that it was not merely by reading ] prayers, or
                            preaching-sermons, nor even administering sacraments, that the work of winning souls would
                            be accomplished. One i of the most urgent needs of the present i day was ministers of the
                            Gospel who were not afraid to live among their people, who were not afraid of contact with
                            the poor and outcast, and who had the courage to speak plainly to the rich and high born. As
                            long as there was in their parishes drunkenness, licentiousness, profane swearing,
                            dishonesty, or any of those thousand sins which disfigured life in the midst of all our
                            proudly boasted civilization, there was need for ministers to be imbued with as much
                            prophetic power and evangelizing grace as in the days of the Apostle Paul, in order to do
                            the work that was to be done effectively. Bishop Foster is reported as saying: " Three out
                            of every four Methodists give nothing to the cause of Christian missions." An exchange tells
                            the story of a man who said, " I've been a Methodist 20 years, and it hasn't cost me a
                            cent." We fear that others outside that church could make the same ingenuous statement. A
                            Silent Eloquence.—Remember that by living a pure and holy life you are increasing the
                            general atmosphere of purity. There is a silent eloquence in a moral and religious
                            existence, which acts upon society with irresistible force. It is not confined to the family
                            or social circle, but spreads on every side, like the undulations of the smitten water. "
                            Persecution produces no sincere conviction, nor any real change of opinion.—On the contrary,
                            it vitiates the public morals by driving men to prevarication, and commonly ends in a
                            general, though secret, infidelity, by imposing under the name of revealed religion, systems
                            of doctrine which men cannot believe and dare not examine."—Archdeacon Paley.</p></div2><div2 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Way to handle sheep" TEIform="index"/>THE WAY TO HANDLE SHEEP</head><p TEIform="p"> A great many men will catch the sheep by the wool on the back with both hands, and lift the
                            animal clear from the ground by the wool only. We have slaughtered a great many sheep in
                            years past, and when removing the pelts of such sheep 'as had been handled by the wool, we
                            never failed to observe that beneath the skin wherever the animal had been caught by the
                            wool, blood had settled. In many instances the skin had been separated from the body so that
                            inflammation was apparent. We have known proprietors of sheep to be so strict in regard to
                            handling them, that they would order a helper from the premises, if he were to catch a sheep
                            by the wool or any part of the body. When about to catch a sheep, move carefully towards the
                            one to be taken until you are sufficiently near to spring quickly and seize the beast with
                            both hands, then pass one hand around the body, grasp the brisket, and lift the sheep clear
                            from the ground. The wool must not be pulled. If the sheep is a heavy one, let one hand and
                            wrist be put around the neck and the arm pressed against the leg. We have always handled
                            sheep in the way alluded to. We never grasp the wool. Others seize the sheep by a hind leg,
                            then throw one arm around the body and take hold of the brisket with one hand. But ewes with
                            lambs should never be caught by the hind legs, unless they are handled with extreme care.—
                            Ihe Farm, Dublin, Ireland.</p></div2><pb n="120" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Believe and trust" TEIform="index"/>BELIEVE AND TRUST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, S. C." TEIform="persName"/>S. C. HALL</byline><p TEIform="p">BY A childless widow, seemingly forsaken, Gave words to wrath—rebellious, fierce, and wild;
                            Wrath that the gift The Giver gave was taken ; And would not pardon God who took her child.
                            She had a wakening-vision, saw a band Of happy children; there she knew her boy; Each held a
                            lighted lamp in his young hand ; And, as they passed, each sang a hymn of joyAll but one
                            mournful child, hu solemn tread,* And face, were gloom ; his lamp, it had no light; When,
                            sobbing through her tears, the mother said "How comes it, dear, your lamp is dark as night ?
                            " " Mother !" he said, "you, mother, make me sad, Your tears put out my lamp; and stay my
                            voice; I must be mournful when I would be glad, And silent when, in soul, 1 should rejoice."
                            ' Up rose the mother from her knees, and smiled ; Her sobs were stilled ; of tears remained
                            none; As, bending low, her head towards her child, She clasped her hands and said " His WILL
                            BE DONE." Out burst the lamp, with a wide-spreading light ! 1 b Out burst from all that
                            group, a joyful hymn ! 'Twas a change to perfect day from night, When heard and echoed by
                            the Seraphim.</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The French Chamber has passed a bill for the taxation of church property" TEIform="index"/>The French Chamber has passed a bill for the taxation of church property
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The French Chamber has passed a bill for the taxation of church property.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To hear patiently, and answer precisely, are the great perfections of conversation" TEIform="index"/>To hear patiently, and answer precisely, are the great perfections of conversation
                        </head><p TEIform="p">To hear patiently, and answer precisely, are the great perfections of conversation.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An unce of keep-your-mouth-shut is better than a pound of explanation after you have said it" TEIform="index"/>An unce of keep-your-mouth-shut is better than a pound of explanation after you have said it
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> An ounce of keep-your-mouth-shut is better than a pound of explanation after you have said
                            it.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A very plain minister once said that some folks talked like..." TEIform="index"/>A very plain minister once said that some folks talked like...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A very plain minister once said that some folks talked like Christians at church and like
                            devils at home.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some men will not shave on Sunday..." TEIform="index"/>Some men will not shave on Sunday...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Some men will not shave on Sunday, and yet they spend all the week in " shaving" their
                            fellow-men: and many fools think it very wicked to black their boots on Sunday morning, yet
                            they do not hesitate to black their neighbor's reputation on week days.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A venerable minister, ripe in the experience of many years' labor, once said..." TEIform="index"/>A venerable minister, ripe in the experience of many years' labor, once said...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A venerable minister, ripe in the experience of many years' labor, once said, near the close
                            of his life: " If any church puts the work of missions in a corner, the Lord will put that
                            church in a corner./ Mark it! The sad experience of many "cornered" churches bears testimony
                            to the truthfulness of the words.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName TEIform="persName">Golden Censor</persName></byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="D. M. Moody suggests that..." TEIform="index"/>D. M. Moody suggests that...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Moody, D. M.." TEIform="persName"/>D.M. Moody</byline><p TEIform="p">suggests that: In all ages God has never used a proud man or a woman, or a conceited man or
                            conceited woman ! The men whom God has used in all ages were men who got glimpses of them
                            selves, and so got the conceit taken out of them, before he used them. It was so with Moses;
                            it was so with Job ; it was so with Isaiah.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unruly Member" TEIform="index"/>The Unruly Member</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Adams, Thomas" TEIform="persName"/>Thomas Adams</byline><p TEIform="p">who wrote about two hundred years ago, is quoted as thus describing the " unruly member." "To
                            create so little a piece of flesh, and to put such vigor into it, to give it neither bones
                            nor nerves, yet to make it stronger than arms or legs, and those most able and serviceable
                            parts of the body, required a God, " Because it is so forcible, therefore hath the most wise
                            God ordained, that it shall be but little, that it shall be but one, that so the depravity
                            and singularity may abate the vigor of it. If it were paired, as the arms, legs, hands,
                            feet, it would be more unruly ; for he that cannot tame one tongue, how would he be troubled
                            with twain!</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No woman knows until she has worn it out" TEIform="index"/>No woman knows until she has worn it out
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">No woman knows until she has worn it out what a convenience a sewing apron is.
                                    Cut a small, round apron of calico, or any other material which you choose, make a
                                    deep pocket across the bottom, in which you may carry work, and into which your
                                    scissors, thimble, and thread may slip when you are obliged to rise and leave your
                                    sewing for a short time. The large pocket may be divided by stitching it through the
                                    center, and smaller pockets may be added at the top.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York post" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Post</bibl></cit></p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>