<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2202" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">22</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">02</biblScope><date value="18920201" TEIform="date">February 1892</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="22" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="02" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
FEBRUARY.
MANIFESTO,
Published by the United Societies.
VOL. XXII.
"For what is a man profited, if he shall,gain the whole world, and
lose his own soul ? or what shall a man give in exchange for
his soul."Matt. XVL, 26.
Canterbury, N. H.
1892.
THE
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
Kentucky Revival, No. 14,
God's Order,
Christmas Offering,
LectureF. W. Evans,
Farewell Sermon, H. L, Eads,
In Memory of E. C. Brooks,
LetterWin. G. Flint,
"        T. J. Stroud,
Editorial,
Notes about Home,
To the Memory of M. P. V.
In Memory of G. M. W.
LetterL. D. W.
MusicFarewell Vain World,
Books & Papers,
Kind Words,         Deaths,
THE WORLD'S PAIR.
Whether you intend to visit the World's
Fair, Chicago, in 1893 or not you will want a
history of it from the beginning. Such a history is being magnificently presented by
THE    EXPOSITION      GRAPHIC
Printed in English, German, French and Spanish.
The first number of this great quarterly
edition of The Graphic, just issued, contains Views of all the Principal liaildings from
official designs (the Administration, Fine
Arts, Manufactures, Fisheries, Mines and
Mining, Agricultural Buildings and everything else to elate,) Portraits of the I'rincipal Officers of the Commission and Directory, Views of the Principal Cities of America, full-page Portraits of President Harrison
and Secretary Blaine, and a superb triplepage Bird's Kye View of the ExpositionGrounds and Buildings from designs by the
Bureau of Construction.
You will want a copy for yourself and several for your friends.
52 Pages, with. Supplement. The finest publication in America,
Do not fail to send for a copy or ask your
Newsdealer for it. Price 50 CtSi (with order.)
Subscription, one year, $2.
IHE GAPHIC-"THAT PHENOMENAL
SUCCKSS OK  ILLUSTRATED   WEEKLIES   IN   THE
world's eair city." All the principal current events finely illustrated. The most
complete, the most popular, and altogether
the most valuable illustrated weekly. Ask
your newsdealer for it, or address the publishers.   Subscription, one year, $4,00
THE GRAPHIC CO.,
DEARBORN AND HARRISON STS. CHICAGO.
MS'An. agent wanted in every town in the U. S
CLUBBING TERMS WITH THIS PAPER.
The Exposition Graphic (quarterly)  and
the Manifesto                                          $1.75
The  Graphic    (weekly)   and   the   Manifesto                                                    ,   $3.60
Both publications and the Manifesto    $5.00
Make remittances under clubbing rates to
office of MANIFESTO.
Vick's Floral Guide, 1892.
True and tried friends are always welcome, consequently "Vick's Floral Guide"
is sure of a warm reception, especially when
dressed as daintily as this year. The "Nelly
Lewis" Carnation on the front of cover, and
"Brilliant Poppies" on the back, are unusually attractive, and the numerous colored
plates of flowers and vegetables are certainly works of art and merit. The first
twenty-four pages, printed in violet ink, describe Novelties and Specialties. Send ten
cents to James Vick's Sons, Rochester, N.
Y., and procure a copy of this attractive and
useful catalogue. It costs nothing, as the
ten cents can be deducted from the first
order.
Scientific American
Agency for
CAVEATS,
TRADE  MARKS,
DESIGN  PATENTS
COPYRIGHTS, etc.
For information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau' for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is brought before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific paper in the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, SS3.00 a
year; $1.50 six months. Address MUNN & CO.,
Publishers, 301 Broadway, New York.
THE   ALTRUIST
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all
their property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing
officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley.
901 Olive St.,   St. Louis, Mo
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism.
A synopsis of Theology of the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing.        By G. B. Avery.
Price 15 cts.
Address H. C. Blinn, East Canterbury, N. H.
Vol. XXII.
FEBRUARY, 1892.
No. 2.--><pb n="25" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kentucky revival. no. 14" TEIform="index"/> THE KENTUCKY REVIVAL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M'Nemar, Richard" TEIform="persName"/> By Richard M'Nemar</byline><p TEIform="p">of Union Village, Ohio. Published in Albany, N. Y., in 1808. No. 14. Explanations. With an
                            inward sense of the power, protection and presence of God, the Believer travels out of the
                            use of shadows and signs, ceremonies and forms of worship to which he might have been
                            strongly bigotted while in bondage under the law. There is no more occasion for calling upon
                            God afar off when he has taken possession of his body and lives and walks in him, nor of
                            calling to his memory a departed Savior by signs and shadows of his dying love, when the
                            only Savior that ever redeemed a lost soul, is formed and living in him, and executing every
                            branch of his office. Water applied to the body appears a beggarly element compared with the
                            baptism of the spirit. As one baptism is sufficient to purify the conscience, he takes that
                            and travels away from the superfluous shadow. Bodily exercises, dreams, visions and
                            ecstacies which had but a momentary effect on the blind and obdurate heart and furnished at
                            best but a fleeting joy, gradually gave place to the sun of righteousness that shines
                            continually the same without cloud or eclipse. Hence, in the progressive work of the
                            testimony, a blessed reality, an enduring antitype is wrought in the Believer which fully
                            answers to all that he could possibly have conceived of, while longing,. praying and hoping
                            for the kingdom to come. As Believers become more and more leavened into the nature of
                            Christ, they discover with increasing accuracy the latent corruptions of a fleshly nature,
                            and the secret wiles of Satan in injecting his poison into the heart. As they discover, so
                            by the cross they overcome and gain an increasing victory over that which is death to the
                            soul by dying to it; the spirit of the testimony runs through all the deportment of a
                            Believer, in public, in private and in secret, so that in no circumstances is he released
                            from the work of selfdenial, or at liberty to defile his conscience with any act of
                            injustice or uncleanness, contrary to the spirit of the divine law, or the nature of the <pb n="26" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> Son of God who first fulfilled it. To the lusts of the flesh, in which
                            the selfish nature of man is formed, the followers of Christ stand in a peculiar manner
                            opposed, and count it their great privilege to preserve their bodies in sanctification and
                            honor. In the death of that in which all men by nature are held, they find deliverance from
                            every branch of evil, such as pride, covetousness, anger, and hatred, so that by crucifying
                            the flesh, its affections and lusts wither, and they grow into a peaceable, gentle, kind and
                            loving spirit in which they can live together from one year's end to another without
                            thinking a hard thought, much less expressing a hard word one against another. Such a spirit
                            and deportment cements them together in one fellow feeling, and promotes the peace, purity
                            and happiness of the whole, and the progress of the testimony. All who receive the testimony
                            in the spirit of it are taught thereby to be diligent and faithful in things temporal as
                            wTell as spiritual, and to serve God with the body as well as with the spirit. The testimony
                            has a proportionate progress in the frugality and honest industry of Believers, whereby they
                            lay a good foundation, not for their own pleasure and aggrandizement, but for the honor of
                            God, and the relief and succor of him that needeth. By faith in the testimony and the
                            influence of that spirit which accompanies it, without any other stimulus, Believers at
                            Turtle-Creek began with the confessing of their sins, forsaking them and taking up the
                            cross, and by the same faith and spirit they came together and received one common gift,
                            united in one common worship, and without murmuring or caviling have continued in it,
                            increasing in love and union, peace, joy and harmony and every good word and work, unto the
                            present day. By this I am emboldened to testify that the kingdom so much prayed for, is come
                            according to the promise of God, and the order which divine wisdom laid out, and the saints
                            have begun to possess that enduring substance which prophets and kings desired to see and
                            died without the sight. The same faith produced by the preparatory work of God, began also
                            to break out at Eagle-Creek, which gave occasion to the testimony being opened there. A few
                            at first embraced it with full purpose of soul, as the only way of God. In the month
                            following, Br. Dunlavy stepped into the ignominious path and began to preach the faith,
                            which for a time he had labored to destroy : and from thence forward the same work, worship,
                            and spiritual travel went forward there as at Turtle Creek, and exists at present in twenty
                            or thirty families in the bounds of the meeting, through the faith and light of Matthew
                            Houston, Samuel Henry, John Bonta and P^lisha Thomas. The testimony entered and was received
                            on the south side of Kentucky, and continued to spread until it embraced as many as were
                            willing to receive it in Mercer, Shelby, Paint-Lick and Long-Lick. In each of these places
                            there are a number of families, who have denied ungodliness and worldly lusts, taken up the
                            cross, live together in the unity of the spirit and <pb n="27" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> bond of peace and
                            while with open eyes they are traveling from death into life, they shine as lights in the
                            world. A few families at Beaver-Creek set out in obedience to the testimony in the Spring of
                            1800, who were numbered with the faithful. The testimony is one and the same wherever it is
                            ministered; is received into one and the same honest and good heart, and wherever it springs
                            up and bears fruit to perfection, that fruit is one and the same. Having given a short
                            account of the entrance and progress of this religious element according to the sense of
                            those who have embraced it, I shall proceed to exhibit it in a more external point of view,
                            in which I shall consider some of the errors with which it was branded, and the unreasonable
                            treatment which it received on that account. Not that I wish to inspire the reader with the
                            least degree of resentment against those who may have taken up the matter in a false light,
                            and through a misguided zeal, acted an unreasonable and unlawful part in opposing it.
                            Confident I am that if Shakerism is properly understood, there is no man in his senses could
                            persecute it. Nor do I suppose that the religion of Christ, under any name, would ever have
                            been persecuted by the men of this world, but through the instigation of a wrongheaded
                            clergy. The government of Christ has nothing to do with the government of this world, and
                            can therefore offer the citizens of this world no provocation. But through the false
                            insinuations of those who have wished to incorporate the Church with the world, and sit at
                            the helm of civil and ecclesiastical affairs in conjunction ; those who have marked and kept
                            up the distinction, have been represented as the enemies of mankind, and treated as such. If
                            it is true that none of the princes of this world knew Christ Jesus, otherwise they would
                            not have crucified him, what conduct might be expected towards those who walk in his meek
                            and lowly footsteps, from the enlightened sons of Columbia, provided their judgment was not
                            warped and twisted by that wild and voracious beast, which long ago made war with the lamb,
                            and overcame him. Herod and Pontius Pilate would never have molested the harmless Jesus, but
                            for the false accusations of the priests and high pretenders to religion, instant with loud
                            voices crying, "Away with him, He says he is the Son of God! He makes himself equal with
                            God! He said he would destroy our temple, and build it again in three days! Away with him!
                            away with him! If you let the deceiver go, you will not be a friend to Caesar." It was not
                            the peaceable citizens of the Roman government that characterized him a blasphemer, a
                            malefactor and a wine-drinker, but those who professed to have all one fa|her, even God. It
                            was the same characters that pursued the saints as "pestilent fellows, movers of sedition,"
                            enemies to the commonwealth, wore out the patience of the civil magistrates with their
                            clamors and finally interested the secular arm to extirpate them from the earth. These
                            things were written for our learning, that when we see any <pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> people
                            persecuted for their religion, we may know it is not primarily by the commonwealth, but by
                            the instigation of some ecclesiastical judge, and of course it is not really the religion
                            itself that is persecuted, but something in the room of it, which the false judge has the
                            assurance to palm upon the multitude while he demands their credit to his false coloring.
                            That Shakerism has been grossly misrepresented in many instances, very few will pretend to
                            doubt; and the source from whence these misrepresentations arose, must be peculiarly worthy
                            of notice. It is easy to perceive that the spirit of the revival had a peculiar tendency to
                            put down that ministerial authority by which creeds and parties were supported, and set the
                            people at liberty, each to follow the dictates of his own conscience. Upon this principle,
                            the jurisdiction of the Synod of Kentucky was renounced, and the Presbytery of Springfield
                            resigned their supposed authority. Though Dagon fell before the ark, yet the Philistines set
                            him again in his place, the generality of the members of the Presbytery, notwithstanding
                            their professed resignation, continued in the full possession of their reputed authority ;
                            and in that capacity stood ready to judge of any increasing light that might be manifested,
                            whether they Were able to comprehend it or not. Having shook off their former reins of
                            government, and attained but little mortification of that pride natural to man, and being
                            carried along in a high gale of the spirit, they began to form imaginations of an universal
                            kingdom, in which they would fill the first rank. As the ground work of this vast kingdom,
                            which must include the whole earth, they proposed to seize upon the sacred name, Christian,
                            exclusive of all other names; and so draw into union and one grand communion, all who wished
                            to be called by that worthy name. The plan of this great kingdom was drawn up by Rice
                            Haggard, and published in the year 1804 ; which proposed as the leading foundation
                            principles, simply to worship one God, acknowledge one Savior, Jesus Christ, have one
                            confession of faith, and let that be the Bible; one form of discipline and government, and
                            this to be the New Testament, and be members of one church. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's order" TEIform="index"/> GOD'S ORDER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="De Vere, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/> Cecelia De Vere.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The cruel monarchies in conquest grounded, The Altars reared for tribute and for show, The
                            Young Republics shattered ere half founded, Are separate from God's government below. And
                            they who would confound the holy nation, With aught that man hath built in pride and will,
                            Are blind to progress that brings forth salvation, Or they are enemies who bode of ill. The
                            world hath haughty officers appointed, In all the countless forms of church and state, But
                            lowly-minded are the Lord's Anointed, Administering the plan, profound and great. Not
                            trained and trammeled for a creed profession, Not voted for in throes of party strife, But
                            taken at the Altars of confession And in the paths of consecrated life. Chosen by angels to
                            conduct through trial, From out the burning bush they hear the call, Answering with fervor
                            born of self-denial, And with the sacrifice that is their all. Not counting coldly like the
                            hireling preachers, The stipends and emoluments outspread, <pb n="29" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> But
                            searching, praying, like the holy teachers, For hidden riches and the daily bread. Thus as
                            they pass the crucial tests before them, Proving a travel in the life divine, The wings of
                            holy cherubim are o'er them, And Shiloh's glory from their souls doth shine, The insincere
                            see not the oil of healing That reaches even to the garment's hem, Nor can rebellion know
                            parental feeling, That clothes their spirits like a diadem. They have the substance, types
                            and shadows vanish, For earth's advancement is their hope, their aim. From all their service
                            every pomp they banish, But minister the word in burning flame. So comes the psychic orders
                            evolution Unfolded from the history of the race, For every phase of peace and revolution
                            Hath had its meed of spiritual grace. The earthly eyes may be awhile withholden, The dawn
                            may crouch 'neath starless wall of night, Yet shall its portals ope with splendor golden
                            Upon the virgin banner gleaming white, Then falling o'er the saviors on the mountain, Who
                            faithfully that standard kept unfurled, Above the crystal waters of the fountain, The soul's
                            Bethesda, last hope of the world. And when that world shall see the quenchless shining,
                            Feeling the death robes that their souls enshroud, Will they not cry " 'tis more than silver
                            lin-* ing," God's Order manifest behind the cloud. That knowledge will the yokes of bondage
                            sever, And they who dwelt in shadow shall arise, They shall accept the light of life
                            forever, And stand before its shrine without disguise. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas offering" TEIform="index"/> A CHRISTMAS OFFERING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shattuck, Alma I." TEIform="persName"/> Alma I. Shattuck.</byline><p TEIform="p"> One year has swiftly passed since last Christmas ; can we review it with comfort, with a
                            satisfaction that it has been well spent or, do wTe look back upon it with regret that it
                            has not redounded to our benefit as we wish it had ? if so, do we realize that it is
                            ourselves that have formed the picture which we see before us, do we once think, that we,
                            individually, could have made the picture one that would daze our eyes to behold the
                            brightness thereof, and could with gratification know this picture was showing how well we
                            had improved the last year? These reflections have certainly awakened my thought to a sure
                            and full determination to be more careful, prayerful and faithful, and to be forming a
                            picture, the ensuing year, with a sky bright and the sun shining, instead of a cloudy
                            horizon that the sun can scarcely peer through. At the closing of the year, I hope I can,
                            with all, behold in retrospect the scenes of the first given picture. It will be a comfort
                            and pleasure, to know I have been successful in carrying out my determination. This can only
                            be done by taking up a daily cross, accepting pleasantly, reverses as they come, making the
                            path of others smooth according to my ability, helping the weak and feeble, and setting an
                            example of uprightness before all, while patterning the good life of my Savior. I certainly
                            have great cause to be thankful for the many blessings I am partaker of, and my earnest
                            prayer is, that I may so live the passing year that I can at its close receive the reward of
                            a justified conscience. I wish you all a Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year. Mount Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge not that ye be not judged" TEIform="index"/>Judge not that ye be not judged
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Judge not that ye be not judged.Matt, vii., 1.</p><pb n="30" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="Lecture" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lecture" TEIform="index"/> LECTURE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/> ELDER F. W. EVANS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> My text consists of the words of George Washington, when making a treaty with Tripoli, a
                            Mohammedan power:"This is not a Christian government." The word "Christian," here used has
                            become a synonym for ' 'inquisition." It means torture and death to heretics, infidels,
                            sceptics and materialists, all secular people, by church and state religionists, who think
                            they are God's agents to compel all people to believe, by authority, as they believe, in
                            "doctrines of devils," civil and ecclesiastical. The priesthood.of the Greek church is
                            driving out of Russia, under the most horrible tortures, men, women and children, by the
                            thousand and million, as Catholics drove Moors and Jews out of Spain. Our Christian
                            priesthood is acting contrary to the Constitution, which forbids all religious legislation,
                            declaring that all men are created equal, and are endowed with inalienable rights to life,
                            liberty and the pursuit of happiness ; that governments derive their just powers, not from
                            God, not from a priesthood of any of the thousand religions of earth, but "from the consent
                            of the governed." I hope that my friend Robert G. Ingersoll, provided that he will become
                            "temperate in all things," and cease to kill and eat animals, or use tobacco and alcohol,
                            will be the next president. "He that killeth an ox" is "as he who slayeth a man," a murderer
                            ; the same as he is an adulterer who "looketh upon a woman to lust after her." "In those
                            days, it shall come to pass, that I will pour out of my spirit upon all flesh ; the old men
                            shall dream dreams, and the young men shall see visions ; and upon my handmaidens I will
                            pour out of my spirit." We want a secular president, so longas one can be found whom the
                            spiritualists have not converted by their rappings, table-tipping, and incontrovertible
                            physical manifestations and demonstrations (as they converted President Lincoln) by evidence
                            which can alone induce belief. The mark of the beast and his image, Catholic and Protestant,
                            Greek, and all sects, is: that human beings can be made, by authority, by war, to believe in
                            a trinity, atonement, vicarious sacrifice, the blood of Jesus, or even in the absurdity of a
                            physical resurrection : whereas belief is not the result of authority, but of evidence. The
                            Inquisition tortured people, as Tennessee is torturing a man named King, to make them
                            believe "doctrines of devils." Did they succeed? We want to keep our government secular,
                            with no theology or priestcraft, in it; a government for all humanity, from the man who
                            knows no God, to the man who says he knows of three Gods. They both err, as I think; and
                            they both have a right to err, as long as they let each other alone ; it is nobody's
                            business. The gods of Greece and Rome are no more imaginary and non-existent than is the
                            male trinity. What of it? Suppose that materialists, like Ingersoll, should outnumber the
                            religionists of all kinds in America: would they do right, to do as Russia is doing by
                            millions of Jews, <pb n="31" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> because they are not Christians ? All have equal
                            rights to plow on any day that they choose, as did King, of Tennessee, whom the priesthood
                            have now in prison, away from his plow, his land and his family, and away from the people,
                            his people.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farewell sermon of the venerable head of the South Union Shakers. Spirit and intellect" TEIform="index"/> Fare-well Sermon of the
                            Venerable Head of the South Union Shakers. "Spirit and Intellect."</head><p TEIform="p">Elder H. L. Eads, of the Shaker Society at South Union, Ky., on Sunday last delivered his
                            farewell sermon before a large audience. Elder Eads is now in his eighty-fifth year, is one
                            of the purest and best of men, a teacher of recognized ability, and the full text of his
                            discourse, which we now publish, will be read with general interest. The Elder said: Being
                            impressed once more to come before you, and wishing to make this my farewell sermon, I may
                            be somewhat tedious, and will have to ask you to clothe yourselves with a little patience.
                            The text 1 have chosen is a rare one, and may be found in I Cor. in., 18-19, as follows:"Let
                            no man deceive himself. If any among you seemeth to be wise in this world, let him become a
                            fool, that he may be wise. For the wisdom of this world is foolishness with God, for it is
                            written, He taketh the wise in their own craftiness." It is my purpose to hew to the line,
                            even though some of the chips should fly into my own face. I am not like the man who came
                            into the court-room weeping, and the Judge told him not to take it so hard, that he should
                            have justice. He replied, whining: "Judge, that's just what I am afraid of." Nay, give me
                            strict justice, and I will call it mercy. The most diflicult thing that all professors of
                            religion have to deal with to-day is to distinguish between spirit and intellectbetween God
                            and the Apocalyptic beastthe great deceiver of the human race, "going about as a roaring
                            lion, seeking whom he may devour." At the present time the whole world seems dazed, looking
                            outward at his material greatness ; while God, enthroned on his kingdom within, is ignored
                            and forgotten. Now, were I to ask this assembly to tell me the difference between spirit and
                            intellect, who could tell? None. It is now as it ever has been, the deep and hidden mystery
                            of the world, that neither chemistry nor philosophy can reveal; and yet, I unite with the
                            philosopher who said: "I adore the God by whom I think without knowing how I think." I have
                            examined the lexicons of several languages and fail to find a satisfactory definition ; and
                            hence feel justified in giving you my own. One thing is certain : It can not be a part of
                            the spirit, nor a faculty of the spirit, as some affirm ; if it were, it could not
                            antagonize the spirit; therefore, the rational conclusion must be, that it is a material
                            faculty of the brain, which, being vitalized by the spirit, has understanding, and the power
                            to compare, reason and direct in the manipulation of material things, but not in the
                            spiritual. It is a great blessing, as is the eye and ear, if kept in subjection to the
                            spirit, as Christ did, but if not, it is the great curse of the world, because it is
                            supremely selfish. Christ seemed to have the least use for it of any person that ever walked
                                <pb n="32" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> the earth; as he said: "The words which he spake were not his own,
                            but were given of God," who was enthroned within him, and if all would do in this as he did,
                            this would be an angel world. He says: "Ask and ye shall receive." You need not look up to
                            the rings of Saturn for an answer, for there is no one who, if he will turn his face to the
                            throne of God within his heart, and ask, that will not receive an answer, in which, if
                            obeyed, no mistake will ever be made. It is the province of the Spirit always to say what
                            shall be done; and that of the intellect to say how it shall be done. It not being an
                            entity, but merely a vitalized brain faculty, although endowed with understanding and
                            reasoning powers, it has no responsibility, no conscience, and being material, it is always
                            on the side of the passional, material body, and will excuse, assist and direct in the
                            commission of the most infamous, beastly and heinous crimes. It has caused all the mistakes
                            and blunders of the world, beginning with its serpentine arguments in the garden of Eden,
                            and on to the golden calfto the rejection of God's laws by typical Israel, and their
                            scattering as a consequence, and on and on through the world, up to Christ's temptation on
                            that imaginary mountain. It was not an external cloven-footed monster talking to him and
                            carrying his body around as some suppose ; but it was the intellect trying to persuade him
                            to worship material greatness instead of the Spirit: but his answer was to the purpose: "Get
                            thee behind me, Satan, for it is written, thou shalt worship the Lord thy God, (instead of
                            the kingdoms of this world), and Him only shalt thou serve.Matt, iv., 10. Eight here, when
                            this intellectual devil was disposed of, angels came and ministered unto Him, and then and
                            there his ministerial work began; and I would ask where is the man, from Pope Leo to Talmage
                            and Sam Jones, who could or would resist such a tempting offer? Echo answers, where? It
                            takes Christ and his true followers to resist such temptation; but a thorough follower of
                            Christ in this most important thing, that of keeping intellect in its place, is hard to
                            find, either in or out of Zion. I make no exception of myself, though I have had many
                            tempting offers, both material and intellectual. Were I to relate, them you would wonder how
                            I withstood them. The first two lines I ever read in my childhood were in Webster's spelling
                            book, and they struck me with such force that I committed them to memory and have never
                            forgotten them. They were: "To be good is to be happyVice, soon or late brings misery." My
                            first reading book was the New Testament, in a log cabin with oiled paper for window glass.
                            There I studied the life of Christ. So when I grew up and temptations came I could but think
                            of what He rejected and his further words: "What shall it profit a man if he shall gain the
                            whole world and lose his own soul?" This enabled me to say as He did: "Get thee behind me,
                            Satan," which I could not have done without his example before me. I relate this for the
                            benefit of you that are young. Many tell me <pb n="33" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> that our anti-typical
                            Israel shows signs of decadence, and must soon die out; while other religious bodies are
                            increasing, and cite me to a late meeting at Round Lake, where, to further missionary
                            purposes, many took from their persons much fine jewelry and laid it on the altar. This
                            would seem to be a good beginning, but wrhat next? Keep your intellect in subordination to
                            the Spirit. What next? Give up all houses and lands. What next? Put off all your finery and
                            lay down all your gold at the Apostles' feet. What next? Give up your generative lives, take
                            up the cross and follow Christ. This is the Spirit's demand, while intellect says give up a
                            little and keep the balance. These are the ones that deceive themselves and seem to be wise
                            in this world, whom God will take in their own craftiness, and the same with those who go
                            around and preach for money, or occupy a pulpit for the same. God will take them in their
                            craftiness. The Gospel is free and should be extended to all without money or pricebut
                            intellect says go and preach where you can get the most money and this is obeyed by all
                            outside of Christ's foldall such deceive themselves and seem to be wise in this world, but
                            will be taken in their own craftiness. I am asked by those without and those within the fold
                            if I can tell the cause of our apparent decline, as there is no effect without a cause, and
                            say any one who has been a teacher for more than sixty years should be able to show what it
                            is. In answering this, I will be guided by God's dealings with his typical people, of which
                            we are the anti-type. Intellect caused them to set aside God's laws and they never prospered
                            any more until they returned to God, accepted and obeyed his laws. Then they prospered as
                            never before, and as we are human, we have allowed intellect to do the same thing and need
                            not expect to prosper as of yore, until we also fulfill the type by returning to God,
                            accepting and obeying his laws. Then we shall "blossom as the rose and flourish as a
                            well-watered garden," for God is the same and unchangeable. (to be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of Emmory C. Brooks" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of EMMORY C. BROOKS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Genevieve" TEIform="persName"/> Genevieve DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is finished, it is finished, The last work here is done, And our faithful, loving Brother
                            Has found a restful home In the many pearly mansions In our Father's house on high; There
                            he'll wait and watch our coming, For we're going, Bye and Bye. He who spent his life in
                            service; In the service of our Lord, Now is reaping richest blessings, 'Tis "the honest
                            soul's reward." Clothed in raiment bright and shining, Crowned with jewels from God's hand,
                            Dwells our Brother with the angels In the blest "Sweet Beulah Land." Now he's living, more
                            than ever, And his living is more real, Since his spirit hastened onward To the upper land,
                            the "Leal." With the Angel choir singing, With the ransomed throng to blend, Unto him it now
                            is given Glory and power forever, Amen. Sonyea, N. Y.</p><pb n="34" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thomas J. Stroud, My Dear Friend:--I have to thank..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Thomas J. Stroud, My Dear Friend:--I have to thank...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="England, Southport, Birksdale, 7 Walmer Road, September 1891" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">7 Walmer Road, Birksdale, Southport, England, Sept. 1891. Thomas J. Stroud, My Dear
                                Friend : I have to thank you again for your letter and the "History of the Millennial
                                Church," also for the numbers of the Manifesto. I have indeed taken your advice, not to
                                answer too quickly, for some months have passed since I received your communications,
                                except the two numbers of the Manifesto which I got recently. I see that you have
                                printed my last letter in the July number. I did not think that my remarks upon the
                                Shaker System would be deemed of sufficient weight to merit insertion in your
                                proceedings. Since further study of your Society, I am convinced the more of its
                                appropriateness to this period of the world. Everywhere we find large numbers of men and
                                women whom the circumstances of life, disposition, spiritual or social tendencies
                                determine to celibacy. These persons, often the very best of their species, find that
                                they can live, work and serve humanity more fully in the single than the married state.
                                In this country, as the recent census shows, we have almost a million more women than
                                men. Few of these will marry, the vast majority will live and die celibate. The
                                difficulty of providing this great section of British society with homes, sustenance and
                                careers is very marked ; and amid the perplexities and anxieties of the age, the
                                question of woman alone and dependent upon her own exertions in a rapacious and
                                luxurious community, is one of the most pressing importance. We have all kinds of
                                philanthropic machinery for aiding and protecting them, but very inadequate to the needs
                                of the women. Happily the best of the sex are bestirring themselves to defend their poor
                                sisters from the vile, the exploitary, and the negligent. Hence some women of the higher
                                and richer classes find careers that are a blessing to them, otherwise dependent for
                                occupation on the frivolities of society and the effete sectarianisms of the time. Many
                                young women of great intellectual force turn aside from marriage and devote their best
                                years to study and travel, art, or other concerns than those of domesticity. Some of our
                                "revolted" women openly oppose marriage as a subjection of their sex to the rude and
                                spoliatory dominion of husbands. A remarkable episode of a woman refusing to live with
                                her husband has recently been before our law courts. The final decision was that a
                                married woman is a free agent and can dispose of her person as she pleases. This case
                                has quite amazed our British folks, and it is among the most significant signs of the
                                times that women are entering into new relations to men and to society. You have
                                doubtless heard of the last great part that woman has taken in our country by the action
                                of Mrs. Bessant who for many years has been a leader of the Secularists. On Sunday last
                                she bade farewell to her former friends and to Atheism, because she has adopted
                                Theosophy as her religion. You have some acquaintance with this eastern <pb n="35" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> philosophy, I presume, for it has many adherents in the United States
                                where it was propounded by Madam Blavatsky and Col. Olcott in 1875 I think. Now it is
                                certainly remarkable that Madam Blavatsky, a woman, has founded a religion on your
                                continent, and that a woman of wonderful intellectual energy, Mrs. Bessant, has
                                sucseeded to the headship of that religion for such she practically has, though Col.
                                Olcott is the nominal leader. The community of Theosophists, I understand favor celibacy
                                as leading to the higher possibilities of our humanity. They seek spiritual progress
                                also by a vegetarian diet, and by devotion to their fellow mortals. Among the men of
                                this country there is a disposition to defer marriage to a later period than formerly,
                                and it is said that celibacy is becoming a symptom of the time among that sex. In Europe
                                generally, there is something similar discernible though it is not possible to make
                                positive statements. All these matters upon which I have dwelt in the hope of
                                interesting your Community seem to be indications of fundamental changes in the destiny
                                of mankind. At present we see the growing segregation of the sexes in the homes for
                                single women workers and single men workers. Both are at a disadvantage by these
                                isolations, economically, socially, morally and spiritually. Either sex, it seems to me
                                must suffer by separation from the other in social work and human effort. The greatest
                                outcome of the system appears to be a distorted individualism ; a ranker selfishness ;
                                the spiritual nature withers, and that is the supreme calamity for individuals and
                                communities. Studying these developments of mankind and speculating upon them, I can not
                                resist the belief that they will finally result in something approaching the Shaker
                                system of the family bond. The compulsion to be social and friendly is so tremendous in
                                this period of unbridled competition and society formation, that a time must soon come
                                when these discreted aggregations of men and women workers will unite under higher
                                conditions. What is needed to produce this amalgamation of efforts is the religious
                                principle. Until the old views are further modified and partly eliminated this will not
                                be possible. But these are taking place so rapidly that I am amazed at the speed. I have
                                acquaintances in many ranks of society, among the learned and the ignorant, the rich and
                                the poor. Everywhere I find the decay of the old creeds and the instinctive search for a
                                something that will dispel the dread darkness of the human fate. This aspiration for
                                light will be followed by the dawn of the new day in which the principles of Ann Lee
                                will certainly be applied. Your leaders, I see from pei'usal of the literature you have
                                kindly sent me, are progressive with a sympathetic touch of the mighty movements going
                                on in the stormy world outside your placid homes. I hope they will continue to be thus
                                knitted to the huge millions that know not the peace you enjoy and for which so many
                                sigh and seek but can not find. As missionaries in the great time which is coming, your
                                Society can not but have immense influence for good. In <pb n="36" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> the Middle
                                Ages the Catholic church was the refuge for the world-weary, for the contemplative, for
                                the spiritual. In the near future I believe your Community will be the haven to which
                                many will go. The roar and vain struggle for egotistic enjoyment is giving place to a
                                sob for loving rest. The savage trampling of the weak by the strong, to a tender
                                pitifulness that is the harbinger of a gentler and wiser age. You are the pioneers, God
                                bless and help you in the work you are doing, and for the greater work you are
                                preparing. Yours sincerely,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Flynt, William G." TEIform="persName"/> Wm. G. Flynt.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/> REPLY.</head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, October 1891" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Oct.
                                1891.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend :I received your interesting letter dated 4th ult. in due course, and now
                                take pleasure in replying to your thoughts. I certainly hope that our faith and
                                principles, may be accepted by many; and I have a sufficient confidence in it to give my
                                best efforts to further the cause of truth as we understand it. The Believers in
                                Christ's Second Appearing commonly called Shakers, have for a long time seen the fact
                                you mention of the increase of population over the means of comfortable subsistence,
                                also of the preponderance of females over males, and also of the unequal distribution of
                                wealth. These evils as we think, are caused by the unbridled indulgence of the sexual
                                propensity. Where are we to find a remedy for these evils which are more keenly felt in
                                Europe than in America where surplus land at present mitigates some of the burdens
                                existing in more populous countries. Now the Shakers' idea is that voluntary celibacy
                                for a religious purpose is a more natural check to population than periodic destruction
                                of large numbers by wars and pestilence. The so-called orthodox religionists suppose the
                                earth will be destroyed by fire in an external sense ; how much more rational the idea
                                that the inhabitants of the earth will be eventually harvested in celibate communities,
                                the fire being the fire of truth which will work in each soul to burn up the worldly
                                elements therein. Again a standard political economist, Malthus, has gravely advocated
                                mutilation of a proportion of the male inhabitants of the earth in order to keep
                                population at its proper rate. The Shakers propose to do this by the means above stated.
                                You will of course perceive that the evils you speak of, unless some means be found to
                                counteract them, will continue to increase. The remedies you speak of can only meet the
                                evil in a very partial manner, and the efforts put forth by the Salvation Army must, we
                                fear, be very inadequate to meet the gravity of the situation. We can not live on the
                                earth without perceiving that all the relations of life are increasing in intensity ;
                                where will the the end be ? The pressure in business, pleasure, and social life
                                increases. All seem absorbed in the struggle for wealth, pleasure or fame. It is a
                                source of consolation that a few like yourself can stop and think whither they are
                                tending, and what will be the final outcome; wpuld that the millions would stop and
                                think! There is a pa- <pb n="37" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> per published in Chicago by J. B. Caldwell
                                104 Franklin St., which shows that some are stopping and thinking. This paper publishes
                                views in relation to sexual purity that are so plain that the impure find them only a
                                subject of scorn, and J believe the editor has been arrested by the authorities for
                                advocating purity in the married life. At present men and women are very gross
                                creatures. The nineteenth century prophets who are moved by the Divine Spirit to protest
                                against evil are as liable to persecutions as were the ancient Jewish, but this is our
                                inheritance left by the founder of our faith, when he said, "Ye shall have a hundred
                                fold of fathers, mothers, houses and lands, with persecutions for my sake." That is for
                                the sake of protesting against making marriage legalized prostitution. You speak of our
                                leaders being progressive and this reminds me that James Burns when speaking in the
                                Medium and Daybreak on the Shaker system says that a more progressive theology might be
                                adopted by our people. How little can any understand us when they apply the term
                                Theology to the Shaker Faith. We believe in a progressive revelation of the will of God
                                to man which is manifested constantly in man's continued spiritual growth, and in his
                                ability to deny himself of wrong. I send you by this mail the last No. of the Manifesto
                                in which you will find a piece by H. L. Eads page 225. He very clearly touches on two
                                points, Theology and the second coming of Christ. Another piece headed "The Shakers and
                                the cause of Peace" page 221, shows our relation to the principle of peace. The Quakers
                                have been very powerful witnesses to the incontrovertible fact that a Christian can not
                                fight with carnal weapons to destroy life, either in self-defense or for aggrandisement.
                                The great complaint the Jews made against Jesus was if the people accepted his testimony
                                of peace, the Romans would come and take possession of the country because no one would
                                fight. The spirit of Christ says "My kingdom is not of this world" there is nothing to
                                fight about. The place for each individual to fight is within, to contest the selfish
                                sensual desires of the human heart. We are not called on to look at consequences, but to
                                do right. In regard to Theosophy I have several acquaintances who have adopted its
                                teachings, but I think it as a singular proof of the mingling of truth and error in the
                                mind of man. The celibate and vegetarian idea, as a means of self-improvement, I regard
                                as good. But the re-incarnation idea does not commend itself to me; I think this idea
                                will gradually fade away. Now in respect to the fading away of old creeds, I think there
                                is no doubt they are doing so. The Spiritualist movement, I believe, has done a most
                                beneficial work in this respect. But it is needful to build up as well as to destroy,
                                the fact that we live forever is of but little value, unless we grow better as we live
                                on, and in regard to the increase of celibacy from choice by both men and women, some
                                people here not interested in our Community have remarked the same to me. Sincerely your
                                Friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas J." TEIform="persName"/> Thomas J. Stroud.</byline></div3><pb n="38" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MAjNTEESTO. PEBEUAEY, 1892. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. All
                            communications should be addressed to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H.
                            TERMS. .75 .40 One copy per year, postage paid, " " six months, " " Send for sample copy,
                            free. Entered at the Post OfflcB at East Canterbury, N. H., as second-class matter.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial.</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If it is the truth that is to make the soul free..." TEIform="index"/>
                                If it is the truth that is to make the soul free...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">If it is the truth that is to make the soul free, then the truth should be presented in
                                the most acceptable manner and an effort made to secure the greatest amount of good. The
                                Apostle has left sufficient on record to establish him as a minister of God's free word,
                                in his testimony of right over wrong. See what he says to his brethren in Christ. "If a
                                man say, I love God and hateth his brother, he is a liar ; for he that loveth not his
                                brother whom he hath seen, how can he love God whom he hath not seen?" It is an easy
                                thing for a selfish man to deceive himself and through this to be disappointed. The
                                false position which he takes, makes him unreliable, and his assumed love for God is of
                                no value to himself nor to any other person. The position for the Christian to occupy,
                                is to love to do good, to walk humbly, to deal justly and to be active in making the
                                world better while living in it. A fearless testimony against the sins of the world, is
                                a redeeming Christian attainment. It brings forward the blessings of new light, new life
                                and impresses upon the mind new truths, which are to aid in building up a Kingdom of God
                                upon the earth.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many argue that the Bible is in every part infallible..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Many argue that the Bible is in every part infallible...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "Many argue that the Bible is in every part infallible and quote St. Paul to sustain them.
                            But this citation from Paul as read in our churches, is very misleading. Comparing the
                            original we find that it is not written : 'All Scripture is God-inspired and profitable,'
                            but 'All God-inspired Scripture is profitable.'"Dr. Rylance of N. Y. No one would care to
                            dispute the point that all God-inspired Scripture was profitable for admonition and
                            instruction in righteousness. The Scripture received from that source must inspire the soul
                            with heavenborn truth and make of those who accept it, sons and daughters of God. Dunlavy
                            says :"The belief of the existence of God, of his charac <pb n="39" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> ter and the
                            revelation which subsists between God and man is the foundation and spring of all religion."
                            It would be expected of a religious Community to accept this belief in order to promote
                            harmony of thought and action. To be godly, means to be like God : good, pure and true. The
                            aim should be to reach the Apostle's conception of God when he says ;"God is Love, and he
                            that dwelleth in love, dwelleth in God, and God in him." The simplicity of the formula is
                            readily accepted and supersedes the necessity of all the more modern theological
                            combinations. It is quite consistent for a Trinitarian to advocate the Trinity, and equally
                            as consistent for a moslem to advocate the divine mission of Mohammed, but those who have
                            accepted the faith of Believers in Christ should be careful to teach that faith and no
                            other.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fifty years in the past, one of our Brethren published..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Fifty years in the past, one of our Brethren published...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Fifty years in the past, one of our Brethren published this statement: "It will be generally
                            granted that the history of the world does not furnish a single instance of any other
                            religious order which has stood fifty years without a visible declension of its principles
                            in the general purity and integrity of its members." After the passing of another fifty
                            years, the same statement may be advanced with a corresponding assurance of the truthfulness
                            of the remark. The moral character of the Society is established and its progressive
                            movement toward higher spiritual attainments must be through the blessing and protection of
                            an over-ruling Providence. The general prosperity which has attended the united efforts of
                            the Community, as a whole, has been sufficient to provide all the blessings of an earthly
                            home, and to contribute largely to the comfort of many not of our order. As the temporal and
                            spiritual interests of a Community must receive corresponding attention to insure its
                            success, it devolves upon every member to consecrate his life to the cause that all gifts
                            may be utilized for the peace, prosperity and happiness of the whole household. *</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/> NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Average of Weather at Mount Lebanon. December. Thermometer. Bain. Snotv. 1890. 20.09 134
                                in. 20 in1891. 32.50 7 in. % in. Foe exactly twelve months our Brother, G. M.
                                Wickersham's name has stood at the head of Home Notes, giving evidence that he possessed
                                that admirable charm of elderly peoplean interest in life. Such never grow old, and we
                                can not fully realize, that one who took note of all animate and inanimate nature, from
                                the bird, the bee and the squirrel, to the mighty laws which rule the Universe, could
                                have seen his four-score years. But like the level and the plumb-line he so often used,
                                so were his last days. His regular and abstemious life, caused him but a brief
                                prostration; the vibrating <pb n="40" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> plummet of earth was soon quiet, and as
                                the merry Christmas bells of all Christendom were ringing their matin chimes, his spirit
                                arose, as the little girls prettily expressed it "one more angel, a beautiful birthday
                                present for Christ." Thus our dear ones depart, each strengthening the magnetic cord
                                which is drawing us to the "grand beyond," of which even Plato could "reason well." But
                                with all these changes the tireless wlieels of life cease not to revolve, and it is
                                "busy business" everywhere. If idleness is a temptation to evil, goodness must reign
                                supreme here. "Labor is worship," if consecrated to worthy purposes, consequently our
                                whole lives are an oblation of praise. But in these well filled moments "What is crowded
                                out? That is the test of life." A. J. C. What is life without health? Is it not more or
                                less a living death? Few fully appreciate the value of health, till they begin to lose
                                it. Let us all be wise and make a right use of our knowledge. D. O. North. ITanriily.
                                Jan. 1892. Nothing of any importance moving on our hillside that can be discerned with
                                the natural eye. The weather makes considerable talk but our talking will not change it
                                and we have to do the best we can. No sleighing as yet and no ice. On Christmas we had a
                                lively company of some sixteen Sisters from our neighboring Society of Hancock, drawn
                                over the mountain by a four horse team. The roads were in such an awful condition, it
                                took an hour and a half to get here, only four miles. I doubt if the roads were in a
                                worse condition one hundred years ago, when the ancient Believers traveled from place to
                                place to visit the Church and get a renewed baptism of spiritual zeal. Few, if any,
                                (except Sisters) would have thought it possible to have crossed our mountain when the
                                roads were so bad. I hope before we pass the next century-post, we shall have a very
                                different condition of things in the line of public roads and conveyances. Health of our
                                family generally good, though there is a great deal of sickness and many deaths in the
                                neighborhood. South. ITamily. Jan. 1892. As the January No. is before us we are
                                impressed to pen a few lines for the New Year. The winter work is being done, at present
                                we are engaged in sawing wood by steam power. We have much to be thankful for as with
                                the prevalent disease now raging our family has been, as yet, exempt. Our duty towards
                                God, includes love, reverence and steadfast faith in trial, as Center IT&amp;mily.
                                Beloved Editor:We wish you a joyous and prosperous New Year. There is very little going
                                on in our family calculated to disturb its equilibrium; once in a while an order comes
                                for medicine and is promptly filled, this is all we do to bring in any money except the
                                raising of some cattle and making butter, of the gilt edge variety. At Christmas we
                                departed from the usual and time-honored custom after having morning meeting. The Dining
                                Hall was tastefully decorated by our Br. George Ogden with evergreens festooned with
                                wreaths, stars and crosses, also an anchor about the center of the room, [n the evening
                                nearly all of the family gathered in and had a nice time, exercises consisted of songs,
                                reading, speaking and recitations interspersed with lunch in place of supper. No inquiry
                                from outside as to Shakerism in any form unless a stray letter once in a while. Have
                                gathered in two children a boy and a girl whom we hope will do well, Please accept our
                                thanks for your kindly greeting in last Manifesto, we were a little apprehensive by the
                                delay, that you had laid down the Editor's pen for some other occupation but am pleased
                                to see we were mistaken. T. D. E. <pb n="41" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> well as sunshine. If we fail in
                                none of these, our daily conduct will prove a blessing. A. Xew Year is budding into
                                resplendent beauty before us, opening new avenues of thought and wider range of action
                                for each individual; thus causing us to pause, on the threshold of the coming year, for
                                quiet reflection and sobei and earnest action. Our every thought and deed, should be
                                with the desire to merit God's grace; to him all things are known. May our utmost desire
                                be to gain his approval and love. A. W.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. We are experiencing a very mild winter. Some parties lately come from New
                                Brunswick report a similar condition there, so that a moderate winter seems to prevail
                                quite extensively. We are improving the mild, open weather to clean up scattering wood
                                in woodlots, and also in repairing buildings. The fear of a short supply of water has
                                passed, and now our thoughts run on ice. Two years ago a similar condition prevailed and
                                we were able to cut but very little ice. We made 2872 spaces of cream in Dec. from 20
                                cows. This leads to the inquiry whether it is not more profitable to make more cream in
                                Dec. and Jan. when cream is worth 4 cts. a space than in May and June when it is worth
                                about 2 cts. Several questions enter into the debate: We have to feed roots and rich
                                nitrogenous food and must study out a properly balanced ration; but on the other hand we
                                get a great increase in the dairy products, and also in the fertilizing constituents
                                that tend to keep up the farm. Some feeds, like cotton seed meal, which are highly
                                concentrated and must be fed with judgment, lose only a small percentage of their
                                fertilizing constituents by feeding. It seems quite clear we must leave the old ruts
                                both in farming and religion, and on this point a passage from Dr. Tarbox in Christian
                                Science Magazine may be appropriate. "Whether we wish it or not, we shall have to meet
                                the inevitable fact, that the people of this and coming generations will not rest
                                content with theological systems constructed centuries ago. The Bible is a book which
                                will abide unchanged in all essential particulars. But theological systems are made by
                                men; and if we are not in a better condition to judge of these systems than were our
                                fathers two, three and four centuries ago, we certainly have not improved our privileges
                                and opportunities. At any rate let us try, ever so hard to keep those old standards
                                unchanged, we shall fail. Truth is always better than error. The things which are just
                                and pure and righteous are to be carefully sought for and cherished. Who can tell how
                                many generous and noble natures have been repelled from our religious systems and kept
                                from our sans tuaries by those arbitrary and cruel features in our ancient creeds which
                                were meant to honor God, but served only to dishonor Him?" T. J. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> DeabEditor: Our hearts were once more made glad on receiving the Jan. Xo. of Manifesto,
                                for we had feared its life had become extinct, and that its wholesome teachings would no
                                more be ours to share and cherish. But thanks to a kind Providence, an able Editor and a
                                brave band of willing workers, it has again started on its yearly mission and comes to
                                us robed in tasty apparel, well laden with messages of truth and wisdom. We are
                                surprised to learn that La Grippe should have been so daring as to venture within the
                                precincts of the Printing Office, although we had before been convinced that it was no
                                respecter of persons or places. Would that it might be driven into exile to the
                                fathomless depths of oblivion. The seasons seem to have become as strangely mixed in our
                                section of the country, as in Sonyea. It has rained almost incessantly for several
                                consecutive days, and now we are having a lively snow-storm. Wonder if Grippe is
                                interfering in the weather department? Christmas came to us rich with blessings; for on
                                that day our <pb n="42" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> beneficent friends of the North Family at Mt.
                                Lebanon, (ever ready to dispense blessings) extended an invitation for a company of our
                                people to come to their home and share the benefits of an entertainment, which they had
                                prepared expressly for the occasion. The invitation was readily accepted, and the season
                                of refreshing there enjoyed will ever be remembered. Speeches, dialogues, recitations,
                                rich vofcal and instrumental music were listened to with deep interest for a space of
                                time, then followed a royal banquet consisting of unleavened bread, cakes nuts candy
                                etc. We think no one there will be found guilty of having hidden their talents, for it
                                was all home production; even the confectionary was of home manufacture. Great credit is
                                due both to those who planned and those who executed. Those who remained at home were
                                also kindly remembered, as evinced by the toothsome dainties received. "Honor to whom
                                honor is due." Love and kindest thanks are extended to each and all. J. L. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ayer, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Ayer, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. How beautifully Br. Daniel Offord wishes us all a "Happy New Year" and then
                                he gives some reasons why all cannot enjoy the happiness of a New Year. Selfishness is
                                one among the many things that is a peace destroyer in society. "Consistency is a
                                jewel," and let us have this jewel in all things. It is a valuable acquirement to obtain
                                that moral stamina that we may be able to speak the truth, and if need be say, I cannot
                                afford it. As there is no honor in riches there is no disgrace in poverty. Indolence may
                                incur debt, and debts may sadly mar the peace of society. To do our duty and make the
                                best of life should be the aim of each one. We may not reach the highest standard of a
                                Christian character but our trials for perfection will no doubt help us attain unto a
                                much better state. We have passed from the old into the New Year, and would gladly have
                                passed from all the burdens of the old year, but unfortunately the "La Grippe" is bound
                                to bear us company and there is more sickness at the present time in Harvard than has
                                been known for the last ten years. We trust, however, that we shall all come through
                                safely and be able to render kind thanks for constant care. Our first snow storm came on
                                the fifth of January and made it much better for the drawing of wood and lumber. We have
                                had a short call from Elder Joseph Holden of Mount Lebanon. The mantle of our beloved
                                Elder Giles now rests upon him, and we rejoice in his faithfulness, as a representative
                                of the gospel work who manifests so clearly before the world the fruits of a life of
                                self-denial. A. D. B.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shirley, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/> Shirley, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. Beloved Eldek Hesry:Well, there are still a few souls striving to keep alive
                                to the duties incumbent upon them, not for their own sakes alone, not from the hope of
                                reward that will surely result from the faithful adherance to those duties ; but rather
                                that the gospel testimony be kept before the people; that faith fully lived out in daily
                                life is a panacea for very many, if not all, the ills of which we hear so much said
                                outside, Socialists, Nationalists, Knights of Labor and others. Truly many are called
                                but few are chosen, or are willing to choose for themselves the "self-denying way,"
                                which yields so much in return of peace and inward justification. The year that has just
                                passed out has been marked by much temporal blessing and bountiful crops. Steam has just
                                been introduced into our laundry which will materially reduce the burdens of the
                                Sisterhood. Large additions of new fence have been made. Further improvements of stock
                                provided for. Seemingly what is most needed is a greater appreciation of the good we
                                have by those now here, and of honest faithful souls to assist, who are willing to put
                                their hands to work and their hearts to God. J. W.</p><pb n="43" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. We see the busy finger of time pointing to present date, which reminds us if
                                we are to be duly represented with Home Notes in Manifesto, must hasten to send in our
                                report. The first month of the glad New Year now numbered with the past, was one of
                                uncommon mildness. The first snow that mantled hill or dale with a purpose to stay, came
                                on the fifth of present month. We have been favored with a good degree of health this
                                season thus far; a few are afflicted with colds, slightly bordering on influenza, so
                                wide-spi-ead throughout the country. On the eve of Dec. 30th. we had a little scare of
                                fire; the alarm was sounded that a fire had broken out at our North Family, but it
                                proved to be only the burning of a chimney which was soon under control, giving us
                                reason to be thankful for our great preservation. Old Mascoma closed in silence her
                                proud majestic waves for a winter's rest, on the 5th. inst., many days later than has
                                ever been known before by "the oldest inhabitant." At this writing we are having a touch
                                of winter weather, with prospect that ere long we shall hear the merry chimes of the
                                sleigh bells. Brethren are at work on corn planters; have a contract for five hundred
                                present winter. Sisters who have made linen bosomed shirts for a Boston firm so many
                                years, have orders very infrequently, betokening a failure for us. Heavy knit goods
                                (better known as sweaters) are at present date in great demand. So while toiling for the
                                daily bread that sustains life, may we not forget that the growth of the Spirit, which
                                is more than food or raiment, should be the first consideration. J. E.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. Beloved Eldek Heney:I see by the Jan. Manifesto, which came to us to-day that
                                "La Grippe" has visited your home as well as ours. We sympathize with you and hope by
                                the time this reaches you that all may be restored to health. Many in our Society have
                                been afflicted and some are still suffering with it, but hope it will soon leave us.
                                Wish it would go to the North Pole and there stay never more to return. On the 5th of
                                Jan. we were blest with the privilege of meeting with two Sisters from Enfield, Conn.
                                Eldross Sophia Copley and Sr. Emily Copley. They stopped with us over the Sabbath and we
                                enjoyed their presence very much. Their chief object in coming was to see our dear Sr.
                                Eldress Mary Vance once more. We all knew she could not stop with us but a short time.
                                But to our loss and her gain, her time with us was shorter than we expected. "La Grippe"
                                must have attacked her. A week ago she was able to dress herself and go from bed-room to
                                sittingroom. Thursday the 7th she began to fail and went down very rapidly. On the 13th
                                at one o'clock she passed very quietly to her Spirit home. How we shall miss her! Yet we
                                could not wish to call her back to earth to suffer! We know she has gone to a beatif ul
                                Mansion which she faithfully earned by a life of true consecration. She has been a
                                member of Society twenty-seven years. None knew her but to love her. She has been an
                                example of godliness and every goodly virtue. In her we have lost one of the truest,
                                noblest and most loyal members in our little Society. As yet we have had but few days of
                                winter weather. No snow to speak of and the ice in the pond not thick enough for
                                cutting. F. C.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/> Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. At Christmas time there were six Brethren and four Sisters sick with La
                                Grippe though it came in a lighter form than two years previous. Those who were the
                                sickest were confined about a week. But all this did not hinder us from <pb n="44" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> having our Christmas festival. In the evening at 7 o'clock the bell
                                called all who were able into the meeting room. The Committee of Arrangements had all
                                things in readiness. In the floor was a beautiful fir tree lighted with wax candles and
                                its branches laden with tokens of love for each Brother and Sister, not one forgotten.
                                We also had recitations from the school children and a spiritual as well as temporal
                                blessing was enjoyed by all present. Thus far the winter has been very mild. Sabbathday
                                Lake remained open until the night of the sixth, when a cold wave froze it over and
                                brought a slight snow-storm, which covered the bare ground making it white and clean. As
                                it now appears we are likely to have a light ice harvest, but it may be that February
                                will be favorable and bring us all the cold weather we shall need. In closing we send a
                                loving greeting to all our Brethren and Sisters. A. S. C. ness. May 12th. 1851, he
                                assumed the office of presiding Minister of Society, acting in said capacity till the
                                Ministerial order dissolved, which was in the year 1859. Again he was elected to
                                spiritual burden, officiating as novitiate Elder at the West Family and many years found
                                him serving in that capacity always striving for the greatest good. He would frequently
                                say to the children when meeting them in a group. "Be good children, you are all mine,
                                you are my interest and treasure." N"ow that he has gone from our vision we still have
                                his goodness before us, a monument reared to his memory that time can never efface. G.
                                D. G.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sonyea, New York" TEIform="index"/> Sonyea, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 11, 1892. The Eussian La Grippe has planted its two ugly feet right down in the
                                midst of our family. Never before were such ills so wide spread. Only a few have escaped
                                its terrible touches. We are now having snow in abundance, eleven inches on the level
                                marked the record Wednesday the 6th. inst. Lovers of sleighing are out, with bells
                                making music in the air. Our dear Br. Emmory has left us. Tuesday evening the 29th. ult.
                                he received the welcome which to him was "glad tidings of great joy," for he had "fought
                                the good fight, finished his course and kept the faith." Br. Emmory united with the
                                Society of Believers at Sodus, N. Y., Feb 15, 1827. He was one of the first company of
                                Believers who came from Sodus in 1837 and purchased of Dr. Fitzhugh, the tract of land
                                now occupied by the Community. Nov. 28, 1838 he was appointed associate Minister with
                                Elder Jeremiah Tollcut, filling the position with faithful</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant Hill, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/> Pleasant Hill, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p"> Jan. 1892. As the Jan. number of Manifesto failed to come as early as usual I did not
                                send my few items in time for Feb. number, so I will now tell you that our mutual enemy,
                                La Grippe, entered our home at Center family and sought for victims the choice part of
                                the flock. Our good Eldress Adaline succumbed to the foe but she gained the victory and
                                is now convalescent. Elder James at the same time was ill and had to remain in the
                                Infirmary. There were twelve persons sick at once, but thanks to a kind Providence, all
                                are slowly recovering. We have had winter in earnest, and as, for three years past have
                                very little cold weather and no ice, we began to think our climate was to be like
                                Florida, but the illusion is dispelled, and now the ground is covered with one mass of
                                ice, and to the luckless pedestrian who is not careful, the scripture is apparent, that
                                "sinners (and saints) stand on slippery places." We had our usual social on Christmas
                                eve at our school house. A tree laden with fruit that made glad the little ones, with
                                music, songs and recitations by the junior classes. Truly "it is more blessed to give
                                than to receive." After New Year the seniors gave an entertainment which was carried out
                                very successfully; good order and thorough mas- <pb n="45" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> tering of the
                                subjects gave those who managed it great pleasure. Trusting all are now on the way to
                                recovery, we send love to all. M. C. S.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/> East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p"> Weather Record, for Dec. 1891. Highest Temp, during the mo. 50. Lowest " " " " 4. Mean "
                                " " " 21.1 Total Precipitation " " 3.60 in. N. A. Bkiggs. On Dec. 1st. we entertained a
                                visitor in the person of Cyrus R. Teed, M. D. of Chicago. Dr. Teed is the Publisher of
                                the "Flaming Sword" and the spiritual head of "The Koreshan System" which has its
                                headquarters in the city of Chicago, 111. As a spiritual guide he is known only as
                                "Cyrus the Messenger," and "comes at the end of this dispensation as the embodiment of
                                the wisdom principle in its scientific degree." Those who had the privilege of
                                conversing with the Dr. during his brief visit, were much interested to learn of his
                                system of religious experience. With kindest of wishes we bid adieu to our new friend.
                                Since our last writing we have also had other visitors. Elder Hiram Baker of Enfield, N.
                                H., who called on us Dec. 1st. and although brief, the visit was quite pleasant. Dec.
                                29, Elder Joseph Holden of Mount Lebanon, arrived at our home and remained till Jan. 5th.
                                Jan. 4, Br. William Wilson of Enfield, N. H., made us a short call. While in our
                                Village, Br. William is always at home and among friends. Jan. 14, Sr. Caroline Whitcher
                                of Enfield, N. H., is with us. After a ride of twelve miles in.this cold, winter
                                weather, I have no doubt she was right glad to reach a home as humble as our own. Sister
                                Caroline is a mother in Israel, and although enjoying a beautiful home in Enfield, by
                                rightful, consecrated inheritance, she is no less at home in the hearts of her gospel
                                Delation who dwell in Canterbury. If "short visits make long friends," we may be assured
                                that our friendship will still hold good, and in this we extend the kindest of welcome
                                for others to call. *</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the memory of eldress Mary P. Vance" TEIform="index"/> To the Memory of Eldress MARY P.
                            VANCE.</head><p TEIform="p"> The Reaper came at noonday And took from our embrace, Our patient, worthy Sister, To dwell
                            in holier place. Yet still we feel her presence, Although no form we seeAn Angel near in
                            guidance As earthly friend can be. We seem to hear her whisper, "Faint not, beloved few, The
                            Comforter is promised, And God hath watch o'er you. In sacrifice I'm with you, In burden,
                            and in prayer; Your fondest hopes and interests Are still my trust and care. Oh precious
                            gospel kindred Acept a Sister's love, This hallowed bond of union O may we e'er preserve."
                            We've heard the Spirit message, Its import we will keep; May you, dear Sister, Mother, Blest
                            fruits of labor reap. Alfred, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of our brother George M. Wickersham" TEIform="index"/> In Memory of our Brother
                            GEORGE M. WICKERSHAM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/> Amelia J. Calver.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "For we know that if our earthly house of this tabernacle were dissolved, we have a building
                            of God, an house not made with hands, eternal in the heavens.'1'2 Cor. v., 1. The
                            Master-builder from the heavens, came To view the handiwork of one to which In early life,
                            he gave a contract, thus : "I give thee here a building site; thou must Erect theieon, an
                            edifice, which will Defy the storm of time, and nobly stand A monument of skill without, and
                            all Within, shall prove that love and faithful trust In my employ, have made a home
                            complete, Where virtues rare shall find abiding rest. I only give thee tools; materials
                            Shall come to thee, as recompense for each <pb n="46" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> Day's faithful toil. If
                            wise thou art, no lack ()f brick nor clay, nor wood, nor wire shalt thou E'er know; and as
                            thou bulkiest here in time, A counterpart is reared eternal in The heavens, which thou shalt
                            find when here Thy toils are o'er. So faithful be and I Will oft return to view thy work,
                            unseen By thee. But when 'tis finished then I'll come And place my seal divine upon thy
                            work, Ami it shall live for aye." Thus read the contract which the Master held. And
                            satisfaction beamed in every glance As o'er and o'er he paced the spacious halls, And with
                            his "Well Done" seal stamped every room; And beckoning to the weary toiler, hand In hand
                            they passed from sight. And we are left. But O how sad our loss; yet may we hope That his
                            example, an impetus strong May be, to others blest writh talents rare, To use them only for
                            the Master's work. Dear Brother thou shalt ever live, within Our hearts and home. Where'er
                            our eyes may rest, Thy consecrated toil shall meet our gaze. And still we hope and trust
                            that thou wilt oft Keturn, to aid, to bless and comfort those Who've loved thee here in
                            time. Farewell, Farewell. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> [The following beautiful letter was received at this Office from the very kindhearted writer
                            and appreciative friend, who, although a stranger to us, has formed a more or less intimate
                            acquaintance with some friends in the Community and has the generosity to present her gift
                            of thankfulness, to the readers of the Manifesto. While there are many unthankful hearts who
                            have shared bountifully of the blessings of God, and the communion of earnest and dearest
                            friends, who are ready at a moment's notice "to turn and rend you,1' forcibly reminding one
                            of the words of Jesus, and warning us to have special care of the distribution of blessings,
                            it is soulcheering and refreshing to make records of the overflow of thankfulness that wells
                            up as a spontaneous gift to bless those from whom we have received those treasures that make
                            our inner life more pleasant and which the spirit of the world can neither give nor take
                            away. Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto:--The memory of some friends I have..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Editor Manifesto:--The memory of some friends I have...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Missouri, St. Louis, January 3, 1892" TEIform="index"/> St. Louis, Mo., Jan. 3, 1892.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Editor Manifesto :The memory of some friends I have' among the Shakers is unspeakably
                            precious to me. George Eliot says, "It is easy to say how we love new friends, and what we
                            think of them, but words can never trace out all the fibres that knit us to the old." It
                            might be better to reflect while we are with true friends that nothing in the wide world can
                            fill their place when we have gone out from among them. I have treasured up some wonderful
                            blessings laid upon me by saints wTho are now gone, and I bear in mind pure teachings of
                            some who are still on this side. Among Shakers one finds friends for all experiences. Some
                            there be who lift one into the realms of spirituality far above the petty trials of life,
                            with whom one forgets to worry over dish-washing and dinner getting. There are those who
                            supply cheerfulness on washdays, and others who bring one to repentance of irritability and
                            rebuke only by their even, gentle lives. There is quaint wisdom, valuable information, wide
                            experience and pure Christianity to be found in the hearts of those who have faithfully
                            lived out their belief, as Shakers. Nothing this world has ever given me has been so
                            satisfactory as the associations of the Shaker Village. The plain, practical living, the
                            atmosphere of sincerity, the sturdy faith and endurance of those who believed what they
                            lived, has been a tower of strength to me and on which I have leaned many times when
                            buffeted by the world. I revere Shaker doctrines ; I love the Shakers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., L. D." TEIform="persName"/>L. D. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="So long as wrong opposes right..." TEIform="index"/>
                            So long as wrong opposes right...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">So long as wrong opposes right The cross must well be borne; And duty ever kept in sight.
                            Till felt and fully done.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, M." TEIform="persName"/>-M. Whitcher.</byline><pb n="47" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farewell vain world" TEIform="index"/> FAREWELL VAIN WORLD!</head><p TEIform="p"> " Set your affection on things above, not on things on the earth."Col., 111., 2. GrARRET K.
                            LAWRENCE. 1835. Mt. LEBANON, N. Y.. 1. Farewell! farewell vain world, farewell! I find no
                            rest in thee; 2. Farewell, vain world, I say once more, I'm bound for Canaan's land! 3. He
                            can command the roaring tide And silence all my foes; 4. Tho' shining millions sailed
                            before, Who gained the port above; form a hell Too dark and sad for me. world before
                            Prepared at God's right hand. I can ride Thro' ev'ry wind that blows. Babel's store, That
                            they could prize or love. Thy greatest pleasures I see a happy With courage safely Found
                            nothing in old Alas, alas! I have too long Prefered thy sinful crowd, On life's ternpestuous
                            sea I sail, While countless billows roll, Then as I daily homeward steer, Toward the land of
                            peace, That everlasting glory bright,Will tarnish all below, I listened to your siren song,
                            While mercy called aloud. But Christ, my pilot will not fail, With Him I trust my soul. This
                            world does less and less appear, And all its charms decrease. Just as the sun's meridian
                            light, Forbids the stars to glow.</p><pb n="48" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>
                                Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Hall's Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New England magazine" TEIform="index"/>
                                New England Magazine
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Ladies' Home Journal
                            </head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The January number of the Phrenological Journal, etc., has for its first subject,
                                General Schofield, Commander of the U. S. Army. The portrait shows the veteran in his
                                uniform, and the sketch bythe editor is appreciative. Next a summary of the work
                                accomplished by the World's Fair Commission is accompanied with views of several of the
                                great Exposition buildings. Mrs. Wells brings her interesting account of Dr. Boardman to
                                a conclusion, and following that is the portrait of an octogenarian farmer of Canada who
                                has done notable service as a teacher and writer. Dr. U. E. Traer discourses well on the
                                utility of phrenology, and a California lady puts in some good points on practical
                                mental science. Florence Hull Brown talks on governing children most sensibly, and there
                                are two or three other good things in the Child Culture department that will be read
                                carefully. Science of Health has a leading article entitled "Health: What Is It?" "Good
                                Advice in Helping the Wounded," a sketch of the centenarian Mrs. Deborah Powers and a
                                good portrait. Notes from anthropological sources discuss interesting facts in human
                                life, and the various editorial comments touch upon live questions. For its cost no
                                other publication gives as much as the Phrenological. This number closes the
                                ninety-second volume, and a new one commences with the January number, 1892. The price
                                is but $1.50 a year; 15c. a number. Now is a good time to subsci'ibe. Address Fowler
                                &amp; Wells Co., publishers, 775 Broadway, New York. Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. Jan.
                                1892. Con. Treatment of the Sick; Thanksgiving Contributions; Food; Heredity;
                                Progression; Silk Sponge; Bread; A warning to Over Eaters; etc., etc. Dr. T. V. Gifford
                                &amp; Co. Kokomo, Ind. Hall's Journal of Health. Jan. 1892. Con. How it seems to be
                                Struck by Lightning; The Work of the Rain Drop; Ants in Africa; An Affectionate Lion; A
                                Strange Vision; Story of Theodore Parker; Exercise for Elderly People; Destroying the
                                Nerve in teeth; Is the Sun a Magnet; The Hair; Prayer made her whole; etc., etc. Office
                                340 West 59th St. New York City. Mr. Edwin D. Mead, treats of Phillips Brooks in his
                                Editor's Table in the January New England Magazine, and makes a pleasant supplement to
                                Mr. Julius II. Ward's article on Boston's great divine. Walter Blackburn Harte writes of
                                sons and daughters in literature in the January New England Magizine. We obtain patents
                                for protection, not for ornament. Send for our valuable pamphlet, DuBois &amp;
                                DuBois, Inventive Age Building, Washington, D. C. Mention this paper. President
                                Harrison's daughter, Mrs. McKee, has written her first article. It treats of "The
                                Training of Children," and will be printed in the February issue of The Ladies' Home
                                Journal.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>KIND WORDS.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brother Henry:--I enclose postal note for subscription..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Brother Henry:--I enclose postal note for subscription...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Tennessee, Fayetteville" TEIform="index"/>Fayetteville, Ten.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Brother Henry :I enclose postal note for subscription. Best love to you. I am very
                                anxious your Manifesto will get a good circulation. I like it very much. Sincerely</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Berne, J. L." TEIform="persName"/> J. L. Berne.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I am much interested in the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>
                                I am much interested in the Manifesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="England, Penrith, December 1891" TEIform="index"/>Penrith, England, Dec. 1891.</dateline><p TEIform="p">I am much interested in the Manifesto, regularly received, and always look for something
                                from Shirley.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Helstone, Isabell" TEIform="persName"/> ISABELL HELSTONE.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shepard, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Shepard
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Mary Shepard, at Watervliet, O., Dec. 22, 1891. Age 56 yrs. 11 mo. and 20 days. Sister
                                Mary has been a faithful worker among Believers for fifty years. She came to the fold
                                when she was but six years old and has been a good Sister to the cause. She will be very
                                much missed by all, for we can see her no more. When well, we could see Sister Mary
                                every-where; she was always faithful at her post of duty. H. W. F. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wickersham, George M." TEIform="index"/>George M. Wickersham
                            </head><p TEIform="p">George M. Wickersham,
                                at Mount Lebanon, Church, Dec. 25, 1891. Age 80 yrs. He bid farewell to earth to celebrate
                                Christmas with his gospel relation in the Spirit world. No more on earth will he take
                                notes of the weather, Nor state the fall of rain and snow forever; For he has gone where
                                it's supposed to be Calm as sea of glass through all eternity. C. G. R. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brooks, Emmory" TEIform="index"/>Emmory Brooks
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Emmory Brooks at
                                Sonyea, N. Y. Dec. 29, 1891. Age 84 yrs. 6 mo. and 1 day. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clement, Moses" TEIform="index"/>Moses Clement
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Moses Clement at South
                                Family, Mount Lebanon, N. Y.. Dec. 31, 1891. Age 67 yrs. 1 mo. and 11 days. Br. Moses
                                left us at 8 P. M. on the last day of the old year, to begin his new journey on the
                                introduction of the New Year. W. A. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vance, Mary P." TEIform="index"/>Mary P. Vance
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Mary P. Vance, at Alfred, Me., Jan. 13, 1892. Age 46
                                yrs. 1 mo. and 28 days.</p></div3></div2><!--
<pb n="49" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
PHYSICAL,   INTELLECTUAL,   BUSINESS,   SOCIAL,
RELIGIOUS   and   HOME   LIFE,   and   short   sketches   of
SUCCESSFUL   MEN.
IT    IS    A
POPULAR  ENCYCLOPEDIA  of EVERY  DAY  LIFE.
by
PROFESSOR   J.    CLINTON    RANSOM.
It is illustrated with a large number of
Superb, Full-page Engravings. The work
is a genuine treasury of the most useful and
practical information upon subjects that
are constantly arising in the daily life of every one. The Publisher's price for books
bound in Extra Fine silk cloth and six
month's subscription to The Home Makee,
the largest Family Magazine in America is
$3.25. For $2.50 we will send the Manifesto for one year, and the Book and Magazine
as above stated.
Address,
THE MANIFESTO,
EAST CANTERBURY, Mer. Co., N. H.
The
Some  folks  get
cheated in buying
a  lamp.     Nobody
ever gets cheated that
buys  the  lamp with
this    stamp,  " The
Rochester." Old eyes
are made new by
its use; its light
is softer than electric light, brighter than gas light, and more cheerful than either.
Insist upon seeing the stamp of the genuine,"The Rochester;" and ask for the written
guarantee. If the lamp-dealer has not the genuine Rochester and the style you want, send
to us for illustrated price list, and we will send you (boxed) any lamp safely by express.
ROCHESTER LAMP CO.,   43 Park Place,  New  York,
Perfect in Construction.
Artistic in Design.
Matchless in its Light.
SUCCESSFUL   LIFE
INCLUDES
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of tartar baking powder. Highest of all in leavening strength.Latest IT.
S. Government Food Beport.
LIBERAL and MUSICAL.
"Shaker Music" is tlie title of a book
of 250 pages, beautifully printed and neatly bound. It was published by the Believers of Mount Lebanon, N. Y.
We will send the Manifesto during the
year 1892 and a copy of the Music Book,
to any address for $1.25 postage paid. If
desirable the Book and paper may be sent
to different persons.
Address,
The Manifesto,
East Canterbury,
N. H.
IF you wish  to advertise anything anywhere at
any time, write to GEO. P. ROWBLL & CO.,
No. 10 Spruce St., New York.
"Tj^VERY one in need of information on the subject
Vl of advertising will do well to obtain a copy of
"Book for Advertisers," 368 pages, price one dollar.
Mailed, postage paid, on receipt of price. Contains
a careful compilation from the American Newspaper Directory of all the best papers and class journals ; gives the circulation rating of every one, and
a good deal of information about rates and other
matters of advertising. Address ROWELL'S ADVERTISING BUREAU, 10 Spruce St. N. Y.
The Life and Gospel
Mother Ann Lee.
Experience of
Price 10 cts.
AGENTS
can make  $5.00 per
J>ayseilins our Albums.
We beat the World for
low prices  this year.
IMPORTED PLUSH ALBUM, $1.00
8U x W4. Embossed padded sides, gold edges, extension clasp, holding nearly fifty Cabinet and Card
pictures. Sent for $1.00 (retails for $2.00). Notwithstanding' the tariff on imported albums is raised
from   15 to   35   <!*                    m
per cent, there  " **                    *-*
will not be any
increase in our
pri ces    thisi
year.  Our new]
line   of   SelfPronouncing Paraj.; el Family Bibles containing
old  and  new   ver.~-.ii, .s, sue what the people want.
-our. jiincyiK c DfinifC wiuProvea
HolidayMUf CHILE   DUUhdBonanza for
Agents from now until Christmas.   Send 22cer ts for
canvassing book. Illustrated circulars tree for all
of our fast   selling  goods.   DOPf'T BKIA1
FORSHEE &  McMAKIN,  Importers, Cincinnati, 0.
DO YOU KEEP BEES
If so, send your name and address for a
Free Sample of the AMEKICAN BEE
JOUKNAL Weekly32 pagesOne
Dollar a year.
Thomas G, Newman &
PUBLISHERS
CHICAGO, ILL.
Son,
The Atlantic Pacific Railway Tunnel Company that is driving a tunnel five miles long
through the Rocky Mountain mineral backbone of the continent, 60 miles west from
Denver in Colorado, for railway and gold
and silver mining purposes, closes the year
1891 without a dollar of floating debt or unpaid bills; with exceeding $4,221,000 of fully
paid for assets, and is on the direct road to
success and profit for all investors. For particulars of this wonderful enterprise, the
greatest of its kind, send four cents to Mark
M. Pomeroy, President, Rooms 46, World
Building, Xew York City, for a large illustrated 34-page pamphlet telling of the enterprise, and you will also receive free a sample copy of Advance Thought, his red-hot
monthly, if you will mention this paper.
The Testimony of Christ's Second Appearing, exemplified by the principles and
practice of the true Church of Christ.
History cf the progressive work of God,
extending from the creation of man to the
"Harvest," comprising the Four Dispensations now consummating in the Millennial
Church.                              Price 01.50
Address, H. C. B"linn, Shaker Village, N. H.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>