<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0211" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18721101" TEIform="date">November 1872</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="81" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">" I WILL SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND THE DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME; AND I "WILL FILL THIS HOUSE WITH GLORT, SAITH
                        THE LORD.' Published Monthly, by and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric. Vol. II. G. A, Lomas, Editor.
                        SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., NOVEMBER, 1872. Xo. 11. Fifty Cents per Annum.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No surrender" TEIform="index"/>No Surrender</head><p TEIform="p">Self-denial is an enforcement of Christianity. There is no such thing as compulsory Christianity—individuals need
                            not be Christians other than of choice; but whoso makes the profession, is under bonds to use an exceeding
                            self-denial. The restrictions of Jewish law were heavy upon that people ; but their observance brought blessing,
                            and prevented the visitation of the direful results of disobedience. Christianity is an improvement upon
                            Judaism, or it is unworthy of any attention. The improvement consists in a direct increase of self-denial upon
                            those habits, customs, passions, that had, previous to the intro- duction of Christianity, made humanity noble
                            types of earthly, reproductive life. Counting reproduction good, under perfected Jewish law, the same of all the
                            attending practices connected therewith; still, Christianity, in its genuineness, is better and best. The
                            government of Christ, being paramount to the professor of Christian principles, the laws, indulgences and
                            general life of the Jews will be departed from, and the more beautiful, heavenly life of Christ ascended unto.
                            Man, in Christ, being "a new creature," all "old things will be done away." Perceive, however, the attempt to
                            engraft Christianity upon Judaism: From the Apostle Paul to the latest sermons, and life of the teachers of
                            popular, but hybrid Christianity, the harmonizing of the earthly, generative life, with the regenerative,
                            virginal principles, may be observed as being ever attempted, but proving a failure at every attempt. A
                            Christian ceases to be the expositor of earthly principles, having been reaped from the earth, " and the angels
                            are the reapers." Why is Christ "the harvest man ? " Will not the assertion apply with equal propriety, that
                            Adam was "a seedsman?" Adam should replenish the earth with individuals. Christ is harvesting ripened souls,
                            above the employment of Adam, and thus replenishing the heavens. The followers of Adam are doing the works o:
                            Adam—reproduction. The followers o: Christ are being resurrected with Christ and are progressed above the
                            generative life up to angelic spheres. Adam and his generative followers belong to the earth, and can never go
                            to heaven, nor heaven come to them, other than a heaven composed of earthly joys. But, convinced of the joys of
                            the higher life, they will ripen, and be reaped from the reproductive plane; and then, what was heaven, will
                            constitute leaven no longer. New joys, new ideas, new life will ensue, and any return to " the beggarly elements
                            of the world " will be accompanied by pain to the soul. See, then, the two orders—both necessary— one
                            rudimental, the other transcendental. Though related, they are antipodes, and ever will be. Whoso attempts to
                            live in both spheres, had better first attempt the possibility of residing at both poles of the earth, at one
                            and the same time. " An individual cannot be in two places at once," is an old truism. Therefore, said Jesus :
                            "Who seeks to save his (generative) life, shall lose life " eternal. " But who, for my sake, loses the former,
                            shall find the latter." We know the earthly, generative life is very dear to those not yet ripe for Christ's
                            harvest, and to such we say, your time has not yet come to be Christians— you are not Christians ; you are,
                            unthinkingly, wearing a false name, making an untrue profession, and expecting a reward of " life everlasting,"
                            while you are sowing the seeds that invariably and inevitably produce "corruption." Your profession of Christ
                            amounts to naught unless your life is as was Christ's! Your profession savors rather of condemnation than any
                            salvation. Better, far more honorable, to renounce the name of Christian, until your whole life comports with
                            Christ's. Living like a Jew or a heathen, and then expecting a reward like Christ's! Supreme folly. " Behold I
                            come quickly, to give to every one according as their lives shall be!" Amen. We know the masses are not yet
                            ready for these truths; some are, and more, in this enlightened age, ought to be. We hope our proclamation of
                            them will prepare others. Men plead with us, to permit more license of earthly affections and lusts ; to grant
                            indulgence to their fleshly natures, if only in small degree. They tell us how numerous we should become, that "
                            all men would believe on us;" they would flatter us, by making us believe that our long training in the school
                            of virginity the better fits us for reproduction than any others. They would frighten us, by repeating to us
                            that we are declining in numbers, with no prospect of replenishing, unless we "come down from that cross;" they
                            argue, without tire, that we can be just as good Christians, and save to ourselves an abundance of earthly
                            pleasure. To all of which we say: We testify of the the two Orders and their Leaders, "Choose ye this day which
                            you will serve." There is "No Surrender!" on our banners; and from this standard we will never re- cede. "
                            Mankind may cry Peace, peace, but there is no peace;" our numbers may dwindle to the last individual; yet he,
                            passing to "the better land," will, in his last act, raise the standard still higher, upon which is ineffaceably
                            written : "No Surrender!" The world may plead, flatter, frown, persecute and destroy us, but with the life of
                            Christ as our example, with the testimony of Jesus and Ann as our Covenant, we will pursue the even tenor of our
                            "narrow way," and patiently work for Priest and People, to experience " the baptism of fire and the holy
                            spirit," when they will praise God for the firm stand we have taken, and with us join in the cry that shall
                            reverberate through all heaven—the gladsome sound of "No Sur- render." *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus" TEIform="index"/>Jesus</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">" Jesus is the Christ," or Anointed. Jesus is not the Christ; i. e., is not the Christ Spirit with which the man
                            Jesus and the woman Ann were anointed. Both assertions are equally true in ideas, if not in words. The Jewish
                            high priest was the Lord's Christ, or Anointed. But the man upon whom the oil had been poured was not the oil
                            itself with which the man had been anointed. The man might have sinned after he was anointed (as Aaron, when he
                            made the calf); but the oil could not sin. When the oil poured upon Aaron's head (to oil him) ran down to the
                            hem of his garment, it indicated that the Holy Spirit, put upon him, should be partaken of by every man and
                            woman of the Hebrew<pb n="82" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. nation. They constituted a "royal priesthood." " I would
                            that all the Lord's people "Were prophets and prophetesses," was the utterance of the " anointed " Moses. " I am
                            the Resurrection." " I am the truth and the way." But the man Jesus, or the woman Ann, was not the Resurrection,
                            or the truth or the way, or the life, any more than the apostles were "the light" because they walked in it.
                            Jesus was the first to be raised from the natural to the spiritual order; from generative life to virgin life;
                            it was through faith and by self-denial. The same with Ann, and with every other man or woman, who then becomes
                            the Christ, the Resurrection, the Way, the Life, etc., to other souls. " Because I live, ye shall live also,"
                            and do the same works, and even greater works than their predecessors ; having a Mother to conceive and bear
                            them again; which the primitive Christians did not have; nay, not even the twelve apostles. Ages before Jesus
                            existed, souls " ate the same spiritual meat that he did, and drank of the same spiritual Rock that followed
                            them; and that Iioclc was Christ"—not Jesus—an unction from the holy of holies, ministered unto them by the
                            Christ angels, from the heaven of all the heavens, to the lower spheres. "Far above all (these) heavens" Jesus
                            ascended when he left the earth. There he awaited the coming forth of the Bride; and where they are, there also
                            will be their children.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep thy integrity" TEIform="index"/>Keep thy Integrity</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">The Apostle exhorts his readers to " prove all things, and hold fast that which is good." If the inquisition of
                            intellect is a test, then it is rife in these days ; but to hold fast the good, which is necessary to make the
                            former of any value, completes the process by bringing on the test of experience. If all, who have been blessed
                            with a talent of spiritual light, had been mindful, always to hold fast the good, there would not be so much
                            instability of purpose and contradiction in character—so much trying to mingle flesh and spirit—light and
                            darkness—bartering a real and eternal good for the momentary pleasures of sense, which ever lead from bad to
                            worse, neglecting practical works of righteousness, which alone give true elevation, to achieve a fancied
                            elevation by chimerical speculations that have no substance nor foundation in truth. To hold fast the good, is
                            to maintain integrity by fidelity to the light of rational understanding; ever heeding to do right because it is
                            right. This requires watchfulness, unwavering determination, faith and fortitude; for it brings the soul into
                            the test-crucible and takes away its dross. If fidelity to principle brings the soul into trial, it will also
                            carry it triumphantly through trial, and endow it with regal power, which creates circumstances, or compels
                            those existing to serve. Being wholly devoted to obey the highest and purest law of Deity manifest, Deity
                            directs and works through it. The soul that never willingly swerves from moral rectitude, moving with or against
                            circumstances until adversity has tested it to the utmost, will at last feel blessed of God forever. Such were
                            the characters wrought by Jesus, and Ann Lee, after they received the baptism of the Holy Spirit.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Resurrection of life" TEIform="index"/>Resurrection of Life</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Davis, A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. DAVIS</byline><p TEIform="p">When mankind shall have become spiritually larger and finer in body, they will have fewer and fewer children.
                            Down in the lower stratum of society, behold how populous ! Take the early races, they propagate rapidly.
                            Earth's mothers have been broken down by their exceedingly numerous progeny. Rise higher in the scale and the
                            married have fewer children and less frequently. Rise still higher in the mental scale and you can easily
                            believe the time will come that reproduction icill cease! There will then be fathers and mothers with their
                            descendants, and the progeny will become as angels, neither marrying nor giving in marriage, having risen above
                            the mission of reproduction. The cerebellum, I repeat, will one of these days cease to have any furniture with
                            reference to reproduction! The finest and most poetic and spiritual minds gather nearly all their propagating
                            power and essences into the front brain and top faculties. Only friends to truth dare to speak the whole truth
                            on this subject.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our sweet shaker home" TEIform="index"/>Our Sweet Shaker Home</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>JULIA JOHNSON, HANCOCK</byline><p TEIform="p">How happy the thought, that we have a home, Where manifold beauties and blessings are strown ; Which have by the
                            hand of industry been sown, And want bringeth never a woe. More worthy we'll walk and humble of heart, From
                            Wisdom's high oracles never depart— Nor yet think to learn a more glorious art Than sweet Christian graces to
                            grow. The temple within we will wall round about With Faith, Hope and Love, never darkened \yy doubt5 The gaunt,
                            ghostly demon, despair, keeping oat, Who blighteth the soul's fairest flowers. Our steps shall be guarded with
                            caution and care ; With friends tried and true, our interest we'll share ; More cheerfully aiding life's burdeus
                            to bear, Thus tipping with gold, the dark hours. Our hearts' pure affection we'll trustingly twine 'Round gospel
                            companions, sojourning in time, With whom we would rise to the regions sublime — Onr spirits cemented as one. Xo
                            more to be parted, forever at rest, In unison joined to the righteous and blest,' With never a shadow of earth
                            to molest Eternity's beautiful home.</p></div2><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music" TEIform="index"/>Music</head><byline TEIform="byline">BT <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Music is a divine art; and, when perverted, the evil done through its influence and agency, is in exact
                            proportion to its divinity. In a tune, a discordant note is repellant and hateful. How much more hateful is a
                            whole tune that is designed to allure and draw souls from their Creator, and to create antipathy towards each
                            other ?—a tune that is not in unison with the divine harmony resulting from a oneness, or agreement, between God
                            and man. To a redeemed man, or woman, martial music, used for military purposes, is as the howlings of demons.
                            And licentious music and dancing, employed to allure the innocent and unwary into circuses, theatres and
                            gambling-houses ; or for entrapping them into the drinking saloons of our large villages and cities, which are
                            as gates opening into the hells, from whence those who go down into them, like an ox to the slaughter, never
                            return ; such music is simply infernal. And when believers, in their eager study of music, as an art, sing
                            Babylon songs from the world's books, they will find, by diligent searching, that the influence proceeding
                            therefrom is effectual to awaken the latent generative elements; just as martial music will arouse the dormant
                            war spirit in an old soldier, however much he ma}r have been religiously converted by war-practicing Methodists.
                            Ever}'tune, or song, given by inspiration, and coming from resurrected souls (whether in or out of the body),
                            inspires the emotional nature with love of the pure and holy, while each song, or tune, proceeding from souls
                            who are in the generative life, tends to excite and feed that life in those who sing or play it, or who listen
                            thereto. Consequently, we would " stop our ears from the hearing of blood "-music. So should we close all of our
                            soul senses from sympathizing with the music that proceeds from, and tends towards generation, or generative
                            lusts; just a£ we would avoid lascivious pictures and novels, or any other agency used to seduce and draw souls
                            down into, and retain them, in the pits (or hells) of this sin-cursed world.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall we call the practice?" TEIform="index"/>What Shall we Call the Practice ?</head><p TEIform="p">Plagiarism is a detestable practice, and excellent literature is so generally and familiarly studied, that but
                            few expose themselves, by the theft of another's productions, to pass them off as their own ; the risk is too
                            great. But what shall we call the practice of those who will make sausages, and label them, "Genuine Shaker
                            Sausages?" or who add, " Shaker socks and flannels for sale here," when these were never looked upon by a
                            Shaker? ' The Shakers discontinued the use of pork thirty or more years ago, and have made no sausage since.
                            Scarcely a branch of business have the Shakers taken up, and succeeded with, ere they were confronted by
                            counterfeits in market, that looked like their goods before being used, but which came to an end of their
                            usefulness much sooner. We can refer any to numerous manufactures bearing the " Shaker" name, but which are the
                            fruits of individuals with shal:y reputations. It is a fraud we cannot help. We had supposed that when our
                            founders adopted the derisive cognomen of "Shaker," that we were safe from being counterfeited. But not so ; the
                            meanness of some individuals will permit the 82 <pb n="83" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEft. 83 palming of very inferior
                            goods upon the credulous buyer, who thinks he is getting the genuine, while they probably have not a particle of
                            Shaker religion in them; and what are goods worth, unless they are full of genuine religion ? *</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two orders" TEIform="index"/>The Two Orders</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Prescott, J. S." TEIform="persName"/>J. S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p">" And be ready always to give an answer to every man that asketh yon, a"reason of the hope that is in yon, with
                            meekness and fear." I Peter, 3:15. The question is asked us, What authority have you for recognizing two orders
                            of people on the earth ? We answer, from reason, revelation, and Scripture. But, says the inquirer, I thought
                            you repudiated the Scriptures, and set aside Jesus for authority. Not so ! This is your mistake, and not ours.
                            We quote largely from the Scriptures. We take the Bible for just what it is, and for nothing more. It is true,
                            we do not crucify Jesus as an impostor, at one time, and make a god of him at another; but simply take his life
                            and example as our rule and guide to follow; be- lieving they contain the greatest amount of wisdom, truth and
                            purity of any example set, either in ancient or modern times. And this example he did not take with him; but, as
                            the Apostle Peter said, " leaving us an example that ye should follow his steps; who did no sin, neither was
                            guile found in his mouth." This, we understand, was after he was made perfect through sufferings. Jesus
                            recognized two orders, when he said: " My kingdom is not of this world ; if my kingdom were of this world, then
                            would my servants fight." Again, he recognized two orders when he said: "The children of this world marry and
                            are given in marriage; but they which shall be accounted worthy to obtain that world, and the resurrection from
                            the dead [dead works], neither marry nor are given in marriage. Neither can they die any more [i. e., the death
                            of Adam] ; for they are equal unto the angels, and are children of God, being the children of the resurrection."
                            What a gross perversion of Scripture this must be, to apply it to a complex marriage, in the flesh, in this
                            world, to increase and improve on licentiousness, when Jesus himself lived a life of virginity, and was about to
                            establish a new, divine, and an angel order on the earth—an equality with the angels in heaven, agreeably with
                            his memorable prayer: " Thy kingdom come, and thy will be done in earth" [i. e., in earthly tabernacles—human
                            beings, like ourselves]. The perversion of the language of Jesus is indeed lowering his standard very much ; it
                            is retrograding—it is bringing down the divine below the human. Two orders of people are indispensable, and
                            implied in the Acts of the Apostles, and throughout the New Testament. " Simeon hath declared how God at the
                            first did visit the Gentiles, to take out of them a people for his name." " Wherefore come out from among them,
                            and be ye separate, and touch not the unclean thing; and I will receive you, and will be a Father unto you, and
                            ye shall be my sons and daughters." Here we have the highest authority for kvo orders. We would not object to an
                            intermediate link being thrown between the rudimental and spiritual orders, to bridge over the chasm, the same
                            as John the Baptist was between Judaism and Christianity. This may be necessary.* Man is a progressive being,
                            and there is no stronger proof of his immortality than his perpetual dissatisfaction with everything earthly—his
                            continual longing for something he has not—which illustrates his spiritual nature demanding spiritual food. We
                            have been quoting Scripture; but the Bible of the past can never supersede the necessity of the Bible of the
                            present and of the future. We cannot possibly beiieve that an infinite God exhausted all his resources on the
                            imperfect Jewish records, or on any age or nation. " Where there is no vision [i. e., revelation], the people
                            perish." We believe in present revelation, as well as past, and that revelation teaches the importance of tico
                            orders of people on the earth, the natural and the spiritual, governed by two distinct general laws; and reason
                            teaches, if a man progresses at all, he will ultimately reach a spiritual order.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No place to begin" TEIform="index"/>No Place to Begin</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">A few years since, a little girl who was not so good but she might improve, was asked by her preceptor, why she
                            was not a better girl ? She immediately replied : " I cannot find any place to begin." Well, according to
                            observation and historical narration, this is just the difficulty in the way of the world, relative to becoming
                            evangelized and christianized. It is now, even as it was in the days of the advent of Christ, in Jesus of
                            Nazareth. When called upon to embrace genuine Christianity, which will harvest them out of the world, and gather
                            them into the garners of God, the kingdom of Heaven, they have " bought a farm to till; or oxen to prove ; or
                            have a father or mother to bury" or provide for; or, yet more, "have married a wife," or a husband; and,
                            "therefore, cannot come;" or, they " cannot find any place to begin." The apostles of Jesus found a place to
                            begin, by leaving their fishing, and nets also— they made a place to begin. But, though this bright example was
                            set nearly two thousand years ago, very few have yet found " a place to begin" to be real followers of Christ;"
                            because that place of beginning is at the " end of the ivorld;" and this, mankind appear to dread, not minding
                            there is a better treasure in Heaven. " No place to begin." Alas, that fearful contributor to delay ! A plebeian
                            once stood on the banks of a swiftly-rolling river, desiring to cross to the other shore; but, waiting * Very
                            many have proposed an "intermediate link;" but this link invariably contained the elements of the lusts of the
                            flesh—not in their plain and proper dress, but in the disguise of improvements to the present system. Admitting
                            that there is an advance called for, to be made by us, we yet want no suggestions nor links, that intend the
                            least amalgamation of flesh with the Spirit. The chasm between these is not sufficiently wide, and should be
                            wider, and more distinctly and practically undei'stood. We thus remark, to prevent any misconception of the
                            above.—Ed. for the stream to run by, thinking that a stream so rapid would soon discharge its wa-" ters—yet on
                            it flowed, and flowed for ages, while many a traveler crossed, and pursued his journey, and obtained his life's
                            pursuit— still stood the halting plebeian, sinking in infamy. Even so do many wait on the banks of Jordan's
                            river (or the river of judgment for their deeds), dreading the reward of their works which true Christianity
                            would present them; but linger, hoping to find heaven on this side of Jordan (judgment), but the river onward
                            rolls. " Thou must walk on, however man upbraid thee, With him who trod the wine press all alone ; Thou wilt not
                            find one wordly soul to aid thee, One faltering mind, to comprehend thy own." , "Poor wandering soul! I know
                            that thon art seeking Some easier way, as all have sought before, To silence the reproachful, inward speaking—
                            Some landward path unto an island shore." " But, across the Jordan, hear the benediction: ' Behold, we count
                            those happy who endure ; What treasure wouldst thou, in the land Egyptian, Kepass the stormy water to secure ?
                            For poverty and self-renunciation, Thy Father yieldeth back a thousand fold; In the calm stillness of
                            regeneration Cometh a joy they never knew of old.'" " And Christ will come, in his own time and power, To set
                            his earnest-hearted children free; Watch, toil on! through this dark and painful hour, And the bright morning
                            yet will break for thee," "But," says the faltering Christian, "I cannot find a place to begin !" Make one then.
                            It was said of Napoleon, that on the advent of a terrible battle, his aids-de-camp said to him : " You will not
                            risk a battle on this occasion; circumstances are against you." " Circumstances—circumstances," said Napoleon;
                            "I create and command circumstances, not bow to them." So does the true Christian soldier, in the battle of life
                            against the powers of sin. " Live to some purpose ; make thy life A gift of use to thee ; A joy, a good, a
                            golden hope, A heavenly argosy."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel eyes are upon us" TEIform="index"/>Angel Eyes are Upon Us</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Dodgson, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA DODGSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Reading the Beligio-Philosophical Journal, I was pleased with the summing up of the long article, " Search after
                            God," in which I found the following beautiful sentence : "Spirits alone can answer prayer. Ever hovering around
                            you, ever showering down upon you the strength of their magnetism and love, to you they are indispensable. They
                            know every thought, they sense every secret wish, they witness every act. Child of earth, beware ! Your secret
                            deeds are all known— every prayer is heard and recorded. Angel eyes are ever upon you. What better answer can
                            there be to prayer, than that which comes from a spirit-band ?" Beautiful spirit-teaching, that is thus brought
                            to bear so closely on our daily earth-life ! What a protective influence would be shed over enlightened
                            Christians, could they be made to believe that spirit-eyes are ever upon them ! Who would transgress the rules
                            of propriety in word, thought or deed? What a moral corrector such a belief would be—what <pb n="84" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>
                            84: THE SHA.KER. a teacher of charity and universal love ! How many prayers would be directed to the spirits of
                            departed friends, in whom the highest degree of confidence for purity, virtue and love could be placed ! and
                            would not erring mortals long to find a Christ, dwelling in mortal form, to whom they might unbosom their secret
                            thoughts, and confess their sins, that they might ever be ready for the communion of good and holy spirits ? Who
                            can bear the thought of being constantly accompanied by bad, unclean, selfish spirits ? No one. But this must be
                            the case, so long as the spiritual consciousness speaks disapprovingly. Nothing but humility, confession and
                            repentance will repel a bad spirit; and earnest, sincere prayer will bring a good spirit to our aid. Let this
                            belief be living in every Spiritualist, and Christian soul, and we should soon have a good world, of which we
                            should have but little reason to complain. Shaker world, indeed ! Reflecting on the foregoing subject, I was
                            reminded of a hymn, from which, in my youth, I received much instruction, and was conscientiously awakened to a
                            realization of spirit presence. It was composed by Garret R. Lawrence, a physician of our Community, who
                            deceased in 1837. He spoke by the spirit of prophecy, at his death, of a time near at hand when we should
                            converse with spirits as freely as with each other. This was fulfilled to the Shakers, in less than a year after
                            his demise, in wrhat is known to them as the "Spirit Manifestation." WE ARE SEEN. All things here on earth
                            revealed, Indicate a Great First Cause, From whose sig-ht there's nought concealed, All efficient are His laws.
                            Every thought, and word, and actionAll lie. open to His view; None can hide the least transaction— We are seen
                            in all we do. Mortals, here, may try to cover, And conceal their sins awhile; There's a God who will uncover And
                            expose the deepest guile. True as Heaven e'er existed, Watchmen there their vigils keep; Every veil shall yet be
                            lifted, Th.;re 's an eye that knows no sleep. Altho' conscience seems to slumber, And resign its sweet control;
                            Yet each deed records its number, Deep engraven on the soul. And from these, the soul eternal Takes impressions
                            day by day, Whether spiritual or carnal, Good or evil, yea or nay. Who can hide a guilty conscience? Fearful
                            state of sin and woe! Who can grope thro' time, unconscious, And their standing never show ? Who can smother
                            flames unceasing, Keep concealed the gnawing worm— Shame and guilt their load increasing, Nor with inward horror
                            squirm ? We may seek to veil from mortals, Deeds which cannot bear the light; Can we hide from the immortals
                            That surround us day and night? Are not thousands now beholding Every action, word and way? And our very
                            thoughts, unfolding In the blaze of endless day ? Have not those, who stand connected With the source of truth
                            and light, Many secret sins detected And exposed to mortal sight ? Are not all our words and actions Fruits
                            which mortal eyes can view ? ' Tis a truth without deception, We are seen, yea, through and through. But the
                            honest, pure and holy Never iear the searching light, Knowing 't will increase their glory To appear in open
                            sight. These shall stand the test triumphant, Joyful that their state is known, Glowing like the stars
                            effulgent, Shining round Jehovah's throne.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sketches of shaker life, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Sketches of Shaker Life.-—No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">THE ADMISSION OF NOVITIATES. The writer is of the opinion that Shakers take for granted that their social
                            relations are much better understood than they really are. As proof of this, inquire of any number you please,
                            What are the necessary steps to be taken, in order to gain admission to membership of the Society ? and nine out
                            of ten will tell you, that if heads of families join the Shakers, they must break up their families, give up
                            their property; the husband and the wife must separate, and their children taken under the charge of the
                            Society, etc., etc.; not one word of which is true. tn order to set this matter in a clear light, I cannot do
                            better than to give a history of my own observations of the practical working of our principles, since my first
                            association with the people in 1817—fifty-five years ago. To go a little further back, I will observe that the
                            faith and principles of the Shakers were first opened in the township of Turtle Creek, Warren county, Ohio, by
                            three missionaries, sent by the Shaker Society of New Lebanon, New York, in the spring of 1805; and within ten
                            years after their arrival, the number of converts amounted to several hundred men, women and children, most of
                            whom lived within a radius of fifteen miles, taking Union Village for the center. All these, except the single
                            adults, lived in their separate families and on their own premises, in the common order of Society, and
                            continued so for several years. But most of these desired to progress and enter into the pentecostal order of
                            consecrating their property, to be shared in common with their brethren and sisters. Finally, the way was
                            opened, and all that felt ready made the consecration about 1815. The oldest members of this body having now had
                            ten years' experience, and having consecrated their money and property, closed their doors against receiving any
                            more mem- bers directly into the Church, as this body was then called. But the Church must have a door, and for
                            that purpose they built a new house, and set off a small family of suitable persons to instruct all inquirers,
                            and admit novitiate members. This was called " The Gathering," or " Junior Order," and had been in operation two
                            years, when the writer came and took up his abode in it, in 1817. It was then in a flourishing condition, and
                            active missionary exertions were being made to spread the knowledge of the truth and gather souls into the
                            Gospel fold. There was a continual accession of members, some of which were single adults, and some whole
                            families. Divers of these continued on their own premises and attended to their own temporal concerns, as
                            formerly; while others moved into the bounds of the Society, and either rented or purchased lands adjacent. Some
                            of these kept their fam- ilies together during their lives, but these were few. There was a sufficient number of
                            these families settled round about the Society to unite in building a school house, and children enough to make
                            up a respectable school, and the writer was the first teacher of that school. In ten years, up to 1825, these
                            and others that came into the Junior Order, within that time, Were two hundred strong, not counting the First
                            Family or Church. They had ultimately consecrated their property and formed a second joint interest or Second
                            Family—had purchased adjoining lands, built two commodious and substantial brick dwelling houses which would
                            accommodate from eighty to one hundred persons each. Now it may be remarked, with regard to the above mentioned
                            families who lived at a distance when t\\ej believed, that they might have continued there if they had so
                            chosen. The selling of their premises, and moving into the bounds of the Society, was entirely a matter of their
                            own choice. No rules of the Society required it. They might have remained with their families on their own
                            premises if they had so chosen. There were then Shaker families, so living in Northern Ohio, Pennsylvania,
                            Virginia, and other places, who were held in union as novitiate members of the Shaker Society; and there has
                            never been a time since, when there were not such members living in various places throughout the country. When
                            receiving novitiates into spiritual relations, we ask not to know their theological opinions, impose no creed,
                            and only require their conformity to a few plain practical principles. They must tell vis honestly what kind of
                            lives they have lived hitherto, and bring all their wicked deeds to light. If they have wronged any one, they
                            must, if in their power, make restitution, and set out henceforth to live an upright life. The relation of
                            husband and wife must cease, and the relation of brother and sister must be assumed instead; and their lives and
                            treatment of one another must henceforth be in conformity with this new relation. They must live pure,
                            continent, or virgin lives, and bring up their children as pure and free from unclean and evil habits as they
                            can. Let them faithfully observe and do these things, and we own them as our dear brethren and sisters, wherever
                            they may be located. We are often questioned, What guarantee we have that they faithfully conform to these
                            practical rules ? We answer, that we take no burden about this matter; we shall not distrust them. As long as
                            they profess to do it, we will take their word for it. I find the following in the " Brief Exposition" published
                            in 1830 : " The first or novitiate class are those who receive our faith and come into a degree of relation, but
                            choose to live in their own family order and manage their own temporal concerns. Any who choose may live in that
                            order and be owned as brethren and sisters in the gospel, so long as they live up to its requirements." p. 9.
                            This practice has never been rescinded, and is the same to-day as it was forty years ago.</p></div2><pb n="85" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom" TEIform="index"/>Freedom</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">This word suggests to different minds, ideas as varied as the mental development and cul- ture of each. To the
                            depraved mind it means unrestrained desires; license of thought and action, without regard to divine or human
                            law. On the contrary, to the mind elevated above the mere sensual plane of existence, it means a life in
                            accordance with divine law, deviating not a hair's breadth, if that be possible, from straightness itself. There
                            is social freedom as well as individual freedom, and these are perfectly consistent with each other. It has been
                            said, that in entering into society man gives up a portion of his individual rights for the sake of a greater
                            advantage to be obtained by association. It seems to be taken for granted by those who make this assertion,
                            that, originally, individ- uals are entirely independent of each other. But this is a mere fanciful assumption,
                            con- tradicted by the entire history of the human race. Man was created a social being, and his highest
                            enjoyment is to be derived from a perfect society. If the individual is obliged to give up any of his rights to
                            society, no plainer proof is needed that society itself is enslaved to wrong-doing. For, what are the rights of
                            the individual but those which inhere in him by virtue of his existence ? These cannot be violated by the person
                            himself, nor by society, without committing a wrong. The individual is entitled to a sound body with a sound
                            mental status, and these may vary, of course, in character and quality, in accordance with various circumstances
                            and conditions, in different ages and in different parts of the earth, yet without any infringement of natural
                            rights. He is entitled also to the opportunities of growth, both physical and mental, and whoever hinders him in
                            the possession and enjoyment of these, just so far obstructs the operation of divine law. The right to these
                            implies his right to use all the means within his reach, to attain them, that do not infringe upon the rights of
                            another; as also his claim upon others for assistance in cases where age or any other circumstances make him
                            dependent upon others. These statements are mere truisms which none will undertake to dispute but those who have
                            been educated in the absurd notion that one part of mankind have rights superior to those of another part, and
                            whose menta' vision has therefore been so obscured, thai they are unable to perceive the truth, even o axioms.
                            But it will be said that regard must be paic to mankind in its present condition in estimating the rights of the
                            individual; that a perfec society upon the earth at present is a chimera —a Utopia—and the individual can expec
                            freedom only in proportion as society is virtu ous and free. This is partly true and partly false. No doubt,
                            when society at large shal have rid itself of the numerous evils that now infest it; when it shall have put an
                            end to iti insensate wars and contentions, and shall em ploy its energies in building up what it still ii a
                            great measure seems bent on destroying, th ndividual will come into possession of much greater freedom than he
                            can now enjoy. But t is not true, that his rights, which are of livine origin, are dependent upon the condition
                            of society, nor, in fact, is his enjoyment of them wholly dependent upon it. Much has seen done in the past by
                            perverted minds, to ¦estrict the rights of the individual, but there las been a gradual though slow growth of
                            the race, in spite of all such efforts. There is in man a power of resistance that has proved tself mightier
                            than armies, and stronger than the accumulated vices of society, though sustained by all the vigor of crowned
                            heads. The simple protest of Jesus was more efficacious ;han the combined power of Roman and Jew; or, though for
                            a brief season his enemies seemed to triumph, yet he secured forever all ;hat Divine Power has to bestow for
                            human enjoyment. What the Apostle Paul declared of Christians in his day, was true: " They sat together in
                            heavenly places in Christ," and that, notwithstanding the persecuting efforts of their enemies. Thus did God
                            show to all succeeding ages, " the exceeding riches of his grace." Vain were all the efforts of English, secular
                            and ecclesiastical power to make inefficient the simple declaration of George Fox and ris followers, that all
                            wars are inconsistent with the precepts and example of Jesus Christ. They could imprison the body, but were
                            powerless to destroy the right, or essentially lessen the enjoyment of the individual, or prevent the spread of
                            opinions that are ultimately to benefit the whole human race. . Adherence to principle will always produce
                            permanent results. Darkness is only a condition; light is as enduring as God himself. "Truth will make free"
                            both the individual and society. Society is the product of indi- viduals, and takes its stamp from their
                            character. The temple of God is holy when the stones composing the structure are "living stones," as was and is
                            the chief corker stone. Let the divine breath flow throiigh every avenue of the soul, and the light of truth
                            penetrate its innermost recess, giving health and vigor to the outward man, and peace and joy to the inner, and
                            there will be a condition of freedom that the possessor of mere political liberty never knew. The union of
                            individuals raised from the death of evil habits to the life of Christ, and constantly progressing in all truth
                            and goodness, will form a society free indeed, whose reflex action upon the individua' will be powerful in
                            proportion to the fidelity of each to the life of divine freedom—the life of purity and love. Such a society,
                            raisec above the earth of mere sensual enjoyment, will, as Jesus said of himself, ultimately draw all men unto
                            itself.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit and wants of the age" TEIform="index"/>The Spirit and Wants of the Age</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Ervin, Anne" TEIform="persName"/>ANNE ERVIN</byline><p TEIform="p">The spirit of the age in which we live i emphaticalhr one of progress. It was reservec for the nineteenth
                            centurj' to witness the application of the grand and beneficent princi- ples of the universal diffusion of
                            knowledgi among all classes, and the almost startling resurrection of mind which is a natural result. And though
                            it is doubtless true that in coming lp from the sepulchre and striving to cast off the cerements in which it has
                            so long been bound, ;he human intellect, so far from being dismayed at these signs of activity, should be
                            stimulated ,o greater diligence in the work of presenting those great elementary truths which alone are able to
                            make men wise unto salvation. Our course is still onward; nor can we limit, even in imagination, that spirit of
                            progress which, before the dawn of the millennial Sabbath, shall crown with perfection the human mind. We are
                            told, and that truly, that the world is full of wrongs and evils, for which a •emedy must be found before man
                            can enjoy lis full heritage of blessings; but the speculative reformer, who seeks to tear dowrn the existing
                            fabric before commencing a new one, tias not as yet shoAvn us intellectual and moral engines mighty enough to
                            perform the difficult process of renovation. The human mind is ever prone to error. " Better is an old error
                            than a new truth," was the remark of a learned divine ; but the state of things is now completely changed. A
                            reaction has taken place, which threatens to destroy all the ancient landmarks and to convulse the whole social
                            system, in the attempt to remove the evils which have gathered strength for ages. If such is the spirit of the
                            age, what then is wanted to meet its exigencies and carry forward the benevolent operations which form a
                            distinctive feature in its character ? We want intelligent, educated men and women, who can properly appreciate
                            and defend the light with which they are endowed, and can diffuse correct principles throughout the land. The
                            preponderance of intelligence and virtue constitutes our only safeguard. We want earnest, practical men and
                            women, to meet the exigencies of the age, who would leave the world better than they found it. But more than
                            all, we want devoted, consistent followers of the Lord Jesus, to be co-workers with him in bringing back a
                            revolted world and to prepare the way for the final triumph of love over every form of selfishness and sin. The
                            noblest of all human means must be that which obtains the exertion of divine power. Without this power from on
                            high, every attempt to ameliorate the condition of men will prove a failure. Go ye into the world and preach the
                            gospel to every creature, is the command of the Redeemer. Never before have the wants of the human family been
                            so great as now. Let those, then, who labor and pray take courage. It has always been the fate of truth to be
                            stigmatized and slandered by falsehood. Whenever the spirit of truth has been revealed, the father of lies has
                            never failed to dispense a sufficient portion of the spirit of falsehood to combat it and scandalize all who
                            maintain it. The great Captain of our salvation was subjected to scorn and derision, and endured the reproaches
                            of the emissaries of Satan. He was charged with drunkenness, and reproached with associating with publicans and
                            sinners; and he repeatedly assured his followers that they would suffer the same indignities and reproaches. "
                            For if ye were of the world, the world would love its own, but I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the
                            world <pb n="86" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE SHAKER hateth you." It is of little consequence what name we assume. "By their
                            fruits ye shall know them."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little things" TEIform="index"/>Little Things</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p">" Take us the foxes, the little foxes that spoil our vines." A little spark will create a great conflagration,
                            burning up villages, towns and cities. A little hole in a ship sinks it. A small breach in the sea-bank carries
                            all away before it. A little over-crowding of the stomach will produce sickness. A little intoxicating drink has
                            been many a man and woman's ruin. A little stab in the heart will kill a person. A little harsh word will stir
                            up anger. A little gift of the Spirit, if slighted, will produce spiritual death. A little sin, as it is
                            frequently and very improperly called, brings death to the soul. So in turn, little acts of goodness, little
                            words of kindness, little smiles of approbation, make up the sum of human happiness.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heaven is within" TEIform="index"/>Heaven is Within</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Silesius, Angelus" TEIform="persName"/>ANGELUS SILESIUS, A. D 1620.</byline><p TEIform="p">How far from here to heaven ? Not very far, my friend ; A single hearty step Will all thy journey end. Hold,
                            there ! where rnnnest thon ? No, heaven is in thee ! Seek'st thon for God elsewhere? His face thou'lt never see.
                            Go out—God will go in ; Die thoit, and let him live ; Be not, and he will be ; Wait, and he'll all things give.
                            I don't believe in death; If hour by hour I die, 'Tis hour by hour I gain A better life thereby.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth, faith, and reason" TEIform="index"/>Truth, Faith and Reason</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">A truth discovered, a duty imposed on the understanding, by reading the tattered leaf of a cast-off book, is as
                            binding on the conscience, nay, as welcome to the heart of a sincere lover of truth, as if it were delivered
                            fresh from the mouth of a Prophet under all the agonies of inspiration. All the reverence paid to truth on
                            account of the " pomp and circumstance " of mighty miracles, or the awe-imparting influence of occular
                            inspiration, is really a derogation from the love of truth as such; and when the impression of the marvelous is
                            past ("which will soon be the case), we shall then be able, by observing what remains, to discover how much the
                            truth was regarded for its own sake. Many sectarians affect to believe mj^steries, and require their votaries to
                            believe, not only without understanding, but against their intuitive perceptions of truth, and they pretend to
                            use argument and reason for the propriety of this. But it is a vain thing to appeal to man's reason, to bring in
                            a verdict against itself. Satan will not cast out Satan. A principle cannot oppose itself. The very act of
                            reasoning against reason, gives the lie to his argument who uses them, and proves more cogently the great
                            excellence and propriety of reason. The main ground of the many great absurdities which abound in all
                            theological systems will be found to be, the taking for granted certain first principles, which being considered
                            the very basis of the system, are held not only too certain, but too sacred to admit of investigation or doubt.
                            To reject that which appears to the mind as unreasonable, is to reject that which is opposed to the will of God;
                            for who can suppose that God wills what is unreasonable ? We should never confound the understanding with the
                            imagination, nor give the latter the ascendency over the former. My understanding, 0 God, is thy workman- ship,
                            thy greatest and best gift! Grant me to exercise it not to selfish ends, but purely for thy glory. As a man's
                            eyes may be of great use to him without a telescope, while a telescope can be of no use to him without eyes; so,
                            a man's reason can be of great use to him without revelation; but revelation can be of no use to him without
                            reason. We never present revelation to idiots or brutes, any more than we present colors to a blind man; for the
                            reason that we know they are destitute of any faculty to judge of its truth, or make the least use of it. If in
                            any case revelation be presented to a man, and he be asked to receive it as such, without using his reason to
                            discover whether it to be true or false, whether it be revelation or human invention ; he is, in that case,
                            asked to be unreasonable—to act without reason. In all cases reason must be the dernier resort, and, so to
                            speak, God is bound, and his messengers are bound to make all his revelations plain and true to man's reason. If
                            this is not done, no revelation is made. Paul prayed to be delivered from wicked and unreasonable men. He could
                            not offer such the revelation of truth in the gospel. His only wish was to keep out of their way, and be
                            delivered from them. The Prophet represents God as desiring to reason with mankind: "Come, saith the Lord, let
                            us reason together;" and Dunlavy says : " What is good reason to man is good reason to God." In all things we
                            must appeal to reason. He that receives revelation without reason, will be quite as apt to reject it without
                            reason. Gospel truth shall stand. Enmity and lust have dug many a grave for it. Intolerance has persecuted it.
                            Many a Judas has betrayed it with a kiss. Many a Peter has denied it with an oath. Many a Dem as has forsaken it
                            for worldly pleasure and pelf. Heaven and earth may pass away, but the word of Truth shall not pass away—it
                            shall stand forever. It will forever console, justify, and make free its friends, while it will as certainly and
                            unceasingly whisper the sentence of condemnation in the consciences of its betrayers.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>"The Shaker."</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM, ENFIELD, CONN.</byline><p TEIform="p">Hail, lovely Shaker ! What with thee can compare In beauty, and goodness, and truth, ever rare ! No dew drop,
                            that glints in the morning sun's beam, Can brighten and bless like the truths of thy theme. How I long for thy
                            coming, thon herald of peace ! Thou fountain of goodness ! May'st thon ever increase! On, on, o'er the earth,
                            and bear on thy pag'e Glad tidings of truth, both to youth and old age ; And teach all mankind false opinions to
                            leave, To use God-given reason, and light to receive. Thou glorious volume, which in wisdom art made, May'st
                            thou understandingly, ever be read, And, as thon adVancedst, let my zeal improve, And glow with the ardor of
                            consummate love.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker's position" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS' POSITION</head><p TEIform="p">The following letter was written sometime since as a reply to a Professor of an Eastern College who,
                                convinced of the " ungodliness of the age," particularly illustrated in the social relations of life, paid
                                us a visit, addressed our family, etc., and upon his return home, sent us a letter entreating us to aid, by
                                material means, the scheme of founding an institution, in connection with ours, that would have for its
                                object the proper reproduction of human beings, "such as ivoulcl make Shakers I" Office of the Shaker, ?
                                ------20th, 1872. 5 Professor H.: Your lengthy appeal, addressed to myself, came duly to hand, and in reply
                                would say: You find yourself in water so deep, that you cannot consistently wade, and you must either swim
                                above the water or you must be drowned. Your thorough investigations of our faith and principles I admire,
                                and your objections of making these a finality, are received with all due respect. You termed us "liberal,"
                                and thus we mean to be, so that we will not engage in warm debate, even for our side; believing that the
                                spirit of truth will create sufficient commotion in any soul, which, like yours, has spiritual aspirations,
                                yet would not give up the desires of the soul for fleshly, generative lusts. You esteem marriage, in its
                                upright condition, to be the ne plus ultra of human bliss. Carried out, as you can mentally picture it, we
                                admit would yield an earthly heaven, and very many with you devoutly wish this ever had been, or ever can be
                                realized. It is a Utopia. Thousands have been just where you are in their convictions—they have seen that
                                "the earth, earthy," was not " the spirit, heavenly," and, writhing in an agony of fear, lest the true
                                presentiment of the cross should cut off all the idols of their carnal imaginations, they pray and plead
                                that the good God will not be so unmerciful as to lead to the abandonment of the husband and wife relations.
                                The lusts of the flesh, even in their most exalted and admired uniform—in legal marriage, and as properly
                                conducted as the very best are capable of—these still, are the grand shoots from the corrupt tree, from
                                which all the minor fibres draw sustenance. We have been stud}ring this subject for nearly an hundred years,
                                and are satisfied that a failure will follow every attempt to sanctify the flesh through the order <pb n="87" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE S ECA-KE H. 87 of marriage, while shines the spiritual light from the Christian
                                heavens. We are willing you should attempt the scheme of which you speak, though not with our means; and
                                though we should rejoice at an exalted condition of humanity on the animal plane, yet we shall expect to
                                record your scheme " another failure." The flesh, in its most glorified habiliments, is a subject of
                                Christly condemnation; yet, unwilling to part with it entirely, you and many others seem wriggling in a
                                torment that evolves a thousand plans for its salvation. But remember, that not one of a herd of swine will
                                believe the swill hot, regardless of the warning shrieks of the sufferers, until each has burned his snout!
                                I would refer you to " American Socialism," before you attempt any ideal plan for christianizing marriage,
                                and you would then be better aware of how your proposition would result. You labor under a misconception,
                                concerning our position, which I thought I had dispelled : It is, that we refrain from marriage, because of
                                its corruptness. Not so. Even though the Utopia jrou seek could be found, we could not unite in its support;
                                for above the ivhole order of earthly coalition, do ice through a life of Christ aspire ; and away from all
                                worldly elements, pure or impure. We have found something so much better than the most perfect connubiality,
                                that as " the sun's meridian blaze forbids the stars to glow," even so, does the order of earthly beings
                                sink into insignificance before the halo of our pure, angel faith and practice. In this light of the
                                subject, how base it would appear and be in us to aid in sustaining a breeding institution, when we know
                                that all the desires that would then be called to action are, at best, so inferior to the life principles of
                                Christ, as to make the scheme disgusting in its every phase ! Not so, Professor, your convictions, unbiased
                                by fleshly passions, convince you that we can never prostitute our consecrated property from its holy
                                intent, to sustain you, or any of your, or others' selection in the fruitful or " unfruitful works of
                                darkness." You, like many others, have had a call to higher things, and we suggest that you squarely face
                                the music of your conscience; nor think the task given human nature, by our Christly preceptors, is too
                                unpleasant to be engaged in, and like Achan, seek to save some idol from annihilation. Be bold enough to
                                obey your convictions of right, and we will risk the rest. We would not force you to be a Shaker or
                                Christian; but labor, if you choose, in the field of generation, for its higher elevation. We find that from
                                the material it produces now, only a few good Shakers can be produced, and can only bid you God-speed in its
                                improvement, if j^our call is to nothing higher. But we would to God, your convictions, being where we think
                                they are, that you would obey them, regardless of all fleshly cravings or faults of the law. You are only
                                one from many thousands who are appealing, that we "come down from the cross," against all fleshly lusts, "
                                that all men may believe on us !" But we prefer being the unpopular few who, walking the narrow way, have
                                joined ourselves to the cross, " laid down our own lives," and mean, voluntarily, there to remain, even amid
                                the jeers and injustice of the multitude who are walking the broad road—we being in the world, yet not of
                                the world. And when life with you is sped, and indulgence can no more be effectually prosecuted, 'tis then,
                                mark well our words, that you, and thousands like you, will regret that you had not ceased battling for the
                                flesh, and willingly united with us in a life that "walks in the spirit, and fails to fulfill the lusts of
                                the flesh." The love of the world has drawn many bright stars to its plane; but the sincere, the resolute,
                                and violent can alone withstand its charms. Bidding jrou adieu, I am yours, etc.,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/>G. A. Lomas, Ed. Shaker. Prof. H., Lewiston, Me.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Novitiate musings" TEIform="index"/>Novitiate Musings</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Shaker :—Having come suddenly from the midnight of anti-Christian darkness to the full blaze of
                                millennial light, that light shows me many things which, though quite familiar to the experienced Zion
                                traveler, are new to me. I experience, especially in our meetings, new and beautiful influences, which, from
                                want of a more satisfactory term, I will call ministrations of the Spirit of God. It is needless to describe
                                them further than to say, that they are golden and harmonious; that they penetrate the whole physical frame,
                                elevate the mind and soul from the grosser appetites of earth, and stimulate the spirit to fresh exertion to
                                struggle upward. They vary in their character so much that no two are exactly alike. I am sincerely anxious
                                to know, from the experience of larger hearts and wiser heads than mine : 1st. What is the source of these
                                ministrations ? 2d. What are their nature, consistency, properties ? 3d. What are the most favorable
                                conditions for obtaining; them ? 4th. Is it possible to reduce the obtaining of these ministrations to a
                                science ? 5th. Is this a proper subject for investigation, or should we accept these ministrations without
                                questioning their source ? 6th. Would it be acceptable to furnish carefully-noted experiences of the kind
                                for publication, so as to obtain information from many sources, and thus establish the truth by the
                                experience of many witnesses ? This last would involve careful noting of the kind and degree of the
                                ministration, and of the state of the mind, feelings, and bodily system at the time of the reception.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stroud, Thomas J." TEIform="persName"/>Thomas J. Stroud, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply to queries of Thos. J. Stroud" TEIform="index"/>Reply to Queries of Thos. J. Stroud</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">The subject presented by our brother is of vital importance to humanity. He denominates the "new and beautiful
                            influences" to which he is introduced in the Shaker meetings he attends, " Ministrations of the Spirit of God."
                            It is a term well selected to nominate the exercises of the Holy Spirit inspiration ally upon the human soul in
                            such a powerful degree, as to cause the mortal tenement sometimes to tremble under the influence of its power,
                            being overawed by a power so much superior to itself; at other times to be so filled with what might be termed a
                            psychological magnetism, as to produce healing of the physical frame, when diseased ; yea, even to raise the
                            dead; in other cases to agitate powerfully the human frame, giving it many fold its ordinary strength, and
                            enabling the recipient of this ministration to perform feats, while under its influence, which would be
                            impossible in a normal condition. For instance, to enable the unlearned to read well, and retain the faculty
                            after reduction to a normal state; to cause the blind to see, the deaf to hear, the lame to walk, and multitudes
                            of conditions to be induced incident alone to supernal life. Our brother inquires: 1st. " What is the source of
                            these ministrations ?" Answer. Their source is the Divine mind, combined Avith harmonious relations of the human
                            therewith, either in the recipient of the ministrations, or in some other person in close sympathy therewith, as
                            his or her intercessor. In some instances it is simply requisite to be in a state of prayerful passiveness.
                            There are instances where the condition of the recipient seems not to enter into the source at all, but so far
                            as he is concerned, every consideration appears to center in the fact of his needs, and he is made the recipient
                            through the harmonious relations and intercessions of his mediator or Elder, who is in sympathy with him.
                            Question 2. "What are their nature, consistency, properties ?" Answer. Their nature is supernal; their
                            consistency, purely spiritual, intangible; their properties are: 1st, absorbing to the senses; 2d, overawing to
                            the affections; 3d, dominating to the will, during their exercise, but their effects may be dissipated by the
                            after purposes and conduct of the recipient, or retained and enhanced at pleasure ; 4th, inspiring, and
                            influential sympathetically. Question 3d. " What are the most favorable conditions for obtaining them ?" Answer.
                            1st. To stand, spiritually, free from any condemnation from the violation of con- scientious convictions of
                            duty, or righteousness; in other words, free from sin. 2d. To give the soul to prayer. 3d. To surrender the
                            entire will and desires to God. Question 4. "Is it possible to reduce the obtaining of these ministrations to a
                            science ?" Answer. Inasmuch as there is a consecutive and consistent application of appropriate means to that
                            end, as suggested in answer to question 3d, it might be said to be scientific. But " ministrations of the Spirit
                            of God " are fruits of the kingdom of heaven; and Jesus said, truly, " The kingdom of God cometh not with
                            observation." Question 5. "Is this a proper subject for investigation, or should we accept these ministrations
                            without questioning their source ?" Answer. The fruits of the Spirit are proper subjects of investigation, in a
                            spirit of holy <pb n="88" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> reverence and godly carefulness. " Try the spirits," etc. See "Tests of
                            Divine Inspiration," a Shaker publication (pamphlet). Question 6. " Would it be acceptable to furnish
                            carefully-noted, experiences of this kind for publication?" etc. Answer. Very carefully-noted experiences might
                            be published with profit; but much, very much wisdom is requisite in selecting and preparing a report of such
                            experiences to present to a mind largely involved in a wordiy sense; for there is danger in presenting all
                            spiritual and heavenly gifts to the unenlightened, lest it prove as the Gospel of Christ to the Jews, a "
                            stumbling bloc7c," or to the mere wordiy philosopher, as Christ's Gospel to the Greeks, "foolishness." These
                            "ministrations of the Spirit of God" are transmissible from one soul to another, the most favorable conditions
                            necessary being a* oneness of spirit between the minister and recipient, and desire of the recipient to receive.
                            But, in certain instances, they may be so powerful, the love of God so great, and the needs of the recipient so
                            ponderous, that they may be forced upon him even against his will. But their most general dissemination is
                            sympathetically. Hence, some speculative worldly phi- losophers, uninspired by the gift and wisdom of God, would
                            term all such pentecostal bap- tisms, moral or spiritual "epidemics." But an epidemic is a disease, an abnormal
                            condi- tion, by some irritating cause, inducing unhealthy conditions. Such is not the case with pentecostal
                            baptisms, that are sympathetically communicated from soul to soul by the baptis- mal influences of the Holy
                            Spirit. Such baptisms are charged with health to both soul and body. Some worldly philosophers have gone so far
                            as to declare that the statements of a person so inspired by a foreign or another spirit as to be elevated above
                            their normal capacity, are not proper subjects for belief. But, according to this rule, the ancient prophets,
                            Jesus and his apostles, would all stand condemned. The facts are, that almost all the remarkable improvements of
                            human society, either in morals, religion or in the arts, and labor-saving, mechanical inventions, may be justly
                            attributed largely, if not entirely, to inspirations from superior souls and minds, or souls and minds
                            progressed to more elevated conditions than those attained by the recipient, or inventor, so called. There is
                            such a thing as Divine revelation, and those souls who are the happy recipients of it, are elevated thereby
                            above their normal conditions, mentally and spiritually ; but are such revelations to be condemned as false,
                            because of their elevating effects upon humanity ? If so, there is no hope for our race.</p></div2><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our Zion home" TEIform="index"/>OUR ZION HOME</head><p TEIform="p">North Family, Mt. L. Tenderly. 1 We need no earthly flowers, To deck oar Zion home, No artificial radiance,
                            To light her sacred dome; For angel gifts and graces, 2 While transient pleasures perish, And fade as earthly
                            flowers, Our joys are for eternity, Our home in truth's fair bowers; Where heart to heart is blending,
                            c=p=2JF3[==Zz=±=±^*-^ Adorn with beauty bright, And God's transcendant glory, Her mansion fills with light.
                            In purity and love, Where ministers attend ing, Renew from spheres above. O, Home, sweet Home! Blest joys
                            are thine. O, Home, sweet Home! Blest joys are thine.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do good" TEIform="index"/>Do Good</head><p TEIform="p">There are many societies established for the improvement and happiness of humanity. We wish in these few words to
                            give a hearty " God bless" to the "Societies for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals." They are doing a noble
                            work, and are worthy the sympathy and active aid of every humane member of society, capable of feeling sympathy
                            and able to lend a helping hand. Our Bro. R. M. Wagan, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., has some beautifully printed cards,
                            with border, which aim to aid the good work. The cards contain a poem, beginning with, " The man of kindness to
                            his beast is kind." Send for a dozen, fifty cents. *</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many thanks for the numerous replies to 'Notice to Believers'..." TEIform="index"/>Many thanks for the numerous replies to 'Notice to Believers'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Many thanks for the numerous replies to " Notice to Believers," from Believers and others. While nearly all urge
                            an enlargement, we mean to be content another year, at present size, with " Extras."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Harvested</head><p TEIform="p">(Since last Issue.)</p><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Barney, G. W." TEIform="index"/>G. W. Barney
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Enfield, Conn., <persName reg="Barney, G. W." TEIform="persName">G. W. Barney</persName>, aged 57.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small child" TEIform="index"/>Small child
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At South Union, Ky. A small child.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smithson, Cynthia" TEIform="index"/>Cynthia Smithson
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Smithson, Cynthia" TEIform="persName">Cynthia Smithson</persName>, aged—.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Berryhill, Betsy" TEIform="index"/>Betsy Bern-hill
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Berryhill, Betsy" TEIform="persName">Betsy Bern-hill</persName>, aged 83.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Martin, Margery" TEIform="index"/>Margery Martin
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, <persName reg="Martin, Margery" TEIform="persName">Margery Martin</persName>, aged 70.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="McIntosh, Lucy" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Mclntosh
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Mass., <persName reg="McIntosh, Lucy" TEIform="persName">Lucy Mclntosh</persName>, aged 91. The last announcement is
                                accompanied with :'She did the works, hence knew of the doctrines."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS.</head><p TEIform="p">Christ-s First and Second Appearing Diuilavy's Manifesto Millennial Church ----Compendium ol'Shakerism Three
                            Discourses on United Interests Shaker Communism—Evans Shakerism, the Possibility of the Race Tracts free, where
                            postage is paid. If! -'£&gt; 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50 0 50 0 10 </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p">Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans. Mt. Lebanon, Columbia
                            Co., N. Y. " Galen Richmond, Shakers. N. Y. " Calvin G. Heed. Sonyea, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabee, West
                            1'ittsflekl, Mass. " H. S. 'Kellogg, Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co.,
                            Mass. " Wm. Leonard. Aver, Mass.. Shakers. " Jonas Nutting, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. " B. IT.
                            Smith, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., ¦NT. H. " Henry Cummings. Enfield, Grafton Co., N. H. " John B. Vance,
                            Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Joseph Brackett, West Gloucester, Cumberland Co., Me.. Shakers; " Chas. Clapp,
                            Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball,
                            Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. " Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. B. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. "
                            J. S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>