<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1002" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18800201" TEIform="date">February 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHIRLEY, MASS. 'And they shall turn to you for a testimony:" "Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO " The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1880. The Shaker FEBRUARY, 1880.
                        Vol. X. No. 2. 60 Cents Per Annum </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                        --><pb n="25" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One journey" TEIform="index"/>ONE JOURNEY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> To what extent man is a predestined being and must act as a passive machine under the hand
                            of fate, or to what degree the gift of free agency enables him to mark out the chart of his
                            own destiny, there are a variety of opinions ; but that the soul is immortal and is granted
                            but one privilege to pass through the school-days of earthly experience, is almost
                            universally accepted, save by the hoary-locked nations of the Orient who still cling to the
                            idea of transmigration. We, who are young, and just entering upon the pilgrimage of real
                            life, should remember that we have only one journey,—once to live our time on earth, and
                            once to cross the river, dark or shining, as our lives shall make it, which divides time
                            from eternity. Considering this, how promptly and earnestly should we learn the lessons
                            which are marked for us each day in the book of life; every one in its season,as its leaves
                            successively turn, bearing in mind that the attainments of to-morrow are dependent on the
                            efforts of to-day, and are related to them as the blossom is to the bud, and the fruit to
                            the blossom. The hours wanted to-day will surely crowd their burdens on the morrow. How
                            cheerfully we should fulfill with consecrated faithfulness each duty as presented ; for we
                            shall never have another opportunity so favorable ; the same cannot recur; but however small
                            in itself a duty may have been, a principle and motive, right or wrong, have been employed,
                            and have left their impress on the character. Conscious of an eternal future existence, and
                            that our relation together, as human beings, is such that no one can sorrow or joy entirely
                            independently of others, and that happiness, in every sphere, is proportionate to the degree
                            in which others participate with us, should, we not, as rational beings, through most
                            benevolent motives, so to live as to benefit others, just as far as our influence may
                            extend,-—thus make that future desirable to meet ? Along the journey of life are many hills
                            of difficulty which all must climb. If we should meet a feeble one caught among thorns or
                            impeded by rocks, and heedlessly pass by, without extending a helping hand or making any
                            effort to clear the way, would not the thorns of a reproving conscience sting us deeper than
                            those of a briery bush ? We might repent, and aid every other needy one we should meet; but
                            the thought of the one left behind, perhaps to perish, would, follow with lingering remorse.
                            Again, the darksome valleys of suffering PAGE. I PAGE. One Journey, - - • - - - -25 A
                            Purported Communication" from a Shaker Spirit, 3i&gt; Thoughts Relative to a Religious
                            Communistic Our Living Redeemer, 37 Life ------- 26 Debts, ... ... 37 Saintly Communion. - -
                            - - . 27 Editorial: Memento Mori, ------ 27 The New Gospel of Christ, 38 Primary
                            Materializations, - - - - 28 The Constitution of Zion, - - - - 39 Consecrated Labor, - - - -
                            - 29 Editorial Notes, ----- 40-41 Among the Shakers — II, - - - - 29 Correspondence, ------
                            41 " Stand fob the Right,1' - - - - 31 Society Record, ----- 44 Begin the New Yeah right, -
                            - - 31 The Children's Grotto, - - - - - 44 "Not AS I will," - - - - - -32 Music: Dancing in
                            Worship, ----- 32 Home of Liberty, ----- 45 The Curse Removed, - - - - - 32 Rook Table, - -
                            - - - - 46 The Communion of Saints, ?A Homb Topics, ------ 40 The Good Work Going On, - - -
                            - 34 Emersonian, ------- 47 Mouth Virtue, ------ 35 Bad. Ambition, ------ 48 Things Worth
                            Forgetting, - - - - 35 Religion in the Life, - - - - - 48 On Belief, - - - - - - 38 <pb n="26" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 26 THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. and grief, which in turn each one must pass ;
                            how often it is our privilege to place the staff of courage in the hand of a struggling
                            brother or sister, and illume their path with the lamp of faith or beams of hope,— but if we
                            coldly turn away, who shall measure the responsibility that will rest upon us if that
                            sorrowing one should fall by the way 1 or to whom should we look for help in time of need ?
                            It is not the benefit which we alone might bestow that is withheld, for angel guardians are
                            ever hovering near ; with clearer vision than that of mortal eyes, they see the needs of
                            all; it is they who often prompt the kindly word and deed, using us only as their
                            instruments. Hence how careful we should ever be to do the right. We scatter seeds wherever
                            we go along the winding paths of life; if the plants of envy, contention, and sorrow spring
                            up, we may sow again of better seed, but can never cause those to yield the fruit of union,
                            peace or joy. We all have one goal to attain. If we stray from the road that leads
                            thereunto, we may retrace our steps, but it will hinder us just that much on our journey.
                            Eternity is long, but time is not the less precious! No deed can be undone, no word recalled
                            ; even silent thoughts bear an eternal impress upon the being. On the walls of the spirit's
                            temple is photographed every feeling and motive of the heart. These pictures will retain
                            exact form and hue long after the works of art performed by mortal hand have faded. It is a
                            matter of individual choice with all, whether these walls are adorned with glory and beauty,
                            or defaced with that which brings pain and disgrace. As children of one parentage, working
                            together for one cause, it is our especial duty and privilege to sustain and bless each
                            other ; to make duty's path one of pleasure ; to strew flowers along the way which others
                            may gather ; to reap advantages from all the incidents of life, by making them opportunities
                            for conquest of the spirit of love over that of selfishness ; then when our slumbering forms
                            are laid beneath the arch of death and our spirits wake in eternity, as we look back to the
                            shores of time we shall never regret that we had only one journey. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts relative to a religious communistic life" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS RELATIVE TO A
                            RELIGIOUS COMMUNISTIC LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Afford, Ann" TEIform="persName"/>ANN AFFORD</byline><p TEIform="p"> While journeying in the pathway of life, participating with kindred friends the joys and
                            sorrows incidental to a religious, communistic life, the question arises : Am I in truth and
                            reality carrying out the principles of true Christianity in the practical duties of everyday
                            life ? If not, what excuse have I for not doing so '? I am certainly privileged to dwell
                            where the glorious sun-light of truth shines with greater intensity, to invigorate and give
                            new impulses to the whole being, than can be found in the outer wheels of God's Providence,
                            where the spirit of war and monopoly are in the ascendancy, and selfish interests bear rule
                            ; where each and all seek gain from their own quarter to build up a natural relationship,
                            which, however good it may be in its time and place, is designed to pass away and be
                            superseded by a spiritual Order of Society on a higher plane. The natural is first; but
                            believers in Christ's Gospel are called to a higher work ; to come under the Divine
                            influence of Peace Purity, and that true love that is "without partiality," and belongs to
                            the family of Christ, that love that expands, and flows to humanity through unselfish
                            consecrated labor. I realize that I am privileged to dwell in this spiritual Order; and that
                            here an altar of sacrifice is erected whereon glows the fire of truth, whose piercing rays
                            of light, and fervid heat, — if permitted to enter the heart—will purify unto perfection.
                            If, under such favorable auspices, I fail in duty, the fault is my own ; I can have no
                            excuse. I rejoice that through the medium of our " Manifesto," I can assure my companions
                            who have entered the gospel work, and have pledged themselves, as I Lave done, to bear the
                            same cross that Jesus bore, that my courage is firm and undaunted ; and that my life shall
                            be consecrated to the upbuilding of the cause of Christ on earth; for the deepest feelings
                            of my heart are to become a true and perfect Christian; and to show <pb n="27" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 27 my faith by my works through adverse scenes, as truly as in the days of
                            prosperity. A weak, frail bark may glide nicely over smooth waters; but fierce winds and
                            rolling billows test the strength of a vessel. In a recent visit among my dear gospel
                            kindred at Enfield, Conn., Harvard and Shirley, Mass., there was nothing that struck me more
                            forcibly than the beautiful spirit of devotion to heavenly principles that I felt from my
                            aged brethren and sisters ; these dear souls who have endured persecution, deprivation and
                            sufferings for truth's sake through many years ; and who have fought the good fight of
                            faith, and laid up treasures in heaven. Although their tottering limbs and whitened locks
                            bespoke age and infirmity, and betoken that their earthly course was nearly finished, yet in
                            spirit they were bright and lovely. The sweet influence of their spirits to me was like the
                            aroma of flowers, and their words were full of wisdom. I will strive to be likewise, and to
                            make my life a blessing to others, as theirs has been to me. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saintly communion: 'Prentissiana'" TEIform="index"/>SAINTLY COMMUNION: "PRENTISSIANA."</head><p TEIform="p"> Of the creed, drilled into my protesting cranium on the 46th parallel of north latitude, in
                            the spring of 1807, one item remains, to wit: " I believe in the communion of Saints." By
                            Divine inspiration it doth fully appear that Humanity is a compound — a germ of Divinity,
                            enshrined in an earthly house, or casket, having appetites and passions not much unlike
                            animals in general. Let the germ germinate — take sufficient growth to keep the earthly
                            house in order — hold its appetites and passions in subordination to the germ's Divinest
                            Idea of the true dignity of the Daughters and Sons of the Holy, Eternal Parentage, and we
                            have Saints with whom to communeThen is actualized the Prophecy of Habakkuk : " The Lord is
                            in his Holy Temple — Let all the earth keep silence before Him"— actualized in every such
                            saint as aforesaid. In children and youth, in comparative innocence, the germ of the saint
                            is more cognizable — more approachable — than in children of a larger growth, who have long
                            been under the control of their animal appetites and passions, called, in Holy Writ " the
                            kingdom of the beast."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memento mori" TEIform="index"/>MEMENTO MORI</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p"> When we stand by the bier ®f those we have loved, and view with sorrow the motionless form,
                            the cold, set, marble features, once aglow with expression and life ; when we walk above the
                            new-made graves, or visit the ancient mounds of the voiceless past ; we need no further
                            reminder of the frailty of mortality or the surety of dissolution. But the mind soon wearies
                            of monuments, epitaphs and tombs. One does not always choose to walk beside the shrouded
                            angel who bears the emblem of the dread destroyer, to entertain gloomy thoughts, nor to
                            dwell amid shadows dark, sepulchral, with eyes fixed on the cold, gray earth, as if a home
                            in its bosom was to be our final resting place. Rather let us gaze star ward, and when our
                            souls are thrilled with awe and wonder, at the marvelous works of that beneficent Creator
                            who formed us even in His own image, think of that glorious translation, when we shall put
                            on immortality and rise into superior conditions of life. Ah ! let us remember death amid
                            the liveliest scenes when we feel strongest; when life in its brightest aspect looms before
                            us like the golden light of some fair morning, giving a charm to every thing it touches.
                            Then as we turn to duty's path, to pleasure's way, to social surroundings, or to spiritual
                            devotions, one sacred, hallowed thought shall touch the spring of action: "I will live as
                            though I had a thousand years to live and as though I were to die to-morrow." Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Lord is in His holy temple..." TEIform="index"/>The Lord is in His holy temple...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The Lord is in His holy temple, let all the earth keep silence before Him. —Heb. 2:20. In
                            every well balanced man and woman with perfect self-control, is the above scripture
                            verified.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. Prentiss</byline></div2><pb n="28" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Primary materializations" TEIform="index"/> PRIMARY MATERIALIZATIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Vague thoughts and theoretical ideas have their place, and serve to agitate the mind,
                            leading to deeper thought and practical knowledge ; but these should not be allowed to so
                            absorb the mind, as to cause neglect of real, present duty, which should claim the first
                            attention. Much has been said, and written, concerning the origin of animals, races, and
                            tribes of men and women of olden time. It is not of so much vital import to us, to know
                            whence we came, and to understand the ancestral history of those who have preceded us, as to
                            know where we are to-day, and whither we are tending. Yet it is pleasant, and often very
                            instructive, to go back upon history, and study the records of our antecedents ; to note the
                            noble thoughts, and unselfish deeds of those who have lived for humanity more than for
                            worldly honor and fame, and who did their work and were gathered to their fathers in peace ;
                            from them we can take important lessons. All agree that there was a time when man and woman
                            were created ; but the mode by which they were created, and first brought into existence,
                            still remains a knotty question to be solved. We think of God, as unchangeable in His nature
                            and attributes ; that by prescience— seeing the end from the beginning—He prescribed laws
                            which would be adequate to guide and govern the outward world of matter, also of races of
                            intelligent beings, adapted to age and circumstances, subject to change of modes of
                            application to meet conditions, but unalterable in their nature. The idea, that the world of
                            matter changed from the liquid, or the gaseous to solids, which contained seeds of vegetable
                            life, from which trees.and plants were evolved, then the lowest form of animal life up to
                            man, the highest, upon whose brow God placed His signet—reasoning powers—as a distinguishing
                            mark from all inferior creatures, to some minds, appears rational: but precisely how the
                            first parents of our race were evolved, or made up, is difficult to comprehend. We can
                            understand how certain kinds of animals may become extinct; but that they should change into
                            other species of animals is less clear. A fish remains a fish from age to age ;—the lion
                            continues a lion ; and the lamb is still a lamb. And it occurs to us that the Anakims of
                            ancient history were not so much like the ape, in stature at least, as men and women of the
                            present generation. The theory that God made man of the dust of earth, and formed him as the
                            potter forms a jug, then breathed into him, and caused him to live—according to Bible
                            history—requires a stretch of credulity. That God had His method of creation we do not
                            doubt; nor that there may have been periods, when by the laws of expansion and development
                            there were generic conceptions, and the great womb of nature brought forth species of
                            animals, or tribes, and races of men and women, is possible, if not to our minds
                            comprehensible. If under the law of materialization, as some persons now claim, one man and
                            woman could be organized, and brought forth in a state of full manhood, by the operation of
                            the same law, any number of men and women might be thus created. Then the queries would
                            arise : " Why did not the same law continue to operate? What caused the change ? " If we
                            accept Bible history, we must admit that the law of materialization, or transfiguration, has
                            at times been in force, in some form, down through the ages, which has generally been
                            accepted as a miracle working power—permission—rather than in accord with established law.
                            That there is a law by which spirits appear with materialized bodies we cannot dispute.
                            Whether that law extends only to those who have once inhabited mortal forms, and been
                            dwellers on our earth, causing a re-union of spirit with matter, or whether it admits of new
                            creations,is a question. If it be argued that the law is broad and strong enough to form new
                            creations, then we might ask : " Why is the race permitted to multiply as it now does,
                            entailing misery upon added millions yearly, who are forced into existence without their own
                            consent?" If the evils which curse humanity to-day <pb n="29" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE
                            MANIFESTO. 29 are obnoxious to and reprehensible in the sight of God, why does He not make
                            an end of sin and sinners, and commence anew— start a new race upon the earth ? If " He is
                            able to raise up children unto Abraham from stones," is He not able to bring forth the full
                            grown tree, also men who will be able to do His will, without so many severe conflicts in
                            life ? Projectors of ideas are at work, and many theories are advanced upon the subject, by
                            scientists, philosophers and spiritual mediums. We listen to them all with interest, but
                            await further proof before we decide who holds the key to unlock the mystery.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecrated labor" TEIform="index"/>CONSECRATED LABOR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Martha Ann" TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA ANN BURGER</byline><p TEIform="p"> When the powers and energies of the being are devoted to the support, and for the
                            advancement of the communistic relation, where temporal and spiritual blessings are alike
                            free to all, selfish interests must be set aside ; and the power of Love be the motor that
                            moves to action. How much more noble and satisfactory is such labor, than where individual
                            benefits are alone considered. True glory rests upon those who consecrate their hearts to
                            God in early life to the upbuilding of His cause, and the welfare of their fellow beings. In
                            a life of self-denial, spiritual powers are unfolded, moral sentiments are developed, the
                            intellectual faculties quickened, and the whole being renovated ; blessing attends the labor
                            of the hands ; and it becomes a pleasure to minister to the needs of others. There have
                            always been those who devoted their lives to promulgate truth according to the day in which
                            they lived, and their degree of conception as to what constituted truth. But as far as our
                            knowledge extends, there has never been a people so favored and blest in this respect, as
                            are Believers in Christ's second appearing at the present time. Intelligence has increased ;
                            and the standard of righteousness to those who choose to bear it is raised higher. Jesus
                            held forth the idea of a community relation, based upon virgin purity, to be out•vrought by
                            Divine law. The organization that was started at the day of Pentecost failed ; the time had
                            not come when it could be carried to its ultimate ; it was a " kind of first fruits." But
                            the knowledge of the principles remained, and were left to work in the minds of the people,
                            until they were prepared to sustain such an order. The same truths that were revealed to
                            Jesus were presented to Ann Lee with in. creased power. She ministered them to others who
                            accepted them with thankful hearts, and were willing to give their all to sustain them.
                            Through their unreserved dedication, and consecrated labor, our beautiful Zion here was
                            created ; and by the same spirit it has been and is sustained. How can we repay the debt of
                            gratitude we owe, except by the same spirit of self-sacrifice and devotion ? Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Among the shakers: II" TEIform="index"/>AMONG THE SHAKERS: II</head><p TEIform="p">The peculiar features of Shakerism are pretty well known, and are usually dismissed as
                            extravagant and unnatural, without much consideration. It cannot be denied that on the first
                            presentation of its general features it strikes one as being a cold, unnatural system. But
                            it is personal character which usually makes any thing what it is; and though there are many
                            objectionable things about Shakerism which are mainly traceable to ignorance, a calm and
                            deep consideration would considerably modify the tone of public feeling toward it. In most
                            of the stories which are published with Shakeresses for the heroines, the older Shakers are
                            represented as cruel persecutors, who are continually trying to thwart the natural
                            affections or love which the younger members show toward each other, or toward strangers who
                            happen upon the scene. The writers do not understand that .the sacrifice of close
                            relationships which Shakerism demands comes from personal conviction, and that people do not
                            usually join the Shakers who feel or think differently about these things. It seems about as
                            hard for strangers to believe that the Shakers live up to their professions as it was in the
                            early part of the temperance <pb n="30" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 30 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. movement to
                            believe that any one could live without drinking ; and it is still believed in England that
                            temperance advocates or teetotalers drink on the sly. The Shakers allow a certain amount of
                            affection among the members. One of the men used to speak in our presence of a woman who was
                            his " good sister," meaning that she was the one who took more special care of his clothing,
                            etc., but they have very strict rules for preventing any thing of this kind going beyond a
                            definite point. Upon our first introduction to them I noticed the cold, stiff manner in
                            which the Elder shook hands with me. I found afterward it was against the rules for men and
                            women to shake hands. They have also different doors for the sexes to enter their buildings,
                            and the brothers and sisters do not sit nor stand upon the same side of a room, and are not
                            allowed to pass each other on the stairs. But they talk to each other without any hesitation
                            or embarrassment upon all social topics, and express their opinions very freely upon
                            subjects which are rarely mentioned in common society. A stranger is surprised at their
                            bluntness, but their straightforwardness overcomes all difficulty of getting at the real
                            points of their faith. The life of a Shaker is full of hard work and rigid discipline. Their
                            founder was a woman of great physical strength and endurance, but very little education; and
                            her standard seems to have been kept up among her followers, who are mostly people of robust
                            health, and have not a very exalted opinion of " book education." They say they find that
                            those who are specially fond of reading are often idle and unprofitable per sons. Still,
                            they have a number of welleducated, intelligent people among them, and the ability to write
                            and speak well, places these among the leaders. They are, in general, pretty well informed
                            upon all progressive movements, and are especially careful upon matters pertaining to the
                            health, diet, etc., although they cling to old-fashioned methods in their farming and other
                            employments. Whatever they do they do well. They used to have a large trade for various
                            articles of manufacture, for their goods were known to be reliable ; but their numbers
                            having decreased, and a large proportion of the members who remain being old and infirm, not
                            to mention the greater use of machinery among outsiders, a great part of their trade in
                            garden seeds,, brooms, etc., has been taken away from them, and they are left largely
                            dependent on farming, though some of their Societies derive a considerable income from
                            outside investments. They rise in summer at half-past four, and in winter about five, and go
                            about their various duties until the bell calls them to breakfast at six or half-past six
                            o'clock, when they attend to their personal appearance, and proceed to the dining-room,
                            where they kneel down for a short time in silent prayer. They then in perfect silence help
                            themselves to whatever they want from an abundantly supplied table, for the women take great
                            pride in their cooking, and always have whatever is in season cooked in the best possible
                            manner. Every thing is clean and good and pure, and great care is taken to make every thing
                            both palatable and digestible. Whatever other sacrifices the Shakers make, good eating and
                            drinking are not among them. After the work of the day they usually have meetings in the
                            evening ; but from what I saw of them I thought them pretty dull. The members would enter a
                            large room each carrying a chair, and would sit— the men on one side, and the women on the
                            other—in two long rows, five or six feet apart. They would strike up a hymn or enter into
                            general conversation ; but it seemed.difficult for them to find topics—at least, whilst we
                            were there—possibly, partly on that account. It was very different in a room up stairs where
                            the leaders held their meetings. We were sent for one evening by the Elder, who wished to
                            speak with us, and were met at the door by a blaze of light and warmth ; and as we entered
                            we found a nice, warm, soft carpet and rugs upon the floor, a large handsome stove, large
                            soft easy-chairs, with foot-cushions, tables covered with cloths, on which, stood different
                            kinds of fruit, a fine German student-lamp in the center, and everything which spoke of
                            warmth and comfort. Perhaps it might <pb n="31" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 31 have
                            been different in the olden time ; but it seemed as if, notwithstanding their preach, ing of
                            the doctrine of perfect equality, it was hard to keep it up in practice. It may be said in
                            extenuation, that all the members have private rooms which are pretty comfortably furnished
                            ; and that the leaders fare the same as the rest in food and other thing's, and like the
                            humblest members are expected to labor with their hands. Saturday afternoon they leave off
                            work early and prepare for the Sabbath. Their public worship on Sunday begins at ten
                            o'clock, and consists mostly of singing and marching around the room ; singing the most
                            lively tunes, and sometimes working themselves up to quite a pitch of excitement, when
                            various members will give their testimony. They used formerly to dance, but the members are
                            now mostly old, and they content themselves with marchiDg. I am speaking, of course, of a
                            single Society; it is different in some of the Societies where there are more young and
                            middle-aged people. Indeed, we ourselves once had the good fortune to be permitted to see
                            the Shakers in a private meeting at the head Society of New Lebanon, where there are a large
                            number of members. The meetings are far more vigorous and lively there, and every thing is
                            done with the greatest precision. They would march around the room at a very lively pace ;
                            then, at a certain point in the tune, would face about and skip or jump a number of times;
                            then turn and proceed upon their march without the slightest pause. And to other tunes they
                            had regular sets, and would go through their movements in the most graceful and picturesque
                            manner possible, and with the greatest precision, and yet without any apparent leadership. I
                            never saw any dancing that had a more pleasing effect. (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Joy a duty" TEIform="index"/>Joy a Duty</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dale, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Dale</byline><p TEIform="p"> We ask God to forgive us' for our evil thoughts and evil temper, but rarely, if ever, ask
                            him to forgive our sadness. Joy is regarded as a happy accident of the Christian life, an
                            ornament and a luxury, rather than a duty.— </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stand for the right" TEIform="index"/>STAND FOR THE RIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcomb, Ola L." TEIform="persName"/>OLA L. WHITCOMB</byline><p TEIform="p"> Stand for the right with unwavering will, Stand firm and be true, but never stand still, The
                            pathway is rough, 'tis trod by few feet, And many, the ills all pioneers meet. From friends
                            we love well sometimes we must part. Although still in sight, heart beat8 not to heart. No
                            two see alike, but Black is not White, And whatever the shade, stand thou for the Right.
                            Stand firm, and be true, and never retreat, Be sure at the start Persecution you'll meet ;
                            But rubbing makes bright the silver and steel, And your mind may need all the friction you
                            feel. But stand for the right, for somebody must; You'd better wear out, than lie still and
                            rust ; The Lord must have help — be steady and true ; For should He come this way, He might
                            want you. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Begin the new year right" TEIform="index"/>BEGIN THE NEW YEAR RIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> In entering upon the new year, the important truth should be remembered, that in the
                            struggle for eternal life, we must work if we would win. If we would end the year with
                            spiritual prosperity, we must commence it with self-denial and self-discipline; these are
                            necessary prerequisites for the kingdom of heaven. It is the cross bearing work that makes
                            life noble. " No cross no crown." In vain are all our efforts if truth and purity form no
                            part of our characters. Suppose that we make these virtues none of our familiar
                            acquaintances; we are sure to find life miserable. None are safe and wise,but the honest and
                            pure. Be true; love and practice virtue. There is "a still small voice," that is a reminder
                            of these things. We need to work up to a high plane of spiritual life, to gain immortal
                            riches, and just here, at the " gateway of the new year," is the place to begin; and to <pb n="32" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 32 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. obtain them, truth and purity must be
                            cultivated, for these habits imply a whole train of noble virtues, which insure real
                            happiness to all their votaries. " Virtue alone is happiness below." The true and virtuous
                            are angelic — childlike ; and Christ said of little children, " of such is the kingdom of
                            heaven." We cannot be too honest nor virtuous. Virtue is a bright jewel, richer than gold,
                            rubies, or precious gems. To obtain it, our hearts, which are the seat of principles, must
                            be right, clean, pure. Who hesitates to enlist on the side of purity ? We would all find
                            heaven; why not make it a point to be honest and virtuous, thus fitting ourselves for the
                            home where we wish to go ? Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Not as I will" TEIform="index"/>NOT AS I WILL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Ida T." TEIform="persName"/> Ida T. Burger</byline><p TEIform="p"> [Lines written by a short time before her decease, aged 21.] Not as 1 will, 0 Father, When
                            filled my cup appears * My soul seeks light in darkness, While in this vale of tears. Not as
                            1 will, O Father — Thy will be done through me, And in the last bright sunset, My gifts I'll
                            bring to Thee. Not as 1 will, 0 Father—While kneeling at thy shrine, Will I break the bread
                            Thou givest. But in Thy will, not mine. Nay ; not my will 0 Father! Thy bread and wine so
                            sweet, Shall fill me, when life's blossoms lie withering at my feet. Not as I will, my
                            Father! In lone Gethsemane. I enter, Love's pure breezes there shall bear me home to Thee.
                            This will, of mine, 0 Father ! I pray may sometimes be Brought into perfect oneness,
                            Accepted Lord of Thee. Canaan Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="dance" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dancing in worship" TEIform="index"/>DANCING IN WORSHIP</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p"> Singing and dancing are inherent in the dispositions of human beings. It is to those in the
                            vigor of life an outward expression of a thrill of pleasure. The idea has obtained, that all
                            worship must needs be expressed through the medium of the tongue. The virtue of piety is
                            often wrongly ascribed to such as can make eloquent sermons and prayers. Being required to
                            devote our " bodies a living sacrifice" why should it be considered irreverent or
                            incompatible with Christian dignity to worship in the dance ? Form in itself is only an
                            outward expression of worship. Revivals of spirituality which stir men's souls with deep
                            convictions often produce outward operations. Shouting and playing on the timbrel did not
                            suffice the Israelites when they were delivered from the bondage of Egypt. Those inspired
                            ones on the day of Pentecost did not so restrain their spiritual emotions that they merely
                            sung. Deliverance from the slavery of evil habits and tormenting lusts, and the opening of
                            the spiritual vision to see the beauties of the higher life, fills the aspiring mind with
                            joy inexpressible, and causes the spirit to leap from its shackles of selfishness into
                            liberty and simplicity. 'Twas thus our leaders learned the beautiful order of marching in
                            circles, and other exercises, sacred on account of the sincerity of their souls ; and
                            because kindred spirits drew near, and the door of inspiration was opened. Modern
                            Spiritualism was not a new lesson to our people. From our origin as a peculiar people these
                            manifestations have attended our worship. There can be no circle of mediums more congenial
                            or attractive to spirits than a company of pure and innocent brethren and sisters united in
                            the spirit of Christian love. In such society and under such conditions the higher class of
                            inspirations predominates ; and false spirits are easily detected and excluded. Shakers, N.
                            T.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curse removed" TEIform="index"/>THE CURSE REMOVED</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p"> St. Paul said: " Let your women keep silence in the church, for I suffer not a woman to
                            teach or to usurp authority over the man." He gave as his reason for this pro- <pb n="33" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 33 hibition that Adam was first created, then Eve. Adam
                            was not deceived, but the woman being deceived was in the transgression. It appears that man
                            and woman were created equal, but in consequence of the woman's yielding to an inferior or
                            animal nature, tempted Adam to disobedience (to which he so readily consented) she had to
                            bear the penalty of her transgression. She was told that "in sorrow she should bring forth
                            children, that her desire should be to her husband, and he should rule over her." But in
                            this condition she was not left without hope, for she was told that " the seed of the woman
                            should bruise the serpent's head." So mankind looked forward to the coming of the Messiah
                            for the fulfilment of this promise. In process of time the Messiah came. His advent was the
                            cause of great joy to those who looked for Him, and the angel choir sounded forth " Glory to
                            God in the highest, on Earth peace and good will to men." Yet in Christ's first appearing
                            woman was not released from bondage — the curse was not removed, for the apostle Paul in
                            nearly all of his epistles insisted that the women be kept in subjection, yea subject in all
                            things. He said " the married woman cared for the things of the world that she may please
                            her husband, but the unmarried cared for the things of the Lord that she might be pure in
                            body and spirit." By ruling herself she is saved from the sorrows of childbearing&gt; and from
                            being ruled by a husband. The second Adam had come. In the first creation the order was not
                            complete till Eve was brought forth; so was it not as necessary that the second Eve should
                            stand in her lot in the new creation to make the order complete '? Christ had taught His
                            disciples of His second coming, so at one time they inquired of Him what should be the sign
                            of His coming and of the end of the world ? for they seemed to think that there was some
                            connection in these events. After showing them the signs that should precede, He said: When
                            the son of Man shall come in His glory and all the holy angels with Him, then shall He sit
                            on the throne of His glory and before Him shall be gathered all nations and He shall
                            separate them one from another as a shepherd divideth the sheep from the goats." We are told
                            that " the woman is the glory of the man;" so if His second appearing should be in a woman
                            where can be the objection? At one time He said to the people that unless they ate His flesh
                            and drank His blood they had no life in them." They reasoned among themselves how that could
                            be. He said, "the words that I speak unto you they are spirit and they are life; the flesh
                            profits nothing." So if it is the testimony, what is the difference whether it is given by
                            male or female ? or as in the case of John the Baptist who came in the spirit and power of
                            Elias ? The apostle said : " Now we speak in part and we prophesy in part; when that which
                            is perfect is come then that which is in part shall be done away." So when the second Eve
                            has come the order will be complete. About one hundred years ago God raised up a woman and
                            endowed her with power to bring forth a testimony whereby all who will may be saved from sin
                            and come into the resurrection of the just. "As many as believe, to them there is power
                            given to become the children of God." Such are the seed of the woman who will bruise the
                            serpent's head, and triumph over a carnal nature. Such know assuredly that Christ has come
                            "in His glory;" that "the bride hath made herself ready and the marriage of the Lamb has
                            come;" yea " Christ has come the second time without sin unto salvation." " The man is not
                            without the woman in the Lord, neither is the woman without the man." The order is complete;
                            the mystery is revealed ; and "that which was in part is done away." The sons and daughters
                            of our Father and Mother of the new creation live the life of the Lamb, or life of
                            innocence, having nothing to do with the works of the flesh ; hence on them the end of the
                            world has come and they are harvested from the earth, and are subjects of that kingdom which
                            the God of heaven was to set up — a kingdom that should never have an end. I having been "a
                            transgressor after the <pb n="34" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 34 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. similitude of Eve's
                            transgression," have suffered the penalty ; have obeyed the command : " Wives obey your
                            husbands," as conscientiously as any other woman, feeling it to be God-given. The law of
                            Christ has made me free frotn the law of the carnal commandment ; therefore, having
                            crucified the flesh with its affection and lusts, I am free to say that no man shall rule
                            over me&gt; for that curse is removed.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communion of saints" TEIform="index"/>Communion of saints
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Farningham, Marianne" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">THE COMMUNION OF SAINTS. Marianne Famingham. The family is large, we are
                                    scattered here and there, We do but come together for a time of praise and prayer:
                                    But the hours are aye the sweetest when we see in kindly eyes The knowledge of the
                                    Father and the faith that seeks the skies ; And our thanks are true and fervent when
                                    we bless the God above For communion with each other, and the joy of Christian love.
                                    We do not always speak of the Lord we love so well, Nor name the one dear home where
                                    we all have hope to dwell; But the glad unspoken thought fills our souls with
                                    tranquil peace, And we think of that fair city where the partings all shall cease ;
                                    And hope and joy and courage help us through the onward way, When our hearts have
                                    been united for one happy, restful day. One goes through shaded scenes where the
                                    harvest fields are white. And one to sunny southward where the days are calm and
                                    bright, And one to where the crowd is the thickest in the street, And one to the
                                    fierce battle, where the deadly foemen meet. But we nevermore are strangers, and
                                    whereever we may roarn. The paths shall meet together, for we all are going home. .
                                    We have a transient time of joy, and then for weary years We cannot walk together
                                    with blended smiles and tears; But we keep all warm within us the love and kindness
                                    past, We shall take up the scattered threads, and make them Whole at last ; And then
                                    complete the story commenced so long ago, When we dwell at home together, and the
                                    full communion know. Some have gone home before us, and yet it often seems That the
                                    only parting veil is the misty one of dreams. Are we not .sometimes conscious that
                                    they are by our side ? Do they not float about us oft in the eventide? Perhaps the
                                    dead are nearer than the living, for the love Has nought to make it colder when the
                                    dear ones are above. But let us thank our Father that even now and here, He gives us
                                    glad communion for our solace and our cheer, And the knowledge of that home far off
                                    from sin and woe, To which with eager footsteps His children ever go ; Oh let us
                                    hasten onward, at last we all shall meet, With the fellowship unbroken and the
                                    friendship all complete. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl">in <index level1="London Christian world" TEIform="index"/>London Christian World.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good work going on" TEIform="index"/>THE GOOD WORK GOING ON</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erwin, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA ERWIN</byline><p TEIform="p"> We often hear the question asked, why we are content in our quiet way, when there are such
                            great opportunities to sound the trumpet of our testimony to earth's inhabitants. But I am
                            persuaded that the Archangel's trump is now blowing, and sounds high over all other strains.
                            I discern his silver thread of music as it solves the doubts of the present time ; and as it
                            knits up the hopes of the future saying to us : "Be brave, be strong, be patient. Think not
                            to accomplish great things without a struggle, and labor. Yea and patient labor too. We need
                            to double our energies, and press forward ; for 'tis the patient brain, and untiring eye,
                            that win the crown." And as the sound passes on the regions of the future, leaving a breath
                            of peace behind it, so shall we, held by its gentle spell, listen, and know the counsels of
                            .God are just and will not fail. We have much yet to learn which experience alone «an teach
                            us. Our Faith is precious indeed, and the standard bearers learn through pains, perseverance
                            and forlorn hopes what well becomes the true cross bearer, and what fits them to aid in the
                            cause of truth. The end and the <pb n="35" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 35 means are
                            strangely confused in the instinctive judgment which guides our actions. Our intentions do
                            not often leap up the high ideals of action ; but while we do our little work to secure
                            peace and harmony, the secret unravels, that we are working as much for others as ourselves.
                            And this has been proved experimentally, and accepted intellectually. The true and honest
                            heart recognizes the brotherhood, and allows the claims of "good will to all," which is the
                            opposite of selfishness, and antagonism. God's tests will bring out the traits of both.
                            Brother Peebles has said : "This life is a hotel in which mortals tarry for a little season
                            for rudimental experiences, ripening through toil and suffering." Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mouth virtue" TEIform="index"/>MOUTH VIRTUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barber, W. K." TEIform="persName"/>W. K. BARBER</byline><p TEIform="p"> Words are but breath — they may be moral, From the tongue may glibly roll, Goodness
                            seemingly their prompter, They're no index of the soul. Yet as such we oft accept them,
                            Gauge by them the speaker's worth, Eanking those whose talk is virtuous With the chosen ones
                            of earth. Knowledge of a man's true nature What he says cannot impart — 'Tis his deeds alone
                            acquaint us With the promptings of his heart. The benevolent and guileless Make of virtue no
                            parade, And instead of oft proclaiming, Keep their good deeds in the shade. But the
                            heartless and the vicious Their real nature to conceal, Of the pious role assuming, Prate of
                            what they never feel. Most censorious, these sham Christians, While the practical, the true,
                            Of their fellow-men's shortcomings Take a charitable view. Hypocrites show no such lenience
                            ; 'Tis their cue, when they detect Any foible in another, Holy horror to affect. Cold their
                            hearts, tight drawn their pursestrings — Though benevolence may flow From their lips in
                            rounded periods, Talk relieves not want nor woe. They, even, who sneer at virtue, Making of
                            their sin a vaunt, Are less than those vile impostors Whose religion is mere cant.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Things worth forgetting" TEIform="index"/>THINGS WORTH FORGETTING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chadwick, Alice" TEIform="persName"/>ALICE CHADWICK</byline><p TEIform="p"> There are a great many things in the common course of social life which deserve to be
                            instantly and forever forgotten. It is hard to forget a harsh word that has been spoken to
                            us, but if we forgive and take it as a lesson not to do the same to others, it would
                            sometimes prove a blessing. Perhaps we have noticed that many speeches become mischievous
                            only by being heard a second time; for they are exaggerated when repeated ; but if they
                            could have been forgotten they would have caused no trouble at all. Dr. Livingstone says : "
                            The person that can let drop all the burrs and thistles instead of picking them up and
                            fastening them on the next passenger, is worthy of a blessing." Such have many friends and
                            are loved and appreciated by all who know them; their cheerful countenances bespeak what is
                            in the heart ; they promote the happiness of all within the compass of their influence and
                            are always happy themselves, for nothing makes such persons happier than to be surrounded by
                            ardent friends. We may think that it is natural for some to be more amiable than others ;
                            but if we do the best we can, we shall be loved. We all know that we can see the faults of
                            others sooner than we can observe our own. If we could only forget the injuries,and think
                            of]the good that has been done, we should feel better than if we brought them to mind every
                            time we feel unkindly toward the persons who caused them. But this we should remember, that
                            the happiness of our whole life depends on the cultivation of a good disposition. Enfield,
                            Conn.</p></div2><pb n="36" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="On belief" TEIform="index"/>ON BELIEF</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Q., G." TEIform="persName"/>G. Q.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Few men know what manner of spirit they are of. A man's real belief is not made
                                    up of sundry words which he has learned from his father, or heard from the preacher,
                                    or read in a book ; but it is made up of those things unto which he squares his
                                    inner and only-to-himself known life, of wish and thought and deed. If this were
                                    otherwise, then many true believers might be made out of parrots and cockatoos and
                                    starlings ; nay, we might have ravens members of the New Jerusalem; for a raven,
                                    with his tongue split early, will talk as plainly and as manlike as Christians do,
                                    who, with divided tongues, speak of Christ and love and heaven and prayer, and so
                                    forth. The true belief of every man is that rule and system according to which his
                                    inner hidden aims work themselves forth into deed. Thus every one's belief makes a
                                    part of himself; nay, is his very self. No teaching passes into his belief until it
                                    becomes himself, and so becomes of him his own. That they do the Father's will, know
                                    of the doctrine ; others do not know, but they have "heard say." For instance, he
                                    believes innerly in baptism who washes with the water of truth that skin of him
                                    which he calls his consciousness, and who puts away its filth by ever checking
                                    himself with the ten commandments. He believes in the resurrection of the dead, who
                                    himself passes from death to life, by following those commands which lead to life,
                                    because they forbid the ways to death. He believes in hell who has found hell in
                                    himself, at this or that time and place, and at many times and places, and knows
                                    that this or that thing which he lias wished or done is of hell, and is hell. He
                                    believes in heaven in whom heaven is. He believes in the hidden Father, in whom love
                                    true and real—not fear or self-love, or the hope of fat things hereafter—has at last
                                    come to be a secret, invisible Father to all that is in him. He believes in the
                                    Word, who, by following the Word and its laws, is coming into that belief in the
                                    Father. He believes in the Holy Breath whose life breathes forth only the holy. He
                                    believes that these Three are one, who shapes his likings till they be one with law,
                                    and makes his deeds to be one with law. He believes in judgment to come, who, day by
                                    day, judges himself, well sifting the outer from the inner, the light from the
                                    solid, the chaff from the corn. He believes in the Holy Supper whose tastes feed on
                                    uprightness, and whose mind drinks in the true. He believes in the only-begotten
                                    Son, whose daily life springs from God and not from the devil; no other man than he
                                    believes on that name or receives the Son and a sonship. In a word, there is no
                                    belief real save that which is wrought forth into the real ; and nowhere but in the
                                    real can any truth be realized. For belief and faith and all those good things that
                                    Christians do so love to exercise the tongue upon, are like the plans of builders ;
                                    true, beautiful, harmonious, logical ; the integral calculus may lie at the bottom
                                    of them, and were they false, there might be no possible equation for an asymptote ;
                                    but for all this, unless they be carried out in stone, wood, brick and iron they are
                                    castles in the air, and tend not to edification. It is well to know and be sure of
                                    this, though with never so clear a knowledge, it still may be that a man will never
                                    prate a word the less about religion, or baulk the inward devil of a single deed. "
                                    .," in N. J. Messenger.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jersey messenger" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purported communication from a shaker spirit" TEIform="index"/> A PURPORTED COMMUNICATION
                            FROM A SHAKER SPIRIT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stebbins, Olive" TEIform="persName"/>Olive Stebbins</byline><p TEIform="p"> [The following encouraging spirit communication was received through the mediumship of W. L.
                            Jack, M. D. :] : Let there be light. These words were spoken by one who came before us, and
                            who taught us, through our Mother God, of love, of purity and peace, those principles that
                            we are now teaching and making so visibly manifest unto the world's people. Ye are my
                            people, saith the Lord, and of a truth I perceive this to be ever so. And I would have ye,
                            brethren, not be ignorant of the fact that your labors are not in vain. Be ye not
                            discouraged, for lo, I am with you alway, even unto the end. Ye have the promise of the life
                            which now is, and of a <pb n="37" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. truth ye do enjoy and
                            possess it, and the godly inheritance of the life to come is thine forever. Verily, verily I
                            say unto you that which you have aforetime been told shall be granted unto all. And may the
                            love of the Father and Mother God, and the light that shone in the heart and life of the
                            meek and lowly Jesus, and His teachings and principles, abide with you all forever, and
                            uphold you with its precious promises in all your undertakings. To my friends at Enfield,
                            Conn., of the different Church families. Dec. 2. We have taken some pains to investigate
                            whether our honored Haverhill medium was acquainted with Eldress Olive or not, and found he
                            was not. We also investigated whether this communication was received by or through any
                            request of any earth friends, and found it was not, but was one of those simple and pure
                            outflowings of attendant surroundings for which Dr. Jack has become somewhat notable. Those
                            desirous of our evidences can have them on application at this office. Ed. Manifesto.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="W. L. Jack: Dear Friend — The communication in the Banner of Light..." TEIform="index"/>W. L. Jack: Dear Friend — The communication in the Banner of Light...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, December 22, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Conn.,
                            Dec. 22d, 1879</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, D. L." TEIform="persName"/>D. L. Orcutt</byline><p TEIform="p"> W. L. Jack: Dear Friend — The communication in the Banner of Light, to which you called our
                            attention, purporting to come from Olive Stebbins, we believe to be correct. The Scripture
                            language of the communication is exactly like her style of speaking. She lived in this
                            Family, was a prominent member for more than fifty years. She deceased about two years
                            since. We are much pleased to hear from her, and thank you for calling our attention to the
                            communication. Yours truly, , For the Society.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I desire to find in books..." TEIform="index"/>I desire to find in books...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="von Leibnitz, Godfrey Wilhelm" TEIform="persName"/>Godfrey Wilhelm von Leibnitz</byline><p TEIform="p"> I desire to find in books, not what may be blamed, but what may be praised, and that from
                            which I may learn something. This course is not exactly in fashion; but it is the most
                            useful. Nevertheless, though there are few books or persons in whom I cannot find some thing
                            of use to me,I know how to make a difference in granting them my confidence.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our living redeemer" TEIform="index"/>OUR LIVING REDEEMER</head><p TEIform="p">The love which will pave us from sorrow and sin, The heart that will peace on true
                            righteousness win, And cause us our heaven and earth to begin, Is the Christ that is living
                            to-day. The hand which is ever creating anew, Uplifting our lives to be perfect and true,
                            And bringing fair Eden yet clearer to view, Is our Living- Redeemer to-day. That ever bright
                            star of affection and love, Which guideth us onward to glories above. O'er brooding, as with
                            the white wings of a dove, Is the Saviour now followed of choice— That Father and Mother and
                            beautiful friend, Who stoop now as ever ready aid to extend, And sympathies sweet in
                            adversities lend, Are the parents with whom we rejoice.</p><p TEIform="p">[Some Shaker sister has written and sent us the above pretty poem. We have departed from our
                            usual rule, of paying no attention to anonymous contributions, and for the purpose of asking
                            all our readers, if such a pretty poem should be at all ashamed of its author's name ?
                        Ed.]</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Debts" TEIform="index"/>DEBTS</head><p TEIform="p"> A debt is a load which you should be slow to take upon you. Debts bring trouble and sorrow.
                            Interest will gnaw at your earnings without ceasing. It will never rest at night. It will
                            not observe the Sabbath. It will not stop for sickness, nor for funerals. In rainy weather
                            or in dry, in summer and in winter, it will keep on noiselessly adding to the load under
                            which you groan. It is a sin to run in debt without a probability of paying. You should
                            never run in debt for any thing that will not stand good for the debt incurred, or will not
                            contribute toward its payment. You had better wear the poorest clothes and eat the plainest
                            food, than buy food or clothes with other people's money. It is always safe to wait for
                            these things until you have the money to pay for them. By so doing you will not only be
                            saved from trouble, but also from pride and extravagance. Give no occasion to any to
                            reproach the cause of Christ because of your dishonesty. Owe no man any thing but to love
                            one another. Sel.</p></div2><pb n="38" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New gospel of Christ: Shaker teachings" TEIform="index"/>THE NEW GOSPEL OF CHRIST:
                                SHAKER TEACHINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The faith and practices which Shakerism would present for the acceptance of all who feel
                                able to engage in them are mainly founded upon the life and teachings of Jesus, the
                                Christ of yore. Whatever additions Shakerism attaches to those taught and lived by the
                                good Jesus, we claim have been introduced by a second advent of the same Christ Spirit,
                                not through the man Jesus, but through the testimony and life of a woman — a simple,
                                good woman — Ann Lee. In all presentations of Shakerism for the acceptance or rejection
                                of those who read or hear, we want to be distinctly understood that there will be
                                nothing presented that does not find its justification and proof in the life of Jesus,
                                the Christ, and in His testimony to His disciples. Shakerism, in contradistinction to
                                the popular theologies of this age, teaches a new gospel of Cheist—one founded upon the
                                life of Christ Jesus, while discarding every semblance of the theory that there is any
                                virtue in the death or blood of Jesus, enacted or shed upon Calvary, and only joying in
                                His death, as He died unto a sinful or inferior life of the world. He died for us, in
                                that He died unto sjn and worldly good, to be our exampler by our following after. He
                                lived for us—and in this living Christ, living like Christ, living after Christ's life —
                                is the grand announcement of Shakerism to the world, and its testimony, that there is no
                                other effectual way of Christian salvation and redemption but by living as Christ lived.
                                As Jesus relied not upon mere articles of a dead faith, but upon works of daily
                                self-denial to all worldly indulgencies, good and bad alike, so does Shukerism warn
                                against a faith in any death excepting a death unto sin and the world, which means every
                                time a life like Christ's, as resurrected not only above sinfulness, but above the very
                                best estate of a worldly-good life. Perversion of the good is sin; excessive indulgence
                                in any lawful, worldly good is sin; the violation of any law of God, whether known or
                                unknown, is sin ; and all these perversions, excesses and violations will be avoided as
                                sins. But Shakerism, which is but another name for radical Christianity, would begin its
                                work of resurrection with those who have ceased to sin, who are living the best of
                                worldly lives; who, like the young Jew of old, have kept the laws of nature "from their
                                youth up," yet agonize for a perfection of Christ not found anywhere in the best good of
                                a worldly life. Shakerism would, of course, first save its adherents from sin by cutting
                                them off from both the good and the bad of a worldly life; then it would present the
                                superior claims of the actual Christ life, which the immediate disciples of Jesus
                                adopted in following their Master, and which life Paul " followed hard after," and
                                succeeded so well in living, while unwarrantably permitting those he taught to live in
                                the flesh, and as neither <pb n="39" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 39 Jesus'
                                disciples, nor himself did nor could live as Christians. Therefore, marriage may be
                                counted, properly lived, as a worldlygood life — a life for "the children of the world,"
                                —but Christ could not live it, did not live it, but lived far superior to it, and as His
                                followers Christians must discard it, however good, or they are so far from being
                                Christians. Private Property : Christianity nowhere recognizes the right to any private
                                property. To the upright Jew it taught a perfection superior to Judaism, by "go and sell
                                all that thou hast, then come and follow me! " There is only equality in the household
                                of Christ—all who are Christians will fare and share alike, which will dissipate the
                                terms my and mine, rich and poor. " Oh, that would be joyful! " Where can there be any
                                thing right in having rich members and poor members in any church or family of Christ?
                                Such are not Christians. Peace : As above illustrated, Christianity does not bring peace
                                to earthly practices, nor to those who indulge in them; but exterminating these as with
                                a sword, there follows a peace that passeth all worldly understanding of that term, and
                                " the love and life of Christ constraineth us " to live as brethren in harmony.
                                Separation" from the world — Separate from its lusts, unspotted by its loves, "freed
                                from the civil law," because living superior to it—"rendering unto Caesar the things
                                that belong to him," but having a citizenship and superior allegiance to a "kingdom not
                                of this world" — relinquishing the follies, fashions, policies and politics of a civil,
                                worldly life. Shakerism teaches of the new gospel of Christ—that Christ's life was not
                                of the worldly order, but heavenly, and as was the Master's, so must ours be if we are
                                His servants. "All cannot receive this saying " — all cannot be Christians — "but
                                whosoever can receive it, let him," for it is his or her bounden duty to do so. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Constitution of Zion" TEIform="index"/>THE CONSTITUTION OF ZION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> To our mind, the signification of Zion is paramount to Excelsior, while all Scripture
                                allusions to it fill the definition of its being highest, chief, superior over all,
                                best. As Mt. Zion of old overtopped all surrounding hills geographically, so were those
                                who should constitute the inhabitants of spiritual Mt. Zion to excel in the
                                righteousness of life those living upon lower and inferior hills or planes. The call of
                                Shakerism to all who would be constituents of it is to engage so deeply in the
                                renunciation of self and selfishness as to be superior in all that constitutes true,
                                radical Christianity. It is not simply a call upon individuals to put away fleshly
                                lusts, while permitting these same individuals to revel in other lusts, which, if not so
                                bad, are at least secondary, and just as unconstitutional for Zion's inhabitants to
                                engage in ; but rather, "sparing not one single idol," it includes in its peremptory
                                call, departures from all lusts—lower practices and loves—and to the engagements in
                                every most excellent, Christian practice, excelled by no inhabitant living upon a lower
                                plane than Mt. Zion. Thus, looking for the most excellent <pb n="40" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 40 THE
                                SHAKEK MANIFESTO. lives to form the constituency of the most spiritual Zion on earth, we
                                shall see the relinquishment of all lusts — lusts for the flesh, lusts for farms and
                                barns, lusts for pre-eminence in any thing over the brethren of Zion; lusts for power,
                                for earthly pleasures, whether wrought out by the palate, the eye, ear, nose or
                                feelings—discarding the lusts, share all blessings as a common brotherhood of Christ
                                should, to the highest advancements of every spiritual, Zion characteristic. And what
                                will be the result? " Look upon Zion, the city of our solemnities! Thine eyes shall see
                                Jerusalem a quiet habitation," etc. Arise, brethren, and would-be brethren. Let none
                                come to our Zion with a purer life testimony than we have and than we live. Let none
                                present a more abiding, peaceful joy. Let ours be an unexcelled, united inheritance,
                                where each rather seeks another's welfare than his or her own; and let "unspottedness
                                from the world" mean with us a resurrection above all envyings, jealousies, accusings,
                                strivings for personal prides and exaltations above our fellows ; then this will be
                                Zion, and Zion will be our home.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorial notes: queries and answers" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES: Queries and
                                Answers</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> G. W. T. — The story in the Christian Union- for Christmas we pronounced silly in our
                                January number because it was untrue, as well as misleading. We have grown up from early
                                childhood among the Shakers, and we know of none who keep Christmas more in keeping with
                                the honor of Him who was the first simple, pure-minded, celibate, illustrious Shaker
                                Jesus, born Christmas, beginning the so-called Christian era. Sometime we may give the
                                details of how rigidly we were called upon in our early days to make peace with our
                                brethren on that day, and the remembrance of the poor was just as rigidly and
                                practically set forth. We will write Editor McCormick, and as you are a reader of that
                                paper, we invite you and others to read that otherwise excellent Union, dropping the
                                "Christian." C. Lawrence. — You ask: " Do we separate husband and wife in our Shaker
                                families?" We answer emphatically that we never did such an act. Married people, before
                                uniting with our institution, settle that point between themselves — henceforth to
                                renounce the civil compact of husband and wife, and to accept as a superior substitute
                                the Christly relationship of brother and sister, after Christ-life pattern; our
                                interference in behalf of the desired spiritual progress of the parties does not begin
                                until that question is settled between them favorable to Shakerism. Jno. C. J.
                                —Certainly. Any one having property when joining the Society can retain the principal of
                                the same urftil they choose to consecrate the same " to charitable and religious
                                purposes," after Shaker signification of what these purposes are. It will pay to make
                                the trial—will you try it? "Mrs. S. C. Gatling."—Concerning literary opportunities among
                                the Shakers we cannot give you any extensive encouragements. We purpose a soul
                                preparation to meet Christ in His glory, and not for the mental illumination for any
                                official capacity or " kingdom of this world." We fear you are on the wrong track. We
                                are a Christian institution, and have no time nor opportunities for the superior
                                literary attainments. If you or friends unite with us we will not ask nor concern
                                ourselves of what denomination you have sailed under, but will simply ask you to "put
                                your hands to work," as we do, and "give your hearts to God " as we ought to. Mary
                                Evans. — Thanks for compliments upon Manifesto. Please consult pamphlet, "Plain Talks!'
                                for the balance of your <pb n="41" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 41 questions. As our
                                bishops have pronounced the little work " a valuable medium of our faith," we feel
                                partially paid for endeavor upon it, and would present it with our kindest hopes to many
                                who would know more of us.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice to everybody" TEIform="index"/>Notice to Everybody</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We have been kindly and handsomely paid with cost price of a copy of The Manifesto, to
                                be sent to every individual applying for it. We express kind thanks in behalf of all-
                                applying, and will send a copy to all who apply within thirty days of this notice.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Special notice" TEIform="index"/>Special Notice</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Parties who desire to introduce friends to the Society of Shakers, or to get personal
                                answers, at Watervliet, N. Y., at (P. O.) Shakers, N. Y., will be more kindly responded
                                to by addressing " Novitiate Elders of Shakers, Shakers, N. Y.," than by addressing the
                                editor of this paper. Having been transferred, we make this appeal as favorable both to
                                ourselves and correspondents. Do not address the editor of Shaker Manifesto upon the
                                introduction of friends or other personal matters.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder F. W. Evans: Dear Sir— As I had the pleasure of hearing you speak at Lake View on..." TEIform="index"/>Elder F. W. Evans: Dear Sir— As I had the pleasure of hearing you speak at Lake View on...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Pennsylvania, Greenville, December 25, 1879" TEIform="index"/>Greenville, Mercer
                                Co., Pa., Dec. 25, 1879&gt;</dateline><p TEIform="p">Elder F. W. Evans: Dear Sir— As I had the pleasure of hearing you speak at Lake View on
                                the Book of Revelations, I was pleased with the last part, it was so different from the
                                interpretation generally given. I would like to see it in print for future reference.
                                You say the Bible is nothing but history, and you believe only what agrees with your
                                theory. But, if it is not an inspired book, why do you take it to prove that your
                                opinion of Revelations is correct? And, if that book gives so much light on the future,
                                why is not Daniel, with the books of the Apostles, equal in importance as a guide for
                                the future ? As you seem to be well posted on the Scriptures, will you please give me
                                and many others, some new light from the Prophet Esdras, second Book in Apocrypha ? Why
                                is not this prophecy as important as that of Daniel ? It is later, and a continuance of
                                his prophecy. I will call your attention to some points, beginning at chapter 6 — 7 to
                                10 verses — also chapter 7 —41 to 45 — chapter 8 — 1 to 4 —chapter 12 — 11 to 15
                                —chapter 14—9 to 14 and 44 to end. These I think very important to all liv. ing at this
                                age. And also chapter 15 — 14 to 21. Is not this fulfilling at this time? And chapter 16
                                — 15 to 21------35 to 36 and 62 to end of chapter. Does not this take us down to the
                                Second Appearing of Christ in person, as given by Peter, Acts 1 — 10 to 14 ? Now, as the
                                Book of Esdras is not in the Bible, but set aside by man, it becomes to us only as
                                history to three hundred and fifty years before Christ; and gives us more light than any
                                other prophet from Daniel to the present time. Now, sir, will you please look over the
                                whole Book of Second Esdras, and give us more light to help the mass of Church members
                                into a higher life of truth and morality ? Will there be minutes printed of the meeting
                                at Lake Chautauqua ? and will the speeches be printed in them, or separate ? I want a
                                copy of all, when they can be had. I will now call your attention to a few verses in
                                Matthew, chapter 24 —15 to 21 to 26, 30,32. Is this in the past, or yet to come ? Also,
                                Mark, chapter 13 —14, 15, 19, 20, 26, 27 and 35 to end of chapter. I think this is all
                                in the future, and it will be well with all who have part in the first resurrection. But
                                I cannot see any life between death and the resurrection; but people are to wax worse
                                and worse, until He comes and sets up his Kingdom here on earth. Then there will be only
                                one faith, one Lord, one Baptism — and one people, of every nation, to worship the only
                                true God. Yours, in the Light of Truth, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Breed, S. R." TEIform="persName"/>S. R. Breed, M. D.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="S. R. Breed, M. D. : Dear Friend — Yours, of the 25th ult. at hand..." TEIform="index"/>S. R. Breed, M. D. : Dear Friend — Yours, of the 25th ult. at hand...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, January 21, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Jan. 2,1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">S. R. Breed, M. D. : Dear Friend — Yours, of the 25th ult. at hand. Perhaps you remember,
                                I separated the Book of Revelations from the rest of the Bible. God knoweth them that
                                are His. When we have <pb n="42" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. a revelation in our
                                own souls, we recognize revelation in other souls. Scriptures should be used to
                                illustrate and confirm revelation. To substitute authority for truth is the unmistakable
                                mark of the beast. Should the Almighty say to me, believe this, or that, with reverence
                                and humility, I would say, please show me the why and wherefore — give me evidence. If,
                                by investigation and research from below, and inspiration and revelation from above, I
                                form opinions and come to settled principles of belief and action, and then upon
                                referring to some book in the various collections called Bibles, Holy Bibles, etc.,
                                should find those opinions had been entertained by a writer hundreds or thousands of
                                years ago, and those principles clearly set forth and illustrated, might I not come to
                                the conclusion that such writer had been baptized with the same Christ Spirit that I
                                have been baptized with? Daniel was a Christ Prophet, and so was Esdras. We are not
                                entirely .unacquainted with them. I have looked over the Scriptures in Esdras you refer
                                to, and am much interested in your selections. It is almost precisely what we should
                                make of them. The New Testament selection and your interpretation thereof are of the
                                Orthodoi class. Of course, I differ from you. Your basic idea of God — the Hebrew God —
                                of Christ, Atonement, Resurrection, Kingdom of Heaven, etc. What I suppose you hold as
                                sacred, we would call the old Heavens that are even now passing away with a great noise.
                                See what Ingersoll and his fellows do with the Orthodox heavens, or theology ! A Shaker
                                hears him and indorses most that he has to say, knowing that neither hit God, Christ,
                                nor the Scriptures have suffered at his hands. Behold I create a New Earth and New
                                Heavens, for the former earth and heavens have passed away, and there shall be no more
                                sea nor world, because the city of Babylon and the sea, or world, out of which it arose,
                                is dissolved and resolved into three parts — First, a new Civil Government, purely
                                secular,with members representing both parts of the population — male and female
                                —holding land for all, both present and prospective population of the country, as
                                belonging to all. Poverty abolished. Disease and all sickness abolished, no one saying "
                                I am sick." Wars no more, as there would be nothing to fight about. This will be the New
                                Earth to generate human beings by strictly confining sexuality to propagation, as do the
                                brute beasts. Second, The Celibate order of intellectual men and women to fill Civil
                                Government offices, leaving the married to take care of their families at home. Under
                                such conditions, population would increase at a rapid rate, doubling each twenty-five
                                years, there being no Infant mortality before, nor after birth. In one century, what
                                would the country do with 1,000,000,000 of people to begin doubling with ? The situation
                                would be appalling. Here comes in part third, to regulate the whole — the Resurrection
                                Order — the Shaker Spiritual System, to check population and hold the balance of power.
                                It could be increased, or decreased, as occasion called for. Dear friend, I can only
                                hint; time would not suffice to speak of all the things pertaining to the New Earth and
                                New Heavens that are even now creating in the form of the United States Government and
                                the United Society of Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, this having already
                                commenced on this earth. I do not know what will be done about the speeches, but think
                                no report will be made. I was not correctly reported. I should suppose you would be
                                interested to visit our Society. You are not far from the Kingdom of Heaven. It exists
                                on the earth ; and a revelation is necessary to find it. " No man cometh to me, except
                                the Father draw him," said Jesus. Shall be pleased to hear from you again. Respectfully, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="John Whiteley, Dear Friend — I have read your advertisement in the 12 mo., Shaker                                     Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>John Whiteley, Dear Friend — I have read your advertisement in the 12 mo., Shaker Manifesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, New Bedford, January 8, 1880" TEIform="index"/>New Bedford, January
                                8, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">John Whiteley, Dear Friend — I have read your advertisement in the 12 mo., Shaker
                                Manifesto, and I will gladly accept your offer to send me the Divine Afflatus and The
                                Shaker Manifesto for the year 1880. I here inclose twenty-one three cent stamps to meet
                                the expense. I would 42 <pb n="43" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 43 say that I have
                                taken The Shaker Manifesto for three years and it has given me great pleasure. In 12 mo.
                                number of Shaker MANiFESTo,vpage 274, is "Shaker Theology," article No. 1. I should like
                                to see more clearly defined, through The Manifesto, as I hardly know what is meant by
                                soul death in the last line. The Orthodox idea is that death is eternal to a great part
                                of mankind. The Adventists say that death meafis that a large portion of our race will
                                be burnt up,.both soul and body. I cannot accept either of the above ideas, for I don't
                                for one moment believe in the possibility of a lost soul. But I do heartily believe in
                                the eternal progression of our race from lower to higher conditions of life, and that
                                All will be finally holy and happy with the ever loving Father of us all. Articles two,
                                three, four and five have my hearty assent, in which I have long believed. In conclusion
                                I would say that I wish it were in my power to help circulate The Shaker Manifesto among
                                the peoples, by subscribing for several copies. But I am a poor old man, and poor in
                                this world's possessions or I certainly would. But I do wish The Shaker Manifesto hearty
                                success in breaking down the walls of old theology, and building up the new. I remain
                                ever yours for the truth, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peckham, Caleb C." TEIform="persName"/>Caleb C. Peckham, 49 County St., New Bedford,
                                Mass.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Misleading" TEIform="index"/>Misleading</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor: In a commentary in the last Manifesto, upon one of my articles, some, if not
                                many, are being '" misled " as to the doctrines I teach. I do not hold Buddah,
                                Zoroaster, Confucius, Melchizedeck, nor John Baptist, " as mere Reformers " on the
                                generative plane, like Wesley, Geo. Fox, Graham, but as Avatars sent of God and inspired
                                from the same Christ, or resurrection heavens that Jesus was inspired and baptized from.
                                It was effected by intelligent missionary messengers, duly sent and commissioned. They
                                did not run as uncertain, nor fight as beating the air. Having in view a definite
                                object, they came in an influx of power sufficient to effect it. They established
                                organizations similar to the Primitive Church, and raised up, in the East, thousands
                                and. tens of thousands of people to the Christ life of Celibacy, Peace, Vegetarianism
                                and Community of Goods. What more did Jesus do ? What more do we attain unto? Those
                                messengers came from the sphere that Jesus ascended into when He went up " far above all
                                heavens " on the plane of reproduction. He went to a heaven even David had not ascended
                                unto — that Swedenborg had not visited. The Spiritualists know not of it, for it is a
                                path that the vulture's eye of greed and lust hath not seen, neither hath the fierce
                                Lion of War ever trodden it. That heaven is, to the whole Spirit World, what the Holy of
                                Holies was to the Temple. God be praised for the Resurrection Heaven and Order. It is
                                the great mediator between God and all souls in all worlds. He speaks peace to every
                                sentient, intelligent being. God is in this Holy Temple. Let the whole earth and all
                                earths keep silence before Him and her. Fleshly-minded earthly men and women understand
                                not its language, neither can they tread the measure of its holy dance. If it be
                                objected that although other Avatars than Jesus did live and work, in their day and
                                among their people, yet retrogression invariably followed — I ask, if a falling away has
                                not also followed in the wake of the day and work of Jesus 1 The Primitive Church has
                                existed in the Spirit World only, for nearly two thousand years. The Celibate Monastic
                                Institutions of the East compare favorably with those of the West, either past or
                                present. Whence the Christian wars and fightings of the worshipers of Jesus, but from
                                their unchristian lusts of generation? Is there any vital characteristic difference
                                between Trinitarians and the Skeptical classes ? Is not our last forlorn Hope in Mother
                                Ann Lee, and "the followers to be wondered at" who are with her? Each one received a
                                revelatioii from the Christ Heavens, constituting them God's witnesses for a New <pb n="44" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 44 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Dispensation, in which there is neither
                                male nor female, rich, nor poor, bond nor free — all being one, in all things pertaining
                                to the world that was, is, and is to come. Reformers are witnesses on the reproductive
                                plane. They contend for its truths. Avatars are Saviors, to resurrect souls from the
                                work of propagation. Please let us understand each other aright, before we assume a
                                disagreement, having no existence, except in the minds of misleading spirits. I am
                                yours, brotherly, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY LOSSES</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hill, Dorcas" TEIform="index"/>Dorcas Hill</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> 1880, At Shaker Village, N. EL, Jan. 2 , aged 86 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kincaid, Lucinda" TEIform="index"/>Lucinda Kincaid</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> At Enfield, N. H., Dec. 30, 1879, , aged 72.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parker, Electa" TEIform="index"/>Electa Parker</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> At Shaker Station, Conn., Dec. 13, , aged 78.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Standish, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Standish</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., , aged 77.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Since last issue" TEIform="index"/>SINCE LAST ISSUE</head><p TEIform="p"> Received of S. W. Ball, $20.00. R. M. Wagan, $15.00. C. Dibble, $5,60. F. W. Evans,
                                $58.00. " Rebecca Jackson, $3.25. J. B. Vance, $30.00. Jno. Whitely, $25.15. N. A.
                                Briggs, $60.90. H. S. Kellogg, $30.00. A. Perkins, $25.00. H. L. Eads, $100.00. C.
                                Clapp, $39.00. H. B. Bear, $36.00. Isaac Beals, $13.20. D. C. Brainard, $20.50. Amos
                                Babbitt, $17.40. Henry Cumings, $20.00. " Simon Atherton, $20.00. Catharine Walker,
                                $9.00. Sophia S. Niles, $2.00. E. Myrick, $17.60, " Roll on, thou mighty power."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editor — We have read in our Manifesto that it would please you to hear from the children..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Editor — We have read in our Manifesto that it would please you to hear from the children...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Shaker Station, January 10, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station,
                                Conn, Jan. 10,1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor — We have read in our Manifesto that it would please you to hear from the
                                children. We want to tell you we are trying to be good, obedient girls, for we know that
                                is the way to make good Christians. We often read of our dear Mother Ann and her
                                sufferings, and wonder if we would be as patient and forbearing with the wicked people
                                who so cruelly persecuted her as she was ! or whether, if the mobs were to come now,
                                would we or not leave our home, friends, and the life we live should they persecute us
                                ever so much! We think too of the many poor children roaming through the streets without
                                shelter or friends, and we cannot express our love and thankfulness to our good brethren
                                and sisters for their kindness toward us ; and we know we can repay them in no better
                                way than obeying the kindly advice they so often give us. We would like our love, and
                                pledge to be faithful, given to all the little girls you see and know through the
                                Manifesto who are trying with us to grow up in the way God would have us. With much love
                                for yourself and The Shaker Manifesto, we remain your affectionate children, Maria
                                Lafayette, aged 12. Cora Pranklyn, aged 11. Hattie Terryson, aged 10.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lafayette, Maria and Pranklyn, Cora, and Terryson, Hattie" TEIform="persName"/>Maria
                                Lafayette, Cora Pranklyn, Hattie Terryson</byline></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little girl in Ithaca described an elephant as..." TEIform="index"/>A little girl in Ithaca described an elephant as...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little girl in Ithaca described an elephant as "the thing that kicks up with its
                            nose."</p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pay day will come" TEIform="index"/>Pay Day will Come</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">He did not think, when sowing those wild oats in his youth, how uncomfortable
                                        the gritty oat-meal would prove for his aged teeth.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Congregationalist" TEIform="index"/>Congregationalist</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A little girl passing the Washington statue lately..." TEIform="index"/>A little girl passing the Washington statue lately...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A little girl passing the Washington statue lately, asked a lady with her, if Washington
                                was buried there, " No," said the lady. " Where is he buried?" said the little girl. " I
                                don't know," said the lady. " Then 1 guess you don't read your Bible much," said little
                                innocence.</p></div3></div2><pb n="45" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home of liberty" TEIform="index"/>Home of Liberty</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell&gt;</byline><p TEIform="p"> 1. Zion, thy founda tion No earthly power can shake, 2. May thy glorious banner, Now waving
                            in the air, 8. May the cross of Jesus, Which he so meekly bore, 4. May a crown of glory,
                            Each ransomed victor wear, Glorious hab Shouts of glad Blessed cross that Spotless raiment
                            tation, The Christian's home to make ; hosanna Within thy courts so fair, frees us,
                            Salvation's open door, holy, Divinely bright and fair; Virgin Every Prove Thus souls in
                            glory, tongue and nation, a boon of gladness, thy habitation, Standing pure and free, Reach
                            and bring to view; To each sin-sick soul,Zion, yet shall be, Chant sweet praises holy Blest
                            and full salvation, Banish fear and sadness Sought by every nation, Of life and liberty.
                            Eternal life anew. And rays of joy unfold. The Home of Liheety. Enfield, N., H.</p></div2><pb n="46" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to learn shorthand" TEIform="index"/>How to Learn Shorthand</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baker, Arthur M." TEIform="persName"/>Arthur M. Baker</byline><p TEIform="p"> ; the Stenographic Instructor. An Improved System of Shorthand Writing.—Arranged
                                specially for the use of those desirous of acquiring the art without the aid of a
                                teacher; being the simplest, most practical, and the best adapted for reporting. By .
                                12mo., paper, 25 cents. S. R. Wells &amp; Co., Publishers, 737 Broad, way, New
                            York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Modern bethesda" TEIform="index"/>The Modern Bethesda</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, J. R." TEIform="persName"/>J. R. Newton</byline><p TEIform="p"> .—By the Newton Publishing Co., New York. This is purported to be an account of the life
                                labors of Dr. . It protests that it is an advertising scheme, but we fail to see it so.
                                After acquiring a competence, the Doctor will still heal — for money.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vick's Floral Guide" TEIform="index"/> Vick's Floral Guide</head><p TEIform="p"> — Is a super-excel, lent work of one hundred pages. It contains for frontispiece an
                                elegant colored plate, which of itself is worth more, we would judge, than the entire
                                book costs, which can be obtained by sending five cents to James Vick, Rochester, N. Y.
                                This is the most instructive work of the kind published in the United States that we
                                know of. Its illustrations are very numerous and beautiful, while the finest, choicest
                                paper is used in the construction of the invaluable guide. We recommand those desirous
                                of obtaining a choice variety of seeds or plants, either flower or vegetable, to address
                                James Vick, Rochester, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="By far the most beautiful color printing that it has been our good fortune to witness..." TEIform="index"/>By far the most beautiful color printing that it has been our good fortune to witness...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> By far the most beautiful color printing that it has been our good fortune to witness,
                                is done by the firm of Russell, Morgan &amp; Co., Cincinnati, 0. Every possible
                                conception of beauty in the arrangements and blending of colors for the printing of
                                labels, calendars, etc., is accomplished by this enterprising firm. If something
                                unusually nice is wanted, seek them out.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The path of the gods is a path of thorns" TEIform="index"/>The path of the gods is a path of thorns
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"The path of the gods is a path of thorns."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some one has judiciously pointed out that..." TEIform="index"/>Some one has judiciously pointed out that...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Some one has judiciously pointed out that a large quantity of the acid which exists in
                                rhubarb, gooseberries, currants, and other fruits, may be judiciously corrected by use
                                of a small quantity of carbonate of soda, without affecting their flavor. To an ordinary
                                sized pie or pudding as much soda may be added as, piled up, will cover a shilling, or
                                even twice such a quantity, if the fruit is very sour. If this little hint is attended
                                to, many a stomach ache will be prevented and a vast quantity of sugar saved, because
                                when the acid is neutralized by the soda it will not require so much sugar to render the
                                tart sweet.</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to detect poison ivy" TEIform="index"/>How TO detect Poison Ivy</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The annoying casualty, which confined Judge Noah Davis to a sick-room the
                                        other day, might have been avoided if the eminent jurist had paid as much
                                        attention to the small as to the large things of life. The poison ivy and the
                                        innocuous kind differ in one particular which is too easy of remembrance to be
                                        overlooked by any one who is interested in thebrilliant-hued leaves of autumn to
                                        care for gathering them : the leaves of the former grow in clusters of three and
                                        those of the latter in fives. As somebody has suggested in a juvenile
                                        story-book, every child should be taught to associate the five leaves in a
                                        cluster with the fingers on the human hand, and given to understand that when
                                        these numbers agree they can be brought into contact with perfect safety. It may
                                        spare our readers no little suffering to bear this point in mind during their
                                        October rambles in the fields.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Syracuse herald" TEIform="index"/>Syracuse Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cutting glass with scissors" TEIform="index"/>Cutting Glass with Scissors</head><p TEIform="p"> .—Many persons may not be aware that glass can be cut under water, with great ease, to
                                almost any shape, by simply using a pair of shears or strong scissors. In order to
                                insure success two points must be attended to — first and most important, the glass must
                                be kept quite level in the water while the scissors are applied, and, secondly, to avoid
                                risk, it is better to begin the cutting by taking off small pieces at the corners <pb n="47" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. and along the edges, and so reduce the shape
                                gradually to that required, as if any attempt is made to cut the glass all at once to
                                the shape as we would cut a piece of cardboard, it will most likely break just where it
                                is not wanted. Some kinds of glass cut much better than others, the softer glasses being
                                the best for this purpose. The scissors need not be at all sharp, as their action does
                                not appear to depend on the state of the edge presented to the glass. When the operation
                                goes on well, the glass breaks away from the scissors in small pieces in a straight line
                                with the blades. This method of cutting glass has often been of service when a diamond
                                has not been at hand, for cutting ovals and segments, and though the edges are not so
                                smooth as might be desired for some purposes, yet it will answer in a great many cases.
                                The two hints given above, if strictly followed, will always insure success.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paint for farm buildings" TEIform="index"/>Paint for farm buildings</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">An old subscriber, Wardville P. O., sends for the benefit of our other
                                        subscribers the following recipe for paint for farm buildings : The following is
                                        a very cheap and excellent paint for farm buildings, forming a hard surface, and
                                        as its hardness increases by time, it is far more durable than paint. Take
                                        freshly burned unslacked lime and reduce it to powder. To one peck or one bushel
                                        of this add the same quantity of fine white sand, or fine coal ashes, and twice
                                        as much fresh wood ashes, all this being sifted through a fine sieve. They
                                        should then be thoroughly mixed together while dry. Afterward mix them with as
                                        much common linseed oil as will make the whole thin enough to work freely with a
                                        painter's brush. This will make the paint of light gray stone color, nearly
                                        white. To make it fawn or drab, add yellow ochre and Indian red ; if drab is
                                        desired add burnt umber, Indian red and a little black ; if dark stone color,
                                        add lampblack ; or if brown stone then add Spanish brown. All these colors
                                        should of course be first mixed in oil and then added. This paint is very much
                                        cheaper than common oil paint. It is equally well suited to wood, brick or
                                        stone. It is better to apply it in two coats, the first thin, and the second
                                        thick.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Farmer's advocate" TEIform="index"/>Farmer's Advocate.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Emersonian" TEIform="index"/> EMERSONIAN</head><p TEIform="p"> Hands to work, and hearts to God. Sincerity is the property of the universe. To make our
                            word or act sublime, we must make it keal. Skepticism is unbelief in cause and effect. The
                            true meaning of " spiritual" is eal. All revelations, whether of mechanical or of moral
                            science, come first to single persons. The attraction of the happy conditions of life is the
                            pledge that they are within reach. Our prayers are prophets; but there must be consistency
                            and constancy in the' petitioners. Beautiful manners spring from self-control and a kind
                            heart. There is no beautifier of complexion, of form, or behavior, like the wish to scatter
                            blessings. It is our system that counts, not the single word nor unsupported action. We only
                            believe as deep as we live. That only which we have within us can we see without. All things
                            go by number, rule and weight, llelation and connection are not somewhere and sometimes, but
                            everywhere and always. As we are, so we do; and as we do, so is done unto us. Vigor is
                            contagious; and whatever makes us think or feel strongly, adds to our power and enlarges our
                            sphere of action. Nothing is impossible to him who can will. Is that necessary? That shall
                            be — is the law of success. Against all appearances, the nature of things works for truth
                            and right forever. Primordial atoms are prefigured and predetermined to moral issues, are in
                            search of justice, so that ever the right comes uppermost, and justice is done at last.
                            Self-poise belongs to every particle, and rectitude to every mind. Every one's task is that
                            one's lti?e-preserver. A just employment is the best insurance. The conviction that our work
                            is dear to God, and cannot be spared, defends and sustains -us. A high aim is curative, and
                            reacts on the organs and resources of the body. Who would be great and good in the future,
                            must be great and good noio. Immortality will come to such as are fit for it.</p></div2><pb n="48" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bad ambition" TEIform="index"/>BAD AMBITION</head><p TEIform="p"> Bismarck is often discontented, and in a period of despondency he is said to have exclaimed
                            -. " In satisfying my ambition 1 have made nobody happy." The company at his Varzin
                            residence protested " No." He continued : " And what a number of people I have cast into
                            misery. Without me three great wars would have been avoided ; 80,000 men—nay, much
                            more—would not have been killed, and such a number of families, of fathers, mothers,
                            brothers, sisters, aud wives would not have been plung ed into mourning. However, that
                            account is to be settled between God and myself so far as the hereafter goes. What happiness
                            have I derived from all my success ? Little or none ; and I have reaped endless worry,
                            vexation, hatred, pain, grief, overwork and care."-—Cm. Gazette.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion in the life" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION IN THE LIFE</head><p TEIform="p"> How few people think of religion as a principle of right living. They look into the Gospel
                            of Christ as though it contained minute directions for daily action, and thus they come to
                            regard religion as a set of rules, a whip to duty, something which is all the time saying to
                            them, "you shall" and "you shan't," — something that has manacles, fetters, chains for the
                            hands, the feet, the eyes, ears, head and heart — when it is liberty to do right,
                            helpfulness in rightdoing, and restraint to wrong-doing, disapproval of all that is evil.
                            Christ's teaching was the outlining of great truths, the statement of living principles.
                            When he said, "Blessed are the poor in spirit," he referred to the condition of mind
                            necessary to be a Christian. When he drew that vivid picture of a selfish, godless man in
                            torment, and a sweet-tempered, pure soul in glory, he gave declaration to the inevitable
                            result of every life. Every man makes the moral condition of his life here, by the
                            acceptance or rejection of the gospel principles, and the fruitage borne by the practice of
                            them. Every man in the beyond will find his own place — a place which he prepared for
                            himself by the manner of his earthly life. Some people have an idea that good people must
                            die to go to heaven, and that bad people must die to go to perdition. But to live the
                            principles of the Gospel is to live heavenly ; to neglect those principles is to live
                            miserably. If you are an upright citizen, you have no fear of the law. The principles of
                            your life enforce in you all good laws. So it is that right principles are the correctives
                            of life and plain guides to duty, and there are no such principles apart from the Gospel of
                            Christ. Men have only to apply his teachings, not in the letter alone, but in the spirit, to
                            their circumstances and relations, to live his life. And his life, embodying the principles
                            which he taught, is the Christian religion. "Follow me." — Golden Rule.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seven bibles of the world" TEIform="index"/>Seven Bibles of the World</head><p TEIform="p"> The are the Koran of the Mohammedans, the Eddas of the Scandinavians, the Try Pitikes of the
                            Buddhists, the five Kings of the Chinese, the three Vedas of the Hindoos, the Zendavesta,
                            and the Scriptures of the Christians. The Koran is the most recent of these seven Bibles,
                            and not older than the seventh century of our era. It is a compound of quotations from the
                            Old and New Testaments, the Talmud and the Gospel of St. Barnabas The Eddas of the
                            Scandinavians were first published in the fourteenth century. The Pitikes of the Buddhists
                            contain sublime morals and pure aspirations, but their author lived and died in the sixth
                            century before Christ. The sacred writings of the Chinese are called the five Kings, king
                            meaning web of cloth, or the warp that keeps the threads in their place. They contain the
                            best sayings of the best sages on the ethico-political duties of life. These sayings cannot
                            be traced to a period higher than the eleventh century B. C. The three Vedas are the most
                            ancient books of the Hindoos, and it is the opinion of Max Muller, Wilson, Johnson, and our
                            own Whitney, that they are not older than eleven centuries B. C. The Zendavesta of the
                            Persians is the grandest of all the sacred books next to our Bible. Zoroaster, whose sayings
                            it contains, was born in Bactria in the twelfth century B. C. Moses lived and wrote his
                            Pentateuch, fifteen centuries B. C., and therefore has a clear margin of three hundred years
                            older than the most ancient of the other sacred writings.—Age to Gome.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>