<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1401" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">28</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">14</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18840101" TEIform="date">January 1884</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="14" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
                    JANUARY. THE MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies, CANTERBURY, N. H. " Blessed are those that hear the word of
                        God and keep it." Shaker Village, N. H. 1884
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    [Advertisements deleted.]
                    --><pb n="1" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><!--
                        CONTENTS. Marriage, PURITY, Selfishness, Impetus, Treasure in Heaven, Education, No 3, Signs, Nothing to do,
                            David Parker, The Shakers, Growth, God's School, Give and Receive, E. Bahb. 1 Thomas, Union, 15 4 The Reward, 5
                            Letter Box, n Children and Conversation, " The Manifesto, IS 9 Sanitary, 19 ** The Influencf, of Cheerfulness,
                            20 " Eulogy, 21 10 In Memory of R. II. Wagan, 22 11 Music—Trust in God, 23 12 Books & Papers, 24 Deaths,
                            24 Vol. XIV. JANUARY, 1884,. No. 1.
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Marriage" TEIform="index"/>MARRIAGE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRAZER</byline><p TEIform="p">Marriage is not a Christian Institution. Why? Those who marry, fulfill the desires of the
                            flesh and of the mind. " Any man who will be my disciple., let him take up his cross daily.
                            " Against what? Against the lusts of the flesh and of the mind. " The flesh lusteth against
                            the spirit, and the spirit against the flesh ; these are contrary the one to the other. " "
                            Ye cannot serve two masters. " Marriage is not a Christian Institution. Why? Because
                            Community of goods cannot be maintained therein. Marriage is cot a Christian Institution. It
                            is an animal one. All animals marry. It is of the world. The children of this world marry,
                            etc. But those who are resurrected into newness of life, do not marry. "I am the
                            resurrection and the life ; " all who come unto me in that life, I will in no wise cast off.
                            Those who for Christ's sake—for the higher life's sake, forsake the marriage order, with its
                            private relationships and property, shall have in my kingdom of communal life an hundred
                            fold. Marriage is not a Christian Institution ; the Law of the marriage order is " Me and
                            Mine." Touch me and mine and I will light. The Law of Communal life is, "Each shall care for
                            others: And each to each shall bend; And all shall fare alike, Hence wars shall have an end.
                            " Marriage is not a Christian Institution. It is an Adamic one. Its function is to multiply
                            and replenish the earth. The order of Christ's kingdom is to harvest the earth. " An angel
                            came out of the temple crying with a <pb n="2" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. great voice to him
                            who sat on the white cloud. Send forth thy sickle and reap, for the harvest of the earth is
                            over ripe. And he who sat on the cloud cast his sickle upon the earth, and the earth was
                            reaped. From the foregoing', we find, that virgin purity is the order of Christ's kingdom.
                            The order of marriage is not purity, therefore, it is not a Christian Institution. Even
                            should that older become perfected, it would still be of the earth, earthy. It will ever
                            remain under the Law of carnal or animal commandment. " Multiply and replenish etc." Should
                            the perfected man and woman come up to the standard of puri-ity manifested by the animal
                            creation, they will do well; but let them not presume to enter the Holy of Holies. Animal
                            life—emotions, have no place therein. Angelic purity, communal life, and divine emotions,
                            can alone enter and abide in the Holy of Holies. The law of the order of Christ's kingdom
                            is'' The love of others, at the expense of self;" and its temporal procedure corresponds
                            thereto. " Unto this last, ¦even as unto thee, will I give a penny." All shall fare alike,
                            as in the virgin order of the Shaker church. The Law of the marriage order, as generally
                            manifested, is, " The love of self, at the ex- pense of the neighbor. " Therefore it is not
                            a Christian Institution. Its temporal procedure, is to monopolize the productive forces of
                            creation for selfish end?. And thus prevents the possibility vof all, to fare alike. Turn
                            the marriage order round and round; and gather up all the facts; and they are found to point
                            but in one direction. That Marriage is not a Christian Institution. Private property is
                            inseparably connected with the marriage order. Monopoly, Wages, Slavery, and War ; is the
                            trinity of that order. The Gentile, or Pagan Christian Church (so called) married, and held
                            slaves. It was not a branch, was not an integral part of the Pentecostal Church. They were
                            distinct bodies ; the latter merely allowed and tolerated the former, as an outer court. The
                            Pagan Church was composed of foolish Galatians, carnal Corinthians, of heterogeneous
                            materialists. The Greek, the Roman, and Protestant churches of today, are made up of just
                            such materials. They are the lineal descendants of said Pagan Church, and within the folds
                            of their drapery is found "The sum of all villainies,"— monopoly of the elements of human
                            subsistence. War, Usury, Wages, Slavery and Sexual Abominations. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity" TEIform="index"/>PURITY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Purity is the divinest thought that can enter the finite mind concerning the Infinite. It is
                            the fountain head of life's immortal stream, the source of every attribute and spring of
                            every blessing. In purity are love and goodness perfect. It is the very essence of Divinity
                            that permeates and infuses the highest spheres ; the unclouded light of eternity's perpetual
                            day. " God is light, in Him is no darkness at all." The purer we become, the nearer we
                            approach Deity ; for, " Blessed are the pure in heart, they shall see God. " This is the
                            greatest and most precious of the promises given by the Christ-inspired Jesus, whose life
                            exam2 <pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. pie—as well as precept—was virgin pu- rity.
                            Impurity broodeth in secret places, under the shadow of darkness ; God is not there ; and
                            the mind that harbors unchaste thoughts, or the heart that cherishes unhallowed desires,
                            shrinks from the light with a just sense of shame and disgrace. "Know ye not that ye are the
                            temple of God? If auy man defile this temple him will God destroy," by a withdrawal of His
                            pure spirit. It is a law inevitable, " The soul that sinneth it shall die." The written and
                            unwritten revelation of God's eternal truth declares the certainty of this. What is it that
                            stultifies the sensibilities, beclouds the intellect, drains the vital forces, sears the
                            conscience, turns love to hatred and disgust, and creates on earth a hell? The carnal mind,
                            unreached by moral law. Lasciviousness is the cancer that is eating out the very heart of
                            Society ; its dens of infamy are the plague spots of every civilized com- munity, the
                            bottomless pit, where virtue is swallowed up, and demons of vice are generated. The slimy
                            serpent crawls over every threshold, victimizing the young, the beautiful, and would be
                            lovely, by the secret charms of its magnetic power. It stealthily holds its sway, in our
                            schools, colleges and halls of science, robbing our youth of the potency and vitality of
                            noble manhood. What hearth-stone boasts of purity's unsullied altar? Whoso still worships
                            there, may " sing of Love, of Home, and Heaven, " three words holy and sacred in their
                            significance, and all the outcome of a truly virtuous life. What means the cry we hear all
                            over the land, the " social evil, " domestic unhappiness, ungoverned households, family
                            brawls, infanticide, foeticide, matrimonial dissolution, and an army of neglected vagrant
                            children? God, and his divine laws in nature, are both ignorantly and willfully disobeyed.
                            The earth reels drunk with crime of every name and nature ; all springing from the
                            hydra-headed monster Lust! It is the ghoul that is gnawing out the vitals of humanity !
                            "Whence come wars and fightings among you? come they not hence even of your lusts that war
                            in your members?" "A man is tempted when he is drawn away or enticed by his own lusts. " The
                            evil lies within each human heart; and there must the battle begiu, for the subjugation and
                            crucifixion ot the carnal, generative life, which has brought sorrow and woe to mankind. The
                            greatest of all wrongs is the sin of transmission, through which, depraved influences are
                            stamped upou the embryotic brain ; the consequence is, thou- sands walk the earth and mingle
                            in society, in whom the inclination and impulse, is stronger to do evil than good. True love
                            is the offspring of purity ; and only under its benign control, can properly developed
                            beings be generated. The praises of virtue were sung by the bards of olden time. Seers
                            declared the glory of the ransomed ! Prophets, sages and philosophers, inspired by the
                            Christ-spirit, conquered the impulses ot passion, and took upon themselves a perpetual vow
                            of celibacy. In ancient temples, vestal virgins were sheltered and secluded far from the
                            eyes of a carnal world ; kept for holy purposes, they were vessels of honor, through which
                            the word of God could flow to man. The baptized Jesus inculcated purity 3 <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. foremost in his system of ethics. The teachings of the apostles, whether
                            to Jew or Gentile, held up this heavenly principle, or attribute, as the highest point of
                            human attainment; recognizing the fact, that because of low conditions, few would be able in
                            this life, to bear the cross and practice the self-denial necessary to reach the perfect
                            state of angelic purity. In every heart—no matter what the education or the ignorance, there
                            lingers a hope of probation ; and though long and dark be the night of error and sin ; there
                            will sometime be kindled a desire for something superior and more soul satisfying, than the
                            fruits of a sensual life. Then will come an awakening. God's pure spirit, brooding over the
                            chaotic elements of the soul, shall find access to its most secret chambers ; in its deepest
                            recesses. His searching light will shine ; the dawning of a new day will break upon the
                            vision ; the first thought that shall fill the mind will be purity ! The first step of
                            spiritual progress will be to " cleanse the heart from all filthiness of flesh and spirit; "
                            then will the ascent upward be comparatively easy. Purity' is light, it gilds the mountain
                            tops of God's everlasting goodness, and in its fullness alone, will the soul ever find peace
                            and rest, or realize the blessing—that is vouch-safed to every human soul,—immortality and
                            eternal progression Mt. Lebanon N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is not the changes of stature, or position, or circumstances..." TEIform="index"/>
                            It is not the changes of stature, or position, or circumstances...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is not the changes of stature, or position, or circumstances, or anything else that can be
                            seen outwardly that makes or unmakes character, hut it is the changes that are made silent
                            and unnoticed in the hidden chambers of mind, where formless and vague lies the material out
                            of which motives are shaped and character is builded.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. S.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Selfishness" TEIform="index"/>SELFISHNESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">What keenness of the vision e'er can spy, Or what expanse of imagery descry The myriad
                            varying forms "of selfishness, Its giant growth, or pigmy littleness ! In one sense,
                            selfishness is ogle eyed, but, its fondness is with the hope of bringing all the treasures
                            home to self. Its side glances are to lure for personal, not social enjoyment; for the sake
                            of personal gratification and advantage, selfishness disregards all the rights and feelings
                            of other persons ; and the character of selfishness assumes as many forms, and different
                            hues, as there are different dispositions in men. So each selfish person has a shrine of his
                            own, at which he worships in greed !—A selfsanctum, within which no other being may intrude.
                            The existence of the monster is only possible, in the immediate neighborhood of other beings
                            ; it could not exist in a person liviagalone, on a desolate island ! Thus its pigmy
                            littleness and meanness is manifest in an habitual longing for, and reaching after, that
                            which justly belongs to, or should be shared by another. Selfishness aspires to make the
                            Universe its tributary, for it the ocean should disgorge its pearls; the mines their
                            glittering gold; the fields their gorgeous flowers and sumptuous gustatory fruits ; the air
                            its feathered songsters ; and the earth its teeming millions of servile life to man. To
                            selfish greed and ambition unnumbered millions of the human family have sorely worn harsh
                            slavery's galling chain ; for sordid self's lust of power unnumbered millions have been
                            shorn of life, and made to bite the dust in pangs of sorrow too deep for human tongue to
                            utter. i <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. But, whoso lives alone for self, dwells in a
                            narrow prison cell, bereft of all the blissful benedictions and grateful oblations of hearts
                            gladdened and blessed by liberal, generous souls! Those sweet sympathies of loving spirits
                            that steal softly into the memories and beguile the otherwise lonely hours of the
                            benevolent, like doves bearing in their beaks an olive branch of peace, or like the flitting
                            humming bird that has sipped from flower to flower of their generous grace returns with
                            sweet mellifluous contribution to give gustation pure and heavenly to every thoughtful
                            moment, all these blessings which make for liberal souls consecrating life, time, treasure
                            to the greatest good of humanity a heaven, these, the pigmy selfish soul has barred from his
                            home, his closeted mind and imprisoned spirit and interest! To him no voice they speak, no
                            soothing tune they sing, no taste to sweets is made a guest! The honest agriculturist, or
                            orchardist, who plants the noble tree for fruit in a rich and mellow soil with wide expanse
                            for nourishment, in quick returning years finds ample growth of trunk and limb, profuse of
                            bloom, and, following bounteous stores of golden fruits to feed, not only himself, but the
                            hungering multitude, and, in its harvest home his heart is glad. This is the characteristic
                            of the kt liberal soul that shall live by liberal things, "—the character of those who are
                            truly consecrated to toil in the vineyard of the Lord. But, the character of the selfish
                            soul Is like an orchardist who should set an infant apple tree in a quart bowl, hewn out of
                            a solid rock, and filled with sand, no expanse of earth, rock-bound on every hand ; no
                            richness of soil; of nourishment bereft; no room for expansion of root', no growth of trunk,
                            nor expanse of limb ; no fragrant foliage or flower, no recompensing fruit!—The baby plant
                            shrinks in its tiny field, and, withering, dies ! And, now, in vision thus we behold the
                            final goal of utter selfishness, Enthron'd upon a pillar, pois'd in ambient air, Its narrow
                            walls hide all its treasure rare! Beneath, above, around no int'rests meet nor blend, No
                            love flows to it, nor affections trend! And, though from hoarded wealth, like Andes high,
                            And though its art with Phidias may vie, Its monumental bulk, like Babel's tower, Reached
                            upward to the skies, and dazed with power, 1Tis art without a patron to commend, A tower,
                            without a chieftain to defend'. 'Tis prowess, ne'er a patron to its throne, A Shrine! No
                            worshipper, but self alone' And, though a hoard of all that earth may boast, Exiled from
                            time, 'tis emptiness, at most! The Selfish Captain, anchor'dat his goal, Of sailors 'reft,
                            anchor'd in waters shoal, No more his merchandise can bring him gain, No more his fragile
                            bark a freight sustain! The Selfish mariner, on time's wide sea. Is lost to all the world,
                            but selfish Me I Mt. Lebanon,N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Impetus" TEIform="index"/>IMPETUS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">My impetus is love to God, And love to all his creatures; Eor Him I walk the narrow road, For
                            him, extend my labors. The flowery mead affords a joy, The song of birds a pleasure; But
                            without heart to do for man I've no abiding treasure. The eye and ear ne'er satisfied, The
                            selfish heart still craving, Must for a goodness be denied, Which is, the world-wide saving.
                            To follow Christ in very deed, We're broad in our endeavor. And feel our own, another's
                            need, As felt the lowly Savior. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our thoughts are character moulds, they shape our language and actions" TEIform="index"/>
                            Our thoughts are character moulds, they shape our language and actions
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Our thoughts are character moulds, they shape our language and actions.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. S.</byline></div2><pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treasure in heaven" TEIform="index"/>TREASURE IN HEAVEN
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Saxe, John G." TEIform="persName"/>BY JOHN G. SAXE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[What I spent I had; what I Left I lost;
                                    what I f/ave I ham.—Old Epitaph-} Every coin of earthly treasure We have lavished
                                    upon earth, For our simple worldly pleasure May be reckoned something worth ; For
                                    the spending was not losing, Though the purchase were but small, It has perished
                                    with the using, We have had it—that is all. All the gold we leave behind us, When we
                                    turn to dust again Though our avarice may blind us, We have gathered quite in vain :
                                    Since we neither can direct it, By the winds of fortune tossed, Nor in other worlds
                                    expect it, What we hoarded we have lost. But each merciful oblation (Seed of pity
                                    wisely sown,) What we give in self negation, We may safely call our own ; For the
                                    treasure freely given Is the treasure that we hoard, Since the angels keep in Heaven
                                    What is lent unto the Lord!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education, no. 3: the folly of ignorance" TEIform="index"/>EDUCATION No. 3 The Folly of
                            Ignorance</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Calvin G." TEIform="persName"/>CALVIN G. REED</byline><p TEIform="p">" The truest characters of ignorance Are vanity, pride, and arrogance ; As blind men use to
                            bear their noses higher, Than those who have their eyes and sight entire. " " By ignorance
                            is pride increased; They most assume who know the least; Their own self balance gives them
                            weight, But every other finds them light. " "Ignorance is the parent of many injuries." "The
                            hopes of a man void of understanding are vain and false. " "Wisdom is very uupleasant to the
                            unlearned: he that is without understanding will not remain with her. " " He that wanteth
                            understanding, will think upon vain things : and the foolish man erring, imagineth follies.
                            " " Go not to him that hath no understanding ; beware of him, lest you have trouble." "Sand,
                            and salt, and a mass ol iron, are easier to bear than a mail without understanding. " •'
                            Sloth is the mother of poverty. Idleness is the root of all evil." " The way of the
                            slothful, is a hedge of thorns. Idleness is the sepulchre of a living man." " The sluggard
                            is wiser in his own conceit than seven men that can render a reason." " Idleness is the
                            pareut of want and shame." "I went by the field of the slothful, and by the vineyard of the
                            man void of understanding ; and lo it was all grown over with thorns, and nettles had
                            covered the face thereof, and the stone-wall thereof was broken down. " " An idle brain is
                            the devil's workshop. " " The devil tempts others, but an idle soul tempts the devil." "
                            Though thou shouldst bray a fool in a mortar, among wheat with a pestle, yet will not his
                            foolishness depart from him." This is the experience and testimony of Solomon, and of the
                            wise and the intelligently good of all times and of all nations. The entire catalogue of
                            wise maxims, like the ones quoted, characterize sloth and idleness as the morphia of
                            ignorance ; and ignorance as the vacuity of indolence; and the united obnoxious trinity, the
                            incubators of all vice and of all crime, as the demon offspring of Folly, clothed with the
                            tawdry garments of shame, dishonor, pride, vanity, arrogance, insipidity, servility, and
                            superstition ; the true insignia of the slaves of temptation and of sin. 6 <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. When the avenues of knowledge are free to all, as water, air, and
                            sunshine, it will be a positive sin of omission to remain ignorant. It is not only a great
                            wrong to one's-self, but to society. No one has a just excuse for being ignorant, when he
                            might and ought to be intelligent and wise. The secular law does not exculpate the
                            transgressor from the penalty of his crime, on the plea of ignorance ; for it claims, that
                            no one has fulfilled his obligations if he does not understand his legal responsibilities.
                            This is true of every system of laws, be it physical, intellectual, ethical, or psychical.
                            Time was, when ignorance, was counted bliss; blind faith, wisdom; mystery and superstition,
                            religion ; and physical tortures, the portals to the mansions of the blest. But these dark
                            clouds of irrational belief, are fast being dissipated from the atmosphere of the educated,
                            who intelligently trace consequence to sequence, effect to cause. One of the marked
                            characteristics of ignorance is, a servile acceptance of the teachings of the past,
                            especially where they assume a religious aspect; as though infinite wisdom and understand-
                            ing centered there, and it was only left for the present and future generations, to gather
                            virtue from the overflowings of their superior wisdom and knowledge, or imputed plenary
                            inspirations. Hence arise the divine right of kings and potentates, and the more divine
                            right of priests, to rule the common people writh despotic sway. So long as tradition formed
                            the chief source of transmitting information from generation to generation, this assumed and
                            accepted divine right was easily exercised over the ignorant multitude. whose superstitious
                            fears urged them to the commission of almost any and every inconsistency, and the acceptance
                            of the most revolting rites and ceremonies. Hence the past is only beneficial to us for the
                            truths it contains, and the ability it confers upon us to eliminate truth from error. But
                            when we trace the historic page, whether sacred or profane, we find : " More proselytes and
                            converts t' accrue To false persuasions than the right and trne, For error and mistake? are
                            infinite, While truth has but one way to be i' the right. " A prime cause for the perpetuity
                            of error, lies in the morbid inclination of the masses to leave investigation to the few,
                            and to accept deductions without apparently questioning the truth or falsity of
                            propositions. Finding it easier to follow than to lead ; to imitate thai: to originate ; to
                            accept than to reason ; to be dependent than self-reliant; to be ignorant than to toil for
                            knoAvledge, understanding, wisdom, truth; mankind, in general, have groped their way through
                            the mazes of error, blindly following blind guides. History, and the literature of the
                            nations, present more of human weakness T error, and degradation, than of wisdom, virtue,
                            and strength. Ante-deluvian traditions characterize the race as monsters of folly and
                            wickedness: wrlvose hearts were only evil and that continually. Post-deluvian records
                            exhibit the blind folly of the people in fulsome measure, instanced in the building of the
                            tower of Babel; the forty yea: s wandering of the Israelites in the Wil- derness ; the
                            superstitious creation of myriads of tutelar deities and demigods with idols to represent
                            them ; and the demoralizing rites and ceremonies practiced by them in their sacrifices and1
                            offerings at their sacred altars and festiv7 <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. ities, by
                            all nations down to the Druids of the British Isles. Added to these are the irrational
                            beliefs iu metempsychosis, incarnations, atonements, and their mythical marvelous legends,
                            rendered hoary by age, and sanctified by the imposition of bloody priests, gladiatorial
                            shows, inquisitorial tribunals, and cruel deaths. Down to the invention of movable types,
                            and the blessing of the enlightening and redeeming printing press, rendering the
                            dissemination of knowledge «asy, it was an age of inconsistent and impractical marvels.
                            Immoralities, rapine and turmoil and terrorism prevailed, that never would have had an
                            existence, had it not been for the stupid ignorance of the people. But the end is not yet.
                            The millennial day of triumph lies still in the future. Vast areas of mental, fallow ground
                            and wilderness land remain to be brought under cultivation and fruition. Dense clouds of
                            mental, ethical, and psychical darkness are to be dissipated from the etherean sky, before
                            the Sun of Righteousness shall arise with healing and refulgent glory, and humanity shall be
                            eliminated from the thraldom of ignorance and error, by the knowledge of the Lord that shall
                            cover the earth as the waters cover the sea. It. is written: God winked at these times of
                            man's ignorance, but now he calls upon all to repent, and be wise, and to know the Lord from
                            the least, even unto the greatest of them; to arise and shake themselves from the slavish
                            bands and chains of ignorance, and to shine with the glory and splendor of intelligence,
                            understanding and wisdom. The divine Teacher of Nazareth, often hurled his incisive
                            philippics of condemnation at the ignorance of his hearers, and by the wise demonstration
                            and application of a grand proposition, taught them an important truth. What could have been
                            more apropos, or what could have more strongly condemned the religious intolerance and
                            ignorance that prevailed among his disciples, than the utterance of the humiliating truth:
                            "The children of this world are, in their generation, wiser than the children of light! " A
                            statement paramount to saying : "This is to you a dishonor! It ought not so to be !" In the
                            memorable sermon on the Mount, in which Jesus propounded some very important principles of
                            Christian ethics ; when about to close, he enjoined it upon his disciples, to seek first the
                            kingdom of heaven and its righteous- ness,—light, wisdom, intelligence, truth ; and not
                            follow the example of the foolish gentiles, who sought earthly treasure in eating, drinking,
                            and clothing. Seek the greater which includes the lesser, and you will ensure both. This was
                            counseling to observe Heaven's Order ; things of first importance first, leaving the broad
                            uncertain road of ignorance which leads to destruction, and take the straight and direct
                            highway which leads to perpetual life and bliss. The very commencement of the mission of
                            Jesus Christ, was to a people who sat in darkness, and the region df the shadow of death
                            :—Gross darkness. The lightening which rifted the clouds of this intense Plutonian darkness:
                            " Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand, " is still lighting the dark recesses of
                            ignorance, revealing the truth that God is not only love, but that in his eternal archives,
                            are stored all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge. Mount Lebanon, N. Y. (TO BE
                            CONTINUED.)</p></div2><pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs" TEIform="index"/>SIGNS</head><p TEIform="p">Wheke spades grow bright, And idle swords grow dull; Where jails are empty, And where barns
                            are full; Where field-paths are With frequent feet out-worn, Law court-yards weedy. Silent
                            and forlorn; Where doctors foot it, And where farmers ride ; Where age abounds, And youth is
                            multiplied; Where poisonous drinks Are chased from every place ; Where opium's curse No
                            longer leaves a trace— Where these signs are They clearly indicate A happy people And a
                            well-ruled State. —From the Chinese.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nothing to do?" TEIform="index"/>NOTHING TO DO?
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "Nothing to do! " in this world of ours, Where weeds grow up with
                                    the fairest flowers, Where smiles have only a fitful play, Where hearts are breaking
                                    every day. " Nothing to dol " thou Christian soul, Wrapping thee round in thy
                                    selfish stole? Off with the garments of sloth and sin, Christ, thy Lord, hath a
                                    kingdom to win. " Nothing to do ! " There are prayers to lay On the altar of
                                    incense, day by day; There are foes to meet, within and without: There is error to
                                    conquer, strong and stout. " Nothing to do! " There are lambs to feed, The precious
                                    hope of the church's need : " Strength to be borne to the weak and faint, Vigils to
                                    keep with the doubting saint." " Nothing to do! " and thy Savior said, " Follow thou
                                    me in the path I tread. " Lord, lend thy help, the journey through Lest faint, we
                                    cry, " So much to do!"</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Baptist weekly" TEIform="index"/>Baptist Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If you wish to appear agreeable in society..." TEIform="index"/>
                            If you wish to appear agreeable in society...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If you wish to appear agreeable in society, you must consent to be taught many things which
                            you know already. A man should never blush in confessing errors, for he proves by his avowal
                            that he is wiser to-day than yesterday.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="David Parker" TEIform="index"/>DAVID PARKER</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">" Mv weary feet have found a resting place, No longer need I roam ; For in the blessedness of
                            perfect love, I've a home sweet home. I've a place to lay my heavy burdens down, A refuge
                            from the storms that come, 0 blessed tho't! the hope of life fulfilled, I've a home sweet
                            home. " David Parker was born in Boston, Mass., May 12, 1807 and Avas admitted to the
                            Society in Canterbury in the year 1817. Entering the religious order at so early an age he
                            grew gradually and substantially into every interest that made it his home as well as the
                            home of his many gospel fathers and mothers. At this date the Society was able to afford
                            their children a good and thorough education, sufficient for all practical purposes. This
                            privilege was so well improved in connection with a religious discipline that at the age of
                            nineteen years David was appointed assistant Trustee. From that time till the date of his
                            death Jan'y 20th, 1867 he was known as one of the most active, as well as honorable busi-
                            ness men of the State. He was genial and in conversation very interesting. A characteristic
                            notice was published in the Boston. Journal in 1862 which may be said to quite fairly
                            represent the man. " Everybody knows David Parker, one of the chief managers at Shaker
                            Village, N. H. I have known him ever since he was a boy. Brought up under the direction of
                            the honored founders of the Society, Francis Winkley, Israel Sanborn and others, he com-
                            bines their industry, thrift and shrewd,) <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE MANIFESTO. ness, with
                            a remarkable development of the New Hampshire yaukee, which has enabled him to keep up with
                            the progress of the age in transacting the extensive business of the Society. Mr. Parker is
                            an upright man. Nobody except some poor specimen of humanity, who may, perchance, have
                            undertaken the difficult task of outwitting him in a bargain, ever pretended anything to the
                            contrary. In the matter of attending to the peculiar rites and spiritual welfare of the
                            Shakers, his people know how to appreciate him better than many others. Pie is a man of
                            business,--Now I see him at half past eight o'clock in the evening, after the arrival of the
                            last I train from Boston, ready for a hasty j supper at the Eagle Hotel, and then a | drive
                            of twelve miles to Canterbury to j sleep. Now you will find him looking j over Shaker wood
                            lots in the wilds of New York. Again you will meet him in Washington, Buffalo, Philadelphia
                            or New York, always with an eye to business, whether he happens to make a call on the
                            President or the proprietor of a wholesale drug store. " In May 1837, David Parker was
                            appointed to the order of Ministers. While officiating in this capacity he made his home,
                            about one half of the time, in the Society at Enfield, N. H. In October 1846, he was again
                            called to take charge of the financial interests of the Community. During the inquisitorial
                            arraignment of the Shakers before tlie Legislature of New Hampshire in 1848, he acquitted
                            himself as an able advocate in defense of his home and friends, against the vilest
                            insinuations as well as the direct defamatory charges of a class of men and women, who had
                            at a former date been members of the Shaker Societies. Assailed, as he was personally, by a
                            modern Jeffrey, with the most vituperative appellations, he withstood the charges with all
                            the calmness of a Baxter. The poisoned arrows fell short of their mark. Enjoying as lie did
                            a remarkably strong constitution, with an active elastic mind, he was enabled to project and
                            execute a very large amount of business till within a few weeks of his death. Surrounded by
                            a large circle of friends, and in the glory of his usefulness, he passed from this life in
                            the 60th year of his age. Canterbury,N. H/.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers" TEIform="index"/>THE SHAKERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/>AGNES E. NEWTON</byline><p TEIform="p">Wk occasionally find, in the periodicals of the day, candid descriptions of this people and
                            their religious belief, by those who have, or are, honestly investigating the same. We also
                            find the most absurd articles written by those who have made, as they state, a visit of two
                            hours or more to some Shaker Settlement ; and from this brief acquaintance attempt to
                            describe a people, of whom they know so little. Whether the Shakers are at fault for the
                            wide spread ignorance concerning themselves, or whether as Paul declared to the Corinthians
                            : The natural man discerneth not the things of the Spirit of God, we will not attempt to
                            decide ; but will make reference to the question so often asked. " Do the Shakers consider
                            themselves the only true Christians?" The word Christian, clearly defined, signifies, one
                            whose life inwardly and outwardly comports with the doctrines of <pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. Christ. Wherever individuals of this class are found, whether within, or without
                            the pale of the Church, we must acknowledge them to be the followers of Christ. He declared,
                            My kingdom is not of this world, My disciples will not engage in the pratice of war. We
                            infer from this, that he intended his followers to be advocates of the principle of
                            practical peace. How different from the testimony of ( hrist, was the course pursued by
                            Constantiue, who through scenes of blood and carnage, established himself at the head of the
                            so called Christian Church. How unlike the cross of the meek and lowly Jesus, was the
                            interpretation which he rendered concerning the one that appeared to him in a dream. The
                            forsaking of all the selfish relations ; which constitute the generative earthly life, was
                            clearly enjoined by Christ upon those who would be his followers. "He that forsaketh not all
                            that he hath cannot be my disciple. " Observe the comforting promise made, by him, to those
                            who had made this sacrifice for the Kingdom of God's sake. Luke, xviii., 21), 30. Again,
                            "Anew commandment I give unto you, that ye love one another as I have loved you. " John,
                            xiii., 34. The words of the poet in the "Vision of Echard" harmonize with this beautiful
                            text. " Who counts his brother's welfare As sacred as his own; And loves, forgives and
                            pities He serveth me alone. " This is a faithful criterion, by which churches and
                            individuals may be judged. Where this evidence of discipleship is wanting, has the testimony
                            and life of Christ been fully recognized? The Shakers have accepted the Christ life while
                            upon earth, as did Jesus, who himself declared, "Strait is the a;ate, and narrow is the way
                            that leadeth uutr&gt; life, and few there be that find it." Matt, vii., 14. Canterbury,
                            N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Growth" TEIform="index"/>GROWTH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>ANDREW BARRETT</byline><p TEIform="p">The soul which cannot die, merits all the moral, intellectual and spiritual improvement we
                            can possibly give it. A spirit form to live forever, should be making continual advances in
                            virtue and wisdom. A avcII cultivated mind regards the body, merely, as a temporary prison,
                            holding it until the long looked for hour comes when it can break the prison doors and soar
                            to the heights of heavenly felicity ; become the associate of advanced minds who have gone
                            before, to that blissful Eden where their longing spirits are to be satisfied by the
                            realization in full of those joys for which they have so earnestly prayed. Are we not living
                            for Eternity, and our life record, will it not condemn or approve in the ultimate? Our
                            heaven is to be formed of our life, thoughts andactions. Like the Mason who places one block
                            upon another in the rearing of the earthly mansion, so do our thoughts and actions stand
                            upon one another in reariug our heavenly mansion, that is to be our Eternal Home. Jesus
                            said, "The kingdom of heaven is within you, " meaning that all the faculties for enjoying
                            heaven is given to every understanding soul, and to insure a certain passport and safe
                            anchoring in that beautiful haven, we must grow and develop those faculties at every
                            opportunity. 11 <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. Growth consists in action. Where
                            there is no action, there is no growth. Action invigorates and warms up soul and body. It
                            puts fire into the individual, that keeps the blood (which is the life) in circulation. On
                            one of the Huguenot churches, stands the emblem of a flaming cross, with these
                            words,—"Burning but not consumed," emblematical of the true Christian character. The Cross
                            is every where a sign of both Svar and peace. War against sin until the banishment brings
                            perfect rest and peace. The Prince of Peace brought the sword and the sword shall finally
                            bring peace. A Romish conception of the sacred heart, is a heart of flame. Why should not
                            the new heart be the same? The work of God always wss and always will be, forever onward and
                            upward, from the earthly to the spiritual; from the terrestrial into the angelic. The Church
                            of Christ should be the lamp, giving forth light to the nations around ; a city on the hill,
                            all aglow as it catches the first rays of the rising " Sun of Righteousness. " Should not
                            the church be also a living body, a center of attraction to draw souls into its embraces for
                            life and salvation ? Let its members be alive with the spirit of God, and let their singing
                            ring out like peans of victory, and prayers throb with faith and desire, and testimonies
                            come warm from experience ; then will be the evidence of the presence of that life giving
                            Spirit, and souls are born anew into the resurrection order. Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The proper way to check slander is to despise it; attempt to overtake and refute it and it will outrun you" TEIform="index"/>
                            The proper way to check slander is to despise it; attempt to overtake and refute it and it will outrun you
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The proper way to check slander is to despise it; attempt to overtake and refute it and it
                            will outrun you.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eliot, George" TEIform="persName"/>George Eliot</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's school: recitation for advanced scholars" TEIform="index"/>GOD'S SCHOOL: RECITATION FOR ADVANCED SCHOLARS
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">One by one, as the days go by, To
                                    learn our lesson we bravely try: For every hour some task is set-— Difficult, easy,
                                    short or long; Whether we come to it weak or strong— Somehow or other it must be
                                    met. Graded well is this school of ours ; Each one's duties within his powers. His
                                    task the thing that he needs to know ; Many a time does the page grow dim— Before
                                    tired eyes the hard words swim, And the hours go by so slow—so slow ! Various ages
                                    the class room shareFlaxen ringlets, and thin, gray hair Both fall over the lesson
                                    books. Often the little ones laugh in glee As beautiful words their bright eyes see,
                                    Wliile the aged sigh with thoughtful looks. Skillful teachers assembled here Toil
                                    unceasingly year by year; Never mistake in their work was known. Only the scholars,
                                    weary and vexed— Idle, impatient, tired, perplexed— Suffer from errors all their
                                    own. The Spirit teaches the highest class ; Time takes all as they onward pass; Joy
                                    is claimed by the happy few, While Experience, Care and Pain Treasures of knowledge
                                    help us gain, And Memory hears the grand review. But patiently learning, day by day,
                                    We are waiting to hear the Master say That our school day's work on earth is done
                                    And after this last, long term shall pass To be transferred to this upper class,
                                    Where advanced work is begun.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New England journal of education" TEIform="index"/>New Enq. Journal of
                                Education.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is far more blessed to give than to receive" TEIform="index"/>"It is far more blessed to
                            give than to receive."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>ASENATH C. STICKNEY</byline><p TEIform="p">As I peruse the neatly printed pages of our " Manifesto," and take special cognizance of the
                            names of its liberal contributors, I am forcibly impressed <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 13 that in this regard, as in alms-giving, "It is far more blessed to give than
                            to receive. " My thoughts linger more especially upon the names and characters of our
                            honored veteran writers who in our view justly belong to the class of the "more blessed," in
                            every sense of the expression. Therefore, we the army of happy recipients feeling ourselves
                            under great obligations to you as public teachers ask you to accept this day a tribute of
                            gratitude for your constancy in advocating the principles of a religious truth which has
                            sanctified and blessed your individual efforts, for so many long years. "Venerable worthy
                            friends ! ye come down to us from a former generation, as it were," bringing your
                            well-earned treasures, greeting us with your practical testimonies, and laying your precious
                            pearls of thought, at the very feet of inexperience ; thus guiding and blessing those who
                            should be your successors in the life and ministry of a pure, an ex- alted Christianity. Is
                            it possible? we ask ourselves, for us to forget to love, appreciate and honor the names and
                            characters of such representative writers. We trust not, and hereby we pledge ourselves anew
                            to live by the precepts which you have so wisely «;iven. For we are witnesses that a
                            life-time of personal practical goodness enables you to present us a genuine religion a
                            proof of self-denial. Yea, Self-denial the only key yet fashioned to unlock to souls the
                            mystic realm of spiritual peace wherein you dwell. May God continue to bless you as " givers
                            " in His cause is our prayer. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do to-day the nearest duty" TEIform="index"/>Do to-day the nearest duty
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Do to-day the nearest duty.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thomas" TEIform="index"/>THOMAS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Field, Floyd C." TEIform="persName"/>FLOYD C. FIELD</byline><p TEIform="p">Thomas was a faithful follower of Jesus, although by some he is called the doubting disciple,
                            yet among all of the disciples of Jesus there was not one who obeyed his mandates more
                            willingly than Thomas. His doubts were the results that would naturally follow, a man of
                            deep thought and careful investigation. Comparatively speaking we know but little of his
                            life, but wherever he is spoken of we can not help but admire his spiritual heroism, and all
                            Believers can undoubtedly see that his obedience to Jesus is worthy of emulation. The first
                            notice we have of Thomas was the speech he made when Jesus had concluded to face the dangers
                            which awaited him, in Judea, on his journey to Bethany. Previous to this the Jews in Judea
                            were about to stone him but he escaped the danger by going beyond Jordan. While teaching in
                            that region the sisters of Lazarus sent word to Jesus that their brother was sick. After
                            remaining two days he said to his disciples "Let us go into Judea again." But his disciples
                            began to oppose him; they said "Master, the Jews of late sought to stone thee and goest thou
                            thither again?" Yea, here were chosen disciples of Jesus coming up in opposition against him
                            seemingly forgetting that he was the lead that should be obeyed. Thomas joined them not in
                            their opposition. He had too much faith in Jesus as his spiritual guide to oppose him in any
                            particular. "Let us also go that we may die with him, " were the heroic words expressed by
                            Thomas. What faith he must have had in the Bridegroom of the regeneration, willing even to
                            sacrifice his own life if by so doing he was acting in obedience to the wishes of his Master
                            and leader. If all Avho dwell within Zion's walls were obedient to the will of God, and had
                            faith in the Bridegroom and Bride as the foundation pillars on which rests the new heavens
                            and the new earth, and possessed the courage and heroism of Thomas, Zion's walls would again
                            shake with the power of God and we could <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO. feel the
                            presence of the beloved Father and Mother of the new dispensation in our midst, and realize
                            the shower of divine love which would be wafted to us from the throne of the Infinite. Yea,
                            Thomas' own brethren opposed him but he could say as did Paul, " None of these things move
                            me neither count I my life dear unto myself, so that I might finish my course with joy and
                            the ministry which I have received of the Lord Jesus to testify the gospel of the grace of
                            God." The next notice we have of Thomas was during the last supper, Jesus was endeavoring to
                            comfort his disciples for he knew that he would soon be crucified. Therefore he said to his
                            disciples, "Whither I go ye inow and the way ye know." Thomas immediately spoke and said,
                            "Lord we know not whither thou goest and how can we know the way?" Look at the cautiousness
                            of this disciple. He was afraid that he might make a misstep or go contrary to the will of
                            God, therefore, he wanted Jesus to make known to him what he should do and how he should
                            walk. What wisdom and childlike simplicity is liere shown in Thomas. He knew who to ask for
                            light. If he had doubts he made them known at the proper place. He did not open Ms mind to
                            his brethren in the gospel and ask them what he should do or burden them with his troubles,
                            but they were all carried to the first anointed in God's order. The last, important notice
                            we have of Thomas transpired a few days after the crusifixion of Jesus. His ten brethren
                            were try- ing to convince him that they had seen their Master and conversed with him since
                            his ex- ecution. Thomas was astounded, he doubted, he thought they might be mistaken; he
                            thought strange that this occurrence should happen while he was absent from them. He mo
                            doubt listened to them attentively, but it gave him no comfort. Ho remembered the language
                            of Jesus, viz. "I will not leave you comfortless I will come to you. " Thomas realized that
                            he had been a faithful disciple, therefore, he was entitled to the same privilege that the
                            other disciples had enjoyed. Jesus had promised to comfort him as well as his brother
                            disciples. Therefore he would aot be satisfied until he could see the same truth
                            demonstrated, He wanted to know for himself. Hence, he said, "except I shall see in his
                            hands the print of the nails and put my finger into the print of the nails and thrust my
                            hand into his side I will not believe. " God will manifest his power to any people who will
                            show by their life that they have faith and implicit confidence in his promises" Heaven and
                            earth shall pass away, but my words shall not pass away." "I will come to you. " These words
                            Jesus spoke and Thomas realized that they were spoken to him, therefore, he relied upon them
                            and expected their fulfillment. God wants all of his people to realize for themselves the
                            truth of the gospel. The testimony of others will not suffice but he wants us to feel the
                            presence of his Holy spirit within our own heart. That only will bring comfort and
                            consolation to a true child of the kingdom. The next time the disciples assembled Thomas was
                            with them. After the doors were shut, Jesus came and stood in their midst and said, " Peace
                            be unto you. " Then saith he to Thomas reach hither thy finger and behold my hands ; and
                            reach hither thy hand and thrust it into my side and be not faithless but believing." "And
                            Thomas answered and said, My Lord and my God. " Jesus saith to him, " because thou hast seen
                            thou hast believed,' blessed are they that have not seen and yet have believed. What
                            satisfaction Thomas must have derived from this demonstration, so ardently longed for. Yea,
                            this disciple was not easily deluded. If he saw Jesus he wanted to recognize him. He knew he
                            was going to preach to a world of unbelievers ; those who would assert that he was laboring
                            under a delusion, therefore he wanted positive evidence concerning the presence of Jesus,
                            then he would be better prepared to battle the world and meet the arguments which would
                            emanate from Satan and his emissaries. ¦ The print of the nails, the pierced side he clearly
                            recognized, not in the midnight darkness but on a bright spring morning. This was a
                            spiritual demonstration under test conditions therefore Thomas was thoroughly satisfied. <pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 God is willing to satisfy the longings of all honest
                            seekers after truth. Wherever there is a fundamental want inherent in man there must be a
                            corresponding provision. " My Lord and my God." How much is there involved in these words.
                            It clearly demonstrates that Thomas was a "Believer" for he recognizes God through him who
                            began the blessed work of "regeneration" which finally culminated in the second appearing of
                            Christ being manifested through the female by which a spiritual relation was formed between
                            the two Anointed Ones. Thereby they have become the foundation pillars on which rests the
                            new heavens and the new earth. Thomas saw andjjeheved but " blessed are they that have not
                            seen and yet have believed. "' God saw that Thomas required a powerful demonstration to
                            prepare him for the work which was set before him. God deals with men according to their
                            needs but the same manifestations have neA'er been repeated in the world's history,
                            therefore ail cannot be eye-witnesses to the demonstrations of God. It Avas so in the days
                            of the disciples, and it is none the less now. Many believed the gospel that were not
                            present at the Pentecostal Baptism. Many to-day believe in the Second Appearing of Christ
                            who beheld not the glory of his coming ; many are to-day believers in the Christ life that
                            never were eye-witnesses to powerful manifestations of God. "Blessed are they that have not
                            seen and yet have believed. " May we all have faith in the Gospel of Christ and stand firm
                            on the principles which were manifested in the days of Mother Ann and we will be endowed
                            with heavenly wisdom which will free us from all the errors of the world and place our feet
                            upon the solid foundation of truth which will stand forever. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Do not be troubled because you have no great virtues..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Do not be troubled because you have no great virtues...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Do not be troubled because you have no great virtues. God made a million spires of grass,
                            where he made one tree. The earth is fringed and carpeted, not with forests, but grass. Only
                            have enough of little virtues and common fidelities, and you need not mourn because you are
                            neither a saint nor a hero.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union" TEIform="index"/>UNION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Flora" TEIform="persName"/>FLORA WILLIAMS</byline><p TEIform="p">" So we being many are one body in Christ, and every one members one or another. Rom. xii.,
                            5. All mankind are bound together by a certain bond of fellowship. The remoteness of the
                            situation in which we are placed does not affect this connection, but rather tends to
                            strengthen it, as we see in the commerce of different nations and in mutual exchange of
                            commodities. The inhabitants of one country cultivate fruits for the consumption of those of
                            another ; and the inhabitants of other countries in return produce articles ot manufacture
                            for their use, thus one gives that which the other needs, and both are provided. There are
                            various distinctions or grades in life ; the lowest are useful as well as the highest; the
                            rich benefit the poor, and the poor labor for the rich. Governors protect their subjects and
                            every loyal subject contributes to the support of its Governor j in this way the interests
                            of leaders and people become one. There is no such thing as independ- ence, and were it not
                            for ignorance and pride, we should never think of it. The laboring class are the basis of
                            society, and why not? The foundation of the wall sustains the superstructure. A larger
                            building requires more support than a smaller. The higher we rise, the more we possess, the
                            less claim we have to independence ; now if this be true in the natural order of things, it
                            is pre-eminently so in the Christian life. And it is in this light that Paul so frequently
                            speaks of it. "I say through the grace given unto me to every man TXNTON. <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 16 THE MANIFESTO. that is among you, not to think of himself more highly than
                            he ought to think ; but to think soberly, according as God has dealt to every man a measure
                            of faith. " To show how important it is to manifest a mutual dependence he remarks, "The eye
                            cannot say unto the hand, I have no need of thee ; nor again the head to the feet, I have no
                            need of thee. Nay much more those members of the body which seem to be more feeble, are
                            necessary. " They all have their respective places and uses. Each is necessary ; essential
                            to the beauty, strength, happiness, and the perfection of the whole. Why then should we set
                            at naught a brother ? The Christian church would never have been reduced to its present
                            disjointed state if the members had not been beguiled from the simplicity found in the
                            religion of the meek and lowly Savior ; and instead of the peace and harmony that should
                            pervade the Christian world we have strife and discord. Indeed how can we call ourselves the
                            disciples of the Prince of Peace if we do not abide by the principles so clearly wrought in
                            the life of our pattern? He said, "Then are ye my disciples if ye love one another. "
                            According to this we must not live for ourselves. Each is to live for the good of each and
                            for all. "AVith brotherly love ; in honor preferring one another. " Even an indulgence
                            harmless in itself, is to be avoided if the peace of a weak conscience will thereby be
                            destroyed. Such was the example of Jesus Christ and such is the duty of those professing to
                            be his followers. ; Canterbury N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Idleness is inconsistent with a Christian life" TEIform="index"/>
                            Idleness is inconsistent with a Christian life
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Idleness is inconsistent with a Christian life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F." TEIform="persName"/>—F</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reward" TEIform="index"/>THE REWARD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danforth, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>nancy G. danforth</byline><p TEIform="p">When Jesus was asked by the rich man what he must do to inherit eternal life, his reply was,
                            The lirst thing to be done, is to sell and to give to the needy, all your selfish, private
                            property. You cannot receive the blessing you seek, or live the life of self-denial which I
                            live, while you are encumbered with earthly cares and anxieties. When you have parted with
                            every thing, that claims your attention alone and beyond the work which I am called to
                            perform, then follow me, live as I live, daily denying yourself for the good of others,
                            being willing to lay down your natural life, if need be, rather than deny the anointing
                            power, which rests upon me for the salvation of humanity. It is by following this advice
                            that eternal life is obtained. What is eternal life? Does it consist in standing around a
                            great white throne bowing and singing psalms through all eternity? Is there nothing more ?
                            The throne of God in every man is his conscience, and when strictly obedient to its dictates
                            according to light and truth, he is worshiping at the throne of God, no matter what honest
                            labor employs his hands. Peter speaks of having left all to follow Christ, then asks what
                            shall be the reward? Jesus says : To these who have followed me in the regeneration (not
                            generation) shall be granted to sit on thrones judging others and again, they are to be "
                            kings and priests," still farther in the parable, to those who had wisely improved the
                            Teacher's gift, after being commended, were gLven more duties, as the care of five or ten
                            cities. These things are verj signifi<pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 17 cant, first,
                            showing that we shall not be idle after our earthly labors have closed; secondly, that
                            probation does not cease with our mortal existence. The very titles, King, Priest, or Judge
                            implies onerous duties, as the welfare of a kingdom ministering at the altar, to discern
                            between right and wrong ; so to decide wisely in all cases of equity. These duties bring
                            care and burden, not a condition of ease. Those servants were examined and having been found
                            faithful in their stewardship they were rewarded accordingly. Thus it seems to be self
                            evident that we are to work for souls after entering spirit life ; for were there no
                            sacrifice of what use is the office of Priest? 80 also of the offices of King and Judge.
                            Should any say these promises are fulfilled in this life, we would ask where the twelve
                            Apostles sat on "twelve thrones judging the twelve tribes of Israel? " This is what Christ
                            declared they should do. They suffered cruel persecution until they yielded their lives in
                            the hands )f their enemies. They had no throne but the throne of martyrdom. Still we believe
                            the promises will be verified, not only to the Apostles, but to every faithful soul. God
                            grant we may merit the reward. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>[Juvenile]</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, 1883" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., 1883</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children ;—It is time to turn over a new leaf in the volume of your lives. Let
                                    the page be free from blots. You cannot recall your past mistakes, but they may
                                    serve as warnings for the future. Profit by dear bought experience. Form good vows
                                    and keep them. You must deny self, to gain immortal riches. Selfishness should be
                                    despised, fought and conquered. Perform the duty of the moment, whatever it may be ;
                                    prepare for the future, by improving the present; prepare for death, by living
                                    aright now. Truth and purity are sure to win. Strive for a life that shall realize
                                    these virtues. No good effort is lost; what you desire, you endeavor to obtain. By
                                    desiring what is virtuous, you may become a power against evil. Abound in goodness,
                                    grow in holiness. Let the daily service of your lives be an offering of "a sweet
                                    savor unto the Lord." Let each moment tell for good. Life is none too long for
                                    repentance. "As every grain of gold is valuable, so is each moment of time." How
                                    much time is lost! Wasted hours count up fast. Gather the fragments of precious
                                    time, and make of them something of moment that will benefit you. Gather the crumbs
                                    of happiness, to give brightness to your lives, and make the way more cheerful.
                                    Garner the fragments of spiritual food into your souls, to nourish, and strengthen,
                                    and beautify; let none be lost. Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div4></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children and home conversation" TEIform="index"/>WRITTEN FOR THE MANIFESTO. CHILDREN AND
                                HOME CONVERSATION</head><p TEIform="p">Children hunger perpetually for new ideas. They will learn with pleasure from the lips of
                                parents what they deem drudgery to learn from books, and even if they have the
                                misfortune to be deprived of many educational advantages, they will grow up intelli-
                                gent if they enjoy in childhood the privilege of listening to the conversation of
                                intelligent people. Let them have many opportunities of learning in this way. Be kind to
                                them and do not think it beneath you to answer their little questions for they proceed
                                from an implanted faculty which every true man and woman should take a great delight in
                                cherishing.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Affectation in any part of our carriage..." TEIform="index"/>Affectation in any part of our carriage...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Affectation in any part of our carriage, is lighting up a candle to our defects, and
                                never fails to make us noticed, either as wanting sense, or wanting sincerity.</p></div3></div2><pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1884</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hail! Happy new year" TEIform="index"/>"HAIL! HAPPY NEW YEAR "</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Tins simple term has a talismanic charm to the many thousands who in their pilgrimage
                                through this life accept the opening of a new year as something of more than ordinary
                                significance. It is the breathing of a u Happy New Year" to all, to the aged and no less
                                to the youth and little children. All alike have the anticipation of happiness in some
                                of its multiplied forms. It awakens a thought for brighter days, for prosperous days,
                                for days in which righteousness shall dwell permanently among men, and in which a
                                spirituality from the abode of the pure in heart shall direct our minds and guard us on
                                our heavenward journey. The worldly-wise m-m makes it a data from which to begin anew in
                                the accumulation of perishable treasures, where moth and rust must forever dwell. He
                                looks forward to the time when he can have dismissed the old year with all that it may
                                have lost or gained, and anticipates in the new, greater fame in his relations toward
                                the world, and a more abundant increase of gold and silver and precious stones. The
                                religious mind also looks forward with pleasure to the opening of a new season, to the
                                beginning of a new year in which will be found renewed demonstrations of God's goodness
                                to man. In our preparation let us arrange a new order of resolutions which shall govern
                                our conduct, and in this make our system of self-denial of greater practical benefit, so
                                that while it affords a Happy New Year and a better result to our- selves, it may at the
                                same time enhance the happiness, more particularly, of our immediate friends and then in
                                the good Providence of God gladden the hearts of all wrho know us. Readers of the
                                Manifesto will appreciate this very much and make the in- coming new year one in which
                                the anthem of " Good news and glad tidings " shall awaken a harmony in every heart. Our
                                lives should be known by the good deeds that are made manifest rather than by the
                                enumeration cf weeks and months, and the introduction of a new year w^ould then present
                                to us a most fortunate season when we may renew, effectually, our obligations to God,
                                and to his people, and step forward into newness of life that shall be an inspiration of
                                love and good will to all with whom we may meet. Increasing wisdom in truth and
                                righteousness must follow the increase of Christ's government. The testimony will then
                                bear a close relationship to the spirit of Divine Light, which like the refiner's fire
                                will consume everything except the pure gold. The anticipated New Year brings an
                                inspiration of love and joy and even of beautiful visions. We see the heavens opened and
                                the angels of God ascending and descending, we hear the revelations of great and good
                                gifts and they betoken most emphatically the wonderful days that are to come. The whole
                                world are in marching order and we see them moving on toward the beautiful Kingdom of
                                God. In this inimitable future when the ransomed of the Lord shall return to Zion ; in
                                these millennial days when the knowledge of the Lord shall cover the land as the waters
                                cover the sea, when the swords shall be beaten into plough-shares and the spears <pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 into pruning hooks, are the days when
                                righteousness shall dwell among men. Indeed, and 1884 belongs to this glorious future.
                                The days and weeks and months will move along with unerring precision, and as faithful
                                workers for this wonderful day of God's grace, let us accept the baptism of the Holy
                                Spirit and become the messengers of a gospel truth that shall save the world from
                            sin.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A Hindoo has been preaching in Boston..." TEIform="index"/>A Hindoo has been preaching in Boston...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">A Hindoo has been preaching in Boston Mass, in a Unitarian church, and we trust that the
                                church members have been made better by his presence. He does not profess to be a
                                Christian and may not see the necessity for such a change. He says " We believe in the
                                grand doctrine that God in his spiritual glory has come down to earth, and that now
                                access between him and us is direct. That glorious doctrine of true Christianity has
                                been obscured and dimmed by men who lack the appreciation of the teachings of their own
                                scriptures, but the time has come when the claims of the Holy Spirit shall be
                                vindicated. If the spirit of God is a living presence, if he is a consuming fire, if he
                                is a ready counselor, if he is one to whom every appeal may be made in a moment of
                                perplexity and sorrow, we are bound to tell the world what the responses of that Spirit
                                are. " This catholic spirit and clear view as seen by the distant light of a hindoo
                                mind, would compare favorably with the greater light of a Christian dispensation. St.
                                Paul has said, "As many as are led by the spirit of God, they are the sons of God," and
                                no doubt this influence may be felt in India as well as in the United States.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who write for the Manifesto should not..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Those who write for the Manifesto should not...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Those who write for the Manifesto should not forward the Mss. till they have affixed
                                their full name. If desired, the name can be with held when the article is
                            published.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to preserve the eyesight" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO PRESERVE THE EYESIGHT
                            </head><p TEIform="p">[From The Herald of Health] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The editor of the Huntsville, Ala., Democrat,
                                        who has passed his three score years without the use of eye-glasses, and can
                                        still, with his natural eyes, read fine print, wishes to give other people
                                        nearing the sere and yellow leaf the benefit of his ocular experience.
                                        Therefore, he tells them that in 1865 he found his eyesight failing, indicated
                                        by dark specks flitting over the page and a hazy appearance of the letters when
                                        he was reading. Remembering to have heard his mother say that exPresident John
                                        Quincy Adams (who lived to about 80 years) had preserved his eyesight and read
                                        without glasses by pressing the outer and inner corners of the eye together, the
                                        editor tried the experiment. After retiring to his bed at night, he has, ever
                                        since the fall of 1875, before going to sleep, pressed gently together the outer
                                        and inner corner of each eye between the thumb and fore-finger of the of the
                                        hand corresponding to the right and left eye, applying equal, simultaneous
                                        pressure to both eyes. Or, using but one hand, he has put the middle finger on
                                        his fore-head above his nose and pressed together the cor- ners of one between
                                        the thumb and forefinger, and the corners of the other eye between the third and
                                        fourth fingers, striving to give equal pressure to both eyes. The philosophy of
                                        the experiment is explained in this way : As people pass the middle age, there
                                        is said to be (and we believe it) a tendency of the balls of the eye to lose
                                        their convexity—in common parlance, to flatten. The habitual pressure of the
                                        outer and inner corners of the eyes together prevents flattening, and thereby
                                        preserves the original normal convexity of the eyes, and thereby the original
                                        power of seeing. Near-sighted persons are exceptions to the rule. Their
                                        near-sightedness (as we un<pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. derstand) is
                                        caused by too great convexity of the eye. Oftentimes, as they advance in years,
                                        their eyes flatten; that is, lose their original convexity, and become more
                                        nearly like the good eyes of young people, and they can see better without
                                        glasses, and lay them aside. Whether our philosophical explanation is right or
                                        wrong, this one thing we know, that whereas we, over seventeen years ago, were
                                        losing our original power of seeing, now, by the manipulation of our eyes as
                                        above explained, we can see clearly without the use of glasses, we can read
                                        small print almost, if not quite, as well as in our youth, while men and women
                                        many years our juniors, some of them our near blood relatives, who have not
                                        resorted to our mode of improving the eyesight, are compelled to use glasses.
                                        Believing it our duty to mankind to do them all the good we can, we overcome our
                                        native modesty about writing of ourself by the consideration that we may benefit
                                        others by relating our own experience. The reason why both eyes should be
                                        subjected to the equal simultaneous pressure is, that to see clearly, both eyes
                                        should behold objects at the same focal distance, and this cannot be if the two
                                        eyes have not the same convexity. If the two eyes should see objects at
                                        different distances, the object would present different images on the two
                                        retinae of the eyes, and produce a confusion of images, and, of course, impair
                                        distinct vision. Instances occur of persons who have a natural infirmity of the
                                        eyes with different foci—one eye seeing at one focal distance, the other seeing
                                        at another focal distance. In such cases oculists provide eye-glasses of
                                        different foci, so accommodated as to correct the natural defect and make both
                                        eyes see alike</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence of cheerfulness on health" TEIform="index"/>
                                THE INFLUENCE OF CHEERFULNESS ON HEALTH
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>HENRY REYNOLDS, M. D.</byline><p TEIform="p">[From the Phrenological Journal.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Cheerfulness exerts an important
                                        influence upon the health as well as contributing much to the happiness of
                                        mankind. The cheerful man, woman, or child is more likely to be healthy than the
                                        gloomy one. Cheerfulness promotes digestion of the food, quickens the
                                        circulation of the blood, and facilitates the proper performance of all the
                                        healthy functions of the body. The food eaten with pleasant companions is less
                                        likely to disagree with the dyspeptic than that eaten in solitude. Some
                                        dyspeptic persons have often remarked, that when dining with friends and
                                        agreeable acquaintances, whose com- panionship cheered them, they might eat
                                        freely, without subsequent harm, of substances which were sure to occasion
                                        distress when eaten at home alone. Not a few have noticed that when feeling
                                        despondent or feeble while alone at home, the arrival of pleasant acquaintances,
                                        or a visit to friends, would at once make them cheerful and cause them to feel
                                        like new creatures. If short seasons of cheerfulness will do so much for
                                        improving the condition of a person's health, it is easily conceivable that
                                        habitual cheerfulness would be a potent means of maintaining a constant state of
                                        healthfulness and physical enjoyment. It may be urged, however, that good health
                                        promotes cheerfulness, and, consequently, instead of cheerfulness being the
                                        cause of good health, it may be the consequence. It is true, that good health is
                                        conducive to cheerfulness, yet there may be good health without cheerfulness.
                                        The two, howeve*1, have been designed by nature to be intimately associated.
                                        Every healthy child is generally cheerful and happy. So universally is this the
                                        rule, that many are disposed to regard childhood as the most enjoyable period of
                                        human existence, and regret that they are no more to experience the pleasant
                                        joys of youth. The child, however, has its troubles and sorrows, but is more
                                        cheerful than those of a " larger growth " simply because it sooner forgets its
                                        griefs and gives itself to the enjoyment of the pleasant things of its
                                        existence. The child is really a better philosopher than the man, and,
                                        consequently, rinds more enjoyment in life, thus preserving its cheerfulness.
                                        Some persons are notably more cheerful than others. For those who are naturally
                                        cheerful, it seems easy for them to maintain their cheerfulness ; but, how are
                                        the naturally gloomy to put on cheerfulness? Will cheerfulness come at the
                                        bidding? The despondent can not become cheerful by willing <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/>
                                        THE MANIFESTO. 21 it. The proper conditions must be complied with, and
                                        cheerfulness comes as its result. Well directed efforts promote the attainment
                                        of cheerfulness. The mind must resolutely put aside corroding cares, keep aloof
                                        from worry, and take a hopeful view of the future. The mind may be active and
                                        devoted to the business of life, and yet so hold itself that life shall be full
                                        of cheerfulness. The cheerful mind is more likely to succeed in life than the
                                        gloomy one. Cheerfulness strengthens the power of mind as well as the body, and
                                        the cheerful mind is better able to cope with the difficulties of life than the
                                        gloomy mind is. The man who is busily engaged in business does not need to shut
                                        out cheerfulness from his life in order to succeed; on the contrary, by so doing
                                        he is less likely to succeed. By persistent effort every one may attain to a
                                        fair degree of cheerfulness. Well-directed efforts are almost sure to be crowned
                                        with success. Every one who will, may be cheerful. Cheerfulness is one of the
                                        good things of life and is well worth possessing. Ralph Waldo Emerson well said
                                        : "The best part of health is a fine disposition. " It is more essential than
                                        talent, even in works of talent. Nothing will supply the want of sunshine to
                                        peaches ; and to make knowledge valuable, you must have the wisdom of
                                        cheerfulness. Whenever you are sincerely pleased, you are nourished. The joy of
                                        the spirit indicates its strength. All healthy things are sweettempered. Genius
                                        works in sport, and goodness smiles to the last; and, for that reason, whoever
                                        sees the law which distributes things, does not despond, but is animated to
                                        great desires and endeavors. He who desponds, betrays that he has not seen it.
                                        As we advance in years and in knowledge from youth upwards, instead of becoming
                                        less cheerful, as is frequently the case, we should become more cheerful.
                                        Cheerfulness not only best promotes health, but it also facilitates success in
                                        all of our undertakings, besides contributing to the enjoyment of life.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The desire to be loved is human nature..." TEIform="index"/>The desire to be loved is human nature...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The desire to be loved is human nature in its purity. It is the first impulse of the open-
                            ing heart, and it lives and breathes in the bosom of all until the hour of death.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lines written upon the occasion of the demise of our good and worthy Sister Mary Ann Emerson. November 26, 1883" TEIform="index"/> 
                            Lines written upon the occasion of the demise of our good and worthy Sister Mary Ann
                            Emerson. Nov. 26th., 1883.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">O happy soul! most nobly hast thou done Thy work below. A treasure thou hast gained,
                            Exceeding far Peruvian gold; and now Thou goest home to thy eternal rest; Unto that mansion
                            now awaiting thee, Which thou thro' faithfulness hast well prepared. 0 dearest sister, while
                            we truly know The blessedness of thy immortal lot, We can but deeply feel the loss of thee,
                            That thou shouldst leave us, even at the time We cherished fondly such exulting hope, That
                            thou wouldst tarry with us yet a while, A goodly while. Ah, sister, all in vain. 'Tis past.
                            And we are left to move along Without thy blest companionship to cheer In many toilsome
                            hours and walks of life, But wilt thou not in spirit be with us, To bless and comfort us? O
                            be it so. And tho' our earnest pleadings failed to hold Thee longer tangible within our
                            midst, We hope and trugtthy blest angelic sway Will move to ceaseless energy each soul,
                            That, struggling oft', seems faltering betimes, And growing weary in the gospel strife. We
                            know what power thy spirit can impart, For many years, within the gospel field, Hast thou to
                            many given evidence Of Stirling qualities thou hast possessed, The young and tender minds of
                            trusting youth, Have been protected, molded into forms That beautify the Zion of our God.
                            And Oh, how very much they owe to thee, Dear sister, guardian, parent—all in one, They rise
                            up now and call thee blessed, Thou Who hast through every scene in life been true To gospel
                            principles, since first thou heard The voice that called thee from a life of sin, Art truly
                            blessed. Thy reward is sure, And thou hast gone to reap what thou hast sown— A harvest of
                            abundant golden grains. It needs no eulogy to bring to view The merits of our worthy sister
                            dear, For many here are witnesses most true, 01 her devoted spirit year by year. These lines
                            are written simply to pot tray The deep emotions of affection'd hearts, And as our sister
                            passes thus away, No wonder that the sadden'd tear-drop starts. A constant burden-bearer all
                            along From early life to three score years or more, Tho' frail in body, still in spirit
                            strong, Her exit now most deeply wp deplore. But she is gone, gone from our mortal sight,
                            Tho' still in spirit near us all the same; While unto spirit realms she takes her flight,
                            Her blessed ministrations still we claim, Thus, like our sister may we toil with care, Thro'
                            life till all its transient scenes are o'er, That we may find our portion ever there, In
                            that bright world where parting is no more. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In memory of Elder Robert M. Wagan" TEIform="index"/>IN MEMORY OF ELDER ROBERT M. WAGAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McFarland, Elsie H." TEIform="persName"/>ELSIE H. MCFARLAND</byline><p TEIform="p">" He crossed in the starlight gray and cold, And the pale mists hid him i'rom mortal view. "
                            Onward the boatman came, regardless of our prayers and entreaties, regardless of our
                            ceaseless watching and thoughtful care, and quickly transferred our brother across the dark
                            river to the other shore. Up the shining way he went, to the golden gate, and passed in with
                            a glad welcome from myriad voices of those who had long claimed him as a kindred spirit and
                            co-worker in the cause of purity, truth and humanity. Hand clasped hand, as brother met
                            brother, in that sphere of fraternal love, where temptation and sin are not permitted to
                            enter. In early life, a guiding hand from this spirit sphere, turned the thoughts, feelings
                            and spiritual aspirations of our departed brother; away from the inharmonies of earth life,
                            away from the strifes and ambitions of a merely worldly existence, to the cause which he so
                            heartily espoused, and for which he so long and faithfully labored. As a child he was
                            tractable and teachable, as a youth he was kind, courteous, loving and obedient; as a man,
                            his noble qualities of head and heart were manifest in all that he said and did. Abroad he
                            always showed himself the true Christian gentleman. In business with the children of this
                            world, he was prompt and decided, and honest to the last farthing, yet friendly and affable.
                            At home we had reason to bless him every hour. To the children and youth he was a kind,
                            tender, loving brother, never too tired, or too hurried or worried to say a pleasant word,
                            or present some little token of appreciation, that was helpful and encouraging. To the aged
                            he was particularly deferential and respectful, looking after their interests, anticipating
                            their wants, and ever striving to make them feel that they were a blessing. In temporal
                            things we leaned on him as on a staff that could never fail us. As a leader we were sure he
                            would never lead us astray. As a teacher we had implicit confidence in the truths he taught.
                            As a brother the best beloved. All about us lie tokens of his tender love and care. On every
                            hand are evidences of his ability to scatter blessings in the pathway of those under his
                            charge. Self was ignored, and selfish interests and selfish motives found no place in his
                            noble soul. Each year was a well rounded period in a life well spent. Farewell brother,
                            though our cup of affliction is brimming over. Rest beneath the shadow of the Tree of Life
                            and we will toil encouraged by thy bright example and beautiful life of entire consecration.
                            Safe beyond the rolling tide—safe from mortal suffering— safe from temptation—safe from the
                            power of sin—safe in the companionship of angelic guides who will minister to thy every
                            need— safe in thy Father's house of many mansions—safe in a home of perfect purity and love,
                            we will leave thee. With sorrowing hearts we must say farewell,—dear brother, farewell. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel admonitions" TEIform="index"/>ANGEL ADMONITIONS</head><p TEIform="p">Be true thyself, if thou wouldst teach The striving ones to love thee; Be true, thy gentle
                            words shall reach The heavenly realms above thee. For angels pause to catch the sound Of
                            words so blest and tender, And bear the news to earth around, Christ reigns in regal
                            splendor. Canterbury, N. H.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="H., L." TEIform="persName"/>L. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cleanse first that which is within the cup and platter..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Cleanse first that which is within the cup and platter...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">'' Cleanse first that which is within the cup and platter, that the outside may be clean al-
                            so. " The words we speak, and the acts we perform are as the contents of the cup and
                            platter, if they are free from selfishness and all that pertains to the world, that world to
                            which Christ referred when he said, "I am not of this world, " our characters which may be
                            likened to the outside of the platter will inevitably be without reproach.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="S., E. A." TEIform="persName"/>E. A. S.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good resolutions are an honor..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Good resolutions are an honor...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Good resolutions are an honor to every heart that forms them. But that honor
                                    takes to itself a new luster, and that heart is noble still, when the resolutions
                                    are not broken., </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Guardian" TEIform="index"/>— The Guardian.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trust in God" TEIform="index"/>TRUST IN GOD</head><p TEIform="p">"Though thy sun may for a season cease to shine." Enfield, Conk. Affetuoso. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            Y. Brother, is life's morning clouded, Brother, all things round are calling, He from His
                            high throne in heaven, Has the sunlight ceased to Calling with united Watches every
                            step you shine, voice, take, pine? Cheer up, Brother, let thy vision Look above, see! light
                            is long. Yea, my Brother, tho' life's troubles Drive thee near to dark demake. Cheer up,
                            Brother, He has power To dry up the bitter near, Soon will come the next transition,
                            Trust in God and persevere. spair, Soon they'll vanish like a bubble, Trust in God and
                            persevere. tear, And though darkest tempests lower, Trust in God and persevere. Is the
                            earth in darkness shrouded, Wouldst thou at thy lot reTho' the wrongs of earth are gall
                            ing, They must lose their strength ere He will see each fet ter riven, Which your foes in
                            anger</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</head><p TEIform="p">Herald of Health. Dec. This number contains an extended list of articles on Health which
                                is well worth the perusal by those who love long life and happy days. The drinking of
                                hot water as a remedy for the many diseases that afflict the human family is fully
                                illustrated in the several rules that are given for its use. The department which
                                contains "Studies in Hygiene for women" has also articles of real value. The work for
                                1884 will be enlarged by eight additional pages. M. L. Holbrook, M. D. Publisher, 13
                                &amp; 15 Laight St. N. Y. $1.00 a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">[A first class monthly Magazine,]
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. Dec. Contents: Prof. Nicholas Joly, the
                                eminent French Naturalist: Foot prints in the An- cient Sand-stone, Illustrated; The
                                Trance; Monsignor T. J. Capel, with portrait; Grand-mothers; King Cetewayo, with
                                portrait; Investments which pay; General observations on Amativeness; The first gun for
                                Peace; Slaves of Fashion; Genesis of Alcohol; Diet of the Chinese, also Notes in Science
                                and Agriculture; Answers to Correspondents, etc., etc. Fowler &amp; Wells, Pub., 753
                                Broadway, N. Y. $2.00 a year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Caxton Illustrated" TEIform="index"/>Caxton Illustrated
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A Famous »ulu\y. People who delight in beautiful and good
                                books will be astonished when they see, if they have not already seen, the annoucements
                                of the "Caxton Illustrated" and other editions of standard authors, issued this season.
                                The typography, and all mechanical qualities of printing and binding are simply superb,
                                and the prices a veritable marvel, to the oldtime book-buyer. The list includes the
                                works, complete, of Dickens, 15 volumes, reduced in price from $22.50 to $9 net;
                                Thackeray's, from $16.50 to $6.75; George Eliot's, from $12 to $3.75; Washington Irv-
                                ing's Works, from $20 to $4; Scott's Waverley Novels, from $30 to $7.50; Hawthorne's
                                Works, from $21 to $6.50; J. Feimimore Cooper's, from $32 to $12.50; Bulwer's, from
                                $31.25 to $8.50; Wm. Black's, from $15 to $4; De Quincey's, from $18 to $6.50. The
                                publisher sends them to any one for examination before requiring any payment, on
                                reasonable evidence of good faith, and will send a 100-page catalogue of these and other
                                works free upon appli- cation. John B. Alden, Publisher, 18 Vesey St., New York.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Significant prayer" TEIform="index"/>A SIGNIFICANT PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">We know that thou art the Infinite love— the healer and not the destroyer ot all thy
                            people—the Father who pitieth his children more than a human father ever yet pitied— yea,
                            the Mother, who comforteth all thy little ones more than a human mother ever yet comforted
                            the children of her travail—and so we know that the hopes with which this mortal life is
                            inspired are but as buds which will bear beneficent fruit for us in the immortal life that
                            is to be. We pray that we may believe in the immortal life—that we may aspire after it, and
                            yearn for it, with an unconquerable yearning—not because we would lead therein a life of
                            slothful ease, but because, in toil and in endeavor, in self-sacrifice and in devoted love,
                            we would become all that which immortal life, and immortal life only, will enable us to
                            realize. But O Father and Mother! even here, while "the muddy vesture of decay doth grossly
                            close us in, " may we be supremely content to serve a glad apprenticeship to that toil and
                            endeavor, to that self-sacrifice and that devoted love. So will eternal life begin in us,
                            and uhy kingdom come in us, and thy will be done in us, even as the eternal life has already
                            commenced for, and thy kingdom already come to, and thy will already done by, those
                            supremely beatified spirits who are nearest to Thee because they stoop the lowest to those
                            of thy children, who, even in the immortal life, are yet sad and sorrowful. Amen and amen!</p><byline TEIform="byline">—Inspiration of <persName reg="Applebee, James K." TEIform="persName"/>Rev. James K. Applebee in Boston
                            Commonwealth.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dow, Mary R." TEIform="index"/>Mary R. Dow
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Dow, Mary R." TEIform="persName">Mary R. Dow</persName>, Nov. 10, 1883, at Enfield, N. H.
                                Age, 83 yrs. 4 mo. and 23 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Emerson, Mary Ann" TEIform="index"/>Mary Ann Emerson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Emerson, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName">Mary Ann Emerson</persName>, Nov. 24, 1883, at North
                                Family, Enfield, N. H. Age 63 yrs. 10 mo. and 16 days. (See page 21.)</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaw, Abigail" TEIform="index"/>Abigail Shaw
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Shaw, Abigail" TEIform="persName">Abigail Shaw</persName>, Nov. 27, 1883, at West
                                Gloucester, Me. Age 77 yrs. 7 mo. and 20 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wagan, Robert M." TEIform="index"/>Robert M. Wagan
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Wagan, Robert M." TEIform="persName">Robert M. Wagan</persName>, Nov. 29, 1883, at South
                                family, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. Age 50 yrs. 6 mo. and 5 days. In him we have lost a dearly
                                beloved leader.—A. E. C. (See page 22.)</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Olmstead, Amanda" TEIform="index"/>Amanda Olmstead
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Olmstead, Amanda" TEIform="persName">Amanda Olmstead</persName>, Dec. 10, 1883, at Union
                                Village, Ohio. Age 77 yrs. 4 mo. and 19 days. She has been a faithful member for 60 yrs.
                                iving a pure virgin life and devoted to community interests. She honored her profes-
                                sion and zealously supported the cause of the Gospel and has now gone to a happy lome in
                                the better Land.—O. C. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>