<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2711" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">27</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18971101" TEIform="date">November 1897</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">161-176</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="27" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1">
                    <!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
NOVEMBER,   1S97.
A CONCISE HISTORY OF THE
SHAKERS.
Just Published.     The book is printed
A SUMMARY VIEW
OF  THE
 CHURCH,
OR
"United   Society   of   Believers"
It treats of the Rise and Progress of the
with large type  and on excellent paper.   Society,  together with  the general Principles of the Faith and Testimony.
It contains  130 pages and has                                                Price   50* cts.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common property, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is publisht by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
The work gives  quite an extended ac-   live and work together, and hold all their
property  in common,   all the men   and
count of the Several SOCIETIES, their women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1119 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
ILLUSTRATIONS
of the Shakers and their
THE ALTRUIST.
organization and general management.
Price, 50 cts.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF  THE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 eta.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
MILLENNIAL
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. 11.
BY
LLOYD H. CHANDLER.U.S. N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTERBURY
is situated in one of the loveliest spots of
New Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,  15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
SHAKER HAMAMELIS
(WITCHHAZEL,)
A remedy for Cuts, Burns, Scalds,
Headache, Sore Throat and all
cases of* external inflammation.
Taken internally for Bowel
Complaint, Bleeding of tlie
Lungs or Bowels, and for
all aches and pains.
For use externally, bathe the parts and
lay on a cloth wet with the Extract,    Internally, take one half teaspoonful three
times a day.    Use hot or cold.
Ask your druggist for it or send your
order to Arthur Bruce.
East Canterbury, N. H.
The New York
Oldest      and      Best      Recognized
Weekly    Paper     in    the    United
States.
Improved        Management,         and
Methods up to date.
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Literary, Scientific,
Humorous, Dramitic, Entertaining. Also G. A. R., Masonic
Fire and Society News.
One Copy,  One  Year,  $2.59.
Post yourself on what is going
on  in     New   York.     Address
The  New  York Dispatch
317 Broadway, New York.
 GOODS
Gents  HALF HOSE   and
SWEATERS, suited to
all   athletic   sports,
Bicycling,   Boat Base ball.
Made of the best Australian wool in
three grades.    Heavy, Medium and Light,
designated as Nos. 1, 2, 3.    Colors, White,
Black and Blue in the above grades.     Tan,
Garnet, Brown and Gray in the medium
only.    Sold at wholesale and retail.
Address Hart & Shepard,
East Canterbury, N. H.
Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism. A synopsis of the United Society of Believers iu Christ's Second
Appearing. Illustrated. By Giles
B. Avert.    Price 15 cts.
DISPATCH
KNIT
ing &
Published  by  the  Shakers,
Vol. XXVII.
 1897.
No.   11.
Entered at the Post Office at East Canterbury,  N,  H., as Second-Class Matter.--><p TEIform="p"/><pb n="161" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecrated common sense" TEIform="index"/> CONSECRATED COMMON SENSE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/> By Elder Henry C. Blinn.</byline><p TEIform="p"> IN the Volunteer's Gazetteamong many other good things, we find Captain
                            Habedank, who is keenly alive to the salvation of souls,writing under the above unique
                            title. Whatever may be thought of any religious faith, or the saving grace that may be
                            attacht to it, we are quite certain that its value will be enhanced in proportion to the
                            amount of "Common Sense" that may be used in the illustrations that are brought forward.
                            That religious commodity which is sometimes thrown to the winds with more zeal than wisdom,
                            under the assertion that it is Bible religion, has in it but little practical value, and
                            sometimes still less common sense. "To be good and to do good," is a genuine quality of
                            religion, of which the possessor need not be ashamed, and yet it is wholly outside of the
                            Bible, so far as the quotation is concerned. To be good is to be godlike, and this includes
                            all the beatitudes of the New Testament. The element of goodness is from everlasting and
                            precedes all the works of creation and especially all records, whether civil or sacred. It
                            is wonderful how much good may be accomplisht by a few individuals if they are devoted to
                            the prosperity of their religious order in the world, and yet their message of God's love to
                            man is as old as the creation of man. The Volunteer message bearers, like many others, have
                            come as "an army with banners" and are gloriously inarching on to a great victory. Many
                            zealous souls are engaged in duties equally as necessary for the present and future
                            happiness of the family of man, even tho their work deals largely in the interests of the
                            body. <pb n="162" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> Salvation must be obtained by degrees, for both the
                            body and soul, and this can be done only as the work of preparation is accomplisht. Those
                            who have fostered unclean or immoral habits, and are marred "as the vessel in the hands of
                            the potter," must begin with personal cleanliness prior to being baptized into any spiritual
                            ministration. An unwasht Christian, or an immoral Christian must, indeed, be a misnomer, but
                            the willing convert to any Christian church, who accepts the beautiful teaching of the New
                            Testament, "Cleanse first that which is within the cup and platter, that the outside of them
                            may be clean also."Matt, xxiii., 26, will find much needful work to do. Cleanliness comes so
                            near to godliness that one might be inclined to say that it is godliness, but the Apostle,
                            as a faithful teacher enters a little more into the details and shows the first and
                            essential work that a saving grace demands. "Let us cleanse ourselves from all filthiness of
                            the flesh and spirit, perfecting holiness in the fear of God."II Cor. vii., 1. Accepting
                            this preparatory work that demands such a rigid purification, a great salvation must follow
                            so long as obedience is maintained. If we can be assured that tlrs "Common Sense" has been
                            consecrated to the good work of redeeming humanity, then it becomes so much the more
                            valuable in its ministrations. Then it is that oui-reason combined with a higher reason in
                            the ministration of good-will to man, will be able to accomplish works that are almost
                            superhuman. A wonderful interest is taken in reading the visitations of Jesus, and how
                            kindly he raised his hand to heal the sick, to restore sight to the blind, and make the lame
                            to walk. While the disciples lookt on with astonishment, Jesus remarkt, "Greater works than
                            these shall ye do." And the disciples were especially gifted, in his name, to accomplish
                            many wonderful things. It is the loving simplicity of this testimony of Jesus that finds a
                            ready response in the hearts of the rich and the poor, the learned and no less the
                            unlearned. There are but few, very few persons who can not, in some degree, discriminate
                            between right and wrong, having reference to their own duty to God and to man, and it is
                            through this channel that they are able to make a divine or consecrated use of their
                            valuable common sense. Jesus very plainly informed his disciples of this fact,"Where your
                            treasure is, there will your heart be also." There is no mystery about this statement. If
                            the treasure is the accumulation of a selfish interest, then the heart's affections are
                            absorbed in the same order of life, and this state forms the heaven for the soul. "Go and
                            sell that thou hast and give to the poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven, and come
                            and follow me." This advice to the rich, young man was the ' 'Consecrated Common Sense" <pb n="163" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> of Jesus, and it was the only terms upon which this
                            promise could be offered as an assurance of entering into the kingdom of God, or of becoming
                            a preacher of righteousness, according to the testimony of the Christ. Eloquent divines may
                            bring forward beautiful illustrations on the "Ministry of Riches," and prove to their own
                            satisfaction that these riches are no barrier against an entrance into the kingdom. Jesus
                            says otherwise ;it was the selfishness of the rich, and no less the selfishness of the poor,
                            whether it represented one dollar or one hundred dollars that formed the barrier. He would
                            carefully impress his disciples that their whole life and all they possest should be devoted
                            to the work of the God of peace and for the good of humanity. That the narrowness of
                            individual interests were the selfish interests of the children of this world, and could not
                            be in harmony with the spiritual life of his heavenly kingdom. In this work for humanity,
                            Jesus illustrated fully the great difference of a journey over the narrow way, which .would
                            lead to peace and prosperity in this life and assure the disciple of a reward in the life to
                            come; and that of the broad road which admitted all that was unclean or belonged to a
                            selfish interest. If we call this manifestation of his wisdom and love his "Consecrated
                            Common Sense," it may be the best illustration of the term that could be brought to the
                            mind, as it appealed to the common sense of his many hearers, and as the record informs us,
                            "the common people heard him gladly." East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is life without self-denial and a strict adherence to the path of virtue; and what propriety is there in a profession without possession?" TEIform="index"/> What is Life without Self-denial and a strict adherence to the path of
                            Virtue; and what propriety is there in a profession without possession?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, B. J." TEIform="persName"/> By B. J. Kaime.</byline><p TEIform="p"> O life ! fleeting life; tell me of thy beauties. Tell me of the comforts which
                            thou dost bestow; But if I'm neglectful of every day's duties, No real enjoyment my spirit
                            doth know. If vain words and jesting do from my heart issue, Or over much laughter my fault
                            prove to be; If I am accustomed to backbiting whispers How can I from Satan's temptations be
                            free? If evil surmisings are constant companions, If hard thoughts and feelings with me bear
                            the sway, <pb n="164" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> Can life be delightful, or can I march
                            heavenward, Till all these preventives are put far away ? If I am too anxious to know others
                            business, And all their employment to be seeking out, Am I in a state to be gaining true
                            riches ? Have I no occasion to fear or to doubt ? If I am inclined to seek entertainment In
                            telling the failings of sister or brother; Will this clothe my spirit in beautiful raiment
                            Or give me a right to the love of "Our Mother?" If I do exalt in another's abasement, Or
                            greatly rejoice to see their downfall; When sorrows assail me, who will give me releasement?
                            Or who will vouch safe to hear when I call ? If self I esteem and strive for its glory;
                            Strive for its advancement in pleasure and ease, Shall I find a place with the pure, meek
                            and lowly, Will those spirits own me, who none but God please? If I am too fond of showing
                            my knowledge, And give my opinion before it's required, Or use the tongue oft, where a
                            bridle is better, Will this be a labor of heaven desired? If I make confession of all my
                            offenses, And loudly proclaim that each evil I hate, Unless I forsake them and purge well my
                            senses, Can I ever travel from my fallen state ? If I profess union, and love and
                            submission, And say to the Spirit, "I will be resigned,' Will merely asserting, yield ample
                            fruition? Can I without acting, the low valley find ? If age I revere not, nor give due
                            attention To the feelings and wishes of those of this class; If I heed not their counsel,
                            experience and wisdom, Shall I not regret it, while through life I pass ? If I with my
                            equals have not condescension, And if of their sorrows I take not a share, When I am bound
                            low and feel tribulation, Who will raise my spirit with kindness and care ? 0 life, fleeting
                            life! What art thou! What art thou, Without self-denial and meekness and love ? <pb n="165" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> A boon without comfort, a wearisome journey, Without the pure
                            gospel, thou surely wouldst prove. Then if any spirit desire to possess thee And taste
                            enjoyment that's wholesome and clean, Let them seek a part of each goodly virtue, And lay up
                            a substance untarnished by sin. East Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cross" TEIform="index"/> THE CROSS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stewart, Ezra J." TEIform="persName"/> By Ezra J. Stewart.</byline><p TEIform="p"> ONE who did.his own thinkingwho was always guided by the ever increasing light
                            of his own inner consciousness,one who lived a pure life given up to the interests of all
                            mankind said,"And whosoever doth not bear his cross and come after me can not be my
                            disciple." Much has been said concerning the cross, so much perhaps as to convey to many the
                            idea of a great burden. To the soul that aspires for spiritual light and guidance it becomes
                            necessary that a constant watchfulness be maintained over the thoughts, feelings and
                            actions; and yet to one who has come into an understanding of the law of the Higher life
                            there need be no distressing burden connected with this call. It is only when the mind is
                            not fully resigned ; when a fixt determination has not been attained; when there still
                            remains in the heart a lingering desire for those things which do not feed the soul, but
                            pander exclusively to the physical senses, only then does there exist a consciousness of
                            burdensome care. Jesus said,"My yoke is easy and my burden is light." We have the power to
                            make our cross light or heavy in proportion as we enter into the work with a whole heart. Is
                            it a burden for the true mother to care for her child,to spend days and years of earnest,
                            watchful devotion ? Many times she may become weary and worn, but never the thought of a
                            heavy cross finds abiding place in her mind because heart and soul are in her work, she
                            loves it. And so it is with those who have entered thoroughly into the new life,the life of
                            the Spirit, into that life which to the animal man appears so mysterious. Having become
                            convinced that only "the pure in heart shall see God" or the good, in making this the
                            all-absorbing desire, we will find with Jesus an easy yoke and a light burden. It will then
                            become second nature to be careful and watchful; our every aspiration will lift heavenward
                            and all the faculties of mind and soul will become so quickened and illuminated as to enable
                            us to perceive and cast from us the slightest indication of any thought which would not tend
                            to the development of the God life within. We shall then know that there is naught but good
                            or God, that this Life fills our life, is indeed omnipotent and omnipresent. Those who have
                            become sufficiently un- <pb n="166" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> folded to realize the joys of the
                            spiritual life, freely and gladly follow the injunction to "seek first the kingdom of
                            heaven," for to them it is given to know that "all things needful will be added." Happy,
                            indeed, is the soul who has h ard the unmistakable voice of his inner consciousness calling
                            to a higher realm than the mere animal or even the purely intellectual plane of being and
                            lias had the courage to answer by casting aside all customs, creeds and dogmas, all
                            preconceived ideas and even the admonition of friends, if these interfered with his
                            advancement. To such an one the gates of heaven are open, the work of eternity looms up as
                            one long and glorious opportunity for conquest. Heaven to this soul will consist in ever
                            reaching out for more truth. The cross is then swallowed up in one long continuous victory,a
                            victory over selfishness and over death. There is a high repose which rests as an abiding
                            guest in the soul illuminated with the knowledge of Godliness. When this resting place has
                            been reacht we may say with John Burroughs; Serene I fold my hands and wait Nor care for
                            wind, nor tide, nor sea; I rave no more 'gainst time or fate For lo, my own shall come to
                            me. And this restfulness does not mean going to sleep, on the contrary it is a soul
                            awakening. It is finding that nothing ctm tire us. It is to have eliminated from our thought
                            the fear of poverty or riches, of disease or death, and to have these fears removed is to
                            become in time completely delivered from the conditions themselves and to be lifted up to
                            those glorious heights where in a fulness of that perfect love which casteth out every fear
                            the burden has been changed to the glory of the cross. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Aaron Wood" TEIform="index"/> TESTIMONY OF AARON WOOD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wood, Aaron" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> [The following was ivritten at Watervliet, N. Y., Sept 15, 1826.] IT is now
                            forty-six years since I embraced the gospel of Christ's second appearing, which was revealed
                            through Mother Ann Lee, and those faithful witnesses of God who came with her from England.
                            As I was intimately acquainted with these beloved witnesses, I feel it a duty I owe to God,
                            to my own soul, and to the cause of truth, to make an honest declaration concerning my
                            connection and acquaintance with them, and my knowledge of their character and ministration.
                            In doing this, I shall relate a little of my own experience before I became acquainted with
                            them.. When I was about twenty years of age, I felt great concern for the salvation of my
                            soul. I was sensible that I was daily increasing in sin against God, and I saw no way to
                            escape his righteous judgment. I fled to the holy <pb n="167" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            Scriptures; but I found these condemned me. They testified that, "He that committeth sin is
                            of the Devil." I cried to God as well as I was able; but found no reliefmy trouble of mind
                            daily increast. I attended the meetings of various denominations of profest Christians, but
                            could find none that, I believed really walkt with God, according to the precepts and
                            example of Christ. My tribulation and condemnation increast for about the space of five
                            years, until my life became a burden to me, but thanks be to God, he at length opened a way
                            for my releasemeiit. About this time, I heard of a strange people who were persecuted and
                            imprisoned in Albany, for their religion. I went from Shelburn, Mass., to see them, and was
                            soon convinced that they lived and reigned with Christ on earth. They spoke the word of God
                            to me, which was indeed "quick and powerful." They taught me to confess all my sins to God
                            before his witnesses, and to take up a daily cross against all sin and all manner of
                            uncleanness, and to live a just, holy and pure life before God and all men. I had so much
                            faith and confidence in them, that 1 was ready and willing to confess my sins, which I did
                            faithfully, one by one, as I had committed them, and the blessing of repentance which I
                            felt, cleansed and healed my wounded soul and releast me from the fear of death and the
                            torments of hcil, and I can testify of a truth, that in obedience to the faith which I then
                            received, I am saved from all sin. In my first visit, I did not see Mother Ann Lee. She had
                            been previously moved from Albany to Poughkeepsie, and imprisoned in that town. This was in
                            August. In the fall I went to see the Elders again, and staid with them one night in the
                            prison. After Mother and the Elders were releast from prison, I went to see them at
                            Watervliet, and from this time I was with them the most of my time. I journeyed from place
                            to place, and was with them in nearly all the places where they visited. I have suffered
                            much persecution and affliction, and thank God that I was counted worthy to suffer with
                            them. I have been beaten and wounded by wicked, persecuting mobs, till the ground was
                            besprinkled with my blood. At one time I was knocked down with a club, and taken up and
                            carried into the house for dead. But these things were light in comparison with what Mother
                            and the Elders suffered by the hands of lawless ruffians. I am confident that nothing short
                            of the power of God, could have preserved their lives through such severe sufferings. I was
                            with them at the time Mother was so shamefully and cruelly abused by that outrageous and
                            horrid mob, which began at George Darrow's, in New Lebanon, on the morning of the 2nd of
                            September, 1783, and which continued until dark, the bare recital of which is enough to make
                            humanity shudder, and bring everlasting disgrace upon the inhuman actors. Shortly after
                            this, I went with Mother and the Elders from New Lebanon to Watervliet; I continued to live
                            there with them for more than a year, and was daily conversant with them, dwelt in the same
                            house and ate at the <pb n="168" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> same table. I was there when Elder
                            William Lte deceast, July 21, 1784, and remained till after Mother Ann's decease, on the 8th
                            of September following. Notwithstanding the evil repoits and the base charges of
                            intemperance and lewdness, that have been circulated against Mother Arm Lee, I can testify
                            that in all my acquaintance with her, I never discovered the lesist symptom of intemperance,
                            lewdness, or any kind of evil. I always considered her to be the most godly person my eyes
                            ever beheld. She truly loved and feared God, and taught the same to others. Her chanty to
                            souls was boundless, and her severity against sin was like a naming fire. No wonder ihe
                            world hated her, for she was not of the world, hence they said all manner of evil against
                            her falsely. In doing this, they brought the greatest possible evidence in her favor. Aid
                            low 1 say unto you that utter falee sceueatior.s; je aie the children of a persecuting
                            generation. "Fill ye up then the measure of your fatheis, that upon you may come all the
                            righteous blood shed upon the earth, from the blood of righteous Abel," down to the
                            suffering witnesses of God whom ye have persecuted and abused. Watervliet, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silent forces" TEIform="index"/> THE SILENT FORCES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/> By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p"> OF the manifestations of life in its varied forms, the most powerful and
                            far-reaching in their results are the forces that to the materialistic mind are void,
                            because in their operation they are removed from the glamor that surrounds and seems
                            necessary to impress the undevelopt spirit. When the Divine teacher announced the importance
                            of retiring into the closet and in silent devotion sending forth the prayer, he announced
                            one of the grandest truths that was ever presented for human acceptance. In the movements of
                            life upward it is from the silent, the powerful forces from which is evolved the strength
                            that is lifting toward the higher. When before the prophet's vision there past in review the
                            noisy demonstrations of life in the earthquake, thunder and tempest, but not to them was the
                            highest manifestations of Divine life, but in the voice of silence there was demonstrated
                            the highest embodiment of truth. That the external may be necessary to attract and center
                            the life on the reality is admissible. As toys in the hands of childhood, so the powers that
                            appeal most strongly to the material sense are a proof that there are yet unfolded forces
                            hid under their noisy demonstrations. Evolution is not a backward movement, for on it is
                            written the law of eternal progression. The life history of our planet, written on its rock
                            strata, and read by the clear eye and unclouded intellect of the true scientist gives <pb n="169" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> proof of the convulsive periods in the remote past when
                            the forms of life then existing were destroyed, and as the creative forces replaced the old
                            with new and better conditions the primitive forms of life could not retain their position,
                            for onward must be the eternal watchword. In the realm of mechanics the nearer that ideal is
                            attained which is seeking to grasp and control the forces operating in the material world
                            the less demonstrative to the extreme sense are their manifestations. Simplicity is the
                            close companion of perfection and the nearer its realization the less complicated are its
                            forces. The mysterious only remains so until it is understood. Like the pent up forces in
                            the material world which result in explosions and upheavals have been the political and
                            religious convulsions which have destroyed nations and overthrown civilizations. Neither one
                            in the highest sense had within them the elements of progress, but were a means used to
                            remove the debris that had collected preventing further growth. The powers which to-day are
                            the most potent factors in the advancement of life move so silently that those who are
                            looking for a great sign in the heavens which is to usher in a new and improved order of
                            life, feel that nothing is being done because it is not heralded with the blast of trumpets
                            and immediate destruction of all opposing elements. "The kingdom of heaven is within." From
                            the internal to the external is the true order of development. The source from which tLe
                            soul draws its inspiration makes it either an obstruction or a builder who is helping to
                            shape and expand the temple of universal life. The intuitive faculty that enables us
                            spiritually to feel the condition of surrounding life is closely allied to the prophetic
                            gift, and while in that illuminated state are enabled to predict future events. This power
                            "cometh not with observation," the method by which unilluminated minds arrive at results. It
                            is felt and thereby the evidence which is given is known to be real. It is the silent voice
                            speaking to the soul that has been prepared to receive those heavenly ministrations. In the
                            interior life even if clouded by externalities or obstructed in its expansion by false
                            theological teaching is that '"temple not made with hands." How to attain the knowledge that
                            will open it to the divine Spirit is a problem that perplexes the soul living in the
                            externalities of life because it does not understand the things of the Spirit. Many ways are
                            devised by which admittance may be gained, but whosoever cometh not through the gate the
                            same is a thief and a robber. Those who have been admitted to communion in that temple, are
                            the ones who have given all they possest to advance the truth in a manner that the left hand
                            knoweth not what the right hand doeth. Like the dew, as it is silently distilled, so are the
                            forces that have in them the greatest power to build a truer and better life in the
                            individual or the state. Shakers, N. Y.</p><pb n="170" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The company of singers from East Canterbury, N. H.  spoken of in our..." TEIform="index"/> The company of singers from East Canterbury, N. H. spoken of in
                                our... </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, Alfred, York County Jail, September 15, 1897" TEIform="index"/></dateline><p TEIform="p">[The company of singers from East Canterbury, N. H. spoken of in our last
                                issue, who spent several days with the Believers at Sabbathday Lake and Alfred, Me., on.
                                Sept. 15th were invited to visit the County Jail in the latter town. While passing
                                through the premises, an opportunity presented itself to sing a few sacred selections to
                                the unfortunate inmates which was kindly accepted. During the singing of the last hjmn
                                to a company at work outside of the main building, the prisoners within listened
                                attentively from the open windows and the singing was answered with a hearty "Good bye,
                                God bless you," from all. Touching indeed was the simple, yet sincere benediction,
                                falling as it did from the lips of the prisoners. On the afternoon of the same day, the
                                following letter was received, which will speak for itself to our appreciative
                                readers.J.] York County Jail, Alfred, Me. Sept. 15, 1897. Elder Henry Green, Dear Sir
                                ;In the name of eachand every inmate of this jail, the present letter is written as a
                                token of gratitude for the precious visit received this day, and the sweet songs heard
                                from the gracious Shakers. If the sweet singers do not reside with you, kindly forward
                                our message to them. Glorious deeds have had their greatest incentive from the homely
                                ballads that gladdened the hearts of our ancestors. Few people who are not distinctly
                                musical realize the benefits to society derived from the refining influence 'of music.
                                Music is said to be the food of love, and love to be the refining influence which
                                creates civilization. Does it not follow then, that a more general cultivation of music
                                would have a tendency to decrease crime ? I believe that a large proportion of those who
                                are now in durance vile would never have been led into the commission of crime if their
                                home life was what it might have been. Increase the pleasures of home life and you will
                                lessen the temptations which everywhere greet the unhappy. Assuring you that in return
                                for your sweet songs which have touched our lonely hearts, we will endeavor to become
                                better men; and imploring our common Father to fill your souls with peace and joy here
                                and hereafter We remain your grateful servants,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="The Prisoners" TEIform="persName"/> The Prisoners. -per R.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thinkest thou that God will be pleased with thee..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Thinkest thou that God will be pleased with thee... </head><p TEIform="p">Thinkest thou that God will be pleased with thee and unite with thy narrow
                            partialities in favor of this one and against another? They are all equally his, and thou
                            art no more so than the meanest.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. P.</byline><pb n="171" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1897. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is publisht
                            by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shakeis Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of
                            the religious views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> September. Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. Thermometer. Rain. 1896. 57.5
                                6.5 in. 1897. 61.6 1.75 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 88. above 0. Lowest " " " " 32 "
                                " Number of rainy days " " 5 " " clear " " " 17 " " cloudy " " " 8 Oct. 1897. A mean,
                                stingy man invited his pastor to dine with him. Altho he was wealthy, he was so
                                penurious that he furnisht a scanty table. The pastor was invited to ask a blessing
                                which he did, thus; "Lord, make us thankful for what we are about to receivefor these
                                greens without bacon, this bread without salt, this coffee without sugar, and after we
                                have received it give thy servant strength to get home in time for dinner." Our staple
                                cultivated crops are generally very poor. Potatoes have rotted sadly, we have not more
                                than one third of a crop. We shall have to be satisfied with two bushels a week if not
                                less, for family consumption until another crop is raised. Tomatoes are nearly a failure
                                throughout this region. Even the hardy cabbage is dwarft. Apples are but a medium crop;
                                yet for what we have we can pronounce the pastor's blessing. We have an excellent dairy
                                and a plenty of some kinds of fruit. The flood July 14th made bad work with our ponds by
                                washing in gravel and rubbish, a mass of it got washt into the aqueduct that drives the
                                laundry w.iterwheel so as to render the power inoperative. This has employed three hands
                                so far this week to remove the obstruction, which is not yet accomplisht. The spring
                                water-pipe from the artesian well refused to transmit water through it. By digging and
                                tapping the pipe we found that polypus and rust formed the obstruction. This we remedied
                                by the purchasing and laying nearly 800 ft. of 2 in. iron pipe at a cost of $120. With
                                all our earthly troubles we keep our hold on heaven. Elder Joseph Slingerland, of Union
                                Village, O. Sr. Angeline Cox, of Watervliet, N. Y. Sr. Marcia Bullard, and a young
                                Sister of Harvard, Mass, are spending a short season with us. Calvin O. Heed, South
                                Family. Oct. 1897. You will please excuse, Our telling the news, That fall has come And
                                the trees * begun To grow sere and brown With leaves falling down, But the apples are
                                ripe And free from blight, Tho potatoes are small We are saving them all And trust they
                                will last Till winter hss past. We're all busy as bees 'Mong the flowering trees, While
                                the laborers are few We have plen- <pb n="172" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> ty to do But the
                                Lord from on high All " needs will supply, So we've nothing to fear Thro' each swift
                                fleeting year. The spirit of enterprise still lives and goes marching on. The old
                                platform roof of the horse barn has been removed and a slate one substituted in its
                                stead the past .summer. Sweet corn drying is the chorus of our morning, noonday and
                                evening song. These fine sunny days are just the days needed for completing our autumn
                                harvest. Sister Elizabeth Sidle late of Sonyea has come to reside with us, happy is she
                                aad thankful are we to have it so. "All things come to those who wait." We were pleased
                                to meet our friend Sr. Angeline Cox of Watervliet who visited us in company with
                                Sisters, Marcia Bullard and Charlotte Tremper of Harvard, Mass. Genevieve DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/> Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> Oct. 1897. We record the date of Oct. 3rd as closing the season of active
                                growth in vegetation, the date of our first heavy frost. In our experimental plat this
                                season we tested eight new varieties of tomatoes and selected one that we will retain.
                                The New Stone is a very desirable variety. Smooth, deep red, solid, making it desirable
                                for canners and for marketing fresh. Of the older varieties we have found none that
                                could excel "Fordhook's First;" early, smooth and excellent quality. We have been
                                enjoying beautiful autumn weather and anticipate a continuance of the same. .The habit
                                of looking on the bright side of life is a very desirable one and can be cultivated as
                                well as any other faculty. We all know that in this world of ours there is enough to
                                depress and sadden the human soul and it needs many times a strong effort to penetrate
                                the cloud that overshadows the material life to realize that beyond there is a silver
                                lining. In the mad scramble for wealth which is being illustrated in the rush to the
                                Alaskan gold fields is portrayed the truth that "all is not gold that glitters," and to
                                be contented is to be happy. This does not imply that there should not be an effort made
                                for the betterment of our condition for in that struggle is realized our happiness. With
                                a joyful and thankful heart we recount the many blessings that have been vouchsafed to
                                our lot the past year as we follow it on its descending scale and realize that if we
                                advance in the knowledge of the truth it must be by progressing from the errors that
                                have been incidental to our environment. May we put on the whole armor and with a brave
                                heart and cheerful spirit meet the issues of life. Hamilton DeGraw.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Narcoossee, Florida" TEIform="index"/> Narcoossee, Fla.</head><p TEIform="p"> Oct. 1897. "With all thy gettings get understanding." It is very evident
                                that there is no liberty, only in the spirit of truth, and when the soul has that in
                                possession and is grounded immovably, it realizes a liberty in its manifestations that
                                is not obtained elsewhere. Unless God build the city they who labor,labor in vain. In
                                union with our parent Society we are striving to build up our little branch. If we have
                                truth for the basis of our structure we shall succeed. We expect trials on our march
                                through life, and the only way to meet them is with an unflinching purpose. During
                                September we had frequent showers, and on the 20th we had a great down pour,eight inches
                                in 24 hours. The rain did much damage. The land in Florida is so porous that after a
                                heavy shower, we can again begin to plough, in about ten hours. Commercial fertilizers
                                are of little value on pine lands, until they have been fertilized by the cattle. Our
                                pinery has been enlarged. The Sisters are engaged in the raising of tomatoes and have
                                over 200 plants set. <pb n="173" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> Our cassava which stands some
                                six feet high, is about ready to dig. This is a root that will be greatly prized in
                                Florida for its amount of starch and as food for the table. Andrew Barrett.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mount Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p"> North Family. Oct. 1897. Thrice told tales being tedious, I will not repeat
                                the harvest reports of grass and grain, but add to the rumor that potatoes are small in
                                size and scanty in quantity; however, our grand old hills are not small; they loom up
                                with more than their usual share of majesty in this clear, crisp atmosphere permeated
                                with gold enough to rejoice the monometalist and other monos whose hearts may the dear
                                God soften and widen! Beside her gold, October has brought us some delightful visitors.
                                You may have heard us speak of Agusta and Sophie, and last, but by no means least,
                                Sophie's horses. Such horses! No checks or blinders there, you may be sure. Sophie loves
                                her horses, and do they not love Sophie? Look in their faces for your answer, see their
                                great eyes soften and necks curve in caresses when their mistress nears them! Ah, it is
                                not the Undines alone to whom love gives a soul! This time our visitors brought with
                                them two other visitors; no less personages than Lotta and her mother. Who has not heard
                                of Lotta? Was she not a star in the sad, dangerous, dramatic world, who touched the
                                earth only to crush the flowers with which her path was strewn by enthusiastic crowds?
                                Somehow no shadow ever touched Lotta's name or fame; but if you noticed, it was always
                                "Lotta and her mother." That tells the whole story; as you would agree should you ever
                                have the fortune to meet this mother. Her age, nearly eighty, says the Christmas time of
                                life, but no, the brisk, bright, aromatic atmosphere about her declares it to be only
                                October. These visitors being invited to speak in one of our meetings, the little mother
                                rose. It was refreshing to hear her vigorous voice and see her earnest gestures. The
                                strongly markt face with character in every line, lighted, as she declared that the day
                                past among us would be a red letter day in all her after life. At the time of departure
                                it was rich to seethe alertness of the little mother, "Have we left anything behind us?"
                                she was heard to say, "any love that belongs to us." "Nay," said Sister Catherine, "you
                                have had a full share, but will not forget to send regular installments for the future."
                                It has been Lotta's mother and not Lotta, has it not? This will suit Lotta who loves her
                                mother as she deserves to be loved. The mother who has kept her pure and high where
                                thousands, with no such influence, have fallen, never in this world, to rise again.
                                Grace A. Brown.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Station, Conn.</head><p TEIform="p"> North Family Oct. 1897 Once more we greet you dear readers of The Manifesto
                                with love and goodwill to all. At present we are enjoying the presence and ministration
                                of our dearly loved Ministry. We have also been iavored with a visit from Sisters Marcia
                                Bullard and Charlotte Tremper of the Harvard Community, who brought much love from
                                gospel friends. Elder Henry Blinn from East Canterbury, N. H. spent a few hours with us,
                                and we hope an occurence of the same pleasant nature will not be far in the future.
                                Elder Joseph Slingerland from Union Village, Ohio also made a short call, and last but
                                not leMount Lebanon Levi Shaw of Mt. Lebanon, tarried with us over night. Now blessed it
                                is to be united to the pure in heart, whose lives are consecrated to God; who maintain a
                                clean separation from the spirit and elements of the world, for such is the life and
                                testimony of the gospel of Christ. Our Brethren are employed in perform- <pb n="174" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> ing the duties encumbent upon them at this season of the
                                year; some are harvesting the fruit of which we have an ample supply, while others are
                                preparing the soil and sowing crops for another year. With this comes the comforting
                                thought, that the ha nils that toil are consecrated to God's service. Edith E.
                            Shufelt.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Causes of headache" TEIform="index"/> CAUSES OF HEADACHE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The ordinary headache which is so extremely common among the
                                        inhabitants of our Atlantic seaboard towns is the outcome of conditions
                                        affecting the nerves through impoverisht blood containing poisonous matter
                                        absorbed from badly digested food. So-called liver torpidity and the catarrhal
                                        affections due to our changeable climate also aid in effecting its spread.
                                        Nervous exhaustion, due to irregular and fast living, plays an important part in
                                        its causation. Nervous strain, especially of the eyes, and inflamed tissues
                                        about the internal bones of the nose are special causes. Nerve irritation, which
                                        is but poorly understood by the general reader, is a prolific cause of so-called
                                        nervous headache. 1 know of no more dangerous practice than to treat headache
                                        pain blindly with drugs. 4 Of course, outdoor exercise is the best possible
                                        thing for permanent cure. It is very easy to relieve most forms of headache by
                                        means of the coal-tar derivatives, of which so many are in the drug market.
                                        These form the basis of the many headache cures found on the druggists' shelves.
                                        Their use is not entirely without danger, for they are powerful heart
                                        depressants if taken in doses of any considerable size.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>Ladies' Home
                                    Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Expression of the face" TEIform="index"/> THE EXPRESSION OF THE FACE.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The expression of the face is continually changing. No
                                        artist, no camera can catch this changing, fleeting, evanescent expression. When
                                        you look in the glass, the very desire to find out how you look is depicted on
                                        your face. The more you strive, the more the intent is intensified, and such an
                                        expression is not natural to your face. How often do we look at a photograph and
                                        find only disappointment in it? Why is this? The camera depicts the sitter just
                                        as he is at the moment the picture is taken, but very seldom can the instrument
                                        catch and record that subtle thing called "natural expression," because few
                                        persons are natural when seated before the camera. Well, what of all this?
                                        simply this. If you are noble, loving and true, such virtues will light up your
                                        face: if you are sordid, mean and selfish, your face proclaims it to the world.
                                        Anything in your life that is active for good or evil will impress itself upon
                                        your personal appearance. Pride, scorn, hate and lust write themselves indelibly
                                        in the physiognomy, when such ignoble qualities rule the life and have become
                                        habitual to the countenance, and the features themselves become permanently
                                        changed to accord with the expressions.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal of medicine and science" TEIform="index"/> [Extract from
                                        an editorial in the Journal of Medicine and Science.]</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to eat a banana" TEIform="index"/> HOW TO EAT A BANANA</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The banana yields more food to the acre than any other
                                        plant, and yet it disagrees with no end of Northern stomachs. This is because we
                                        eat it the wrong way. But the wife of a missionary to the tropics tells the glad
                                        tidings from heathen shores of how to eat a banana. When you have stript off the
                                        willing rind, just scrape off the stringy and hairy coat that lies beneath the
                                        rind, and you may eat your banana without tasting it all the rest of the day. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Fruitman's guide" TEIform="index"/>Fruitman's Guide.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Many years ago farmers of Australia imported bumble-bees..." TEIform="index"/> Many years ago farmers of Australia imported bumble-bees... </head><p TEIform="p"> Many years ago the farmers of Australia imported bumble-bees from England and
                            set them free in their clover fields. These bees cost the farmers about fifty cents each,
                            but they were worth all that was paid for them.</p><pb n="175" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Please write to the ''Chemical Division of the Department of Agriculture''..." TEIform="index"/> Please write to the ''Chemical Division of the Department of
                            Agriculture''... </head><p TEIform="p"> Please write to the "Chemical Division of the Department of Agriculture," a
                            concise statement of what you may know about the adulteration of foods and drugs; presenting
                            the facts which can be substantiated if necessary, and not theories.A. J. Weddeebukh,
                            Special Agent.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two little boys, one seven years and the other nine..." TEIform="index"/> Two
                            little boys, one seven years and the other nine... </head><p TEIform="p"> Henderson, Ky.Two little boys, one seven years and the other nine attempted to
                            take away some honey from wild bees, when the bees s warmed over their bodies. The youngest
                            died before he reacht home and the oldest is not expected to live.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A man in Burlington, Iowa has subsisted on milk only, for twenty-five years..." TEIform="index"/> A man in Burlington, Iowa has subsisted on milk only, for twenty-five
                            years... </head><p TEIform="p"> A man in Burlington, Iowa has subsisted on milk only, for twenty-five years.
                            When an infant he accidentally drank some lye and since that date has been unable to take
                            any solid food into the stomach. He weighs one hundred and forty pounds and is strong and
                            vigorous.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Received from a lady friend, a very beautiful specimen..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Received from a lady friend, a very beautiful specimen... </head><p TEIform="p"> Received from a lady friend, a very beautiful specimen of variegated clay from
                            Gay Head, on the coast of Massachusetts</p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The pamphlets--''A Christian Community''..." TEIform="index"/> The
                            pamphlets--''A Christian Community''... </head><p TEIform="p"> The pamphlets--"A Christian Community" and "Brief Exposition" will be sent to
                            any Believers for free distribution. Copies of the "Beautiful City" will also be sent for
                            free distribution. Address The Manifesto, East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thanksgiving hymn" TEIform="index"/> THANKSGIVING HYMN.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> [Contributed by Amelia Tait.] Now, Father, the harvest is ended,
                                    Ere twilight has curtained the sun, With hearts overflowing with gladness, We thank
                                    Thee for what Thou hast done We thank Thee not only, great Giver, For harvests of
                                    wheat and of corn; We thank Thee for Thy daily mercies And works Thou renewest each
                                    morn. "Thou crownest the year with goodness;' Thou blesseth our lives with Thy care,
                                    The earth is too small for Thy kindness, Thy mercies are strewed everywhere. Thou
                                    filleth the earth with Thy sunshine, Thou sendeth the dews and the rains, Thou
                                    giveth us all that is needful To ripen the fruits and the grains. Oh, Shepherd! our
                                    lives Thou protecteth, Each day thou hast guided our feet, Thy wonders as thickly
                                    are scattered As sprays in the sheaves of the wheat. We never can measure Thy
                                    greatness, So vast is Thy power and might, Then teach us, our Father, all blessings,
                                    To use for Thy praise and the right! </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Josiah Edgerly, was a Trustee or Deacon in the Society..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Josiah Edgerly, was a Trustee or Deacon in the Society... </head><p TEIform="p">Josiah Edgekly, was a Trustee or Deacon in the Society at Canterbury, in 1792. As
                            there were no roads for carriages, traveling was generally done on horseback. The Deacon had
                            been abroad on business and was returning to his home. A young man met him and knowing that
                            lie was a Shaker, challenged Josiah to fight. The Deacon dismounted, hitcht his horse, and
                            catching the young fellow as best he ould he gave him a severe ducking in some water by the
                            side of the road. Do you call this fighting, said Josiah, as he continued the ducking, till
                            the young man promist to use better manners.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths.</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Foster, Maria" TEIform="index"/>Maria Foster </head><p TEIform="p"> Maria Foster, at Harvard, Mass. Sept. 9, 1897. Age 75 years 4 mo. and 26
                                dajs. Sister Maria was born in Concord, Mass., and was placed under the care of the
                                Community when at the age of seven years. When she arrived at the age when she could
                                understanding^ choose for herself, she chose to remain where she had spent her youthful
                                days, therefore becoming a faithful and trusted Christian. She has held many important
                                offices of trust and responsibility. At her death she had been twenty-two years an
                                associate in the min-' isterial order. At one time she had a large class of girls under
                                her charge and taught the public school of the Society for sixteen years. She will be
                                greatly missed by her associates.</p><pb n="176" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers.</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Outlook" TEIform="index"/>The Outlook </head><p TEIform="p">Among the specially noteworthy contents of the Magazine Number of The Outlook
                                may be named; Profes&amp;or Luneia nils beautifully illustrated article on Modem
                                Home; another installment i i Mr. initial IViiCr rthy's The Story of Gladstone's lite,
                                ^ith seventeen pictures, some of exceptional interest; an account of the founding of The
                                Firat Working Girls' Club, by the founder, the Honorable Maude Stanley; an illustrated
                                article on The Real Isaiah, by Clifton H. Levy, which describes the extremely
                                interesting work being done at John Hopkins on the famous Polychrome Bible; a charming
                                out of doors love story by Priseilld Leonard called A Day at Lone Island; an article by
                                Bishop Hunting-ton on The Imitation of Christone of a series called Aids to Devotion. -
                                The history of the week is given as usual succinctly and broadly; and there are other
                                articles than those mentioned, both with pictures and without the in, departments of
                                reviews, religious news, stories for little people, etc., etc. [$3 a year. The Outlook
                                Company, 13 A stor Place, Sew York.] </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ladies' home journal" TEIform="index"/>The Ladies' Home Journal </head><p TEIform="p">The first and only pictures Mrs. McKinley has had taken in ten years will
                                appear in the October number of The Ladies' Home Journal. They form part of a series of
                                new and unpublisht photographs of the new occupants of the White House. Mrs. McKinley
                                wore for her picture her inaugural ball dress of silver and white brocade, at the
                                special request of the President, who thought it particularly becoming. The excellent
                                portrait of Mr. McKinley in his office was taken in June. The other pictures in the
                                series show the many changes in the arrangements and furnishings of the rooms and
                                grounds, made by the President and Mrs .McKinley. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Frank Leslie's popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Frank Leslie's Popular
                                Monthly </head><p TEIform="p">The Hawaiian Islands are well described and well illustrated in an article by
                                George H. Johnson in Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly for October. It gives in an
                                attractive manner the history and' customs of the people of this future territory of the
                                United States. In the same magazine is an interesting andvalii able historical paper on
                                The Landmarks and Memories of the Hackensack Valley, by John P. Ritter: in which are
                                recalled, with photographic views, many of the stirring events of the Revolution which
                                occurred in the lower part of New York State, including the trial of Major Andre. Some
                                Kentucky Women, is a brief paper on the belles of the Blue Grass, made particularly
                                attractive by numerous portraits of beautiful women. George Willis Bardwell contributes
                                a pleasing sketch of the Breton peasants, which is illustrated by beautiful
                                reproductions of paintings by Henry Mosler. Another article which contains entertaining
                                reading as well as important information is Salmon-fishing on the Columbia, by Joseph
                                Williams Collins; giving a graphic picture of the work and methods of those engaged in
                                the securing and canning of salmon. The college article this month, the twelfth in the
                                series, describes that great western institution, the Leland Stanford Junior University,
                                and is written by O. L. Elliot. Like the preceeding papers it is pi-ofusely illustiated
                                with portraits and views. Other articles in this * number are; The Island of Marcken,
                                Old Coaching Inns, Some Paintings "by Modern Artists, The Last Duel in the Place Royale;
                                there are a number of short stories, the continuation of the serial, a department for
                                boys and girls, a poem by Louise Chandler Moulton, and an illustrated Hallowe'en poem by
                                Minna Irving.Frank Leslie's Publishing House, New York.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to grow flowers" TEIform="index"/>How To Grow Flowers </head><p TEIform="p">How To Grow Flowers for October furnishes a feast of good things for the
                                lovers of flowers. This is the season to plant bulbs for winter and spring flowering,
                                and the current" number of How To Grow Flowers gives full cultural directions for this
                                purpose. "House culture of The Rose," is begun in this number, as is also an interesting
                                floral story, "Outside the Altar Bail." In addition there are installments of "Fall work
                                in the Flower Garden," "Bulb Growing in Holland," and "The Rose." All the usual
                                departments are filled with seasonable advice.How To Grow Flowers, Springfield, Ohio.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word and works" TEIform="index"/>Word and Works </head><p TEIform="p">Word and Works for October has a chapter on the Sun, Moon and Planets, which
                                will afford a fund of information to the careful student. Also a chapter on Star Study,
                                for October, so that any one can study the heavens while he is busily engaged with
                                duties on the earth. Word and Works is by no means confined to star gazing. In this
                                number will be found a long chapter on Single Tax, and the writer promises that in his
                                next article he will point out the theory of Single Tax and what it will do when in
                                operation, and by reading Single Tax ]So. 2 which will be found on another page of this
                                same paper, the whole story will be solved. In the Forecasts, for October the reader
                                will have a chance to note what changes to expect and to prepare himself accordingly.
                                The Department of Home Sweet Home, affords abundant information for doing good. Progress
                                in Science, abounds in useful information while the Query Corner, is full of new life.
                                Other good things may be found in this same number, as the fortunate possessor will be
                                sure to learn.Word and Works Pub. Co. 2201 Locust St., St. Louis, Mo. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moral aspects of the higher criticism" TEIform="index"/> The Moral
                                Aspects of the Higher Criticism </head><p TEIform="p"> The Moral Aspects of the Higher Criticism by H. L. Hastings. The writer of
                                this little work says,"one of the settled conclusions of the leading Higher Critics of
                                our day is, that the Scriptures of the old and new Covenant are not Scriptures of J
                                Truth." Mr. Hastings does not accept this statement but in expressing his own mind<pb n="176a" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> goes onlo say,"Much of the higherCi itieism of the
                                present (hiy .shows the inac :uraey of the critics and their very supei liciai
                                aequainttanee with the books they comment upon. The fact is a plain man who read* nnd
                                understands his English Bible is likely to !) better informed on many points than a
                                scholar with a head full of Hebrew roots, who neglects an.I discredits the writings
                                which he processes to study and expound." II. L. Hastings, No. 47 Cornhill, Boston,
                                Mass. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/> The
                                Phrenological Journal and Science of Health </head><p TEIform="p"> The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health f &gt;r Octouer has an
                                illn.-tr;;t d article by Jessie A. Fowler an i oi' no 1,' - a personage than the
                                president oi the Briti.-h A a.-o'eiation for the Advancement of ScienceSir John Evans.
                                Piofessor Sizer lias written upon a very interesting subject,Brain, Mind, Thought, Soul
                                and readers ol the Journal will stuiv it with much care, as it is an answer to this
                                question, Does Phrenology teach Materialism? Phrenotypes have reacht No. lii.in.I this
                                one by H. S. Dray ton, M. L&gt;. is a vindication of "Poe." Klondikers will be
                                interested to real about the Alaskan Natives and to see the ueairiful poi ti ait of
                                their next . io.&gt;r n yighoor. Then follows a iJiMivr o:\ K luxation, l&gt;y
                                Miss S. Dexter and I hen :.n ilai tinted article on "People of Note." A Portrait of
                                Father K:),'i:)p, "the genuine old priest whose water euie, or grass cure made him
                                famous," will be stu lied with interest while they wonder at the "N.-w Cure System." The
                                ^Esthetic Force of A m:;ti veness by B. Y. Lain. A Snap Shot at the T :n\. K.s^Kmtum and
                                then The Science of Health. Children Precious and Promising, is always interesting, uml
                                "the best mother is r-he. who studies the peculiar character of each child and acts with
                                well instructs 1 ju ljm;y.it, upon the knowledge so obtained."Fowler &amp; Wells Co.
                                27 East 21st St. New York, N. Y.</p></div3></div2>
                    <!--
SHAKER   THEOLOGY.
A Book of 320 pages.    It contains not
only the Shaker's Faith but explains
Scripture Metaphor.    By H. L. Eads.
Address IT. C. Blinn, East Canterbury,
N.   H.
To
those
AGENTS WANTED.
that are Willing to work I can give steady
employment. The work is light and easy.
Write me for terms.
C. L. Yates. (Nurseryman,)
Rochester, N. Y.
A  PRIVMount LebanonL
For Girls will be opened, at
Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
Oot. 1, Mount Lebanoness        El dress Anna White,
Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y.
Instructions in English and the Industrial Branches, board, etc., two hundred
dollars a year, consisting of two terms of
twenty weeks each.    Fifty dollars to be
paid at beginning and fifty dollars at close
of each term.
Competent and experienced instructors
at head of each department.
Location among the beautiful Berkshire
Hills.
Hygienic condition perfect, and all
healthful recreation encouraged.
Careful attenti n given to moral as well
as mental and physic il (level opine'it.
Here are taught hand and m u-hine sewing, plain and fancy knitting.    With help
of instructors each girl will learn to keep
her wardrobe in repair.      Younger girls
will assist in dining-room, duties about
the house, and light ironing;  larger ones
in general house-work; strength and
adaptability being duly considered.
Those who remain long enough will
have unequalled opportunities to become
proficient in the management of households where order, cleanliness and the
best methods are considered of first importance.
No tiniform dress required.    Simplicity
in make and durability in mat. rial the
chief requisite.    All articles to be laundered should be particularly plain and
simple.    No jewelry allowed.
E
is an illustrated Monthly, now only 50 cts.
per year, devoted to PHRENOLOGY,
PHYSIOGNOMY,  HEALTH,   MEDICAL
& SOCIAL EEIOEM.
Would you like a copy?
Send 5 cts. for Sample to Prof. Haddock,
Phrenologist, 1016 Market St.,
San Francisco, CaJ.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
Royal makes the food pure,
wholesome and delicious.
SO  YEARS'
EXPERIENCE.
*   TRADE   MARKS,
DESIGNS,
COPYRIGHTS   &c.
Anyone sending a sketch and description may
quickly ascertain, free, whether an invention is
probably patentable. Communications strictly
confidential. Oldest agency for securing patents
in America.    We have  a Washington office.
Patents taken through, Munn & Co. receive
special notice in the
SCIENTIFIC  AMERICAN,
beautifully illustrated, largest circulation of
any scientific journal, weekly, terms $3.00 a year;
$1.50 six months. Specimen copies and HAND
Book on Patents sent free.   Address
MUNN   &   CO.,
POWDER
Absolutely Pure
ROYAL BAKINO POWDER CO., NEW YORK.
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY11
AND  THE
"Appearing of Christ,"
is the title  of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
HOLLISTER Of MT. LEBANON, ft. Y.
The many at the present time who are
interested in the fulfillment of prophecy,
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
FREE   EDUCATION.
An education at Harvard, Yale, or any other
college or institution of learning in the United
States, or in the New England Conservatory
of Music, can be secured by any young man
or woman who is in earnest. Write for particulars quickly.             JAMES D. BALL,
36 Bromfleld Street, Boston, Mass.
THE MANIFESTO
is the only   periodical tliat is published by
the   United Society of Believers.   It illustrates the order of
Christian-   coivcvLTnsnsM:,
and publishes peace on earth, and to all men
good-will.
A copy will be sent on receipt of a postal
card.            Address,      Henry C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
WONDERFUL strange REVELATIQE
EXFiL.^iisriisrG
DANIEL'S & STJOHN'S
FHOFHECIES.
48 page pamphlet.    Price 10 cts.
13 for $1.00.
Address,   H. B. Beak, Preston, Ohio
THE SHAKER D07EKAHT.
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES  and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION     AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all inquiring  minds.    Price 5  cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>