<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1706" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">23</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">17</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">06</biblScope><date value="18870601" TEIform="date">June 1887</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="17" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="06" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
<pb id="p1"/>
JUNE.
THE
     MANIFESTO
Published by the United Societies,
"Every plant which my heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted
up."- -Matt,  xv.,  13.
Canterbury, N. H.
1887,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
THE  MANIFESTO.
CONTENTS.
The Gospel Testimony, No. 15,
Shaker Pronunciamento,
Letter,- -D. Orcutt,
In Memory of Johanna Bloomberg,
Address to Young Friends,
Morning Thought,
The New "Work,
Testimony of Lucy Wright,
How to make the. world bright,
Letter,- -A. Lewis,
A Peril to our Homes,
Sowing and Reaping,
Cast not dirt into the well,
Ill-Temper,     ....
Christ the Light,
Notes,- -Light,
Sanitary,- -Sore Eyes,
Christian Communism, Xo. 3,
Success,    Good and Bad Habits,
Gone,        Living on Vegetables,
Music,- -Redemption's Song,   Books & Papers,
Kind Words,
Deaths,           ....
121
123
124
125
130
131
133
136
137
138
140
141'
142
143
144
$/5KAMQNTH   and BOARD Guaranteed
[J%- - 3 Young Men or Ladies in each  country,
and highest commission paid (often $150
a'month)    MEW  ROOK, already  on
TIDAL WAVE flf-^Sp'TJT^ KFT*l"P T? - -i
of success ub- -  W wi^JJ- -jJi.5a
in North and South. America, at the Ice-Bound
Poles, over the lands of the Midnight Sun, under the
Equator, through the Dark Continent, among the Old
Temples of India, in the Flowery Kingdoms of China
and Japan, amid the ruins of Incas, Aztecs and Znni, within Canons, Cliff Building*, and Gardens of
the Gods, on the Isles of the Sea, and in all parts of
the glohe. 300 engravings, Low Price. Quick Sales.
Send for Circular, p, W. Ziegler, & Co,, 720 Chestnut St, Philadelphia, Pa,
EBSTER'S
Ilnatriigei Dictionary,
A DICTIONARY,
118,000 Words, 3000 Engravings, a
GAZETTEER OF THE WORLD,
of 25,000 Titles, and a
BIOGRAPHICAL DICTIONARY,
of nearly 10,000 Noted Persons,
ALL IN ONE BOOK.
Contains 3000 more Words and nearly 2000 more
Illustrations than any other American Dictionary.
G. k C. MERRIAM & CO., Pub'rs, Springfield, Mass.
After Forty years'
experience in the
preparation of more
than One Hundred
Thousand applications for patents in
the United States and Foreign countries, the publishers of the Scientific
A.merican continue to act as solicitors
for patents, caveats, trade-marks, copy- rights, etc., for the United States, and
to obtain patents in Canada, England, France,
Germany, and all other countries Their experience is unequaled and their facilities are unsurpassed.
Drawings and specifications prepared and filed
in the Patent Office on short notice. Terms very
reasonable. No charge for examination of models
or drawings.    Advice by mail tree
Patents obtained through MnnnA Co. are noticed
inthe SCIENTIFIC AMERICAN,which has
the largest circulation and is the most influential
newspaper of its kind published in the world.
The advantages of such a notice every patentee
understands.
This large and splendidly illustrated newspaper
is published WEEKLY nt $3.00 a year, and is
admitted to be the best paper devoted to science,
mechanics, inventions, engineering works, and
other departments of industrial progress, published in any country. It contains the names of
all patentees and title of every invention patented
each week. Try it four months for one dollar.
Sold by a,U newsdealers.
If you have an invention  to  patent write to
Munn & Co., publishers of Scientific American,
S61 Broadway, New York.
Handbook about patents mailed tree.
MEDAL   MACHINES.
HEW 70SE STATE AGEICffLTUBAL WOSES,
1st. Premiums at all Competitive  Trials
Railway, Chain and levcrHone Powera, Threshers and Cleaners, Threshers
 Shakers, Clover Hullers, feed Cutters, "Wheel Howe Rakes, Morse Pitchforks, Shing-le Machines, Straw Preserving- XSytt Threshers, Portable ftleam-Eng-ines, Cider and Wine Mills and Presses,
Dog- and Pony Powers, Disc Harrow*
& Springy Tooth   Marrow*.     "Robinson's Hay Press, of four sizes- Will
work as easy with one horse, as
others with two. Made with Steel
Gearing which can not be broken."
WHEELER & MELICK Co.,
Send stamp for Circular and report of Centennial
trial.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Vol. XVII.
JUNE,  1887.
No. 6. --><pb n="121" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the elders, William Lee and James Whittaker no. 15" TEIform="index"/> The Gospel Testimony of Mother Ann Lee and the Elders, William Lee and James Whittaker,
                            No. 15.</head><p TEIform="p"> Published expressly for the several Communities of Believers in 1S1G. Re-written by Henry C.
                            Blinn. Mother Ann and the Elders visit the towns of Norton, Stonington, Preston and other
                            places. While the Believers in Harvard were suffering at the bauds of cruel persecutors,
                            Mother Ann and the Elders were holding religious services in Woburn. After closing the
                            meetings in this place, they pass on to the town of Norton, and make their home with William
                            Morey about one week. Their next visit is with Morrell Baker of Rehoboth, where they remain
                            over the Sabbath, and then return to Norton. They remain in this vicinity some three weeks.
                            Meetings are held, the several families of Believers are visited and the testimony of life
                            and peace is presented to the world. From Norton they pass on to Stonington, Ct., and dwell
                            at the house of Joshua Birch. For three weeks they held meetings and preached, prayed and
                            sung, and conversed upon gospel truths with all who came to see them. In this work they were
                            liberally aided by the several families of Believers. The gospel of Jesus Christ was the
                            subject upon which they preached, by which they could show that the present manifestation of
                            the work of God required1 an honest confession of sin, and then power to forsake it. Those
                            who would follow Christ in the regeneration, must take up a full cross against the lusts of
                            the flesh, and the pride of this life. To some of the people this doctrinewas very
                            distasteful, especially to that class that wished to be Christians without bearing the cross
                            of Christ. Many were so bound down by old traditions that they could not endure to have
                            their false foundations uncovered, nor to have their sins exposed before the light of gospel
                            truth. In this the words of the Apostle become verified. "All that will live godly in Christ
                            Jesus shall suffer persecution." Not only did the Believers suffer from cruel persecutions,
                            but were often disturbed by busy-bodies and mischiefmakers. Simeon Brown of Stonington, the
                            son of a Baptist minister, was one of the last class. In company with others, he would visit
                            the place of worship and threaten and revile the worshipers. One of the company by the<pb n="122" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>name of Minor was very free with his threatening language, and ordered
                            the Believers to leave the town within twenty-four hours, or he would not be responsible for
                            the consequences. As the Believers had already arranged tto leave the town of Stonington on
                            Friday, the threats did not surprise them nor produce much fear. Near the close of the month
                            of Oct. 1782, Mother Ann and the Elders reached Preston, and wrere entertained at the home
                            of Elias Brown. The Elders were treated with marked consideration and kindness. - - From
                            this place they pass to the town of Windham, and by request, call at the residence of a
                            friend by the name of Abbey. Although he was not a believer in the faith preached by the
                            Elders, he said his house was open, and gave them a most cordial welcome. This manifestation
                            of peculiar kindness was so different from the treatment which they had received in some
                            places that the Elders felt as did Jesus on his visit to Zacheus. "This day has salvation
                            come to this house. " Public worship was held on the Sabbath before a large assembly, and
                            the gospel preached with great plainness, and the necessity of confessing and forsaking all
                            sin was clearly presented. The impossibility of following Christ without a full and final
                            cross against the life of generation was declared with such plainness that the congregation
                            gave marked attention. Several accepted the faith and became members of the church. Quite a
                            number of the Believers who had come to see Mother Ann and the Elders, now returned to their
                            own homes. The meetings at this place were closed and the Elders continue their journey to
                            Stafford, and call at the house of Ezekiel Slate, who with all his family, had at an earlier
                            date, embraced the testimony. A few days were spent in teaching and encouraging the
                            Believers, but a class of malicious characters, from the town of Somers, learned of their
                            presence and formed a combination to take them by force, while passing through Somers to the
                            home of David Meacham in Enfield, Ct. David, however, learned of the design of this mob
                            violence and informed the Elders of the fact. Upon further consideration, Mother Ann and the
                            Elders concluded to travel as they had arranged, and accept the consequences. Calvin Harlow
                            and David Meacham were on horseback, while Mother Ann, Mary Partingtcn and a brother were in
                            a carriage. They passed through Somers without being molested, but were pursued by some
                            thirty men on horseback. This company arrived at the home of David Meacham soon after the
                            Believers had entered the dwelling. Captain Kibbee was their recognized leader. As might be
                            expected of a body of riotous characters, they soon broke into the house and a reckless,
                            savage violence marked all their actions. They demanded the .presence of Mother Ann, but the
                            family paid no attention to their threats. Supposing that Mother Ann was in an upper
                            chamber, they began to force their way by beating the Brethren and Sisters and dragging them
                            in the most cruel and shameful manner from the house. Mary Partington was forcibly carried
                            out and placed upon a horse, in front of one of the men. His attempt to carry<pb n="123" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> her away, however, did not succeed. The man was unhorsed and Mary was again
                            allowed to return to the house. Iu this affray David Meaeham was knocked down aud severely
                            wounded. While the company were bewildered in this confusion, Mother Ann passed to an upper
                            room without harm. With the screaming and crying and praying the captain of the mob became
                            frustrated and instead of reaching the upper rooms, he and his party left the house. John
                            Booth, a constable of the town of Enfield now appeared and commanded the peace. At the same
                            time he threatened the mob with the severity of the law for their riotous conduct. As these
                            reckless characters were acting without law, they would not listen to the officer and in
                            turn threatened to burn the house before morning. The constable was so offended at this
                            treatment that he came the next morning with other officers and requested information of the
                            violence and also the names of the rioters. In a few days they were summoned before the
                            court at Hartford, Ct., and required to settle the matter with David Meaeham, or stand trial
                            and suffer the penalty of the law. The leaders soon called upon David to learn upon what
                            conditions he would settle the case. David replied,- -" I do not want your money, nor do I
                            wish to see you in prison ; but if you will make a public confession of your conduct in your
                            own church, according to the requirements of your own religion, I will be satisfied."
                            Although the leading rioters were professors of religion, and members in good standing in
                            the church, these terms were quite too humiliating to their pride. They preferred to stand
                            trial and were fined by the court, in a sum proportioned, as the judges supposed, to the
                            enormity of the crime. One of the company, subsequently, came to the Believers and made
                            confession of his wicked conduct and asked their forgiveness. This was the last act of the
                            mobs and of the riotous proceedings against the Believers in the state of Conn. Elder
                            William Lee and Elder James Whittaker did not arrive till after the mob had dispersed. The
                            Believers remained with David a few days aud then crossed the Connecticut river at New
                            Providence and tarried four days with Joseph Bennett. Public service was held on the Sabbath
                            and largely attended. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker's pronunciamento" TEIform="index"/> A SHAKER'S PRONUNCIAMENTO
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We, as Christian Communists and followers of the
                                    heaven-inspired Teacher- -, Jesus the Christ, our Elder Brother, make appeal that
                                    the heaven-born principles embodied in his beautiful evangel, testimony and life may
                                    be restored ; that genuine, practical and pentecostal Christianity may again
                                    prevail. Instead of fallowing our Great Exemplar in the regeneration, by a life of
                                    virgin purity and innocence, and an equal distribution in all temporal goods, we
                                    find you still on the selfish, Adamic plane- -in the line of generation- -fulfilling
                                    the lusts of the flesh. How demoralizing ! how inconsistent ! When the kingdom of
                                    God was first introduced, in all its purity and pristine glory, for many years was
                                    its influence felt for good, Avas appreciated and ac-<pb n="124" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>
                                    knowledged by the people of that day ; since which it has been enshrouded in
                                    Anti-Christian darkness, its professed adherents palming off upon the human family a
                                    counterfeit; hence the alarming and distracted condition of society, in all its
                                    phases, throughout our land and the world, at the present age. As a people, we are
                                    the only true witnesses of practical Christianity as taught and promulgated by its
                                    God-Appointed Founder; hence the inspiration of the hour constrains us to sound the
                                    tocsin of alarm, and send forth this appeal for help to sustain the structure- -in
                                    other words, the cause for the redemption of the human fanrly. In view of what is
                                    already set forth, we beg of you, dear friends, one and all, to ponder well the
                                    signs of the times, to consider most deeply and solemnly whether this call is not
                                    worthy your most candid and immediate attention and special interest. The momentous
                                    day of the Lord is upon us, when the vail ts to 1"- -e be MOVED FROM ALL FACES. See
                                    Isaiah XXV., 7- -1). All things considered, let us all most devoutly and earnestly
                                    desire a fresh baptism of the Infinite Spirit from on high, that we may all heed the
                                    responsibilities resting upon us, remembering that the kingdom of heaven suffereth
                                    violence, and the violent taketh it by force. From the conservatism of the present
                                    day, we find it extremely difficult for truth to have its sway. We could go into
                                    long and labored arguments to convince you that our life and testimony, as embodied
                                    in the beautiful Evangel of Jesus, is the only panacea for all the ills of suffering
                                    humanity. At this writing we do not deem it wise to elaborate in this direction.
                                    Rest assured, dear friends, the foregoing hints are the promptings of a heart
                                    overflowing with love and Christian friendship to one and all. May you awake,
                                    without delay, to the importance of what is here presented, lest the very stones in
                                    your streets testify against you, in behalf of the truth, to your shame and
                                    everlasting disgrace. I wish to add that what is here written has been offered for
                                    publication to the so-called Christian and secular press, and beeu refused. How
                                    menial, low and servile has the press become ! Alas, how lamentable the moral
                                    cowardice of the age ! Ciiakles Clapp. Union I lUage, Ohio. From </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="World's advance thought" TEIform="index"/>World's Advance- Thought. </bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear children: Hold fast that which is good..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Dear children: Hold fast that which is good...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield 1887" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn. 1887.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Deak Children :- -" Hold fast that which is good " To be good is to be happy. Do not, after
                            making mistakes, give up striving to do right. Begin every morning and see how much better
                            you can do each day. If you stop striving for one moment, you do not stand still, you fall
                            back. It is the patient, constant toilers that gain and keep the prize. " Never despair, "
                            is an excellent and useful maxim. Grow despondent never, for your "star of hope" shines
                            ever. If you fail, try again. u Those who win are those who try. " "Little by little the
                            wrong gives way, little by little the right has sway. " Don't stop to be discouraged when
                            trials come. They show what you are worth. All truly noble characters have been tried. Would
                            you shine with heavenly brightness in God's kingdom? Then " think it not strange concerning
                            the liery trial that is to try you, but rejoice that you are counted worthy to suffer."<pb n="125" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>None are made pure without the trial. First the trial, then the
                            blessing. You wonder why there must be so many trials. They are all necessary for your
                            spiritual growth. No portion of them could be spared. For the gold to appear, the dross must
                            be consumed. Remembering the Savior's trials, sufferings, charity, and pity, nothing right
                            should be too hard for you to bear, and wrong should be borne with meekness and patience,
                            even as He bore it. He sends strength for every trial, and gives precious comfort and help.
                            Look to Him for your sustaining and your guidance. His example should be your standard. His
                            teachings should lead you from the wrong ever into the right. Your Brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute to the memory of Sister Johanna Bloomberg" TEIform="index"/> A Tribute to the Memory
                            of Sister Johanna Bloomberg.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnston, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY JOHNSTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Gone to thy rest, O dear worthy Sister, Gone to the land of thy bright happy home, Where
                            joys evermore await thy pure spirit, And the message of comfort, my servant, well done.
                            Gone, gone, fair jewel at noon of life's journey, In the beauty and glory and strength of
                            thy prime; O ! how can we spare thee dear gentle Sister, From the fort of our Zion, with thy
                            virtues sublime. O ! truly we need thy bright presence to-day, To aid against the spirit
                            that error maintains; To hold forth the banner of the pure gospel way, For which thy example
                            did nobly sustain. Deep on (he pages of memory i.re written, The halcyon daj-s with thy
                            comrades below, Thy deeds of true merit to the Lord freely given, Are left as the seeds that
                            will flourish and grow. Tho' marked the simplicity of the obsequies, No less do we prize the
                            fair jewel of worth, And offer this, our simple tribute of praise, As token of love from
                            gospel kindred of earth. Our spirits are sad while 'neath the chastening Yet, why should we
                            mourn at thy happy release, For a myriad throng are chanting sweet pcans, Which welcome the
                            victor to blight realms of peace. Pleasant Hill, Ky</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Addressed to my young friends..." TEIform="index"/>Addressed to my young friends...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Chandler, Olive F." TEIform="persName"/>OLIVE F. CHANDLER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Addressed to my Young Friends, soliciting more earnest effort io deep thought and
                            self-knowledge. 0 walk upright, make straight thy paths, Know, angel light does scan each
                            thought; And cherish not the slightest hate, Let each desire to truth be brought. O garner
                            Love, one thread each day, Make warp and woof of finest peace ; Let every thread be straight
                            and smooth, That bitterness and strife shall cease. Thus early learn your thoughts to train,
                            This is a science grand and vast; And let not error's veil deceive Nor ignorance's pall thy
                            mind o'ercast. Search deep within thyself to scan And analyze the powers within ; Each
                            motive view with critic's eye, Have not a touch or stain of sin. .Harvard, Mass. T</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Morning thought" TEIform="index"/> MORNING THOUGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, Hannah E." TEIform="persName"/>HANNAH E. WILSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What is life?- -'Tis worth so little If the earth we only see; In this sphere our days are
                            numbered, " Over there, " no end shall be. Let us daily work with patience, Wisely choose
                            the seeds we sow; That the harvest may be joyous Of our sowing here below. For we all are
                            passing onward, Sure not of another day ; Let us well perform our mission While in earthly
                            life we stay. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New work" TEIform="index"/> THE NEW WORK.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Joseph H." TEIform="persName"/> JOSEPH H. WOODS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The Lord hath promised to create a new heavens and a new earth, wherein dwelleth
                            righteousness, and that the former shall not be remembered no <pb n="126" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>come into
                            mind, consequently, all the works of the old heavens and earth are of necessity excluded
                            from the new. The Apostle Peter says, by the word of God, Gen. i. The heavens were of old
                            and the earth standing out of the water and in the water whereby the world that then was,
                            perished, being'overflowed with water ; but the heavens and earth which are now, are
                            reserved unto fire against the day of judgment, and perdition of ungodly men. That day of
                            the Lord, lie says, shall come as a thief in the night, synonymous with the words of Jesus.
                            Behold I come as a thief in the night, in which the heavens shall pass away with a great
                            noise and the elements shall melt with fervent heat, the earth also and the works therein
                            shall be burnt up. We, according to this promise, look for a new heavens and a new earth
                            wherein dwelleth righteousness. The Revelator saw a new heavens and a now earth, for the
                            first heavens and the first earth were passed away, and there was no more sea and He that
                            sat upon the Throne said, "Behold I make all things new." No more sea, no place in the new
                            heavens and new earth for the works of generation ; the works of the first Adam, the old
                            heavens ; sensual appetites and passions have passed away with a great noise. The elements
                            of carnal man have been melted with fervent heat. The earthly man, see Jno. iii., 31, with
                            his earthly works, see James, iii., 14, 15, shall be burnt up. The Apostle Paul says, I
                            beseech you by the mercies of God, that ye present your bodies a living sacrifice, holy,
                            acceptable unto Cod and let not sin reign any longer in your mortal bodies. If the spirit
                            that raised up Jesus from the dead, shall quicken your mortal bodies, by his spirit that
                            dwelleth in you. An individual having put off the body of the sins of the flesh, aud put on
                            the Lord Jesus Christ, presenting his body a living sacrifice, holy, acceptable unto God,
                            and no longer allowing sin foreign therein, so that he walks daily in newness of life ; such
                            bodies bear a very near relationship to the new heavens and earth wherein dwelleth
                            righteousness. The Lord has said, The old heavens and earth shall not be remembered nor come
                            into mind. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Testimony of Lucy Wright" TEIform="index"/> TESTIMONY OF LUCY WRIGHT,</head><p TEIform="p"> When I was young I used to be much affected with reading about the sufferings and
                            persecutions which Christ and his disciples endured from the wicked ; and I often thought if
                            I had lived in that day, I would have been one of Christ's disciples. jWhen I was about
                            nineteen years of age, I was taken very sick with a nervous fever ; so that my life was
                            despaired of, both by myself and others. In the time of this sickness I fell into a trance
                            and thought I died. Finding myself alone in the world of spirits, aud no one to help me, I
                            was in great trouble, and prayed that some one would come to my assistance, and conduct me
                            to a place of happiness. And there appeared to me a very pure, bright looking man, who
                            conducted me to a house, as it seemed, where I saw a number of people who looked so pure and
                            clean that I began to feel greatly ashamed of myself. Among the rest I saw a man who seemed
                            to be walking<pb n="127" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>the floor under the operations of the power of God. The
                            sight of such heavenly purity as these people seemed to possess, and the sense I felt of my
                            own impurity and unfitness for such a place, brought excessive tribulation upon me, and I
                            felt as though I wanted to get away and hide myself. I told the people that when I was in
                            the body, I thought when I died I should go to heaven ; but I could not find heaven because
                            I had come there in my sins, and I asked them if there was not some place where I could go
                            and repent of my sins and be saved. They said there was, and I might go and repent. About
                            this time my father came to my bed-side and took hold of my hand and I awoke from my trance.
                            I asked him if he thought 1 was dying. He said he thought I was, and asked me if I did not
                            think so. I answered, no. He asked me if I was willing to die. I replied that I was not for
                            I was yet in my sins ; and if I should die in my sins, I could not be saved. My vision in
                            this sickness greatly awakened my feelings, and led me to search for some way out of sin. In
                            this search I continued for several years without success- -no way appeared ; but I did not
                            then know the cause. In the year 1779, there Avas a great revival of religion in New
                            Lebanon, in which I received a witness that the time of Christ's second appearance was near
                            at hand ; but in what manner it would take place I could not tell, for I believed his second
                            appearance, like the first, would take place in a manner contrary to all human calculation.
                            I was afraid I should be like the unbelieving Jews, and oppose Christ in his coming. In the
                            spring of 1780, there were various reports in circulation about a strange sort of people
                            living up above Albany ; and I felt great anxiety to go and search them out and see whether
                            there was anything good among them or not. Accordingly I set out with six or seven others to
                            make them a visit. While on our journey, one of the compaay asked me if I was going to join
                            them. I replied that I had searched a great deal after religion, but had never yet found any
                            that had a very solid foundation, and if their religion had no better foundation than what I
                            had found before, I should not join them : for, said I, "they cannot catch old birds with
                            chaff." We went to John Partington's and stayed over night. The next morning being Sabbath,
                            we went on to the place where Mother Ann and the Elders lived and arrived there just before
                            they began their morning worship, and attended their meeting which was unspeakably powerful,
                            solemn and striking. We also attended their afternoon meeting. The mighty power of God was
                            evidently preseut in visible operations among the people. I was so affected with a sense of
                            fear, guilt and shame, on account of my own wretched and lost state, and my unfitness to be
                            with a people of such purity, that I drew back and kept out of sight as much as possible.
                            Among other extraordinary manifestations of the power of God which I noticed, one of the
                            Elders, while walking the floor under the visible operations of divine power suddenly
                            extended his hand towards me, and came directly up to me, saying, "God knows what is there,
                            and so do his servants." This struck me very forcibly. I fully be-<pb n="128" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            lieved what lie said, and felt as though all my sins were as plain and open to their view as
                            they were to ray own, and I felt as much tribulation as I was able to endure. We attended
                            the evening meeting, when I again stepped behind the people and sat on a bench, in hopes of
                            keeping out of sight. Elder James YVhittaker soon came and sat by me, and said, "Woman, what
                            do you think of this great work of God?" I answered, "I know it is the work of God." '"So
                            you do," said he ; "but you are like the Jews of old, who waited long for a Messiah, but
                            when he came he was too mean for them ; so is this work of God too mean for you." 1 replied,
                            that I did not think there was any way of Go;] for me. Then Mother and the Elders came and
                            kneeled down bejbrc me ; my head was bowed and I was unable to raise it up, or to help
                            myself. Mother wept and cried for a few minutes, and then he-ran to sing, and sung very
                            melodiously. They then told me that there was a way of God for me, if I would confess and
                            forsake my sins. This I fully believed, and in obedience to the faith I then received, I
                            went immediately out and . confessed my sins honestly before MotherlArm ; and I found her to
                            be a Mother indeed. I found that releasernent from the burden of sin which I had never felt
                            before, and which 1 had never been able to find in any other way,^though I had long sought
                            for it. The vision which I had seen in my sickness, more than four years before, came fresh
                            to my mind. Here was the house and the people. I remembered the guilt and confusion I had
                            felt in my vision, and now I had realized it. The man.who came to me with out-stretched
                            hand, I found to be Elder John Hocknell ; and I knew him to be "the same man that I saw in
                            my vision, "walking the floor tinder the operations of divine power. All the scenes of that
                            singular vision were this day realized to me in a very striking manner. I now felt as though
                            I had got upon a sure foundation where I could safely stand. We continued there the
                            following day ; during this time Mother faithfully instructed us in the way of God. On
                            Tuesday morning we took our leave and returned home, greaily satisfied with our visit. When
                            I reached home. I told my father I had found the people I saw in my vision ; ana I knew
                            Elder John Hockjiell to be the same man 1 saw walking the floor under the power of God; and
                            my father recollected the vision. When we first heard of Mother Ann and the Elders, we found
                            by the report of their neighbors, of whom inquiry was made, that they were considered as a
                            peaceable, honest and industrious people, having a good name among their neighbors, who were
                            plain, honest, Dutch people, and did not meddle with the religion of other people, and of
                            course had no prejudice against the Shakers on that account. But when we came to hear and
                            embrace their' testimony, and to receive a measure of the spirit of Christ through their
                            ministration, and walk according to it; then it was that evil reports began to spread, so
                            that in a short time Mother was charged with every kind of wickedness ; but so far from
                            weakening my faith, these reports strengthened it the more, because the great similarity
                            between the accusations against the Lord Jesus and Mother Ann, was thereby made to appear
                            more striking and evident.<pb n="129" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> It was not long after I embraced this
                            testimony, that Mother Ann and the Elders were imprisoned in Albany, as were also most of
                            the leading characters of the work in New Lebanon. When wicked men took Mother Ann and the
                            Elders to convey them to prison, they made their boasts that if they could get away the
                            principal members of the Society from New Lebanon, they could easily overthrow the rest, and
                            put a stop to the work. Accordingly they seized and committed them all to prison : and we,
                            poor children, were left like sheep without a shepherd. Yet through our humble prayers to
                            God, day and night, we were protected and strengthened in our faith, and our persecutors
                            failed in their object, and were not able to destroy the work of God. While the Elders were
                            in prison, I visited them once ; but Mother Ann had been conveyed down the river and
                            confined in the jail at Poughkeepsie. The winter following she returned home, and I visited
                            her soon afterwards. I saw her again at Harvard in a time of great persecution. I also
                            visited her twice at Ashfield ; both of these times her meetings were attended with the most
                            remarkable manifestations of divine power. I was with her also at Hancock and New Lebanon,
                            where persecution raged without control. In these persecutions she appeared perfectly
                            undaunted, and boldly reproved the wicked for their ungodly conduct. She spoke as she was
                            influenced by the spirit and power of God, and was no more severe than was Jesus when he
                            exclaimed to the wicked in his day, "Ye serpents, ye generation of vipers ; how can ye
                            escape the condemnation of hell? Matt. xxiii., 33. But, however great or severe their
                            persecutions, Mother Ann and the Elders always bore their sufferings and abuses with
                            meekness and humility. In all my acquaintance with them, under all circumstances, 1 never
                            discovered anything in any of their conversation or deportment, either public or private,
                            that was in anywise contrary to the pure gospel of Christ, of which they evidently possessed
                            a very large portion. When we had visited them, and were about to return home, in taking our
                            leave of Mother, we never failed to receive her parting blessing in some virtuous and
                            wholesome counsel or instruction, either of a spiritual or temporal nature, and generally
                            both. She would sometimes say, "Go home and put your hands at work and your hearts to God :
                            pay all your just debts, and right all your wrongs. Remember the poor; if you have but
                            little to spare, give to them that need. Be neat and clean, and keep the fear of God in all
                            your goings forth." Though my father and most of his family embraced the testimony and
                            faithfully kept it; yet we found many trials to pass through, and much opposition to
                            encounter. My mother died while I was quite young ; and though I had a kind father, yet I
                            knew not the value and importance of a mother till I found Mother Ann. In all our trials and
                            sufferings from the opposition of the wicked, since we embraced the gospel, the promise of
                            Christ has ever been verified towards us: "Blessed are ye when men shall revile you, and
                            persecute you, and say all manner of evil against you falsely for my sake." In all my
                            tribulation I have found comfort in the gospel. My faith has been my<pb n="130" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>
                            treasure ; and my obedience to the gospel testimony has always afforded peace and comfort to
                            my soul. My faith is firmly fixed on a sure foundation. I have no more doubt of the divine
                            mission of Mother Ann, or of the truth of her testimony, than I have of that of Jesus Christ
                            and his apostles, for it has kept me from sin, and is to this day, like the bread of life to
                            my soul. That same testimony which I first received from her, still remains like a living
                            witness, and in obedience to its teaching, I have received many blessed gifts of God, and
                            many precious seasons of heavenly joy and comfort. I have enjoyed Mother's spirit and
                            presence in times of tribulation and often felt her present with me. These things are not
                            fanciful dreams of the imagination, but as real as the light of the sun in a clear day.
                            Could I believe the charges of the wicked against Mother, I must believe that a corrupt tree
                            can bring forth good fruit, for I know I have received much good and heavenly fruit from her
                            ; nor did I ever see anything but goodness in her, from the first day I met her to that of
                            her decease. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1826. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to make the world bright" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO MAKE THE WORLD BRIGHT
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Poole, Hester M." TEIform="persName"/>BY HESTER M. POOLE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">How bright and fair the world
                                    might be Were men more often known To try and mend- -not other's faults- - But,
                                    better far, their own : Did we but try mankind to teach A nobler, better way, Not
                                    merely by a formal speech, But actions, day by day. How bright and fair this life
                                    might be, No more a troubled dream, If men would live for what they are, And not for
                                    what they seem : Did we but garner less of wealth, Which leads so eft astray, And
                                    more of mind and soul delights, That cannot pass away. How bright and fair this
                                    world might be ; What marvels 'twould unfold, If men would do one-half for love That
                                    now they do for gold ; If we to truer, simpler ways Were only more inclined, We then
                                    should learn life's choicest gifts Are health and peace of mind.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Ex." TEIform="index"/> Ex.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear Shaker friends; I wish that the..." TEIform="index"/>My dear Shaker friends; I wish that the...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maine, North Falmouth, March 4, 1887" TEIform="index"/> North Falmouth, Maine. March 4, 1887. </dateline><p TEIform="p">My Dear Shaker Friends ; I wish that the Manifesto might be put into every family in the
                            world, the principles it advocates are so pure and so charitable, so comforting to the weary
                            and sin laden, who are longing to live a purer and higher life. Could they only see the
                            beauty and holiness of the Believer's order, they would embrace it witli thankfulness. Yea
                            with thankful hearts. There is a germ of spiritual truth, planted in many souls, who are
                            kept in spiritual darkness by the " Lo here and lo there." Could the pure principles of
                            Believers, be laid before them, it would be a 'l Morning Star, " a harbinger of the coming
                            morning, when the Sun of Righteousness, shall arise and dispel the darkness, that shrouds
                            them almost completely at the present moment. Although the Shakers are few in number when
                            compared with other churches or denominations, yet the pure principles of your Society are
                            permeating all classes of people to-day more than all others. The Lord be praised ! May
                            these glorious truths, which you preach and which<pb n="131" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> are carried out in
                            your every day lives, live, and may you dear Brothers and Sisters be filled with the love of
                            God, that " perfect love which casteth out all fear " and enables you to say, as did our
                            blessed Lord and Master, " thy will not mine be done." With these few lines, accept my love
                            and kind regards for yourself and all your people ; the words I have here written are true
                            and in the sincerity of my heart I send them to you. Do with them as it pleases you, I am
                            willing all the world should know the sentiments of my soul. I have taken the Manifesto
                            regularly, ever since the publication of the first little paper " The Shaker. " I then
                            subscribed for the first copy, which 1 received from the hand of a Christian Brother, Elder
                            Otis Sawyer, it has been my daily food ever since, and has brought me many blessings. He has
                            since gone to his happy reward, but his precious memory, I cherish, still. The Manifesto is
                            a feast. Your friend and brother in Christ, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Archelaus" TEIform="persName"/>Archelaus Lewis. </byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Peril to our homes" TEIform="index"/> A PERIL TO OUR HOMES
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">. Our safety as a people pivots on the sanctity of our
                                    homes. The sanctity of our homes can be guarded only by intelligent and unremitting
                                    watchfulness. A present peril to our homes which is liable to be overlooked, but
                                    which can hardly be over estimated in its possibilities of evil, is in the average
                                    daily newspaper of our American cities. That peril needs to be recognized as a peril
                                    in order that its perilous consequences may in some way be averted. Again and again
                                    the Christian public sentiment of this country has been aroused against some special
                                    form of evil agency for the misleading of the young, and for the debauching of the
                                    moral sense of the community. Dime novels, obscene books and prints, sensational "
                                    flash " newspapers, and exceptionally indecent theatrical shows, have in turn come
                                    under the ban of the better class of well-disposed citizens, and are now stigmatized
                                    as moral nuisances- -even if still unabated- -to be dreaded and shunned by those who
                                    would keep ^themselves and their loved ones pure. But to-day the average daily
                                    newspaper of our larger cities is even more pernicious in its influence than any or
                                    all of these agencies of impurity, in its disgusting details of crime and of
                                    shameful conduct, displayed conspicuously and offensively before its ordinary
                                    readers. Indeed, there is, perhaps, at the present time, no more insidious and
                                    effective a destroyer of the innocent purity of the average Christian home than the
                                    average daily newspaper, which brings its vile contents to the sight of many who
                                    have not been warned against its obnoxious features. Of course, not all city dailies
                                    conform to the standard of the average city daily. There are daily papers in our
                                    larger cities, the contents of which are scrupulously guarded with a view to the
                                    purity of the homes they enter. These are honorable exceptions to the ordinary rule.
                                    They do not need to be mentioned by name, any more than do the papers of the
                                    opposite extreme. Any intelligent observer can see for himself to which class
                                    belongs any paper into which he looks but casually. But the objectionable papers do
                                    include many which are of an extended circulation, of large political influence, and
                                    which are edited with conspicuous ability. All this, however, makes them only the
                                    more dangerous to the home; because it gives them a good name, and a standing
                                    calculated to disarm suspicion as to their pernicious influence. It is not that the
                                    newspapers make necessary mention of crimes and of other evil doings in their
                                    records of the events of the passing time. There would be no special exception taken
                                    to this course. But it is that they give an undue and an unseemly prominence to the
                                    sensational display of the disgusting details of foul crimes and of indulgings in
                                    vice, where no good object is thereby to be gained and where the only apparent
                                    purpose is the pandering to a depraved taste and a<pb n="132" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> prurient
                                    curiosity. To such an extent is this unworthy practice now carried that some cf the
                                    more " enterprising" city dailies expend money freely in order to lay before their
                                    readers every morning the latest disclosures of some criminal scandal or some
                                    infamous divorce trial, in the courts beyond the sea; expanding in their columns the
                                    specific portraiture of obscene transactions and the explicit narration of shameless
                                    words and ways, which are utterly beyond the limits of common decency, and which no
                                    pretence can bring within the bounds of reputable journalism. This evil is seemingly
                                    on the increase; and it is already a question whether any details of vice could be
                                    sufficiently foul and abhorrent to insure the exclusion of their full description
                                    from the pages of the average city daily. The specious apology which the culpable
                                    editors make for this indecent display of disgusting details of vice and crime in
                                    their columns is that their readers are interested in the obscenity thus presented ;
                                    and that it is supplied, not because the editors deem it fit to be read, but because
                                    the readers have sufficiently low tastes to be gratified with its loathsomeness.
                                    Thii plea is, of course, only an aggravation of the offence itself; for it is an
                                    implied admission of the editor's willing. ness to prostitute his position and
                                    powers to the demands of the populace, regardless of the right or wrong of those
                                    demands. It suggests a readiness to do what is found to be profitable rather than to
                                    do what is known to be right. A similar plea to this is put forth in behalf of every
                                    form of evil doing. The vilest panderers to human lust have the excuse of
                                    ministering to those who want to be ministered to in that way. No man is worthy to
                                    be editor of any journal whatsoever who has no higher standard of right than the
                                    depraved morals and tastes of the more viciously inclined among his readers. An
                                    editor ought to be an educator of the community, and a leader in good; not a pupil
                                    of vice, and a follower of evil. He who says he will give a place in his columns to
                                    whatever details of indecency his readers will tolerate and enjoy is confessedly
                                    unfit to be an editor, and is deserving of the reprehension and contempt o; the
                                    well-disposed in the community. The evil of this daily newspaper pollution needs to
                                    be fully recognized as an evil, in order that something be done in the direction
                                    guarding against its extension into our better regulated Christian homes: even if it
                                    cannot yet be suppressed as an evil. Action toward ts restraining might, indeed,
                                    very properly be initiated by the Society for the Suppression jf Vice. If additional
                                    legislation be needed n order to secure this restraining, steps toward the required
                                    enactments should s-peediy be taken. Meanwhile there ought to be no question about
                                    the position which every person of common decency and of fair morality akes with
                                    reference to this chiefest peril to our homes to-day. There is one thing that every
                                    intelligent Christian man can do, and ought to do, in this emergency ; and that is
                                    to keep out of his lome every newspaper the contents of which are calculated to
                                    defile the mind and pollute ;he sense of the purest members of his .lousehold. No
                                    matter how prominent the paper may be, or how much ability [be displayed in its
                                    management, if it be one of these foul and filthy sheets, let him shut it from his
                                    house as be would the germs of pestilence, or the fumes of an uncleansed sewer. It
                                    would be better to live and die without the news of the day than to find that news
                                    only in a paper which is shamelessly edited, and which would force before the pure
                                    mind of an unsuspicious reader the abhorrent details of vile sayings and doings
                                    which ought not so much as to be named among persons of common decency. If the
                                    average city editor will load his columns with all the filth which he finds his
                                    readers are disposed to tolerate, see to it that he has no countenance from your
                                    support. Shut your eyes against his columns, and shut your home door against his
                                    newspaper. Anything short of this, is short of your personal duty in the premises.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Sunday school times" TEIform="index"/>Sunday School Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Suffering" TEIform="index"/> SUFFERING.</head><p TEIform="p"> To suffer for the cause of Christ Is noble and rewarding, But suffering for sin and self Is
                            never worth recording.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W. </byline></div2><pb n="133" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing and reaping" TEIform="index"/> SOWING AND REAPING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Marion" TEIform="persName"/> MARION JOHNSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "Whatsoeveb a man soweth that shall he also reap." Gal. vi., 7. The text quoted, shows to us
                            that the law* of compensation is operatne in spiritual as well as natural things, and
                            renders to each action its own inherent reward. That like causes produce like effects, is a
                            law of Nature as unalterable as those of the ancient Medea and Persians. This is a weighty
                            consideration, aud teaches us how great should be our care and anxiety lest we sow what we
                            are i ot willing to reap. How often have the seeds of some hasty, impatient or passionate
                            act, borne fruitage in a life-lorg sorrow and regret, the effects of which perhaps may be as
                            far reaching as eternity. It is very aptly said in the context, "If we sow to the flesh we
                            shall reap corruption ; but if we sow to the spirit, we shall reap life everlasting." If our
                            highest ambition and aspirations in life, center wholly ou the pleasures, honors and
                            emoluments which this world bestows, and we pursue those to the exclusion of higher objects,
                            we may be successful in our pursuit; but as these are the fruits of sowing to the flesh, aud
                            must be classed with the perishable and corruptible, hence the harvest that we shall reap,
                            will be one of grief for wasted time and energies, of which a portion at least, should have
                            been improved in caring for the interests of our immortal souls. While on the other hand, if
                            we hunger and thirst after righteousness, to that extent that we are willing to sacrifice
                            all to obtain it; daily crucifyiug the world in ourselves with its affections and lusts;
                            seeking only to knoAv and do the will of God, we shall reap a reward commensurate with our
                            efforts aud the sacrifices we have made. Daily and hourly are we sowing these seeds by the
                            weyside on the journey of life ; either those of love and kindness aud blessing, or those of
                            unkindness, hatred and strife ; and though we may have forgotten the time and place of the
                            sowing, yet none the less sure are they to germinate and bring forth fruit unto a harvest
                            which, painful or pleasant, it will be our sole prerogative to reap. Did we realize this
                            subject as we should in all its bearings upon our own and other's welfare, we should often
                            inquire of ourselves, are we sowing the seeds which we shall be willing to reap? " Will the
                            reaping of life's harvest Yields eternal life to thee? 0 my soul, be wise in sowing, That
                            the harvest blest may be." God grant that to each one of us, may be the reaping of a golden
                            harvest of the peaceable fruits of righteousness ; and may it be our earnest endeavor to
                            root out from our hearts the evil weeds which have sprung from the seeds of worldliness and
                            selfishness, that the beautiful plants of goodness, truth and purity may flourish and grow
                            in the sunlight of God's love. Canterbury, N. H. i:</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cast not dirt into the..." TEIform="index"/>Cast not dirt into the...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA J. CALVER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Cast not dirt into the well that has given thee water-" To fully understand the worth of
                            this plain Oriental maxim, we must go with the traveler over the arid wastes, aud sandy
                            deserts of the East, where with<pb n="134" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> only a stinted measure, is the
                            life-preserving blessing of water given to the inhabitants of that sterile land. Imagine
                            yourself, toilworn and weary, famishing with thirst, often deceived by the tantalizing
                            mirage, at last nearing the fertile oasis, where the water is sure, and life again seems
                            worth the living, in anticipation of reviving chaughts from the spring, the clear depths of
                            which reflect the scattered sunbeams, dancing among the leaves of the miniature palms
                            fringing its borders. But alas ! on nearing its coveted retreat, you see foot-prints of all
                            sizes. A caravan has just moved on, leaving behind them only tokens of selfish ingratitude ;
                            for after fully assuaging their thirst, forgetting at once their former sufferings, either
                            the wanton plays of childhood, or the maliciousness of maturer age, have cast turf, dirt,
                            and stones, into the once clear basin, which is now only a turbid pool; and probably such an
                            instance caused this reproach : " Cast not dirt into the well that has given thee water,"
                            which ripening into a proverb, holds volumes in its meaning. Take it. for instance in the
                            friendships of. life, how easy it is to cast dirt into the well that has given us water. A
                            wise man once said, "If you have a friend who guards your interests, even though he weighs
                            you with impartial justice, cherish him, for such gifts are rare;" while Solomon says, "The
                            mouth of the righteous is as a well of life." But do we not often forget to discriminate
                            between that friendship, which like the bubbling spring, comes from the innermost recesses
                            of the heart, giving nothing but the pure exhilarating waters of life, and that which at one
                            draught we can drain the cup, to find ourselves intoxicated by its seeming strength, a
                            relapse from which, demands a repetition of the same, until the relish for the pure elixir
                            of life is destroyed, and in our revels, we are ready to cast aside true friendship for that
                            effervescence, which leaves us at last to perish on the plain ; and too late we find that we
                            have cast in dirt into a well that has given us water. Still a broader illustration. As
                            "waters in the wilderness" as "springs in the desert" have always those efforts of humanity
                            been compared, which consolidates good, to form homes, bands, societies, where all needing,
                            or choosing united virtue, might find a haven of rest; of working rest, where they too, may
                            be enabled to cultivate the oasis in the desert, which contains the wells of salvation; that
                            other travel-worn pilgrims who would quench their thirst, might gather in safety. Such is
                            our home. Its original principles, unalloyed by the waywardness of selfish human nature,
                            strengthened, *as they should be, by increasing growth from age to age, are as life to the
                            famishing, healing to the sin-sick, and strength to the worker ; and shall we in our
                            childish ignorance, or thoughtless ingratitude, cast dirt into the well that has given us
                            water? When we hear those of mature age, throwing the blame of their own undeveloped lives
                            upon the society under whose shadow they have been protected from many severe conflicts of
                            life, are we not led to suppose that they have cast so much dirt into their well, that the
                            waters have muddied their lives. When we find that all the love we have for our home is its
                            " loaves and<pb n="135" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> fishes," its gatherings of material comforts, unwilling
                            to turn from our beaten track for the comfort of our surrounding friends; shirking the
                            burden of adding to the mental or spiritual growth of our home, can we feel that we acquit
                            ourselves honorably in the duty of guarding the fountain that others may drink of the waters
                            pure, as has been given us. Again if we find in ourselves a willingness to support parties
                            or factions, by sly intrigue or open slander, are we not rendering so muddy the life element
                            of our home, that many, seeking, will turn from it in disgust. Wealth may be ours, fame may
                            be ours, but unless we are cemented by the pure, spiritual Christian love, which controls
                            every passion, banishes all enmity and contention, our association will crumble like
                            sand-houses on the beach, when the tides of time wash over them, for it is indeed true, that
                            "religion is the cement of all society." Let these reflections be ours who were placed by
                            this well of salvation in early life. We have witnessed its benefits on those who have been
                            made the counterpart of angels by its cleansing waters, and have tasted enough ourselves to
                            know that its properties are sufficient to heal all infirmities of the spirit, if
                            unadulterated by selfish, perverse human nature. O what responsibilities are ours ! to guard
                            these waters from contending parties for worldly gain, to rescue the pure spring in the
                            wilderness from the encroaching walls of selfishness, to widen its borders that ail may
                            partake, without money or price. This is done by a strict surveillance each over our own
                            individual lives, that it need not be said of us, that our influence lowers the moral or
                            spiritual tone of society. The waters that have redeemed can redeem again, and let us who
                            have proved their efficacy, so unite to guard their sacred flow, that none can cast dirt
                            into the well that has given us water. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ill- temper" TEIform="index"/> Ill-Temper.</head><p TEIform="p"> A single person of sour, sullen temper- -what a dreadful tiling it is to have such an one in
                            a house ! There is not myrrh and aloes and chloride of lime enough in the world to disinfect
                            a single home of such a nuisance as that; no riches, no elegance of mien, no beauty of face,
                            can ever screen such persons from utter vulgarity. There is one thing which rising persons
                            hate the reputation of more than all others, and that is vulgarity ; but, trust me,
                            ill-temper is the vulgarest thing that the lowest born and illest-bred can ever bring to his
                            home. It is one of the worst forms of impiety. Peevishness in a home is not only sin against
                            the Holy Ghost, but sin against the Holy Ghost in the very temple of love. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/> Theodore Parker. </byline></div2><div2 type="quote" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christ is the light of man, and enlightens every soul..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Christ is the light of man, and enlightens every soul...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Christ is the light of man, and enlightens every soul that comes into the light. We must be
                            alive before we can travel. If we have no life, we have no light. If we walk in darkness, we
                            are liable to fall, and our fall may be great. If the light that is in us, is lost, how
                            great will be our darkness.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Larz" TEIform="persName"/>Larz Erickson. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To live is not merely to breathe, it is to act..." TEIform="index"/>
                            To live is not merely to breathe, it is to act...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> To live is not merely to breathe, it is to act; it is to make use of our organs, senses,
                            faculties, of all those parts of ourselves which give us the feeling of existence. The man
                            who has lived the longest is not the man who has counted the most years, but he who has
                            enjoyed life most. Such a one was buried a hundred years old. but he was dead from his
                            birth. He would have gained by dying young; at least he would have lived till that time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rousseau" TEIform="persName"/>Rousseau. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="So speak to God as if men heard you" TEIform="index"/>
                            So speak to God as if men heard you
                        </head><p TEIform="p">So speak to God as if men heard you.</p></div2><pb n="136" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> THE MANIFESTO, 1887. Office op publication. The Manifesto is published at Shaker
                                Village, Mer. Go. N. H. All articles for publication should be addressed to Henry C.
                                Blinn, and all letters on financial business to A. Y. Cochran. TIE! DERIVE ffiS. One
                                copy per year, postage paid, ' six months, " Send for specimen copy, free. . 15 .10 </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Light" TEIform="index"/> LIGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> More thau ever it becomes the imperative duty of every one to "Let yowv light shine."
                                Obstacles that have been placed in the way should be removed, conditions that have
                                clouded the mind should be changed and the light, of the revelation of God's will to
                                man, of the humanity of man toward man, of the laws that should be our teacher in
                                morality, and the laws that should demand a care for our bodies as temples for the holy
                                spirit to dwell in, should be allowed to shine so clearly and so continuously that even
                                those Avho run may read without the least fear of making a false step. Sometimes we
                                think there can be no excuse for taking shelter in unrighteousness. That the day is
                                already dawning upon us when the "knowledge of the Lord shall cover the land as the
                                waters cover the sea," while the wise men and women are publishing so freely their best
                                and most carefully wrought out investigations in regard to the laws of life and the
                                beneficial effects of a moral education. More than ever do we occupy a responsible
                                position before the world, as we have the history and experience of all who have
                                preceded us on the earthly pilgrimage. Thousands of years have given man a long
                                experience in which to learn many valuable lessons for the prosperity of the race. These
                                can never be lost from sight only in isolated cases when a tribe or a nation carelessly
                                forget God, in their neglect of his laws toman. Light came in the past ages as it comes
                                to us. It may have been of less magnitude and of more distant intervals, but it was the
                                same light, and it came from God. It gave to the people a system of laws for the care of
                                their bodies, and foreshadowed, at the same time, a care for their souls. Nothing but a
                                light from God could have turned Abraham from his Pagan dietary customs and stimulated
                                in him the necessity for a reformation. It was an advanced step in righteousness, his
                                best offering to God, and a great benefit to the race of man, in that it widened the
                                distance between the "sons of God" and the omniverous beasts. This was a special divine
                                favor that soon became a "lamp to his feet and as a light to his path. " The prophet
                                also enjoyed a manifestation from the same spirit, when he became able to urge the
                                necessity of a greater discipline for the mind. " Let the wicked forsake his way, and
                                the unrighteous man his thoughts, and let him return to the Lord. " Without the
                                self-denial that was imposed by Abraham and Moses, it is doubtful if the prophet could
                                have succeeded in establishing an interest for JUNE<pb n="137" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> something
                                higher. These .first preachers readied only the selfish propensities, while the spirit,
                                illuminated man with more soul devotion, urged the necessity for a greater discipline in
                                morality, and saw the \ery great need of an order of life beyond the animals that
                                perish. The undisciplined or unrighteous man is more or less a subject of darkness and
                                can only learn a better way where the light shines. He is liable to fall into states and
                                conditions that are not protective, and frequently becomes a sorry specimen of humanity,
                                ignorant or brutal. That which was denominated unclean under the ministration of the law
                                and unsuitable for use, can be in a day of greater light, no less unclean, and must be
                                more objectionable for man. If it stimulated coarseness and grossncss of mind in that
                                day it will probably do the same now. The morality of that early age, as a whole, would
                                hardly be acceptable in the Christian Societies of today. The mind grows to love and to
                                accept a higher standard. The good of the past is retained, and the increase of the
                                present is added to it till u righteousness shall flourish like the palm tree and grow
                                like a cedar of Lebanon. " A better care of the body, in its meats and drinks, and the
                                departing from all unrighteous thoughts will accomplish very much in helping us on our
                                return to the Lord from whom we have so unwisely gone astray. Religious bodies should
                                hold up a light of which they need not be ashamed. ]f they are the children of God, the
                                light of the world, then their light should illumine a path in which others can walk in
                                safety, and in "- -pleasantness and peace." </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary. </head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sore eyes" TEIform="index"/>SORE EYES
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To the Editor : Dear Sir- -I have been a reader of your magazine
                                        for several j^ears, and have gathered much wisdom from its useful pages, and now
                                        I feel a greater interest in it than ever before, as I perceive that its
                                        articles are less conservative than formerly, and that the views set forth
                                        therein are keeping pace with the enlightenment of the age in hygienic and other
                                        matter pertaining to the welfare of the human race. But there is one thing I
                                        have never seen in print, which, I fear, has been entirely overlooked by
                                        physicians and oculists, and which is the cause of so many people having weak,
                                        or slightly diseased eyes, especially of late years. I attribute the cause,
                                        primarily, to this fact: a great many people now-a-days, read newspapers fresh
                                        from the press, without thinking, or knowing, that the ink used upon them
                                        contains a quantity of arsenic. "Well," the reader may say, " what has this to
                                        do with sore eyes?" Very much I reply. By handling freshly-printed sheets, very
                                        minute quantities of the ink offsets upon the end of the ringers : perhaps, not
                                        enough to soil them, but enough to deposit the arsenic thereon. Then, if there
                                        is a particle of itching of the eyelids, the persons so affected, almost
                                        involuntarily, rub their eyes with the tips of their fingers; and, as the
                                        arsenic is a poison, the result is, disease of the eyes ensues, more or less.
                                        Now my advice is, that people wash their hands after handling such newspapers,
                                        or, if not convenient to do so, then keep their fingers carefully away from
                                        their eyes. If this advice is strictly adhered to, there would be less use for
                                        the physician or the oculist in this particular. It is an old and true saying,
                                        that " an ounce of preventive is worth a pound of cure, " and if this brief note
                                        of caution meets with your views, Mr. Editor, give your readers the benefit of
                                        it. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health. An Old
                                        Printer.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="138" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian communism no. 3" TEIform="index"/> CHRISTIAN COMMUNISM. NO. 3.</head><p TEIform="p"> [TAKEN FROM THE CINCINNATI POST.]Ulder Goepper tells of the Philosophy of Shakerism. But I
                            mistake. There was also a clock. Blessings on the man who first invented clocks. They are
                            the most sociable, companionable machines in the world. It is the only machine in the worM
                            that lives with you. It never scolds, never frets, never stews, never gets angry nor
                            impatient nor worried nor flustered. It goes cheerfully on its contented way of life,
                            keeping regular hours, never dissipating, never fooling away any time, always contented and
                            peaceful and happy, never offering advice, yet never refusing information. It is just the
                            same serene, quiet old friend from day to day whether it rains or shines or snows or blows
                            or freezes. It is industrious. It is persevering. It is truthful. It is unselfish. It is
                            humble. It is unobtrusive. In fact, a good clock is a whole Christian example. That is what
                            a good clock is everywhere. But there, in that peaceful, prompt, industrious Shaker
                            community, it is a good deal more. It is, probably unknown to them, one of the two emblems
                            of the whole society. If the Shakers ever shall grow proud and want a coat of arms to brand
                            on their broom handles it should be a broom and a clock addorsed. My clock was the long,
                            gentle kind, that ticks about once a second. That is the only kind to have. These short,
                            energetic, irascible, distracting clocks going rippety-clip, ten furious, strident beats to
                            the second, rushing ahead regardless, as if eternity was just leaving the dock and the
                            chances were against their making the gang-plank, are an aggravation to a quiet soul. My
                            clock was the Yankee sister of the one in the hall, and of the one which hung in the next
                            room, occupied by "Brother Peter" Boyd, now past eighty years old. He winds and regulates
                            all the clocks in "the office," and so nicely adjusted does he keep them, that while I was
                            there his clock and mine were not three seconds apart in striking, and that difference he
                            explained was due to the unusual fire in my room which by its heat had infinitesimally
                            elongated the pendulum of my clock, making it lose the least trifle. I say the clock is an
                            emblem of the Shaker community, because everything goes on time. All the meal times are
                            exact to a minute Everybody is in bed and the houses closed at eight in the evening.
                            Promptness, absolute punctuality is a sine qua non of a successful community. As certainly
                            as an army without discipline would degenerate into a mob, so certainly would a community
                            without punctuality fall into wasteful idleness. I spoke of the broom as another emblem of
                            the Shakers. Its manufacture is one of their favorite industries, and they have more ways of
                            making it useful than are known to the outside world. They never disgrace it by. making it
                            stand behind the door, as if it were responsible for the untidy litter about the house. The
                            Shaker broom is always hung up against the wall when not in use. They put a clean white
                            cotton hood on some of their brooms, and when thus equipped use them to dry-polish their
                            smooth hard wood floors and to remove the last trace of dust from the hard and shining
                            surface. At the very bountifully supplied supper table I met about ten hired men and the
                            school teacher. In the evening I had a call from "Eldor Leopold" Goepper, a man of great
                            force and originality of thought and character. He may not take so much stock in the
                            religious feature of the institution, but sets great store by the philosophical merits of
                            the system. He is sixty years old, but you would not think him over forty-five. He came to
                            this country from Strasburg, Germany, when nine years old. He has been a tanner, a
                            physician, a farmer and always a student and thinker. "The ideal community," said Elder
                            Leopold to me as we both sat about the cheery little wood-stove in my room that cold
                            evening, " is based upon the fact that the human family is a unit, and the unit cannot be
                            perfect till every constituent factor of that unit shall be perfect. The perfection of each
                            factor consists in, and is the result of, laboring for the common good. And just in
                            proportion as he is able to do that exclusive of all individual and selfish considerations,
                            in that proportion will this individual human<pb n="139" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> factor of the collective
                            human unit promote his own well-being. Take an individual and place him by himself outside
                            of society, and there is nothing to elevate his moral character. He could not develop under
                            such conditions." ''But I do not see why a member of your community may not be very
                            unselfish in his relations with his fellow members of the community, and yet the community
                            as a whole be very selfish and indifferent to the wants and needs of the outside world."
                            "The fact that community life requires as its principal and essential condition that the
                            individual shall sacrifice himself for the good of the community, and derive his happiness,
                            not from selfish gratifications but from the peace, prosperity and happiness of the
                            community, imposes upon the whole community the same characteristic state of feeling with
                            reference to the whole human family, of which it is a part." "Well, now, in point of fact,"
                            I persisted in asking, "what has this community of Union Village done for the betterment of
                            the world outside?" "In the first place," promptly replied Elder Leopold, "it has maintained
                            here for eighty years these institutions, and this better and happier mode of life, and has
                            kept an open door of invitation to all the world to leave the selfish, competitive struggle
                            and enter our peaceful, prosperous and happy community. The maintenance of such an example,
                            and the honest and hearty tender of such an invitation for all these years is one good this
                            community of Union Village has done. No man who ever lived here among us long enough to
                            imbibe the spirit of the institution was ever satisfied after he went out. We have never
                            found an instance of a man who here among us has laid his selfishness aside who was ever
                            afterward satisfied in the world of selfish competition. "In the second place," continued
                            Elder Leopold, "we have raised hundreds of children under the careful moral influence and
                            Christian training of our institutions; and those which were not so depraved by nature that
                            they could not be helped, here received the benefit of this pleasant home and of this moral
                            training. Many of them have left and gone into the world, but they always speak of this
                            place as home, and manifest in the world much of the unselfishness they learned among us. In
                            the third place avo have established and maintained for eighty years a character and
                            reputation for honesty, truthfulness, integrity, purity and kindness which has made the
                            Shaker name respected wherever it is known. "I tell you, " added Elder Leopold,
                            enthusiastically, "when one has lived community life long enough to learn its release from
                            the care and responsibility and struggle of the competitive fight outside, he ceases
                            thereafter to be able to live comfortably any other life. ' The community life is the normal
                            condition of man, and lies at the basis of the social organization of Christianity." "I
                            understand it to be an indispensable requisite in your community life that open confession
                            of all one's sins and meannesses be made by the men before an elder and by the women before
                            an eldress; what is the necessary relation of that requirement to the communal system as you
                            practice it?" "That simply means," replied Elder Leopold to my inquiry, "that a man among us
                            must so live and act, and even learn to think, as to realize that he must neither do nor
                            think anything, whether seen or not that he would not be willing the whole world should
                            know. He must purify himself from the core out, and it is a life work. In our relations
                            toward each other between the sexes every individual is expected to school himself so as not
                            to recognize any sex. His conduct must be in all respects such as is proper between Brethren
                            and Sisters in Christ." "Do you want your numbers to increase," I asked, "and if so, what
                            missionary work are you doing to that end, and what arc your expectations in regard to it?"
                            "Some of us differ in regard to that. My own judgment is that just so fast as the
                            competitive world crowds itself against the wall, and is thereby compelled to look forborne
                            better system, in that proportion will people be led to recognize the community principle,
                            and just as fast as people learn to recognize it and to look for it, in that proportion will
                            we expect an increase in our numbers, and<pb n="140" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> not otherwise. In the line
                            of missionary work we have published books and panr phlets, and are issuing a monthly
                            journal called The Manifesto, from one of our Eastern societies. We also issue tracts of
                            various kinds. There has been some missionary work done in the East by individuals going out
                            to lecture in New York, Philadelphia, Boston, Albany, and even some have gone to England."
                            "If it be a fair question to ask, What, in your judgment, are the defects and hindrances in
                            your system here, for no earthly thing or scheme is absolutely perfect, and every living
                            thing and every living system is bound to change as time goes on. Changelessness argues
                            death." "I will say in the first place that the community is changing and has changed more
                            in the ten years that I have been here than it has changed in the thirty years previous. The
                            chief defects that our community is laboring under- -and now I am only giving you my
                            opinion- -are relies of its theology, that were brought in with it in its formation, with
                            regard to certain forms of worship ; but these do not, however, hinder an individual from
                            living here his highest and most perfect conception of goodness. "These forms may even have
                            their uses for some, and no doubt, do. But I have small use for the forms of religion. I
                            consider all formal religion fetichism. My life, my everyday acts and thoughts are my
                            religion." In my next and concluding letter I want to give some idea of the habits and modes
                            of life of this remarkable community. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaiandri, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theo. Kaiakdbi. </byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Success" TEIform="index"/> SUCCESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Newton, Agnes E." TEIform="persName"/> AGNES E. NEWTON.</byline><p TEIform="p">Decision, promptness and perseverance are the prime elements of success in every undertaking
                            in life. The first is of the utmost importance in the formation of a character, which will
                            fit its possessor for the trusts and responsibilities of earth life which is but a preface
                            to that beyond. A wise decision as regards the course to be pursued in the one, ensures
                            ultimate success in the other. Promptness was one of the ruling characteristics in the life
                            of our Savior, as the many incidents recorded in the New Testament give evidence. We cannot
                            recall an instance where the opportunity for doing good was postponed or an indefinite
                            answer returned to the needy who sought through his agency divine aid. The poor unfortunate
                            who cried, "Lord, if thou wilt, thou canst make me clean, " received the ready answer,
                            accompanied by the compassionate touch of the Savior's hand, "I will, be thou clean. " He
                            did not silence the importunities of the Ruler with the promise to call at his earliest
                            convenience, to see his little daughter who was lying at the point of death ; but went with
                            the stricken parent at once, and rendered the assistance that no'je but a Christ could have
                            given. The impotent man waiting at the pool of Bethesda, in painful suspense, alternately
                            hoping and despairing as he sought the healing of its waters, which he was unable to reach
                            because of the selfishness of the throng, Avhen made conscious of the Savior's presence was
                            immediately restored by his wonderful power. The invitation extended to those whom he
                            selected to be his disciples, to follow him, required prompt obedience. Matthew sitting at
                            the receipt of Custom obeyed at once ; arose and followed him ; leaving lucrative
                            employment, to share the persecutions and fortune of one, who himself declared had not where
                            to lay<pb n="141" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> his head. Andrew and Peter were not given time to finish
                            mending their nets, nor to settle the matter of leaving with their father ; but left their
                            little all of earthly possessions and relations and followed the master. The worth of the
                            lessons which these few incidents, selected from among the many, is their practical
                            adaptation to human life with its burdens and responsibilities, its joys and its sorrows. To
                            be negligent and procrastinating in the performance of duty, whether of a spiritual or
                            temporal nature, and in a truly Christian life, the two are inseparably blended, is not
                            following the example of our Savior. The Christ mission implies earnest active service. The
                            decision to obey the diviue injunction, " Deny thyself take up thy cress daily aud follow
                            me," promptly made and perseveringly carried out, will bring the perfect fruition of the
                            soul, and the living Christ will be found therein enshrined. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good and bad habits" TEIform="index"/> "GOOD AND BAD HABITS."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stickney, Asenath C." TEIform="persName"/>ASENATH C. STICKNEY. </byline><p TEIform="p"> While reading the above named title I could hardly help exclaiming: llow forcibly yet
                            truthfully the writer lias depicted facts with which we are all more or less acquainted !
                            Indeed how habits grow upon one especially bad ones, and how often they seemingly fetter
                            every faculty of body and mind. In my opinion the secret of growth ill this regard lies in
                            repetition. A repetition of thoughts, words or deeds in any given direction gradually but
                            surely tend toward fixed habits, which, like some poor captive's chain, is wrought link by
                            link till it is strong enough to secure its victim. Let us look at this subject in its most
                            practical light for our own benefit. Does not the desire for petty excitement or sensational
                            delights constantly indulged create a habit of gossiping? and does not the habitual gossip
                            ripen into the habitual slanderer? We think so. So also an untidy person becomes thus by
                            repeated neglects in the common details of daily duties essential to cleanliness. The
                            results of these repeated neglects is a habitiir.1 uukept personal appearance, which too
                            often becomes the central figure of slatternly surroundings. "Many people suppose that they
                            can drop a bad habit any time they choose" says the writer, but I am not one of those who
                            thus believe. On the contrary, I think it must take as long to eradicate a bad habit as it
                            took to form one,. aud therefore I would advise every youth to watch carefully every
                            tendency of thought and action, to see if these repeated will ripen into worthy friends or
                            not for "Happy is the man whose habits are his friends. " Age and experience may also be
                            benefited as they reread the record of the past, if they but try to discover the many
                            unwelcome habits which need to be canceled by a more rigid self-denial here, and.a more
                            willing sacrifice there of unheavenly selfish conditions, for so true it is, that a
                            repetition of acts, not of years, fashions the habits which, blight or bless our usefulness.
                            Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vanity weaves her flimsy tissues..." TEIform="index"/>Vanity weaves her flimsy tissues...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Vanity weaves her flimsy tissues in the empty garret of the brain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><pb n="142" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gone" TEIform="index"/> GONE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/> ADA S. CUMMINGS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Composed for our dearly loved Eldress, Mary A. Gilleipie. Gone, our Mother, to the gleaming
                            shore And reached the shining goal; To meet the loved ones gone before, A bright redeemed
                            soul. The Eeaper's hand outstretched in love, Gave her a welcome free, A happy home in
                            heaven above : Her robe is purity. The bitter cup we cannot shun, Our heart must feel its
                            woe. 0 God, Thy holy will be done, Our sorrows Thou dost know. Upon the wings of peace she
                            sped, Bidding adieu to time ; By angel guardians she is led, Into a holier clime. Gone where
                            the chilling storms of earth, Pierce her frail form no more; Her spirit from its heavenly
                            birth, On freedom's wings doth soar. Her dearly loved with whom she toiled, Will not be left
                            alone ; The loving one from whom she's called, Still claims her as her own. But she has
                            traveled on before, A mansion to prepare ; A glorious home on that blest shore, So wonderful
                            and fair. Still she will be our loving friend, Help us our victories win; And she will lead
                            us by the hand, Until we enter in. We all shall miss her precious voice That cheered in
                            times of need. When on the waves of sorrow tossed, It proved a soothing mead. We would not
                            call her back again, Into this world of care ; We'll go and meet her, free from pain, And
                            greet her spirit there. Still, gentle mother, be thou near, Still lead us in thy ways, And
                            feed us from thy loving hand, As in the former days. "Gone" yet we know that all is wel,l
                            Enjoy thy tranquil rest; For laurels rare, and gems of worth, Are with thee, pure and blest.
                            West Gloucester, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living on vegetables" TEIform="index"/>Living on Vegetables
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The number of those who think that vegetables constitute
                                    the only proper food for man has increased largely in this country during the past
                                    ten years. It would have still a larger increase but for the fact that reformers of
                                    every kind have to bear the reproach of being to some slight extent eccentric.
                                    Elderly people, who have suffered untold misery by submitting for years to the
                                    dictates of fashion, broken in health and utterly discouraged, are ready to try any
                                    system that has in it the hope of relief. What is needed is the enlistment of young
                                    vigorous men and women in the ranks of the vegetarians. Make it interesting to them
                                    to experiment with their appetites, and to discover whether life is worth living
                                    when the food supply is composed exclusively of vegetables and fruits. A
                                    correspondent says : " The elephant and rhinoceros build up their mighty frames
                                    without the assistance of flesh food ; the horse, the ox and all the domestic
                                    animals whose strength is serviceable to man, are by nature vegetarians ; in short
                                    there are innumerable indications of the fact that the purest, most wholesome and
                                    most nourishing food for man may be obtained direct from the bountiful hand of
                                    nature, without any admixture of blood and slaughter. I myself can, after five years
                                    experience, bear witness to the immense benefit which the bodily health derives from
                                    this simple and frugal method of living, which has none of the exciting and
                                    stimulating qualities of flesh food, but induces a calm, strong and equable habit of
                                    body, together with far clearer and more vigorous powers of mind. In short, let
                                    those who have a will try for a month or two the reformed method of diet, and they
                                    will soon learn to smile at the admonition of chemists and doctors. "</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One ill word will ask another" TEIform="index"/>One ill word will ask another
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> One ill word will ask another.</p></div2><pb n="143" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Redemption's song" TEIform="index"/>Redemption's song
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. Redemption's song, for thee I long, Thy bliss my soul would know, 2.
                            I'll learn one measure day by day Thro' study, pains and care; 3. This passage of the
                            victor's song O let my heart repeat; From whose rapt chords and living words Pure
                            inspirations flow; And no false note, no siren lay, Shall plant a discord there. In union
                            with the sainted throng Discourse its music sweet. Whose notes of joy from triumphs. won The
                            victors only sing, I'll set it to the Golden Rule The Savior gave- -said he, This is the
                            song for which I long, The bliss my soul would know; And from whose voices blent in one The
                            grandest peans ring. "Do unto others as ye would That they should do to thee." Its thrilling
                            chords and living words From highest sources flow.</p></div2><pb n="144" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> KIND WORDS. </head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We love the Manifesto..." TEIform="index"/>We love the Manifesto...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Kentucky, Pleasant Hill" TEIform="index"/> Pleasant Hill, Ky. </dateline><p TEIform="p">We love the Manifesto ; and believe its Monthly yield of fruitful leaves, will eventually
                                heal all nations, "glory to God. "</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Napoleon" TEIform="persName"/> Napoleon Brown.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers. </head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hall's journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Hall's Journal of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. May. Contents. Ludwig Windthorst; The
                                Bible and Phrenology : Familiar Talks with our Young Headers; The Divorce Question;
                                Beecher and Phrenology; Head Measurement; What one sees in Jamaica; A Darling; Data of
                                Universal Knowledge; Short hard for the many; Mary's Vision; Health Papers; Temperature
                                and Health of Homes; Hypnotism; Kotes in Science; Wisdom, Mirth, etc., etc. Fowler
                                &amp; Wells Co., 775 Broadway, N. Y. Herald of Health. May. Contents. Health and
                                Workinp- Habits of the Shakers; Liberia and its Climate; What does our Superior
                                Civilization amount to?-Woman and the Household; Mothers and the Nursery, etc., etc.
                                Herald of Health Co., 13LaightSt.,N. Y. Hall's Journal of Health. May. Contents. The
                                Occult Forces; Injurious and Adulterated Beverages; Water, its Agency in Therapeu:i':s;
                                Dr. R. C. Fisher's Fasting Cure; Strange Admonition of Death; Food Adulterations;
                                Molecules and Atoms; Pome forebodings of Incipient Insanity, etc., etc. Office 206
                                Broadway, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Earth, so the story goes..." TEIform="index"/>Earth, so the story goes...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> "The Earth," so the story goes, lias joined the Shakers, and the Shakers, some of them, are
                            in close fellowship with Henry George. Things might have been much worse. The Earth, brings
                            to us an abundance of interesting matter, and has its own way of representing the life that
                            now is, in language as choice as theology does of the life that is to come. It tells the
                            story of a man whose house was only six inches from hell, and that of course was exact
                            truth, but it has been proved that the above undesirable place is in the center of the
                            earth. Published every Saturday, at $2 per yr.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="As the least bit of cinder blinds the eye..." TEIform="index"/>
                            As the least bit of cinder blinds the eye...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">As the least bit of cinder blinds the eye, so the least unkind feeling toward the
                                    meanest of God's creature man will shut up your soul in darkness.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="War Cry" TEIform="index"/>- - liar Cry.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Law" TEIform="index"/> LAW.</head><p TEIform="p"> Laws, as we read in ancient sages. Have been live cobwebs in all ages. Cobwebs for little
                            flies are spread, And laws for little folks are made; But if an insect of renown, Hornet or
                            beetle, wasp or drone, Be caught in quest of sport and plunder, The flimsy fetter flies in
                            sunder. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Beattie, James" TEIform="persName"/>James Beattie.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's favor" TEIform="index"/> GOD'S FAVOR.</head><p TEIform="p">THY favor, Heavenly Father, I feel it every da}', Through kindness of thy children, Who walk
                            the narrow way, May I requite thy giving, In honor to my call, And with like love and
                            blessing, Do good to one and all.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/> M. W. </byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths. </head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gillespie, Mary A." TEIform="index"/>Mary A. Gillespie</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., J. B." TEIform="persName"/>J. B. N.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Susan" TEIform="index"/>Susan Smith</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., H. L." TEIform="persName"/>H. L. E.</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thurstin, Mary J." TEIform="index"/>Mary J. Thurstin</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Death of a noted Shakeress. Eldress Mary A. Gillespie of the Shaker Society at Alfred,
                                died April 15th. of pneumonia. She was born in Portsmouth, N. H., June 9th, 1829. She
                                was taken to the Shakers in Canterbury when but a child. At an early age she manifested
                                those religious traits that marked her later years. When but little more than a youth
                                she was placed as assistant eldress in the Novitiate order. Twenty-seven years ago she
                                came to Maine to act as one of the ministry for the societies in Alfred and New
                                Gloucester. During all these years she has been an able minister of the truth, her life
                                emphasizing her teachings. A woman of uncommon ability. Her heart was so filled with
                                love for all humanity that the many friends outside of our society who became acquainted
                                with her will share in our bereavement and unite with us in mourning the departure of so
                                able a minister, so loving a sister, and so true a friend. J. B. N. Susan Smith at South
                                Union, Ky., May 7, 1887. Age 75 yrs. 10 mos. and 11 days. Soon, too soon will the
                                ripened sheaves be gathered. A well tried veteran of between sixty and seventy years.
                                II. L. E. Mary J. Thurstin, at Sec. Family, Enfield, N. H. May 5, 1887. Age 59 yrs. 3
                                mos. and 12 days.</p></div3></div2><pb n="145" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!--  
THE MANIFESTO.
POWDER
AbsoSuteSy Pure.
This powder never varies. A marvel of
purity, strength and wholesomeness. More
economical than the ordinary kinds, and
cannot be sold in competition with the multitude of low test, .<hort weight, alum or phosphate powders. Sold only in cans. Royal
Baking Powder Co., 106 Wall-st., N. Y.
AGENTS "WANTED to sell " BE WINISCENCES"
of 60 YEARS in the   NATIONAL METROPOLIS,
JOEN PERLEY POORE
Illustrating the Wit, Humor, and Eccentricities of
noted celebrities. A rin-lsSr illustrated treat of inner Society History, from " ye
olden time " to the wedding of Cleveland. Wonderfully Ponular. Agents report rapiil
sales. Address for circular and terms.
 ., Pub's, Boston, Mass.
CHEAP Reading.
Send     10 cents
and    receive   6
back numbers of THE HOME COMPANION, no two alike, filled with good
reading  for  all homes.           Address,
The Home Companion,
Troy, N. H.
to canvass for one of
the largest, oldest_ rseries in the country. Most liberal terms. Unequaled facilities.
Prices low. Geneva Nursery. Established
1846.   W. & T. SMITH, Geneva, N. Y.
AGENTS WANTED!
established, best-known Nui
The Cosmopolitan
The handsomest, most entertaining, low price,
illustrated family magazine in the world.
($2.50 per year, with a $2.25 premium
free.) Sixty-four beautifully printed pages in
each number, filled with short stories, sketches,
travels, adventures, bright and brief scientific
and literary articles, by distinguished American
and foreign writers, such as Julian Hawthorne,
Harriet Prescott Spofford, George Parsons
Lathrop, Louise Chandler Moulton, J. Macdonald Oxley, Ella Wheeler Wilcox, H. H.
Boyesen, Catherine Owen, Rev. R. Heber
Newton, Alphonse Daudet, Paul Hevse, Count
Tolstoi, Th. Dostoivsky, William Westall and
many others. Also entertaining JDVE1VILE
and invaluable HOUSEHOLD departments.
One or more illustrated articles and several fullpage engravings in every number.
A Shannon   Letter and
Bill File or a Shannon
Sheet-Music Binder
Free   to   every
Subscriber.
These premiums sell
everywhere for $2.25
each. The File is the most
perfect device ever invented for the preservation and
classification (alphabetically and according to date)
of all letters, bills, etc.
Any paper can be referred
to, taken out and put back
without disturbing Ae
others. With the BinUr
one can insert or take out
any piece of music without
disturbing any other sheet.
Get SAMPLE COPY at NEWS STAND or
send 20 Cents to publishers.
AGENTS WANTED. BIG COMMISSIONS PAID.
Schlicht & Field Co., Rochester, N. Y.
b      " \UKu
9225.
*TESTED*
EED
S
SEND '"^'Illustrated CATALOGUE
Vegetable. Flower, Field - -* Kf BT 8"fc C
Plants, Bulbs. Implem'ts. Cs> - - - - - - C,eJPO
EC Id ET ET   by mall on application.
r n[bil   Don't neglect writing for it
HIRAM SIBLEY & CO.
ROCHESTER, N. Y.
322-32S E. Main St.
CHICAGO, ILL.
12-14 N. Clark St.
Student Life is published monthly during
the University year, by the students of
Wasl.in^ton University, St. Louis, Mo. $1
per annum.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
Mt. Lebanon,  N. Y.,
<pb n="" id="p"/>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>