<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0306" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18730601" TEIform="date">June 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="41" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                        <p>Vol. III. No. 6. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. P" ^DIxJRAN9> Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. June, 1873 Fifty
                        Cents per annum. EXCHANGES. PUBLICATION OFFICE, MT. LEBANON, N. Y. ADDRESS SHAKER & SHAKERESS, Not F. W.
                        Evans.</p>
--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother's day" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER'S DAY</head><p TEIform="p">A writer, in the Peace Advocate, proposes to set apart one day in the year to be observed by the women of the
                            nation assembling together, " in hall, church, or parlor," as should best suit their numbers and inclinations,
                            and to be called " Mother's Day." " They should hear a sermon, an oration, an essay or an ode. They should sing
                            hymns and offer prayers. But the one theme should be how to bring God's peace on earth. A record of proceedings
                            should be sent to a central committee, charged with the publication and circulation of an appropriate report. As
                            far as possible, women should be the speakers and writers on these occasions." Julia Howe says: "Let us emulate,
                            not only the industry, but also the harmony of the ant, the bee, and the coral insect; and our efforts,
                            insignificant in isolation may build up institutions and sentiments which shall bless and protect the whole
                            human race." A good suggestion! better than holding tea-parties. Let the mind of the people once settle down to
                            the conviction that they—not the Rulers — are the source of power, and that they can create a Government that
                            will execute, through the laws that they shall enact, their most interior moral and religious convictions ; and
                            we shall have a "Mother's Day." A " Mother's Day " can be made a day of power — a day on which conscience can
                            hold high carnival, before a Lent, in which no blood shall be shed. All women have been earth mothers long
                            enough. Now, if a large number of them will form themselves into a superior order — arise, and become " nursing
                            mothers" to human souls, who shall be born into the kingdom of heaven upon earth—the fulfillment of Millennial
                            prophecies will have commenced. One prominent argument for war, is, that it is a means of checking population;
                            the practical result of which is, that, in England, there are a million and a half more women than men on that
                            island. And, in our own New England, they are fast approximating the same proportion of disparity between the
                            sexes. The formation of a new order, whose members should live in " Platonic love " with each other, is just the
                            thing needed, as a substitute for war. From its ranks, women-rulers — legislators, judges, juries, advocates,
                            physicians, etc., — could be chosen, without being obnoxious to the charge, that the children at home were being
                            neglected while they were caring for the children of the Republic. And the male humans would be no longer under
                            the necessity — instigated by their generative passions — to kill each other in order to make room for their
                            posterity; as, in that Paradise of innocence, there would be room enough for all, who should be properly born,
                            to live until they died a natural death; even if the doctors should, with the soldiers, become an extinct
                            species, in that Prophetical Garden of plenty and physical health. Having been accustomed to observe one day in
                            the year, in commemoration of Mother Ann, the Founder of our Order, we can easily enlarge our conceptions, and
                            keep the day in the name of the great Mother in Deity. What more acceptable offering to the ''Mother of us all"
                            could we there bring than a covenant signed and sealed with our consecrated lives, in keeping "God's peace on
                            this earth? " Hail to the time when all of " earth's warring children " shall keep, and keep forever, a
                            universal "Mother's Day." N. B. — The 2d day of June next is proposed as the first to be observed.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Follow me" TEIform="index"/>FOLLOW ME</head><p TEIform="p">When, in our childhood's leisure hours, we used to steal off into the groves, ramble among the ever-greens,
                            woodbines, honey-suckles, and wild roses, climb the lofty mountain's cliff to catch the inspirations of Nature,
                            as we viewed, in the distance, the variegated land- scape, dressed in vernal bloom, the wondrous beauties of
                            creation, in the skies above, and on the earth beneath, we became pensive, and caught mental visions of heaven,
                            and greatly longed to soar away from earth to that fancied happy land; but no practical conveyance ap- peared to
                            present itself for the journey, and we always had to return from these pleasant reveries earth-bound, still
                            wondering which was the prettiest way " to go to heaven ;" not yet having learned that the way to enjoy heaven
                            was to bring it home to us. Thus onward we wended in one of the myriad paths of life trodden by earth's restless
                            throng of weary travelers, busily seeking the way " to heaven," when, lo! a call beat upon our ears in clarion
                            tones," I am the way; follow me." We sought its source, and found it was the voice of " Christ, the Saviour." We
                            now inquired for his authority, when, from Jordan's banks a voice re-echoed, " This is my beloved Son; hear ye
                            Him." A voice from heaven, though re-echoed from the banks of Jordan, was just the kind of authority that
                            recommended itself to our understanding and desires ; at once we accepted it, and resolved, not only to hear the
                            " Son of God," but to follow Him, whithersoever He goeth, though it be through self-sacrifices, perils of false
                            brethren, persecutions, prisons, or death. Since that eventful hour, we have been a constant inquirer of all
                            whom we met on the heavenly pilgrimage, of those who have tidings from others still on before, aye, and from the
                            worldly throng: Whither traveled Jesus? We called at the vestibule of self pleasures' temple, Multitudes —
                            people of every tongue and nation — were congregated here; we asked, Has "Jesus Christ," the "Saviour of men"
                            worshiped at this shrine 1 Not one averred he had seen Jesus bowing there! We next entered the gilded halls of
                            fortune, where Mammon lay at ease, reclining on luxury's sunny banks, with the entire contents of the horn of
                            plenty in his lap. A selected number of earth's busy millions were seeking heaven here. Of them we inquired,
                            Have you met here " Jesus Christ, the Son of God 1" But none could answer that they had seen him reclining here.
                            In anxious agony of spirit we paused, when lo! his voice, " Lay not up for yourselves treasures on earth, but
                            lay up your treasures in heaven, where neither moth nor rust doth corrupt, and where thieves do not break
                            through and steal." Through a mediator (for we feared to enter their abodes), we next inquired of the residents
                            of the haunts of sensual pleasure, if they had seen Jesus, the Son of God, harbored in their domain,
                            participating in their lascivious feasts ? But, not one had seen him there. An Angel of heavenly type now
                            pointed his finger to the door of these parlors, and, on the lintels thereof, we saw the handwriting of Jesus,
                            thus," Whoso looketh on a woman with intentions to gratify lustful desires, hath committed adultery with her
                            already in his heart." Next, we entered the political arena of ambition's fearful strife, only, however, as a
                            visitor on inquiry; for we had witnessed so many myriad fortunes spent fraudulently to attain to the goal of
                            power and fame, that we had no desire to join the throng. Here we inquired of emperors, kings, potentates, of
                            all the regal powers of earth, if Jesus, the Son of God, had run a race for these goals. But none had ever met
                            him in these fields of fame. But, they naively remarked, Jesus Christ declared, " My kingdom is not of this
                            world." In short, we found<pb n="42" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEK .A.ND He spoil'd the laurel wreath of fame, Made vain
                            ambition blush with shame, Taught, to be truly great at all, The secret lies in being small. " Except ye become
                            as a little child, ye shall in nowise enter the kingdom of heaven ;" that is, innocent and teachable, subject to
                            heavenly tutors. We next visited the closets of the world's philosophers and sages, and inquired if the Son of
                            God obtained the wisdom of godliness, and the power of salvation at these schools. A voice, which we recognized
                            as the words of the Saviour, replied, " The world, by wisdom knew not God." Now we inquired of the chivalrous
                            and vain-glorious armies of earth's kings, nobles, and generals, on the gory fields of battle, if Jesus Christ
                            had marched beneath their gaudy banners ? A general replied," We have heard his instruction," " He that hath no
                            sword, let him sell his coat and buy one." But, the voice of Jesus rang out upon the air, " Put up thy sword
                            into its sheath; for, he that taketh the sword shall perish by the sword." " I came not to destroy men's lives,
                            but to save them." We visited the thrones of earthly kingdoms, inquiring if Jesus Christ was regnant there. But,
                            while wondering at their splendor, and contemplating the immense degradation, suffering, and woe, produced by
                            the wringing of this wealth from the poor and toiling subjects who bowed at these shrines, we heard a voice, it
                            was the cry of Jesus, " My kingdom is not of this world," " He that would be greatest among you, let him be your
                            servant." Then we saw him with a napkin, washing his disciples' feet, and one of these proclaimed, " God hath
                            chosen the poor of this world, rich in faith, and heirs of the kingdom which he hath promised to them that love
                            him." We then desired to know if Jesus ever became tributary to those worldly kings ; for we began to feel
                            weaned and lifted up from earth; her governments and thrones ceased to tempt our ambition; her riches had taken
                            wings ; her fame was vanished ; and we sought a higher life. But now the voice of Jesus, as of yore, beat upon
                            our ears, saying, " Render unto Cesar the things that are Cesar's, and unto God the things that are God's."
                            Jesus here appeared so careful to give to every one his due, we sought him among the judges of earth's kingdoms,
                            to learn his wisdom in the dispensation of justice; but, lo! Jesus was not here, and again we heard his voice,
                            after the manner of authority, " Bless them that curse," " do good to them that despitefully use you and
                            persecute you." We went to the judgment hall; for we would know if Jesus dispensed capital punishment, according
                            to the manner of our civil rulers of earth's kingdoms. Behold a woman was brought before him taken in adultery;
                            he inquired, " Doth no man condemn thee 1" She answered, " No man, Lord." " Neither do I condemn thee, go and
                            sin no more," said Jesus, for " If ye forgive not men their trespasses, neither will your Father in heaven
                            forgive your trespasses." Now, with the professed Christian throng we went with the multitude, to the nuptial
                            hall, to witness the climax of the lover's vow. We inquired, Has Jesus, the Saviour manifested his sanction here
                            ? The throng replied : " He attended a marriage in Cana of Galilee, and turned water into wine for the feast,
                            thus celebrating the marriage." We asked, was the marriage celebration the Qbjec£ of this miracle ? The sacred
                            Record answered, " This beginning of miracles of Jesus, was to manifest his glory, that his disciples might
                            believe on him." Thus the object of Jesus' attendance was to get the audience of the multitude to the miracle,
                            to make converts and disciples, not to justify marriage as an institution of his kingdom ; he would leave that
                            tribute to Cesar. Concerning marriage, he condemned divorce, except for adultery; and when his disciples replied
                            to this, " If the case be so, it is not good to marry," Jesus replied: "All men cannot receive this saying;
                            there be eunuchs that have made themselves eunuchs for the kingdom of heaven's sake (that is, they deny
                            themselves sexual indulgences); he that is able to receive it let him." "I am the resurrection ; in the
                            resurrection they neither marry nor are given in marriage; but are (present tense, while here on earth), as the
                            Angels of God in Heaven." We now heard the echo of an ancient voice; it was that of a Prophet, saying of Jesus,
                            " WTho shall declare his generation ? (for he had none) his life was cut off from the earth " (the generative
                            plane). Now we were caught away with St. John in vision, and saw Jesus as an Angel with a sickle in his hand,
                            and we saw him reaping men from the earthly works of generation and selfishness, and we heard his ancient word,
                            " The harvest is the end of the world." " My kingdom is not of this world," but is established in this world, in
                            answer to my prayer " thy will be done on earth as in heaven; thy kingdom come" (on earth as in heaven).
                            Marriage of the flesh is necessarily a worldly institution; but a celibate life, and the " marriage of the Lamb
                            " (Jesus Christ), spiritual union, is a heavenly institution, inaugurated now on earth. Now we visited the
                            saloons of the voluptuous, and inquired if Jesus set this gluttonous example. An Angel showed us his simple
                            fare, and we heard him say, " the life is more than meat: " he did not join those feasts. WTe then visited the
                            halls of fashion, where gayety, wealth, and pride, swallowed up the thoughts of the multitude, and inquired if
                            Jesus thus lived. But Jesus was not, had not been here, but he remarked to his disciples, " The body is more
                            than raiment." Having vainly sought in worldly societies, and the ways of the world, for the " way, the truth,
                            and the life," and believing Jesus to be a religionist, we next visited the so-called Christian Churches of the
                            multitude, where Pride is worshiped, and where Fashion is umpire; we listened to the long prayers made to be "
                            heard of men ;" to learned, studied, theological sermons of the so-called " divines" who preach " for hire," and
                            inquired, if thus taught Jesus; but sorrowfully we heard his admonition, " This people draweth nigh unto me with
                            their mouths, and honoreth me with their lips, but their hearts are far from me." " In vain do they worship me,
                            teaching for doctrines the commandments of men! " These churches all taught salvation, not as the fruit of good
                            works, but by the merits of Christ. But we heard the voice of Jesus above the roar and clamor of the multitude,
                            saying, " My reward is with me, to give to every one according as his works shall be." We turned from these
                            temples of fashion, pride, and folly, and inquired for the instructions of Jesus, and lo ! his voice sounded
                            aloud, saying to this babel throng of worshipers, "Why do you transgress-the commandments of God by your
                            traditions ?" " Every plant which my Heavenly Father hath not planted shall be rooted up."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Giles B. Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Convention" TEIform="index"/>CONVENTION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>Elder James S. Prescott, of the Shakers at North Union, Warrensville,
                            delivered a short address, which we print in full:</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">We are pleased to meet with the Spiritualist Association of Cleveland, and with the chil- dren's "
                                    Progressive Lyceum," to commemorate the twenty-fifth anniversary of " Modern Spi- ritualism " to the
                                    world. In celebrating this event we have a sentiment to offer : " Modern Spiritualism ! We hail its
                                    advent as the harbinger of the Millennium ; based upon the law of progression, co operating with and
                                    through visible agencies, the last and only hope for the redemption of the human race." When it first
                                    went to the world, it took the inhabitants by surprise. It commenced on the animal plane in the
                                    rudimental sphere, and progressed rapidly until it reached the intellectual, and is now the all
                                    absorbing topic, and delightful theme of seers and sages, poets and philosophers, extending to all
                                    classes, ranks and conditions of people, from the crowned heads of Europe, down to the humblest indi-
                                    vidual that walks our streets. And still the subject is not exhausted. It is beginning to assume a new
                                    form, or phase, and that is the evolution of the moral and spiritual faculties which will lead to a
                                    moral reform — a virgin life. This is what the world needs more than any thing else — men have been
                                    governed by the back-brain region long enough. Is it not time that Spiritualists took another step
                                    higher on the ladder of progression ? This can onlv be done by co-operating with the " spirit world ;"
                                    as saith the poet: "Let us grasp the hands of the angels, As they spread their shining wings, They are
                                    singing, Come up higher. Reach after heavenly things." It is said there is something very revolutionary
                                    in the character and mission of " Modern Spiritualism." A late writer says that "the world is now upon
                                    the verge of birth into the era of moral growth, of which we have as yet had no scientific formulation."
                                    This is what is needed—moral growth, moral reform, in every department of human society, beginning with
                                    the priests and rulers of the people, the heads of the civil department not excepted. We are living in
                                    the days of the fulfillment of prophecy: " And he will destroy in this mountain the face of the covering
                                    cast over all people, and the vail that is spread over all nations." Isaiah, 25: 7. Mountain signifies a
                                    high place. It means wickedness in high places, of honor, emolument and trust, under the covering of a
                                    vail of dishonesty, hypocrisy and deception, which is about to be taken off and destroyed. It means the
                                    " social evil," and legal prostitution, cloaked under the cov- ering of marriage, and a false religion,
                                    which will be destroyed by the exposition and testimony of living witnesses. This is what is needed —
                                    moral growth — supposing it should lead to a virgin life; and there should be an army of seven thousand
                                    volunteers, who will never more bow the knee to the Baal of lust, of equal number of both sexes,
                                    enjoying the society and companionship of angels claiming an equality with them, having no intercourse
                                    but such as the angels approve, which is social, what could be more desirable, and in accordance with
                                    the great law of progress, and in the full glow of the evolution of the moral and spiritual faculties,
                                    man's highest aspiration ? We will now attend to answering some questions. The Yankees, you know, are
                                    very inquisitive. Are the calamities sweeping over the earth the fulfillment of prophecy ? They
                                    certainly are. What prophecy1? A certain prophecy given in 1843. Where ? In every Shaker community in
                                    the United States. Do you not think they will cease soon ? Never ! until the cause is put away. What is
                                    the cause ? The cause assigned is the wickedness of the inhabitants ; in living in constant-and
                                    perpetual violation of natural laws, which are the laws of God. Why did you not tell ua 42 <pb n="43" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> of these prophecies before ? We did tell of them; " these things were not done in a corner
                                    ;" they were made public at the time, and the world did not believe our report, neither do they now
                                    believe, except a very few. Is there no way to avert these calamities? Put away the cause and the effect
                                    will cease. Cease to do wickedly. Return to the law of nature — keep that law unviolated — learn to do
                                    right; live up to your highest convictions of right, regardless of a false public opinion. " For when
                                    thy judgments are in the earth, the inhabitants of the world will learn righteousness." Isaiah, 26:9.
                                    They will learn to do right from principle, if they learn at all, not because they are compelled by the
                                    civil law. Therefore, we object on this ground, to having the terms God, Christ, and the Bible, ever put
                                    into the Constitution of the United States. We protest against this Trinity ever being inserted in that
                                    instrument. We believe the wise fathers who framed it were inspired men, and their inspiration holds
                                    good yet, and will to the end of time. If Christianity cannot stand upon its own merits, without calling
                                    to its aid the arm of the civil and ecclesiastical powers combined to sustain it, we say, let it go
                                    down! — the sooner the better! The world has had enough of the union of Church and State, during the
                                    dark ages. The freedom of speech and of the press is already assailed in New York, and, " if these
                                    things be done in the green tree, what will be done in the dry ? " We never swear; but, in the language
                                    of Thomas Jefferson, we affirm " upon the altars of God, eternal hostility to every form of tyranny over
                                    the mind of man," and woman too. Where now is George Francis Train, one of earth's noblest men ? In the
                                    Tombs of Kew York! Ah! What was his crime? Why, for quoting obscene language from the Bible, and
                                    circulating it through the United States mails. Is that all ? That same Bible, too, that is set up as a
                                    Christian standard to be recognized by all as such, by putting it into the Constitution of the United
                                    States. What a paradox! [," Hark from the Tombs a doleful sound." Human organizations are good and
                                    indis- pensable, so far as they go to facilitate and promote human progress; but, when they operate
                                    against, and stand in the way, and say, Thus far shalt thou go, and no further, they ought to be
                                    reconstructed immediately on a more liberal and scientific basis. Not in the lower, but in the evolution
                                    of the higher, moral and spiritual faculties. Then will the Shakers and Spiritualists co-operate
                                    together, occupying the same platform. " How has the gold changed, and the most fine gold become dim."
                                    The pagan Gentile Christian Church of to-day has failed to reform the world. It is not what the Jewish
                                    Pentecostal Church was eighteen hundred years ago. Then the Gospel of salvation was preached free,
                                    without money and without price, and a poor man stood as good a chance as a rich man. Now it is preached
                                    for " manhood and money." Then " the poor had the Gospel preached to them." Now it is preached to the
                                    rich in a special manner, and the reason assigned for this change is, that the rich need it more than
                                    the poor and are better able to pay for it, because " the earth is the Lord's and the fullness thereof,
                                    and the cattle upon a thousand hills." " My ways are eq ual saith the Lord — your ways are unequal." We
                                    will conclude by reading one of our inspired poems: " From the dark shades of earth, I'll away ! I'll
                                    away ! To my home in that better land. Through the trumpet that's sounding, I hear the angels say,
                                    Hasten on, there's a better land, Toil on, struggle on, fear not the conflict, There is rest in the
                                    better land. If the cross you will bear, A crown you shall wear, In heaven, the better land."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Cleveland herald" TEIform="index"/> Cleveland Herald.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Non-resistance" TEIform="index"/>Non-resistance.</head><p TEIform="p">The non-resistant Lamb, by any manifestation of combativeness, increases its danger from fighting animals.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our shaker home" TEIform="index"/>OUR SHAKER HOME</head><p TEIform="p">How lovely our mountain home appears in the calm, still morning! All is so quiet; the sun looks down so joyfully
                            on the beautiful landscape, that gladly responds to its smiles. Whence comes its beauty, if it be not from the
                            peace that reigns over it, and from the sweet influences that element throws over all it can reach and touch ?
                            No wonder that we love it, when we see the manifestations of its presence in Nature. And still more does it
                            attract our admiration, when we behold it operating in the higher realms of human existence ; when, pervading
                            the social life and relations of beings endowed with mental and social powers, and exercising those powers for
                            mutual good and happiness. Doing good is the essence of life. The feelings of the heart cannot go out in love
                            and tenderness toward our fellow-men, our brethren and sisters, whether in Nature or in God, without the good we
                            thus do, reflecting back upon ourselves, and making us better, nobler, purer, happier than we were before. In a
                            community life, based upon true Christian principle?, this is realized better than any- where else. For the sake
                            of these principles, we have sacrificed all of a lower nature ; we have secluded ourselves externally from the
                            world with all its influences, and from our own hearts and minds we are constantly expelling those elements that
                            would otherwise produce among us the same conditions that cause the troubles and sorrows of life there. Thus the
                            will of God is done here on earth, as it is done in heaven. It directs all who subject themselves to its
                            guidance, onward and upward to higher degrees of goodness and truth, but further and further away from every
                            thing opposite to its own nature. As a reward, it brings the satisfaction of a justified conscience, a power of
                            self-control, unknown in any other condition, and a measure of that peace, which overshadows even the least one
                            of God's children. Under the reign of this divine power, all is love and harmony; like always produce like.
                            Jesus Christ said : " If I be lifted up, I will draw all men to me." It is not recorded of Ann Christ, that she
                            ever spoke those same words, but she did what they indicated; and so do her followers today. They draw to
                            themselves all souls, who come to them to be attracted, and they do it by love. Beaming from the eyes, speaking
                            from the lips, radiating from the features of the countenance, manifesting itself in the smallest actions,
                            inspiring through good and virtuous examples, does this love perform its work of lifting up those who are
                            fallen, of saving those who are lost. Like fishes in a net are they caught; many are the meshes, and strong;
                            tighter and tighter are they drawn, till no escape is possible. The fish must give up; he is conquered. Here is
                            the end of the figure, borrowed from nature (I would not like to carry it further; I wish they were forever done
                            away with, both the catching offish and the destroying of other animal life, by human agency); but in the case
                            of spiritual growth, of which it represented only one feature, this is merely the beginning, the first steps of
                            a long march, reaching onward through eternity, and ending in God. It is the peace-maker's first victory in the
                            conquest of aliuman soul. Why should there not be joy, where there is peace ? Why should there not be sunshine
                            where there is purity? When clouds arise over our heads, hindering the rays of the physical sun from bringing us
                            their sweet messages of cheer and comfort, where do they come from? From the earth are the vapors exhaled, and
                            back to it they return, whenever they find an opportunity. It is the same in the minds of men. From the earthly
                            nature, ascend all influences that becloud and darken the spirit, and shut out the higher light; the workings of
                            the carnal and selfish elements in the inner being, bring; forth their corresponding results on the outward
                            stature, — gloominess, stupidity, insensibility to the feelings and conditions of all around. While the fruits
                            of a purely spiritual and heavenly life are love, peace, and joy forevermore.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bretzner, Emil" TEIform="persName"/>Emil Bretzner, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York, April 9, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co. ' N. Y., U. S. A. April
                                9,1873</head><p TEIform="p">To Thomas Hull, England: Dear Friend : Elder Frederick has just mentioned your case to me, and thinking you
                                might like to hear from some one who has recently entered the Community, I concluded to take the liberty of
                                writing you. Perhaps you may have seen my name mentioned in the Medium, in connection with the Spiritual
                                movement in Bromsgrove, Worcestershire. I came here some six weeks ago, and, up to the time of leaving my
                                native place, was a worker in the cause of Spiritualism. The time I have spent here has been the happiest
                                period of my life, and I have enjoyed a continual feast of spiritual things. To me Shakerism is Spiritualism
                                reduced to order, thus avoiding the various anomalies to be met with in Spiritualism of the current sort.
                                The joys I experienced in Spiritualism have been increased a hundredfold in Shakerism, and my Shaker home
                                daily becomes more precious to me. I have lived in the town and the country, but it has never been my lot
                                elsewhere to be among so many truly religious and loving souls as are to be found in this Community. Peace
                                and purity reign throughout our domain. The history of how I became a Shaker is as follows: Many years ago I
                                was impressed with the idea that for a man to be spiritually perfect he must lead a celibate life. When
                                Elder Frederick lectured in London, I learned from the Spiritual periodicals that the Shakers held views
                                similar to my own, and some time afterward, in November, 1871, I was impressed by a spirit friend to write
                                him. I resolved to come to Mt. Lebanon, but was detained by business matters until last February, when I
                                came over here with my mother and sister. Although we had a comfortable home in England, and a fair prospect
                                of " getting on in the world," yet we feel glad we elected to come here. The more we see of the confusion
                                and strife prevailing throughout society, both in temporal and spiritual matters, the more do we appreciate
                                the peace and joy of the Shaker Order. The country round here is mountainous like many parts of England, and
                                the locality of the Shaker village is very healthful. The houses are built in good style with every modern
                                contrivance for convenience and health of the inmates. In this family (North Family) we have six English
                                Brothers and several Sisters, while other European nationalities are represented among us. Our food is of
                                the most wholesome kind, properly cooked, and in short, no pains are spared to secure the good health,
                                physically and spiritually, of all members of the Shaker Society. In conclusion, I would say, that I am
                                acquainted with (Mr.) Burns and other London Spiritualists, also the Birmingham Spiritualists, Franklin,
                                Hawkes, Smith and others. Trusting we may at some future time meet face to face, and with kind regards, I
                                remain yours sincerely,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witheford, Ernest J." TEIform="persName"/>Ernest J. Witheford</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Troy, April 11, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Troy, April 11,1873</head><p TEIform="p">Editors of Shaker and Shakeress: — I have just received the first four numbers of your publication for this
                                year (having subscribed last Sabbath), and having eagerly devoured their contents, I hasten, before it
                                fades, to give the impression they made upon my mind. I am of the " world's people," to be sure, but a
                                SHAKEEESS. 4:3 <pb n="44" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKER AND man may be magnanimous enough to concede the good contained
                                in theories and systems to which he cannot fully subscribe. You, doubtless, have heard, to nausea, the
                                objection to Shakerism ; that it is unnatural, a monkish and nunnish mode of living; but you answer it, if
                                not convincingly to us weak, passion-ridden mortals, who have not attained the sublimity of self-control,
                                you indicate to us, yet, in such lofty and earnest terms as to excite the deepest respect in every worthy
                                bosom. Dedicated to purity, commencing with the spiritual, and reaching upward to the ideal, you are a
                                glorious anomaly in this age of corruption, materialism, and groveling aims. Every page of your little paper
                                is elevating in its tone, so full is it of the spirit of self- abnegation. You not only proclaim, but
                                faithfully practice the principle of heroic duty, and thus set a unique and much needed example in these
                                days of utter selfishness and vice. Whether or not you have properly embodied it, remains to be seen. But
                                your organization is founded upon a grand idea; and, in your isolated communities, is unfolding a germ of
                                promise whose full blush shall be the race's regeneration. Continence chastest love, universal brotherhood;
                                what better destiny can we wish than that their empire be established over us ? While all mankind seeks for
                                its own, you, the pioneer exponents of the Millenial Era, are far ahead on the upward pathway, and, though
                                conscious of your higher plane, exhibit remarkable liberality toward other sects and doctrines. If morality
                                has an impregnable refuge on the globe, if is among you, Avhere true and changeless religion (not fickle
                                theology) has erected her temple. Goaded and begrimed, in this busy turmoil of existence, I shall value the
                                monthly visits of the Shaker and Shakeress, as would a traveler in a hot desert appreciate a cooling gale,
                                or a limpid and gelid spring. Though we never anticipate a conversion to your technical tenets, thoughts
                                surcharged with so much that is ennobling cannot fail to influence and help any right-intentioned
                                individual. As one reads he feels his nobler nature quickened and expanding within him. Heaven bless
                                Shakerism, at least for its honorable motives, its undefiled aspirations, and its exemplary life!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Williams, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theo. Williams</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Danby, Vermont, March 8, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Danby, Vt. March 8,1873</head><p TEIform="p">I like the independence and nobleness of the " Shaker and Shakeress." Of course, I do not Bee the exact
                                application of some of your peculiar principles. I cannot appreciate every identical tenet of those with
                                whom I come in contact; yet I feel that the spirit of kindness, manifest in the " Shaker and Shakeress,"
                                toward those who honestly differ with it, is a high recommendation of those who conduct it. And, as an
                                exponent of Shakerism (I use the term in its noblest sense), I think it carries an influence upon its very
                                face recommendatory of its high purpose and aim. Certainly, it is not so much what we believe as what we do,
                                that commends us to the kind regards of the good in all communities. Belief is not a matter of choice, but
                                of evidence. We must needs believe, when the evidence of a fact, or proposition reaches our comprehension.
                                Consequently, belief, or disbelief, does not determine the moral character of a human being. With best
                                wishes for your health and prosperity, I remain, with great respect,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Baker, A. S." TEIform="persName"/>A. S. BAKER</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evidence" TEIform="index"/>EVIDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">It is for lack of evidence that men do not believe in a future state of existence, and that those who do believe
                            have such vague conceptions of it, because their minds are so engrossed in the pursuit of pleasure, ambition, or
                            the cares of this life, that they do not attend to the evidence existing in their own souls. Franklin, reasoning
                            from principle, or the angel side of his nature, was induced by humanitarian considerations of the cruelty and
                            injustice done to animals, to abandon a meat diet. He afterward adopted it again, from ob- serving that animals
                            ate each other. Thus, reasoning from the animal side of his nature, and the habits of an inferior order of
                            creation, over which man was appointed to rule in the spirit of goodness and mercy that comes from above, he let
                            go the restraint which the latter placed upon appetite. Which was the superior wisdom, that which taught
                            restraint, or that which removed it ? The wisdom from above is first pure, and then peaceable; full of mercy and
                            good fruits to all of God's creatures. Man forsook his own mercies by loving the thing that is not good, and, by
                            neglecting the wisdom from above, he has created false and unnatural appetites and conditions, in which the
                            image or reflection of true wisdom cannot be found. Still blinded by continuing the original perversion, or
                            unwilling to accept the treatment necessary for a radical cure, he seeks a remedy in expedients — outside
                            cleansings or whitewashings — local applications, and the excision of excrescences from the social system;
                            leaving the cause, which exists in the life, untouched. Consequently the disease when reduced in one form,
                            breaks out in another, until it may be truly said that society is full of wounds and bruises, and putrefying
                            sores, from the crown of the head to the soles of the feet. Jesus adverted to the same state of things when
                            reproving the hypocrisy of his countryman, He said: " Woe unto you Scribes and Pharisees, hypocrites, for ye are
                            as graves which appear not, and the men that walk over them are not aware of them.* Ye make clean the outside of
                            the cup and the platter, but within are full of extortion and excess. Thou blind Pharisee, make clean the inside
                            of the cup and the platter, that the outside may be clean also." The last clause points out the divine method
                            which descends to us through the revelation of Christ. This Anointing Spirit, directed by a wisdom that
                            comprehends all, and sustained by a power that overrules all, to the destined final righteous adjustment of all,
                            commences by cleansing the inside — changing the life of the individual — eradicating the poison from the
                            centre—purifying the fountain from spiritual disease — thus plucking out the evil plant by the roots, and
                            changing conditions, until restored to the image or reflection of the Divine Law. This introduces harmony, co-
                            operation, and that unity of spirit which excludes conflict and disturbance, by its very compactness of order,
                            and the power with which it invests the individual. Consequently, by this channel the peace and love of God can
                            flow into vessels fitted to receive and retain, and also to diffuse it when needful. This method uproots the
                            world from .its foundations, and turns it upside down. For the world is made of individual lives, and when all
                            are redeemed that can be induced to work with the wisdom from above, there will be nothing left of the world
                            that any rational being can desire or enjoy. The peace and justification, without which there can be neither
                            heaven nor happiness, will all be withdrawn to build up the new and supernal creation, of which this natural
                            world, as well as the natural soul of rcan, is but the shell or husk. Blessed and happy beyond all others will
                            those be who secure a place in this rising building, while still encased in the earthly form. " All such offer
                            to God the first ripe fruits of their souls, and thereby secure that honor and crown of glory which no other
                            souls can ever obtain." They will everlastingly increase in goodness and purity, and draw perpetually nearer the
                            eternal fountain of all happiness and peace. But the fruits of a life of sin, and disobedience to the voice of
                            wisdom, must all be burnt up, and those who bear such fruits will suffer irretrievable loss. What are a few
                            short-lived pleasures, that place the receiver in the power of the enemy — Death — wh*i compared with the
                            eternal glories, and everincreasing joys of the righteous ? If thou art wise, thou art wise for thyself. If thou
                            arb otherwise, thou alone must bear the final result. *And thus become unclean seven days (Num. 19: 2) this kept
                            all true Jews out of grave-yards. Ed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. O. HoUister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel race" TEIform="index"/>THE GOSPEL RACE</head><p TEIform="p">Paul, in his exhortations to the Corinthians, alludes to the Grecian games, which consisted of running, leaping,
                            etc. " Know ye not," gaith the Apostle, " that they which run in a race, run all, but one receiveth the prize ?
                            So run that ye may obtain." 1 Cor. 9 : 24. According to history, the celebration of the running match excited
                            great interest, and the preparation for these races was very extensive. All who presented themselves as candi-
                            dates for the prize, were required to submit to very strict regulations: Their diet consisted of very coarse,
                            unpalatable food; each candidate was to bear a good moral character, and to practice Bevere exercises, etc.,
                            according to certain prescribed rules, for twelve months before racing; all who participated in the race
                            divested themselves of all needless clothing. The successful runner was greeted with shouts and cheers by the
                            people, and crowned with a laurel wreath or a garland of flowers. The Gospel is compared to a race. The course
                            marked out is the straight and narrow path of self-denial, which leads from this world to the world to come. All
                            professors of religion are candidates for the prize, which is a crown of salvation. When starting in this Gospel
                            race, all are required to lay aside every weight (by honest confession), relinquish the besetting sin, and run
                            the race with patience, etc. Some run well for a time, then fall, overpowered by their besetting sin. A few
                            persevere to the end of the race, and win the prize. Observe this : In the Grecian race, only one could win the
                            reward, which was a crown of fading flowers ; and the judge was sometimes partial. In the Gospel race, all may
                            run so as to win : And the Judge is righteous, and gives crowns of righteousness that fade not away.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carpets" TEIform="index"/>CARPETS</head><p TEIform="p">Carpets are injurious to health, so far as the lungs are concerned. They accumulate dirt, and hold it as a
                            reservoir. Every motion of persons, things in the room, or even of the air, causes it to rise in an impalpable
                            powder, to be seen only in the rays of sunshine that may chance to get into the room to fade the colors of the
                            carpets. Therefore, to preserve the carpets and the accompanying furniture in their beauty, carefully exclude
                            the light; and, to exclude the dust, keep the windows closed; and, to preserve the health of the family, let
                            them live in other rooms, with no carpets, plenty of air, and floods of sunshine. This arrangement would keep
                            things even between the family and friends visiting, inasmuch as they pay, for a generous hospitality, with the
                            most precious of all coin — their own health.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every good desire and feeling..." TEIform="index"/>Every good desire and feeling...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Every good desire and feeling, whether uttered or unexpressed, is prayer. It is converse and communion with
                            unseen guardian friends by which we are spiritually educated, and we feel a tranquillity while in this element
                            that the tumultuous waves of passion cannot reach, for our hearts, through prayer, are lifted into angel
                            spheres.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Subscribers" TEIform="index"/>SUBSCRIBERS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Atii new subscribers (50 cts.) will receive the paper from January 1st, 1873, until January 1st, 1874. Those
                            whose subscription expires in July next, may remit 30 cts. to pay until January 1st, 1874.</p></div2><pb n="45" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: gold king" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: GOLD KING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">We are accustomed to look upon those who hoard up silver and gold, and who add one pile to another and feast
                            their eyes with the sight thereof, as idolaters. Some would say, such persons were extremely selfish. But it is
                            usually the case, that, through an excessive thirst for more gold, they deprive themselves of even the necessary
                            comforts of life. Hence a miser, in the estimation of an enlightened public, will be deemed a slave to avarice.
                            But we would ask, are there not many kinds and degrees of slavery existing in society at the present time ? Gold
                            is the crowned king of to-day, and holds out a glittering scepter to the warrior, to the ambitious man, to the
                            sensualist, to the devotee of fashion, and to the wine-bibber. " Wealth is power." By it, the nation's warring
                            armies upon the land, and her fleets upon the seas, receive their support. Gold aids the wine-bibber, who seeks
                            to satiate his raging thirst, and he drinks, and drinks again, till the dregs are bitterness, and demons mock
                            him! And the sensualist, by the same means, finds easy access to the foul pools from whence he draws his
                            supplies. The devotee of fashion bows before the throne of king Gold, and throws her all at his feet; while he,
                            in return, bedecks her with jewels and costly pearls, and clothes her with scarlet and fine raiment, and helps
                            her to seek out many inventions through which to gratify desires that never can be satisfied; for the more they
                            are indulged, the stronger they become, and the greater are their demands. Is not this slavery ? Can we marvel,
                            when we hear the low murmuring, the discordant sounds, and the loud wail of grief, so often borne along on the "
                            wings of the wind," which come up from all ranks of society ? While self is the center around which all the
                            thoughts and feelings revolve, and to which all the labors and efforts are directed, there can be no real
                            happiness ; for, unless the physical powers co-operate with the social, mental, and moral attributes of the
                            being, there must be inharmony ; the better part is enslaved, entombed, and shut out from the light of true
                            science, which shines upon the natural man and woman who stand in moral integrity on the earthly plane. In the
                            natural order, the family relation is an indication of a desire which inheres in the human soul to expand beyond
                            selfhood' and, although the circle thus formed is narrow and partial in its bearings, yet it is an advance from
                            individualism toward universality : Toiling for others, even if it be for kith and kin, is better than
                            concentrated selfishness. And, when individuals go outside of the family circle, and extend aid and influence to
                            friends and neighbors, or, going still farther, they work for the nation's weal unselfishly, just in proportion
                            as they enlarge their sphere of usefulness to bless humanity, they will receive a blessing in return, whether it
                            be in a temporal, intellectual, or moral point of view. The world's benefactors never fail of receiving from the
                            great public heart, a grateful response to their labors, though many have waited a long time before their
                            efforts were appreciated. And if there are some who, for conscience God-ward, and from love to truth and
                            humanity, have left the natural, genera- tive plane of life altogether, with its partial relations and selfish
                            professions, and are rising into a new life, seeking the order of angelic beings, and striving to be like them,
                            consecrating their substance and gains, temporally and spiritually, to the " God of the whole earth," and of all
                            souls; do not such give the greatest manifestation of unselfish love possible to mortals ? And will not such lay
                            up treasures in the heavenly kingdom, and secure a great reward ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Triumph of truth" TEIform="index"/>TRIUMPH OF TRUTH</head><p TEIform="p">All truth is from God. Truth is the embodiment of every principle in religion and science, revealed to man and
                            woman through chosen mediums whom God appoints. Those principles were more clearly illustrated and exemplified
                            in the life of Jesus, and in the lives of his immediate followers, than in any mediums or teachers who had
                            preceded them. The life of Jesus was the opposite of falsehood and error. He said : " I am the way, and the
                            truth, and the life;" showing that the Spirit which is able to lead into all truth, had taken up its abode in
                            him, by which he was enabled to set the most perfect example of godliness that the world had ever witnessed.
                            Inasmuch as he lived the true life and walked in the light, he could say : " Follow me ; I am the way." As the
                            Christ Spirit has baptized me, and become my Leader, so will I baptize and lead you. " The Law was given by
                            Moses," and he prepared the people for the more spiritual work of " grace and truth, which came by Jesus
                            Christ." But only those who were thus prepared received his testimony. The world, those who loved the sensual
                            life, and chose darkness rather than light, rejected him, because he testified that their deeds were evil. And
                            they imagined that, by crucifying the man Jesus, they would put an end to the truths which he uttered, and they
                            would hear no more of those principles which he inculcated, that were so distasteful to them; but in this they
                            were disappointed ; for the good seed which he had sown had taken deep root in the hearts of his followers. Nor
                            could they, by a long course of malignant persecution of his followers, eradicate truth from the earth. But the
                            spirit of antichrist finally gained access to the primitive Church, and did its work, and a long night of
                            darkness, error, and superstition ensued. A few witnesses, scattered here and there, clothed in garments of
                            mourning, kept the lamp of truth burning, which made the darkness more apparent. The prince of darkness swayed
                            the scepter over his willing subjects. In Scriptural language, " Darkness covered the earth, and gross darkness
                            the people." Liberty of conscience, and freedom of speech, were almost unknown. And those who dared to dissent
                            from the Church of Rome were subjected to torture and death in many ways; religious bigotry and intolerance
                            seemed to have reached their climax. But, in the fullness of time, a way was prepared, through suffering
                            witnesses, for the second advent of the Christ Spirit, through a female (Ann Lee). Again the spirit of
                            persecution was aroused, and the enemies of the cross seemed determined, if possible, to suppress the truth
                            which was revealed through her. This they were unable to do; but, through divine agency, she was directed to
                            come to America, which was then seeking to free itself from the yoke of British tyranny. And, when liberty of
                            conscience was established, she and her little band found a freedom to live and promulgate their religious faith
                            that was denied to them in their native land. It was to them a safe " refuge from the storm." We believe that
                            the principles of truth, as contained in the Gospel, which Mother Ann lived and taught, will continue to advance
                            and gain strength, until all man-made creeds shall be level with the dust. Truth will out-live error. We would
                            not set bounds to Truth. New spiritual truths will be revealed from time to time, and souls will be led from "
                            faith to faith," till all true Believers shall be of one heart and mind, which will be to know and do the will
                            of God. Souls who are under the influence of truth, Avill be led to confess and forsake all known sin, and make
                            reparation for all wrong done to others. This will enable them to become new creatures — live a new life. They
                            will become simple and teachable as little children, and thus gain an entrance into the kingdom of heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, M." TEIform="persName"/>M. Johnson, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Liberty" TEIform="index"/>LIBERTY</head><p TEIform="p">" The sweet sound of liberty now is rolling: May it extend over mountain and plainT" That " liberty wherewith
                            Christ hath made us free 1" how it echoes and vibrates through the heart of every true Shaker! O the glorious
                            Liberty of the Gospel! While reading the views of the Press, my soul breathes forth in prayer to Him " avIio
                            tempers the wind to the shorn lamb," to strengthen and support the brave souls who dare to raise their voices
                            against the evils of the present generation. The seed of the enemy is sown, and is rapidly bearing fruit. Yet,
                            although mankind, in their natural wisdom and understanding, have followed in the paths of sin and wickedness,
                            partaking of the fruits of evil, to which our first natural mother yielded, there is, at the present time, no
                            excuse for continuing any longer therein. The day has dawned, when a spiritual Mother comes to our rescue; and
                            we behold, in her, one who rooted out every evil seed from her own heart, thereby giving us a perfect example of
                            -purity, to guide us onward through all the labyrinths of iniquity. Now the question arises: ' Have we not a
                            right to proclaim our freedom throughout the length and breadth of the land, that others may hear the sweet
                            sound, and gather to the standard of Liberty ? I hear the loud tones of response from our lovely " JShakeress,"
                            YEA! And my earnest prayer is, that the truths poured forth through your columns may ultimately find an abiding
                            place in the heart of every woman; for I believe there are many women writhing beneath this " yoke of bondage,"
                            who, were it in their power, would gladly shake off their fetters. Lovely " Shakeress," I feel and know that I
                            have a right to rejoice and dance — and will — " with those that make merry ;" for whereas I was bound, now I am
                            free.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Strowbridge, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Strowbridge, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pure language" TEIform="index"/>PURE LANGUAGE</head><p TEIform="p">Ignorance is blind to right judgment; but intelligence throws light on all solvable pro- blems. How important,
                            then, is the necessity of attention to the proper unfolding, education, and training of every faculty of the
                            mind in the various departments of knowledge which develops the understanding to a clear comprehension of those
                            fundamental principles which are the basis of all true science, ethics, theology, religion, and progress.
                            Commencing with the a b c, or first principles, and carefully analyzing each successive lesson of a subject of
                            mind or matter, to learn or ascertain the elements of which it is composed, and the quality and significance of
                            each ; then again compounding into a variety of forms, substance or consistencies, to answer the use and
                            necessity of the occasion. By these processes many things are brought to light which were before vailed in
                            mystery. What was thought to be incomprehensible miracles, is shown to be the outgrowth and unfolding of God's
                            immutable laws, which are in harmony with all his works, and underlie the diversified revealments of the wonders
                            of creation in every form and feature. Is this knowledge to be obtained from books only ? By no means. As mind
                            is superior to books, being their creator and author, so is it capable of much culture without their aid. Yet
                            very much can be learned from the writ45 <pb n="46" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEE .A.ND ings of the investigator and
                            experienced authors in any department of life. Hence a necessity of the study of books when the mind is
                            sufficiently matured to comprehend the arbitrary signs and significance of written language. Education commences
                            with the infant when it opens its eyes to behold the tangible objects by which it is surrounded. From this
                            period should the careful attention, guidance, and assistance of parents, or other authorized guardians and
                            educators, be employed to give proper direction to the growing and expanding intelligence and understanding
                            which follow the movements and absorb the examples of those with whom they are associated or connected, to be
                            made manifest at times and in manners least expected, and frequently to the astonishment of those who have
                            unguardedly done or said that which was improper in their presence. If all adults, who hold themselves as
                            members of civilized or cultivated society, would pay due regard to propriety in conduct and conversation,
                            teaching the same to their immediate posterity, not many generations would pass before a marked improvement
                            would be perceptible in the elevation of the human race. The inmates of dens and resorts of vice and crime would
                            become decimated, and the moral atmosphere of cities and villages clear and healthful. Above all, will those who
                            come into the Christ-sphere — the resurrection life — adopt and exclusively use that pure language which God, by
                            his Prophet, has promised. " For then will I turn to the people a pure language, that they may all call upon the
                            name of the Lord, to serve him with one consent." Zeph. 8: 9.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Harriet" TEIform="persName"/>Harriet Hastings, Shaker Village, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Eldress A.:" TEIform="index"/>Dear El-dress A.:</head><p TEIform="p">I drop this line that you may know I have not fallen asleep, or passed into the spirit land ; but still live
                                to work, and to bless. The undying love of kindred hearts, made pure by self-denial and obedience to the
                                principles of truth, we cherish as a " pearl of great price." But who can know its worth save those who have
                                sold all selfish and partial love to obtain it ? Those who give but part, receive accordingly. Our
                                consecrations are made to God, and not to mortals ; and we cannot hide the defects in our characters from
                                Him, nor from the eyes of immortal guardians, who are sent to keep their vigils around us. We must all
                                receive the just reward of our doings ; we cannot deceive nor rob God ; neither will He withhold our just
                                dues. If we are untrue to ourselves, we commit a wrong against our own well-being, and we must suffer the
                                conse- quences. This principle is illustrated by the Bible story of Ananias and Sapphira, who, through love
                                of pelf, reserved a part, and sought to evade the truth ; and their reward quickly followed. How important
                                it is that all who profess the Christian religion, should be true to that profession : If we " name the name
                                of Christ to depart from iniquity," walk in the light, and be willing to be seen and known just as Ave are;
                                then we shall have confidence toward God, and can draw nigh unto Him in prayer, and ask for what we need. If
                                we live in purity like the angels, we shall rise where we can stand with them on the pure plane of spiritual
                                truth, and travel the " highway cast up for the ransomed of the Lord to walk in ;" Where we shall feel the
                                gentle dews descend, and the healing zephyrs of heavenly influences blow upon the vineyard of the Lord ; so
                                that every branch therein may become fruitful. After the wintry winds have passed, and spring time returns,
                                all Nature is glad, and wears a cheerful aspect, and seems to feel new life, strength, and vigor. We watch
                                the opening buds, and rejoice when the flowers ap- pear. Thus may it be spiritually. Let us leave the cold
                                regions of " the world" and Bin, and dwell in light and love, which will warm and vivify the heart, and
                                cause the seeds of truth to grow, and flowers of innocence to bloom. This will be an eternal spring time to
                                the soul.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Riley, Nancy" TEIform="persName"/>Nancy Riley, Hancock</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Eldress A.:" TEIform="index"/>Dear Eldress A.:</head><p TEIform="p">Is the testimony borne by the Shakers of today the same as that borne by Jesus and his apostles eighteen
                                centuries ago ? And, in their daily lives, do their profession and practice agree? These are simple
                                propositions for discussion by those who are interested in the growth and spread of true principles. If the
                                underlying principles of the institution are true, they will bear strict scrutiny ; if they are false, let
                                it be proved by honest investigation. We claim that Shakerism is not only a revi val of Christianity, as
                                preached and practiced by Jesus and his Apostles, and also practically exemplified in the primitive. Church;
                                but that it is the revelation of the Christ Spirit, through the female, which has given new impulse and
                                strength to all its parts. May I be permitted, through the columns of the Shaker and Shakeress, to express
                                my gratitude for the great privilege that I am enjoying in my beautiful Shaker home. Here I can live a pure,
                                chaste life, through which I receive a plenitude of spiritual and temporal blessings. I feel that my life is
                                so free! O that those of my sex who are in captivity could realize this as / do! how gladly would they flee
                                the false pleasures of the animal, sensuous life, and, of their own volition, accept the straight path into
                                which truth would lead them. Then would they know how good is the power of truth that is able to make souls
                                "free." My heart is drawn out in love and gratitude to the guardians and teachers of my early days; my
                                thanks are due to them for their timely discipline. By love, they guided my feet in Virtue's paths, and led
                                me in Wisdom's ways, which are safe, peaceful and pleasant. I am now able to see that " what we associate
                                with we become like," in a great measure; and, if we would be pure in spirit, we must keep our bodies pure ;
                                for it is impossible that any person can be a true follower of Christ while living in sensual pleasure. Only
                                those " Who govern their passions with absolute sway, Will grow wiser and better as life wears away."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Johnson, Tyringham, Mass.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Editress" TEIform="index"/> Dear Editress :</head><p TEIform="p">— We are pleased with the new form your much admired paper has assumed. We have ever cherished the idea that
                                woman possesses God-given faculties; and that she lias an inherent right to exercise her powers of body and
                                mind freely. And, in this day of Christ's second appearing, it becomes her duty to take a firm stand in
                                aiding the great work of progress in its onward march, which must, sooner or later, revolutionize all
                                man-made systems and creeds; and your little paper seems to us the best exponent of the dual principle,
                                recognized by the Shakers, of any thing that has yet appeared. And coming, as it does, fresh from tke
                                intellects, and warm from the hearts of its con- tributors, it enlivens our feelings, while we increase in
                                gratitude to God that we are numbered with the little flock who are receiving such bountiful blessings.
                                Great coldness is manifested in this section of country in regard to religious matters. Religion is of
                                secondary importance. But in our Zion home we earnestly pray to God for the protection of His heritage, and
                                for the advancement of truth throughout the land. We believe that His hand is not shortened, but He is still
                                able to save all who call upon Him—to open eyes that are blind, and unstop ears that are deaf. And we wish
                                your little craft much success, now that she is loosed from her moorings, and launched upon the waters,
                                freighted with golden treasures. God grant that she may bear light and truth to this sin-darkened land. And
                                should she, at times, be tempest-tossed on the billows of opposition, we have faith that she will out-ride
                                all storms, and come safely into port; and that each successive trip her value will be enhanced, because she
                                will be better appreciated. We would hold up the hands of those who are so nobly defending the cause of
                                purity and righteousness ; for the zeal manifested is worthy of all commendation and support from every Zion
                                traveler who loves God more than mammon ; and who, from his or her heart, desires to perpetuate true
                                principles and that living faith which will elevate and regenerate fallen humanity. And we will renew our
                                pledges to battle for the right with increased zeal, and to move straight forward in duty with unbroken
                                ranks, and to renounce all that is self-pleasing, that we may do the will of God. "Our work is before us,
                                and our reward will be with us;"— we shall reap what we sow. And may we leave behind us, as the poet aptly
                                said, "Footprints on the sands of time; Footprints that perhaps another, Sailing o'er life's solemn main,— A
                                forlorn and shipwrecked brother Seeing, may take heart again."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cowan, Jane" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Cowan, South Union, Ky.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress A.:" TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress A.:</head><p TEIform="p">Since the first appearance of the " Shaker," we have hailed with joy, and perused with interest,each
                                succeeding number; at the same time, wishing it might be enlarged, or be issued more frequently. And our
                                love and interest is now doubly increased, since our good Mother, the " Shakeress," is introduced, thereby
                                enhancing its beauty and completeness, and more fully representing the dual forces, Wisdom and Love, which
                                are at work in the spiritual kingdom of Christ, co-operating together, seeking to elevate Zion's sons and
                                daughters, and to send forth rays of light and truth to erring humanity. We have strongly desired to add our
                                mite to the little craft that is sent forth so richly freighted with goodly treasures ; and now that an
                                opportunity is so kindly offered (thanks to the "Waste Basket") we will gladly improve it; for if nothing
                                more, it will tend to our own growth and spiritual improvement. We believe that the higher faculties should
                                all be cultivated and brought into exercise, for the special purpose of developing within our own being, the
                                glorious image of the Divine ; thereby fitting us to become messengers of Love and Light, that we may
                                diffuse blessings to other souls. We love the beautiful, the good, and the true. We love the flowers, the
                                fragrance, and the fruit — aspiration, effort, and success — in every direction which leadeth God-ward. And
                                we resolve to work patiently, and struggle on to the end, and win a crown immortal; that palms of victory
                                may be ours, and that we may join in the sweet song of triumph with those who stand on the heights of Mount
                                Zion, and have gained the victory over sin and death. Dear friend — we thank you for those beautiful
                                soul-stirring expressions of thought in your " Appeal to the Sisterhood," which we appreciate, and will
                                endeavor to turn to good account. May your life be full of health, joy, and prosperity, throughout the
                                present year, and be spared* many years that are yet unborn, for the strength and comfort of your friends
                                both at home and abroad. In love — most kindly adieu. Yours ever,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>Julia Johnson, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love thy neighbor" TEIform="index"/>Love thy Neighbor</head><p TEIform="p">— The few short years of our earthly pilgrimage should be spent to the honor and glory of God, and in doing all
                            in our power to promote the happiness of our fellow-beings, whom we should love as we love ourselves. What a
                            wide field of labor stretches out before us! Shall we not enter, and work diligently to sow the seeds of truth,
                            love, and kindness, which will, in due time, with proper cultivation, spring up and grow, and yield an abundant
                            harvest? By the simple transactions of every-day life, we practically show how we keep the command to ''Love thy
                            neighbor as thyself." If we were really so unselfish that 46 <pb n="47" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKERE8S. " we sought not our
                            own, but another's wealth," or good, and would rather spend and be spent for others than to live by unjust
                            gains, or upon the Labors of others, how pleasant would be our reflections when reviewing the events of each
                            passing day. Instead of feeling that we have injured our brother, or sister, by an unkind word or deed, we
                            should feel that we have strewed flowers in their pathway. We have the means of doing this placed within our
                            reach; let us wisely improve them; it is a duty we owe to God and to each other, as we journey through
                            time.nearing the heavenly home. Let us resoi, e, by acts of kindness, and by words of encouragement and love, to
                            comfort the afflicted, bind up the broken- hearted, and pour the balm of consolation into the sorrowing spirit.
                            Then we shall show, by our works, that we keep the commandment, " Love thy neighbor as thyself."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Settles, Mary C." TEIform="persName"/>Mary C. Settles, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">Prayer is as sweet as the distilled dews from the skies wh': h canopy the heavenly Paradise. Can it be that any
                            intelligent being has lived on this earth, and passed to the life beyond, without having felt the pure influence
                            of the spirit of prayer, and who has not at times found relief for his or her troubled spirit, in supplicating
                            the Father of all mercies for his tender ct-.re? If, amid the tempest of wild temptation, or the flood of
                            unanswerable doubt, and in the chill of cold indifference, a soul can only bow beneath the sweet, yet potent
                            influence of prayer, the victory is half won ; for, when the better impulses of the soul gain the ascendency,
                            luring temptations and blinding doubts will dissolve like frost-work before the morning sun. In the silent hour
                            of prayer, when ministering angels are gliding down the golden ladder, and are filling the air with the essence
                            of true humility, and the spirit bathes in its beautiful wave, r.nu drinks of its electrified waters, there is
                            joy inexpressible; and it gives pure delight thus to blend with angels, and commune with them through the
                            beautiful door-way of praye;, and is productive of pure and delightful satisfaction of soul. But there are h
                            urs, when life or death seems wrapped up in prayer that trembles on the lips; and, in deep anguish, the soul "
                            prays because it must." The great fruition of such offering, is its own reward. The prayer for others' sorrow,
                            prompted by sympathy and love, and the earnest, unselfish supplication which the pure in heart offer, in behalf
                            of the weak and erring, penetrates the clouds of doubt, disarms the foes to purity, calms fear, inspires love,
                            whispers forgiveness and restoration to happiness, and is as sweet as honey in the comb, and as musical as the
                            song which was sung by the " Morning Stars." We read of one who prayed in the garden of Gethsemane, when his
                            deep agony wrung drops of blood from his pores; yet he arose calm and subdued, with those beautiful words
                            falling from his lips: " Not my will, O Father, but thine be done." And she whom we call Mother, when in the
                            prison cells of Manchester (England), Albany, and Poughkeepsie, through the long, dark watches of night, gave
                            her soul to earnest: supplication, and came forth with songs of praise on her lips. And, although human pride
                            may often stand as a barrier in the way of prayer and contrition of spirit, yet every one who has felt the holy
                            and inspiring influences induced by this heavenly gift, realizes that " sacredly blest is the hour of Prayer."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Wheeler, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eating without hunger" TEIform="index"/>EATING WITHOUT HUNGER</head><p TEIform="p">This is a very foolish and injurious habit, one which almost every one is more or less subject to. Hunger is the
                            signal which nature gives to indicate the necessity for a supply of food. When the system requires food, and is
                            in a condition to make good use of it, it will call for it in its original way. There are some exceptions to
                            this rule in certain diseased conditions, but they are very few. The digestive organs are in the best possible
                            condition for digesting food when the sensation of hunger exists, and they can then do it far more easily,
                            thoroughly, quickly and with less effort than at any other time. Most people pay little attention to this ; they
                            are sure to eat whenever they are hungry, if it is so that they can ; and they are just about as apt to eat when
                            they are not, if it is convenient for them to do so, or they chance to see any thing which " tickles their
                            palate." Especially is this rule — never eat unless you are hungry — violated in sickness. In acute disturbances
                            of the system the sensation of hunger is seldom manifested, for the simple reason that the system does not
                            require food. If food is eaten at such times, as it usually is, for everybody thinks the patient will surely
                            starve if he does not eat just so much and so often, it becomes a burden to the system which must be got rid of,
                            for there is no use for it; and as it will not do to let it remain in the stomach, the vital powers, which are
                            engaged in the reparative process termed disease, are called from the work upon which they are engaged to remove
                            the substances which are creating the disturbance. Thousands of persons have been prematurely laid in their
                            graves simply by eating heartily when the system was not in a condition to properly digest and appropriate the
                            food. Let this rule be observed by those who desire health with all the untold blessings which always accompany
                            it; whether sick or well, do not force food into the stomach tinless there is a demand for it. No fears need be
                            entertained of starving, for a desire for food will be manifested long before the starvation point is reached. —
                            Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to be happy" TEIform="index"/>How to be Happy I am well aware is not a new subject; but, as it is one that
                            interests us all, I give my experience, which is simply this: To live up to the highest light given, and obey
                            the purest convictions of duty. I cannot conceive of true happiness short of this. But lest it should be thought
                            too brief, I will add:</head><p TEIform="p">As all for happiness aspire, I know no wiser way Than do by others as I would That they should do each day: The
                            Saviour's rule, when well lived out, A blessing rich will prove ; Our words will be the words of peace, Our
                            works the works of love. We do not live for self alone, But have a higher call: Not me and mine, but we and
                            ours, A bond of good for all. By consecration unto God, A holy life to live, Our time and talents, great or
                            small, Our all to freely give. I know of nothing that doth yield Such perfect joy and bliss, As when to others
                            we can be A source of happiness: When we can soothe the troubled mind, Assuage another's grief, Unto the aged be
                            a staff, To orphans give relief. A gentle word, a loving smile, Though all we have to give, Which costs us
                            nothing, yet to such Diffuse a hope to live. Henceforth I will my time improve, And all my powers bestow, To
                            shed new sun-beams all around, That brighten as they glow.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Laura A." TEIform="persName"/>Laura A. Prentiss, Watervliet, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sign of the cross" TEIform="index"/>Sign of the Cross.</head><p TEIform="p">This much despised symbol, bears within it a weighty meaning. The hand presses the forehead, the throne of
                            thought; then the heart, the center of the affections ; and then the shoulders, which typify manual labor. Thus,
                            by a few motions, a full consecration is emblemized; and a prophecy is set forth; yet they who present it " know
                            not what they do."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature and grace" TEIform="index"/>NATURE AND GRACE</head><p TEIform="p">I'd rather be a quarried stone, And be disrobed of all disguise, Than cover'd with the prettiest moss That in the
                            shady woodland lies ; Hewn out from nature, carved and smooth'd, A pillar in the house of God, A " polish'd
                            stone " which cann't be moved, Or fitted for the tents abroad. Blest Zion be my dwelling-place, Though pitying
                            turn my eyes away, To see the suffering human race Grope darkly in the light of day. And oft my cries ascend to
                            Thee, O God of love and holy pow'r, That thy salvation, full and free, May triumph at no distant hour; May bring
                            thy wand'ring children up From degradation, sin and strife, To Nature's order ; thence above To Grace the higher
                            Angel life ; And make this earth a place of peace, Where none shall give or take offense; But all shall stand
                            redeem'd in love, In purity, and innocence.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extract" TEIform="index"/>Extract</head><p TEIform="p">— lam pleased Avith the "Shaker and Shakeress Monthly." I think the ideas expressed are all of an elevating
                            nature; even the appearance of the paper, pleases me, as it is the whitest of the Avhite, and the ink the
                            blackest of the black, and nice size type to read readily. The piece of poetry entitled " The Churches of our
                            Land." written by Cecelia Devyi, I think contains excellent sentiment. The piece of music "Beautiful Shore," I
                            will get D. to play for me. I hope to visit the Society some time when the pleasant weather comes again.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., M. J. R." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. R. N.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious principle" TEIform="index"/>The Religious Principle.</head><p TEIform="p">The principle in human nature from which religion springs is the desire to establish relations with a Being more
                            perfect than itself. The fact is as re- markable as it is incontrovertible, that the human race, all but
                            universally, has conceived of some Existence more exalted than man. If there is one principle, indeed, that may
                            be declared to be essential in human nature, it is this unwillingness to shut itself up within its own limits,
                            this tendency to aspire after intercourse with some Divinity. It is true that men at various periods have formed
                            most unworthy conceptions of their objects of wor- ship. Still, by selecting the qualities which they esteemed
                            most highly in themselves, and by enlarging and exalting them without bounds, they have showed, as plainly as
                            have more enlightened ages, the spontaneous longing of the human spirit to rise above itself, and to ally its
                            destiny with a Supreme Power. Discourse of William Ellery Channing. Human happiness depends upon general
                            exertion for goodness. The spirit which incites to harmony and universal love is the product of self-denial.
                            Discordant elements come from unsubdued passions raging in the human soul, while kindliness and gentleness are
                            from angel spheres. Self-indulgence is the producing cause of the former; self-denial of the latter. Who would
                            not prefer the lamb to the lion for a companion ? 0, it is beautiful to mark the footsteps of the lowly. Truth
                            is their motto; love, their shield. By an act of his Majesty James II, the penalties attached to witchcraft were
                            declared applicable to every woman who, by means of cosmetics, false hair, padding, stays, hoops, high-heeled
                            shoes, or other feminine devices, should seduce and betray into matrimony any member of the opposite sex, and a
                            marriage contracted under such circumstances was pronounced null and void. Were such a statute in force
                            now-a-days, there would be little need for Indiana divorces, and mothers- in-law would become the most transient
                            of life's fleeting ills.</p></div2><pb n="48" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Retirement" TEIform="index"/>RETIREMENT</head><p TEIform="p">1. When a lone and retir'd in the 2. 'Tis a time when the soul while in soul's silent chamber, With thoughts
                            flx'd on heavenly treasures above, deepest emotion, Can newly aspire lor the unction of Christ, The
                            angels endow'd with the true resurrection, Waft to our spirits the balm of sweet love. How cheering the
                            thought, that a time for reflection Can press for the blessing, in fervent devotion, Unfolding growth, of
                            the angelic life. Tis a season of peaceful, and holy seclusion, Will banish all sorrow and fear from the
                            heart, Will brighten the hopes of the future before us, And unto our spirit sweet solace impart. When we for
                            the life that's eternal prepare, Remote from the world with its strife and confusion, Blest hour of
                            retirement, I'll spend thee in pray'r.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lost birthright" TEIform="index"/>LOST BIRTHRIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">If ten thousand years were due me, And I held the globe at cost, What, pray what, would all avail me, If by it my
                            soul were lost ? Said the Lord, the great Exemplar, Not a night shall pass from here, Till the soul, whose life
                            is endless, Will be in another sphere. Sold ye fast your claim —your birthright — To a life in endless bliss;
                            All this world, with all its treasures, Cannot be compared to this. Should I misimprove my calling, Waste my
                            summer-time in sin, Where, or when, or how, 0 tell me, Can I get my time again ? Who will run and overtake it,
                            Chain and bring it back to me ? Place me in the same surroundings Just as all were wont to be 1 I've refused the
                            good Physician, Scorn'd the balm she oifer'd me, Set at nought her kindly counsel, Till I'm left to sink, you
                            see. All my light has turn'd to darkness, All my comrades gone on by, I am left alone to perish ; But, alas ! I
                            cannot die. All the past comes up before me, All my work to do again! None to help me, none to pity ! None to
                            cure or share my pain! Though I cry with heartfelt sorrow, Howl in bitterness of soul, None to hear me ! dread
                            dilemma! No companionship in hell!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Runyon, G. R." TEIform="persName"/>G. R. Runyon, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God in the Constitution" TEIform="index"/>GOD IN THE CONSTITUTION</head><p TEIform="p">O ye who strive for outward forms of Law, That statute books may flaunt the sacred Names, You do not press and
                            cavil for a straw ; You are not making merely wordy claims. Nay, never, since the young Republic's hands
                            Stretch'd forth with welcome for the earth's oppress'd, Were forged for her such life-destroying bands, Such
                            poison'd arrows pointed at her breast. For, whether motives selfish or sincere Impel your hearts to such
                            benighted zeal, You draw Inquisitorial terrors near, And whet anew the persecutor's steel. Of fomto-dhsetpvag
                            Pharisees beware, Who cry, Lord !' Lord! while yet they crush the poor; For pride, pretense, and solemn,
                            lengthen'd prayer, Shall, as of old, but reprimand secure. They would rebuild old Babel's dusky tower, And prove
                            her sequel efforts brought to nought; But ne'er again shall Superstition's power Defeat Progression, or repress
                            new thought. Yea, they would make a graven name of God, To bow before, or cover public stain ; Truth thunders
                            like mount Sinai, far abroad, " Thou shalt not take the name of God in vain." The foul adult'ries of the Church
                            and State, Whose fiend-like progeny have cursed the earth. It is not theirs again to consummate, Or give to
                            tyrants all that life is worth. There was but one who trod the " press" alone, And twelve dispensers of the
                            heavenly wine : Had you their " gift," your numbers (so outgrown) Might draw baptismal floods of life Divine. O,
                            when the nation's needful work is done, When sins of Government shall be no more, When Christian love shall
                            shine out as the sun. And God can bless the land from shore to shore, You will not ask for empty names, to bring
                            The heart's acknowledgment of heavenly care. Men do not write a label for the Spring, When blossom'd trees are
                            breathing on the air. Take from the books the penalty of death, And laws which hold fair womanhood in thrall;
                            Let Freedom breathe, with. Inspiration's breath, Life, liberty, and happiness for all / Yea, honor God
                            yourselves, in deed and word, Teach the pure lesson of the " golden rule," Strip all your creeds of ev'ry thing
                            absurd, And be as Angels at Bethesda's pool.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parable" TEIform="index"/>PARABLE</head><p TEIform="p">Then shall the kingdom of Satan be likened to a grain of tobacco-seed; which, though exceedingly small, being
                            cast into the ground, grew, and became a great plant, and spread its leaves rank and broad, so that huge and
                            vile worms found a habitation thereon. And it came to pass, in the course of time, that the sons of men looked
                            upon it_ and thought it beautiful to look upon, and much to be desired to make lads look big and manly. So they
                            put forth their hand, and did chew thereof. And some it made sick, and others to vomit most filthily. And it
                            further came to pass that those who chewed it became weak and unmanly, and said: We are enslaved and cannot
                            cease from chewing it. And the mouths of all that were enslaved became foul, and they were seized with a violent
                            spitting; and they did spit even in ladies' parlors, and in the house of the Lord of hosts. And the saints of
                            the Most High were greatly plagued thereby. And in the course of time it came also to pass that others snuffed
                            it; and they were taken suddenly with fits, and they did sneeze with a great and mighty sneeze, insomuch that
                            their eyes were filled with tears, and they did look exceedingly silly. And yet others cunningly wrought the
                            leaves thereof into rolls, and did set fire to one end thereof, and did look very grave and calf-like; and the
                            smoke of their torment ascendeth up forever and ever. And the cultivation thereof became a great and mighty
                            business in the earth; and the merchantmen waxed rich by the commerce thereof. And it came to pass that the
                            saints of the Most High defiled themselves therewith ; even the poor, who could not buy shoes, nor bread, nor
                            books for their little ones, spent their money for it. And the Lord was greatly displeased therewith, and said:
                            Wherefore this waste; and why do these little ones lack bread, and shoes, and books? Turn now your fields into
                            corn and wheat, and put this evil thing far from you; and be separate, and defile not yourselves any more; and I
                            will bless you and cause my face to&gt;shine upon you. But with one accord they all exclaimed: " We cannot
                            cease from chewing, snuffing, and puffing; we are slaves."—Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Augur, Leverett" TEIform="index"/>Leverett Augur
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Augur, Leverett" TEIform="persName">Leverett Augur</persName>, April 7th, aged 88 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Boynton, Marcia" TEIform="index"/>Makcia Boynton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Boynton, Marcia" TEIform="persName">Makcia Boynton</persName>, April 14th, aged 86 years. Both of Hancock,
                            Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whiting, William" TEIform="index"/>Willliam Whiting
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Whiting, William" TEIform="persName">Willliam Whiting</persName>, March 25th, aged 76 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turner, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Turner
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Turner, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Turner</persName>, March 35th, aged 31 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Roberts, Nancy A." TEIform="index"/>Nancy A. Roberts
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Roberts, Nancy A." TEIform="persName">Nancy A. Roberts</persName>, April 15th, aged 76 years. All of Mt.
                                Lebanon.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pendleton, David" TEIform="index"/>David Pendleton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Pendleton, David" TEIform="persName">David Pendleton</persName>, April 6th, aged 37 years, Poland Hill, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Palmer, Charity" TEIform="index"/>Charity Palmer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Palmer, Charity" TEIform="persName">Charity Palmer</persName>, April 6th, aged 87 years, Po- land Hill, Me.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>