<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0111" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Mount Lebanon Bishopric</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Albany, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18711101" TEIform="date">November 1871</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="81" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p"> I Wai SHAKE ALL NATIONS, AND TUB DESIRE OF ALL NATIONS SHALL COME J AND I WILL FILL THIS HOUSE
                        WITH GLORY, SAITH THE LORD." Published Monthly, by, and under the direction of the Mt. Lebanon
                        Bishopric. Vol. L SHAKERS, ALBANY CO., N. Y., NOVEMBER, 1871. No. 11.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Extremes" TEIform="index"/>Extremes</head><p TEIform="p">That one extreme produces another, is a truism. Dogmatic theology " demands absolute,
                            unswerving submission from the human mind. Doubt is sin ; unbelief is damnation." The other
                            extreme—simple materialism—rests upon the axiom that religious (ars well as every other)
                            belief is the result of evidence; that unbelief, in any proposition, arises from the want of
                            proof—demonstration. All children are materialists; and if, as they grow to puberty, they
                            would never profess to believe what they do not understand, it would *' save" them from
                            hypocrisy, and cause their teachers to reason, not to threaten. They would not then, as now,
                            " affirm things whereof they know not.'' " Come now, and let us reason together, $aith the
                            Lord i" Why do not the clergy, who profess to be his ambassadors, pass the invitation down
                            to the people ? Simply because their dogmas are unreasonable, or, as they (in phrase polite)
                            express it, " above reason;" and every man and woman ought to be " above" fretending to
                            believe them as an act of the wiU^ a thing impossible. Let any one try to believe that his
                            mortal body, when laid six feet deep in the ground, will do anything but decompose, as would
                            the body of a horse, " for both go to one place—the earth ; and as dieth the one, so dieth
                            the other," as decayeth the one, so deeayeth the other. Then let him try to disbelieve that
                            a grape-vine, anywhere within twenty feet thereof, will send its roots thereto, to make that
                            human body into grapes. Or, let him try to doubt the additional fact that some mischievous
                            boys, or busy girls, will incorporate those grapes into their living bodies, and give some
                            to their friends, thus utterly subverting the absurd doctrine of a physical resurrection by
                            proving that men and women, in more ways than one, are continually " eating one another." He
                            is a " fool, who saith, in his heart, There is no God," and equally a fool is he who saith
                            with his tongue, " There is a God," wlfen he knows it not with his under- standing, and ("in
                            his heart") does not believe it. I honor, as honest men or women, those who are just what "
                            they seem to be, and who profess and seem to be just what they are." Do they believe simply
                            in external matter — the object of their external senses ? Let them honestly declare, " I am
                            a materialist! and what I do believe all human beings belitve!" materialism being
                            rudimentary to the race. Who knows when Spiritualism, as an idea, first enters the brain ?
                            and when endless life and immortality (which are the same thing) come into the
                            understanding, as a light shining in a dark place, making things visible which (before) were
                            " not seen?" I love the frank simplicity of soul that enables one to say, I have done wrong;
                            I have been mistaken; or, " I do not know." Teach me, and I shall be instructed ; turn me,
                            and I shall be turned ; convince me, and *'lead me in the way everlasting." That is true
                            nobility! Cannot you convert me by your good words ? then confound me by your good works, so
                            shall I believe for your " very works' sake," inasmuch as, by the superior fruits of the
                            spiritually religious Believers in Christ's second advent, all men and women shall
                            distinguish, or " know," them from the innumerable sects who, though naming the name of
                            Christianity, do not depart from selfishness, nor do they love one another into a religious
                            Community.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E., F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. E.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Difficult lesson" TEIform="index"/>The Difficult Lesson</head><p TEIform="p">LOSING ALL, AND GAINING MORE THAN ALL. One of the most difficult lessons for individuals to
                            learn, is the fact that there are two planes of existence for humanity, either in this
                            world, or in that to which we are hastening with every diurnal revolution of our planet. The
                            vulture-eyed philosopher, nor the lionhearted reformer, outside of Shakerism, seem to
                            comprehend this fact, excepting in very rare instances. Hence, we are not surprised, when
                            Horace Greeley, writing of The Shakers, asks : " Are our relations with men and women so
                            universally pure, that we may rightly despise those, who, unable to separate the palpable
                            evil from the latent good, reject both together ?" Nor are we disappointed, when Alcander
                            Longley, of The Communist, asserts that Ann Lee's very proper disgust at the low state of
                            morals around her, caused her to run to the other extreme—that of celibacy—instead of
                            stopping at the condition of respectable marriage i In answer to " our later Franklin," and
                            our would-be founder of a community, we here say : That we are just as able to see, and to
                            separate the good from the evils of the marital relation as any others; and that we have
                            "run to the other extreme," not so much from our disgust of social evils, as for our
                            admiration of the superior joys of angelhood. We know marriage has its proper sphere—on the
                            earthly plane—there it is honorable, when honorably conducted; and for a criterion of
                            honorable marriage we would name either the system of Mosaism or that of George Fox.
                            Scarcely an instance can be produced of marital relations being conducted now, upon either
                            of these admirable bases. And yet, not because of the mourning cry of humanity from one end
                            of the land to the other, do we invite any to become celibates! The Jews were very perfect
                            in their reproductions, when they could bring forth such specimens of humanity as Jesus! and
                            yet, amid the most perfect on the earthly plane the necessity appeared for a celibate order
                            of beings ; and he who was the fulfillment of God's promise to Moses, in " taking all
                            sickness from the midst of Israel," became the leader of the celibate or Christian order!
                            Was the reason of Jesus' renunciation of the marital relation, because he could not separate
                            " the 'palpable evil from the latent good ?" Or were his surroundings so disgusting in
                            consequence of lust that he " ran to the other extreme ?" Jesus and Ann were the
                            evangelists, not of an improvement of the old order of things, but for the introduction of
                            the New Creation; not for the recuperation of " the earth and those who are earthy," but to
                            baptize souls with the resurrecting power of " the Lord from heaven"—the very antipodeof the
                            " Adam of the earth, earthy !" Recognizing the distinction between the earthly and the
                            heavenly as we do, we can easily " comprehend the good and the bad of the earthly," and "
                            reject both together," because of the superior joys and relations of the heavenly. Could we
                            enjoy the felicities of matrimony exceeding the most finely drawn picture of the most
                            exaggerating, sensational novelist; and could we reproduce offspring as perfect as was
                            Jesus; we should feel no more permission to engage therein, than we now do, when "
                            incompatibility of temper" is so common, and when the production of less healthful progenj^
                            than monkeys is so general! To us there is a sphere that is as elevated above the
                            reproductive, as our estimates of heaven are superior to our <pb n="82" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 82 T tl E
                            SHAKBE estimates of the earth. " Marriage peoples the earth," said the saint; "but Celibacy
                            increases the forces of heaven!" and said a 'greater: " The children of this world (the
                            earthy), marry and are given in marriage;" very properly so, and we wish more honorably so;
                            "but my children—the children of the Resurrection order—I am the Resurrection—neither marry
                            nor are given in marriage !" Claiming, as we do, to be Christians —having aspirations to be
                            " the children of the Resurrection;" how eon we be expected to soil our bodies or souls in
                            the mire and filth of that which constitutes the order we profess to having been raised
                            above ? And yet, we are not practicing celibacy because Jesus did; nor because Ann Lee
                            taught it to be a necessary element in the Christian's character; but we have risen in love
                            with the eternal principles they have presented to our enlightened understandings, instead
                            of falling in love with the temptations of nature, pure, or perverted ! Could the angelic
                            hosts personate physical humanity, so would we,have our lives resemble them; not for the
                            appearance, but for the enjoyment here upon the earth, the fruition of thesame principles
                            engaged in by the disembodied pure and perfected. Let others cleave to the earth; to earthly
                            institutions and practices as seems to them proper; such cannot reasonably expect that we,
                            who have had our lives cut off from the earthy plane, can remain satisfied with the
                            nourishment of earthly pleasures; but having become ripe for the Christian harvest, we find
                            a new and higher source of supplies; when leaving our loves of earth, its vanities and
                            relations, we find the never-failing manna, and the ever-flowing fountains of life, eternal
                            life. We are being schooled into eternal life. We have forsaken the loves of the word as
                            well as its lusts, because neither are eternal. We realize war to be the product of earthly
                            loves and relations; we will not fight, nor vote for those who do fight; nor for those who
                            believe in marriage, private property, or who engage in fleshly lusts of whatever
                            description; for these are not eternal, and we pray for their discontinuance. But few have
                            ripened up to this necessity, and to the solving of this difficult lesson—a lesson
                            impossible for the carnally-minded to learn; but the fields of human souls are ripening unto
                            the harvest, and for such we have attempted an illumination. Already in the distance, in
                            America and over the waters, we see, we hear mighty souls pro- claiming the everlasting
                            testimony; still nearer, we see, we hear, from Hammonton, N. J., to Monticello, Minn., the
                            more perfect testimony of an enduring life; and nearer still, we see, we hear, we feel
                            Brethren and Sisters in Christ—" the few who have found it"—walking the narrow way, and "
                            despising the shame" of peculiarity from the multitude, losing their lives on the plane of
                            earth for an eternal residence in the heavens. *</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Among the many justifiable bible authorities for wrong doing..." TEIform="index"/>Among the many justifiable bible authorities for wrong doing...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">AMONG the many justifiable Bible authorities for wrong doing." is the following:—The tobacco
                            user finds his in: " He that is filthy, let him be filthy still.' What says the -'Shaker?"</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="M., E." TEIform="persName"/>E. M</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hope on" TEIform="index"/>Hope On</head><p TEIform="p">Hope on to the last, tho' the dark clouds may gather, Encircling thy course in tempest array;
                            The storm shall pass o'er, and the sun in its splendor, Will brighter the beauties of nature
                            display. Hope on to the last, tho' many oppose thee, Be true to the cause of justice anil
                            right; For truth is a legion, and God will sustain thee, And turn in their souls the
                            darkness to light. Hope on to the Iast, tho' the soft shades of evening, Are hidden behind
                            the curtains of night, And the haven of rest, which gleamed in the distance, Enveloped in
                            blackness, is hid from thy sight. Hope on to the last, there are joys in the future ; Weep
                            not for those phantoms long since past away, For the pleasures of earth are exceeded in
                            heaven, As the stars are outshone by the bright orb of day. Hope on to the last, for thy
                            joys are eternal, And thousands shall join in thy welcome above, While the untiring strains
                            of heavenly music, Announce thy approach to the regions of love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, J. V." TEIform="persName"/>J. V. Calver</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Owe no man, etc" TEIform="index"/>"Owe no Man," etc.</head><p TEIform="p">" I do not know that I owe any man a dollar!"—Edward Fowler. " Once it was the custom for
                            each individual to^repeat, from memory, "some regulation of the family or society, when all
                            had gathered for worship. The ministry were not excepted. We were all anxious to know which
                            rule Elder Ebenezer Bishop (then the presiding Elder of Believers) would repeat, supposing
                            it would be the most important spiritual requisition. All were disappointed when he
                            repeated, ' Believers must not run into debt!' But circumstances have since proved the
                            wisdom of his choice, as touching both the temporal and spiritual prosperity of our
                            people."— Chauncy Miller. " I have been in the Trustee's office for many years, yet I never
                            gave my note to any one, and I never will."—Simon Atherton. " Of all afflictions, being in
                            debt is the worst. I make it a rule to pay my employees in full once a month, whether they
                            want their wages or not."—Benjamin Gates. " I endeavor to keep my accounts in that manner,
                            that the whole could be straightened and balanced with an hour's notice."—Levi Shaw. " Hand
                            in hand, with the injunction that we must not run in debt, should be an injunction not to
                            live, nor desire to live, beyond our means."—Galen Richmond. The above, as may be seen, are
                            the remarks of some of the most prominent members of Shaker Society to-day, doing business
                            as Trustees. " That child around, and taking notes, and faith he'll print them," will
                            surprise these members somewhat, but he, nevertheless, feels honored by the testimony he has
                            unobservedly obtained, and in being able to record for the benefit of others their sage
                            counsels. Undoubtedly, the column could be many times filled with like matter, all tending
                            to advise : "Look before you leap," and "Dip not out more than gets in, else you will come
                            to want." Carelessness on the part of Believers has caused them to swerve somewhat from the
                            rule enforced by that good Elder in an easterr Society, who would not permit the Trustee to
                            mingle with the rest in worship, because he had failed to pay two or three shillings due on
                            a hogshead of molasses he had brought home Suppose the same rule were now in force, how many
                            ti'ustees would be in durance ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation by obedience" TEIform="index"/>Salvation by Obedience</head><p TEIform="p">Obedience to God—obedience to his law—to faith and principle: This has always been required
                            ever since the creation of man, and his being placed in Eden's Garden. It was necessary for
                            the order and regulation of man's doings in the ordinary course of business life. It was
                            needful for man's daily protection and salvation, spiritually. Law, without obedience, is
                            like faith without works— man without soul, or a body without spirit. Obedience is the very
                            life principle of law. The laws of a people, country or nation are of but little value
                            without obedience, for they will be neither enforced nor kept. The law which saith, " Thou
                            shalt not commit adultery ;" if a man commit adultery, how is he benefited by the law ? He
                            may meet the penalty of the law by chastisement or imprisonment ; but unless his confinement
                            or mfferings by such penalty work repentance, he will again sin when opportunity offers. In
                            tracing back God's dealings with his creature—man—we find the original law de- livered to
                            him by his Creator, when placed in the Garden of Eden, was, " Of every tree of the garden
                            thou mayest freely eat; but of the Tree of the Knowledge of Good and Evil, thou shalt not
                            eat of it: for in the day that thou eatest thereof, thou shalt surely die." This was God's
                            law or commandment to man in the beginning. Did man keep this law ? Now, this law, whether
                            given to man verbally or written upon his heart—intuitive knowledge— it matters not. He was,
                            doubtless, made able to comprehend it. The breath of the Almighty breathed' into man, by
                            which he became a living soul, endowed him with reason and understanding sufficient to know
                            his duty to his Maker, and what was in that day required of him. By disobedience to law, to
                            the commandment or the knowledge of God implanted in the soul, man lost his union and
                            communion with his Creator, and his right to the Tree of Life, which was also in the garden
                            placed. Shame and dishonor ensued; yea, even death ! Consequently, the disposition in man to
                            hide in the bushes, to evade the countenance of the Almighty. Man discovered his own
                            nakedness. He knew he had transgressed God's law. He was fearful of the consequences— the
                            doom pronounced upon disobedience—the penalty of the law. The promise of God afterwards
                            given to man, that the " seed of the woman should bruise the serpent's head," has ever been
                            man's anchor and hope through all time of the past up to the present. And ever since the sad
                            event of the fall, it has been man's duty and privilege, through God's goodness and mercy,
                            to be eradicating from his soul the bane then received by disobedience. Jesus Christ opened
                            the door, and led the way to man's redemption. "All who will may partake of the waters of
                            life freely." Man is still left to choose or refuse. " Come unto me all ye that labor and
                            are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. Take my.yoke upon you, and learn of me; for I am
                            meek and lowly in heart; and ye shall find rest to your souls. For my yoke is easy, and my
                            burden is light." <pb n="83" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHA.KER. 83 From the day of the original
                            transgression of God's law, there have always been ministers or teachers of =God's word,
                            those endowed with a measure of ligfetand truth, sufficient to show mankind their duty, and
                            to lead them upward (by degrees) from death to life, if they would yield obedience to the
                            divine truths made known by those empowered to teach. Those who were obedient to the
                            instructions and warnings of Noah, were saved from the mighty deluge which was about to
                            destroy the world. Abram was a teacher of righteousness. His faith and obedience was an
                            example to mankind, worthy of imitation. Obedience to God's laws through Moses, was leading
                            the human race, step by step, higher up the Ladder of Progress, into a knowledge of God's
                            will to man, as pertaining to the work of his redemption from under the curse. It is as
                            impossible for man, in his lost state and condition, to become immediately"reinstated, or
                            joined in full union and communion with his Creator—God— to be redeemed from the fall, all
                            at once, as it is for a chi*d ^The has commenced to learn his a, b, c, in literary
                            knowledge, to become immediately master of the arts and sciences. He has departed from the
                            true knowledge of his Maker, and must retrace his steps, grow into the knowledge of the
                            truth, by degrees, as he has departed from it. For man did not—could not fall into the
                            lowest state of degradation all at once. This immediate conversion and redemption from death
                            to life, without self-mortification, and a daily cross-bearing, is a deception. The im-
                            puted righteousness of Christ, which is said to release converted souls from all responsi-
                            bility and trouble thereafter, on the part of the sinner, is a false covering of the
                            adversary of souls, designed to ease the consciences of men and women, and lull them into
                            sleep and death, deeper than before. " Except a man deny himself, take up his cross and
                            follow me," saith Jesus, "he cannot be my disciple." Jesus did not effect the great work of
                            overcoming the world in himself, in a moment, an hour, nor a day. It was by daily training
                            from childhood to manhood, up to the time of his Baptism in the River Jordan, and many sor-
                            rowful days thereafter. How greatly wras he tempted, and how severe were his struggles,
                            combatting with his enemy, the Devil (whatever may have been his form or feature) which,
                            according to Scripture account, lasted forty days and nights ! " The kingdom of heaven
                            suffereth violence, and the violent take it by force." Jesus set the example of daily
                            cross-bearing, overcoming evil with good, whenever and wherever opportunity offered. " Let
                            him that nameth the name of Christ depart from iniquity." The law of Moses served as a
                            schoolmaster to lead souls to Christ. In obedience to that law the children of Israel
                            inherited the promised land—a land flowing with milk and honey. If there had been no law or
                            commandment saying, " Thou shalt not kill; Thou shalt not steal; Thou shalt# not commit
                            adultery," etc., man would not be culpable for so doing. By the knowledge of the law, sin in
                            revealed. " Where there is no law, there is no transgression." " For sin is the
                            transgression of the law." Jesus Christ came into the world to put an end to sin, and
                            introduce an everlasting righteousness. This he did by overcoming the would in himself, and
                            setting an example for others to do likewise. "I am the Resurrection," said Christ. Man must
                            be resurrected from death and deathly works, into the new life, which is in Christ. He must
                            be born again. This new birth is spiritual, not carnal—not physical. " Except a man be born
                            again," said Christ, " he can not see the Kingdom of God." This saying of our Saviour was
                            not comprehended by Nicodemus. Our Savior explained it to him more fully. That he must be
                            born of the spirit, and not after the flesh. " That which is born of the flesh is flesh, and
                            that which is born of the spirit is spirit. . Marvel not that I say unto you, ye must be
                            born again." Mankind, instead of being led by the spirit of Christ, which worketh by love
                            and purity of heart, are governed too much by selfishness, passion, pride and lust; seeking
                            their own ease and aggrandizement, not God's honor and glory. Trace the travel and progress
                            of the children of Israel from their rise to their fall —from their deliverance from
                            Egyptian bondage to the destruction of Jerusalem; and you will find that in all or nearly
                            all cases, where they were subject to God's word and law to them, prosperity attended; but
                            when they rejected or disobeyed, they were smitten by their enemies, or in some way suffered
                            loss. It reasoned not wTho was ruler, judge or king over the people, disobedience to God's
                            requirements always brought trouble. Kings and rulers may err and deviate to the right and
                            left of the true standard of Truth and Equity, but God's word abideth forever. Principles
                            vary not. While under the law, all must be subject to the law. But when having come out from
                            under the old commandment into the new, or covenant of Grace, the latter takes the
                            pre-eminence—the old is fulfilled—as in Jesus Christ. " One jot or one tittle shall in
                            nowise pass from the law till all be fulfilled." Jesus Christ was the end of the law to them
                            that believe—those who walk no more after the flesh, but after the spirit—who follow not the
                            first Adam in the work of generation, but the Second Adam in the work of the regeneration.
                            If we say we have no faith in such a one or ones, or that we have no confidence in the
                            administration of God's law by or through such individuals or persons called to be rulers in
                            the Church or House of God, are we justified in rejecting, or in going contrary to their
                            counsel and instruction ? Such are ministers of God's word or law; and obedience to the law
                            or testimony is required of all under it. If we respect not the person or persons, have
                            respect for God's law, though administered by them. The principles of truth and right should
                            govern us, not passion and partial feelings. Man cannot change principles by misdirection or
                            misapplication of them. Jesus said, " If a man love me he will keep my sayings." Many
                            professors of Christianity make great pretensions of their love to God, or love to Christ,
                            who really are unwilling to prove their love by acts of kindness, selfdenial and the daily
                            cross, as Jesus did. They seem willing to name the name of Christ, but unwilling to depart
                            from iniquity. The teachings of our Lord and Saviour were on this wise: " Love your enemies,
                            bless them that curse you, do good to them that hate you, and pray for them that
                            despitefully use you and persecute you." " Whosoever shall smite thee on thy right cheek,
                            turn to him the other also." "Render not evil for evil, but good for evil." Here is a new
                            commandment given under the gospel dispensation. It is Universal Love. No more an eye for an
                            eye, a tooth for a tooth, but love and good will toward all men. No more war and bloodshed,
                            strife and contention, selfishness and individual promotion, one rising above another with
                            superior claims and usurpation, but community of goods, united interests, brotherly and
                            sisterly love, justice, righteousness and equity in all things. No special toleration for
                            particular, personal fellowship, or affection for this or that one, but it is all
                            ours—universal brotherhood. Every house set in order must have laws, rules and regulations
                            to keep it so. But wThoever knew one kept in that condition, unless the gift or principle of
                            obedience r signed there?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. Buckingham</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth, faith, and reason" TEIform="index"/>Truth, Faith, and Reason</head><p TEIform="p">Truth and reality must be the basis of all moral excellence and durable bliss. Fiction and
                            false views, like unsuspected counterfeit coin, may appear like reality, and give great
                            present satisfaction, but sooner or later the deception will be discovered, when the sting
                            of disappointment will succeed, and be in proportion to the ever-departed joy. As we rarely
                            or never discover the true amount of large accounts, without carefully considering and
                            adding each particular item, so neither shall we ever attain to truth without patient and
                            careful investigation. We may reasonably suspect the man who requires us to believe without
                            investigation, for, if he be neither dishonest nor designing, he must be under the influence
                            of a credulity that renders his opinions unreliable. He that imposes first on his own under-
                            standing by believing without examination, will most likely impose on that of others, if
                            permitted. He that has thoroughly investigated a subject, and satisfied his own
                            understanding of its truth, far from wishing others to take it upon trust, earnestly desires
                            them to examine for themselves. There can be no permanent happiness, only in conformity to
                            the truth and reality of things; whatever is forced, far-fetched, or false, must ultimately
                            fail. Many assertions do not make one truth. He that does nothing but that which is good,
                            says nothing but that which is true, thinks nothing but that which is pure, need not fear
                            being put to shame. " All power," said Jesus, " in heaven and <pb n="84" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE S PI
                            ^l K E R . earth is given me," i. e., all power—the power of God is pledged for the support
                            of my gospel, the truth which I have taught, for truth is Almighty. God is truth. 0,
                            Heavenly Father, teach. me thy truth ! my desire is to believe all that is true, and
                            practice all I believe. If we cannot bring truth to agree with onr wishes, we must subject
                            our desires to truth. We never act rationally while in our affections we give temporal
                            things the ascendancy over those which are spiritual and eternal. To deceive, and act the
                            hypocrite, costs more than sincerely to be what we pretend. How base, then, is hypocrisy.
                            Universal truth comprehends all the real qualities, relations, and dependencies that exist
                            in and between ail things in the universe. Some smali portion of these have been $is-~
                            eovered by, o? revealed to, man. For convenience of investigation, universal truth may be
                            divided into two departments, Moral and Physical —the one relating to mind, the other to
                            matter. All truth is precious, but truth in relation to moral subjects is infinitely more
                            important than that which merely relates to the physical, inasmuch as it relates to the
                            present and eternal well-being of infinite millions of immortal intelligences-,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham" TEIform="persName"/>Pelham</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="World" TEIform="index"/>The World</head><p TEIform="p">What is tfi-e world!? A blinding maze, "Where"sin hath marked ten thousand ways, Its victims
                            to ensnare; They're broad, they're winding, and aslope, They're void of truth, and void of
                            hope, All ending in despair. Millions of travelers throng these roads, Borne down by sin in
                            heavy loads. To dark and dismal night. One humble path, thai never bends, Narrow, yetrongh
                            and steep, ascends froM darkness into light. Ir there no guide to show that path ? The
                            Gospel! He alone who hath The Gospel, need not stray; But he who hath, yet doth not give The
                            Gospel light that souls may live, Himself shall lose the way.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hampton logic" TEIform="index"/>Hampton Logic</head><p TEIform="p">In order that a religious superstructure or organization may be eternal in duration, its
                            foundations must be deeply laid in a substratum of Eternal Truth. In accordance with this
                            proposition, I propose to show that we, as a Church of Believers in Christ's first and
                            second appearing, are based upon an immutable and steadfast foundation, impregnable to any
                            assault, so long as we ourselves continue to build thereon ; conferring upon each faithful
                            builder complete immunity from sorrow and danger, and, finally, placing such in a condition
                            of sinless perfection, completely saving all souls, in all worlds, who are obedient to its
                            practical suggestions : 1. The highest wisdom possible to be brought to bear on human weal
                            must be embraced in that plan only, which, in its practical results, will secure the
                            greatest good to the greatest number. 2. Again, this wisdom can reach and benefit man only
                            through the agency of a universal law—that the less is and must be blest of the better. In
                            other words, those possessing a measure of wisdom, goodness and perfection, must reach
                            higher degrees of these through the agency of those possessing a greater amount of wisdom,
                            goodness, etc., or remain forever where they are. Now, if our system of religious life can
                            be proved to stand upon these two immutable principles, it is safe for all time and
                            eternity. Let us see: I remark then, first, that we are organized on the plan of the
                            Pentecostal Church of Jesus ; that is to say, we have all things mi common, none being
                            permitted to consider or to call aught that he holds his own, tut distribution made as each
                            has need. We are equally conditioned according to our several needs and circumstances
                            relative to labor and clothes—equal in facilities for intellectual improfement, and equal in
                            all the gifts, graces and consolations of the Holy Spirit. And, moreover, the sexes are
                            equal in regard to the distribution of powers, privileges, responsibilities and offices, in
                            the administration of the government of our organization, in things temporal and spiritual.
                            Is not our organization, on this principle, the only one capable of securing the greatest
                            good to the greatest number; at least the best that can be devised for man, during his abode
                            on this earth ? A society or organization based on these principles is manipulated with
                            undeviating reference to that great law of the universe, by which "the less is blest of the
                            better." And here, it seems to me, is the point in which the Religious System, based on the
                            foregoing principles, pre-eminently lays legitimate claim to a foundation firm as the
                            everlasting hills. Every individual of Christ's true Church, from the least child to the
                            highest officer, is mediately superintended and cared for by all the orders and spheres of
                            the heavens who are farther progressed than he is; and superintended immediately by an order
                            of persons supposed to be sufficiently in advance of him to subserve his every purpose for
                            protection, and salvation from sin, as well as for growth in grace and holiness I NoWy this
                            Divine Arrangement does not terminate in the highest representatives thereof here on the
                            earth, but is continued through many orders, reaching, in its sublime gyrations, our Mother
                            Ann and Jesus our Father, then their direct ministering angels and intelligences, etc.,
                            passing on through myriads on myriads of heavenly orders of spirits; intact passing into a
                            boundless infinitude of arrangement whose end is nowhere. If this sublime system of agency
                            terminated at the highest point reached here in time, how could we Be linked to the great
                            battery of heaven, so as to receive its magnetic influence, and through that, our power to
                            progress ? We have better assurances. This connecting, transmitting claim of agency passes
                            beyond the gateway of death, and on through sphere after sphere and order after order of
                            heavenly intelligences, even ad ivjinitum. Jesus and Ann are only heavenly links in the
                            great chain or concatenation of agencies, through which the magnetisms and powers of
                            progress are transmitted to all below them, for the purposes of spirit culture in holiness,
                            and every good and! perfect gift. That there is no end to this series of agencies, I think I
                            have the best of reasons for believing, viewing the subject from philosophical and logical
                            points. Besides, I have trie testimony of one who declared, " there was no end to the
                            heavens," when interrogated upon the subject of the different orders therein. Then the query
                            arises, where is the great center of this magnetic influence, permeating every part of the
                            universe, and moving by grand and sublime pulsations through the countless heavens, and
                            earths, which " roll in the depths of immensity i" I answeT: Where there is no circumference
                            there can be no center ; consequently this Divine influence is distributed wherever the
                            visible or invisible machinery is found for its transmission in the whole concatenation of
                            individualized intelligences throughout the universe. The direction of this power of the All
                            Father and All Mother is forever toward higher and higher degrees of perfection iff goodness
                            and intclligenee, fro-m lower and? more imperfect conditions. It may he asked : 'Do you not,
                            by this argument, destroy the theory of a personal God outside of and independent of the
                            universe of forms and forces ? Answering this question indirectly, we think we furnish a "
                            local habitation and a name" for the Father and Mother God, more consistent than any other
                            theory can develop; and indeed any other theory or ascription of personality to God, will
                            not bear the rigid scrutiny of logic or common sense for a moment; so at least it seems to
                            the writer. The universe then is the home of our Father and Mother, and all progressive
                            manifestations are the results of their influence and presence. This must be so, for if the
                            universe of mind and matter is boundless and infinite, no God can be predicated as having a
                            separate, personal existence outside of it, because there is no outside, and, consequently,
                            no room for such existence. Again, if the universe is peopled by infinite myriads of
                            entities and individual intelligences, and the Father and Mother spirit permeate and abide
                            in these, what need of a separate, incomprehensible abode outside of all these, or if these
                            are infinite in extent, which is Ann Lee's testimony, what room, as before stated, m left
                            for this separate abode? Whefl we pray, we pray to all the hosts' of heaven, even the
                            myriads of individualized intelligences embracing the entire universe who are greater,
                            holier and more perfect than ourselves; through these we reach the heavenly Father and
                            Mother, who reside in this multinomial series as a sublime whole. Is not thispraying to the
                            All Father and Mother in their entirety, as far as we can nave any intelligent comprehension
                            of that entirety ? " But in this view is implied the great law of the universe, that " the
                            less is blest of the better," and through this, that other condition, the plan by which the
                            greatest good is secured to the greatest number. Millions of purposes are subserved through
                            the medium of this arrangement, having for their object the best and highest results in the
                            evolution of all things toward perfection. Among these benevolent purposes 84 <pb n="85" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE. 85 and intents, the eternal progress of man in intelligence, and
                            greater and greater degrees of goodness and consequent salvation and happiness, stand
                            pre-eminent. Jesus being the most holy, as well as the most intelligent organizer of which
                            we have any history, and Mother Ann Lee having organized her Church precisely after Jesus'
                            model, and both being based upon the two eternal laws of the universe (above stated),
                            therefore it would seem to be proved that the foundation of the Church of Christ's second
                            appearing is sure, steadfast, eternal, one upon which we may forever build in safety,
                            passing on from grace to grace and from glory to glory forever, evolving from age to age
                            higher degrees of intelligence, goodness and felicity during all the endless ages of the
                            interminable future.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>O. C. Hampton</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flowers" TEIform="index"/>The Flowers</head><p TEIform="p">I walked through a beautiful garden so green, My heart was quite filled with delight at the
                            scene; The flowers were all blooming, most gorgeously dressed; But soon sad emotions my
                            spirit depressed; For this thought came o'er me : How short is your stay, Ye beautiful
                            flowers, so brilliant and gay ? With leaves now expanding, with colors so bright, And buds
                            bursting sweetly the eye to delight; Refreshed by the dews of the morning so fair, Exhaling
                            sweet odors, perfuming the air; But all those enchantments, so gay to the eye, Though rich
                            in their beauty, soon wither and die. The beautiful summer!—how soon it is o'er, And the
                            bloom of the flowers is remembered no more; But deep in the heart that is free from all
                            stain, There are flowers that bloom, and their beauty retain; No rough wintry storms, nor
                            fierce tempests that roll Can harm those sweet flowers that bloom in the soul; 'Mid the hot
                            scorching rays of earth's fierce summer SUllj Their freshness and vigor appear just begun.
                            They will blossom anew in that heavenly land, Where joys are eternal and beauties expand;
                            Where pure crystal streamlets continually roll To water those flowers that bloom in the
                            soul. Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rupe, Polly M." TEIform="persName"/>Polly M. Rupe</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">The following article speaks • for itself. Some of our correspondents need just this in-
                            struction, with additions. We have some otherwise good articles*, on hand, which we know not
                            what to do with, while very many have been reluctantly hurled into the waste basket: The
                            Lowell Courier says : "When will that millenium for editors arrive when correspondents and
                            writers for the press will no longer fill their articles with such abbreviations as "Sect."
                            for secretary, " Pres." for president, "o'clk." for o'clock and the like? when they will not
                            interlard their sentences with nondescript hierogtyphics which they think answer for
                            punctuation, but which are as meaningless to the typographical eye as an inscription from
                            the Moabite stone ? when will they not underscore every third word under the mistaken notion
                            that the italic fronts of type are as large as the Roman ? It is ordinarily easier for the
                            journalist to copy a piece of manuscript than attempt to edit that furnished by those
                            unaccustomed to write for the press. And yet the only directions to be followed are the
                            simplest : to let the manuscript alone after putting down the words needed to express the
                            meaning. As for not writing on both sides of the paper, we despair of ever beating that into
                            the heads of correspondents."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialism" TEIform="index"/>Materialism</head><p TEIform="p">The influence of Spiritualism, and its widespread action, is, indeed, one of the wonders of
                            the nineteenth century. And, while it is a fulfillment of past predictions, it is also a
                            prophecy that the face of modern civilization will undergo a change. Several years (about
                            1843) before the advent of the " rappings," I heard the following prophecy uttered: " That
                            which you have witnessed (Spiritualism on a small scale among the Shakers, will break forth
                            among the world." This prophecy struck me wTith much force, for I saw in its fulfillment,
                            revolutionary results. It has been, and is being fulfilled to an overflow beyond measure.
                            The mission of Spiritualism thus far has been to arrest materialism, and to disintegrate old
                            organizations and ideas. All attempts by spiritualists to organize, have made bad worse. In
                            the present phase of Spiritualism, there also is a prophecy, namely: " That as a wave of
                            spiritual light has reached rudimental humanity, so it will be succeeded by a wave of light
                            and warmth combined, producing religious conviction, which, in its results, will be
                            organizing. The elements with which to organize are plentifully strewn all over the realms
                            of sentiment and intelligence. Prominently among these will be new religious formations ;
                            the organization of labor, and its results; physiological matters, referring themselves to
                            the right use of the generative and nutritive functions. Also, governmental adaptations,
                            taking cognizance of property in, and the distribution of, land, with the abolition of
                            usury.* Getting into debt makes a man a slave; and taking usury makes a man a robber,
                            abstractly. Quietly standing amid the din of human thought, is the Shaker form of human
                            social life—"not numbered with' the nations"—a Peak, isolated and alone. Its foundations not
                            resting on mere human animal emotions, but on their denial, as a substratum, to be overlaid
                            with humandivine emotions, as a new base of action. Human reproductive emotions are the
                            foundations of all forms of social life; domestic happiness and embroilments rest there
                            also. Hence the wisdom of watching the heart, the emotions—with all diligence—for out of
                            them are the issues of hate and war, as well as of love and peace. One of the prominent
                            sentiments of society at present is in the direction of a permanent amelioration and
                            elevation of humanity as a whole. Governments that rule by might and power, force and fraud,
                            as do lions and tigers, are less and less acceptable. The power to obtain and possess
                            wealth, by merely lending *The law of Moses required an equal division of the land to the
                            Jewish people. It also made provision for such of them as might be too poor to cultivate
                            their lots, for it, in the name of God of Israel, called upon the more wealthy of the people
                            to give, or lend, to their poor brethren all they might be in need of for that purpose,
                            without asking or receiving either iisury or increase. And, moreover, if (through poverty or
                            misfortune) any of the poor were unable to discharge the debt before the end of the sixth
                            year, they Avere, in the seventh (or Sabbatical year) to be freely and entirely liberated
                            from all and every demand of their creditors. What a brilliant contrast is herein presented
                            between the Mosaical and the (as it is very improperly called) " Christian" modes of
                            providing the means of subsistence for the poor! money without creating any wealth, is too
                            palpably iniquitous to be recognized under any other.denomination than that of Satanic. The
                            antagonism between the accumulated products of labor and the laborer, shows such a devia-
                            tion from the rule of right as justifies an assertion to which I have to plead guilty, "
                            That humanity is now comparatively in hell." All over Christendom war establishments exist
                            to kill and destroy, associated with extensive efforts, at home and abroad, to preach a
                            gospel of peace, mercy and love, which is comparatively heaven yet. This is so outrageous
                            and unnatural a mixture, that there can be no wonder in truthful men and women spurning with
                            contempt such a combination, and looking elsewhere than to the meeting-house or the churches
                            for hope and peace. Such a state of things so long continued has brought forth the infidel
                            dogmatic materialist. He is the product of the absence of the divine in " the powers that
                            be," coupled with doings which violate the common sense, as well as the higher instincts of
                            humanity. That form of materialism which ignored spiritual facts is to me the most illogical
                            of all isms, because spiritual entities and their forces are the most material of all
                            things, and are eternally manifesting themselves in tangible creations or effects. Our world
                            is a world of effects modified by conditions; the unseen world is the world of causes—of
                            spiritual intelligent forces. The most repugnant form of materialism is found in a praying,
                            fighting, singing Christianity. To all doubters I would say, " Doubt, but be honest;" yet,
                            do not allow doubting to make ruts, lest the wheels of progress should get bemired, and new
                            and open ground could not be reached. A few days ago a person said to me, " I am a
                            materialist; wrhat my five senses can take cognizance of, I can believe." He then began to
                            decry Spiritualism as a humbug. To prove it so, he and some friends formed a circle, and the
                            table began to move; a bulky person placed himself on the table, and still the table moved.
                            His idea is, that the force that moved the table was confined to those in the body. I then
                            began to analyze and illustrate somewhat as follows : It was not the bodies of those who
                            formed the circle that moved the table, but an unseen impalpable force in pos session of the
                            circle. I then drew his attention to the indubitable evidences of spirit entity. I asked him
                            if he ever had seen a dead spirit ? implying, that as spirits in the body (taking him on his
                            own ground), being in possession of an unseen impalpable force, when out of the body, would
                            not be destitute of the same attribute. Spirit is force organized. Force is eternal, and
                            that power which renders force subservient to intelligent will, could not be less than
                            eternal. He related the following : " He had a friend engaged in carrying (by water) butter
                            to market. At a distance of more than a hundred miles, he saw his friend's vessel go to
                            pieces ; in a fewr days he had a letter informing him of the loss. I remarked that he was in
                            possession of another sense in addition to the five." <pb n="86" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 86 THE SHA.KER. A
                            person well known and of good standing among his friends, had spent the best part of his
                            life an invulnerable materialist; and had shown his great devotion to truth by much
                            doubting. This, with its associate caviling, had made some ruts in his mind. Spiritualism
                            came in his way—in his family, if I don't mistake. On its appearance, he met it with his old
                            tactics; but the manifestations came so thick and strong that the old ruts caved in, and he
                            appeared in print, declaring his conversion and adhesion to the truth of disem ¦ bodied
                            spirit-entity. Robert Owen, the social reformer and materialist, was met in the same way,
                            and with the dignity of a true man, and the simplicity of a child, he accepted Spiritualism
                            as a substantial reality. The many proofs of spirit-entity have so thinned the ranks of the
                            whole class of earthly materialists, that a corporal's guard is about all that is left of
                            them. One fact .dissipates the whole fabric of their doubts and negations. I consider
                            anti-religious materialism as only a passing phase of abnormal spirit-life, induced (as
                            above stated) by long-continued outrages against the common sense and higher instincts of
                            humanity which, by its love of truth, has providential^ operated to destroy the system that
                            gave it birth, a system falsely called " Christian," but which (its professions and
                            practices considered) is really the most Satanic the world has ever beheld. I have been
                            asked, "What is your idea of God ?" Upon this subject I have but few words to offer. I am
                            capable of thought and of organizing thoughts, and of manifest- ing them in external forms.
                            I am child enough to believe that I had a father and a mother; and that there is a Great
                            Central Father and Mother of us all, who are capable of thought, and of organizing thoughts,
                            even as I am, and of manifesting those thoughts by creations so grand and good, as to
                            impress me with wonder, admiration and awe. They are not far from any one of us. I will
                            follow on to know them. I am thankful for the "express image" of their Divine attributes, as
                            manifested through their first-born Son and Daughter from the human family—Jesus of
                            Nazareth, and Ann of Manchester, which manifestation, with increase, is still continued
                            through their successors in Christ—the Shaker Church, of their own establishing. These I
                            will follow, to them I will gather, as to the properly anointed Shepherds of those whom
                            Jesus Christ designated a "little flock." " Come !" and (with me) learn of them, for thejr
                            are "meek and lowly in heart." They seek not their own but others' welfare.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Fraser, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virtue alone is happiness below" TEIform="index"/>"Virtue alone is Happiness Below."</head><p TEIform="p">And, of course, the move perfect the virtue the more perfect the happiness. Self-indulgence
                            is not virtue. Virtue is self-denial—"the narrow way tha leadeth unto life"—happiness. Vice
                            is self-indulgence gratification — "the broad road that leadeth unto death'1—unhappiness.
                            NOBTH Union, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consecration" TEIform="index"/>Consecration</head><p TEIform="p">According to Webster, means " devoted to sacred uses." Let us consider this important
                            subject. We, as members of the Society of Believers, have covenanted to consecrate our ill
                            to the upbuilding of the principles of Zion. This is a weighty obligation ! It signifies
                            o-ir willingness to sacrifice our worldly inclinations, and yield obedience to a visible
                            lead. These cannot be accomplished by following our own inclinations, unless these are
                            consecrated and ratified by the Church. If I say I am consecrated, yet claim the right to
                            dispose of my services as I think proper, I give the lie to my profession, for I have
                            solemnly agreed to yield myself obediently to a visible Lead, and failing to do so destroys
                            my avowal of consecration. No matter how talented an individual may be, if not consecrated,
                            he may be the means of great discord, and the cause of Society's failure of blessing.
                            Consecrated truly, will be the devotion of our all for the benefit of mankind, having no
                            selfish objects in view, no personal desires to gratify; looking not for any reward, other
                            than an approving conscience; standing firm for the cause of truth and justice; devoted to
                            the right because it is right. Then are we truly consecrated.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Price, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Price, Shakers, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Angel's call" TEIform="index"/>Angel's Call</head><p TEIform="p">Hear the voice of Angel spirits Calling1 loudly unto all, " Come up higher—Come away from
                            Sinful acts by Adam's fall. " Leave behind all works of darkness— Leave a life of sin and
                            woe! Live to God—live pure and holy, While upon tills earth below. " God's right arm will
                            guide you yonder, Far above earth's pleasures vain, Where pure joys, substantial, holy, With
                            you evermore remain. " Then let all be found advancing— Toiling with a heart and will;
                            Laying waste the haunts of wll, And the Oil of Love distill." Shakers, N. Y.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Ann Buckingham</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Truth's mission" TEIform="index"/>Truth's Mission</head><p TEIform="p">All hail with joy the blessed day, That gospel truth may wing its way O'er this
                            heaven-favored land of ours, To aid the soul's expanding powers. O, may it enter every
                            heart, And quenchless light and faith impart; Until the kingdom here shall come, To be the
                            humble seeker's home. O, Gospel, gentle as a dove, Thine olive branch of peace and love
                            Shall guide the weary traveler's feet, Through fields where hostile armies meet. For in
                            earth's-field of toil and strife, The soul that seeks the higher life Will, by thy
                            talismanic charm, Be kept secure from every harm. Thou art the very Source of Truth,— A lamp
                            alike to age and youth.— From each polluting thing a shield, For all in thee, to God are
                            scaled. Bright Gospel, let thy glory roll In thunder tones from pole to pole; And wake the
                            slumbering ones of earth, To struggle for the heavenly birth. Yea, cast the veil of night
                            aside, And break the bands of sin and pride ; Unto the sorrowing race of man Reveal
                            salvation's lowly plan.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woodward, L. A." TEIform="persName"/>L. A. Woodward, Whitewater, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Omnipresence of deity" TEIform="index"/>The Omnipresence of Deity</head><p TEIform="p">Alas, how weak, short-sighted, and inconsistent are we! We may say we feel the )ower of God
                            within us, but would be shocked to hear one say, " I feel God within me." It will do very
                            well to say that no soul can be saved without the operation and indwelling of the spirit of
                            God; we should be startled to lear one say he could not be saved without the indwelling of
                            God in his soul. So, we lesitate not to admit that God is Omnipotent —Almighty, but we can
                            scarcely grant the possibility of his ubiquity. We must fix him a ocal habitation, give him
                            a form, and take from him Infinity. Nevertheless, we may be assured that wherever the power
                            of God is elt or perceived, there is the God of Power, since it is as absurd to suppose the
                            power of God without God, as to suppose God without power. Where the spirit of God is, there
                            is God, for God is spirit; and it would be as absurd to suppose the Spirit of God without
                            God, as to suppose God without Spirit. It is a mere figment of the fancy to suppose that the
                            Spirit of God is something distinct from God, and is as absurd as to consider the mind or
                            spirit of man something distinct from man. The phrase, "Spirit of God," may be defined as
                            God's influence, and it is mostly applied to the manifestation of Divine power in
                            individualized being—an inspirational saving influence of God in the soul of man. As to the
                            Omnipresence of God, which is so much more difficult for some to perceive than his
                            Omnipotence, it will be found that the latter cannot be rationally conceived to exist
                            without the former. It must be admitted that where God is there is power, and because his
                            presence is infinite, his power must also be infinite; and it is for this very reason that
                            his power is infinite, because he is everywhere, there ready to do what he sees should be
                            done. " The eye of the Lord is in every place, beholding the evil and the good." (Prov. xv.,
                            3.) Again, His Omniscience can no more be rationally admitted without supposing his
                            Omnipresence, than can his Omnipotence. Inasmuch as he is everywhere present, he in every
                            place sees and knows all that exists or takes place, and happy is he who believes that
                            nothing, the most minute, can take place without, at least, his notice. " The very hairs of
                            your head," said Jesus, " are all numbered, and not one of them falls to the ground without
                            your Heavenly Father's notice—not one sparrow falls to the ground without your Father." How
                            could he have taught the ubiquity of God in stronger language ? How, more clearly and
                            cogently, could he have set forth the infinity of his power and providence, his goodness and
                            government even in the most minute things ? Happy are they who heartily and habitually
                            believe in this Omnipresence and infinite goodness of God, the Heavenly Father and Mother,
                            and who are reconciled to everything which He permits .; who see his footsteps in every
                            thing without them, and feel Him " working within them to will and to do of his own good
                            pleasure," being conscious that they are daily and faithful co-workers with him. By Father
                            and Mother, I do not mean two distinct persons or beings in Deitjr, but that in the one <pb n="87" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHCA.KER. 87 Infinite Spirit or Divine Essence, there exists the
                            attributes of Father and Mother, just asmuch the one as the other. But Father and Mother are
                            the names of relations, not of esserices, and belong to that class of things which logicians
                            call accidents. They are accidental qualities or titles. This by-the-by. We will proceed
                            with our main subject, the Omnipresence. If it is difficult to conceive the ubiquity of
                            Deity, how shall we comprehend his eternity ? How shall we grasp the tremendous thought that
                            " He inhabiteth eternity !" (Isa. lvii., 15)—that all time, all being, and all possible
                            events, past, present, and to come, are alike intimately present with him, so that he
                            "inhabits," dwells in, and comprehends the whole as fully and clearly as the least
                            parts—that, as he inhabits and fills infinite space, so he as perfectly inhabits and
                            comprehends the whole infinite duration ? Yet all this is but a faint and inadequate idea of
                            his infinity. Our ideas on this subject must always be imperfect, and can only amount to
                            this, that after extending them to the utmost bounds of thought on every side, there is
                            still something to be added—an infinity of greatness and glory beyond, that a finite mind
                            can never reach. Yet even such inadequate thoughts of Deity are profitable and consoling,
                            when we consider that this incomprehensible infinity of power and goodness stands pledged
                            for the protection and final happiness of all who put their trust in him and obey his laws.
                            Into what insignificance and nothingness we little wrorms do sink, with all our boasted
                            greatness! Surely, if God were anything less than infinite we should be entirely overlooked.
                            But while the thought of his infinity humbles us in the dust, it consolingly assures us that
                            we cannot exist without his special notice and regard. For if we should conceive of the
                            least animalcule or atom existing somewhere in the universe out of the reach of his
                            knowledge and notice, we should instantly destroy the idea of his infinity, yea, of his
                            existence, because if one animalcule or atom can exist without his creative and sustaining
                            power, thousands more —yea, all the animals and atoms in the universe can exist without him
                            ! Thus, the necessity of God's infinity rests on the same foundation as that of his
                            existence, and we cannot overturn one without destroying the other.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism is a desperate remedy..." TEIform="index"/>Shakerism is a desperate remedy...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Siiakbrism is a desperate remedy for a desperate disease. It is radical, certainly, and it is
                            a question whether any less radical measure can meet the appalling character of the pas-
                            sions, as they appear in the unvarnished manifestations of every day life. But whether it be
                            a finality or not, it is manifest that there can scarcely be even a decent degree of saint-
                            liness till men and women are able to live a celibate life, so long as duty, inspiration or
                            reason shall dictate. If there be a possibility of living out a partial affiliation of
                            fraterna love and sexual passion, without the cast iron rules imposed by monogamic marriage
                            and the Shaker brotherhood, the road to it lies through Shaker grounds, at least.—New
                            Campaign.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the juvenile class" TEIform="index"/>To the Juvenile Class</head><p TEIform="p">Childhood, Youth, Manhood, and Old Jlge are analogous to the seasons. The human leart
                            represents the soil. Childhood is the spring time of life. Then is the proper time ;o
                            prepare the mind and heart to receive the seeds of truth, such as Honesty, Chastity,
                            Meekness and Love. The heart, like the earth, contains seeds or germs that would grow spon-
                            taneously and bring forth fruit; but an enemy tias infused poison into the soil, and sowed
                            seeds there that are not pure and good, and, if [eft to grow,would produce wild and bitter
                            fruit, if not decidedly poisonous, and they are unworthy to occupy a place in such a
                            beautiful garden as the human heart should be. Hence the necessity for commencing early to
                            plow deep, that we may upturn the soil and destroy any vile weed that may already have taken
                            root there. Some young persons cling with great tenacity to those plants which spring
                            spontaneously from the heart, because they are pleasant to the eye and sweet to the taste,
                            and are not very bad. But, if wise, we shall seek the best—the very best. There is only so
                            much soil, and we can ill-afford space, even for the indifferent. If young minds would only
                            decide upon one point, i. e., that they will always relinquish the inferior for the
                            superior, and welcome the hand of the cultivator to pass over them, and pluck up and cut
                            down everything but the useful and the good, then, through the medium and by the help of
                            those instruments which the great Husbandman of souls has provided, together with the action
                            of the spiritual and divine elements, wind, rain, dews and sunshine, every good plant will
                            flourish and grow, and yield its increase a hundred fold. And, like the industrious tiller
                            of the material soil, such will gather with a prudent hand all the choice fruits in their
                            season—natural and spiritual truths—in science and religion, and store the mind with all
                            useful knowledge pertaining to the life that is. present and future, and cause the reason
                            and conscience tp be coworkers in gathering all that is virtuous, good, and true into the
                            mind and heart. And when spring, summer and autumn have passed, and the infirmities of age
                            creep upon them, they will be able to wrap themselves in a mantle of truth which they have
                            woven, and feast upon the fruits of their labors, until an angel messenger is sent with his
                            chariot to convey their spirits home. Then they can lie down upon their couch and be
                            gathered in peace to their spiritual fathers and mothers, to feast upon the fruits of their
                            toil in the bright summer land, where the wintry winds can never reach them more. The change
                            from the terrestrial to the celestial spheres will be a source of joy, not of sorrow and
                            sadness, to those who have wellperformed all the duties pertaining to the rudi- mentary
                            sphere of existence. The death-sting is taken awajr, and the grave can have no victory over
                            the heart where nought but true plants have been cultivated, and which wil continue their
                            growTth, and bear fruit in the immortal land. Love-angels stand ready to extend the hand of
                            welcome to such, and to offer the meed "well done, enter 'into rest." But rest does not
                            imply inaction. Thehighesi order of angels work. An approving conscience m reference to the
                            past will stimulate to future action in the life and real home of the soul, which is beyond
                            the shadowy vale of time. My young friends, you are now in the springtime of life. What is
                            to be your future course of action ? Will you seek to satisfy the emotional feelings which
                            so often crave present pleasure, at the expense of principle, and thus produce the wild
                            flowers and plants of nature at the expense of the good and the true— blight the finer
                            feelings, and desecrate the soil of your hearts ? Or, will you choose the better part, and
                            cultivate in your hearts innocence, purity, child-like simplicity, and every other virtue
                            that will fit you to be companions of angels in spheres above ? In the celestial garden,
                            immortal flowers are blooming of the fairest, richest hue, and they send forth a sweet
                            perfume. It is the work of the angels. They sow, and they reap what they sow. They plant
                            vineyards, and eat the fruit of the vine. The blight, nor the cankerworm does not reach that
                            clime, for there law is not broken, and sin is not known.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life in God" TEIform="index"/>Life in God</head><p TEIform="p">Men are hunting for God, seriously looking after a physical being who will compare with their
                            pre-conceived opinions of a Supreme Being; by continuing the search, they will certainly
                            come up somewhere, perhaps among the ancient Egyptians, Greeks, or Romans, for they had gods
                            many. The holy Saviour said, "God is spirit, and they that worship him must worship in
                            spirit." Again, " no man hath seen God at any time," for the simple reason that he cannot be
                            seen by the natural eye. We may see and feel the agency of God in our fellow beings, where
                            he is manifest for salvation; we judge of good men, who are intellectually enlightened, by
                            their actions— those who see, know, speak, and act the truth. God is truth. Every work of
                            God is founded on truth, and the continued growth in truth is a positive test that the work
                            is divine; the man of God is thus manifested to the world. In the Lord Jesus was God
                            manifest in flesh or humanity; so in his faithful followers, the apostles, and thus in every
                            pious man or woman in his or her degree. God is justice, and is manifested in every just
                            person, whose life is a continued exemplification of the divine attribute. God is love, and
                            whenever and wherever love flows into our souls direct, it is God, and from the brethren and
                            sisters, it is God flowing through his children to each other—in fact, love is the
                            permeating and pervading, and alluniting bond of the universe. God is wisdom, as seen in all
                            his plans and works; for the "universe of organized mind and matter is planned and executed
                            with the most consummate skill and intelligence. God is power, the motive power of the
                            worlds without end; this force of the Almighty is continually in operation, carrying forward
                            the universal machinery; without this infinite and continued propelling force, the whole
                            would cease action. Growth, of every description, comes under <pb n="88" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 88 THE
                            SHAKER. the same supervision and law of love, in the development and maturation of all
                            plants, and their continuation and perfection by the immutable'laws of increase. To sum up,
                            the whole, both animate and inanimate, the plan, the execution, and continuation of the vast
                            expanse, all are of our Heavenly Parents! It will not do to talk of inherent principles, for
                            principles are only the emanations of the Godhead, and of themselves they are simply a
                            nullity — without the creative Original, a blank. If man is carelessly curious to see God,
                            and will not be satisfied to believe that he is, because of his intangibility, as an ocular
                            demonstration, let us ask him to make some experiments on himself. He is moved by spirit or
                            intelligence; has he ever had ocular demonstration of his own powers of thought ? Can he
                            inform us of the mode, of the wonderful working of the machinery in the production of his
                            ideas, and his continuous faculties on the complications of mind and matter ? Man is said to
                            be a microcosm of the world, of the solar system, and of the universe. In him there is a
                            center, or focus of thought; the whole body is moved and controlled by the nerves connected
                            with the power of thought, and extending to the extremities of the animal machinery. Also,
                            the mind has the power of self-control; the whole economy of body and mind is moved by the
                            central controlling influence—intelligence and love. Looking at the solar system, we see the
                            sun himself, with his deputed power, in the center of the dependent orbs, controlling and
                            carrying them with him in his unceasing cycles; this system is in concatenation with
                            another, and it again has its joining; and so, by analogy the whole universe is joined to
                            the Empyrean of the Eternal; the center—the God-home of intelligence and love! Around this
                            eternal center—the Empyrean— revolve the whole universe of mind and matter, and from this
                            inexhaustible source radiate law, life, love, and intelligence to the whole creation. God
                            governs the universe of matter by fixed and inherent laws; the universe of mind by agency of
                            ministering spirits. And if we may be allowed and permitted the figure of speech, by way of
                            illustration: to the Empyreal battery are connected all the ethereal telegraph wires which
                            send the divine intelligence to the innumerable hosts of intelligent beings, from the
                            highest archangel down through the conjoined precincts, with their kingdoms and families^ to
                            our earth, peradventure, near the very verge of intelligence.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Redmon, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Redmon</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life is like a flower bed..." TEIform="index"/>Life is like a flower bed...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Life is like a flower bed. in which thorns and roses grow promiscuously. Wisdom alone teaches
                            us to gather one and refuse the other. The great test of true friendship is constancy in the
                            hour of danger, and adherence in the season of distress. A mind well trained and long
                            exercised in virtue, does not easily change any course it once undertakes. Stereoscopic
                            Views of Shaker villages—Mt. Lebanon, Watervliet, N. Y., and Hancock, Mass., can be obtained
                            of James Irving, Troy, or at this office, $2.50 per doz.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be encouraged" TEIform="index"/>Be Encouraged</head><p TEIform="p">When dark spirits, round us stealing, Storm the castle of our heart, Let us, to our faith
                            appealing, Bid them, in God's name, depart! Why, with clouds dark o'er us rolling, Veil the
                            radiance of our sky, While bright angels, 'round us calling, Come with sunshine from on high
                            ! All above, around, is beauty, Sun by day and stars by night; Happiness our only duty, And
                            in God our sole delight. Every pulse that beats to heaven, Every thought attuned to prayer,
                            Every tear to pity given, Is a crown of glory there. There each stream is music flowing, And
                            each breeze is melody, Heart to heart in union growing, Soul to soul in purity. See the
                            golden chain ascending, Joining earth to heaven above ; See bright glories with it blending,
                            And its links all formed of love.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. Leggett. Union Village</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Freedom" TEIform="index"/>Freedom</head><p TEIform="p">What is Freedom and where is it to be found ? Our fathers fought for freedom. We inherited
                            it; are said to be the free-born sons and daughters of America. We certainly are inspired
                            with a love for freedom, and consequently have acquired a strong detestation of bondage. But
                            liberty, true liberty, is not attained by the sword. Though our country may boast of
                            freedom, yet are the. people free ? Are they not fettered down to earth by passion, pride,
                            envy, revenge, and evils too numerous to mention? Can we boast of liberty when we are not
                            able to govern ourselves ? Jesus said : " Ye shall know the truth, and the truth shall make
                            jrou free." Cowper, in some of his inspired writings, says : "He is a free man whom the
                            truth makes free, and all are slaves beside." This has been a subject I have considered
                            attentively from my youth up. It seems really lamentable that in these professedly free
                            United States, after the struggle there has been to emancipate slavery, that it should still
                            exist in our midst, wherein all might and should be free. I hate slavery. I read in one of
                            my school books, words like these: "And even now in some parts of united America, women are
                            but little better than slaves." How shocking! And again: "Man tarnishes his name and
                            brightens it again; but if woman chance to swerve from the strictest rules of virtue, " Ruin
                            ensues reproach and endless shame, And one false step forever blasts her fame; In vain with
                            tears the loss she may deplore, In vain look back to what she was before, She sets like
                            stars that fall to rise no more.'' Is this right ? I think not. It is not so in Christ's
                            kingdom. Jesus said : " He that is without sin, let him first cast a stone." And to the
                            woman : " Go and sin no more." If it is so in the kingdom of this world, I do not blame the
                            women for wanting more rights. Certainly all now have a right not to tarnish their name ;
                            and I would that they all had the grace and dignity not to do it. I am sensible that I live
                            in a very enlightened age and country, and do feel a strong sympathy with those of my sex
                            who would be glad to live lives of purity, if they could find the requisite protection. I
                            believe there are many refined ?young females who would wish to live virtuous lives devoted
                            to God, if they knew of a way. To all such I would say there is an asylum—I have found it,
                            and have for many years breathed its pure air free from all contaminating influences,
                            surrounded by dear brethren and sisters who are ever willing to strengthen and encourage,
                            not draw down, and back, but onward and upward. This haven, and this relation, The Shaker
                            will point you to.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Laura A." TEIform="persName"/>Laura A. Prentiss</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Obituaries</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beal, Henrietta" TEIform="index"/>Henrietta Beal...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Beal, Henrietta" TEIform="persName">Henrietta Beal</persName>, at Shirley...........Aug. 10
                                aged 17</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanchard, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Blanchard...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Blanchard, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Blanchard</persName>, at Harvard........Sept.
                            21</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fosgate, Mary" TEIform="index"/>Mary Fosgate...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Fosgate, Mary" TEIform="persName">Mary Fosgate</persName>, at Harvard..........Sept. 28</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reamer, Margaret" TEIform="index"/>Margaret Reamer...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Reamer, Margaret" TEIform="persName">Margaret Reamer</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon . .Oct.
                            6</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ulrich, Caroline" TEIform="index"/>Caroline Ulrich
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Ulrich, Caroline" TEIform="persName">Caroline Ulrich</persName>, at Watervliet......Oct.
                            8</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smith, Anna" TEIform="index"/>Anna Smith
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Smith, Anna" TEIform="persName">Anna Smith</persName>, at Mt. Lebanon........Oct. 10</p></div3></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker</head><p TEIform="p">This is the title of an able periodical, published monthly at Albany, N. Y., under the
                            direction of the Mt. Lebanon Bishopric of Shakers, and in the interests of that interesting
                            people. While almost every other sect and ism in the United States has its organ, it was
                            only last January that the Shakers established one of their own for the first time, and it
                            was done in response to the urgent demands of the friends of reform, that they should give
                            their ideas of life and happiness as viewed from the Shaker platform. The world at large is
                            somewhat cognizant of the life and practice of the Shakers, but are almost entirely ignorant
                            of their principles and doctrines. " The Shaker " gives information upon all these points,
                            and is a very interesting paper to every inquiring mind. Fifty cents per annum. Address G.
                            A. Lomas. —Springfield (.Mass.) Union. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Members of society" TEIform="index"/>MEMBERS OF SOCIETY</head><p TEIform="p"> Appointed to answer Correspondents, among whom are the Board of Editors. Elder F. W. Evans.
                            Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. " Issachar Bates. Shakers, N. Y. " Calvin G. Reed, Mt.
                            Morris, Livingston Co., N. Y. " Simon Mabeo, West Pittsfield, Mass. " Stoughton Kellogg,
                            Thompsonville, Conn., Shakers. " Albert Battles, Tyringham, Berkshire Co., Mass. " Win.
                            Leonard, Ayer, Mass., Shakers. " John Whiteley, Shirley Village, Middlesex Co., Mass. "
                            Kehemiah Trull, Shaker Village, Merrimack Co., N. H. " Henry Cummings, Enfield, Grafton Co.,
                            N. H. " John B. Vance, Alfred, Shakers, York Co., Me. " Alonzo Gilman, West Gloucester,
                            Cumberland Co., Me., Shakers. " Chas. Clapp, Union Village, Warren Co., O., Shakers. " Ezra
                            Sherman, Preston, Hamilton Co., Ohio, Shakers. " Stephen Ball, Dayton, Shakers, Ohio. "
                            Jacob Kulp, Pleasant Hill, Mercer Co., Ky. " J. R. Eades, South Union, Logan Co., Ky. " J.
                            S. Prescott, Cleveland, Ohio, Shakers. </p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publications" TEIform="index"/>PUBLICATIONS</head><p TEIform="p"> Christ's First and Second Appearing Dunlavy's Manifesto .... Millennial Church .....
                            Compendium of Shakerism Three Discourses on United Interests Tracts free, where postage is
                            paid. $1 25 1 25 1 00 0 50 0 50</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>