<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0701" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18770101" TEIform="date">January 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-8</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="1" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—-PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " if*7 Qtttk the ftittfldom of (Bod!" ^!(c
                        fosfimontt of eternal tmfh. Vol. VII. [ G. A. LOMAS, Editor, &gt; ( Shakers, N. Y.. y
                        JANUARY, 1S77. N. A. BRIGGS, PCBLlSflBB, i "V"^ 1 \ Shaker Village, N. H. j x\ O. 1.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Living present" TEIform="index"/>The Living Present</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline><p TEIform="p">It was a wise axiom with our early I ancestors, that they would recognize II "the greatest
                            gift (of revelation) as I i their lead." This cardinal principle f should never be lost. It
                            at once con- s firms the" greater works", the "greatif increase"; stimulates to present,
                            active if service, and is the conservator of all acquired good. Mother Ann Lee, feeling a
                            loss of the inspiring gift of God in her soul after sleeping, promised that if she could
                            regain it, she would never lose it through slumber, and many times she "labored all night".
                            She was then thebody, the church. And should not the church to-day, work diligently, lest
                            through! its slumbers, the gift of God be lost and I the darkness of night overshadow its 1
                            light, and the city On a hill be cloud" I capped? The Sabbath, the Bible, the church, the
                            ministry and the christian name, j each beautiful in itself, work ruin, when I made
                            substitutes for holiness of heart ~ and a divine life-for religion-which is something more
                            than historic chris- I tianity-if is life. Is our life, religion? I livingorembalmed? I We
                            need to look around often and see what is passing before our eyes, instead of looking
                            behind and before us. Time is a fragment of eternity. Devote every day to something TWW in
                            order, and let what is gained by one be I invested in all; becoming a permanent investment
                            for all time. Devotees who stand in the foot-prints of theirfathers, resting on their
                            laurels, stand square in the way of the living .present. Supine loyalty is not a christian
                            trait. "Follow me, the way, the truth and the life ", was the voice of Him, who, standing
                            guard around truth, cnrricd'n love stronger than death.] Hetloes notforecloseIiuman
                            concious-' ness against the income of new truth, nor make a nv one fact of human history, a
                            bar to developmcnt; but fairly I admits of an advance beyond him. I The little child,
                            innocent and trusting, just introduced into theworld of effects, seekingtoknow the causes;
                            is like those born spiritually into the divine)ifc, the kingdom. of Christ. Each.. onemnst
                            undcrstand icause and effect. . "Count tllecost",willalwaysbe in order .. 1\s thetestimony
                            of ]esusisthe .. spirit of prophesy';~Qisevery true christinn Institution , the cradle of
                            liberty and of progress. VIe look in vain to the tomb for the buds cf promise. Our hold on
                            the past is the needed lever to stretch the warp of time, making the web of life's
                            experience more! firm and perfect. But the tension should never resist the unfolding;
                            refnse the smiling woof; nor impede the flying shuttle of time. • Talents should never be
                            laid away in 'a napkin, white though it may be. God does his work by endowment; but the i
                            glorious destination to which a wise and: I active improvement will bring us, is not i the
                            work of the giver, it is ours. Why !then, wait upon th.c Lord, when the! l Lord is waiting
                            our service ? We have the example, the experience, the proof-sheet of the prophets, who have
                            given value to the world's history j their heroism, their living and dying for truth in
                            t!teir time. We, too, must battle with our errors. Cast away whatever has become of fate,
                            "perished in its using." Like an old carriage, if 1 fastened behind, will only aid in a
                            descent. Jesus broke from the exclusiveness ofl his early education, and tiding over on i
                            the John Baptist wave of inspiration. became an active agent in the world, for good,
                            aggressive good, else we had never known his history. And it was the •• Acts of the
                            Apostles" that were worth reading. Let each one add their mite and might to the record. Like
                            the glow-worm we only shine when in motion. "The prayer of action moves the world, It breaks
                            and tills the sad." Whenever such a prayer ascends, 'T will find response from G~d. Our
                            needs are parent to our prayer, .We seek for more of the divine; 'Tis breathed upon the
                            willing air, For those who live in present time, </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rev. Dr. McGibson, having just returned to Australia from New York..." TEIform="index"/>Rev. Dr. McGibson, having just returned to Australia from New York...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">REv. DR. MCGIBBON, having just returned to Australia from New York, is enlightening that
                            region with recitals of the shortcomings of American churchcs. The doctor is especially
                            aggrieved by remembrances of Dr. Hall's church. "I submit," 'he says, "that the magnificence
                            of the temple in which Dr. Hall ministers, its gorgeous exterior, its massive steeple, its
                            elaborate windows its luxurious pews, its richly carpeted and upholstered stairs and seats,.
                            and skylight, its , polished wood its unique everything, costing , $2;000,000 ought to be
                            condemned as a sinful • waste,and a practical notice to the poor that here the gospel and
                            the ordinances of Christ are intended for the rich." </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perhaps we have no greater sting or rebuke..." TEIform="index"/>Perhaps we have no greater sting or rebuke...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Perhaps we have no greater sting or rebuke for our transgressions, than to ,see. those .we
                            love most truly, committing the same Just as virtue brings its own reward, sin finds its own
                            punishment</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Materialism—spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>Materialism—Spiritualism</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName"/>William H. Bussell</byline><p TEIform="p">Spiritualism and spirituality are very intimately connected. re reality or the latter depends
                            upon the substantial reality of the former. Because, if there is no existence of man
                            spiritually after the dissolution of man corporally, then the entire regulation of his
                            conduct with reference to such an existence is a nullity. [Notonly is that which is styled
                            religion 'a myth, but morality, which supposes obligations of human' beings towards each
                            other, is a mere rope of sand. There can be no such thing as progress for man, for, towards
                            what shall he progress? But the substantial facts I gathered from the history of mankind, ,
                            show that they are, and have been for ages, powerfully influenced by the idea of {mmortal
                            life for themselves in other spheres, and of intercommunication be- I tween the occupants of
                            those spheres f1and of the earth. It matters not that, . in their ignorance, the ideas
                            entertained by them were not originally and for fllong ages of a character adapted. to the I
                            i greater culture and refinement of these , latter ages, it is of consequence to know , that
                            they have rbeen strongly affected I by them in the regulation of their conduct towards each
                            other and towards : the gods in whom they believed. 'Whence came those ideas? From II ~
                            chance thought of ignorance and superstition,the materialist says; yet this chance
                            thought. has had a wonderful hoki upon the human mind, and it seems impossible, even at tbis
                            late day, to I loosen it. Men-not the religious I teacher alone, but the sage, the
                            philosopher, the scicntist,-have severally labored to improve upon it. From the forces of
                            nature, as seen in the vegetable and animal kingdoms ; ill the sun, ; the mopn, the stars;
                            up to those ideal ; things remarkable for their'. beauty, - strength, or authority, such .as
                            Jupiter, ~ Apollo,ancl the like ; and then to Brahma, Buddha, and Jehovah, the products : I
                            of the still advancing human intellect ; - tiIl the modern idea was reached, of the Infinite
                            Life, the Infinite Love, Wisdom,and Power, . there. has been a gradunl ..• enlargement of
                            the thought, which has. affected all, whether they have. professed to'-be believers or
                            unbelievers, I~.proportion.asthe ideasof [)eityand.theJuture.life have been ended,
                            there has,been an improvement I in the mental and moral character of those who have accepted
                            them. And even many of those who have professed to reject them altogether, have
                            participated with the others in the higher conditions that have ensued. Our modern
                            sceptical scientists are, in high-toned morality, the equal of their believing brethren of
                            the laboratory and the lecture-room. "Hope springs eternal" even in the sceptic's breast;
                            and when a full demonstration of tile future life has awakened certain dormant faculties
                            within him, it is wonderful how enthusiastic he oft-times becomes in defence of views be
                            formerly regarded with apparent scorn. His motions, as well as his calmer judgment, urge.
                            him at once to obey" the heavenly vision." The proof of immortalitymustbe within the heart
                            of every individual. Outward evidences and arguments.may.be ever so clear, but they never
                            can impart to the soul the certainty which the divine life established and increasing within
                            always gives. This is the lesson to be learned in the. school of Christ. It appeals to the
                            innermost of . man; to his natural unrest and longing for something still better and better.
                            It is the lesson' which Jesus and his disciples learned, so that they loved not their
                            life-their merely sensual life to its d~ath, looking and working for one far higher-the•
                            eternal life. Before this glprious sunlight the shades of skepticism disappear forever;
                            This is, really, spirituality, or the spiritual life. It includes not only the highest grade
                            of n1oral, but conscious inspirations from the highesfsot1rcesof life, of whatever degree of
                            refinement or power. In the language of the old "apostles' creed," it includes especially
                            "the communion of saints,"the intimate association of those in whose hearts there is the
                            utmost sincerity," in whose mouth there is no guile, and in whose outward course there "is
                            no shadow of turning~"•. they being without fault before the throne of God." These are the
                            vanguard of that "greatmultitude which no man can number, who send. down through all the
                            adyancing hosts the word of faith, of couruge and hope. These are they " who pass through
                            the valley and make it a fountain," imparting through all its streams the fertility which
                            gives health, strength and beauty," and which will finally make" the desert rejoice
                            and.blossom as the rose.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Attention is called to "Plain Talk," page 8. </p><pb n="2" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bring forth, therefore, fruits meet for repentance" TEIform="index"/>Bring forth, therefore,
                            fruits meet for repentance."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName"/>RUTH WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">In each dispensation every increasing work of God has benn shered in by a call to repentance.
                            There are many at the present time who profess conversion and join the church, because it
                            has become popular to do so; but where are the "fruits meet for repentance?" In the great
                            revival under the ministration of John the Baptist, see what was considered "fruits meet for
                            repentance" at that time. "Then went out to him Jerusalem, and all Judea, and all the region
                            round about Jordan, and were baptised of him in Jordan, confessing there sins." There were
                            some came without bringing forth the fruits of repentance. Such he called "a generation of
                            vipers." Others said, what shall I do? He said, "He that hath two coats let him impart to
                            him that hath none, and he that hath meat, let him do likewise. This was fruit meet for
                            repentance. After John was cast in prison, Jesus proclaimed the same message,saying the time
                            is fulfilled, repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand. Therecame to him a certain ruler
                            and asked what he should do to inherit eternal life. Jesus .. said; keep the commandments.
                            He said, aU these have I kept from my youth up. what lack I yet? Jesus said . jt .thou will
                            be perfect, go sell all that tbQu hast, come and follow me, and t1\oll.sbalt have treasure
                            in heaven. He went away sorrowful for he had great possessions, There was no . fruit here
                            meet for repentance. At another time jesuspasaed through Jericho. There was a man by the
                            name - of Zacheus, chief of the publicans,' and was rich. H-e soiJght to seeJesus, but could
                            not tor the press, as b~ was small of statue, $0' he ran before and climbed up, into a
                            sycamore tree, Ut~ he was to pass that way Jesus looked up and saw him said to him,
                            "Zacheus, make haste and come down; for to-day I must abide at thy house." He hastened down
                            and recieved him gladly. Jesus must have preached repentance to him, for before he left,
                            Zacheus said, "Behold, Lord, the half of my goods I give to the poor, and if I have taken
                            anything by false accusation, I'll restore four-fold." Jesus said, "this day has salvation
                            come to this house." Here were the fruits of genuine repentance. No doubt he had taken this
                            oppotunity to confess his sins, and was now ready to right his wrongs. Let us see what were
                            the fruits of repentance in the great Pentacostal revival, when three thousand were added to
                            the church in a day. "And all that believed were together, and had all things common and
                            said their possessions and goods, and parted to all men is every man had need." Surely this
                            was preparing the way of the Lord, as it was written, "every vally shall be filled, and
                            every mountain shall be broaght-Iow," The true spirit of the gospel in its operation, levels
                            all distinctions, makes new and equal men and women.r.Revivals that donot produce this
                            change-c-repentance-s-without fruit, will fail to bring salvation from sin. In modern times,
                            when there has been a genuine revival; it has produced the -same results, and there have
                            been many baptized into one spirit. It has been aid. that -no one -could carry:out the'
                            precepts of Christ in practice, without becoming a pauper. So far from this I being the
                            case, those who live. out the principles of the gospel most perfectly, live in communities
                            where pauperism is impossible. In order to become successful in any undertaking, we must
                            comply with certain' conditions; we do not look for the stars' while the sun shines, nor for
                            the glow-worm till it is dark; neither need we look for the principle of selfishness to be
                            eradicated while living in an isolated selfish condition. Nor will those who depend upon the
                            merits of Jesus,' find salvation from their sins. They will have to follow his example, and
                            walk even as he walked, live as he lived. For he became the author of eternal salvation to
                            all those who obey him in their lives. Union Village, O . </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who wants happiness?" TEIform="index"/>Who wants Happiness?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erickson, Larz" TEIform="persName"/>LARZ ERICKSON</byline><p TEIform="p">True happiness is only to be found in a true self-denying life. Shaker faith, carried out in
                            practice, will fill the soul with goodness and true happiness, Obedience to the faith will
                            purity our hearts ready to receive spiritual things. Riches and honors of this world do not
                            make men nor women happy; because mankind are lost in transgression and disobedience to
                            natural and spiritual laws. It was intended that a great deal of happiness should rest upon
                            mankind in the natural order, if they would practice obedience to the laws for offspring;
                            but now, transgression of the law destroys the best of it, and causes so much sickness of
                            body and weakness of mind, with the affliction of licentiousness on the offspring,ihat now
                            fills this earth with sorrow and anguish of soul in children and parents. And mankind are
                            unhappy indeed; and there is no other way to remove it, but to reform: "cease to do evil and
                            learn to do well." There is a voice from heaven to -mankind, repent and believe in.th'e
                            gospel of Christ's second appearing. He will, reveal himself in every soul who will receive
                            :him ',. He revealed himself in great Power and glory to our mother, Ann Leeso that he was
                            able to crucify. all deeds , of the flesh, and rise with Christ in the first resurrection,
                            and many others that shine bright as stars, on this earth, in all the,Shaker societies in
                            America. Now men and women and youths of every kind and class, why not rise with Christ in
                            the first resurrection? Why not come out from the world and purify yourselves from sin and
                            from sinners, and-be, happy? Why not honor and respect your Savior and meet him with joy and
                            thanksgiving? He will make an end of sin in your souls, and destroy the power of darkness;
                            lay the foundation for a new heaven in every soul that receives him, and who renders
                            obedience , to his requirements. He wants you to give up all: father, mother, wife and
                            children and your own life also. If you do that you will be happy, and free, full of joy and
                            thanksgiving night and day. You will be the light of the world even as He was the light of,
                            the world. Every true Shaker is happy in tbe midst of suffering and tribulation, able to
                            give thanks and glory to God now and evermore. Pleasant Hill, Ky . </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature" TEIform="index"/>Nature</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah Ann" TEIform="persName"/>SARAH ANN NEAL</byline><p TEIform="p">Behold, upon nature's countenance fair, A. lesson of brightness and joy written there; Each
                            leaf as a letter, each cluster aline, Forming a part of creation divine. For a teacher is
                            nature, so simple and rare, to scholar of science can with her compare; A. volume of
                            knowledge is seen in her face, While deeper the lines of rich substance we ,trace: Every
                            flower and shrub is a work so complete, No skill at the artist can with it compete; But in
                            magnificent grandeur, the forests excel, ln displaying the hand that doth all things well."
                            .. _ There are uses and beautie; in nature we see; Both clasp hands together in sweet unity,
                            Both forming a link between pleasure and toil, Which brings forth the fruits of creation's
                            rich soil. Ah! nature's a science exquisitly fine; Outwrought through the skill of an all
                            supreme mind; , , And out, through the face of creation so fair, This spirit divine looketh
                            everywhere. This spirit so grand, is seen in the storm, A.nd heard in the breeze of a calm'
                            summer morn; While each growth of nature, is destined to be A. glory and praise to its
                            divinity. Fair nature! so simple and beautiful too Our minds love to linger and commune with
                            you. A. magical power o'er our feelings you throw, That bears us away from all trifles
                            below, To a region all tranquil, all bright and serene Where the angels of God e'er delight
                            to convene,- , While joy, that's supernal, forever rolls on, And friends meet to part not,
                            in one happy home.c-- A home in the heavens, all lovely and fair, Where pervesion ne'er
                            comes; but true nature is there The image of God-the just, perfected. man, Where nature, as
                            pure as when worlds first began. Then sing not to me of a nature that sins,- Of the syren
                            that strives till her victim she wins; Nor yet of unspiritual nature applaud- But that God
                            of Nature, whose nature is God Sakers, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A rational church is what thousands are in search of..." TEIform="index"/>A rational church is what thousands are in search of...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A rational church.is what thousands are in search of. They are dissastisfied or
                                    disgusted with the actual church, and have no thought of abandoning a religious
                                    life. They are waiting for the ministry of the ideal church.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">Whether in the company of the rich or poor, educated uneducated; the necessity for the
                            exercise of wholesome good manners is ever the same. Without affectations.it holds its
                            possessor the genial and simple representative of what Webster defines, an educated mind.
                            'In the difsusion"of this liberal' education which the masses are so happily receiving at
                            the present time, we may be justified in the expectant hope; of a higher interest in that
                            departmeat which signally exalts the mind of man. It is one of the beautiful. gifts of God,
                            which has not upon it the condemnation of caste. It glows in all its loveliness, in the
                            cottage as well as the place, in the youth as in the adult. No disciplined , moral mind can
                            well afford to be negligent in this respect ; while the professor of a spiritual life, the
                            disciple of the Nazarene, would prove himself most unfortunate to assume that high calling,
                            and at the same time treat with carelessness' the preliminary degree of simply good manners;
                            But our time and our little paper has limitations; so we will make reference more
                            particularly to that phase of the subject which, at present, interests us most. ,Always.,
                            for a proffered as well as for actual kindness, we should make a liberal compensation,
                            through this free-will and beautiful compliment," I kindIy thank you." This was a cherished
                            form of expression among the first founders of our institution,and has ever been the
                            instruction of our gospell home. It is a treasure far more substantial than can be purchased
                            by flatttering words, or by the bestowing of presents. How pleasantly everything. awakens
                            into new life, when this beautiful response, heartfully follows a deed of kindness! Those
                            who have learned to speak this sentence, and at the same time have learned that gentleness
                            which .should accompany the remark, have, indeed, in their posession, a pearl of great
                            price. " I thank you! "Did you ever realize what a magic influence these four little words
                            exercise upon the hearer, and also upon the speaker? Take the first opportunity and make the
                            experiment. Age is no barrier, for we must need ever be Iearning., Children should have the
                            spirit of this sentence so indelibly impressed upon their minds, that no burdens, nor
                            duties,which ;may devolve upon them in more advanced years will ever cancel or even dim this
                            very essential obligation. , .' The introduction of an . abbreviated form of the sentence,
                            destroys in a great degree, the cherished-effect, for what is worth doing at all is worth
                            doing well; and whatever is worth our notice..of thankfullness, demands from us the best
                            that we are able to bestow, That which costs us but little anxiety or: expense to secure,
                            has generally. a corresponding appreciation.. Indeed, men of manners and men of the world,
                                may<pb n="3" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/>greet you with the simple word, "thanks.", If it wells up from an
                            .affectionate and generous heart it may be a most lovely award. But it is oftener a cool,
                            formal recognition Its commerciall value warrants its use by many. It occupies less time.
                            eTo use it, however, requires but. little effort, and in many cases, even the simple
                            monosyllable is mutilate« by the .suppression of the "tit," which measurabl y depri v es the
                            hearer of the anticipated blessing, and the shaker of the so much needed discipline. III
                            this form it can neither be consldered d~aodmannersnor good grammar; .and is by no
                            means-commendable in anyone. On our pilgrimage through this life. w.e.-nust be more or less
                            dependent upon each other. To admit this dependence shoulrl not only be a duty, but a life
                            privilege; In the society of our aged parents, this simple remark of thought-]
                            fuhppreciatioll, "I kindly thank you," D:J~y .for many days be to them.as the beautiful
                            sunshine in their path. Do not forget to use it. In whatever company. We maybeplaeedv-among
                            older oiyouriger, rich or poor, bond or free; We should never forget this christian
                            oblgation. Return thanks, and let it be from the goodness of the heart. Try this, beloved
                            friend, and witness the result.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>Prayer
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">True prayer is not the words that glide forth from the oily tongue; tis not the narrow wish
                            that the bounds the worthy supplicant's dome. Tis not the bended knee' of fear, crouched
                            'neath Jehovah's frown, !;. , Nor' yet the scalding, bitter tear, remorse " pleads with
                            renown. We see a hungering, sincere soul, bowed ;neath its Maker's shrine, ,.Its 'soul-throb
                            breathings, uttering, "O, not '. my will, but thine." , it's all a consecrated gift to God,
                            with utmost care, .:And'• Heaven, in accents clear, proclaims, .•. this, .mortals, this is
                            prayer. 2 A.., wrestling earnestness of soul, no epithet can trace; . a struggling, running
                            for the goal, of God's ....... assisting grace; Deep; ,deeper than the realms of thought,
                            more real than its blare, . And full dependence on its God, this, mortals, this is prayer .
                            . Abstracted from the world's turmoil, and '., .shielded from its gaze, And emptied of its
                            every spoil, the soul must " be :who prays' . . And filled with love to every soul,
                            recipient of God's care,' Read'y to glve to God the whole. this is 'the '; 'Work of prayer.
                            3 . But, prayer is more; 'tis Heaven's decree; a power the lame to heal, The sick restore;
                            the bond to free; to blind the light reveal ...•. ' The power to build on-earth a heaven,
                            and . store it with God's grace, . ;:And permeate it with a leaven to raise the ,~ ;. human
                            race, To mansions of the higher life where shame, nor sin, nor wrong, .! •. ; -; .Are ne'er
                            presented in the strife, which to its saints belong. . .' ,' The race is run from faith, to
                            works of peace, .. " And love, and joy Their prayers uplift their working souls, to heaven
                            without alloy </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Memorandum, No. 1" TEIform="index"/>Memorandum, Number 1</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Ever since the manifestation of Christ in the female, a work of shaking has; with many
                            extraordinary results," been going on ;and from, time to time has been felt among ourselves.
                            Under the idea of progress some have urged their conceptions upon our notice, tending in
                            some cases to the subversion of our form of government. We feel that a true line of faith
                            teaches that the work we are in is of God; that all true progress will proceed from', Him,
                            through the work itself in those who are subject to its order, and not in the line of
                            individual theories. We find it recorded: ., That the invisible things of God are clearly
                            seen by the things that are 'made, even His eternal power and Godhead," and with safety we
                            can add, the visible things of creation also clearly show that all' normal growth proceeds
                            from a living\.'=enter, and wheuuny part of a living body sets up local action not
                            controllable by central life, a wen;' a boil, or a carbuncle, tending to' disorganization,
                            will be the result. If we look through the four grand divisions of animate life, viz: the Ra
                            diate, the Mollusca, the Articulate, and through all the multifarious forms ot the
                            Vertebrates up to man, we find central life predominating, harmonizing with the members and
                            the, members with the central controlling power._ Central controlling life is a leading,
                            prominent, ever present manifestation of animate existence, and what is truly remarkable,
                            the growth of each, individuaI, from the low Radiate up to man is independent of the animal,
                            its will or volition. Jesus Christ saw this: " Which of you by taking thought can add one
                            cubit to his stature?" Those who venture to think and speak lightly of our form of
                            government will act wisely to be still and learn that God is in his holy temple, a redeeming
                            central power and authority, redeeming us from the bondage of our animal self-hood, its
                            passions and pro-] • penslties, and creating us anew in the. likeness of 'His divine
                            attributes. Even as the growth of our body is • irrespective of OUT choice, - so also the !
                            growth of the work of God will he • ' irrespective iof our calculations. The • best we can
                            do, all of us, is to be faithful to the appointed center of life, order and authority before
                            us. Let each and • all be true to " finish Transgression, put an end to sin, make
                            reconciliation for iniquity, and bring in everlasting righteousness." Do so, and, in due
                            time I every true desire will be fulfilled as regards government and development I of
                            functions. I say again, peace be : still i that which is calculated to disintegrate, let it
                            alone i it is for outside action. Even natural truths need to be ; sanctified to us,
                            otherwise they will do hurt, • There.is such a thing as a seeming subjection; Let your
                            obedience be from an undivided heart, warm and affectionate, overflowlng wlth thankfulness
                            that you have a part and a lot in a work which confounds the wisdom of this world and
                            humbles in the dust all selfexaltedness, Shirley, Mass • </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brother G. A. Lomas:" TEIform="index"/>Brother G. A. Lomas:
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Child, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>Henry T. Child, M.D.</byline><p TEIform="p">At the decade meeting of the Pennsylvania Peace Society, held at Mercantile Hall,
                            Philadelphia, Thursday, November ;16th, we. were favored with an able address by Elder Henry
                            Cummings of Enfield, N. H., a report of which will be published in the Voice of Peace, . At
                            the close of hit; remarks the following resolution, offered by John M. Spear, was
                            unanimously adopted: Resolved, That this society recommends the different families of
                            Shakers to send out their members as missionaries to speak on the subject of Peace. I do not
                            know of any way in which I can so effectually convey the above to the proper persons, who
                            will consider it and judge of the propriety of acting upon it, than through your paper, and
                            I will be obliged if you will give it an Insertion so that it may reach these. Truly thy
                            friend and brother, HENRY T. CHILD, M. D., 634 Race st., Plliladelphia, Nov., 1876 . </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hands to work, and hearts to God" TEIform="index"/>Hands to work, and hearts to God
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cornell, Jane A." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">While unto our daily labors, We with diligence attend, We may fix our thoughts on heaven, Let
                            our musings still ascend. Though our toils be hard and irksome, Taking all: our strength to
                            ply, It will make the burden lighter, If our thoughts we place on high. Often when we're
                            working hardest, All our thoughts are wandering far; Proves not this, that labor, seldom, To
                            reflection is a bar? 'Tis a lesson that our mother, Taught and practiced when on earth; And
                            to every true believer, All her teachings are of worth. Often did her weary toiling, Stretch
                            from morn far in the even; But with holy thoughts inspired, Dwelt she on the things' of
                            heaven. Let us then be ever striving, To obtain a good reward, By observing her example,
                            Hands to work, and hearts to God. Shakers, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbath" TEIform="index"/>The Sabbath</head><p TEIform="p">[The following communication' by •• ONE ~ OF THE BRETHREN" will have its purposed result a
                            recurrence of the orthodox, Shaker view upon the Sabbath day. For our own part, this is very
                            acceptable ; and we all, radicals and conservatives, may rest upon the necessity of some day
                            as a Sabbath, which I should be kept in general seclusion from secular duties and in all
                            religious sacredness..,~ • ED.) . ; .. The testimony and practice, of believers, Shakers, in
                            regard to the observance of one day in seven, as a day of rest from secular affairs, and its
                            appropriation to worship and social duties, has been attended with unspeakable blessings,
                            however much it may have been prostituted..Poor humanity, down • through many ages, has
                            greatly been benefited by the. institution of the Sabbath, and it is justly deemed of
                            incalcuIable importance, inasmuchas it draws a line of distiction between the secular and
                            sacred. We are happy in stating, that, on our last . visit with our beloved ministry, they
                            drew our attention to strict observance of the Sabbath day. We feel in union with them, and
                            believe .that the individual, the family or the society who applies the Sabbath the most to
                            divine uses and to the avoidance of all secular affairs, not absolutely necessary to health
                            and comfort in a normal sense, will be the most bIest~ &gt; Hence we were astonished and
                            grieved on reading an article, in The Shaker which, as we understand it, favored a secular
                            use of the Sabbath in regard to the "Centennial Exhibition." ' Being sure, that the
                            principles, and practices of Shakerism, together, with the explicit instructions of the
                            faithful leaders of this .religious people,have ever required a strict observance of the
                            Sabbath and its entire application to religious duties and spiritual labors; We anticipate
                            that the real ideas and purposes designed to have been conveyed in that article were not
                            clearly expressed. As we would be slow to believe that any brother of our Shaker faith
                            could. fail to perceive the irreligious immoral and sin inviting influence; which a neglect
                            of the observance of the Sabbath: would institute; and what debasement of society its
                            appropriation to secular. affairs, or mere pleasurable amusements would engender. We would
                            not, by any means, invite nor provoke controversy on the philosophy suggested by this
                            Sabbath question. But, there is no need of. comment to make manifest to all persons of good.
                            sense and common observation, the fact that, as a general thing, Sabbath breakers have a
                            disregard to religion- and its elevating discipline; and, in their history are embraced
                            great dissipation and abundant crime. In these remarks no personal reflectlons are intended
                            or . indulged, . Shakers, of all people professing the Christian name and character. have to
                            be the most deeply concerned;. protective discipline of the rising generation; and the
                            prevailing influence-, upon all classes of society to keep the Sabbath as a day necessarily
                            ,apart I for a Godly use, worhipful devotions, and the cuiture of the spiritual nature. It
                            never can be consonant with principles of Shakerism to abandon Sabbath keeping, nor to
                            encourage appropriation as a galaday. It is hoped that remarks that appeared in THE SHAKER,
                            relative to closing the "Centennial Exhibition" on the. Sabbath, were intended to admonish
                            the principles of sectarianaristocracy, rather than to indicate, much less to encourage the
                            prostitution of the Sabbath to mere secular amusements; and, by no means, to stimulate or
                            approve of the abandonment of Sabbath keeping. The laws of nature require periodical seasons
                            of rest and recuperation both to the soil and its vegetable production;<pb n="4" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/>and to all animate creation; and, the night season does not fill this demand. The civil
                            and religious nature of man institutes a Sabbath, or a periodical! season for cultivation
                            and development of the moral faculties and spiritual constituents of our being. The Jewish
                            religious law and all subsequent religious I revelations have recognizcd this and acquiesced
                            in these demands, and unite I in instituting a Sabbath. ' Because all mankind are not agreed
                            relative to what day of the week should he kept as Sabbath, it does not offer a consistent
                            reason for its abandonment; rather let the specific advocates of each religious profession
                            be true to their own convictions, and sacredly keep one day in seven as a Sabbath, and to
                            them THE SABATH OF THE LORD. ONE OF THE BRETHREN.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="One of the brethren" TEIform="persName"/>One of the Brethren</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hypocrisy" TEIform="index"/>Hypocrisy</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, E. T." TEIform="persName"/>E. T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">With every class, from men of sense Down to the prating fool, Sincerity is the pretense,
                            Hypocrisy the rule. The legislator in debate, The lawyer in his plea, And little lights, as
                            well as great, All talk hypocrisy. Grand prayers that from grand churches rise, With many a
                            pious groan, Cleave not the blue o'erarching skies, Nor reach Jehovah's throne. Here vice
                            usurps fair virtue's seat, And gathers homage there; There hypocrites, with faithful meet,
                            In God's own house of prayer. In language of hypocrisy, All nations fraternize; And
                            diplomats most courteously, Still dust each others eyes. Yon priest that points with
                            reverend hand, And eyes upraised to God, His followers to the heavenly land, Knows not
                            himself, the road. From pole to pole, in every zone, 'With nations bond or free, One tongue
                            alone to a ll is known, And that, hypocrisy. The smooth amenities that gl'ace The higher
                            walks of life; The polished greetitl\'!s that preface The foeman's deadly strife, The fr
                            iends hips, that adversity So wonderfully cures; Or writing to your enemy, "Affectionately
                            Yours;" All pregnant as dark realms below, Of rank hypocrisy; The only creed earth's nations
                            know, In which they all agree, </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sunday question" TEIform="index"/>The Sunday Question </head><p TEIform="p">A correspondent, from West Pittsfield, Mass., says: "I have often thought that Sun-day, being
                            a day named after the sun by the worshipers of that planet, should not be recognized by us
                            as the sabbath, etc," This is the same ground of : objection not long since used by our
                            worthy 1 Elder Evans. Our pcnwoman continnes: "Sunday being the .fint day of the week,
                            'while we were strictly commanded to keep the seventh, etc." We would say to Mary R. 1
                            Wheeler, that if her first objection, to our present sabbath has any force, it destroys
                            whatever reasoning may be used in defence of ' her second. All the days of the week were
                            named after gods or kings; and there is no more good reason for objecting to Sun-day as a
                            sabbath for religious thought, than there is to Moon-day, Saturn-day or the very licentious
                            signific,;nce of Fr;-day; or the day devoted to the god of thunder-Thurs-day; or the day
                            highest in the estimation of the idolatrous Germans and Scandinavians- Wednes-day; and what
                            better the day named after the god of war, :Mars-Tues-day? Let the union of the spirit be
                            the principal thing concerning the sabbath to be kept, as well as all things else about
                            which there may questions arise. We raise a much more important: I question, so liciting
                            answers thereto: How I can the Sabbath be most profitably observed? </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grand issue" TEIform="index"/>The Grand Issue</head><p TEIform="p">We salute eaeh and everyone, in this opening volume for 1877, with all the wishes of
                            God-speed in our hearts. Our highest purpose is humanity's best interest-our hope, the
                            elevation, regeneration, harvesting of souls, already ripened for a life, superior to the
                            narrow, selfish, reproductive clements of earthly life. "Adam was of the earth, earthy" ;
                            and Adam, with his co-workers and followers, we leave to the care 01 Moses, and Levitical
                            statutes; and plead for the abandonment of the earthly plane, only upon the principle of a
                            presentation of the superior life of the Christ-' 'the Lord from heaven, a quickening
                            spirit." "Servants we are, to whom we yield ourselves to obey" ADAM or CHRIST. W e cannot
                            obey two antipodal masters; we cannot walk in opposite directions at one time; we cannot
                            live in the flesh-engaging in the works of generation, fruitful or unfruitful-either the
                            good or bad of the earthy -and at the same time "walk in the spirit"-and be "vvarkers
                            together with Christ." We cannot be generative men and women, and truthfully wear the
                            christian name. Neither marriage, nor reproduction belongs to Christ; therefore, christians
                            will not do these things, but live as did Jesus, the Christ-he was a 7.Jil~']"ill-a!!
                            christians are virgins. The life of the heavens is a commtcne ; no personal, private
                            property there; so in Christ, christian life on earth, "none will possess aught he calls his
                            own." In Christ, in christianity, there is no private property, no personal possessions. In
                            Christ there is no war, contention, nothing to fight nor quarrel, about, all is peace;
                            "else 7.uoltld my , servants fight." Christians will not, cannot fight nor quarrel. "Render
                            I unto Caesar ;" but let christians maintain the distinction of Christ's government. It is
                            not meet that a christian and a Jew should be synonyms in name I nor in life. One may be a
                            good Jew, 1 and as yet, no christian. A christian 1 has transcended Judaism, been rcsur- 1
                            rected by following Jesus' example, to ( the superior, Christ life. Now is the ~ harvest of
                            souls, such as are ripe for the 1 life Jesus Christ Iived. Who is ripe ( for the harvest?
                            Who are christians? I " The jield is the world; the harvest 1 is the end if the World j and
                            the reapers are the angels." Thrust in thy :- sickle, and reap; for the harvest of the earth
                            is ripe." And some have been reaped into christianity-the angel life-in this present time.
                            And the grand issue is, who is ripe for Christ? - Who is a living, willing sacrifice unto
                            christianity? Let those who wear the name of christian answer first, by departing from all
                            unchristian life; or let them abandon the name. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saved? Then save others" TEIform="index"/>Saved? Then save others. </head><p TEIform="p">That the gospel of Christ is a saving element. every practical christian is a I '... ~ .
                            ready evidence. To a very large majority of professedly christian people, the price of
                            salvation is an unreserved, unquestioning faith upon the merits another, by whom they are,
                            or are to be saved j but this is not Shaker faith. Upon whomsoever is saved from sin, there
                            has settled the responsibility being very anxious for others, that they may be saved.
                            "Freely ye have received, freely give." "By this," love for one another, "shall it be known
                            that ye arc" saved. If the passage from the death of sin, unto a life in Christ, is to he
                            evidenced by "love for the brethren," then who is saved? Casting aside, as mere shams by
                            comparison, every ism of the head, the active practical religion of the heart is alone
                            christianity. The glorification that many indulge in, because of an infatuation that they
                            arc especial objects of salvation; who look with cool indifference, or with a heartless
                            sorrow upon myriads who are not as blessed as they are, this glorying is as thin and
                            inoperative as the escaped gases of an elevated balloon. The solid bottom of salvation,
                            will and must be reached: does your saiuatiou sat:c ot/sers ? Jesus was a saviour, because
                            he was saved; and there have been, and will be "many saviours arise," from this cause, and
                            this alone-being saved. Does salvation mean to us more love for others-a working love for
                            those unsaved? Does it mean to us more charity for, and a longer forbearance with the
                            erring? Does it lead us "to feel another's woes. and hide" by obliteration, " the faults we
                            sec?" Does it cause us to meet others, even half wayan their return from prodigality? As
                            whilom renegades from justification, do we recall the needs 'u!e had, of the fatherly and
                            motherly "falling on our necks, and kissing us?" Do we go down into the valley of
                            humiliation with those who need to go there, and thereby give hope to those that are without
                            it? The formal ceremonies of the confessor, and of going down into the waters with those who
                            are subjects of . baptism, are powerless for salvation, , unless the spirit of Christ
                            precedes, exceeds and succeeds the form. Go IN SPIRIT WITH THE SUPPLICANT. "\Ve had an high
                            priest" in Jesus, " that: could be touched with our infirmities;" nor in Jesus alone. And it
                            is more, very much more of this spirit of helping others over hard places, that we all need,
                            to be true, representative christians, saviours to mankind. To be implacable to our own
                            faults first and most j to manifest our superior christianity by an excess of charity j to
                            exalt the good l of others, even by self-abasement; to l be pure from principle, and to
                            teach purity from the love of it and of souls; to resist not evil; to speak no ill, and to
                            desire so greatly the salvation of humanity from sin, that we so offer ourselves as
                            sacrifices for men, that we willingly share their exertions to be saved: arc needed
                            requisites to prove OUl" rights to the name of Christian, and as proofs that we are saved.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record and Social Life</head><p TEIform="p">The necessary haste, to put copy into the hands of the publisher for this particular number,
                            is Our excuse for leaving until February, SOCIETY RECORD, and more extensive "SOCIAL LIFE"
                            letters, None can understand but ourselves, why the haste. But we would remark , that there
                            has been nothing looked for more eagerly by our renders, than the items of our" SOCIETY
                            RECORD," so far as we are made aware, That this RECORD I may do good alone, it should be as
                            full as II possible, ever dignified, and free from mere gossip. We cordial lv invite such
                            items of , interest each month,' from each Society, as will corrti nue to make the RECORD
                            appreciated and most profitable. A short time siuce, we remarked that there was much
                            correspondence to and from the Societies, that would be very interesting arid proper for THE
                            SHAKER to invest. Let ue have it, "boiled down," and full of sunbeams. We know not why
                            SHAKER SOCIAL LIFE should not be the happiest; and if it is, why withhold the recipes, with
                            directions? </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? no. 1" TEIform="index"/>What shall I do to be a Shaker? No. 1 </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/>BY THE EDITOR </byline><p TEIform="p">NOTE: It is our Intention to answer the question, forming the title of the following article,
                            in all, or nearly all of the numbers of the present volume; and having invited some, hereby
                            invite all Novitiate Elders, to share in glving an answer to the quest.on. \Vo nrc realty
                            sorry that delay on the part 01' others, lins ne;,'e~silntt'd cur writing No.1, our
                            connection with tho Noviriate Order having ceased some years since. El1.] What shall I do to
                            bo a Shaker? No. 1. BY THE EDITOR. This interrogatory has been addressed to us so often,
                            that we would make a plain statement, giving a satisfactory answer, and thereby meet the
                            ncccss itics of many who dread "there are lions in the way." There are many Novitiate
                            Elders-each Society having tour, two of each sex-whose duty it is to answer this question.
                            And though om' verbal expressions might differ, there is no disagreement in our
                            understanding, concerning the means an i ndi v idual rnus t take if they would become
                            satisfied, trusty, aud permanent members of our Society, Our first thoughts are: \Vhat is
                            YOUl" motive in wishing to join us? Among the hundreds of answers which might honestly
                            meet this query, only the following will prove efficacious in the end, which is: ;, I am
                            sick of sin, and want sal vation from it!" Where this is apparent, we are never anxious to
                            know if an individual is rich or poor; but would prefer one of this class with only the
                            clothes commonly in possession of moral people, than to admit any on other reasons, though
                            they had the wealth of an Astor. Anyone seeking admission as a member, is rcqu ircd, ere we
                            can -give any encouragement at all, to settle as fat' as possible, all debts and contracts
                            to Hie satisfaction of creditors; and then our rule is: If candid seekers after salvation
                            come to us, we neither accept them nor reject them; we admit them. leaving the Spirit of
                            Goodness to decide as to their sincerity<pb n="5" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> cerity to bless their efforts,
                            if such,or to make thell; very dis.satisfied if h ypocritical. After becoming thoroughly
                            acquainted with OUl' principles, we ask all individual to give evidence of their sincerity,
                            if really sick of sin, b v a n honest confession of every improper t;allsaction or "in that
                            lies within the reach of their memory. 'This confession of sin to Elders of their own sex,
                            appointed for the purpose, 'we believe to be the door of hope to the soul, the Christ ian
                            valley of Achor.and one which every very sin-sick soul scize s wuh avidity, as being'
                            farmore conlforting' tha 1121l1Darrus s ing. And this opportunity remains a permanent
                            institution with us-e-to confess, retract out" ',"Tongs as 111cnl0ry rna.v recall thcm ; and
                            aids individuals in so thoroug hly repenting 0[; past sins that they are enabled to leave th
                            ern I in the rear, 'while they pass 011 to greater salvations. It often take" years for an
                            individual to complete this work of thorough CONfession and 1~{'il?Jttallcc j bu; upon
                            this, 1110re than upon aught else, depends th.eir success as/ permanent and happy ll1ernbers
                            .. Those who choose to usc deceit, can do so, but never make I reliable members; always
                            uncomfortable wh i le I they rernai n ; and vcry few do or can remain, unless they fulfill
                            th is important dcrna nd 0:-/ '~OPCl1iil •. ::;- the lulu_d.H If 'Zue do not detect their
                            insincerity, God does, and they are. tcmpted of the devil beyond their wish to remain with
                            the Shakers: while "he that cOll.fcsscth and .fursa!:cth his sins, shall find me rcy." Th is
                            is not a lucre confession to mortality, but unto God, witncsser; by those who have
                            thoroughly cxper ienced the prac tical results of the ordcu], "My son, givc gl~r'y to the
                            God of heaven j confc .... •s u ut» 1-1111-1, and tcll me what thou hast do nc." S0111e
                            InaJ" ask: After pasdng this ordeal: is it expected we can gl'-e up our early educations,
                            our rooted theologies, and ideas pecul iur to our parents and tutors? We answer: Believe
                            what you please; we only ask you to live a pure, clean, holy life. Believe in one God or
                            three, only let no god be an interference to the principle of 8trict(~st dr cipl ine of
                            purity. Inclinc, if you choose, to predestination, only regard it as e stab l is her] that
                            you were predestined as a Christian, to be a follower of Jesus in virginity of life and
                            thought. ' Your education, pcrh"ps, has led you to bel ieve in Jesus as an atouerncnt ,
                            continue to do EO, if you prefer, but also assure us that to he at-one-ment with Christ is
                            to live free and apart from fleshly lusts and worldly ambitions, and to pattern your life
                            by the Christian model. \Ve care not what you bcl ieve nor: have bel icved ; we are not
                            concerned with I! your ruetaphys ics.j-ou- matcria l lsm nor spiritualism : we ask you to
                            square your lift by I' him ,vhose life was "without fault" before i Pilate and before high
                            hea\'en. Do you ask: I: Must I give up my property O,' mercy? Not I: until you choose to do
                            so. We have arrangements by which you can be a member and retain every dollar or dollars
                            worth of property ; but while enjoying the bounty of Society, it ! demands as its right the
                            use or interest of such properly for its maintenance or improvement. True, so long as you
                            retain as personal property any private possessions, you are not considered as truly and
                            fully a member as others who have consecrated their all, even if this consisted of naught
                            else except their devoted selves. The thorough consecration of one's self, is giving up or
                            losing all of worldly life to find eternal life; while saving aught of that, loses
                            this-eternal life. You are married : if a man, take excellent care of t her whom yOll have
                            promised to love and ( support; but this care must not entail upon ~ you the practice of
                            unchristian, fleshly lusts, Are you a woman? Lead about your husband as a Brother only; set
                            a guard to retain his feet in the chaste affections and associations, of angel life. Have
                            you children? Bring: them up as pure as the heavens. If they have inherited aught but
                            purity, nip in the bud the practice of vice, Teach them that Jesus said "Come, and be like
                            unto me, for of such is the kingdom or heaven." Introduce to them early, the necessity of
                            accounting for every misspent word and deed. All arc required to give their signature to a
                            COVENANT, which embodies obedience to the fundamental principles of our insitution. It. II
                            expressly provides that for the benefits of the ) I Gospel, derived while such remain as
                            mern~ bel'S, none will make other demands of remuneration for services performed, than that
                            which the insu-ument illustrntes. None sign away their rights to wit.lrdraw from the
                            institution , nor is the institution bound to retain any whom it would expel. But upon
                            mutual t agreement, dcrived by fulfilling the spirit of I this COVENANT, any individual may
                            assure themselves, in return for their services, the best care of the institution for body
                            and soul, in sickness and in health, in childbood and old age, and participate to as much
                            fullness in all its religious and spiritual blessings as they may choose. We ask none to
                            abuse their conscientious , convictions, unless these should prove adverse to the spirit of
                            Christianity; and although to the multitudes this kind of conscience appears an
                            impossibllity, we have had assurances of its existence. We all labor with our hands, pray at
                            the same time with our hearts, and endeavor so to live that each day shall find us prepared
                            for a better beginning on the morrow, in this, or in some better world. Our onIy demands
                            are, the successful prosecution of a pure life, after the Christ pattern; believing and reu
                            liaing that all other feature, of Christian communism will immediately succeed. Do you say
                            you have been living apart from all fleshly impurities. all wrong. ing of others or
                            yourself, aud endeavoring to feel consecrated to God in all your ways, words and thoughts?
                            Truly, you have been a Shaker without the name, and without the knowledge of your many
                            confederates! And none are more ready to welcome JOu to their hearts and homes than true
                            Shakers, nor more ready to recognize that" thou art not far from the kingdom of heaven."
                            Bear in mind one other important feature: It is not a positive necessity that men no] women
                            leave an unbelieving partner to become fully united to us in spirit. Many at either sex have
                            progressively jostled along in the work of regeneration until they have either won the
                            unbeliever to the faith, or heaven has opened some way for the deliverance of both to the
                            better life. While we are cognizant of the hundreds of difficulties appearing in the way of
                            a believer in true Christianity, when bound by civil ties to an unbelieving partner, still
                            we can only urge a mutual understanding between parties for maintenance of the faith by the
                            believer, either by an Instrument in writing', granting a permit to separate for this
                            purpose, or by I agreement to live together, yet maintaining I the same chastity of soul and
                            body which the one believing would feel called upon to practice if in the Society. It is
                            ever prefer. able, to have the husband and wife united in thei r determination to carry out
                            the demands I of our faith; but where only one has faith, which is not uncommonly the case,
                            then a mutual agreement is necessary to separate, that the believer nlay unite with Society.
                            But, if for any prudential reasons, business. children, property, etc., parties are
                            permitted to remain out of Society, they must understand that close adherence to the
                            fuudamental I principles of our faith is all that can mainlain their connection; while any
                            intended departures from these, however secretly engaged in, or covertly unconfessed, will
                            positlively work their expulsion. When all things of earth, man-made creeds, worldly
                            pleasures and carnal vanities fail to yield that needed peace and rest to your weary
                            spirlts, turn to, and address your nearest and dearest friends- THE SHAKERS. _________ A.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is a stern truth which is stronger..." TEIform="index"/>There is a stern truth which is stronger...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is a stern truth which is stronger than all Spartan lessons:- Poverty is the master ill
                            of the world.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There are some things which we confess..." TEIform="index"/>There are some things which we confess...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">There are some things which we confess are very difficult for us to explain. Among
                                others: How Spurgeon, a professor of Christ or Christianity, could : "hope the time is
                                short, before the entire Mohammedan race will be swept t from the face of the earth!" to
                                which his auditors responded, with a "tremendous amen" We ask, in the light of genuine
                                Christianity, could devils hope for worse, or respond more tremendously? Again: The
                                World's Crisis, in a nearly three column editorial, , illustrates the strength of the
                                contending forces in the East, and sorrows that the " Christians are not united in
                                slaying the Mohammedans I" The World's Crisis looks for Christ daily! Surely, "My
                                kingdom is not of this world;" and those who pleasure in war are devils, not Christians.
                                Who follows Christ in war? </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When professedly christian people do wrong..." TEIform="index"/>When professedly christian people do wrong...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">When professedly christian people do wrong, or that which Jesus never did, and which, "to
                                follow him" would forbid; they do not commonly presume they were not christians, but
                                christian sinners for the time. It is far easier. quite popular, to be a christian
                                simler; but truth demands that we say there are none such, and who sins is of the devil.
                                and is not a follower of Jesus, is none of his.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Celibate does not sufficiently define shakerhood..." TEIform="index"/>Celibate does not sufficiently define shakerhood...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Celibate does not sufficiently define Shakerhood. By a SHAKER, we mean a virgin celibate,
                                one who either never has lost virginity by carnal contact, or one who, having been so
                                unchristianly unfortunate, is redeeming that virtue by dint of an extreme self-denial,
                                equaled only by the example of Jesus, the Christ. It is a matter of importance only, not
                                whether an individual SHAKER has ever been a virgin celibate, or of recent conversion;
                                the importance lies in the fact whether he or she is living the life of a virgin
                                celibate now, "to go no more out forever" Jesus was more than celibate; he was virgin.
                            </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why call me Lord..." TEIform="index"/>Why call me Lord...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"Why call me Lord, Lord; yet do not the things that I say?" And to every christian church
                                of all lands, this question implies with equal importance. They alone are christians who
                                love the Christ life so well that they walk" the way " Jesus walked; learn'" the truth"
                                of his words; and live the life of him whose" way, truth and life," are our atonement,
                                by following the Lord in the same. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In the face of so full a knowledge..." TEIform="index"/>In the face of so full a knowledge...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">In the face of so full a knowledge, that licentiousness is the ruling sin of this
                                age-nearly everything bending to cater to the sensual, sexually and solitarily-how can
                                any, without excessive shame, decry the gospel testimony, or living examples of a people
                                whose lifework is to counteract, encompass, and, subdue this extensive field of the
                                devil?</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What if benevolence were as strong a force in human nature..." TEIform="index"/>What if benevolence were as strong a force in human nature...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">WHAT if benevolence were as strong a force in human nature as selfishness; couId not this
                                be a happier world? Yet It might be as strong a force if it were as persistently I
                                cultivated. Then don't go on applauding every selfish net or purpose you know of, unless
                                you stop complaining of a bad world.-New Age</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Paragraphic of life" TEIform="index"/>Paragraphic of life
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The exposure, that "Mother Shipton's Prophecy," so extensively quoted, was writen in
                                1862, and not in 1448, will be a disagreeable surprise to many thousands. It was the
                                deceptive work of a man named Charles Hindley, of Brighton, Eng. It is not generally
                                known, that our Bro. J. M. Peebles has been a student of Materia Medica, and graduating
                                recently, received this M. D., and is now Dr. Peebles. We were permitted a knowledge of
                                his training and metamorphosis. The Chief Justice of the U.S. decides that no woman
                                needs apply for permission to practice in the U. S. Supreme Court. Here is the silly
                                reason: "By the uniform practice of the court from its organization to the present time,
                                and by the fair construction of its rules, none but men are admitted to practice before
                                it as attorneys and counsellors." The music in THE SHAKER, present issue, is the
                                production of SHAKER souls; the typography the work of SHAKER hands; and we are proud to
                                feel, that it will be appreciated the more, when the fact is made known. We feel almost
                                warranted in challenging better typography than is set by our dear, Shaker sisters. We
                                would answer C. W. S., by saying: Gov. Tilden was not born among The SHAKERS; that he
                                never was a Shaker, that we do not attribute his bachelor lite to any influence of
                                Shakerism. His birth-place joined the Shaker farms at Mt. Lebanon, and himself and
                                brothers, besides father and mother have been familiarly known to the Shakers, for a
                                time equal to the governor's age. A recent paragraph tells us that Spurgeon's sister has
                                entered the pulpit. Our word for it, she will prove more charitable, liberal, and
                                dispense more salvation than her noted brother, who "deals damnation round the land," on
                                each, he judges the Lord's foe. We are glad theprcfcssedly christian pulpits are being
                                opened to women, if the courts as yet deny them practice. Almost anyone can discover the
                                soul of the following gospcl wit by Josh. Billings: "Trying tu l iv on the rcputashun uv
                                a dcd grundfather, iz just about az enterprizing az I trying to hatch out rottun eggz
                                under a tin wether-cock. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Said Parker: ''No step backward, is the rule of human society...''" TEIform="index"/>Said Parker: ''No step backward, is the rule of human society...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Said Parker: "No step backward, is the rule of human society. What is gained by one man is
                            invested in all men; and is a permanent investment for all time."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Any one doubting the benificial effects of Shakerism..." TEIform="index"/>Any one doubting the benificial effects of Shakerism...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Anyone doubting the beneficial effects of Shakerism upon the churches, can profitably
                            investigntc the modus operandi of Thos, K. Beecher's church in Elmira, N. Y. The poor are
                            cared for by the church. A refectory is attached thereto for the hungry, There is a church
                            horse and carriage to convey the aged and crippled to and from church, and to take the sick
                            and convalescent on an airing excursion. It looks after the morals and occupation of its
                            youth, and is educating quite a number for the ministry. It was this Beecher who recommended
                            confession of sin, as c , helping a man a good deal, to know that some one else knew of his
                            misdeeds." </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="I see no advantage in piety which permits a person to be a scamp..." TEIform="index"/>I see no advantage in piety which permits a person to be a scamp...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Murray" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">"I see no advantage in a piety which permits a person to be a scamp. I do not see how society
                            is to be benefited by a religion which is not applied to the destruction of these vices. If
                            Christianity cannot stop a person from lying, slandering and cheating, either outside of the
                            law, then what is it good for? AntI has not the time come for us so to define relligion as
                            to make it mean virtue, and nothing short of it?" Murray. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If I cannot govern my own tongue within my own teeth..." TEIform="index"/>If I cannot govern my own tongue within my own teeth...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Franklin" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">If I cannot govern my own tongue though within my own teeth, how can I hope .to govern the
                            tongues of others?" Franklin</p><pb n="6" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every man takes care that his neighbor does not cheat him..." TEIform="index"/>Every man takes care that his neighbor does not cheat him...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Every man takes care that his neighbor does not cheat him. But a day comes when he begins to
                            care that he does not cheat his neighbor. Then all goes well, He has changed his market cart
                            into a chariot of the sun." Emerson. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emerson" TEIform="persName"/>Emerson</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My religion is known to God and myself alone..." TEIform="index"/>My religion is known to God and myself alone...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">My religion is known to God and myself alone. Its evidence before the world is sought in my
                            life ; if that has been honest and dutiful to society, the religion that has regulated it
                            cannot be bad." </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jefferson" TEIform="persName"/>Jefferson</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let everyone ask, ''Why am I a Christian?''..." TEIform="index"/>Let everyone ask, ''Why am I a Christian?''...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Let everyone ask, "Why am I a Christian?" and there will appear a heavy responsibility
                            resting with the answer. If it is because it makes life better, like unto Christ's, then is
                            the answer correct-any other reasons will prove unchristian apologies. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Show me your faith without works..." TEIform="index"/>Show me your faith without works...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Show me your faith without works, and I will show you my faith by my works"--life.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Paul" TEIform="persName"/>Paul</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Science of a new life" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cowan, John" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Household cyclopedia" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Zell, T. Ellwood" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principia: or basis of social science" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wright, R. P." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Book Table. I \Ve would not recommend an unworthy book, sooner than we would counsel evil
                                companionship ; for both '-'-forrupt good manners." It is our great pleasure to
                                present to o u r t liou-a n ds of readers' notice three valuable volumes, enc.i at
                                which IS worthy of a column of praise. "Till': SCIEXCE OJ! I\. KE.W LIFE," by JollJI Co
                                zua n, lIf. D. Whe n wefirst read th is book nearly two years since, we pronounced it 
                                unequaled by any book published in the present cen tury. It is certainly wonderful, that
                                in all age of 1110raI corruption, of pelf hunting and sord.d graRping, there should be
                                such a display of u nreserved con secrat io n to thebest go~d ~f p hvs ica l humanity!
                                l Iere in are the ,,!;ins of licentious ness. and the forcing upon the world unwanted
                                and unwelcome children. to pine, suffer and die, no honor to their parents, ane! unowned
                                by nature, thorou vh l« rebuked. IIerein are instructions, which if followed, would make
                                our earth an Eden in a few generations, and the a sce n s io n from the perfected enrtb
                                1)' to a state of "heaven on ear th," would b ecornc so easy and natura l that Shaker
                                societies would -beCOl11elhe true balance of the lawful principle of reproduction.
                                Again. we sa.v, this book has had no equal in its line. Cowan Ca., P/(bl,~~ltcrs
                                .1'ic::! York. THE HOUSEllOLD Cvcr.or nnt.v, by T. Eliwood Zel!. In this volume of 500
                                pages, we find th e 111:)st compe nd.ous work upon almost enry imng i nabl e subject,
                                that has been issued from any press in this world. Not only 1:),0::::0 and more well
                                tried receipts upon the most excellent themes, but a fund of information upon many
                                thousands of top;cs which would necessitate an extensive library to procure. It is a
                                beautifully illustrated work, and w el l worth the small price asked for it. 111d~~d,
                                rnrmv editions of it must be wid. before its publisher can he repaid for the extensive
                                researches necessarily made in its com. p ila tio n. Ba/.:er, Du zus Ca., Pitt/adelphia,
                                r«, Publisaers. PRI:S-CIPL\: O~ B.\SIS OF SOCL\L SCIEKCE. by R. P. T-Vrt:f{ltt. So much
                                has been said of this work 011 social science, that all we can add may seem superfluous.
                                Its table of contents is the most replete with subjects of any work of its kind, be in
                                z fully twenty closely printed pages, while the div i s io n s and subdivisions of the
                                work itself, d.s p'nv the labor of many years, by one who.Iy devoted to the science to
                                which the title inroduces us. Would that there were mere thoughtful men and women i for
                                here is . a b: ok of 524 pages treating upon themes of vital importance to the I
                                perpetuity arid happiness of human society. I Although many of the talented author'sl
                                schemes, for the illustraton of heave'! on . I I earth, m \V seem utopian, yet on y
                                great I good could be derived from the attempts at their solution: We are cnwu,;j;eJ in
                                practi-l co lly solvng a part of these problems j ar d it is agreeable to think how much
                                the author credits our labors as a class of Spiritual Socialists, while dealing with
                                all other forms contained in the almost illimitable field of sociology. The work is
                                published by LiPPi,,-  cott : Co., Philadeljhia, Pa. The Am. Spiritual Jvlag-aziJll: is
                                a bold, noble per.odical. Its aim i s higher than any other s p ir itual istic sheet
                                that we know of. While it "did not fully endorse" our views upon "The Dcc~ille (If
                                Spiritualism j" nor of "The Neiv Mouemeut;" as published in Nov. Shaker, yet it was the
                                only so-called Spiritual paper that alluded to those articles; and it had the unusual
                                and unlooked for courage to quote both entire, as being" food for thought." As it is
                                worthy of much help, send to Memphis, Tenn., a helping hand and a ppreciati ve heart.
                            </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Recipe Gleanings.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One of the best washes for the teeth..." TEIform="index"/>One of the best washes for the teeth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">One of the best washes for the teeth is camphor water reduced to a weak solution. It is
                                not only very detersive, but really healthful to both gums and teeth. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Science of health says: Germany excels any country..." TEIform="index"/>The Science of health says: Germany excels any country...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Science of Health says : Germany excels any country in the cleanliness of its beds
                                for sleeping. To the daily stripping and airing of Shaker beds, may be attributed much
                                of the general good health of its people. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Add a little carbolic acid to your mucilage..." TEIform="index"/>Add a little carbolic acid to your mucilage...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Add a little carbolic acid to, your mucilage, paste, glue, and these will not mould. An
                                ounce of the same added to a pailful of whitewash used in cellars, barns, dairies and
                                meat rooms removes the disagreeable odors usually found in such places. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A valuable liniment is recommended by The Cottage of Hearth..." TEIform="index"/>A valuable liniment is recommended by The Cottage of Hearth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A valuable liniment is recommended by The Cottage Hearth, for sprains, bruises and
                                lameness in man or beast. Take an ounce of oil of wormwood to a pint of alcohol, and
                                bathe freely. It also recommends a </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flax seed lemonade" TEIform="index"/>Flax seed lemonade
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Flax-seed lemonade: Pour a quart of water over four tablespoonfuls of flax-seed. Steep,
                                not boil, three hours; cover closely while steeping; strain and sweeten to the taste.
                                Add the juice of two lemons, thinning with more water if necessary. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Those who are troubled by cold feet..." TEIform="index"/>Those who are troubled by cold feet...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Those who are troubled with cold feet may be largely assisted in being more comfortable
                                by sprinkling the inner side of the stockings with Cayenne pepper.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Household gives us a new ''Indian Pudding''" TEIform="index"/>The Household gives us a new ''Indian Pudding"
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Household gives us a new "Indian Pudding:" To a pint of scalded milk, add half a pint
                                of Indian meal, a teacup of molasses, and six sweet apples, pared and cut in small
                                pieces. Bake three hours. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Also the following for ''Corn Bread''" TEIform="index"/>Also the following for ''Corn Bread''
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also the following for "Corn Bread:" One pint of slightly scalded Indian meal, one
                                tablespoonful of shortening, two eggs; stir well; add half teaspoon of salt, with yeast
                                enough to make it rise. Bake in a quick oven, </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lemon Pie" TEIform="index"/>Lemon Pie
                            </head><p TEIform="p">LEMON PIE: The yolks of two eggs, one lemon, grate the peel, one cup of white sugar, half
                                a pint of milk. Cover and bake. Make a frosting of the whites of the two eggs, three
                                tablespoons of white sugar. Pour over the pie and let it brown lightly. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Now that the long winter months are upon us..." TEIform="index"/>Now that the long winter months are upon us...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Now that the long winter months are upon us, let us profit by what The Country Gentleman
                                says on hulled corn. This old fashioned luxury is coming into style again, and as it is
                                really a delicious dish when properly prepared, it ma.y be acceptable to knew the modus
                                operandi of doing it right. Take a six quart pan full of ashes (hard wood ashes if
                                possible, as they are I stronger); put them into an iron JettJe, with I three gallons of
                                water; let them boil about I five minutes j then set off from the fire and' turn in a
                                pint of cold water to settle -it. Turn I off the I ve and strain; put it into an iron
                                kettle, and put in six quarts of shelled corn .put I it over a brisk fire, and. let it
                                boil half an hour, skimming and stirring frequently. The outside skin of the kernels
                                will then slip off, Strain 0fY the lye, and rinse thoroughly in several clear waters.
                                When the lye is thus weakened, turn the corn into a large dish-pan, and turn in. water
                                enough to cover it j then rub thoroughly with the hands, till the little black chits
                                come off': rinse and strai~ off till the water looks clear; then put back into a clean
                                kettle. with water enough to cover it, and let it boil sIowly. It will swe ll to more
                                than double the first quantity. Boil till quite soft; it rna) be necessary to add water
                                occasionally; stir often, so as not to burn at the bottom of the kettle; when guite soft
                                put in two large tablespoonfuls of salt, and stir well. To be eaten with milk or butter
                                and sugar. It is a healthy dish, and though there is work in preparing it, yet it is
                                good enough to pay for the labor and trouble. It iii good either hot or cold. and was
                                considered by ou grand-parents to be one of the greatest luxuries of the table. Wheat
                                hulled in the same way is considered a great delicacy, and a very beneficial diet for
                                invalids, but it is not so staple or nutritious as Indian corn. Smaller 'quaru i tle s
                                can be prepared by using less lye and corn. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keeping the tongue" TEIform="index"/>Keeping the Tongue</head><p TEIform="p">Keeping the Tongue, Keep it from unkindness: Words are sometimes wounds. Speech is unkind
                            sometime. when there is no unkindness in the heart so much the worse that needless wounds
                            are inflicted-so much the wane that uninte national pain is caused. Keep it from falsehood:
                            It is easy to give a false coloring, to so make a statement that it may convey a different
                            meanir.g from, the truth, while yet there is the appearance ot truth, that we need to be on
                            our guard. Then are many who would shrink from telling a lie, yet who suffer themselves in
                            such inaccurate exaggerated or one-sided statements, that they really come under the
                            condemnation of those, whose" lying lips are an abornination unto the Lord." Keep it from
                            slander: The good reputation of others should be dear to us. Sin should not be suffered to
                            go unrebuked; but this should be according to the scripture method: "Go and tell him of his
                            fault twixt thee and him alone." What is too often considered as harmless gossip, runs
                            dangerously near, if it does not pass the confines of slander. A reputation is too sacred to
                            be made a plaything of, even if the intent be not malicious. (Waverly.) </p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">Lebanon-its beauty is incomparable; sunshine, in its pristine glory; air and water fresh and
                            sweet; landscape varied and extensive ; valleys, mountains arid little hills in every
                            direction; vegetation, from the forest to the flower, in full uniform: orchards and gardens
                            and meadows, with abundance of scattering fruit-trees of choice variety: ever greens,
                            berry-bushes, and white willow around ponds and beside the water-brooks go to make up the
                            pleasing diversity of OUR home, in its outward external aspect. The plagues of Egypt are
                            known only by hear-say mosquitoes, flies, gnats, poisonous serpents, and injurious plants
                            are the exceptions and not the rule. Health a good, sickness an evil. Of the moral virtues
                            and spiritual privileges--the gifts from above and the grace: from beneath-that adorn our
                            holy Mount they are innumerable. as seen by the pure of heart. Is not all this good, these
                            beautie and blessings-this God manifested in humanity a beginning of heaven upon earth: When
                            all the thorns and briars-the vice: and vile passions of human beings- are eradicated, and
                            all thought is in the light; who shall bear the glory ? </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Manifestation of truth" TEIform="index"/>The Manifestation of Truth</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p">Somewhere I have read that " anything which will unite people, and make them behave well, may
                            be called religion." I accept the declaratro n. No people can long exist and prosper without
                            religion, which to them must become an organic element, the tendenry of whose nature and
                            principle is, to unite and consolidate; otherwise, the constituent principles of
                            disintegration exist, and consequently, detruetion is inevitable. No family, people, nor
                            nation, not a christian church, however blest and prospered, however gifted and inspired of
                            God, can long hold an honorable standing, unless interwoven in itsIife, there exists a
                            religion having power to unite, to save and cause the body to behave well and make it
                            better. Is not this a subject of sufficient magnitude and importance to every individual ,
                            to every body of people, and especially to every christian church, worthy of being taken
                            home and brought to bear upon the life and character of that body or church? Should it not
                            so operate as to enforce a canvass of its life and character and an analysis of its
                            properies? Should any individual flinch from duty, because of the work he there finds to 10
                            and the burdens connected therew.th P Or, shall he seek to escape the scrutiny of
                            investigation , because of the imperfections of society and the evils of his own heart? Nay
                            if he attempts such a course, he is a coward, unworthy the name of a man, much less a
                            christian. If he is unwilling to let the light of heaven shine upon his acts of life, and
                            .huns investigation, he lack; moral courage and acts the hypocrite. And unless he makes
                            corrections, amendments and progress his life-work, he is dishonest, disloyal, unprincipled
                            and untrue to himself an.I (to his proession. lle who str ives every day of hs ife agreeably
                            to the light of his own concience, to live in perfect' justification before God and fears
                            no ill: he has notLi:J.g to .over nor conceal. Such a ma n is \\ illir g that h is life, his
                            labors and the motives of his 'ieart should be mapped out and spread before all the world
                            for inspection; he seeks -iot to evade the most scruti niz.n g survey, .he closest and
                            severest disquisi tio n or the Ieepest research, even of his enemies. If ie lives in
                            upri;htnes.;;, no true knowledge of lis life can harm him. He who fears most .hat the truth
                            should be told, is he whom the .ruth would indict. s , Lord, who shall ab.de in Thy
                            tabernacle, .vho shall dwell in Thy holy hill r" lIe only, vho is honest, just, innocent and
                            pure. He m ly, " that walketh uprightly, and worketh 'ighteousness, and speaketh the truth
                            in his ieart j that backbiteth not with his tongue, ior doeth evil to his neighbor, nor
                            taketh up l reproach against his neighbor; in whose 'yes a vile person iscontemnecl," and
                            "honor.th them that fear the Lord." (Psalm, 15th.) The spirit of the Lord was upon David
                            .vhen he uttered the words of tliat song. At hat tithe he had more theology than he
                            pesessed religion. Those principles lived, .vou ld have produced a \'ery different dispe
                            nation in those days of licentiousness and val' j and, carried out to-day, would make a
                            iaradise of this world. No more should we rear the call to arms; no more the din and
                            ufferings of war; 110 more the scourge and 'nhuman cruelty of slavery j no more would rrate
                            upon OUI• ears the hocking reports cf he corrupting, debasing, beastly and fiendish .vorks
                            of man j no more selfishness, '" mine md thine j" but one common interest would iervade our
                            paradis leal world j sin world be Ione away and the souls of men absolved "rom e\'ery taint
                            of evil and every influence hat would bring bondage or shame. Our i"overnment would become
                            divine, and comununity of interests and virgin life- would be ts basic principles; an order
                            after that of the <pb n="7" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>primitive christians, as that of the church I
                            established at Jerusalem in the days of the - Apostles would be our order, and the kingdom
                            of peace would be set up for us, universally to enjoy. In conclusion. let me ask :-ls not
                            this the work of the millennium? Is not this the angel, the resurrection order, the work of
                            Christ, as wrought- out in the life and exarn-l pie of Jesus? If so, will we sacrifice for
                            it and make it ours? Here lies the work for the decision of conscience. Obedience to this
                            faith gives us our christian, covenant relation. This perfect consecration alone is Shaker
                            life; and this alone extends the ranks of our holy institution. Canterbury, N. H . </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Elder Albert:  I owe you lots of apology..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Elder Albert:  I owe you lots of apology...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, December 24, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Dec. 24, 1876</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Elder ALBERT: I owe you lots of apology for not preparing something nice for jnn ua
                                ry, I am, head arid heels, into orcharding. I work, for these ten weeks, until, at noon
                                and night, the muscles set up an irresi stab!e cry for rest, like a brood of hungry
                                chickens for food. I am so tender-hearted that, although I know my duty to you and THE
                                SHAKER-to everybody depending on me to furnish something to stir up the dormant powers
                                of amazed indignation against new theologies, or ancient tr uth s-e--wh e n I lay me
                                down to "leep, and my rest is as sweet as revenge, while the resulting effect is , to
                                me, far better. But to you, to THE SHAKER, to everybody I do so love to rouse from
                                death-sleep of orthodox conservati-m-or to quiet in the excrte men t of mis-named
                                reform, it may b e disr s .rous in the extreme. Hew am I-to help in the matter of THE
                                SHAKER? I am on the earth or in the trees. The mysteries of apple raising occupy my
                                thoughts by day a n d my dreams by night when I do not bleep so sound that I cannot d:
                                .a m without going out of my bundle at muscles entirely. Then again, write? Wh at can I
                                Fay that is good, not already said in the December number, and fill" better said than 1
                                can say it? Love to you, as -c.ver ; and when I get all my out-door work done up, you
                                may expect to hear from me again by way of the pen. Of the Constantine Sabbn t h : As a
                                day of national. rest from physical -Iabor, and 01 spiritual indmtry-gocd. As a
                                theological day, on which the things that are were made, out of nonentity, by congeries
                                of creators":t&gt;s than a shadow. Do you take the Weather Probabilities? It (:0, are
                                they certai nt ies to you, as to us? 1 get, from the department, l11y daily report, 01
                                rather prognostics, which, for the last three weeks, has been as m i nr.te lv accurate
                                in slightly varying ~han.g-es of temperature, of clouds and sunshine, of rain and snow,
                                as 1 could make at the end of each day. Are we not entering upon a new era, where in man
                                will not only predict, but govern and control-ride the whirlwind and direct the storms
                                of nature, in the outward and inward clements of his own being? All is mall. As the soul
                                pertains to the spir it, so the body pertains to the soul, and the natural world to the
                                body, Therefore, when there is no government by man, in all these elements, it i~
                                because there is no God recognized by man-man living , but living without God, and
                                consequently without the power of government over his own spirit, soul, body, and the
                                outward natural elements. Is any sick, let him send for the Elders of the Church, as
                                the medium for communicating with God. Follow this law, through each department of kuowl
                                rdge, and God will be all, in each human being. All , power is given to me, said Jesus,
                                as pionce- of redeemed souls, both in I-leaven and Earth. And the power God has given
                                me is e qua lly for you, when you come into the condition I have' attained unto. What
                                manner of man is this, that even the winds and waves obey him? Just such manner of man
                                as all believers may become. F. W. EVANS.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My very dear Brother Nicholas:  As the mail brings me..." TEIform="index"/>My very dear Brother Nicholas:  As the mail brings me...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, December 11, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., Dec. 11, 1876</dateline><p TEIform="p">AYER, MASS,. Dec. II, 1876. My very dear Brother NICHOLAS: . As the mail brings me the
                                last of Vol. VI of THE SHAKER, I am very agreeably reminded that Vol., VII, which is to
                                be our welcome visitor the coming year, must receive material aid. Enclosed you will
                                find P. O. Order for full amount, as per circular July 26, 1876. Words are an impediment
                                in attempting to convey to JOu our gratitude for the willing burden you bear in support
                                of our little organ. As long as there is progress, there will be agitation of thought
                                and opjnions, which are as tr.butar ies to knowledge - to absolute truth. "Agitat;on of
                                thought is the beginning of wisdom." When that ceases! there will be no need of a paper
                                as an educator. "Silence in Heaven for half an hour j" or half a century. will not
                                quiet the elements. After "the fire of the altar was cast into the earth," "there were
                                ,-:oices, and th underings and lightnings, and earthquakes." We applaud the iconoclast
                                when he break; another's idols. Let no fondness or reverence. for form or custom blind
                                the eyes tc idolatry. Whatever claims our veneration: that discovers no present life,
                                and is not adapted to our daily needs, and fails to vital. ize religious devotion into
                                good works, savors of idolatry. Material or ideal. it matters not. Let us be "living
                                stones" in the rising temple; working for the growth of our souls: and for the
                                increase of the Christ kingdoin. And, if sometimes on our journey we feel the chilling
                                mists of the valley, and our feel press upon uncertain soil, and all seem: transition,
                                remember that all the apos tles of truth who have led the advance, found their line' of
                                march along this road. 1"01' ., Never on custom's oiled grooves The world to higher
                                level m o ves ; But grates and grinds with friction hard, On granite boulder and rlinty
                                s ha rd ; Even by losses the right must rcign, Ever." good have its birth of pain; And
                                graces and cha ri tiee feed the fire ! In which the wrongs of the age expire." i In
                                love, I remain, as ever, your abiding;~".' brother, ELIJAH MYRICK. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="G. Albert Lomas:  Dear Brother--I have been much assisted..." TEIform="index"/>G. Albert Lomas:  Dear Brother--I have been much assisted...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, December 23, 1876" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, Dec. 23, 1876</dateline><p TEIform="p">MT. LEBANON, Dec. 23, 1876. G. ALBERT LoMAs: Dear Brother-I have been much assisted and
                                comforted by "Would you?" in the December number of THE SHAKER, just at hand. ft has
                                assisred me to serious reflect io n, and by sa id reflection I have been comforted. May
                                it prove a word in due season to man.\ who are" 'twixt wind and water." We an
                                individually responsible for our e\'ery deed: word and thought; and although communism 
                                may possess a thousand blessings, it can never obliterate i ndividun!
                                resj-omibility. J wish youmuch success in Jour editorial fa. bors, For proof, I enclose
                                my mite. Would that I were able to do better. WiII you give "The Young Folks" a corner
                                in your enlarged edition of 1877? Yours, fraternally, THEO. GORHAM. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gorham, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theo. Gorham</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social life letters: cook's manual" TEIform="index"/>Social Life Letters. COOK'S MANUAL</head><p TEIform="p">My DEAR S.: Since I esteem you as a good cook, and an excellent counselor in this
                                department. per, mit me to call your attention to a subject which occupied my thoughts
                                while at breakfast this morning. It is not a startling om however, though it has a
                                surprisingly long title; and was suggested on seeing a dish 01 nicely prepared mashed
                                potatoes close at hand viz: The advantages derived frcrn " Labor-Saving Machinery," as
                                applied to modern cookery. Do you marvel that my thought: took this directlcn P \~ell, I
                                sat speculating upon the healthfulness of this vegetable as food; of its early historic
                                reputation as a poison, c., c, when I seemed to hear audible tones proceeding from some
                                sort of a "labor-saving machine," (constructed on the pestle and mortar principle), and
                                anon me-thought I saw the pestle materi,alize, and strike a most imposing attitude,
                                giving me to understand by sign, that I must partake of a vegetable which had been so
                                nicely prepared, "Observe," said the mechanical voice, "to what a refining process it
                                has been subjected, since removed from its native soil, through our efforts." " Again,
                                how long and faithfully we have served your people, in helping them to facilitate the
                                ready dispatch of cooked vegetables! Are we not entitled to your fullest confidence,
                                and a place on the list of 'labor-saving machines' in the record of arts?" Almost
                                confounded by this singular manlfestation.T meekly replied: Indeed; now I think of it,
                                the amount of dental labor \\'hich you have saved us, as wel l as a nation of patrons,
                                for many years is quite astonishing! The tons of vegetables, which have yielded to your
                                powerful impression, are almost beyond computation! Do not these facts prove to YOlT.
                                that your reputation is established, as well a s popular? Yeu should be estimated
                                truly, as a successful rival of the machines used in the extensive fouring mills ef
                                the great West. To« pulverize vegetabes, they reduce the hard gra:ns of wheat : to an
                                almost impalpable POWd_I', which is subsequently fashioned into [aky, snowy loaves, to
                                tempt the Franklin: cf our day to purchase. "L~tbor-saving 111a. hinery" in deed, which
                                saves one from chewing the hard substance of boiled potatoes! which renders teeth no
                                longer a necessity, save in speech! It follows, then, that food reduced to the
                                consistency of a sern i-so lid, invites the epi-cure to swallow some, digest less, and
                                ch e w none at all. Hence the process of eating, which once occupied thirty minutes, can
                                no w be performed in one fifth of that time, Mighty progress in science and art! A
                                hundred years of experience and scientific experiment in the culinary department,
                                culrni nating in such results! The word 1llast/ca!/OJ1, which occurs so frequently in
                                subjects tre.rting upon Hygiene, and which was n lW,l)'S ineuphonic, n1:1,v soon become
                                obsolete, if lexicographers do not object. (Exit ma- i c'r i ne.) Have patience, my dear
                                S., for thought expands by exercise, and I am disposed to see another side to this
                                subject, for the question arises: Why did the AIl- Wise design such a convenient
                                apparatus for our usc, if it was not intended to serve some grand purpose in the economy
                                of nature? Ph'ysi()logists and dentists nll claim that the teeth were made to use, and
                                are an essential part of the digestive npparatus ; and, is it not a fixed law of our
                                physical being, that every faculty must be exercised in order to maintain health? In my
                                opinion more teeth decay for want of labor than trorn any  ther cause, save want of
                                cleanliness. That here are triumphs in art as applied to machinery, I am not inclined
                                to dispute; but some machines denominated labor-saving, are, in the strictest sense,
                                labor-making; this fact allow me to prove. First, then, food prepared in a manner to I
                                dispense with chewing. is not onl)! unhealthy, but leads to the pe rn icious habit of
                                eating too rapidly. I have frequently observed that children accustomed to soft food,
                                show a disposh ion to reduce all hard substances given them to cat, to the same
                                semi-solid consis-l te ncv. Give such a piece of bread crust to eat. I and plump it goes
                                into the cup of milk near, or it is baptized with water till mellow enough to swallow
                                without mastication; and what are some of the unfortunate results of such a course P
                                Dyspepsin , with its legion of ills; teeth, prematurely decayed for want of use; while
                                around' the last sorry fact. cllH:t",rl: " series of facts too .doleful to forget when
                                once experienced in the form of grumbling, aching teeth. And now comes in the extra
                                effort, in acquiring the money used for repairs, the labor expended, the time spent in
                                repairing carious teeth, all these I present to prove that our so-called" labor- saving
                                machinery," is labor-making in more ways than one. " Gold and si lver have I none," enid
                                one, years ago. "Of gold and silver I have some," might a nation of young folks
                                exclaim, (though not born with a silver spoon in the mouth,) since many carry mere geld
                                in the teeth than in the purse, at least the value of this metal concealed in the
                                savings bank of a carious tooth, might purchase man)' a desirable object for the wealthy
                                passesser. Taking a retrospect of these facts, then, shall we not conclude that the
                                direct source of much -do mestic or physical infelicity ex-ists in our modern process of
                                cookery? I am aware that this co ncl us io n brings but poor con-elation to the fa.thful
                                time-serving ceo!", who caters to our perverted tastes, prov ided she seeks reward in
                                culinary achievement-: but •. Truth is mighty and must prevail." even in the kitchen.
                                1';O\V S., if after reading this medley of t viis, you can devise a remedy, please
                                manifest it in writin g, and by so doing coris ider yourself the contributor of a
                                benefit to the Cook's Manual, Please answer through ItS columns as ccc n :1S convenient.
                                Cordially, A.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A." TEIform="persName"/>A.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reply" TEIform="index"/>Reply</head><p TEIform="p">Reply. DEAR A.: I have read your musings at the breakfast table with ~ some thought and
                                care, and have reflected upon the long lid of physiological -i ns, wh ich I may have co
                                mrni tted in my ambition and zeal to be kind, by giving my best efforts in the art of
                                cooking for my friends and guests : never failing at such times to call to my aid the
                                pestle, or any other lablabor saving appliance at hand which would render good service.
                                But it seems, according to your suggestion, that I have caused other people to commit
                                physical sins, and from the in harmonious condition of the system thus induced, to
                                commit all manner of sins. At first I Was disposed to laugh at your cogitations; but,
                                indeed, I am growing very scber as I think of the sufferings and wrongs to which I have
                                been indirectly 01.' remotely accessorry It seems that the ills arising unhygienic diet
                                result not only in loss of health, ! loss of teeth, and, shall I say it?-Ioss of moral
                                integrity. It leeks reasonable that teeth must decay if they have never been
                                sufficiently used, or allowed to perform their natural functions. Again, I see that the
                                introduction of food into the stomach, masticated by artificial means, is not conducive
                                to health, it not having been mixed with the saliva, which nature affords, as is the
                                case when substances are properly divided by the teeth; thus we are inclined to swallow
                                the same too rapidly and this is another abuse of the stomach. The financial view of
                                your subject is quite appalling. I wish we had known how to live just right many years
                                ago, and consequently saved the money paid to dentists and. doctors, to expend in a more
                                sensible way, don't you? or retained it ill cur pockets. LA place for everything, and
                                everything in plnce;" L; a good motto for us in the cooking department, and equally
                                appropriate when applied to the care of money. I think it high time, in view of our
                                profession, to repent of Our past wrongs, praying meanwhile, that the sins of our
                                ignorance may be winked at, or winked away. Dear A., when you write again for our
                                "Manual" please make some suggestions for reform, or invite some one else to do so for
                                we are earnest for the right, and would like the best thoughts of reformers on this
                                subject, Yours, S.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="S." TEIform="persName"/>S.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="8" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Over the river" TEIform="index"/>OVER THE RIVER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Moorhouse, Benjamin" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">No longer we shrink on eternity's brink, or wish for a further delay; Clean robes are
                            prepared for the justified souls, and angels are guarding the way. Over tho river of death,
                            only just over there! The spirit released from its burden of clay, lives when made pure, in
                            an eternal day. 2. While nearing the stream, in vision I see a structure rise noble and
                            grand; 'Tis not built on any false dogma nor creed, 'Tis a bridge to the fair summer land.
                            Chorus. The shadow of doubt is forever dispelled, And kindreds are joined heart and hand ;
                            For messengers cross on this bridge: every day, From their horne in the bright spirit land,
                            Chorus. 4. Each day that we live, some gem we may store, The work of our own willing hand;
                            The garment we weave in this valley below, We shall wear in the bright summer bad. Chorus.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cui bono?" TEIform="index"/>Cui Bono?</head><p TEIform="p">The answer of a youth who was asked: What are the benefits that you receive by having a home
                            among the Shakers? It is a great blessing to me to be removed from Irreligious or vain
                            companions, through the influence of whom I might have become equally as irreligious, and
                            may be, far worse. At the same time my privilege places me among a cultivated and religious
                            people, who believe in living acceptably to God, through the purity of their lives, and who
                            teach all ethers the same practical religion. In this it gives me the privilege of leading a
                            better life than I otherwise could have done. It teaches me the confession of all sin before
                            God, an act which a certain gifted divine says, cannot but make a person better. It gives me
                            a union which my beloved Brethren and Sisters who have lived this life and who work
                            earnestly to develope the good in those who choose the same way. Finally, it makes me
                            conscientious and teaches me to work from a christian principle. Shaker Village, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Evergreen Shores</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shane, Thomas" TEIform="index"/>Elder Thos. Shane
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We learn, with sorrow, the decease of<persName reg="Shane, Thos." TEIform="persName">Elder Thos.
                                Shane</persName>, of Pleasant Hill, Ky., 84 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Haskins, Betsey" TEIform="index"/>Betsey Haskins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., <persName reg="Haskins, Betsey" TEIform="persName">Betsey Haskins</persName>, Dec. 8,
                                1S76, aged 85.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. R. H. Stores is one of the few clergymen..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. R. H. Stores is one of the few clergymen...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">DR. R. H. STORES is one of the few clergymen who refuse" loud calls." He was invited to Fifth
                            Avenue brick church on the top of Murray hill, at a salary of $10,000, and a millionaire
                            offered to purchase a house which readily sold for $65,000 before the panic and to furnish
                            it handsomely from top to bottom for his use while he remained pastor of the church. and yet
                            he would not ,accept. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oil up" TEIform="index"/>"Oil Up."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Gorham, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>THEODORE GORHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">Man, like a machine, is a combination of a system of forces. A community is a combination of
                            combinations, an instrument by which the direction and intensity of individual
                            force-faculty-is changed or concentrated to perform a work which could not be performed
                            without said combination. In m a cirincs we find always a loss of force through friction. In
                            a comrnu n ity we find a friction caused ;by the different parts of the combination-the
                            different faculties and natural tendencies of the constituent members-being brought in
                            contact; frlct ion is unavoidable, hut the true spirit of christianity is the oil, the oil
                            which calms the troubled waters and modifies the friction natural to the machine. The more
                            perfect the machine I the less friction. Mt. Lebanon. N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker experience" TEIform="index"/>A Shaker Experience</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Briggs, Caroline E" TEIform="persName"/>CAROLINE E. BRIGGS</byline><p TEIform="p">Away with all doubting ye feeble and fainting; Away with all fears for the Zion of God. The
                            Lord in his infinite wisdom is guiding The feet of the wanderer to Zion's blest horne. To my
                            mind the signs of the times indicate just this, and although some seem to see only darkness
                            and a withdrawal of the spirit of God or goodness from the face of the earth, I can see
                            beyond the clouds of error aud a seeming disregard for everything of a spiritual or
                            religious nature, the" silver lining," and hope and trust spring up within me, and I can
                            afford to "Learn to labor and to wait." Oh! the beautiful gospel of Christ and Mother, which
                            says" Come unto me all ye who are heavy laden and I will give you rest." Oh! how often I
                            have exclaimed within myself, "would to God that there were more, that had even perhaps as
                            faint a glimpse as I have of what that rest is." It is indeed, a gift of God. I glory in the
                            fact that I am able to live a Shaker life, that I have had a privilege to confess, and in as
                            great a degree have been able to forsake my former sins. To battle with old nature in all
                            its forms; to deny ourselves daily, striving ever to attain a measure of those christian
                            graces which so adorn and beautify the soul, is an honorable work, and pne that I am
                            thankful [ was led into, while sojourning in this earthly tabernacle. The thought that I am,
                            even in my small capacity, helping on the cause of-Christ whose spirit I always loved, and
                            reverenced}, is ample reward fer every sacrifice. About fifteen years ago, (I being in my
                            thirtieth year), it was my good fortune to come, out of mere curiosity I then thought, to
                            visit the Shakers at Enfield; not having any previous knowledge of their peculiar views, I
                            was not at all prejudiced. On entering the village, I experienced feelings that could not be
                            described, and after a short' tarry, became convinced that I had been guided wiser than I
                            knew, and I saw plainly what my duty was, and from that time have endeavored to square my
                            life by this precious gaspe: testimony. Hoping this little sketch of my experience may
                            induce some weary soul to investigate our principles, I have thus written, for I believe
                            there are many who would gladly avail themselves of the privilege to live in an atmosphere
                            of greater purity than the ouside world affords them. To all such I would gladly extend the
                            invitation, " Come and see." Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talks</head><p TEIform="p">There is a loud call for a new edition of OUR little pamphlet-" PLAIN TALKS I" and just as
                            soon as we can get sufficient encouragement from Novitiate Elders, we will issue a large
                            edition. Elder H. L. Eades, South Union , Ky., says of this little work: "In my judgement it
                            is the best work to send to enquirers that we have yet published. It ought to be reprinted.
                            Abundance of the should be kept in every Society-they would save their cost in writing,
                            etc." They will be issued, similar to first edition, and form one of the neatest pieces of
                            printed work ever issued. The names af all Novitiate Elders and Eldresses will be printed on
                            a page of the work, who render us any aid in the new edition, They will be sent to any
                            address, at cost, to all ordering twenty-five copies or more, four and one-half cents each:
                            or six cents per single copJ'.c Will be issued in February. Send orders, great or small \Ve
                            would also recommend to any desirous of reading short. but brilliant pamphlets u!;on
                            Shaker-ism. to send to Elders Daniel Fraser, nud joh n Whiteley, of Shirley Village, Ms.ifor
                            "The Shaker's Answer," and" Divine Afflatus I" the first at $3.0::&gt; per hundred, the latter
                            $05.0). Who will send for and circulate a few hundreds? "God is mindful of our zeal."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How admirable and beautiful is the simplicity of the Evangelists..." TEIform="index"/>How admirable and beautiful is the simplicity of the Evangelists...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> How ADMIRABLE and beautiful is the simplicity of the Evangelists! They never speak
                            injuriously of the enemies of Jesus Christ, of his judges, nor of his executioners. They
                            report the facts without a single reflection. They comment neither of their Master's
                            mildness, when he was smitten,' nor of his constancy in the hour of his ignominious death,
                            which they thus describe: "And they crucified Jesus,"-</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Racine" TEIform="persName"/>Racine</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">Writers for THE SHAKER are requested to write on but one side of their paper. </p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>