<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1501" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">15</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18850101" TEIform="date">January 1885</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="15" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>JANUARY. THE MANIFESTO. Published by the United Societies. SHIRLEY, MASS. 'Blessed are those that hear the word of
                        God and keep it." SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. 1885. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="article">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Information for inquirers"/>INFORMATION FOR INQUIRERS</head>
                        <p>For the better understanding of those who wish to know of the rules and regulations of our religious home, we
                            have prepared the following brief summary. Further information may be obtained by addressing any member of the
                            order. 1. The form of government in the Society is adapted to the different orders of which it is composed : its
                            powers and authorities growing out of the mutual faith, love and confidence of the members. 2. No one is
                            excluded from the privilege of becoming a member on account of poverty ; nor will they be accepted because of
                            wealth. 3. Plain and explicit facts will be laid before the investigator. To become a member, is a voluntary
                            concession of the individual. 4. Those who accept the privilege to reside with us, as well as those who visit
                            the Society as inquirers, are expected to regard the rules of the family where they are entertained. 5. By the
                            principles of this Society, no believing husband or wife is allowed to separate from an unbelieving partner,
                            except by mutual or legal agreement. 6. Parents that become members are not required to give up their children :
                            but they will be requested to see that the children keep the rules of the family. Minors are never taken under
                            the immediate charge of the Society, except by the request or consent of those who have the lawful right over
                            them. 7. No corporal punishment is approved in the government of the Society, nor any external violence
                            exercised on any rational person. 8. It is expected that the .'•hildren admitted into the Society, will receive
                            an education suitable for the general management of business. 9. Probationary members may retain the lawful
                            ownership of their property, but the interest accruing therefrom will be devoted to the benefit of the Society,
                            until by their own free will, and the consent of the Trustees, they shall consecrate said property to the
                            support of the family where they reside. 10. The Society will not be responsible for debts contracted by
                            persons, previous to the time of their membership. 11. Those who dispose of their property to relations in the
                            worldly order, should remain with those relations. 12. A person wishing to become, a member of the Society, must
                            rectify all his wrongs, and discharge all just and legal claims. 13. Those who ask for admission to our Home are
                            supposed to be in seai*ch of more truth and light, hence, an important principle in the Shaker Church, is the
                            confession of sin to God, in the presence of a witness. * 14. Those who have dedicated their property, and
                            afterward withdraw from the Society,—according to the law of justice amVequity, there can be no ground for
                            retraction. 15. To live as Brethren and Sisters in the gospel of Christ, we can hold no private correspondence.
                            All communications sent from or received into the family, whether printed or written, will be subject to the
                            examination and advice of the Elders of the family. 16. The leading authority of the Society is vested in a
                            Ministry, consisting of two Brothers and two Sisters. Elder.s and Trustees are also appointed. These orders
                            constitute the general government, of the Society, in all of its branches.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb id="p4"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>--><pb n="1" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                   <div2 type="none">
                        <p>CONTENTS. Education, Wisdom from Above, Consistency, Silent Prayer, Religious, Scatter the Germs etc., View of
                            Alfred, Me. Alfred, Me. A Vision, God is Love, The Gospel, Intercession, Issachar Bates,' Page. 1 4 8 9 11 12 13
                            14 Three Travelers, Laws, Love for All, Letter Box, Word to Children, Notes, With Care, Guides Through Life,
                            Kind Words, Deaths, Music ;—Consolation* , Books & Papers, Clarion Call, Page. 16 17 18 19 22 23 24 Vol.
                            XV. JANUARY, 1885. No. 1.</p>
                    </div2>--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Education, physical, mental, spiritual" TEIform="index"/>Education, Physical, Mental,
                            Spiritual</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">Education, is a word, that, by a certain class of minds, appears to be understood as
                            applying, almost exclusively to the training of the mind in literary, scientific, or
                            philosophic pursuits, while, in its proper sense, it justly implies the culture of the
                            entire manhood, and, in its most fitting capacity,'has reference to informing and training
                            the physical man in such a manner as to insure health of body; the mental so as to give a
                            knowledge of the laws of life, not only those pertaining to the phys'ical organization, but
                            those giving mental capacity so to live as to secure soid welfare also ; the spiritual so as
                            to bring man into a near and true relation to, his Creator, and thus enable him to live in a
                            pure, peaceful, and consequently happy relation to his fellow man. Angesilaus—King of
                            Sparta, beingasked what things he thought most proper for boys to learn, replied " Those
                            they ought to practice when they come to be men. " One of the direst evils of life is
                            misplacing, misusing, and thus abusing, God's best gifts to man,—thus, happiness is often
                            sought by the attainment of sensual pleasure as the highest object ; success and prosperity,
                            by the education of the mind alone, while the soul is left uncultivated, whereby the mental
                            and physical man is left to roam in passions' vagarious fields, untutored, unclothed with
                            protection from the defilements of sin against God's laws for human weal ! The soul's
                            tenement not realizing that, " What nothingearthly Rives, or can destroy, The soul's calm
                            sunshine, and the heartfelt joy, Is virtue's prize. "<pb n="2" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. "
                            Moral and religious instruction derives its efficacy, not so much from what men are taught
                            to know, as from what they are brought to feel! " And, this feeling is the result of soul
                            culture, rather than mental knowledge ! " There is a spirit in man, and the inspirations of
                            the Almighty giveth him understanding, " while, " Minds, though sprung from heavenly race,
                            Must first be tutored for the place. The joys above, are understood, And relished, only by
                            the good. (given,) Souls are my charge, "(sayeth religion)" to me ' tis To lit them for
                            their native heaven. " "But, wisdom and knowledge, so far from being one, are, oft-times,
                            found to have no connection. " Life, to amplify, dignify, perfect and happify must be
                            accomplished by the discipline of the entire physical, mental and spiritual man, according
                            to the laws of God in his constitutional being. To disregard the physical, allowing it to
                            grovel in filth and rags, to languish for the want of proper nourishment, to surfeit it with
                            needless bounties, or whimsical luxuries, is to disease the body, degrade the mind, and
                            imbrute the soul. Professor Moore truly said, "Dirt is no sooner needlessly left upon the
                            skin than it begins to travel soulward. " " Our physical senses are constituted for this
                            world, and,"[if true to God's laws,]" we enjoy it." But "Our undeveloped spirits are
                            constituted for another world, and we shall enter it. " Therefore, as we consist of body,
                            soul, and spirit, our education, to be consistent with our proper development, and well
                            being in its wholeness of constitu- tion and capacity, must have a constant care for the
                            spiritual culture also ; for, the motive force of man, is his inspiring spirit, this is the
                            engine that directs the mind that moves the body. Spirit is the oar that moves the human
                            will. Divine Wisdom has created the mind of man of too expansive a nature to be limited by
                            the attractions of earth, even though garnished with all the culture that a mere mental, or
                            material education can bestow upon it, for " it acknowledges no enduring relation Avith
                            things " or conditions "that perish. " There is something more wanted for the complete
                            formation of human character than knowledge ; it is strength and beauty that is born of
                            conforming the spirit to the will of God to man mademanifest ; for, though he grope through
                            the howling wildernesses of Africa, prowl through the vast prairies of America, ensconce
                            himself in the vast cities of the earth, cloister himself as a monk, closet himself in the
                            libraries of Alexandria, now no more, or the modern haunts of literary science and art,
                            still he is not content, not quiet nor satisfied without Divine aid ! And "The time is
                            rapidly approaching, when the highest honor is to be bestowed upon those who possess the
                            moral and spiritual attributes which lift man into true kinship with his Maker. Then, the
                            intellect alone will not be held as of transcendant importance, but, will be made
                            subordinate to an exrJted grandeur of character which recoguizes intellectual qualities as
                            only instruments, or powers to be used for promoting man's highest good. " Some minds are
                            prophetic ; and, Henry Ward Beecher, at a recent lecture, remarked, " I believe there will
                            succeed to these disseminations of the truth of natural science, an era of moral science "
                            and, we will add, an era of soul culture by spiritual education. " The signs of the times
                            indicate this coming era. " But, " the education of the mind alone 2 <pb n="3" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. develops skepticism " while spirituality is left imprisoned in darkness, and
                            poverty ! Man needs the education of the soul to develop spiritual perception,—
                            consciousness of his relation to kindred spirits, and to his Maker. The man who so lives
                            that his character is molded in purity, peacefulness, goodness, and that unselfish love and
                            charity which enables him to sacrifice his life's labors for the elevation and ble-sing of
                            the human family as did Jesus Christ, has raised a monument to his memory contributing to
                            his blessing, happiness and honor, as much loftier in its ideal, as much grander in its
                            designs, an:! magnificent in its structure than the pyramids of Egypt as heaven is higher
                            than the earth ; and one that will be found sound and perfect, with increasing beauty and
                            glory, in an infinitude of ages, 1 after the pyramids of Egypt shall have crumbled into
                            dust, and their glory and memory departed forever ! Then it will be understood that the
                            purest and loftiest ideals of Divinity are not objects of sense, not even the pyramids of
                            Egypt, nor the ancient cities of renown ; not any namable thing material; but, those ever
                            living glorified spirits, who, possessed of heavenly angelic graces, symbolize the
                            characteristics of Divine Wisdom and Love. Man, left to the simple field of his own narrow
                            human sphere, bereft of Divine ministrations and guidance is, comparatively speaking,
                            powerless, and unfruitful of progress and development as the seed of a plant cast into the
                            earth, bereft of moisture and sunshine ; he is, in its proper sense, as really dependent on
                            that God who gave him being, as the lily upon the stalk upon Avhich it is borne ! God never
                            made an independent man ; and all the possible education and culture of his mind in science,
                            art, literature or philosophy, can never enthrone him as a being independent; not even
                            independent of his fellow man ; for " we were not made for ourselves only, " much less may
                            he ever be independent of his Creator ! To anticipate a condition of independence, gained as
                            the fruit of education, is as futile as to anticipate " frozen music ! " And, however
                            humiliating this may be to the pride and ambition of man. from its ordeal there is no
                            escape. "The greatest things, the most vital, " (pertaining to life,) " do not lie within
                            the scope of our powers '* '• There are hourc when the whole worlu% and all it contains,
                            shrivels to nothingness, in our estimation, and God alone fills the mind. " But, God has
                            committed to the "Son of Man" the revelation of that plan, conceived in wisdom, by which the
                            human family can find a pure, true, and genial relation to the Divine Author of his being ;
                            He has made him the recipient and Mediator of that Word of Life, and Law of Love, that forms
                            a tribunal by which man will be judged ; thus, " man is judged by man" (in the exercise of
                            his Divine Commission,) "'•nothing else were fit." "Know ye not" (ye disciples of Christ,)
                            "that ye shall judge angels'3* but, not as natural men ; but, in the exercise of that light
                            of grace of Go«I committed to those who had become heirs of salvation. This capacity for
                            judgment Avas not attained by mental culture alone, but, by having conformed the spirit to
                            the pattern of that Word which reveals the Law of God for man's salvation, redemption, and
                            endless progress into the fullness o-f God's grace3 <pb n="4" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. love,
                            and truth. " And, this is not an arbitrary arrangement for the future" (nor for the
                            judgment.) '• dissociated from the laws of our nature, but, it is their inevitable
                            outworking." And, though it has been said " man- kind are becoming independent in thought
                            and judgment, and are assuming the prerogative to decide for themselves, in matters
                            pertaining to their present and future welfare, and dictation is distasteful. " Yet, this is
                            an assumed position from which they will have to descend, and be taught in the School of
                            Christ, or never become the Children of God, and heirs of the kingdom He has promised to
                            them that love Him. For God has planned the way, and lie hath said, "My ways are not as your
                            ways, nor my thoughts as your thoughts. " '"But. as the heavens are higher than the earth,
                            so are my ways than your ways, and my thoughts than your thoughts. " This, indeed, is a
                            position that the pride and vain conceit of the worldly and sensual man revolts against, but
                            when, if ever, he is purified by the workings of that law. which, in its ministrations,
                            makes man the compeer of angels, of heaven, he will feel it a Shekinah for the mercy seat of
                            Goal's love ! Thus, by parity of reason, by the human experience of the ages, by the light
                            of science, by the revelation of godliness, we are taught to know, that, a true and proper
                            education is one that curbs and subdues the pride and assumed ostentation of man, and, by
                            revealing to him his own weakness, and the immense narrowness of his limited sphere of
                            knowledge, however high in the temple of human fame he may have climbed, it takes out of him
                            his vain self-conceit, and causes him to feel the needful guidance of his heavenly
                            parentage. The illustrious Newton, when he had discovered some of the most momentous laws
                            that pertain to human knowledge, said he felt like a child, playing on the beach of the
                            great ocean of truth, amusing himself with a pebble, or a shell he had found, which the
                            great ocean ot truth was rolling before him in all its majesty and splendor, uuattained.
                            Thus does true culture, which leads man to discover his wonderful dependence on superior
                            wisdom, operate to work humility, instead of pride and independence, and, as illustrated by
                            the educated poet he will sing, " Had I all knowledge, human and Divine, That thought can
                            reach, or science can define. And, had I povv'r to give that knowledge birth, In all the
                            speeches of the babbling earth; Did Shadraeh's zeal my glowing breast inspire To weary
                            tortures, and rejoice in tire, Or, had I faith like that which Israel saw. When Moses gave
                            them miracles and law, Yet, gracious charity,---indulgent guest, Were not thy pow'r exerted
                            in my breast. Those speeches would send up unheeded prayer, That scorn of life would be but
                            wild despair. A cymbal's sound were better than my voice, My faith were form, my eloquence
                            were noise. * * * Thus, in obedience to what heaven decrees, Knowledge shall fail, and
                            prophecy shall cease, But lasting charities more ample sway, Nor bound by time, nor subject
                            to decay, In happy triumph shall forever live, And endless good diffuse, and endless praise
                            receive. * * * So, whilst our minds in knowledge would improve Its feeble eye bent on things
                            above, High as we may, we lift our reason up, By faith directed, and confirmed by hope, Yet
                            are we able only to survey Dawnings of beams, and promises of day ; Ileav'n's tidier
                            effulgence mocks our dazzled sight. Too great its swiftness, and too strong its flight. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wisdom from above is first pure" TEIform="index"/>"The Wisdom from Above is First Pure"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM LEONARD</byline><p TEIform="p">It should be remembered that the Apostle who made this singular expression was born a -few,
                            and grew up under the wines of the Priesthood. What 4 <pb n="5" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO.
                            they called wisdom, we now call knowledge, as "God gave Solomon wisdom," or as he says : "I
                            gave my heart to know wisdom. " Again, " The wisdom of the wise shall perish." Besides, the
                            Rabbins spake of worldly wisdom, the u wisdom from beneath. " Here we see the Apostle
                            borrowed tin's and many other forms of expression from their former priesthood. When the
                            priests spake of the •' wisdom from above, " it conveyed to their hearers the idea of their
                            peculiar inspiration from the Almighty ; or the teaching conveyed to their fathers by
                            angels. What Enoch, Abraham. Moses or tlie prophets communicated to the fathers by
                            revelation, they handed down as the " wisdom from above." When Jesus came as tlie great
                            teacher of the Christian system, with higher inspiration, .lames still called his whole
                            revelation, "The Wisdom from Above." Me knew his Lord from the beginning, learned the
                            Christian faith from his lips, knew that Jesus lived out this faith, and taught his
                            followers to do the same; and by its effects, he knew that such teaching came down from
                            Heaven to men. With this knowledge, when he spoke of the Christian faith, he declared it to
                            be first of all pure. The whole text is a beautiful compound of tlie Christian faith, and
                            James says that this is first of all pure, that Jesus by the virgin life he lived, came
                            squarely up to it and into it, and that every true disciple must take his life for the
                            pattern and carry it through just as he did. As the blood circulates through from the
                            arteries to the minutest vessels in the physical system ; as a course of literary studies
                            civilizes and enlarges all the intellectual powers ; as morality controls aud checks all the
                            passions of the natural man, just so the effect of the virgin life must run through, cleanse
                            and purify the never dying spirit of a Christian. The spirit of man i-s in strong league of
                            brotherhood with the flesh which is fallen and depraved. This pure life must be studied, and
                            lived out, till it beautifully effects a separation between the flesh and spirit, and the
                            spirit was to be under the revelation of God, who would give a law to rule the animal
                            passions aright. Since man fell, the spirit lias been under the dictation of the flesh, and
                            the ilesh lias been controlled by tlie powers of darkness, aud his whole being has gone
                            wrong, spiritually. Man's animal nature deserved, and received from Paul, the degraded name,
                            a "carnal mind. " Then what business has the spirit of a Christian to be brought under this
                            carnal 'influence? which the Apostle says, " Is not subject to the law of God, neither
                            iudeed can be. " How is it possible for the spirit to follow Christ, fettered in such
                            terrible chains of bondage? Or how is it possible for it to Kud salvation from sin, placed
                            in a condition that it must necessarily live in sin continually? Just as long as (he spirit
                            is held in such servitude to low ami lawless passions, it is as far from being subject tothe
                            true Christian faith, as any depraved being who never heard of a Savior. Why is it, that for
                            all the sins committed in the body, the condemnation falls invariably on the spirit? Is it
                            not because the spirit panders to man's sen5 <pb n="6" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. suality,
                            seeks objects to minister to his indulgence, contrives his gratifications, takes t!-,e lead
                            in carrying them out, and then comes in for the lion's share in the •excitement ? Under
                            these considerations, we are not surprised that the Apostle lays down purity as the first
                            Christian principle. Uere the enemy has most effectually despoiled the noblest work of God,
                            and here he must first be attacked aud routed. If there is no virgin purity, there is no
                            separation ; if no separation, no rising up into tjie resurrection of a higher and holier
                            life ; if no rising into a higher life, no standing with the Lamb on Mount Zion, pure,
                            spotless and undented. I have said that all condemnation comes in consequence of the sins
                            committed ia the body or flesh ; but when the spirit declares its independence from the
                            flesh, and crucifies it "with all its tvffectsons and lusts, " it will find what Paul said
                            to be strictly true. "There is no condemnation to them that are in Christ Jesus, who walk
                            not after the flesh but after the spirit. " I suppose that all professois will agree, that
                            the life of Jesus is the pattern for .all to follow. John said, "I saw the dead, small and
                            great, stand before God, and the books were opened, and another book was opened, which is
                            the '-Book of Life ; " and the dead were judged out of those things which were wTritten in
                            the books according to their works." Mnu stands as a monument of the highest mechanical
                            skill of the Almighty, on this earth. In that piece of living machinery he has placed a
                            recording instrument, like a gasometer. Gas may be consumed in millions of places, but this
                            instrument will record the number of feet consumed, to the minutest fraction in each place.
                            No matter how long before the examination, there stands the record with no variation. It is
                            so with man's conscience, an unseen hand pens in that book all the actions of each son and
                            daughter of Adam. They may sink deep in the sins of the flesh, and become steeped in crime,
                            but the unseen hand makes its unerring marks as accurately as the gas table. No matter how
                            sleepy, careless or forgetful the sinner may be, the hand that penned the record can shake
                            him from his slumbers and revive his recollection, in the judgment here or hereafter. The
                            deeds done in the body are not left to chance. This book and its contents are part of
                            themselves, and will go with them through earth and helL When called into the judgment we
                            must stand before the tribunal, and each read his own book before the saints, who are to
                            judge the world ! However dark we may be now, we shall know then just how far they have gone
                            astray. Jesus too had a conscience, and in that book was written all the actions of his
                            life. On earth he walked so obediently to the will of God, that his Father's hand penned
                            that life carefully upon his conscience that it may be presented as the Book of Life, by
                            which all are compared who are called into judgment. The life that Jesus commenced and
                            carried through, is called "eternal life," or a life needing no amendment, and it will
                            therefore stand eternally. It will be a terrible reckoning when these books are read and
                            compared with the more perfect ledger. Whatever tiny may think of it, men will have to trace
                            their daily accounts, € <pb n="7" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. comparing all things therein
                            with this more perfect ledger. And who can es- timate the pains, the groans, settlements,
                            confessions, penitence and tears it will take to wash away the stains, and make each like
                            the pages of the '' Lamb's book of life," and this must be done before men can stand upright
                            in the judgment. We think that this teaching corresponds with the teaching and example of
                            Jesus. Men who have no light to see the beauty and glory of cutting the spirit loose from
                            the bonds of the flesh, with such we have no controversy ! If you wish to follow the example
                            of the first Adam, and maintain morally the family relations of earth, this renders you the
                            highest class of worldly citizens, and as such we respect you. But the real Christians, as
                            we profess to be, are traveling in the higher and more excellent way. We are striving to
                            come up to the example set by Jesus, standing justified and gaining the victory, on the
                            higher plane above, while all that follow Adam stand on the earth plane beneath ! Under this
                            cross, we are raised to newness of life, and into the liberty of the sons and daughters of
                            God. We do not euforce these views, but present them kindly, saying as Jesus did ; " He that
                            is able to receive them, let him receive them. " Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consistency" TEIform="index"/>CONSISTENCY</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">What seers, what Saviors and what Gods, T'is needful we should be ! And yet we are but merest
                            worms To act in such degree. God grant humility of heart, Best armor of defence, That better
                            we may act our part Removed from arrogance. Our motives must decide our case In part, but
                            not the whole ;— Unless we've studied for our race Creation of each soul— We'll say no more,
                            but think anew On this consistent plan, While least and most that we can do, Is, " do the
                            best we can. " Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Silent Prayer" TEIform="index"/>SILENT PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">In prayer we speak to God, but there is also the silence of prayer. Our lips utter no sound,
                            we cannot find words to express the language of the heart, but the soul still prays. Perhaps
                            we are too weary in body or in mind, perhaps the brain may be too utterly exhaust- ed to
                            frame the petitions we would ask. Still we desire to hold communion with Him who bids us
                            come to Him when we are tired. " Come unto me, all ye that labor and are heavy laden, and I
                            will give you rest. " Then comes the experience and the sweetness of the silence of prayer.
                            What is it? 1. It is just kneeling down in our accustomed place, and lifting up our hearts
                            to Him in wordless petition which speaks only in the well of longing deep down in our souls.
                            2. It is letting God speak to us in our silence and listening to His voice. There are many
                            things He will say to us if we will only hear them—deep, sweet, holy things—comforting
                            things, and things that will draw us away from the world to follow Him more closely. 3. It
                            is a time of great nearness to Jesus. Is he not close by? Having felt the weakness of our
                            nature, he draws near in full sympathy with our weariness. 4. It is a time of strengthening.
                            Our " strength is " sometimes " to sit still. " No less do we receive strength from God when
                            we are drinking in silence from Him who chooses sometimes Himself to be "silent in love." So
                            may we arise from the silence of prayer invigorated and strengthened. —New York
                        Observer.</p></div2><pb n="8" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious revivals" TEIform="index"/>RELIGIOUS REVIVALS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">In this 1871) Centennial year, Religious Revivals seem to be the rule. Are they of use? To
                            answer the question nnderstandingly, let us take a look at man, as we find him-— and when we
                            say man, we include both moieties. Man, in all deference to Holy Writ, man takes his
                            initiative low down in the scale of being, but one, or two grades above some other forms of
                            life. But inasmuch as this little Universe is being constructed on the progressive idea, we
                            reasonably expect man to go higher. We will give him the motto of the Empire State, for his
                            motto. To man, on his lowest plane, we magnanimously concede the germ of Divinity: and from
                            stubborn facts, before this Honorable Court, we are compelled to admit, that in some types
                            of the race homo, that germ has taken no growth. We have no evidence that it lias even
                            sprouted. The use, benefit and behoof of religious revivals, is to stir the enshrining soil,
                            that the vitalizing elements may percolate, causing the germ to germinate. Some have
                            mistaken Revival for Salvation. A grave mistake. In most eases, Revival leaves its subject,
                            in his, or her own eyes, more a sinner than before. This is so much gained. Though he may
                            delight in the law of God, after the inner man, and though he find a law in his members,
                            warring against the law of his mind, and bringing him into captivity to the law of sin in
                            his members, if there be integrity in that soul, there will be perpetrated no such
                            stultifying compromise as serving God with the mind, and sin with the flesh.— The honest,
                            self respecting soul will ejaculate with the immortal Henry—Give me Liberty, or give me
                            death ! With power will the soul utter it, keep uttering it, till it reach the Eternal
                            Throne. When the soul's integrity is fully tested, a voice, a still small voice will be
                            heard, saying, " This is the way, walk ye in it. " And now comes the tug of war: a splendid
                            test of manhood and womanhood. Incarnated on the banks of theRichileu, in the Religious
                            Tornado of the last century, your not very humble servant may be regarded as the
                            personification of the Religious Revival element. And now, after long and varied experience,
                            the conclusion arrived at :s, that no soulawakening revival is without effect fir good.
                            Though it may not enable the soul, thus awakened, to grasp the power of full salvation, in
                            the present time, that soul will never lapse to its former inertia. Xor is that the limit.
                            For the iniquities of the fathers are no more visited upon the children, to the third and
                            fourth generation, than are the soul Teachings out for a higher plane of life. Commensurate
                            with the varied states and conditions of the diverse tj-pes of our common humanity, must be
                            the instrumentalities and appliances to help souls up the ascending grade. Let us leave
                            their selection to the Committee, of Ways and Means. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scatter the germs of the beautiful" TEIform="index"/>SCATTER THE GERMS OF THE BEAUTIFUL</head><p TEIform="p">Scattek the germs of the beautiful! By the way-side let them fall, That the rose may spring
                            by the cottage gate, And the vine on the garden wall. Cover the rough and the rude of earth.
                            With a veil of leaves and flow'rs, And mark with the opening bud and cup, The march of
                            Summer hours. Scatter the germs of the beautiful! In the holy shrine of home, Let the pure
                            and fair, and the graceful there. In the loveliest luster come. Leave not a trace of
                            deformity In the temple of the heart, But gather about its altar the gems Of nature and of
                            art. Scatter the germs of the beautiful! In the depths of the human soul, They shall bud and
                            blossom, and bear the fruit While the endiess ages roll. Plant with the flowers of charity,
                            The portals of the tomb, And the fair and the pure about thy path, In the paradise shall
                            bloom.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kellogg, Amos M." TEIform="persName"/>Amos M. Kellogg</byline></div2><pb n="9" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="figure" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Village, Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER VILLAGE, Alfred. Maine.</head><p TEIform="p">[Figure]</p></div2><pb n="10" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/><pb n="11" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine, no. 1: origin of the shakers in Maine" TEIform="index"/>ALFRED, ME., No. 1.
                            Origin of the Shakers in Maine. New Light Baptists, called Merry Dancers Come-outers, etc.</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>ELDER OTIS SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p">John Cotton, son of John Cotton whose name is mentioned in the history of the town of
                            Gorhain, in connection with his brother William, was born in Portland, Me., Feb. 16, 17G0.*
                            John Cotton was the first person in the State of Maine, that received faith in the Second
                            Manifestation of Christ, and set out to be one of the disciples of Mother Ann Lee. He moved
                            into Alfred about the year 1781. Was married to Eleanor Coffin, the daughter of Simeon
                            Coffin, f At the time John moved into the town there was a great religious awakening which
                            prevailed quite extensively in the western part of the State, and also in New Hampshire,
                            Vermont and Massachusetts. This served to draw those who were the subjects of the revival,
                            from the set forms and creeds of the old established churches, and from all their
                            superstitions and bigotry, believing that an important era was abov.t to dawn upon the
                            country. Some of the subjects in their inspired moments predicted the millennial day was
                            about to usher in, and many in their great zeal would often bear testimony against the
                            deathlike, creedal forms and superstitions of the ¦churches. They had no established leader
                            at this time, ¦who resided in this section of the country, but were sometimes visited by
                            Benjamin Randall of New Durham, N. H. and Father Tingley, as he was called, both ministers
                            and leaders in the Free-will Baptist order, but these enthusiastic religionists would meet
                            together for worship, when each one was free to speak or sing as the spirit gave utterance.
                            At times they were impressed by the spirit to manifest the power of God, which was very
                            great among them. They found it im* Cotton Street was mimed in honor of the ancestors of
                            this family. t Simeon Coflin is reported to be the first settler of the town, lie took up
                            his residence in an Indian wigwam that stood near the present site of the house of worship
                            at Shaker Village. The place was then called Massabesic or Sanford north Parish. possible to
                            remain quiet, and in the spirit of that new light which tney had received and the freedom
                            they felt in being extricated from the shackles and bondage of anti-christian bigotry, they
                            would express their joy in songs and dances. This exercise became so frequent among them
                            that the unbelievingcalled them Merry Dancers, New Lights, Come-outers, etc., but they
                            preferied to be called New Light Baptists, by which name they were known wherever they had
                            an existence. John Cotton was a zealous member of this New Light order. At this date, 1781,
                            there was quite an emigration to Vermont, which was then called the New State. John with
                            others concluded to purchase a farm in Vermont, and in May 1793 in company with Daniel
                            Coffin, started on foot, with knapsacks fastened to their backs, to find a new home in the
                            state of Vermont. They passed through the town of Canterbury, N. H. and visited some of the
                            New Light brethren who lived in that place. On arriving at Enfield, N. H. John again found
                            himself among another company of his New Light brethren, over whom had come a great change.
                            Fortunately, John found hospitable entertainment with James Jewett, a well to do farmer, and
                            was made a welcome guest. He soon learned what had made the great and improved change. James
                            was a zealous believer in the testimony of Jesus Christ, and had accepted the faith as
                            preached by the ministers sent out from the Society at New Lebanon. He soon informed John of
                            this fact, and told him that to profess to be a Christian, and to be one practically, were
                            very different things. "Christians," said he, "could not marry; they must live as Jesus
                            lived, a pure, virgin life. Christians could not fight for Jesus was the Prince of Peace.
                            The New Testament teaches that he who takes the sword shall perish by the sword. My Kingdom,
                            said Jesus is not of this world, hence my subjects cannot fight. If you would receive the
                            power of God unto salvation, you must confess your sins, for sin and the nature of it
                            separates souls from God. In Christ's Kingdom there can be no rich nor poor, no high, no low
                            ; all are equal brethren and sis<pb n="12" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 12 THE MANIFESTO. ters in Christ. This
                            revival of true Christianity was brought to light through Mother Ann Lee. As Jesus
                            represented the Father in Deity, so Ann Lee was made perfect through suffering to reveal the
                            Motherhood of God." John soon became convinced of the truth of this testimony, and accepting
                            James as a minister of the word of God, lie honestly confessed his sins and brought all his
                            evil deeds to the light. This occurred on the 26th day of May 1798. John now learned that
                            the light and conviction which he had received was a prepa-fatory work for something
                            greater, and after he had confessed his sins, and was released from that burden, the power
                            of God filled his soul. Tie was now convinced, beyond a doubt, that Christ had appeared the
                            second time without sin unto full and free salvation. One morning after breakfast, lie
                            entered into conversation with James, and to use his own language, he says, "The power of
                            God came upon me, rilling my soul and controlling my whole being. It raised me from my chair
                            and under its influence I turned around, swiftly, for the space of half an hour. The door of
                            the house was open. I was whirled through the door-way into the yard among the stones and
                            stumps, down to the shore of the Mascoma Lake, some rods distant. On reaching the shore of
                            the lake that same power that led me to the water whirled me back again in like manner, and
                            I found myself in the same chair that I had been takcn from. This was a seal to my faith and
                            a baptism of the Holy Spirit, and I promised to obey it to the end of my days. " This vow
                            John was faithful to keep. A few days before his death he was heard to re- mark, that he had
                            lived a clean, pure life since the day he confessed his sins. This sudden conversion changed
                            his mind and he returned to Alfred and then to Gorhain to tell his brethren and his friends
                            of the wonderful things of God which he had found. While traveling toward home, he said his
                            soul was filled with the spirit of God, so that he hardly realized that his feet touched the
                            ground. He arrived at Alfred at midnight, and called at the house of one of his old friends,
                            John Barnes. He says, "I rapped for admittance and shouted witli all my might. " John and
                            his wife Sarah were soon at the window, and very much frightened at the unusual noise in the
                            night. The fright over the traveler was invited into the house and immediately asked, " What
                            sent you back so soon." "I came back," said John, "to bring you good news of great joy.. (To
                            BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision" TEIform="index"/>A VISION</head><p TEIform="p">In the fall of 1821, Ralph Resell, of Warrensville, Cuyahoga County, Ohio visited Union
                            ATillage, Warren County, in the south part of the State, and united with the Society called
                            Shakers, and returned home, expecting to move his family in the Spring. As an evidence of
                            liis faith in Shaketism, he related the following Vision. " I saw," said he ki a strong,
                            clear, ray ot light.proceeding from Union Village, in a perfectly straight, horizontal line
                            until it reached a spot near my log cabin, (and that spot is the very place where the Centre
                            House, or Church Family now stands.) And then it arose in a strong erect column, and became
                            a beautiful Tree."</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>James S. Prescott</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God is love" TEIform="index"/>"GOD IS LOVE."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Tatterton, Matilda J." TEIform="persName"/>MATILDA J. TATTERTON</byline><p TEIform="p">It is written tGod is Love," and the more we love, the mure must we resemble Him who is the
                            great Fountain oi love and excellence. Then let each one who bears the Christian name, add
                            drop to drop until the clear waters spread wide over all the earth. Let us nourish the
                            sentiment of love in the hearts of others by the manifestation of our own kindly <pb n="13" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 13 thoughts in charitable deeds ; and forget not the love we
                            owe "Him who first loved us." if there is beauty in one part of the Bible more than in
                            another, it is expressed in that sentiment. Let us take it home for our consideration,
                            reflect upon it; and if we can rise from our meditation with other than an interested love
                            for auy of the children of God, our heart is indeed shrouded in darkness. Inasmuch as He who
                            created us in His own image, created also our brother, should we not extend our love to him.
                            Is revenge our .object? Will it spread sunshine on the downward path of life, or smooth the
                            dying pillow? Ah nay, it will embitter the hours of reflection, and when the soul reaches
                            out for support, our hearts will yearn for that love which in its hour of prosperity we
                            denied to others ; but if we have cherished those sentiments which have their origin in
                            Heaven ; if we have loved not only our friends, but those who have done us wrong, we can
                            meet more confidently those whom we may have wronged, but whose forgiveness we implore. As
                            we desire charity and love we must extend the same to others ; in this way can we become
                            Sons and Daughters -of our God. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel" TEIform="index"/>THE GOSPEL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Marion" TEIform="persName"/>MARlON JOHNSON</byline><p TEIform="p">O where is the power that can lighten, The heart that is burdened with woe? O where i,s the
                            love that will hrighten. The journey ot life here below? For hearts over-laden with anguish,
                            Is no healing bahn to be found? When in desolate places they languish. In sorrow and
                            heaviness bound? The soul that aspires to be holy To rise above bondage and sin To walk in
                            the narrow path lowly, All hallowed without and within. O where is the aid that it needeth,
                            To throw off the fetters that bind? Whose is the strong hand that leadeth, T*he way of
                            salvation to find? The Gospel. Ah,— that giveth power, The soul's deepest cravings to meet
                            It sheds o'er the dreariest hour, A balsam that's healing and sweet. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Intercession" TEIform="index"/>INTERCESSION</head><p TEIform="p">Kind Guardian Spirits guide my pen AVhile I a line do write, I'll say within my heart amen To
                            what they do indite. 0 ! could I soar to regions bright And view that peaceful shore, Where
                            angels dwell in sweet delight And live forevermore. 1 feel I soon shall pass away From
                            mundane scenes belowr, Do me receive, where love's sweet ray Will guide me as I go. But
                            patiently I'll wait the time WThen my kind Parents call, And say, " not my own will but
                            thine" To them resign my all.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Shepard, Arabella" TEIform="persName"/>Arabella Shepard. Aged 85 years. North Union,
                        Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When the seed of faith becomes rooted in an honest understanding heart..." TEIform="index"/>
                            When the seed of faith becomes rooted in an honest understanding heart...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">When the seed of faith becomes rooted in an honest understanding heart, its effects will flow
                            from thence into the outward conduct, and produce those conditions which are best adapted to
                            manifest the Christ life. Duty to the material part, like the care of a servant, will come
                            in secondary, merely7 as an aid in the practical work of righteousness. " For which of you
                            having a servant plowing and feeding cattle, will say to him when he is come from the field,
                            go and sit down to meat; and will not rather say, Make ready wherewith I may sup ; gird
                            thyself and serve me until I have eaten and drunken, and afterwards thou shalt eat and
                            drink. "</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="H., A." TEIform="persName"/>A. H.</byline></div2><pb n="14" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Issachar Bates, no. 6" TEIform="index"/>ISSACHAR BATES-NO. 6</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">Busko creek wa« on the borders of Indiana, in Busseron Co. and at this early date the country
                            was very sparsely settled, and yet the Believers were able to form a settlement and meet
                            with general prosperity. The Shakers called their village Busro, and for a time man;fested a
                            commendable zeal in preparing it for a permanent settlement, but it proved to be a very
                            unhealthy place on account of the low river lands. Another source of deep anxiety and dread
                            weje the tribes of Indians who occupied all the country on tlie north of the settlement and
                            these were reported to be preparing for war. Issachar saj^s that this combination of
                            unpleasant conditions "made me feel as though my bones were all out of joint, and that I had
                            no place for rest. " He was soon after prostrated with a fever caused by severe labor in
                            Busro Creek, while making preparations for a mill-dam. On his recovery be visited Union
                            Village, where he would willingly have made it his permanent home, but after a few weeks for
                            rest he returned in company with James Hodge to Busro. The Society continued to make
                            additional buildings for their better accommodation and yet they lived in great fear of an
                            Indian war. Forts were built and United States soldiers were rapidly increasing as a
                            protection to the people on the frontier. Gov. Harrison very kindly offered to assist the
                            Believers to a residence in Vineennes, and would provide all the tents that they would need,
                            and then guard the place with his soldiers. The Believers appreciated the kindness but had
                            concluded to move into the Societies in Ohio and Kentucky. Issachar immediately went on to
                            Union Village to make arrangements for this great and perilous undertaking, and it was
                            appointed that all the members of the Society should leave Busro on the 15th of September
                            1812, and pass on to Ked Banks, and encamp on the Kentucky side. From this place some were
                            to pass on to South Union, some to Pleasant Hill and others to Union Village. Those who were
                            to move to the last named place crossed the Ohio river at Ked Banks and on the 12th of
                            November entered Union Village. The sorrows and sufferings that fell to the lot of those
                            Christian pilgrims Issachar has left for others to write, but he says " it was joy in the
                            midst of tribulation to meet them. " In 18i;&gt; Issachar went to Busro and assisted
                            tlie six Brethren who had been left at that place as a guard over the property, to sell oft'
                            everything except the land and buildings, which was very satisfactorily accomplished. As the
                            war with tlie Indians had closed and a prospect of continued peace gave more encouragement,
                            the Believers were anxious to return to their own home on the Wabash. Issachar and several
                            others returned to Busro in the Spring of 1814 to make preparations for the others to once
                            more occupy their former house. One house only was found suitable for them to live in as the
                            soldiers had used the property to their own advantage during the war with the Indians. On
                            the 4th of Aug. 1814 all who had formerly lived in Busro again returned to that place,
                            having made the trip much more expeditiously and pleasantly than the one in 1812. Issachar
                            says, "We now went to work and made a comfortable living, as to food and raiment; erected
                            good buildings and mills and kept a good measure of faith and gospel order, and in a few
                            years we had things in a flourishing condition, and I think, we had an equal portion of what
                            belongs to the people of God, tribulation and suffering." Busro was not a healthy locality.
                            A great deal of sickness prevailed during the first years that the Believers made it their
                            home. Not less than one hundred persons were confined at one time, with colds, coughs or
                            fevers and yet the number of deaths were very limited. The year that the largest number was
                            confined to the Infirmary with fevers, it proved fatal to only one person. "We in sorrow
                            mourned our great loss in the' death of Eldress Kuth Darrow on the 18th of Dec. 1814. She
                            was a lovely woman of God, and a Mother in Israel. " Jan. 29, 1824 Issachar made a journey
                            to Union Village, and then to the Believers in Kentucky. In March be left Union Village <pb n="15" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 15 for North Union, Ohio, and visited, he says, "a
                            society of Dutch people at Zoar. " On this journey he met with a serious accident which we
                            give in his own words;—"The horse that I rode was very skittish, and on our third day out,
                            while the snow was falling quite rapidly, I took off" my hat to shake it, when my horse
                            caught the bits in his teeth and ran into the woods. As I fell to the ground he sent his
                            sharp corked heels and hit me just below the knee, and made a severe wound. Samuel Hooser
                            who was my companion on the journey, caught the horse, and I again mounted the saddle, and
                            rode, that day, not less than thirty miles, under intense suffering. At night we examined
                            the wound and I concluded it would be best to continue the journey and we rode on for three
                            days, by which time my leg had swollen fearfully and I feared it would end my life. God
                            heard my pleadings and gave me a gracious promise that I should return to my Brethren. This
                            filled me with perfect reconciliation which I kept through all my sufferings. "When we
                            arrived at Zoar, several young men took me from my horse and carried me into the house,
                            which is the last that I can accurately remember. For forty seven days I was confined with a
                            violent fever, and under the car^ of two careful attendmts Whether I had common sense all
                            that time, I cannot say and whether I was in this world or not, I cannot say, but I hid
                            myself among the dead, to keep out of the way of death, so that I might save my life and
                            return to my home. At the end of forty seven days two Brethren came from Union Village to
                            see what had become of us, as they had just received a word in regard to my condition. I
                            wanted to return to the Village but the Dutch people, said it would not do to move me, as I
                            could not live to ride five miles. I heard the Brethren say, ' He will go, ' and this was
                            joy to me. A carriage was provided and I was placed in it on a straw bed. After bidding
                            adieu to these kind people, we started homeward, and the Brethren gave me the best vf care.
                            We were nine days on the road, making a distance of 21-1 miles. «I was now but little more
                            than bones and sinews. Kind care however, gradually restored me and in two weeks I was again
                            on my feet " In August he visited the Believers in AVhitewater, Ohio and tarried with them
                            about six days. On the 2nd of September he again, in company with several others, left Union
                            Village for North Union, in a carriage and was ten days in making the journey. They made a
                            short stop at Kingston, and held a meeting in that place. After a visit of sixteen days with
                            the Believers of North Union they returned to Union Village and on the way made a visit to
                            the settlement in Zoar. t On the 14th of Oct. 1824 Issachar was appointed to take charge of
                            the Society at Whitewater, Ohio. It was a very great cross to him to move from Union Village
                            to this place, but as he had consecrated soul and body to the service of God and his people
                            he accepted the gift and entered inco the interests-of the place and people. The families
                            were gathered into order, their debts were cancelled and a brick dwelling finished, into
                            which the family moved before the first day of the new year 1825. They raised a irame for a
                            "Meeting House " on the 26th of May, and in June it was dedicated for worship. A blessing
                            attended the faithful labors of the Brethren and Sisters in this place and they were soon
                            able to purchase 100 acres of excellent land. They also built another dwelling, a saw mill,
                            a grist mill and made many other improvements. On the 29th of July 1S2G Issachar made
                            another trip to the Society at Busro in company with two brothers and two sisters who were
                            from that place on a visit to the Believers in Ohio. They reached their home in Indiana on
                            the 4th of Aug. making the trip in seven days. In 1805 Issachar traveled this same journey
                            on foot and it required not less than twenty one days. Then it must be made on foot or on
                            horseback. Now they could ride in a carriage. Then they were filled with fear on account of
                            robbers, and wild Indians. Now the robbers had mostly faded away and the Indians had become
                            peaceful. (TO BE CONTINUE!).)</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Constancy in  well-doing,  insures happiness" TEIform="index"/>Constancy in  well-doing,  insures happiness
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Constancy in well-doing, insures happiness.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline></div2><pb n="16" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Three travelers" TEIform="index"/>THREE TRAVELERS
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Browne, Emma Alice" TEIform="persName"/>EMMA ALICE BROWNE
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Three errant angels, shod with starry light,
                                    Came thro' the gates ajar, at break oi day; And one was fair—clothed in celestial
                                    white; And one was dark, and clad in pilgrim gray: Pale rue and rosemary wreathed
                                    the locks of one— And one waa crowned with radiance, like the sun. And oue—the
                                    silent angel of the three— Was cowled, and shrouded close from crown to heel;
                                    Strange characters, in mystic blazonry. His palmer scrip and girdle did reveal; And
                                    weird devices, wrought in dimmest gold, (iliminered, or paled, upon his mantle's
                                    fold. Upon the rosy threshold of the dawn Their mingled shadows for a moment lay;
                                    And then, by some mysterious impulse drawn, They three went forth, on their
                                    appointed way; And ever farina: on, and hand-in-hand, They wandered far, thro' many
                                    an alien land. These errant angels, journeying day by day, Thro' barren wilds, or
                                    fruitful summer lands. Came to a low, green valley by the way Set in the midst of
                                    waste nnd desert sands: Beneath one stately palm a glittering shaft Of bubbling
                                    crystal water leaped and laughed. " Oh! I am weary of the grievious road ! I faint
                                    beneath the burdens I must bear! Wild are the wastes, and thorns unnumbered goad My
                                    faltering steps : kind sleep awaits us there! " Her listless golden head fell on her
                                    breast: " Sweet comrades, let us tarry—I would rest! " And Death, 1he sombre angel,
                                    turned aside With Life, the overburdened; fain was he In that dim valley evermore to
                                    bide; Butlo! the mute and shrouded, Destiny, With grim, resistless hand still led
                                    them on, To some appointed goal, yet far withdrawn! And Life, with bruised feet and
                                    failing breath, Bearing her heavy cross, still follows slow; Looking for rest and
                                    solace unto Death, When that far destined goal to which the,}go, That distant,
                                    unknown End, is reached at last, And all their toilsome wandering is past!</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Laws" TEIform="index"/>LAWS</head><p TEIform="p">Laws are enforced on us in childhood before we understand the principle. Laws are the shell,
                            the casket containing the jewel. In after years, when the jewel is set—when the principle is
                            fixed in our nature, the law is laid aside. Let the young practice virtue un- der restraint,
                            if needs be, and in age the practice will be natural. What you are at eighteen you will be
                            at forty. When Christ went away he nailed the law of Moses to the cross, but left the
                            morality. He took away the material form, and left the spirit. This was an expedient change.
                            The wisdom of God is displayed in leading men along to look up to Him and trust in Him. Six
                            thousand years of discipline only leave us where we can catch glimpses of the Infinite One,
                            and of our relation to the spiritual universe. That man labors in vain who does not
                            cultivate his spirit. The student studies in vain, and the hero must end his career in dust
                            and dismay. But he who receives Christ, and cultivates His own spiritual nature, may see God
                            mirrored in the brook and flower and cloud and sky, and be led up in adoration to Him who is
                            separated from all materiality and is full of universal love.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Garfield" TEIform="persName"/>Garfield</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love for all" TEIform="index"/>LOVE FOR ALL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p">We would the "wise and prudent, " even. Could know the path that leads to heaven ? That they
                            might sacrifice their dross, And find the glory of the cross. Our God so good, so great,
                            humane, Extends to all of every name The blessing his, and theirs to be By sacrifice and
                            purity. Not pure by being held to right. But pure through love and sweet delight From heart
                            made pure by death to sin Which souls may long have traveled in. But if the inside cup be
                            clean, The outer will not bear the stain ; But pure at heart and clean of hands Doth meet
                            the gospel's full demands. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith and good works harmonize character" TEIform="index"/>Faith and good works harmonize character
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Faith and good works harmonize character.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline></div2><pb n="17" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>[Juvenile]</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div4 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, Connecticut, 1885" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, Conn., 1885</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Children ;—Again you stand on the threshold of another New Year. Has the time
                                    given you by the Great Master been well spent? To thoughtful minds this question
                                    will come, bringing more than on? regret over some wasted opportunity, some willful
                                    neglect, or failure through carelessness or thoughtlessness. Alas! there are so many
                                    who, with good impulses, yet wanting in stability of purpose or action, make great
                                    resolutions for doing good, and often begin some worthy work, and then grow
                                    discouraged because of little obstacles, and lack the perseverance to go on through
                                    difficulties. The New year is a time to make good vows for future action. A good
                                    beginning is an essential element of success. Count each day a golden privilege.
                                    Profit by experience both bitter and sweet. Make the most of life and its
                                    possibilities for goodness. Improve the little opportunities for gaining happiness.
                                    Greater opportunities will not come byneglecting these. Perhaps the little duties,
                                    as they seem to you, are the most important things, in which you can be engaged. The
                                    Father knoweth. If you perform faithfully whatever you ought to do, neglecting no
                                    opportunities, trusting all to God, you will be doing the best you can, and you
                                    cannot go far astray. Have the courage to be true and virtuous, have the love and
                                    faith to be Christ-like, and may heaven bless you with a HapJ&gt;y New Year.
                                    Your Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div4></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word to children" TEIform="index"/>A WORD TO CHILDREN</head><p TEIform="p">Dear children, listen while 1 tell you something which deeply concerns your welfare. The
                                subject is the shape of your bodies God knew the best shape. He created us up- right, in
                                his own image. None of the inferior animals walk upright. God fitted the great vital
                                organs in your bodies to an erect spine. Do your shoulders ever stoop forward? If they
                                do, so do the lungs, heart, liver and stomach fall down out of their natural places. Of
                                course they can't do their work well. To show you liow this is, I will tell you that
                                when you bend forward you can only take about half as much air into the lungs as you can
                                when you stand up straight As I have said, God has so arranged the great organs in the
                                body that they can't do their duty well except when the body is straight. Oh, how it
                                distresses me to see the dear children, whom I love so much, bending over their
                                school-desks, and walking with their head and shoulders drooping! My dear children, if
                                you would have a strong spine and vigorous lungs, heart, liver and stomach, you must,
                                now while you are young, learn to walk erect. If a boy were about to leave this country
                                for Japan, never to return, and were to come to me and ask for rules to preserve his
                                health, I should say, " I am glad to see you and will give you four rules, which,
                                carefully observed, will be pretty sure to preserve your health. " He might say tome,
                                "Four are a good many; I fear I may forget some of them; give me one, the most important
                                one, and I promise not to forget it. " I should reply, " Well, my dear boy, if I can
                                give you but one, it is this : Keep yourself straight, that is, sit up straight; walk up
                                straight; and when in bed, at night, don't put two or three pillows under your head, as
                                though intent on watching your toes all night;" and I believe that in this I should give
                                the most important rule which can be given for the preservation of health and long life.
                                My dear children, don't forget it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lewis, Dio" TEIform="persName"/>Dio Lewis in Golden Rule</byline></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dull weather" TEIform="index"/>DULL WEATHER</head><p TEIform="p">We sigh for bright and pleasant days, But when our sun is shining, We oft forget that
                                thanks and praise Should equal our repining.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God sustains those who truly serve Him" TEIform="index"/>God sustains those who truly serve Him
                        </head><p TEIform="p">God sustains those who truly serve Him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline></div2><pb n="18" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO. JANUARY, 1885</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Welcome happy New Year ! a season that will, we trust, be fraught with abundant blessings
                                !! All our writers and readers will share with us in this advent of glad tidings and bj
                                a cheerful and renewed effort help on the glorious work in which we have become the
                                willing servants of our Lord. As we open the account with pleasurable anticipations of a
                                fruitful and prosperous future, which we trust will redound to the honor and glory of
                                God, and at the same time afford us the inestimable blessing of peace on earth ; we must
                                not fail to return thanks for the manifold gifts that we have shared so bountifully
                                during the past year. We are also to bear in mind that the present number of the
                                Manifesto brings us to the fifteenth volume. It carefully and kindly reminds us of the
                                continued obligations that are demanded of us. to work while the day lasts, in earnestly
                                contending for the faith which leads toward goodness and practical righteousness. We
                                have not wanted for able and devoted souls, who know to a fullness whereof they write,
                                and speak, to come forward and publish the truth as it has been revealed to their souls.
                                But the old year has passed away, and it carries the record of our lives. The new year
                                dawns upon us, and asks of us new resolves, new testimonies and new sacrifices to the
                                holy Spirit that we may not become absorbed in the perishable things of this life, and
                                by this means, miss the prize of salvation. More than ever before the Christian worker
                                should zealously and faithfully "put on the whole armor of God" and stand unswervingly
                                in defence of gospel principles. More potent than at any former age is the voice of God
                                to his people, while the revelation of divine Truth comes with ik no uncertain sound. "
                                " Blessed are the pure in heart. " •-Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be
                                called the children of God.'* These ring out their heavenly tones as they did on the
                                fair mountains of Galilee, and are being caught up by the faithful disciple of the
                                present day and carried with a lively zeal into the homes of those who "hunger and
                                thirst after righteousness. " It is a message filled with truth and life, and those who
                                bear ifc are, indeed, blessed of God. From it comes a knowledge of the. heavenly pathway
                                which leads to the kingdom of eternal rest. Let your light shine follows as the
                                imperative work of thoso who have obtained not only this heavenly privilege, but also
                                the confirmation in their own souls that they are called of God. To receive the
                                assurance that we can attain to the great blessing of becoming children of God, or can
                                be made able through the purification of the heart to see the Holy Spirit in its
                                loveliness, is a blessing which has been conferred upon but few persons. The new year
                                opens as with a fresh and clean book, upon which the record of our lives may be written
                                in loving kindness. If the past has been fair or clouded ; if it has measured out to us
                                much happiness and much sorrow, we are assured that the present is overflowing in
                                goodness, and we look upon it with fond anticipation for the moral and spiritual
                                JANUARY, 1883. <pb n="19" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. growth that may be our future
                                inheritance. In the protection that is awarded to us we feel confident that " God's arm
                                is not shortened that it cannot save, neither his ear heavy that it cannot hear. "
                                Isaiah lix. 1. With this new year comes new courage, a revival of faith and a resolution
                                to walk circumspectly before God and man. All share alike the privilege of consecration
                                and all may abound iu the manifestation of good and choice gifts. To the aged parent as
                                well as to the youngest child, all things will be formed anew as the matured, the time
                                worn, passes away. The Manifesto as the messenger of good news and glad tidings will
                                continue to go out on its mission of love. Its pages as heretofore, will we trust, be
                                filled with that testimony which is of the Christ spirit, and harmonizes fully with the
                                doctrine of the sermon on the Mount. This, as Jesus himself declares, was the sharp
                                sword which should separate the good from the evil, and its ultimate would establish a
                                spiritual kingdom upon the earth wherein should dwell righteousness. In this we are
                                working and praying to the same spirit, believing that the blessing and protection of a
                                kind Providence will be over all who walk in the path of holiness and peace.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="With care" TEIform="index"/>WITH CARE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We find the following in the History of Cumberland Co., Me. "In the book of written rules
                                for the observance of the members of the community, the first one, written in a bold
                                hand, is the following. " "Believers (Shakers) must not run in debt to the world, and
                                any one, even a Trustee, who departs from the rule is held personally responsible for
                                the debt so contracted, and the Society will not hold itself responsible ; and of this
                                fact the Leaders keep the public well informed, by frequently publishing it in the
                                leading Newspapers that circulate where the Shakers do business in the form of a
                                Declaration and Caution to the public."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guides through the journey of life" TEIform="index"/>GUIDES THROUGH THE JOURNEY OF LIFE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sproat, Granville Temple" TEIform="persName"/>GRANVILLE TEMPLE SPROAT</byline><p TEIform="p">All along the journey of life, there are way-marks and guide-boards to direct us. Let us look
                            at some of them and see what is written, in clear, legible characters, on the face of each.
                            1. Be patient. Patience and long suffering cure half the ills of life. They are like the
                            magic lamp of Aladdin that turned all things it touched to gold. Who has not read and ad-
                            mired the story of Uncle Toby, in Sterne's Tristem Shandy? A fly had been buzzing about him
                            all the morning, drumming in his ears, tickling his nose, and, as often as he put his hand
                            up to take him, darting off like a shot, only to return again, as if on purpose to torment
                            him. At length Uncle Toby gently caught him in his hand. He arose, went to the window and
                            opened it, to let the fly escape, and said, softly, " Get thee srone, poor devil. Why should
                            I harm thee? Is not the world big enough for thee and for me? Get thee gone my blessing go
                            with thee. " More striking still is the story told of Isaac Hopper, the good Quaker of
                            Philadelphia. While lying awake, one night, he heard the voices of thieves in his cellar,
                            stealing meat from his meat barrel. He arose, Avent outside of his dwelling, and saw a thief
                            there holding a bag at his cellar window, while a thief inside was lifting the meat through
                            the window, into the bag. As Isaac approached, the thief fled, and Isaac took his place at
                            the window, " Is not the bag most full? " asked the thief from the cellar. " Not quite, "
                            said 1» <pb n="20" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. Isaac, altering his voice; " two pieces
                            more, there, that will do; now it is full." The thief came up the cellar stairs, and who
                            should he meet hut the honest Quaker! Isaac knew him at once. He was one of his nearest
                            neighbors, and very poor. He started to go. " Stop" said Isaac, " I have somewhat to say to
                            thee. Had I known of the deep poverty, and thy distress, I would have given thee all this
                            meat, and more too,—all that thou couldst carry away. As it is, take it; take it all; and
                            tomorrow come and see me. I would like to speak with thee. " The man demurred ; but Isaac
                            made him take the bag of meat on his shoulders, although, as he aft. erwards said, "It was
                            like taking coals of fire on his back. " The next day he came to see Isaac. The result was,
                            that, instead of being arrested as a thief, Isaac, after hearing of his poverty, and his
                            subsequent temptation, furnished him with a good, payable sit" uation which he held through
                            life; and he ever afterwards blessed the name of Isaac Hopper, who, by his patience and long
                            suffering had saved him, and his family, from destruction. 2. Be modest and unassuming.
                            Isaac Hopper-—he deserves to be remembered for his deeds of goodness, and charity—was sent
                            on business of importance to Europe. He was dining with a family of wealth and high social
                            position, in the city of Dublin. A card was brought in. It was an invitation for Isaac to go
                            and dine with a family in the city the following day. After the bearer of the note had gone,
                            the host said, "This family with whom you are to dine tomorrow are very respectable; but
                            they are not exactly of our class. The father was a carpenter, and the host, himself, was
                            once a tailor. " " Did I understand thee aright," asked Isaac. " His father was a carpenter,
                            and he, himself, a tailor? Well, I was once a tailor too. Dost thou doubt it? Then look at
                            my hands. Thou canst well see the marks of the shears upon them still. I was once a tailor;
                            but I was never ashamed of it, I have often walked with the Mayor of the city of
                            Philadelphia, who was, himself, once a tailor, I was not ashamed of him, and I believe he
                            was not ashamed of me. " o. Be sincere. All men love simplicity of character, but the man
                            who squints, who speaks one thing out of his eyes, and means another, all good and rare
                            spirits avoid him. It was said of Napoleon, that he could throw all expression out of his
                            face, the moment you looked at him, to interpret his secret motive. And what squeaking there
                            is through masks that hide the meaning of the face behind them ! " Let me see your face, and
                            look into your eyes, " said a wise old teacher, " and then I can tell what you m an. " The
                            greatest men have always been the simplest men. It was so with Newton, of whom it is said ''
                            science was as easy as breathing. He used the same wit to weigh the moon that he did to
                            buckle his shoe, and all his life was .simple, wise and majestic. So was it with
                            Archimedes—always self-same, like the sky. In Linneus, in Franklin, the like sweetness and
                            equality; no stilts* no tiptoe— and their results were Avholesome and memorable to all men.
                            " 4. On the guide board it is writtten, " Lie not one to another; seeing that ye have put
                            off the old man and his deed*. The lying tongue is but for a moment. " A lie will burn as
                            well as any other lamp, while the oil of reputation lasts; but the oil is soon expended ;
                            the lamp flickers and flutters, and, finally, goes out, and fills the house with noisome
                            stench, and all the inmates turn away from it with loathing and disgust. "A lie glasses the
                            eye, pinches the nose, furrows the cheek, and writes on the forehead of a king, ' fool!
                            fool!' The Avorld is full of judgment days, and wherever a man goes, he is guaged and
                            stamped for what he is worth. " Character will speak under the closest mask. Let a man with
                            a false, deceitful tongue go among others and they will say, "Now, look out for him! he is
                            not to be trusted. He is a broken reed. Do not lean upon it! He is quicksand. Do not step
                            upon it! " He is like the two fabulous sirens of the ancient Greeks—Scylla and Charybdis. If
                            you fell into the hands of Scylla, she tore you to pieces; of Charybdis, she swallowed you
                            alive. " Dreadful limits are set, by nature to dis- simulation. When a man speaks the truth,
                            his eye is clear as the heavens. When he de- ceives, it becomes muddy, and squints. " The
                                <pb n="21" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 21 tongue also stammers and stutters. Sweden, borg
                            says, he saw, in one of his visits to the spiritual world, a group of persons who tried to
                            speak what they did not believe. The way they twisted and screwed their mouths was a wonder
                            to see. They struggled, and stammered, and halted, and almost choked with vexation. The lie
                            rose up, and smote them in the face They were like dumb mutes, who sometimes strike and beat
                            their breasts to make the words come forth which they are struggling to utter. A lie carries
                            with it its own punishment. It was the penitent, would-be murderer of good king Alphonso, of
                            Castile, who, after he had been hunted from his lair in the mountains, secured, and
                            threatened with* torture exclaimed, " Torture ! and what torture can be equal to what I have
                            already felt in trying to conceal the crime of which I knew myself to be guilty? What can
                            rack and pincers do to him who has felt the agonies of remorse? " A lie cannot be concealed.
                            It will blab. " Though you pile a mountain on a lie, " said the wise old Seneca, "yet the
                            lie will turn over, and throw the mountain off, and the lie will stand revealed. " The
                            sinner shall not go unpunished. The Indians called a liar, " Ne-bo-nas-se,'' double tongued.
                            "Let me look into your mouth, " they would say, " to see if you have not two tongues. Let me
                            cut out one of them, for what right lias a man to live with two tongues? " 5. Shun bigotry.
                            The bigot does not know that in shutting the doors of the kingdom of heaven against his
                            neighbor, and leaving him out in the cold, he also shuts himself out, and shivers with a
                            worse cold than he makes his neighbor feel. It is the eternal law of recompense. We cannot
                            escape it. On the balances of God it is written, "A pound for a pound." Justice holds the
                            scales. We have all read the story of the ancient medieval artist who invented the brazen
                            bull. He took it to the emperor, and said, " See what I have made ! It is a wonderful
                            instrument for torture ! Ir it I will put my enemy ; a fire shall be kindled beneath it, and
                            the cries of my enemy shall sound like the roaring of an infuriated bull. It will be
                            wonderful to hear him roar. " " Will it? " replied the emperor. " Then we will have you the
                            first put into it; a fire shall be kindled, as you have intended for your enemy. We will be
                            the first to be amused by hearing the bull roar. " It was the crying sin of the Pharisees
                            that they shut the door of the kingdom of heaven : they would not go in themselves, nor
                            suffer others to go in. Therefore Jesus reproved them. That great heart cften spoke to them
                            in parables, exposing their narrowness and bigotry. One of his parables, with its moral, may
                            be read thus :—A traveler was beset by robbers, and wounded, and left weltering in his
                            blood. A priest and a Levite passed that way. They saw him there, covered with blood. Could
                            they defile their hands by touching him? Had not the law and the temple stronger demands on
                            them than the law of humanity? They " passed by on the other side. " A poor outcast
                            Samaritan, also, came along. He ran to his help. In helping him, he helped himself. What a
                            man does, that he has. What lin gives he gains. He gained the reward which the priest and
                            the Levite lost. " Go, and do likewise, " said, Jesus. What we withhold from others, we
                            withhold from ourselves. It is the eternal law. The thief steals from himself. Jesus
                            reproved the Pharisees ; but it was always in a spirit of love. Love is like the sun. "It
                            melts all hearts but what are mummy-cased in selfishness and bigotry. True love appreciates
                            all things. It knows not the cold words, mine and thine. It says, "I and my brother are one.
                            All I am is his, all he is is nit. " " All things are yours, " said the great heart of Paul.
                            It was a beautiful reply of Fenelon to the Romish priest, who came to dispute with him,
                            threatening him with excommunication. "You cannot excommunicate me, " said he, " I own you.
                            I own the whole church of Home. I own you, although you may not own me. Home cannot build
                            her walls so high but I can fly over them. My love shall embrace you all. You may scratch my
                            name from the rolls of the church, but you cannot scratch your names from my roll, and that
                            is just as good. " The priest went away confounded. Home, with all its legions, was not so
                            strong as that great loving heart. <pb n="22" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MANIFESTO. G. Beware of
                            avarice. We remember once looking at an old English print, containing»a terrible sarcasm
                            against the sin of avarice. It*was a picture of Satan carrying a miser, on his back, to
                            purgatory. The miser, true to his intuitions, was trying to strike a bargain with his
                            Satanic majesty, and was saying, " Say, old fellow, what is the price of coal down in your
                            region? Would there not be a chance for a fellow to make a few thousands down there? hey? "
                            It was wonderful to see the leer with which the " old fellow "— his Satanic majesty regarded
                            him. It was as much as to say, "What! would you cheat the very devils themselves, and that,
                            too, when you are yourself on the high road to hell?" It has been said, " The devil cheats
                            all souls but one; the miser cheats the devil." His soul becomes corroded, so covered with
                            rust that the true metal is nowhere to be seen. He has lost fellowship witli all humanity,
                            and stands a blank in God's creation. His business is to ruin and defraud others. Prayers,
                            tears, widow's prayers, and orphan's tears, avail nothing with him. Money he must have ;
                            money, though souls are ruined and betrayed ; money, though the earth is made a vale of
                            tears, money, though dug from the lowest depths of hell. The miser often perishes through
                            his own devices. A few years since, in maRing im" provements in the city of Paris, they tore
                            down a large stone building that had once been the residence of Foscue the miser, who had
                            suddenly disappeared from the world, nearly a century before. In digging among the
                            foundations, the workmen discovered a trap door, rusty with age, and fastened with a
                            spring-lock,—itself nearly consumed by rust. They forced open the door. There were steps
                            leading to a vault beneath, silent and dark as the tomb. They procured lights, and descended
                            the steps. There, among chests of gold and silver, hung a human skeleton. The clothing was
                            hanging in tatters from the fleshless limbs, and from one hand had dropped a lamp on to the
                            ground beneath. The skeleton was that of Foscue, the miser. He had been solicited for a
                            large loan of money to enrich the royal treasury. Unwilling to incur the displeasure of
                            Louis sixteenth, and fearful that the money would not be refunded, in those dark and
                            troublous days of the French nation,—in order to make it appear that he had not the sum
                            demanded, he had caused these vaults, secretly, to be built, and the money conveyed into
                            them. The sequel is easily told. A spring lock had fastened him in there; and lie had died
                            there, gloating over his treasures, and feasting his eyes, even in death, witli gazing on
                            the god of his idolatry—gold. Canaan N. Y..</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kind words" TEIform="index"/>Kind Words</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Washington, D. C. June 1884" TEIform="index"/>Washington, D. C. June. 1884</head><p TEIform="p">I gather much comfort from the teachings of the Manifesto. Religion is made to live out
                                the Christian life, which the great body called Christians have only in theory. I hail
                                the time when the great majority will obey the teaching of our Christ and King, and to
                                this end I like to study and get comfort from the Manifesto. Your friend, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Toepper, J. G." TEIform="persName"/>J. G. Toepper</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bangor, Maine, August 1884" TEIform="index"/>Bangor, Me. Aug. 1884</head><p TEIform="p">For some reason my Aug. Manifesto did not reach me. Will you please forward it at once
                                and oblige. I feel at a great loss without it and do not feel willing to have one number
                                drop out. Yours truly, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Emery, Simeon" TEIform="persName"/>Simeon Emery</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Every good deed that we do..." TEIform="index"/>Every good deed that we do...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Every good deed that we do is not only a present good or pleasure, but a prop for the future.
                            Like is a sum and it becomes us to do it properly, as it can be done but once. A gentle
                            disposition is like an unruffled stream. AniDE in the light and no power can harm thee.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rice, Abigail" TEIform="index"/>Abigail Rice
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Rice, Abigail" TEIform="persName">Abigail Rice</persName>, Nov. 14, 1884, at Second Family,
                                Mount Lebanon, N. Y Age 90 years and 8 mo.</p></div3></div2><pb n="23" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Consolation" TEIform="index"/>CONSOLATION</head><p TEIform="p">West Gloucester, Me. Watching and praying I find you, O my beloved, my own, Trusting a
                            Father's rich promise, I will not leave you alone, I will not leave you alone. Tho' thro'
                            the desert I lead, Or a part in the mountain ye pray For strength in the hour of need, I
                            never will answer you nay, I never will answer you nay.</p></div2><pb n="24" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. December, Contents : Tygmund F.
                                Milkowski, the Polish Patriot and Author; Organic Cerebration; The Christian Church ;
                                Progress ; Mcrv and its people ; Cagliostro as a medium; The French in China; Old
                                Superstitions; A well dressed woman; Prevention of Decay of Teeth; Individuality in
                                Relation to Physiology; Animals as Physicians; The Scourge of Quackery; Poetry; Wisdom,
                                Wit, etc,.etc. Fowler and Wells, Co. 753 J5ro:idway, N. Y. Terms $2. a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to live a century and grow old gracefully" TEIform="index"/>How to Live
                                a Century and Grow Old Gracefully
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">How to Live
                                a Century and Grow Old Gracefully. By «T. M. Peebles, M. D. New York: M. L. Holbrook
                                &amp; Co. Price 50 cents. The author in his preface says : " Human life being both
                                the gift of God and a blessing, it is a duty to preserve it. as long as possible. No
                                truly gooil person, however aged, ever yet outlived his or her usefulness. En all
                                enlightened lands old age is con- sidered honorable; the hoary head is a crown of glory.
                                "In preparing the following pages, while avoiding technicalities and Greek and Latin
                                phrases, I have aimed to be practical, rigidly practical, rather than original or
                                elegant; aimed to bring to mind and clearly present the vita) importance of air, food,
                                clothing, drink, sunshine ami sleep in such varied ways as to inspire the reader with a
                                proper and persistent use of them that the number of years upon earth may -be many—even
                                a hundred! "My only purpose as an author is to instruct and benefit my iellowmen. Laws
                                are immutable, and all laws have their reflex action. There is nothing more certain than
                                that in helping and blessing others we are blessed, Therefore if I pluck a thorn from a
                                mortal's pathway and plant a rose there ; if upon the tear-wet cheek I can plant a
                                rainbow of hope;; if by tongue or pen or practice I can prevent, or in any way relieve,
                                human suffering, and lighten the burden of sorrow, thus aiding my fellowincn to reach a
                                peaceful and happy old age, then a n 1 satisfied. " The following are the titles of the
                                chapters : The Five Forces; Old Trees; Longevity of Birds and Animals; I Repeat the
                                Inquiry, Why? Long lived Persons, and Why? Pure Air and Deep Breathing Necessary to Long
                                Life; How to sleep in order to Live a Century; What Shall We Bat to Live a Century? What
                                Shall We Drink to Live a Century? What Clothing Should be Worn to Live a Century? Are
                                Medicines Necessary to Prolong Life a Century? How to Treat Babies and Children that
                                they may Grow up and Live to see a Century; Summarized Rules of Health enabling one to
                                Live a Century. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Triple E." TEIform="index"/>The Triple E
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clark, S. R. Graham" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The Triple E. By Mrs. S. R. Graham Clark. Boston. D. Lothrop &amp;
                                Co. Price, $1.50. Mrs. Clark is known as the author of Yensie Walton, one of the most
                                popular Sunday-school books which has been published for many seasons, and the qualities
                                which attracted attention in that work predominate strongly in this. The "Triple E " is
                                the name playfully given by her friends to a girl of eighteen, whose three names begun
                                with that letter, and who is left with a younger sister to make her way in the world aft
                                or-the death of her parents. She has promised her mother on her deathbed to not only
                                care for her sister, but also for an insane uncle, and a little girl waif who came into
                                their family in the most mysterious manner. Much of the interest of the story ccjiiiis
                                in this latter character, and the mystery in . which her parentage is involved lends it
                                a strong fascination. The iwo sisters are compelled to enter a large mahtrfaotorj in
                                order to gain a subsistence and earn means for supporting their charges. The record
                                of.their experiences in this new life, their trials, and the victory over adversity they
                                finally achieved, is told in a manner which commands attention from first to last. It is
                                a book which cannot fail to make a strong impression upon the minds of those who read
                                it. Mrs. Mary II. Hunt, Superintendent of Scientific Instruction W. C. T. U. has had
                                prepared a capita! primary treatise on Physiology with reference to narcotics and
                                alcohol, which the W. C. T. IT. is strenuously recommending to Schools and Boards of
                                Education. It is such a book as will instruct and interest whole families i,s well as
                                schools. Price 60 cents. A. S. Barnes &amp; Co., Publishers, New York. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Herald of health" TEIform="index"/>Herald of health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Herald or
                                health. December, Contents: Influences of School Life on Eyesight; Count Rumford's
                                Substitute for Tea; The Mind Cure; Massage for Indigestion; Gardening for Health;
                                Studies In Hygiene for Women; M. L. Holbrook. M. D. 13 and 15 Laight, Street N. Y. $3.00
                                a year.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clarion call" TEIform="index"/>A CLARION CALL
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brunton, William" TEIform="persName"/>BY REV. WILLIAM BRUNTON
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Ye brave of heart who dare to serve
                                    where honor calls; Ye sons of God on whom the, prophet mantle falls; Ye lovers of
                                    mankind, who seek to know the truth, And comfort age thereby, and strengthen
                                    weakliug youth, Wiio wish to cheer the weary on their toilsome way, Reclaim the
                                    lost, and lead them back to golden day, Who wish to teach the dull to feel true
                                    manly worth, And bring once more the Eden life to darksome earth, And give to
                                    trembling hope the confidence of love, To vain and savage pride the meekness of the
                                    dove, Unite with us : we seek and prize the good and true, We fain would sin and
                                    death by light and love subdue' In heart and soul we grieve that falsehood, wrong,
                                    and might Should rule the world in gloom, when truth would rule in light. Inspired
                                    with loyal zeal, a brave, crusading band, We, venture forth in love to free our holy
                                    land, The land where captives weep in passion's direst pain, And woes beset the
                                    poor, and wrongs the rich maintain ' Tis there we boldly press,proclaiming love and
                                    light Defending men from harm, upholding truth and right, ' Tis there we seek the
                                    foe, unfearing death or loss, With joyous valor filled, glad soldiers of the cross,
                                    There haste to tread with us the path grave vet'rans trod, And soon the world shall
                                    be the paradise of God. What greater joy than this, to elevate mankind, To speak the
                                    word of truth for heart, and soul, and mind; To labor for the right, to suffer for
                                    the just, To work for God and man, in man and God to trust; To live the saintly
                                    life, that common life may see This fair and glorious world more beautiful and free;
                                    To gem the spacious vault that rounds the spirit sphere With circling realms of
                                    love, at once iar-offnd near? Divinely blest the work! And earnest heart that shares
                                    In all these burning?hopes, in all these lofty cures, Make this your task in life,
                                    your life's supernal aim,. Responding to the call of honor, love, and fame.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Advertisements" TEIform="index"/>[Advertisements]</head><p TEIform="p">[Advertisements deleted.]</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>