<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm1505" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">30</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope"/><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope"/><date value="18850501" TEIform="date">May 1885</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">97-119</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="15" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="5" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb n="t.p." id="p1"/>
MAY.
THE
Published by the United Societies,
"Blessed are those that hear the word of God and keep it."
SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
1885.   .
MANIFESTO
CANTERBURY
N. H.AD VERTISEMENTS.
THE SHAKERS
IN

Are Sole Proprietors of the best
For all bilious complaints they are
certainly unequaled. They are prepared
from vegetables only. They act as a
powerful cathartic, or as a mild laxative,
according to the dose.
Are   you   afflicted   with
Headache,      Faintness,     Dizziness,
Bad Breath, Loss of Appetite,
Dyspepsia,   Jaundice   oh
Diseased   Liver ?
You will find relief by the use of
CORBEIT'S    VEGETABLE     FAMILY     PILLS.
Price b;; mail 25   cts.   per   box.     Five
boxes for one dollar.
N. A. BRIGGS, TRUSTEE.
Shaker Village,  N. H.
km
k Remedy k all Pulmonary Diseases.
CURES
COU&HS, MLUEBZA, HOARSENESS, ASTHMA, WH00Pffl& COUGH, BRONCHITIS, PAIN in He
SIDE and CHEST.
PEEPAEED by the SOCIETY
AT
SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
N. A. Briggs, Trustee.
- -rieo 50 cents per bottle.
Sold by all Druggists.
117
- - - - Sewing Ma-<
^iI chines. Only
 ncluding a full set of extra
Attachments, needles,'
oil and usual outfit of 12 pieces w!l!i
h. Guaranteed Perfect. Warranted i
irs.   llamSDiiie and Durable.   Don't
pay $40 or - -."><> for machines no bettor.
We will send them anywhere on 15 ds.js1
trial before paying-.   Circulars and mil
particulars free by addressing
E. - -. HOWE & CO.,
188 PJori h fith St.,      P1IILA., PA,
Loci. Sox 1087.
AnviU Vise, Cutoft' Tooifo? Farm
&Hrm.;vise. 3 sizes, $4.50 $6.50.
Sold by hardware dealtrs. To
introduce, one
free to i.rst person wlio gets ut> a
JUST WHAT YOU
WANT.
:
ts 1 or circulars
ClUGSEY
 - -!fc VISE CO.,
DETROIT,' MICH.
Canvasser anil Printer Wanted.
mouth, IV. H.
eachcrs   who   use   reward   cards    in
their schools should  send  2ct.   stamp
for samples and prices to
TOWNE'S
BOOKSTORE.
FRANKLIN FALLS.
N. H.
Sci-pio, Cayuga Co, N. Y.
To my collection of
Porcheron Stallions
land Mares, I have
jadded, by direct im.
fportation, 57 fine anijmals, making 130
(head. Large number of prize animals.
Imported stock registered in Perchcron
Stud Bcmk of France and America. All stallions warranted breeders. New catalogue out soon. Station
Ensenore, on South'n Central R. R. John W. Akin.
MAYNARD & NOYES,
MANUFACTURERS   OF
SLACK WRITING INK.
ItOSTOX.
THE BACKUS WATER MOTOE,
Wo have one of eleven  inches,   new,
that we will sell at a bagrain.
Pub.   MANIFESTO,
FAMILY PILLS.
SHAKER'S
91A $8
State age, experience, and
wages.   PB.I    TES,    r'iy --><pb n="97" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><!--           CONTENTS.
Page.
Spirit op Truth,        ....          97
Influence, -         -         -          -         -          -98
Love,      ......          99
Justification,      -                                                 101
Gospel,           .....           102
Aid yourself, and God will aid you,         -     "
The Signpost,           ....            "
The Music of the Spheres No. 1.                 -   103
Alfred, No. 5.          -         -          -         -           105
Pious Pretensions,        -          -          -           -   107
How to be Miserable,       -          -          -          108
Health Maxims,              -          -          -           -     "
Ever Near,    .....           109
Patient With The Living,
The Manifesto,
Busro, No. 1.
Purity,
Letter Box,
Notes,
Sanitary,
Tribute,
The Motherhooii of God,
Early Quakers,
Art of Thinking,
Music ,- -Supplication ,
Books & Papers,  Pagb.
-    110
112
-    113
114
-    115
110
117
-    118
119
-    120
Vol. XV.
MAY, 1885.
No. 5.--><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spirit of truth" TEIform="index"/> THE SPIRIT OF TRUTH.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Tins is the life-spring of all religion, and where it exists, it must manifest it self, it
                            must plead, it must persuade, it must convince and convert. The same spirit which fills the
                            missionary with daring abroad, gives courage also to the preacher at home, bearing witness
                            to the truth that is within him. There are those who say that if they held the whole truth
                            in their hand, they would not open one finger. They seem to think it impertinent to mention
                            religion unless it is asked for. Such people know little of the working of the spirit of
                            truth. As long as there is doubt, and darkness and anxiety in the soul of the inquirer,
                            reticence may be his natural attitude. But when doubt has yielded to certainty, darkness to
                            light, anxiety to joy, the rays of truth will burst forth. And to close our hand or to shut
                            our lips, would be as impossible as for the petals of a flower to shut themselves against
                            the life-giving warmth of Spring. What should we wait for, when thousands are ready to
                            listen, if one will but speak the truth and nothing but the truth? Thousands are starving
                            because they cannot find that food which is convenient for them. And even if the spirit of
                            truth might be chained by fear or prudence, the spirit of love would never yield. There may
                            be times when silence is gold and speech silver ; but there are times also when silence is
                            death, and speech is life- -the very life of Pentecost. How can man be afraid of man ; how
                            can we be afraid of those we love ? Though political economists tell us that every convert
                            costs us $1000 and that at the present rate of progress it <pb n="98" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> would take
                            more than 200,000 years to evangelize the world, there is nothing at all startling in these
                            figures. Every child born in Europe, or America, is as much a heathen as the child of a
                            Melanesian cannibal; and it costs us more than $1000 to turn a child into a mature
                            Christian. Why not, if every natural child must be born again, or born from above, before he
                            can be a Christian, or in other words ''see the Kingdom of God?" Jno. iii. The other
                            calculation is totally erroneous ; fcr increase of mental and spiritual propagations must
                            not be calculated by simply adding grain to grain, but by counting each grain as a living
                            seed, that will bring forth fruit, some thirty, some sixty, and some a hundred fold. A
                            religion may linger for a Ions; time, it may be accepted by people because it is there, and
                            they know of nothing better. But when a religion has ceased to produce advocates of the
                            faith, prophets, champions, martyrs, it has ceased to live. The Prophet says "- - His word
                            was as a burning fire, shut up in my bones. " Mt. Lebanon. N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence" TEIform="index"/> INFLUENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Marion" TEIform="persName"/>MARION JOHNSON.</byline><p TEIform="p">Webster defines influence as literally, a flowing in ; and from observation and experience,
                            we should also draw the same inference ; that it was an unseen mystical power, flowing into
                            and permeating the mind, whether from visible or invisible agencies, and in a greater or
                            less degree, affecting or modifying our physical, intellectual and moral actions. It also
                            seems a self-evident fact, that this power is inherent to - -ome extent, in our very being,
                            "and that we are constantly exercising it, unconsciously or otherwise. This is a solemn
                            reflection to an awakened mind, pregnant with the deepest meaning, and one by which we
                            should square the thoughts and actions of our daily lives. If this were always realized to
                            the extent that its importance demands, how very different would our record stand. How
                            should we ever diffuse around us an atmosphere redolent of love and kindness, immarred by
                            discord or disunion, but ever breathing forth a spirit of forbearance and longsuffering
                            under provocation or injury, which those who come within our sphere wTould realize. Thus
                            should we not onlv be elevating our own character, but we should unconsciously be
                            instrumental in the moral and spiritual development of all who come under our influence. If
                            the theory be true, that ^e leave our impress upon everything with which we come in contact,
                            and that impression can be discerned by those whose- spiritual natures have been
                            sufficiently developed, though perhaps it may not be until ages afterwards; if this theory
                            were true, and it were possible to always keep a realizing sense of the fact, what an
                            incentive it might prove to moral discipline, that the impress we left should be pure and
                            right, one we should be willing to meet; and what a stimulus it would be to an active growth
                            in all the Christian virtues and graces ; how ardent would be our endeavors to imitate
                            Christ, our pattern and exemplar. But, alas! this is a subject of too small interest to the
                            mass of mankind, even professors of religion seem to care<pb n="99" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> very little
                            whether their influence is purifying or otherwise. Each one seems iatent on carrying out his
                            own selfish schemes and aims, regardless of the wrong they are doing to themselves, or the
                            effect they may have upon the well being of their neighbors whether it will guide them into
                            the strait and narrow path that leadeth to life, or whether it may give them an impetus on
                            their downward course. As Believers in practical Christianity, we teach that a moral
                            responsibility rests upon each one for the influence we exert upon others, and hence, we
                            strive by a life of purity and uprightness to win others to the same life according to the
                            precept of the Scriptures, "So let your light shine before men that they may see your good
                            works and glorify your Father which is in heaven." Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/> LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bates, Louisa" TEIform="persName"/>LOUISA BATES.</byline><p TEIform="p">In no age or clime, in no language in which thj human tongue finds utterance, is there
                            expression more potent, fraught with deeper meaning, than the simple word, Love, the praise
                            of which has been spoken and sung since Time began. No other emotion of the human mind has
                            been more exalted, yet more debased, more reverenced, and more basely counterfeited, than
                            this, whose spirit reigned in the garden of Edenic Innocence, and whose name daily falls
                            from the lips of thousands, few of whom are conscious of its deepest, truest meaning.
                            Webster defines Love as the '' concentration of the affections upon some particular person
                            or object." Poets and philosophers of every age, dissected and analyzed at this hidden
                            spring of the organic machinery, with equally unsatisfactory results, until the intelligent,
                            thoughtful people of to-day, are inquiring, "What is this Love of which we hear so much yet
                            know so little? "The world is undergoing a change. We live in one of those mighty
                            transitionary epochs of human history, when old things are passing away, and all things
                            becoming new. We are realizing the prophetic tidings of ages ago, that God would pour out
                            his spirit upon all flesh." The perception of this truth divine, is even now descending from
                            the spiritual heavens, upon those who will receive it, unclasping the sealed book of
                            Mystery, and causing the clouds of ignorance and superstition to retire before its glorious
                            advance, as the shadowy clouds of night retreat, when the Morning Stars herald the approach
                            of the new born day. " God and the Angel World are rolling away the rock of a base
                            sensuality and carnality from the sepulchre of the sleeping spirit, and, obedient to th3
                            voice of Omnipotent Love, it is coming forth in the renewed power of a risen humanity." Even
                            so, the awakening intuitive perception of the human soul, is beginning to comprehend the
                            great Truth, voiced hundreds of years ago,- - " God is Love, and he that dwelleth in Love,
                            dwelleth in God, and God in him. " Then where shall we look for this precious gift, this
                            boon of Love, to brighten our lives and strengthen our souls? Not in far off lands beyond
                            the sea, for there they may not know God, nor the love that dwelleth in him. Shall we seek
                            it in the many churches of our Christian land, whose costly spires point<pb n="100" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> upward, whose deep toned bells ring out their calls to mankind, to come in and declare
                            themselves saved, through the merits of that Christ whose praise they sing, whose Love they
                            profess, and whom their daily lives do deny ? Nay for this Love of God for which we are
                            searching, is unchanging as the heavens, as abiding, as pure and as true. Let us search for
                            that tender, all embracing Love of God, in the charmed circle of the domestic family, but we
                            find instead, at best, the tender natural affection which draws the sharply defined circle
                            around its own, stamping upon it the law of "me and mine." Can we for a moment believe this
                            to be that Love which is of God ? prizing above all things of earth, the inestimable worth
                            of one poor lost soul ? O! where shall we search for the Love of God, which passeth all
                            understanding ? For we would fain sell all that we have, wherewith to obtain this fount of
                            Love divine, which shall be as a " Well of water springing up unto everlasting life." But
                            listen, for even now cometh the answer from the depths of the soul within. "Draw nigh unto
                            God and he will draw nigh unto you." Ho, every one who seeketh after Eternal Life, let fall
                            the bands which bind you to earth, to the one set rouud of thought and feeling whose bounds
                            are fixed, never to be encroached upon, whose theological tenets are securely packed away in
                            little bundles like patchwork, just so many of them, and never to be any more. Can it
                            satisfy a hungry man to know that his neighbor enjoyed a bountiful dinner, yesterday ? Nay
                            Christian friend and when you are weary with trying to raise an inspiration by imagining the
                            di. vine and heavenly afflatus with which the patriarchs were imbued, so many hundred years
                            ago, of Peter being led from prison at night, by an angel of the Lord, of the calm peace
                            which filled the breast of the beloved disciple John, of the emotions which thrilled the
                            soul of John the revelator, upon the lonely isle of Patmos, and the real living presence
                            within refuses to be satisfied by contemplating the spiritual feast of others, then stretch
                            out thy hand for thine own portion. Contrast the fullness of heavenly life they enjoyed,
                            with your own barrenness, and then realizing the spiritual poverty of your own soul, "Draw
                            nigh unto God, and he will draw nigh unto you." Reach out, with all the spirit power you are
                            capable of, for something higher, nobler, truer, than you already possess, and then
                            conscientiously live, no matter what the cost, up to the best of your light and
                            understanding, as fast as it is revealed to you, and daily stronger will grow the cords
                            which bind the soul to the one Infinite Central life, to Love, to God, whom "none but the
                            pure in heart shall see. '* Jesus of Nazareth, after his daily labor was past, went apart to
                            the mountains at night, to pray, that he might be filled with power to do his Father's will,
                            and did not the Father fill the empty cup to overflowing? Ann of Manchester, in prison
                            persecuted, prayed to see and know of the power to save, and found it. Go. thou who wouldst
                            obtain Eternal Life, knock at the windows of heaven, in the blessed assurance that they will
                            be opened unto you, to-day. Labor for the gift of God, to discern the "things of the spirit,
                            " and it will be given, and. when, in Time or Eternity, there comes to you a call to
                                follow<pb n="101" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>101 Christ in " spirit and in truth, " to live the life he
                            lived, and bear the cross he bore. Then " put off the old man with his deeds, " and become
                            joint heirs with Christ and Mother, rejoicing in the j spirit life which "hath set us free
                            from the law of Sin and Death." "Do the Shakers suppress Love?" asks the world. By no means,
                            honest inquirer and seeker after Truth, by no means. We seek to suppress the animal
                            passions, whose vile indulgence the risen Jesus affirms has no part nor lot in the life of
                            those who are in the resurrection, and against which, your true Shaker, recognizing in his
                            soul the voice of that God who is calling him to forsake tke earthly, generative order, with
                            all its kindred ties, its ambitions, and perishable fame, to receive the kingdom of heaven,
                            as a "little child." For Christ's sake, he may go forth, strong in the Lord, to labor in the
                            fields "already white with the harvest," and will never cease to wage relentless war, until
                            God *'giveth him the victory." Then, and then only, will Love, the gift of God to the
                            triumphant soul, the offspring of heavenly Purity, the dove of Peace, descend to make its
                            abiding place in the temple of his pure spirit. It will endow its possessor with that true
                            Christ-likeness, which, freed from the limitations of self, finds its chief pleasure in
                            strewing pearls of joy and happiness upon another's darkened pathway, ever seeking to uplift
                            and bless, willing to lay down life itself, that others may live, and grow, and expand in
                            the sunlight of God's truth. " Draw nigh unto God and he will draw nigh unto you." Ho, every
                            one who doth hunger and thirst after righteousness, the " Spirit and the Bride say come, let
                            him that heareth say, come, and let him who is athirst, come," draw nigh, and drink of that
                            everlasting fount of Life, whose name is Love. Thou Love Divine, from God come down,
                            Descend, thou Dove, from Mother's throne, Abide with me, and be my own ; My guide, my stay,
                            forever. My daily strength and comfort be, Until from Earth and Time set free, My soul in
                            peace shall walk with thee, Beside Life's crystal river. Watervliet, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Justification" TEIform="index"/> JUSTIFICATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Do your duty every day,- - Live to God the best you may,- - Yours shall be the earned pay Of
                            sweet justification. Cloudy days and nights will come, While the darkness makes them one;
                            Notwithstanding, you've a home In sweet justification. God would be no God to serve To the
                            tension of each nerve, If in Him was no reserve Of sweet justification. It is enough, the
                            earth will move, And only half is made of love, And what the metal yours, will prove To
                            bring justification. 'Tis all according to your light Obeyed or saddened, wrong and right
                            Kept in the Motto clear to sight Is your justification. 'Tis done, in honor let me stand,
                            The laboring oar is in my hand, And by its plying brings the Land Of rest and restoration.
                            All this in time, eternity May hold a greater joy for me, But what can Heaven really be But
                            sweet justification? Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obedience is better than many oblations" TEIform="index"/>Obedience is better than many oblations
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Obedience is better than many oblations.</p></div2><pb n="102" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel" TEIform="index"/> GOSPEL.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shepard, Arabella" TEIform="persName"/>ARABELLA SHEPARD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> "The gospel is pure, easy to be entreated, full of mercy and good fruits, without partiality
                            and without hypocrisy. " This short sentence of scripture language, speaks volumes. Who
                            would not be in possession of such a gospel? It is worth more than silver or gold, or all
                            that this earth can bestow. Whoever hath this gospel, and doth strictly live it, hath the
                            durable riches ; riches that never will fail to comfort or console under the most
                            complicated and severe tribulation that we could be called to pass through. It is the pearl
                            of great price, and will recommend itself to the mind under all circumstances. To become
                            possessor of this gospel, a thorough work of self-examination is necessary in order to expel
                            from the heart every evil propensity, and when impurities are re" moved, we shall be in the
                            way of cultivating and cherishing the heavenly and the Christian virtues which alone will
                            recommend us to a beau! if ul home beyond the scenes of time. North Union, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aid yourself and God will aid you" TEIform="index"/>AID YOURSELF AND GOD WILL AID YOU
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Walter, J. F." TEIform="persName"/>J. F. WALTER.</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> "Aid yourself, and God will aid you," Is a
                                    saying that I hold Should be written not in letters Wrought of silver or of gold,
                                    But upon our hearts be graven, A command from God in heaven, 'Tis the law of Him who
                                    made you- - Aid yourself and God will aid you. Aid yourself- -who will not labor All
                                    his wants of life to gain, But relies upon his neighbor, Finds that he relies in
                                    vain. Till you've done your utmost, never Ask a helping hand, nor ever Let the
                                    toilful man upbraid you- - Aid yourself and God will aid you. A d yourself- -you
                                    know the fable Of the wheel sunk in the road; How the carter was not able By his
                                    prayers to move the load, Till, urged by some more wise beholder, He move1 th- -
                                    wheel with lusty shuulder. Do your ovv work- -your Maker bade you- - Aid yourself
                                    *..u God will aid you. It is well to help a brother Of a sister when in need, But,
                                    believe me, there's another Not-to-be-forgotten creed. Better lore did never science
                                    Teach to man than self-reliance, 'Tis the law of Him who made you- - Aid yourself
                                    and God will aid you. Aid yourself, be not like ivy Clinging still to wall or tree,
                                    That can only rise by striving For support unceasingly. Rather be the oak,
                                    maintaining, Heart and branches self-sustaining; For this the " Great Task-master "
                                    made you. Aid yourself and God will aid you.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="The Moderator" TEIform="index"/>The Moderator</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signpost" TEIform="index"/>THE SIGNPOST
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">If you sit down at set of sun, And count the acts that you have
                                    done, And counting find One self-denying act, one word That eased the heart of him
                                    vrho heard; One glance most kind, That fell like sunshine where it went, Then you
                                    may count that day well spent. But if through all the livelong day, You've cheered
                                    no heart by yea or nay ; If through it all You've nothing done that you can trace,
                                    That brought the sunshine to one face; No act most small, That helped some soul, and
                                    nothing cost, Then count that day as worse than lost.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Youth's companion" TEIform="index"/>youth's Companion.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="103" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="music" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music of the spheres, no. 1" TEIform="index"/> THE MUSIC OF THE SPHERES. No. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> '; Soon as the evening shades prevail, The Moon takes up her wonderous tale, Arid nightly to
                            the listening earth, Repeats the" story of her birth. While all the stars that round her
                            burn, And all the planets as they turn, Proclaim the tidings as they roll, And spread the
                            truth from pole to pole. Ever singing as they shine, The hand that made us is Divine. "
                            Materialism is not constructive, it is a force to shake anything that can be shaken. In as
                            much as you have operated in the interest of truth and goodness you have done well. To all
                            who have so operated, we are to a certain extent indebted for the mental and personal
                            freedom we enjoy to-day. The order of human progress at present seems to be, that old
                            theologies have to be greatly broken up before much can be done in removing creeds!
                            limitations. Even then, a great work has to be done, before the material rights of all can
                            be secured. Under the pressure of new ideas and corresponding sentiments, modern
                            civilization is evidently near in g a crisis. To direct the forces inhering in this movement
                            aright, will be true statesmanship ; to oppose, or obstruct, is only to increase them and
                            render their action destructive. The Declaration of Independence, was as much as could be
                            done in 177(5. It has been charged with being a " glittering generality." Even the result of
                            the Great Rebellion did not meet that charge ; the emancipated being left destitute of land.
                            The corner stone of modern civilization is the monopoly of land ; rendering all who have no
                            land " Commodities." Forcing the landless into the labor market, and subjecting them to the
                            "Law of supply and demand." Another "Declaration"' is needed, declaring that every person
                            shall have access to all the elements by which life is sustained, without money or price. To
                            say that he or she, has an inalienable right to the pursuit of happiness, and shall have
                            access to all the air, sunlight, and rain that comes ; but cannot get an inch of land except
                            at somebody's price ; is to make those who cannot buy, servants, slaves, commodities ! Land
                            being the source of human sustenance, of social and judicial equality, and a regulator of
                            the exchanges of commercial equivalents ; they who have no land, have in reality no social
                            nor judicial standing. They cannot even regulate the value of their own labor, the food
                            supply being in the hands of others. Therefore, modern civilization in this light, "is the
                            sum of all villanies." It brought forth Southern slavery, the pauperism of wages, and the
                            millionaire. Standing armies, and a vast net work of debts ; which, with the interest
                            thereon, are of themselves huge villanies. They burden the poor to oppression ; corrupt
                            public morals with the presence of luxurious idlers, and with hungry multitudes "funding in
                            the marts of labor. The troubles in Ireland a.;d elsewhere have arisen, because the millions
                            are at the will of those who hold the land; These troubles are a presage of the coming
                            crisis, and of the manner in which it will be met. The relation of Landlord and Tenant, is
                            one of the forms of human vassalage; is illogical with the idea of a Republic, and also with
                            human equality.<pb n="104" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>The foundations of all just governments, will ever rest
                            ou a just apportionment of land. Morality rests there, and no where else. Where land is held
                            by a few families, or vast tracts by corporations, they will make the laws, and execute them
                            in their own favor, irrespective of all considerations. Here Rationalism and Justice, is a
                            needed Force. Morality grows out of the fact that every human being has a distinct
                            personality, and a sphere of rights, as extensive, and as well secured as are those of any
                            other personality. Therefore, if one man has a right to land, all men have. Morality is
                            justice. Religion is not theology, it is goodness- -doing something whereby the neighbor is
                            benefited. Modern civilization organically, has neither morality nor religion ; there being
                            in it no foundation for either. Hence, some of the attacks on what is called religion, may
                            be accepted as public services. The ruling classes are the veriest materialists- -they hold
                            land to the exclusion of their equals by material force; if a hungry family takes from their
                            stores, they inflict material punishment, and send the spirit of the thief to an impossible
                            material hell. In the degree that a materialist does good, he is religious. Materialism
                            however is a negation, has ignorance for its foundation, not knowledge. The identification
                            of even one disembodied spirit upsets it. This has been done to the entire satisfaction of
                            some most honorable men. The Personality of God- -the Creator, Is as well established, as is
                            our own personality. What is personality? that is the question. If we affirm, that we are
                            personalities, the Personality of God, is also established. On this important subject, we
                            need not hurry up conclusions ; eternity is now ! Let us walk among created things, and
                            learn the lessons they impart, bearing in mind that inorganic Nature, never reasons, cannot
                            think, 'has no inventive creative ability; cannot create a state of things like itself, nor
                            control its own conditions. Living things claim our notice ; the smallest plant and the
                            loftiest cedar, have they not each a distinct identity ? And do not all the plants, fruits
                            and flowers, in beauty and usefulness grow harmoniously together through the ages, and
                            maintain their individuality entire? And are they not all commissioned to control inorganic
                            Nature? And does not each plant do so in its own peculiar way ? And for its own special
                            purpose ? Is not every plant a chemist, working out wonderously, not only a definite
                            thought, but a combination of them for an express and definite end? One grows on the naked
                            rock, assimilates a little sunshine, a little air, and a little moisture ; it grows,
                            thrives, matures and dies, and decomposes a little ol the rock on which it grew. Another, a
                            more elaborate worker, strikes its roots into the new formed soil, and yields food for man.
                            What a profusion of beautiful and useful products lie around us ! There is the spotless
                            lily, emblem of purity, innocence and peace. And is not its sweet perfume figurative of the
                            aroma of Divine goodness? Grace is spiritual aroma. Does this perfume not also show, that
                            its Creator has a knowledge of, and an ability to manipulate the delicate affinity of
                            chemical action ? Every flower and sweet smelling leaf, have not the odor of the<pb n="105" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> lily : noticeable variations abound. The same conditions which developed the
                            lily, develops the blackberry. Why is it not a lily? Inventive ability in man shows itself
                            in many ways ; so in the handiwork of the Creator. With equal pertinence we inquire why are
                            a pair of scissors not an apple-par er? The answer is, the plants- and these tools are
                            expressions of thought intelligently exercised, causing each to answer a definite purpose.
                            The thoughts are essentially alike, although the one transcends the other. One is human
                            thought and will, causing iron to assume certain forms for certain purposes The other,
                            Divine thought and will, creates living, chemical organisms capable of building themselves
                            up by manipulating and appropriating the inorganic elements ; fulfilling thereby the designs
                            of their Maker. If we would save om selves from confusion of thought, we must come to the
                            conclusion that each plant is a creation of thought, and part of a great pla^ for the
                            support and happiness of animated creatures. To grant personality to the maker of the tools,
                            and deny personality to the Maker of the plants, is not reasonable. We now come to a
                            consideration of the order of the fruits in relation to human wants. There is the fragrant
                            strawberry sheltered by the wintry snows, when they melt away, a few warm showers and
                            pleasant sunshines, and this lowly and pre-eminent berry comes forth and heads the list of
                            refreshing fruits. The delightful raspberries of various kinds, colors, and times of
                            ripening follow, succeeded by the blue berries from the rocky uplands, and by the salubrious
                            blackberry, whose very thorns are beneficent, without them probably it would have been
                            extinct. The shining cherry pleasantly introduces itself among the berries and points to the
                            larger fruits. The noble apple, the acceptable pear, the delicious peach, combining in
                            themselves refreshment and nutriment. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. (TO BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, ME, no. 5" TEIform="index"/> ALFRED, ME, No. 5.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Otis" TEIform="persName"/>BY ELDER OTIS SAWYER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Origin of the Shakers in Maine. New Light Baptists, called Merry Dancers Gome-outers, etc.
                            Many manifestations of divine power attended the preaching of the gospel. Prophecies, gifts
                            of healing, and remarkable signs, as evidences of the work, which were, no doubt, intended
                            to confirm the people, in their faith. William Nason was a very upright and conscientious
                            man. Like the prophets of old he felt called to warn the people to keep the fear of God. He
                            marched around Massabesic Lake, in the road, a distance of some four miles. His message
                            which he repeated at intervals, was, "Woe, woe to the inhabitants of the earth. Touch not my
                            anointed and do my good prophets no harm. " Although scattered at some distance from each
                            other, in private families, they were quite punctual in their attendance at public service,
                            and in these seasons they found the most spiritual power, so necessary for their prosperity
                            and protection. These services often continued till ten and eleven o'clock at night. A few
                            hours were then allowed for rest and sleep. In the morning another service began at four
                            o'clock and continued for an hour when the people were dismissed for the day, to attend to
                            their temporal business. These protracted meetings continued only during the visit of the
                            ministers from New Lebanon, and this was thought to be necessary in order to stand against
                            the powers of evil, the spirit of opposition and persecution which was their daily portion.
                            It was not uncommon at an early hour of the morning when they were not engaged in religious
                            service, for one brother to salute<pb n="106" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/>his near neighbor with,- -"More love
                            brother David, " and then for this person to reply "More love brother William.'" A more
                            distant neighbor would hear the sound and repeat the watchword, ''More love," until for a
                            long distance the air was made vocal by the sons of God shouting for joy, the angelic
                            salutation which served as a bond of union and peace, like the cry of the watchmen in
                            ancient cities. " All is well." but more in harmony with the voice of the angels at the
                            birth of Jesus, "Peace on earth, good will to man." The Society at Alfred, Me., was
                            organized in March, 1793, under the charge of Father John Barnes of Alfred, Elder Robert Me.
                            Farland of Gorham, Me. Mother Sarah Kendall and Eldress Lucy Prescott, both of Harvard,
                            Mass. The Sisters rode from Harvard to Alfred in the saddle, and this was almost the
                            universal mode of travel at this date. The Society of Harvard made the Sisters a present of
                            the horses, saddles and bridles. These were the first Shaker Sisters that visited the State
                            of Maine from the west. In 1792 timber was cut for a more commodious "Meeting House, which
                            was built after the pattern of the one at New Lebanon. This house was finished at the close
                            of the year 1794. We here copy, verbatim, the oldest piece of writing extant, sent to us
                            from New Lebanon. This refers to the building of a house for religious purposes, and was
                            passed to Father John in 1791. "When the gift and order of God, to build the house to meet
                            in for the public worship of God, in this place was publicly made known to us, the
                            conditions were as follows; 1st. That it should be built by free contributions. None were
                            desired to give anything towards the building, but such as could do it freely, as a matter
                            of their own faith, and never after bring any one into debt or blame on account of what they
                            had done. They need make no excuses of being in debt or in poverty, as God required no more
                            of them than what they were able to do, according to justice. 2nd. That it should be done by
                            a joint union and agreement with each other. 3rd. As the house is for religious and not for
                            common use, none might hold a right of government in the house, by virtue of what they had
                            done, but by Church order the property being changed from a private to a public use, is
                            consecrated to the Lord. It is the privilege of all that believe and are holden in union,
                            according to their opportunity, to assemble in, one day in seven, for the publie worship of
                            God. Any further privilege to the use of the house must be by order, as the good of the
                            Church and Society may require." The above was received from Father James Whittaker, and was
                            the Covenant by which the house of worship was built in New Lebanon. Father Joseph Meacham
                            then writes, " If you as a people believe it to be j^our duty to build a house to meet in as
                            you have signified, you have liberty, according to the same order and covenant. " A great
                            many visitors called to see the Believers, as inquirers, and at such times shaved their
                            generous hospitality. Sometimes their stock of provisions would run quite low, when a system
                            of rigid economy would have to be practiced. Potatoes, salt meat and brown bread were staple
                            articles. Milk, cheese and butter were sometimes added, but these were used more as
                            luxuries. On this fare they thankfully gave their hands to work and their hearts to God,
                            that they might lay the foundation for a united inheritance. If there was a select spot of
                            ground that was considered holy in ancient times, then sacred and thrice hallowed is this
                            consecrated soil upon which our feet should lightly tread. Sacred is each dwelling and upon
                            the lintel of each door, let noliness be engraven. Trustees \vere appointed to take charge
                            of the property and Gowen Wilson and Jonathan Nowell were called to this office. Members of
                            the Society that lived at a distance either sold or exchanged their farms and moved into
                            their new home. Nathan Freeman, Joshua Harding, Josiah and Aaron Whitney, also Barbara Brown
                            came from Gorham. Gowen Wilson brought his family and most of his property from West
                            Gloucester. Eliphaz Ring owned property in Poland, where Hiram Ricker now lives(1884) and
                            where the celebrated mineral springs are situated. Eliphaz made an exchange of prop-<pb n="107" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>erty with Jabez Ring, and by this the Believers obtained their
                            excellent water privilege and mills. This was a valuable acquisition. The new meeting house
                            being finished the Ministry soon moved into it. They found it much more convenient than the
                            former one and furnished with so many rooms that it not only could accommodate their own
                            order but could be the home of the Ministry when such chanced to come from New Lebanon, or
                            from other Societies. Mother Lucy Wright, in her visit to the Societies in Maine, in 1803
                            made this house her home during her sojourn. The other members of the order at this date
                            were Elder Abiathar Babbitt Stephen Markham and Eldress Euth Langdon. After closing their
                            visit at Alfred, they returned directly to New Lebanon. Mother Lucy again visited Alfred in
                            1810 and occupied as at a former date, the upper rooms in the Meeting House. A dwelling
                            house for the family was raised in 1794 and finished in 1795 and on the 3rd day of January
                            1796 (Sabbath day) the family moved into it. Elders were also appointed at the time of the
                            organization of the Society. David Barnes, John Cotton, Sarah Barnes and Dana Thombs. The
                            Society was now duly provided with directors in accordance with the or der of the gospel.
                            After providing a Meet ing House, and dwelling for the family, i was their next object to
                            build some workshops, suitable for the Brethren and Sisters. As the Sisters manufactured
                            their own cloth they occupied several rooms with their spinning wheels and looms. It was not
                            uncommon for Sisters to work late into the night, carding and spinning both cotton and wool.
                            Flax was raised every year and manufactured into cloth for shirts, sheets and pillowThe
                            sister's shop that was built in 1796 underwent a thorough repairing in 1872. The interior of
                            the building was changed to meet the demand of today. The exterior was also changed, then
                            painted white and trimmed with green blinds The Meeting House of 1786 was used for many
                            years as a workshop, where the brethren manufactured a great many tubs, pails, churns and
                            also linen and woolen wheels. Other buildings have been raised as need required so that
                            ample accommodations have been provided for the several branches of business. ( The End. )
                            cases, and they would, at times display their skill in making beautiful kerchiefs of fine
                            linen. Some of these were white with blue borders and others checked, blue and white. The
                            cotton was bought of merchants in Portland and manufactured into cloth. After the
                            introduction of machinery in Rhode Island for the making of cotton yarn, the merchants of
                            Portland would supply the Society with the yarn which the Sisters would weave into cloth and
                            were paid a certain price per yard.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pious pretensions" TEIform="index"/> PIOUS PRETENSIONS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Washburn, L. K." TEIform="persName"/>L. K. WASHBURN.</byline><p TEIform="p">The distinguishing characteristic of the religion of to-day is pretension. The mightiest work
                            of the Church is to make men and women profess religion. Belief is exalted above character,
                            and moral men are told that God does not care for them. The most prominent preacher before
                            the world to-day said, in a recent discourse, "To believe in Jesus is a)l the religion we
                            need;" and, we are sorry to say, that a great many people agree with him, for it is all the
                            religion they have,. The popular motto of piety is: " Where Christianity is religion, 'tis
                            folly to be moral; " and so hypocrisy takes a front seat in the temple of Pretension, and
                            the man who cheats his neighbor and believes in Jesus is invited to lead the meeting in
                            prayer. Professional piety has done little more than make up a pious face. Its articles of
                            belief outnumber its good deeds. ' There is a great deal said about following Jesus, but we
                            only hear about these followers, we never see one. Where is the man that follows the
                            commands or the footsteps of Jesus? Jesus said, "Sell what thou hast and give to the poor. "
                            Who heeds the command? Do people know what sort of a man this Jesus was whose name they take
                            so piously on their lips? He was a friend of publicans and sinners. He was a companion of
                            the )oor and lowly. He worked to help those whom the world despised and forsook. He<pb n="108" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> associated with men who broke the Sabbath law. Do people know what
                            persons Jesus praised for their piety? The Samaritan, hated and scorned by the Jew. The
                            Publican, whom the Pharisee would not touch lest he be contaminated. The poor widow, who
                            brought two mites to the treasury of her Lord. Do people know what Jesus taught? He did not
                            preach the God of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob, but the God of the grass, the lily, and the
                            sparrow. He did not say, Do as Moses told you to do ; but, " Why judge ye not of yourselves
                            what is right?" He did not say, They shall have eternal life who call me Lord, Lord! but, "
                            They who do the will of my Father in Heaven. " Where is the minister who pretends to be a
                            disciple of this Nazarene preacher? Who is doing what Jesus did? Who is commending the kind
                            of persons that Jesus made models of piety? Who is preaching the God of nature's beauty and
                            life? He is not to be found in a Christian pulpit in the United States. Where is the man who
                            professes to be a follower of Jesus, who is following him? If men do not honor this man,
                            then let them stop pretending to honor him. If they do honor him let them do as he did; let
                            them teach as he taught; let them live as he lived; but I do not hesitate to declare that
                            there cannot be found in a single church in Christendom one person who honors Jesus enough
                            to imitate his life. I raise no question now of the virtue of following Jesus, or of living
                            as he lived. With that we are not at present concerned. I merely assert that people who call
                            themselves Christians care nothing for the man whom they call Christ, and that the religion
                            of these people is only pious pretension. Let men stop putting on religion, stop wearing it.
                            To carry a cross upon the breast is no surety that the heart that beats beneath it is pure
                            and holy.- -The New Age. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to be miserable" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO BE MISERABLE
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by <persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery.]</byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Sit at the window, and look over the way at your neighbor's
                                    excellent mansion which he has recently built, and paid for, and sigh out, "Oh that
                                    I were a rich man." Get angry with your neighbor, and think that you have not a
                                    friend in the world. Shed a tear or two ; take a walk in the burial ground,
                                    continually saying to yourself "when shall I be buried here?" Sign a note with a
                                    friend, and never forget your kindness ; and, every hour in the day whisper to
                                    yourself, '' I wonder if he will pay that note !" Think everybody means to cheat
                                    you. Closely scrutinize every bill you take, and doubt its being genuine till you
                                    have put the owner to a great deal of trouble. Believe every dime passed on you is
                                    but a sixpence, crossed and express your doubts about getting rid of it, if you take
                                    it. Never accommodate, ifyou can help it. Never visit the sick and afflicted, and
                                    never give a farthing to the poor. Grind the faces of the poor and unfortunate.
                                    Brood over your misfortunes, your lack of talent, and believe, that at no distant
                                    day, you will come to want. Let the poor house ever be in your mind, with all the
                                    horrors of poverty and distress ; then you will be miserable, if we may so speak, to
                                    your heart's content; sick at heart, and, at variance with all the world.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health maxims" TEIform="index"/> HEALTH MAXIMS.</head><p TEIform="p">Take the open air, The more you take the better; Follow nature's laws To the very letter. Eat
                            the simplest food, Drink of pure, cold water, Then you will be well, Or at least you ought
                            to. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anonymous" TEIform="persName"/>Anonymous.</byline></div2><pb n="109" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ever near" TEIform="index"/> EVER NEAR.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lewis" TEIform="persName"/>LEWIS HORTON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> When the shadows darkly gather, O'er tht toiling rugged way, Lo ! bright angels from the
                            Father, Turns the night to brightest day. When the storms of life are falling, And the path
                            seems long or drear, Then a voice in spirit calling, Whispers softly, "I am near. " Sing my
                            soul, O ! sing forever. Of the joys they bring to me, Earth with all its glory, never Can
                            outshine their sympathy. Thus for all that comes I render Thanks, to him who knoweth best,
                            Storms or shadows, clouds or splendor, All a loving God hath blest. Canterbury, N. H</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Patient with the living" TEIform="index"/>PATIENT WITH THE LIVING
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sangster, Margaret E." TEIform="persName"/>MARGARET E. SANGSTER.
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Sweet friend, when thou and I are
                                    gone Beyond earth's weary labor, When small shall be our need of grace From comrade
                                    or from neighbor, Passed all the strife, the toil, the care, And done with all the
                                    sighing, What tender ruth shall we have gained Alas, by simply dying! Then lips too
                                    chary of their praise, Will tell our merits over, And eyes too swift our faults to
                                    see, Shall no defect discover. Then hands that would not lift a stone Where stones
                                    were thick to cumber Our steep hill-path, will scatter flowers Above our pillowed
                                    slumber. Sweet friend, perchance both thou and I, Ere love is past forgiving, Should
                                    take the earnest lesson home,- - Be patient with the living; To-day's repressed
                                    rebuke may save Our blinding tears to-morrow;- - Then patience,- -e'en when keenest
                                    edge May whet a nameless sorrow. 'Tis easy to be gentle when Death's silence shames
                                    our clamor, And easy to discern the best Through memory's mystic glamour; But wise
                                    it were for thee and me, Ere love is past forgiving, To take the tender lesson
                                    home,- - Be patient with the living. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Good cheer" TEIform="index"/>Good Cheer.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reasons for supporting the Manifesto" TEIform="index"/> Reasons for supporting the MANIFESTO.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT.</byline><p TEIform="p">Much credit is due the Editor ami Publisher for the able manner in which they have conducted
                            our Journal, the past year, in giving us a new and improved edition of that excellent work.
                            I have been much edified in reading the biographical sketches of some of the first founders
                            of Shakerism. I always feel the wiser and better for having read them. Likewise, the
                            Pictures of "Our Homes," in Enfield. N. H. and South Union, and Pleasant Hill, in Ky. They
                            are delightful to look upon. Likewise those in Alfred, and New Gloucester, in the State of
                            Maine. I consider them all model examples, of ''Rural Homes, " in the world. May God bless
                            the inmates thereof, and increase their numbers, from the rising to the setting sun. 1.
                            Because, It is the best moral reform paper published, and as such, is worthy of universal
                            patronage. 2. Because, It contains original articles, from some of the best writers, among
                            Believers, of both sexes, on Theology etc. 3. Because, The music on the last page, is worth
                            more than the subscription price of the paper. North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother is love and charity to the penitent" TEIform="index"/>Mother is love and charity to the penitent
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Mother is love and charity to the penitent </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H." TEIform="persName"/>H. H.</byline></div2><pb n="111" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="shaker report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Busro, no. 1" TEIform="index"/> BUSRO, NO. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="McClelland, Samuel S." TEIform="persName"/>SAMUEL S. MCCLELLAND.</byline><p TEIform="p"> On the first Sabbath in Aug. 1805, a camp meeting was held in Dunlavy's congregation, un
                            Eagle Creek, Adams Co., Ohio. Elder Benjamin S. Youngs and Elder Issachar Bates went from
                            Turtle Creek, Warren Co., in the - -ame state to attend the meeting. As both of the Brethren
                            were preachers of the word of God, they were invited to speak. The word was received into
                            honest hearts, and the Rev. John Dunlavy was one of the first that accepted it. In May 1810
                            a proposition was made to form settlements at Turtle Creek, Ohio, Shawnce Run. Ky. and at
                            Busro, Ind. In June George Lagier and Wm. Gallagher were appointed to go to the Wabash
                            country to select a place for settlement. They called at the house of Robert Gill, Robert
                            Houston and Joseph Worthington. It was finally decided to form a society at Busro Creek,
                            which report gave general satisfaction. From Eagle Creek, Ohio to Busro, Ind. is about 300
                            miles. A company of Brethren had been selected to drive the cattle and sheep, and to mow the
                            prairie grass for their winter forage. All the estate at Eagle Creek was sold in 1810 and
                            early in the winter of 1811 they made preparations for the journey, as will be seen by the
                            following memorandum of events, as written by Samuel S. McClelland. During the month of
                            January the Brethren had obtained two boats and brought them to Red Oak, in Mayville where
                            they were to be held in readiness for the reception of the property. A large part of
                            February was spent in making preparations for thejourney. Many of the household articles
                            that could not be conveniently taken to Busro were sold at auction, while the others were
                            packed and taken, to the boats, a distance of ten miles. On the 4th of March the two boate,
                            one with a keel and the other flat bottomed set sail for the Wabash. At Jeffersonville the
                            boats were unloaded and the wagons set up. The horses were taken to this place by land. On
                            the 9th three wagons with seven families left Jeffersonville for Bu- -ro, a distance of 120
                            miles, where they arrived on the 16th. The boats now passed on to the moutb of the Wabash,
                            when the keel boat received all that was in the flat boat, except a pair of mil' stones.
                            These were left on the bank and afterwards sold. The keel boat now passed on to the mouth of
                            Busro Creek, and reached that place the 29th. But few notes were kept of the journey of this
                            first company, so that we shall now refer to the one that left Eagle Creek oc the 20th of
                            March. Eldress Ruth Darrow, Saloma Dennis, James Price and Samuel S. McClelland left Union
                            Village for Cincinnati in order to meet the second company, that were to make the journey in
                            the boats. Of this trip to Red Oak Creek, Samuel writes: We reached Cincinnati in the
                            evening and put up at the Columbian Inn. The next morning all went on board the boats at
                            eight o'clock, but did not leave the place till quite late in the afternoon. At night we
                            landed on the Kentucky shore just below the mouth of the big Miami. Before leaving
                            Cincinnati we found it necessary to purchase another boat for transportation of our stores.
                            Mar. 23. We set sail early in the morning but the day was very unpleasant. At night we
                            landed on the Indiana shore, and the Sisters, with a few of the feeble Brethren found
                            accommodations in a house. This was a fearful night. The thunder and lightning was dreadful
                            while the rain was poured down upon us. Before morning the river had risen full eight feet.
                            Mar. 24. Sabbath. We sailed at eight, A. M. with fair wind, but at ten A. M. while passing a
                            great bend in the river the wind drove us violently against the Kentucky shore ind we were
                            obliged to remain here till the next morning. Mar. 25. We sailed at six A. M. At one 3'clock
                            P. M. we passed the mouth of the Kentucky river, and went on thirty miles to i small creek
                            on the Kentucky shore. The lay had been very pleasant and we rested comfortably at night.
                            Mar. 26. We sailed at six A. M. and at two ?. M. landed at Jeffersonville where we renained
                            about two hours. We then passed &gt;ver the falls and went on shore. The rain nade our
                            night very uncomfortable.THE MANIFESTO. Ill Mar. 27. Eldress Ruth Darrow, Saloma Dennis,
                            James Hodge and William Price took a carriage at Jeffersonville for Busro and arrived at
                            that place on the 30th. Our hoats were lowered to Silver Creek. The goods were now unloaded
                            and taken three miles up the Creek in a pirogue to a place where the wagon, had been
                            stationed. Mar. 28. We were still employed boating the property to the landing. On returning
                            with our last load, night came upon us. It was cloudy and dark, and we learned to our sorrow
                            that we were lost among the drift wood, and finally grounded in a field where we were
                            obliged to leave our boat and make the best of our way through the water, mud, logs and
                            brush to our camp at the mouth of the Creek. Mar. 29. We found our boats in the field some
                            distance from the Creek. The water had fallen rapidly during the night so that we were
                            obliged to haul them off All of our plunder was now placed in our four boats and we pushed
                            off at nine A. M. The boats were lashed together and floated along very pleasantly. We
                            passed the mouth of Salt River at two P. M. and made arrangements to sail all night. At
                            three o'clock on the morning of the 30th we struck an island and were obliged to cut
                            thTTTsrshing of our boats. They immediately parted and could not be secured again til] after
                            sunrise. Mar. 30. We floated along pleasantly all day and landed for the night seven miles
                            above the Yellow Bank. Mar. 31. Sabbath. We sailed till eleven A. M. when the wind blew so
                            violently that we were obliged to land. We remained here the balance of the day and through
                            the night. Apr. 1. The wind is still blowing. However, we pushed off and passed the mouth of
                            Green River. At two P. M. the wind ceased, the river became calm and we had a fine day. We
                            passed the Red Banks and landed for the night near Diamond Island. Apr. 2. Floated without
                            interruption till two P. M. when we landed about half a mile above the mouth of the Wabash.
                            We remained here till the next morning. Apr. 3. A company of able bodied men met us at this
                            place. They had made the journey from Busro in three days. Apr. 4. We loaded our small
                            boats, made some oars and after due preparations began ascending the Wabash for Busro. It
                            was three P. M. when we set sail, and we had made only nine miles when we encamped for the
                            night on the Bone Bank. Apr. 5, and G. We moved up the river about twelve miles. On the
                            night of the 6th we had heavy thunder showers. Apr. 7. All wet this morning. We sailed
                            twelve miles and about the same each day till the 14th. Apr. 14. Sabbath. Passed Coffee
                            Island and encamped on the west bank of the Wabash opposite the mouth of White River. Apr.
                            15. Passed the grand rapids, sailed fourteen miles and then encamped near the Dochee River.
                            Apr 17. We landed at Vincennes at three P. M. and aftei rr sting an hour we sailed four
                            miles and then encamped for the night. Apr. 18. We reached the landing at Busro at four
                            o'clock P. M This was our last stopping place and our last encampment Apr 19. The boat and
                            rafts were unloaded and the goods taken to the settlement, a distance of six miles. The
                            Eagle Creek and Busro people were now united in one community. The larger number were
                            accommodated at the house of Robert Gill, and this was considered the central family of the
                            Society. Four miles N. E. was another family called the Upper settlement. About three miles
                            west were the families of Robert Houston. Joseph Worthington and others ami this was called
                            the Lower Settlement. Most of the Brethren were engaged in the business of the farm. One
                            hundred and fifty acres were under cultivation, the management being given to George Lagier.
                            The central family contained seventy two members, and the whole Society three hundred. The
                            first house that was built after the Society was formed was of hewn logs and contained ftrar
                            rooms. This was finished in the month of June and gave good satisfaction. One death occurred
                            from fever June 17, Anthony Fam. Age 35 years which was attributed to the low, wet lands. At
                            the same time several persons were confined to the house with the same disease but no more
                            deaths are recorded for this year.<pb n="112" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> In July Gov. Harrison appointed a
                            meeting at Vincennes and made a treaty with the Indians but it amounted to but little good
                            as the red men went away as ill humored as they came. A company of rangers followed to see
                            them safe out of the settlement. (To BE CONTINUED.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Purity" TEIform="index"/> PURITY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danford, Nancy G." TEIform="persName"/>NANCY G. DANFORD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> " Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God." Here seems to be a peculiar
                            blessing for those who keep themselves unspotted from the world ; therefore it is of great
                            importance that we know what is meant by being pure at heart. When we speak of pure gold or
                            pure water it is easily understood what is meant; but a pure heart who can know how to
                            obtain the treasure to which so great a blessing is promised, "They shall see God." Gold is
                            not pure in the ore, but liar to be heated and smelted, repeatedly, until the refiner can
                            pronounce it pure. How can we purify the heart the very seat of lifetime and affections.? We
                            know that all our natural tendencies are toward the earth ; then how can we rise to a state
                            of purity, but by a refining process, and how shall we find the furnace? The Lord hath said
                            by the mouth of his Prophet, ''1 will place my fire in Zion, and my furnace in Jerusalem."
                            The Savior says, i-I came to bring fire on earth, and what will I if it be already kindled."
                            It is not a fire to consume the outward world, but the testimony of eternal truth, planted
                            in the soul like a consuming fire to all evil desires a::d appetites ; the baptism of the
                            Holy Spirit and fire with which our Savior was baptized, and through which every soul must
                            pass again and again until wholly purified from a fallen and corrupt nature or forever be
                            debarred from that City whose streets are paved with gold, so pure that it is as " clear as
                            crystal'' for nothing can enter there that defileth noteven one thought or imagination, all
                            must be pure and clean. Therefore, saith the Savior, " Straight is the gate and narrow is
                            the way that leadeth unto life," to eternal life, so very straight it will not even admit
                            the appearance of evil ; nought but the humble soul clothed with the garments of holiness,
                            by living the life of Christ, walking even as he walked without sin and blameless before the
                            throne of God, then will souls be accepted when they reflect the image of the refiner while
                            hi the crucible, or furnace ; for he says, '' I have chosen you in the furnace of
                            affliction." But we have all sinned and what can we all do to become pure? It is written,
                            "If we confess our sins He is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse as
                            from all unrighteousness. " Here, we are shown the way ; it is by confession to cancel the
                            sin, and then by a true repentance and forsaking of sin in deep humility, to wash the stains
                            from the soul, thus make it clean and white, then seek, devotedly, to clothe it with all the
                            graces and beautie? of that lovely character, Christ our exampler. Canterbury, N. H. Faith
                            in God is to learn his problems by going and doing them; not trying to understand them
                            first, or doing any thing else whatever with them first, than obeying them. - George
                            Macdonald.</p></div2><pb n="113" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>LETTER BOX</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Children; Work out your own..." TEIform="index"/>Dear Children; Work out your own...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Connecticut, Enfield, April 1885" TEIform="index"/> Enfield, Conn. Apr. 1885.</dateline><p TEIform="p">Dear Children ;- -''Work out your own salvation. " Begin now. While you wait for that
                                which may never come, precious opportunities are passing away forever. You have no right
                                to waste a moaient. Wastefulness oftime is a sin. " Time enough is little enough. "
                                Press on for the crown awaiting the faithful. The present well improved is the best
                                preparation for the future. Time is short. Improve your portion small. It is the little
                                moments wisely used, the little duties well performed, that make up the sum of a
                                virtuous life. Little by little your work is done; step by step, the crown won. Purity
                                insures a crown worth wearing. What though temptations assail? How shall you know your
                                strength but for them? " It is the Lord who girdeth with strength unto the battle. " Be
                                strong in Him. Your days are golden now. Be wetchful. Constant watchfulness is the price
                                of salvation. " Make your calling and election sure.'' Not only to be called, but to be
                                Christians. It is what you are that will make you valuable. It is not how long, but how
                                well you live. " Since earthly joy abideth never, work for the joy that lasts forever. "
                                Work ! Thanking God who gives you the strength and the opportunity. '; Work, for I am
                                with you saith the Lord of hosts. " Your Brother, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear little sister Emma Bell; Four years ago on a..." TEIform="index"/>
                                My dear little sister Emma Bell; Four years ago on a...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, 1885" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. 1885.</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Dear Little Sister Emma Bell;- - Four years ago on a bright October day a little girl
                                was brought here by her father to claim a place as your sister. Now, you have gone from
                                home. Although she has a great many more sisters, yet she misses her own little Emma
                                Bell and prays every evening that no harm may come to her, but that she may return again
                                safely. Do you know who this little girl was or is? Well, I have never regretted the day
                                nor the working of the good spirit that put it into the mind of my dear father to
                                provide me with such a good home and so many dear little sisters to love, and who, I am
                                sure, love me in return. Then the dear, dearer and dearest friends, who are each day
                                caring not only for all my physical wants but the wants of my soul as well. Just think,
                                Emma, you and I will some day be women and what place in our home do you think we can
                                fill? I am studying music a little and would like to be a music teacher, would not you?
                                I have been sewing during the past week. Sometimes I have changed this work to help the
                                sisters assort the winter apples, and once or twice have assisted Sister Sarah Frances
                                and others. AVe have set out the tulip bulbs that will bloom this Spring. These are the
                                first flowers that bloom after Winter, as you know, and I think they get more notice
                                than any other flower, because they are the first. As I look from my window I see some
                                very pretty trees. In one or two places, they are so placed that they look very much
                                like bouquets of flowers. Would you not like to see this pretty picture? Please accept
                                the love of sisters Mabel, Josephine and my dear teacher Helen for Sister Dorothea, Mary
                                Ellen and yourself, also my kindest love. Your Little Sister, Lizzie Horton. Age, 13
                                yrs. Emma B. King,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Horton, Lizzie" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Moved by the duty..." TEIform="index"/>Moved by the duty...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Moved by duty, is the prompting Near akin to Christ, the way ; Not for any worldly honor But
                            for virtue we obey. All that's fitful flees before us Till the solid track we find ; Here
                            established, ever glorious Is the well contented mind.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judge none lost..." TEIform="index"/>Judge none lost...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Judge none lost; but wait and see With hopeful pity, not disdain : The depth of the abyss
                            may be The measure of the height of pain, And love and glory that may raise This soul to God
                            in after days. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Procter, Adelaide" TEIform="persName"/>Adelaide Procter.</byline></div2><pb n="114" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes" TEIform="index"/>NOTES </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Editor]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The mission of the Manifesto in its testimonies of truth, in its messages of love and in its
                            hymns of praise, is from month to month,- -'" Peace on earth, good will to man." Inasmuch as
                            it i- able to bear the impress of the spirit of our Divine Teacher, it may meet the
                            anticipations of those who believe that the love of God is most potent in its ministrations
                            for peace and righteousness. All that is good should be sacredly preserved while all that is
                            evil should be consumed. In whatever we may do whether teuding directly to the building up
                            of the new Heavens or the new Earth, or entering the warfare with the Apostle against the
                            powers of darkness, or the spirit of wickedness that dwells in heavenly places, we shall
                            entertain fully and freely the spirit of divine truth, believing as Jesus has said, w' The
                            truth shall make you free. " To obtain this freedom, this inestimable treasure, and to be
                            able to assist other souls in securing the same godly prize, is of itself an assurance of
                            peace and happiness. Nothing contributes so largely to the individual, spiritual prosperity,
                            to that quality of the mind that forms a Kingdom of God upon the earth, as interested
                            prayers and active work. As soldiers of the cross of Christ we should put on the whole armor
                            of God and look forward to the time when we shall be found among the victorious, " having
                            fought the good fight and kept the faith. " In teaching, the testimony of Jesus was very
                            simple, his yea was yea and his nay, nay. It was not hard to comprehend. " He that forsaketh
                            not all that he hath, cannot be my disciple. " This was the test of Christian discipline and
                            comes in that form of truth which is to make us free, as children of our Heavenly Father.
                            With forms of godliness and a blind superstition that has found its way into the religious
                            world and fortified themselves behind creeds and churchal dogmas, we can have but little
                            sympathy. Where selfishness rules, there rules, at the same time, a dominant spirit and the
                            growth of this worldly element is a rapid development in every evil work. Jesus actively
                            preached the spirit of universal love and good will for all the creation of God. Even the
                            sparrows were worthy of a special notice of tender care, while the disciples who were so
                            privileged as to share his gospel exhortations, he said,- -''Are ye not of more value than
                            many sparrows?" If God has a loving care for the creatures that perish, most certainly He
                            will have a deeper regard for those that are worthy of eternal life. This led Jesus to
                            advise his disciples to this end.- - '- -Lay not up for yourselves treasures upon earth
                            where moth and rust doth corrupt and where thieves break through and steal. " An admonition
                            filled with an interested love for the children of God. The better way is to lay up our
                            treasures in the heaven of heavens where thieves cannot break through and steal. These were
                            the preliminary steps to a higher and better life in the Church of Christ; in a Church that
                            must stand apart from the world and wholly separated from its forms, its follies and its
                            sins. In it will be found those who have accepted the cross and -ire already in the order of
                                the<pb n="115" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>resurrection. Mine and thine are to be laid aside and a united
                            inheritance accepted as representing the testimony which Jesus from the first, sought to
                            establish among his disciples. All that a man hath, said he, yea, and his own life also must
                            be dedicated to the service of God. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Another star of hope..." TEIform="index"/>Another star of hope...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Another star of hope is clearly seen in the religious world, and it will, no doubt, have a
                            salutary influence upon those who are so fortunate as to come within the circle of its
                            influence. The church of the "United Brethren" are proposing stringent measures in regard to
                            the use of tobacco. Over the signature of one of these active workers, is an article that is
                            well worthy the serious attention of those who would wish to do themselves good and to set a
                            worthy example for those who are younger. Br. Kephart suggests, " That no person addicted to
                            the use of tobacco shall receive license to preach the gospel." This seems to be moving in
                            the right direction and the agitation of the subject must necessarily do good. He then very
                            kindly and considerately enlarges upon the subject as follows. ;'I do not mean to say a word
                            against the older ministers who use tobacco. They have been faithful servants in the Church,
                            and have done much good despite the difficulties they have labored under from the tobacco
                            habit. They unfortunately Decame slaves to it when they were boys, likely, induced thereto
                            by ministers of the gospel; and when they entered the ministry there was not the light on
                            the tobacco-iniquity that there is to-day. Science and the high authority of the best
                            medical schools had not demonstrated the injurious effects resulting from the use of to.
                            bacco; and now they are so confirmed in their slavery to the habit that it may be impossible
                            for them to break it; but not so with young men entering the ministry to-day. If they are
                            sufficiently intelligent and well informed as th^y ought to be to preach the gospel, they
                            can not be ignorant of the filthiness, the expensiveness, and the injuriousness of the
                            tobacco-habit. And surely the young man who, knowing all that science, medicine, and good
                            manners testify against it, has not grace enough and grit enough to break away from that
                            habit, has not grace enough nor intelligence to preach the gospel of Christ." We also fail
                            to see wherein a person u. specially benefited by the indulgence a bad habit. Those who use
                            tobacco soon infect a room with their breath and the emanations from their garments, and to
                            that degree that it becomes very nauseating to most persons.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>SANITARY</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sanitary rules" TEIform="index"/> SANITARY EL'LES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>EMILY OFFORD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Shake your bed-clothes separately, and air your bed every morning, so that the effete
                                matter that has been thrown from the body may escape, and not remain to be again
                                absorbed by the lymphatics. Inhale the fresh air freely before partaking of the morning
                                meal, it gives zest to it. Never eat what you do not need because it pleases your taste.
                                It is better to bear the cross and be saved from dyspepsia. Never eat between meals.
                                Never eat or drink contrary to your own conscientious principles even though others may
                                deride you. Never drink unless you are thirsty, and then nature's wholesome and
                                healthful bever age will be agreeable and delightful. Never wear more clothing than is
                                sufficient to keep the body warm. Never let a day pass by without shedding on some one,
                                a ray of the sunshine of goodwill and kindly cheerfulness. Never neglect to pray for the
                                guidance and protection of the Holy Spirit. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><pb n="116" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our departed shepherd" TEIform="index"/> OUR DEPARTED SHEPHERD.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>AMELIA J. CALVER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> TRIBUTE To the memory of Elder Daniel Crosman, Of 27ew Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y. The
                            night damp settles on the fold; The shades of evening fall; A sorrowing flock, now wait in
                            vain, Our trusted Shepherd's call. Far down the vale, we find him not, Nor on the mountain's
                            crest; For the Shepherd of the " Upper Fold" Has called him home to rest. Gone home to rest?
                            Oh, can it be? When we have lov'd so long! Could not our filial constancy, His labors here
                            prolong? Could not our earnest pleadings hold, Our dearly lov'd and blest? Though the
                            Shepherd of the "Upper Fold' Oft call'd him home to rest? Ah nay, the cruel toils of time
                            Have worn his life away; 'Twas not within the pow'r of love, To ask his longer stay. Long
                            suffering, with relentless hold, Has giv'n a martyr's test; And the mercy of the " Upper
                            Fold" Now bids him " come and rest. " No hireling Shepherd has he been To flee in danger's
                            hour; No midnight watch, no heated noon, No foe, no alien power Has an unguarded vigil
                            found, Nor a slighted Lord's behest, 'Till a message from the " Upper Fold " Has giv'n him
                            time to rest. And who will now, with patient toil Bestow such loving care ; Who'll bless the
                            nine and ninety safe And seek the wanderer? Who will with courage strong and bold, A
                            Savior's name confess. And, like him, in the "Upper Fold" Find a Savior's hand to bless?
                            Dear Father, we'll not mourn thee now As one forever gone; Thy love still guards thy earthly
                            fiock, And leads us ever on. And, when the river we have cross'd Which bounds that land so
                            blest, We shall meet thee, in the "Upper Fold" Where the weary are at rest. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                            H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Motherhood of God" TEIform="index"/>THE MOTHERHOOD OF GOD
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Rev. Ileber Newton of New York City, whose lectures on
                                    the Bible, it will be remembered, caused so much attention a year ago, is not to be
                                    silenced. " The voice of God in the soul of man, " sounds with a trumpet call within
                                    an organization altogether too large for the bands of the church. On Sunday last,
                                    Jan. 4th, his sermon was upon ''The Motherliness of God," from the text: ''As one
                                    whom his mother comforted, so will I comfort you. " It will be seen that the noble
                                    minister sees the principle of the duality of sex, running through all life,
                                    beginning with Deity. It marks an advanced era in religious thought when such as he
                                    dare to give voice to their own inspirations. We learn from the Herald that- -
                                    "Readers of Theodore Parker," said Mr. Newton, "will recall his favorite invocation
                                    to the ' Divine Mother.' In those noble prayers which reveal the inner spirit of the
                                    man who is known to the church only as the stern iconoclast, one comes continually
                                    upon such a phrase as ' We thank Thee, O God, that we know that Thou art our Father
                                    and our Mother.' ' Very beautiful,' the heart instinctively whi.- -pei-s, while the
                                    head, perhaps, objects, ' but not at all sound. ' The thought of God as the Divine
                                    Mother is a very ancient one, found in most early nature worships. 'Tainted thus,'
                                    you will say, ' by a genuine paganism.' What, then, about St. Augustine's cry, ' O
                                    God, Thou art the<pb n="117" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> Father, Thou the Mother of Thy children !'
                                    The churchman and the heretic meet thus in the spirit's longings, the true worship.
                                    To seal the union we have no less an authority for this thought than the greatest
                                    seer of the Old Testament, the second Isaiah, who, speaking in the name of Jehovah,
                                    said : ' As one whom his mother comforteth, so will I comfort you.' I wish to speak
                                    to you to-day upon this thought of God as not alone our Father, but our Mother.
                                    ''Mr. Newton then referred to the shock which, he said, the title conveyed to many
                                    minds, and proceeded to account for it by the fact that the church had been in the
                                    hands of men who, rather than women, had fashioned theology, reflecting upward upon
                                    God the distinctly masculine qualities, and by the fact that civilization itself has
                                    been chiefly fashioned by men, and that its ideals of power had thus grown out of
                                    the stern struggle they had to carry on. Nature, however, warranted the ascription
                                    of this gracious title to God. She wears undoubtedly at times a very dark look, said
                                    Mr. Newton, little like the face of a motherly power ; but this stern and savage
                                    aspect breaks away into a milder and gentler expression when the mask she ordinarily
                                    wears falls off and her secret is revealed to them that know her well. Sit beneath
                                    the sacred pines with Emerson and hearken to the whispers of his communings with the
                                    spirit of nature, a.nd you will understand the smile upon his Spartan face. He has
                                    felt the beatings of the heart ' whose throbs are love.' ''Nature, however, cannot
                                    quite clear the divine idea in it. Matter so clothes mind as to conceal its true
                                    form. We must rise to man in order to know rightly what God is. Humanity plainly
                                    images a power which is at once the source and pattern of the womanly as well as of
                                    the manly qualities, inasmuch as woman as well as man is needed to fill out the idea
                                    of humanity. The womanly traits are as worthy of the Divine Being as the manly
                                    traits. " Mr. Newton then passed in review the peculiar characteristics of
                                    womanhood- -pity, forgiveness, gentleness, patience, sympathy, unselfishness-
                                    -arguing that each proves itself a real virtue or strength, and as such really flows
                                    out of the divine nature. " Jesus bodied the womanly ideals as well as the manly
                                    ideals, and the God who is manifest in him shows himself to us, therefore, as one to
                                    whom we can rightly address Parker's and Augustine's prayer. Mr. Newton, in
                                    concluding, dwelt upon the comfort such a conception of God brings to those who,
                                    amid the congratulations of the New Year season, are bowed down under suffering and
                                    care and affliction. " </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio P. Journal" TEIform="index"/>Religio P. Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Early Quakers" TEIform="index"/> THE EARLY QUAKERS.</head><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by
                            <persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>Elder F. W. Evans.]</byline><p TEIform="p">" Quakerism aimed at the overthrow of nearly all vested interests. The Quaker dogma of an
                            unpaid ministry was hateful to the ministers of other denominations. Its non litigious
                            principles dealt as great a blow at the very existence of lawyers as its noncombatant ones
                            did that of the soldiers. All who loved the beautiful disliked the idea of a religion which
                            forbade music and painting, and which prescribed a sober monotony of dress. Whilst the gay
                            dreaded one that held every amusement, however harmless, as mere waste of time, and
                            therefore sinful. The rich and noble still more<pb n="118" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/>dreaded one that
                            destroyed all inequalities of rank and forbade the honors they considered theirs, by right.
                            The Quaker system not only run counter to the habits and customs of the time, but it ran
                            perpetually counter to them. Other dissenters, if they chose, might conform to them in
                            social or political matters, but the Quaker was forbidden by his creed to do so. In the
                            house and workshop, in the field or on the highway, he was a marked man. His speech was
                            couched in different phrases from that of other men. His dress was not of the same cut and
                            was of more sober color. His manners were less polished and seemingly less courteous. His
                            whole existence was a protest against conventionalities, nor could he consent to make any
                            concessions to the weaker brethren. None of these peculiarities were absolutely novel, nor
                            were any of the religious! doctrines of the Quakers. In the most distinctive of the latter,
                            the doctrine of the inward spiritual light which superseded revelation, they had been
                            forestalled at least in part, by the German Mystics, and in others, such as the non use of
                            the Sacraments, they did little more than copy or continue the earlier Puritan religious
                            systems. " Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Art of thinking" TEIform="index"/> THE ART OF THINKING.</head><byline TEIform="byline">[Contributed by
                            <persName reg="Avery, G. B." TEIform="persName"/>G. B. Avery. ]</byline><p TEIform="p">One of the best ways of improving the art of thinking, is 1o think on some subject before you
                            read upon it, and so observe after what manner it lias occurred to the mind of some great
                            master ; you will then observe whether you have been too rash, or too timid, what you have
                            omitted, and, in what you have succeeded ; and, by this process you will insensibly obtain a
                            great manner of viewing a question. It is right, in study, not only to think when some great
                            opportunity provokes you to think, but, from time to time to review what has passed ; to
                            dwell upon it, and, to see what trains of thought voluntarily present themselves to your
                            mind. It is a most superior habit of some minds, to refer all the particular truths which
                            strike them, to other truths more general, so that their knowledge is beautifully
                            methodized, and, the general truth, at any time, suggests all the particular
                            exemplifications which at once leads to the general truth. This kind of understanding has an
                            immense and decided superiority over those confused heads in which one fact is piled upon
                            another, with the least attempt at classification and arrangement. Some men generally read
                            with a pen in their hand, and commit to paper any new thought which strikes them ; others
                            trust to chance for its re-appearance. Which of these is the best method to the conduction
                            of understanding, must, I siippose, depend a great deal upon the understanding in question.
                            Some men can do nothing without preparation ; others, little with it; some are fountains,
                            others, reservoirs.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Sidney" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Almost sundown" TEIform="index"/>ALMOST SUNDOWN
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Sidney Smith. I am looking over my labors By the light of the
                                    setting sun: For I see by the lengthening shadows That my day is nearly done. My
                                    work for the blessed Master Is drawing towards its close ; Far lbss have I done in
                                    the vineyard Than I hoped when morning rose. And yet, while the daylight lingers I
                                    will work as well as I may, Nor waste the remaining moments Kegretting a misspent
                                    day. And 0 ! if now in the vineyard, Are any led there by my hand, I give you this
                                    word at our parting, As near to the gateway I stand. Do all you can for the Master;
                                    Do better than I have done : And then, when the day is ended, You may welcome the
                                    setting sun. </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="119" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Supplication" TEIform="index"/> SUPPLICATION</head><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Hear us, Hear us O righteous God, Hear us, Hear us; Hear our supplication. In
                            humility Hear us, Hear us;  we come into Thy house of prayer. Gire t.s strength, O Lord, we
                            pray, To renew our lives to Thee. Open Thy avenues of boundless love, Thy fountains of
                            life-giving waters. Bless Bless us O Lord, us. O Lord, Bless us with Thy blessing. Cover us
                            as with a mantle, from all harm. Bless us and shield us Bring us nigh unto Thee, as children
                            of Thy tender care, and lead us, O God, forever more.</p></div2><pb n="120" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOKS AND PAPERS</head><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Library of the fathers of the church" TEIform="index"/>Library of the Fathers of the
                                Church</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>Phrenological Journal and
                                Science of Health</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Industrial America" TEIform="index"/>Industrial America</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Public herald" TEIform="index"/>Public Herald</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gleanings in bee culture" TEIform="index"/>Gleanings in Bee Culture</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Monteith's new physical geography" TEIform="index"/>Monteith's New Physical Geography</head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> AD VERTISEMENTS. Good books are always welcome messengers. We have received a specimen
                                copy of the series to be issued, bearing this title. " LIBRARY OF THE FATHERS OF THE
                                CHURCH. " In the publication of these valuable works it will give those in humble life
                                an interest in the treasury of knowledge which has heretofore been the property only of
                                the wealthy. In these books we shall have before us Augustine, John Chrysostom, Ephrein,
                                Athanasius, Cyril, Cyprian and many others who have through their lives and writings,
                                influenced more or less every form of religious belief. " The works contained in the
                                celebrated English collection, and reproduced here, all belong to the period anterior to
                                the division of the Church into Eastern and Western. " The first number contains the
                                confessions of St. Augustine, and many a valuable lesson maybe learned even from these
                                few pages. Published by J. Fitzgerald, 20 Laytayette Place, N. Y. Phrenological Journal
                                anb Science of Health. April Contents: Elizabeth Tudor and Catherine DeMedicis; Shaking
                                Hands; A Mountain Predjudice; El Mahdi, the fighting Prophet of the Soudan; The
                                Christian Religion; Mark Hopkins, L. L. D. The Currency Question; The Intelligence of
                                Ants; A Mushroom Head; An American Diana; The Education of the Future; Constipation;
                                Temperance in Schools; Notes in Science and Agriculture, etc., etc. Fowler and Wells Co.
                                753 Broadway, N. Y. $2.00 per year. Industrial America has been publishing some very
                                readable, timely and instructive articles on a variety of important subjects. These have
                                been tersely and ably written, in popular language, and handsomely illustrated. Among
                                the more important may be mentioned the series on the new Croton Aqueduct, by Thomas
                                Whiteside Rae, C. E . recently completed; the series on Photography in (he Manufacturing
                                Establishment, by W. E. Partridge, now running; the articles on the Natural-Gas Wells of
                                Western Pennsylvania; the Eads Ship Railway; Water Gas Manufacture, etc. The March 14th
                                and 28th issues of Industrial America are Special Exposition Numbers, being devoted lo a
                                carefully-prepared and copiously-illustrated review of what is to be seen at New Orleans
                                likely to interest the intelligent reader who wishes to know what advance America has
                                made in the industrial arts. These two special numbers can be purchased of any
                                newsdealer at 10 cents each, and the paper may be had regularly in the same way at a
                                cost of 10 cents every other week, or by mail direct from the publication office, 9
                                Murray street, New York, at $2.00 a year. Industrial America fully deserves the marked
                                success that has attended its publication. The Editor and Publisher of Public Herald, L.
                                Lum. Smith, of Philadelphia, deserves many thanks for his untiring effons to expose the
                                many " Cheats and Frauds " th.it are, like the frogs of Egypt, becoming a plague in the
                                land. Every paper has an alphabetical list of this objectional class of persons and may
                                be a profitable if not an interesting study to all publishers. Gleanings in Bee Culture.
                                A. I Root, Medina, Ohio, $1.00 a year. Every Bee Keeper should have a Bee Journal, and
                                learn how to keep his bees and secure the honey. Unfortunately for Central New
                                Hampshire, Bee Keepers are very limited in numbers. The Keepers have lost their luck or
                                the bees have pined away at the loss of their Keepers. Which ? MONTEITH'S NEW PHYSICAL
                                GEOGRAPHY. Just Published. 4- -B~ Small Quarto, 144 Pages, 125 Illustrations,',15
                                Colored Maps. In mechanical execution it is unexcelled. It embraces all the recent
                                discoveries in Physiography, Hydrography, Meteorology, Terrestrial Magnetism and
                                Vulcanology. The Maps and Charts have been compiled from original sources. While the
                                easy style, graphic description, and the topical arrange m nt of subjects, adapt it
                                especially for use in Grammar schools, it w&gt;ll be found equally for use in High
                                and Normal schools. A feature of special interest will be " The Record of Recent
                                Geographical Discoveries, " which, contain brief accounts of the Explorations of DeLong,
                                Greely and others. The work possesses the great merit of Prof. Monteith's other books,
                                in being comprehensive and accurate, also thoroughly practical and tractable. The
                                classes that have " Monteith's " invariably show good results. 4QJ* For speci nen pages,
                                sample copies, &amp;c, address A. S. Barnes &amp; Co., Publishers, New York and
                                Chicago. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/> Kind Words.</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Editor; I yield to a very..." TEIform="index"/>Beloved Editor; I yield to a very...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Harvard, 1885" TEIform="index"/> Harvard, Mass. 1885.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Beloved Epitor;- -I yield to a very pleasing inclination to congratulate you, and
                                co-laborers, on your successful efforts to keep our little white sail afloat on the
                                great sea of human affairs. This flag of truce, extends an invitation to fraternize with
                                all loyal fidelity to human love, and happiness in the many bannered crafts that float
                                upon time's sea. They are no longer satisfied " with skimmed milk here, with a promise
                                of cream in the clouds. " This beautiful green earth is no longer a curse, but a
                                blessing, made to be, and to make happy in. Mother Ann said, " If I possessed the whole
                                world, I would turn it all into joyfulness. " True religion unites, and makes happy, all
                                who " cease to do evil, and learn to (be and) do good, " and do it. May the good angels,
                                and earth's best spirits be your helpers So hopes and prays your abiding Brother. Elijah
                                Myrick.</p></div3></div2><pb n="121" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><!-- ADVERTISEMENTS,
WHAT WE  MANUFACTURE.
Turbine M'f e Co.
iADii   MAKK.J
" Swift-Sure" Super-Phosphate,
" Swift-Sure " Ground Bone,
" Swift-Sure" Bone Meal,
" Swift-Sure "    Coarse Bone.
"Swift-Sure" Dissolved Bone,
"Swift-Sure" Guano,
':Good Enough" Super-Phosphate,
" Echo " Super-Phosphate.
"Twenty-Three Dollar'" Super-Phosphate,
Ammoniated Dissolved Bone,
Dissolved South Carolina Rock,
Prepared meat for Poultry, Prepared Bone for Poultry,
Ammonite "A, " Ammonite "B"
and all other Fertilizer Material.
For printed matter, samples and further information.    Address
M. L. SHOEMAKER, Co.,
(LIMITED.)
I>lillaclelx>liia, Pa.
hen you want  BOOKS   - -f ariY kind
mTIQJ^mMlt or   anything  in
WRITING   MATERIALS,
DO NOT FAIL TO VISIT
TQWJtM*8 BQQMSF&MM*
FRANKLIN FALLS,
N. H.
LADIES!
w
For Ten Cents, we send, you
ten beautiful designs for
Fancy Work, different sizes
and kinds, from which you can
transfer 100 designs if you
wish. Send at once.
INDUSTRIAL  Co. Lock Box 10.
S0UTHBRME, MASS,
MANUFACTURERS  OF
CHASK'S   PATENT   CIRCULAR   SAW MILLS
ai<l  TURBINE   WATER WHEELS,
its         SELF-SHIPPING POWER FEED
_     ii          SAW BKNCHES.
SHINGLE  MACHINES.
BOARD   EIHJKRS.    .MATCHERS,
IRREGULAR MOULDERS, &e.
Also. ShafMnar, Pulleys.Hangers.
Gears, (both wood and iron'. Saw
Arbors. All Kinds of IronWork,
sat A 80-ineh Wheel tested at HolyH    oke,   June  7,  1S84, gave   the
!                    following results: - -
7(>.6O per cent, at full discharge.
78.90 per ct. at .t):5() per ct. of full discharge.
78.82     "      "   .837     "     '- -       "         "
70.97      "     "   .674     "     ''       "         "
Send for  Illustrated   Catalogues and   Price
Lists, free, to                  ORANGE,    MASS.
THE OLDEST JOURNAL IN THE WORLD DEVOTED
TO THE
SPIRITUAL. PHILOSOPHY.
ISSUJEB   WEEKLY
At Boswortn Street (formerly lon'gomsry Place,)
BOSTON, MASS,
COLBY & RICH,
>   Publishers and Proprietors.
Isaac B. Rich.....Business Manager,
Luther Colby.....Editor,
John \V. Day......Assistant Editor,
Aided by a large corps of able writers.
THE BAXXER is a first class Familj Newspaper
of eight pages- -containing forty columns of interesting and INSTRUCTIVE READING.
TERMS OF SUBSCRIPTION, IN^DVAtfCE:
Per Year*............. &3.OO )
JSix Months............1.5O [
Tliroe IVIoiitlis..........<7?5 )
Postage Free.
Advertisements published at twenty cents per
line ior the first, and fifteen cents per line for each
subsequent insertion. Subscriptions discontinued
at the expiration of the time paid ior,USB"Specimen
copies sad free.
COLBY & RICH
Publish and keep for sale at Wholesale and Retail a
complete assortment of
AND
CATALOGUES of BOOKS PUBLISHED and for sale
BY COLBY & RICH, sent free.
By a young man of 30 yrs.
I    I    experience, a position as
editor, manager, as proofreader or '- -eporter. Is also
well qualified to work  as
compositor,   or   pressman. Fair   wages    desired.
Address, "FAUST " Plymouth, N". II.
BANNER OF LIGHT.
ChaseAD VERTISEMENT8.
Furnished at 25 cents per.
mill KSS WS eommercial note page. In- -.. ciuu juo.uu formationof any kind erven
for 25 cts. a quest'on. Payable ia cash. J. H. TEMPLE, Plymouoh, N. H.
 Patchwork. For 50 cts' wc will send one
yflAjLl package containing 12 pieces of silk or
ribbon stamped ready to be worked, with quaint designs, sprays, etc. Each piece is worth singly 10c
each.
rnn 35ets. we will send our New Book of FanI Un (V Needlework and Kensington Embroidery.
Tells, the correct colors, and stitches, for working
nearly 100 flowers. Profusely illustrated. The most
complete guide to that beautiful work yet published.
rOQ 25 cts. we will send our New Book on Crazy
rUn I'atchwork. Shows 125 new stitches. Gives
full instructions. Shows 8 full sized squares and 10
pages of stitches.
Tfl any one ordering either of the above, we will
I U send The Household Monthly, 3 months Free.
THE ILLUSTRATED HUB SffiTHLY,
is a large 16 page illustrated paper, devoted to Fashions, Fancy-work, Household-matter etc. Price
$1.00 per year.
SPECIAL   OFFER!
We will send The Household Monthly One year and
every thing named in this advertisement for $1.00.
w. or. swett & co.
LYNN, MASS.
 BALSAM,
Price 25 Cts. per  Bottle.
The most effectual Eemedy ever known
for all the ailments mentioned below.
None GENUINE without likeness of the PROPRIETOR.
A Sure Itcmculy for CROUP, DIPHTIIGltl.l, -and all tlivoat  flfseasoa.
^I>SO    CUKE8 :
Burns, Scalds, Cuts, Bruis- -s, Chilblains, Corns,
Frost-Bitten Limbs, Toothache, Ague in the Face,
Sore Lips, Sore Xose and Hands, Ring-worms,
Stings of Bees and other Insects, Coughs, Colds,
Bronchitis, Sciatica, Soreness of the Lungs, Contraction of the Muscles, Rheumatic Pains, Cramps,
Sore Nipples and Breast, Chapped Hands, Cold
Sores, Sprains, Fractured Limbs, Colic, Cholera
Morbus, Dysentery, Wounds of all kinds, Inflammation of the Stomach and Bowels, Iloarsenss, Sove
Feet and Gout.
Equally Good for Horses and Cattle.
- -Prepared by- -
A.    S.   DAVIS,
31 Central Ave., Chelsea, MASS.
To WHOM all ORDERS  SHOULD be addressed.
N.B_For Directions,  see Wrappers around the
Bottles.
TTVPTT A "NTfTP WANTED.- - - -Printers
JjrffevXldCHN WTJJ. Publications and Materials, Chemicals, Minerals, etc., in exchange for
Printing, Books, Periodicals, Pictures, Medicines,
Curiosities, &c.-.Printed List Free, C. II. KIMBALL, Plymouth, N. H.
The Springfield Republican is, in our view, the
nearest a perfect newspaper printed in Neiv England
or elsewhere.- - [Be/fast {Me.) Progressive Age.
THE
Springfield Republican.
Comprehensive,   Compact,  Varied,   Interesting, Entertaining, Improving and
FULL OF NEWS.
Able Editorial Articles, Literary INews and
Reviews, Foreign and Domestic Correspondence, Original Stories, Poetry, Sermons,
Religious News, Mechanical and Scientific
Notes, Dramatic and Sporting Interests, an
Agricultural Department, a Corner for the
Young Folks. These and other features
make The Republican a
FOPCIAB 1AMIIY JOlrB]fAli
Among New Englanders at home and abroad.
Send for a free Sample Copy, or make a trial
subscription to the
IIirMEPJE^nEJXT   SEWSPAVEB,
An advocate of Honest Government,  Sound
Money, and a  Reduction   of Federal  Taxation, for the protection of all classes.
SUBSCRIPTION: Daily, 75 cents a month, $9 a
year; Sunday, 5 cents a copy, $2 a year; Weekly,
3 cents a copy, $1.50 a year.
LIBERAL REDUCTION TO CLUBS FOB, THE
WEEKLY.          Commission to Local Agen's.
Address - -3?tX3B K.EFXJBLICAW,
SPRlNG-i IELD,    MASS.
0 llecipo an J notes
Low to harmlessly,   effectually
;id rapidly cure
, obesity  witliout
semi-starvation dicta: y , elc. European Mail,Oct. 21 til,
say : "Its effect 1; not merely to reduce the amount of
fat, but by affecting' the source of obesity to inditco a
radical c;?vo of the disense. Sir. K. makes no chargro
whatever; any person,rich or poor,can obtain his work
prva&.fty send"incrC cts. to coverpnstaco toF.C.RUSSKLL,
Esq., Wolmrn House, Sforo St., Bedford Sq., London, Eng."
One of the Best Papers for
ILLUSTRATED
SemiMonthly,
kt Three Months on Trial
FOR   10  CENTS.
ADDRESS
American    Young    Polks'
Manchester, N. H.
AMERICANAD VERTISEMENTS.
Bowditch's
Collections Seeds & Plants
I will prepay and deliver at your own
door any of the following Seeds or Plants
Flowering Plants.SSSE
turn, blue, ScH Begonias, four sorts
6c- -Calceolaria, yellow8c- -Coleus
pink, violet, rose, crimson, yellow etc. 6c
Chrysanthemum new Japanese and
hybrids, 8c- -Carnations, Pure White,
Crimson King GraceWilder etc 5c- -Daisy
Crimson Button, 6c- -Dahlias, single or
double 5c- -English Ivy lOc- -Fuchsia,
single or double 8 sorts 8c- -Geraniums
single or double 40 sorts 8c- -Gen Grant
geranium 6c- -New French Hybrid
geraniums 15c- -Silver Leaf geranium 10c
Scented geraniums 9c-HeliotropesCc- -Paris
Marguerites shrub daisy 12c- -Petunia Eobusta flowers three to five inches in diameter, 30c
PentStemon in white, blue, scarlet or pink 6c- -
RoS9S Monthly 10c- -Hybrids 15c- -Tea15c- -New
Dwarf Sr.evia 5c- -Vinca myrtle 8c- -Any of the
above sent free at prices annexed; the 24 plants and
one year's subscription to Bow ditch's Monthly
Floral Magazine for $2.00; 50 plants by express
buyer paying charges, 4.00 and one years subscription
Flower Seeds, ft?n!riS- -iSL5S?2:
turn Swanley Blu<-> dwarf, 10c- -Balsam extra
largo 15c- -Oonvolvul us, tricolor Kermesinus 15c
Helianthus variegata I5c-Mignonette grandiflora. extra5c- -Nic otiana; fflnis lilyflowers
20c-phlox Drummondi nanadwarf 15c-Poppy
Danebrogr scarlet I5o- - i\^Pyrethrum Golden Gem ~-.
15c- -Pansies Odier 25c- -
BlacK Pansies 20c-Superb Extra Large Eng/!J/W\!
lish or Belgian Pansies 50c *- -
Verbena bybridafrom named sorts25c- -New
Pompons Zinnia^daisy flowers, 25c- -Any of the
above sent free at prices annexed, set of 15 packets
$2.25 and two yearly subscriptions toBowditch'S
FloralMonthly Magazine, all to one address
or each to    separate   addresses  as desired.
New Vegetable Seeds-wri__
Wax Bean, 15c- -Peerless Cabbage 25c- -
Snowball Cauliflower 50c- -Early Marbleheiad Sweet Corn. 15c- - Dwarf Golden
Heart Celery, 15c- -Peerless White Spine
Cucumber 15c- -Arlington Celery, 15c- -
Cuban Queen WaterMelon. l5c-BayView
Musk Melon lOc-Improved Danvprs Yellow Globe Onion. 10c- -American Wonder
Pea I5c-l- -iving8ton's Favorite Tomato 10c
Any of the above sent free at prices annexed, the 12
for $1.75 with two yearly subscriptions to BoWditch's Illustrated "Magazine, a monthly
guide to the garden, both to one address or separate
We will deliver at your own door free of I
......| cost everythingin this advertisement for $5. |
A]] of the above 24 plants, 15 packets of flower
seed, 12 packets of vegetable seed, making a complete
garden and 5 subscriptions to Bowditch's Illustrated Floral Monthly for $5.00.- - - - -The value,
of these goods at retail is over $12.00- - - -For hundreds'
of plants and seeds not here mentioned see our General Catalogue, sent free. Magazine, 10c.; 3 for 25c.
W T? UnWflitoh Seedsman and Florist.
WiD,DUWullbU645 Warren St Boston Mass
"C^- II.     KimbaH
P-Tmouth   S.   II
Wanted To Buy. I
 Newspaper and Job Ofce, or either  separately.
PRINTER,       Plymouth,
N. H.
-THECottage Hearth
This Monthly Magazine will publish during 1885,
bright and interesting stories by the best American
writers, such as
Louise Chandler Moulton, Edward Everett Hale,
Susan Warner, Joaquin Miller, Frances L. Mace,
Mrs, Abby Morton Diaz, Eose Terry Cooke, Celia
Thaxter, Lucy Larcom.
Choice Poems Sketches, and Articles upon Noted
Persons and Places, Departments for Mothers, for
Children and for Sabbath reading; Music, Vocal
and Instrumental; Fashion and Fancy Work; Hints
on Floriculture, and valuable tested Receipts for
household use.
All Beautifully Illustrated.
$1,50 A YEAR.
We will send as samples
Sin Back Numbers for 25 Cents,
post paid, to any address
AGENTS WANTED.
To whom liberal pay and permanent positions will be
given.    Address
THE COTTAGE  HEAETH CO., Boston, Mass,
n PliW Ttiilik Tn Fiftre". S'ates and all the
 e 1 aieni ivUIHS Territories. cheiply made, sells
Fni' Silo          - -well, is ornamental, useful and
i ui  ooic          needed in every   family. Circulars free. Samples sent for $1.50. INVENTOR'S
AGENC2", Plymouth, N. H.
THETEXAS METHODIST
A fearless and outspoken religious journal
devoted to the propagation and defense of
METHODIST views of
CHRIS TIANIT Yand CHRISTIAN DUTY
Always open to a free, full and digninVd investigation of the truth.
THE METHODIST.
is an 8-page Weekly, neatly printed, on
good paper, and will always be filled
with plain, terse, trenchant reading matter well calculated to promote piety and
strengthen Methodism.
REV. WM. PRICE,    REV. B. W. WILLIAMS,
ASSOCIATE EDITOR.
The Subscription price is $1.50 per year; to ministers $1. Address, Northwest Texas
3?u.~blisliing Company,
WETUEBFOBD,   TEXAS.
Phonographic Lessons by Mail
EDITOR.A D VER TISEBIEN TS.
These Celebrated Milla have lone teen
UFfd hy the Farmers and most piominent
A>liters btiii Grain dealers in the United
8tat> s, who rf (.omtneiul them isleingthe
iiKST Maihiui">< vrr f'roducfd for cleaning
ni:d giadins Wheat, Bai ley. Oa<e, Corn and
Seeds of every deeciiption. Tliey do Ihe
work mote pfiferily and have gieater
capacity than buy other niachines.
They are etrnngly built of the very best
rrjflkrials, highly Unit-hid, and piovided
wiih Supentr Attachments, W- -ves, and
nre mace in three different sizrp, one for
F\irm uae. and two for 'Waifenougo or
Miller's use.
They are warranted to give satiseao
tion.
Correspondence solicited and descriptive
circular and price list sent lree on application to
JOHNSON & FIELD,
RACINE, WIS.
A PRESENT FOR YOU!
The handsome knife represented by the annexed illustration is given free to every person sending a trinl ::-nionths'subscription to tho
ing of fine bone or eliojjy, lined and riveted with brass, with German silver tips and nanu-ulnte. It is a genuine imported
Itnife, well made, strong, neat, and durable. It is as fine a knife as any one need want, and is of the very pest size for
carrying in the pocket of either lady or gentleman. Many storekeepers charge from 75p.. to $1.00 rar a knife no better
than this; yet we make it a free gift to all. The PEOPLE'S FIRESiDE JOURNAL is a Mammoth EightPage Paper, containing 48 lonS columns filled with interesting and instructive reading matter suitable for all classes,
Ein-h as Stones of Land and Sen. Romances, Sketches, Poetry, Usej'ul Knowledge, Wit and Humor, Receipts for Workshop
end Household. Fanci/ Work, Puzzles, etc., etc. Bach issue is sure to contain something of interest to every member of
the family. We send the paper tor three months and the splendid knife described above for 36 CENTS i;1 one-cent
stamps or money. This is an unusually liberal offer. Bear in mind, the JOURNAL is an old established paper, and in SEVEN YEARS has never missed an issue. We guarantee double value of the money, and you are sure
to get what you pay for. Money refunded to those not fully satisfied. Five Knives and five Subscriptions for $1 50. Get up
a club among your friends. Order at once, and secure^ a real and genuine bargain. All orders filled promptly.
Address PEOPLE'S PUBLISHING CO., 409 Washington St., Boston, Mass.
Semi far our   ITXIJ^TJIATEIIB anil  E>E=
PTlVK   CATAHJUIJi.   of          f
 Flower   and   Field   r
 BU1.RS3.   FLORISTS'*
r LUSl I O   {'MR*   nml   MIl'IAJHRXTg
of till kinds, inuilcd FltKK imi applicaiiou
ROCHESTER, W. Y.        CI.'iCACO, tLL.
322-326 E. Main St.    200-206 Randolph St.
 liisurtucl in vai'ious puuiicuuonshikI ]j,u meat taken iu goods. C. II. KIMiiALL,
 Plymouth, N U.
IMPOBTAJX.
When you visit or leave New York City, save
Baggage Exprcssngc and Carriage Hire ansl stop at
the Grand Union Hotel, opposite Grand Central Depot. Elegant rooms fitted up at a cost of one million dollars, reduced to $1.00 and upwards per day.
European plan, Elevator. Restaurant supplied with
the best. Horse cars, stages and elevated railroad
to all depots. Families can live better for less
money at the Grand Hotel than at any other firstclass hotel in the City.
9  FOR
YOURl
With the TRIUMPH
STEAM  GENERATOR
It will save l/3 to % of your
feed,   and  your  stock will
thrive    better    and    fatten
quicker.   Send for 1 lustrated circular.    Address
 RICE,WHITACRE&CO.,
35 So. Canal St., Chicago.

MANUFACTURERS  OF
The Racine Farm and Warehouse Fanning Mills.<pb/>--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>