<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0812" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18781201" TEIform="date">December 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">288-313</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--                 <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. VIII. NO. 12 DECEMBER. 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) PUBLISHED BY THE
                        UNITED SOCIETIES. OUR HOME AT SHIRLEY, MASS. ' "GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD." 1878. PUBLISHED AND PRINTED AT SHAKER
                        VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher.<pb n="288" id="p2"/> The Proper Community Disposition 289 Ann Lee 302
                        Religion 290 What shall -we honor most, honest Breaking in the Tonguo 291 Infidelity, or dishonest Christianity? 803
                        Mountains 292 Shakerism 803 Prayer 294 Items of Interest 804 What shall I do to become a Shaker? 294 Prayer and
                        Potatoes 805 Indians No. 10. 295 A good Law. 30G Nonconformity 296 A good Reminder 80G Jew or Gentile 297 Selected
                        800 Vegetarianism 298 O'jituary 808 Clean out of Egypt 298 Home Topics 808 Give us a Hearing 299 For the Children
                        809 Editorial Notes 299 Farm and Garden 811 Correspondence 801 Music 813 TERMS OF ADVERTISING. For ©no inch, one "
                        one half column, " one insertion $ 1. 00 $ 3. 00 $ G. 00 page, " $12.00 Continued insertion for three months, 20 per
                        ct. discount. " six "* 25 " " " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address, N. A. Briggs,
                        Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription will begin when order is received.—No back number*. CONTENTS</p>
                    --><pb n="289" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p"> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A.. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL. VIII.—
                        DECEMBER. 1878.— No. XII. </p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Proper community disposition" TEIform="index"/>The Proper Community Disposition</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Clough, Henry T." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY T. CLOUGH.</byline><p TEIform="p">The proper state of our temper, with respect to one another. It is evident, if we consult
                            either public welfare or private happiness, Christian charity ought to regulate our
                            disposition in all mutual intercourse. In my estimation, Charity is the same as benevolence
                            or love; and is the term uniformly employed in the New Testament, to express all the good
                            affections, which we ought to bear to one another. It consists not in speculative ideas of
                            general benevolence, floating in the head, and leaving the heart—as speculations too often
                            do— untouched and cold. Neither is it confined in that indolent good nature, which makes us
                            rest satisfied with being free from inveterate malice, or ill-will to our fellows without
                            prompting us to be of service to any. True Charity is an active principle; it is not
                            properly a single virtue; but a disposition residing in the heart, as a fountain whence the
                            virtues of benignity, candor, forbearance, generosity, compassion, and liberality flow, as
                            so many native streams. From general good will to all, it sheds it's influence particularly
                            on those with whom we stand in connection, and who are directly in the sphere of home. From
                            the community to which we belong, it extends to the smaller associations of neighborhoods,
                            relations and friends, and spreads itself over the whole circle of humanity. But as the
                            great principle admits of several diversified appearances, let us consider some of the chief
                            forms under which it ought to show itself, in the usual tenor of life. What first presents
                            itself to be recommended, is a peaceable temper; a disposition averse to giving offense, and
                            desirous of cultivating harmony, and amicable intercourse in society. This includes yielding
                            and condescending manners, unwillingness to contend with others about trifles ; and in
                            contests that are unavoidable, prop er moderation of spirit. Such a temper is the first
                            principle of self-enjoyment ; and is the basis of all order and happiness among mankind. The
                            positive and contentious, the rude and quarrelsome are the bane of society. But they cannot
                            disturb the peace of others, more than they break their own. The hurricane rages first in
                            their own bosom, before it is let forth upon the world. In the tempests which they raise,
                            they are always tossed, and frequently it is their lot to perish. A peaceable temper must be
                            supported by a candid one, or by a disposition to view the conduct of others with fairness
                            and impartiality. This stands opposed to a jealous and suspicious temper, which ascribas
                            every action to the worst possible motive, and throws a black shade over every character. If
                            we would be happy in ourselves, or in our connections with others, let us guard against this
                            spirit. Let us study that charity "which thinketh no evil;" that temper which without
                            degenerating into credulity, will dispose us to be just; and which can allow us to obseryc
                            an error, without imputing it as a<pb n="290" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> S9O crime. Thus, we shall be kept
                            free, from the continual irritation, which imaginary injuries raise in a suspicious breast,
                            and shall walk among men as our brethren, not as our enemies. But to be peaceable, and to be
                            candid is not all that is required of a good man, lie must cultivate a generous and
                            sympathizing temper, which feels for distress wherever it is beheld; and to all that he has
                            intercourse with, it is gentle, obliging and humane. How amiable appears such a disposition,
                            when contrasted with a malicious or envious temper, which wraps itself up, in its own narrow
                            interests, looks with an evil eye on the success of others and with an unnatural
                            satisfaction, feeds on their disappointments or miseries ! How little does he know the true
                            happiness of life, who is a stranger to that intercourse of good offices and kind
                            affections, which by a pleasing charm attaches men to one another, and circulates joy from
                            heart to heart. Let it be remembered, that of small incidents the system of human life is
                            composed. The attentions, which respect these, Avhen suggested by real benignity of temper,
                            are often more material to the happiness of those around us, than actions which carry the
                            appearance of greater dignity and splendor. No wise or good man ought to account any ¦ rules
                            of behavior, as below his equal, which serve to cement the great brotherhood of mankind in
                            comfortable union. Particularly amidst that familiar intercourse which belongs to domestic
                            life, all the virtues-of temper find an ample range. It is very unfortunate, that within
                            that circle, men too often think themselves at liberty to give unrestrained vent to the
                            caprice of passion and ill humor: whereas there, on the contrary, more than anywhere else,
                            it concerns them to attend to the government of their heart; to check what is violent in
                            their tempers, and to soften what is harsh in their manners. For there the temper is formed.
                            There the real character displays itself. In all our intercourse then with others,
                            particularly in that which is closest and most intimate, let us cultivate a peaceable,
                            candid, gentle and forbear:-!" dixposi;ica. This is the temper, which by repeated
                            injunction, true religion seeks to reform us. This was the temper of the Christ. This is the
                            temper of Heaven. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religion" TEIform="index"/>RELIGION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>ELDRESS A. DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">Religion is the staff of life upon which the soul can lean for support as it journeys through
                            the low lands, in the rudimental sphere of existence, where are thorns and briars—the
                            product of sinful deeds of violated law through ignorance or otherwise, and while striving
                            to climb the rough hills of progression to more cultivated fields of expanded thought, and
                            concentrated action. True Religion is a staff that cannot be broken ; there is a divinity in
                            it that never changes ; its sweet tones can be heard far above all inharmonious sounda of
                            changing theologies from age to age which have been formed and re-formed to meet existing
                            conditions of the people, whom they represent for the time being. As the people change,
                            forms of theology change ; but Religion embodies all that is essentially true and good. It
                            is the home of God-like attributes, and is the offspring of Deity. Jesus was a chosen Medium
                            to represent the heaven-born child in a more perfected form of character than earth's
                            children had been previously prepared to receive ; and as far as he was the exponent of
                            those divine principles by being identified with them in precept and example, He was the Son
                            of God—the Christ—a Savior and Emancipator to other souls. They who are the most deeply and
                            sincerely eii^safef. +.: find the Rock THE SHAKER, MANIFESTO.<pb n="291" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER 391 whence issue living waters that will cleanse and heal the soul of all sin
                            contracted disease, and perfect it in holiness, feel the least disposed to contend about the
                            personal superadded name affixed, whether king, prince or ruler; but are careful to
                            understand his mission, and copy his divine example ; and from it to gain spiritual
                            knowledge and wealth, by strict conformity thereto. It is good to be zealously affected in a
                            righteous cause and to listen to the voice of conscience ; but conscience unaided by reason
                            is not a sure guide ; and if reason and conscience are brought into conjoint relation, both
                            need to be imbued with the power of true Religion, and to take counsel of higher
                            intelligences whose dwelling is in holier spheres; then, the high-way of truth will ever be
                            open, which unclean beasts and birds cannot find, nor false theologies fetter and bind those
                            who walk therein. The higher souls rise in the scale of progression, the better able they
                            are to eee and conserve the good of the past, to use and not abuse the present, and to
                            prepare for the increasing future ; and they feel that they can safely trust the keeping of
                            truths yet to be revealed, in the fulness of time, to that power that has hitherto guided
                            and guarded the destiny of nations, knowing that all will be well done in proper time and
                            season. Old decaying forms of thought, that possessed life and were fresh and beautiful in
                            their day, will not be lost, but will fall like ripe seed into properly prepared soil—take
                            root and produce fruit and flowers in more perfected forms and varieties. Religion is the
                            soul's dearest friend, av:r] will bear it onward and K-warthrough all the vicissitudes of
                            the. terrestrial sphere of existence, and guide it safely over the waves of changing
                            theologies and consequent controversies and agitations into the quiet Port of the soul's
                            rest, where Truth is the crowned victor, and God reigns supremely. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Breaking in the tongue" TEIform="index"/>BREAKING IN THE TONGUE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fletcher, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD FLETCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> "If any man" (or woman) "bridleth not the tongue"—bridle ? Is that all ? Why not break in
                            the tongue to full harness—collar, traces, saddle lines and all? A halter on the tongue is
                            more than some persons use to guide it. A bridle and head-stall helps still more to keep the
                            unruly member straight, from wagging right and left into neighbors' door-yards and other
                            none-of-your-affairs places. Then if good traces are added, it can be made to draw useful
                            burdens of sound sense instead of flimsy, skeleton sulkies of constantly-rattling
                            small-talk. The whip is needed too, for lazy tongues, to stir them up to speak a cheery word
                            in place of grunting, if it's no more than "A fine morning, brother," and to urge them to do
                            a small fraction of their share of Avitnessing for a religious life, in meetings for
                            worship. Suppose it does seem like a trial to speak before others ! How many times a day are
                            we ashamed to be engaged in discussing the details of cooking our favorite dishes, just the
                            exact shade of flavor, this and that preparation must have, before "I" can endure to swallow
                            it? If there were one-tenth the relish fcr cr-rjuer-r ?R2il-?s3 a:::] ether bx2
                                MANIFESTO.<pb n="292" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 292 THE habits that some of us have in raising up the
                            ghosts of departed dinners, our seasons of devotion would not be given over almost entirely
                            to "the few," aided by the willing-hearted singers. Any one who thinks before speaking, even
                            half the time, has indeed got the coltish member well broken in to double harness. With
                            steady, calm judgment for the nigh horse, and strong double harness, what a huge load, of
                            big bales of solid chunks of good temper such a prize team as that, can roll along the level
                            roads and up and down the hills of life ! Even when cutting whips of others' thoughtless wit
                            and ridicule does the owner of such a well-broken tongue, sudden injustice, he does not get
                            run away with. A spirited team he has, too ; but such a load of solid sense behind, they
                            cannot break away from the better feelings, pull they ever so strongly. What shall a
                            slurring, sarcastic tongue be compared to? A vicious, kicking animal. Everybody keeps out of
                            the reach of those heels, for it is hard to tell which way they'll fly next. So does the
                            habit of always running things down, of joking on the weak points of character among
                            acquaintances, keep a person from having many close friends. They don't like to be too near
                            the sarcastic, kicking tongue. What a sorry old scrub of a mule, is a vulgar tongue. It's an
                            insult to fourlegged brutes to compare it to an old "hack," or a canal donkey worn to a
                            skeleton by hard labor. A three-year old colt, turned out all the year in a rundown sorrel
                            pasture, wooly as a sheep with last year's burdocks, is not so unsightly an object as a
                            coarse, ill-mannered habitually slangy tongue. No hope for it, except to knock it on the
                            head, or shut it away from public hearing, feed it with pure thoughts, and curry it down
                            with a mortified conscience. Srach a member is worse than useless, and unless entirely
                            broken off from coarse habits, is worse than a balky horse or any other kind of a tricky
                            beast. A good harness would be thrown away, trying to regulate an impure, low-talking habit.
                            Making it work with others, might spread the mischief. Nay ! Sell the dirty nag for
                            phosphate : it has an odor rich enough for a ten-acre field. But, perhaps the owner might
                            purify the thoughts and so cure the trouble. There are several other kinds of unmanageable
                            organs of speech. Some of them need curb bits, others, spurs, and a gentle touching up with
                            a whip. Tight collars, snug breeching, and wellfastened tug-back straps may be used to
                            advantage on that large class of unruly members that are popularly supposed to be 'hung in
                            the middle' and wagging at both ends. Each and all may apply the moral to suit, remembering,
                            there never was, nor ever will be a wild colt, or a human tongue that cannot be improved by
                            good training. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mountains" TEIform="index"/>MOUNTAINS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Great offspring of the Globe! what mighty throes Upheaved in pyramids such massive piles, And
                            knit the granite substance, till it formed Enduring monuments of passing time. In firmly
                            welded links the giant chains Encompass lands, and bound the coast Where restless ocean's
                            stormy billows roll, Or calmer seas reflect their grand repose. What altitudes! what
                            towering heights sublime! Grey, cragged clifi's and steep escarpments bare, Plateaus
                            outspread like broad savannas lie, And peaks majestic, wear their gleaming crowns. SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO.<pb n="293" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> the; shaker manifesto. In regions of eternal ice and
                            snow; Or where the torrid rays directly fall, Volcanic craters pour their fiery blast,
                            Engulfing cities, and destroying plains. Sad records tell that thus fair Pompeii fell; And
                            Herculaneum shared her wretched fate. What awe-inspiring feelings thrill the mind, When
                            contemplation touches on a theme So rich in beauty and diversity, In viewless range,
                            outstretching finite sight. Of all the features of the landscape scene, The mountains most
                            conspicuous do appear; Their wooded slopes—in living verdure bright— Conserve the moisture
                            of the atmosphere, While from their rocky crevices and clefts, Gush forth the limpid
                            springs, which overflow The smiling valleys, and the desert waste Which lies afar from
                            fertile, woodclad hills, Where sunbeams scorch, but clouds disdain To stoop, when freighted
                            with refreshing showers. From white capped crest, where golden shafts descend) The noble
                            cascade leaps in weird delight; From dizzy heights it foams and dashes down, Resounding
                            through the canyons solemn depths; Then, mingling in the dark abyss below, The echo of its
                            music dies away In the calm silence of the lonely wild. Deep flowing rivers have their
                            secret source In springs, or lakes that nestle in the hills; Or, in the myriad streams that
                            rippling flow From upland turf, and fern-leaved moss grown rocks, Where spreading trees
                            preclude the burning heat. O sacred shade ! and blissful solitude! The saints and sages of
                            the long ago, Turned from the din of worldly elements, And sought retreat, where nature all
                            serene Mocked the fierce strife of human passions base; Where, dense primeval forests
                            intertwined, Or, in seclusion of some darksome cave, They paid their vows at virtue's holy
                            shrine. Some dwelt as anchorites, in narrow cells Built in the fastnesses of mountain sides;
                            While others chose the quiet shady groves, In which to teach the broad, unfolding truths Of
                            life's religion, and philosophy. When polytheistic tendencies o'erruled The undeveloped
                            intellect of man, Unnumbered gods were fashioned, in the mould Of mortal fancy's vague,
                            distorted forms; And altars to their worship were dispersed Among the lovely grottoes of the
                            hills. The classic bards sang of Olympia fair— Abode of gods—whose apex reached to heaven;
                            Of Helicon, the muses blest retreat, And famed Parnassus—'neath Apollo's rule— Where
                            inspirations of divinity, Through living oracles revealed to man The truth of his eternal
                            destiny. The ancient nations of the mystic East, In centuries preceding human lore, Hewed
                            from the solid quartz at mountain base, Their spacious subterranean fanes; These were
                            adorned with wondrous works of art, Colossal forms and emblematic signs; With paintings
                            highly wrought in changeless hues Appeared upon the walls in bold relief; And though the
                            blight of time has o'er them passed, A study and a marvel still remain. Historic races had
                            their origin Among the rugged highlands of the North; Born with a conquering energy of will,
                            They pressed their way diverse from peopled lands, And founded nationalities their own. From
                            orient to Occident, is traced The onward march of the advancing host, Where empires rise,
                            and civic law prevails, And youthful science waves her magic wand. Imagination, wrapped in
                            silken robes, May revel still in mythologic dreams; Where palm trees wave and nature drops
                            her sweets Content to rest on the unchanging past. But sterner qualities on reason built,
                            Uprose like Rome upon her seven hills, And gave new impulse to progressive life. No more the
                            slave of superstitious fear, Nor manicled by olden, honored rites, Man stands a man and
                            claims the right to think. With stimulated active powers of mind, Inventive genius sways the
                            growing West; It plows the waves, and spans the trackless waste, Through depths unseen the
                            strange electric wire Winds coral reefs, and pearl-embedded vales, And bears intelligence
                            from shore to shore. The mountains rest no more in quietude; The antelope and deer the
                            forests flee; And the wild hunter—crushed in hope forlornRetreats, with bow and arrows at
                            his side; For lo! the iron horse succeeds the chase, And traverses the pathless, rocky
                            track, Where the proud eagle thought her nest secure; Or, thundering through the very heart
                            of hills, It starts the beast from out his hidden lair, And in its train, come all the arts
                            Of civilized and complicated life. While continents shall clasp magnetic hands, And
                            glittering steel unite all lands as one, Can we not pray that love's fraternal bands, May
                            thus cement the nations of the earth? Thus through the interchange of wealth and thought,
                            The brotherhood of man shall stronger be. Religion, Science, intcrblending truths, Broad in
                            expression, yet shall meet the needs And mould humanity harmoniously; Then "beautiful upon
                            the mountain's height,'1 Will be the feet of those who gladly bear The tidings of a
                            universal peace; That, like the morning dawn, shall greet The hills and vales of every land,
                            And make the world, a paradise of love. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He that does good to another man..." TEIform="index"/>He that does good to another man...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He that does good to another man also does it to himself, not only in the consequence, hut in
                            the very act of doing it, for the consciousness of well doing is an ample reward.</p></div2><pb n="294" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Glass, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. GLASS</byline><p TEIform="p">Prayer is the breath of the soul. A breathing operation, through the spiritual organs of
                            respiration ; by. which the soul is nourished, and furnished with food, and clothing,
                            necessary to its existence, and eternal progression ; being analogous to breathing through
                            the physical organs, the lungs, by which the external body is animated, and moved, by the
                            essential elements, of an outward physical existence. Although this operation, in both
                            cases, is involuntary and natural, yet it can be rendered more powerfully effective for good
                            or evil, by voluntary exercise ; the will, and mind, combining the strength of all the
                            faculties, of soul and body. So it appears we must pray, "whether we will or no."—But to
                            make more profit by prayer, we must earnestly use our most important faculty of Judgment; to
                            reason, and discern, what we need to progress us, unto real happiness ; which is that
                            blessed condition, that all rational beings desire to attain unto. But why are so many
                            disappointed, and come short of this all desirable object? We might say briefly, because of
                            a lack of understanding what to pray for, and how to ask aright. Perhaps we might enlighten
                            our understandings by looking farther than this comprehensive, and indisputable answer. The
                            details of such a study, and meditation, let every one run out for themselves. It is
                            sufficient to show that our associative assembly for the more special purposes of the sacred
                            gift of prayer, is no idle, trifling, or unimportant object. If we choose to trifle with it,
                            it will fail to be as edifying, and beneficial, as it is our privilege, if not our duty, to
                            make it. But as the subject embraces, and comprehends, a much greater field than I am
                            capable of harvesting, I will leave it, for abler heads, and more inspired pens than mine,
                            to do justice to this peculiarly interesting theme. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to become a shaker?" TEIform="index"/>"What Shall I Do To Become A Shaker?"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER P. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">bonds your state, acre ? Your l'st. Examine yourself. Generation is the life of the world—the
                            corner stone of human society. Do you wish to die to it—to ail its ties, relations and con-
                            nections ? If not, you do not want to| be a Shaker. Let Shakerism alone. 2'nd. Except Christ
                            be in you, as Christ was in Jesus, you cannot be a Shaker. 8'rd. Are you free from legal and
                            obligations? What is : ingle, or married? Your health, mental and physical? Your edu-
                            cation, business, or profession? What disciplinary process, or educational history !,ai
                            brought you to the end of the world, causing you to ask, "What can I do to b3come a
                            Shaker"—a Christian? If you ivill come, to the extent of your ability, pay all just and
                            honorable djbts—right all wrongs done to any human being. Then collect your just dues—gather
                            up your all, in money, clothing and goods, that you come not empty 1 landed to be fed and
                            clothed while going through^a probationary trial and investigation, preparatory to full
                            consecration of covenant membership. No wages paid, nor charges made, during probationary
                            membership. MANIFESTO.<pb n="295" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER J95 Let none come to spy out our
                            liberties—to appropriate the knowledge, garnered in the Institution, to selfish, worldly
                            ends—nor to act as critics, or dictators to the Order of Shakers. All such are welcome to
                            establish a better Church than ours—but here they are not welcome. Except a man, or woman
                            accept the Kingdom of Heaven— Shakerism—as a little child accepts earthly things—through
                            parents—neither he, nor she can become a Shaker. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians No. 10" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 10</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES S. PRESCOTT</byline><p TEIform="p"> "The white man wants the Indians' home." "¦Chickasaw." We learn with regret from the "Coun-
                            cil Fire" published in Washington how the white man is trying to get away the Indian's home
                            in the Indian Territory. It is as follows. "The Indian nations are contesting our rights
                            (and well they may,) to establish a new Territory viz : Oklahoma—where we could get our-
                            selves down from St. Louis, and Cairo, and getaway with 23,000,000, acres of the finest
                            valley lands in the Indian Territory, much of which is improved—worth to day $10 to $20 per
                            acre. This small part of subsidy would role the red man, 'tis true, but would benefit us
                            about $200,000,000.. Why should we not have it?" Answer* 1. You should not have it, for the
                            following reasons—you have robbed the Indians enough already, and too much altogether, and
                            it is high time this robbery was stopped. 2. It is no more justifiable to rob the Indian
                            because he is an Indian, of his land and home, than it is a white man, although the crime is
                            much more common. 3. You should not have it because it is the Indian's "Home"—"Sweet Home" !
                            "There is no place like home" ! and it is just as sweet to the Indian in his Wigwam and
                            blanket, as it is to the white man in his splendid palace. Why should he be deprived of it?
                            4. You should not have it because it belongs exclusively to the Indians, and should be
                            secured to them by law, for nine hundred and ninety nine years, during which time it should
                            be a closed door, which no white man can open as a possessor. 5. You should not have it,
                            because the Indians have claims on the United States which no other nation have, for lands
                            in their possession, unpaid for. Why rob them of any more? 6. You should not have it,
                            because it is the only place the Indians have to fall back on, when they are crowded out,
                            and robbed of other reservations as they surely will be by the whites. 7. You should not
                            have it, because the Indian Territory is destined to become the future Mecca of 'the
                            Indians, a permanent home where all the tribes must ultimately be gathered for safety and
                            protection, besides, you cannot establish a new territory over the Indians* without their
                            consent, which they will never give, and you cannot do it without violating an expros.s law
                            of the United States. We learn too from the same source, that "The Terms for bill passed the
                            House by a small majority. When it reached the Senate, a majority was counted upon by its
                            friends, but when it came upon its final passage, a proposiMANIFESTO.<pb n="296" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            396 THE SHAKER tion was made and adopted for a Commission, composed of three Senators, and
                            five Representatives, to investigate and report to Congress upon the pro- priety of
                            transferring the Indian Bureau to the War Department." This delay in the Senate was a wise
                            move, not to force its passage without giving the friends of the Peace policy time to enter
                            their protest. It is generally conceded by the best writers on the subject, that there is no
                            way to save the Indians but by being civilized. And this can never be done by the War
                            Department. It is said the Indians won't civilize. Why? If the War Department carries among
                            them, as they have heretofore, guns, powder, bad whisky, and various disgusting diseases, it
                            is true, they "won't civilize"—and they never will, under such conditions, and who can blame
                            them? But, under the Peace policy supported by the Government the Indians can be civilized,
                            and have been, as proof of this we need only refer to the progress and advancement made by
                            the '•'•fivenations" in the Indian Territory, viz. Gher- okees, Ghickasaws, Ghoctaws,
                            Greeks, and Seminoles, and many other scattered over different parts of the U. S. who are an
                            honor to their race. And they owe their civilization to other causes, one side and
                            independent of the War Department. If the Hon. Commissioners will allow the civilized
                            Indians' testimony on this subject, consisting of 60,000, or more in the Indian Territory,
                            we are sure this bill of "Transfer" will never pass the Senate, of the U. S. so as to become
                            a law, and it never ought to, because the Indians are opposed to it, universally—they would
                            rather die—they see in the final issue it means extermination, and nothing else—and no one
                            wants to see the Indians exterminated, unless it is some had whites, who themselves or their
                            vices ought to be exterminated, and not the Indians. It is not the military, alone, which
                            the Indians fear, but, it is the money power, behind—it is Aristocratic Establishments,
                            Chartered Monopolies, and Rail Road Corporations ; these are undermining the Indian's Home.
                            North Union, Ohio.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nonconformity" TEIform="index"/>N0NC0NF0RMITY</head><p TEIform="p">In an ably written article upon nonconformity with the world The Brethren at Work (Dunkard)
                            produces the following very good points. Thus acknowledging, we would remind the above paper
                            that there are other practices than that of dress, which to be conformed to the pattern of
                            Christ's life, we must refrain as Christians. Does any ask : "What are they?" Let such study
                            Christ, and read The Manifesto. Ed. The reason some people wear gold is because it is in
                            their hearts. This is why they dress fine and wear costly array, following the vain and
                            foolish fashions of the world. The fountain is corrupt—the mind not yet renewed, and we
                            cannot reasonably expect anything better from their actions. There are hundreds who are very
                            strict about their dress, but seemingly about nothing else. It would appear that they have
                            centered all their ideas of non-conformity in a few clothes. When it comes to conversation,
                            they are just like the world. They buy and sell like the world, using their wits to drive
                            sharp bargains, and every and any way to make a little money, just like the world, too, at
                            that. Were it not for their dress, MANIFESTO.<pb n="297" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAK1E MANIFESTO.
                            29-7 you would never think about them being professors. They can talk about their neighbors
                            ; do a little tattling now and then; use rough language. In fact, conform to the world out
                            and out, all but in dress. Such characters are a disgrace to any church. There is no Bible
                            non-conformity about them. It is all outside, and but little of that, while the mind remains
                            full of corruption and deceit—has not been renewed. Then there is another class who are very
                            strict about the cut of their clothes. They purchase fine, costly broadcloth and have it cut
                            in the order, thinking this is non-conformity. Such work is mockery. God has forbidden the
                            use of fine apparel and costly array, and all the non-conformity cutting in the world will
                            not make it right. If we are going to follow the Bible, let us be consistent about it, and
                            not attempt to take advantage of circumstances. Then there are sisters who seem to have too
                            much respect for the church to wear a fine dress bonnet or hat, but will take their
                            otherwise plain bonnet and ruffle and trim it until it is just as bad as a fashionably
                            trimmed hat. Their dresses must be ruffled and trimmed until what little non-conformity they
                            ever had is completely destroyed. This is worse than following the fashions of the world. It
                            is polluting and bringing shame on a religious thing. It is degrading God's order. If we are
                            going to be non-conformed to the world, let us be consistent about it, and not try and mix
                            things up—half religion and half world. </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True happiness has no localities; No tones provincial; no peculiar garb" TEIform="index"/>True happiness has no localities; No tones provincial; no peculiar garb
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> True happiness has no localities; No tones provincial; no peculiar garb. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jew or Gentile" TEIform="index"/>JEW OR GENTILE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Talmage, T. Dewitt" TEIform="persName"/>T. Dewitt Talmage</byline><p TEIform="p"> 'Last summer the land was ablaze with discussions about the Jews being excluded from one of
                            the leading hotels. I have this to say : A Gentile is no better than a Jew—no better in
                            morals, no better in providence and forethought. There are more Gentiles in Sing Sing and
                            the Tombs and on Blackwell's Island than there are Jews. The Gentiles are no better in the
                            profession of law—Moses, the greatest lawyer who ever lived, was a Jew. They are no better
                            in banking—Rothschild, the greatest banker, is a Jew. They are no better in military—Joshua
                            was a Jew. They are no better statesmen— D'Israeli is a Jew. They are no better
                            theologians—the Lord Jesus Christ was a Jew. The Jews are not .physically inferior to the
                            Gentiles. Why is six feet high any better than five feet high? Did you ever hear of
                            Wellington or Napoleon? They were small. I know a great many tall fools. A crane is taller
                            than a dove. Their features are not so attractive. Who decreed that a nose curved up is any
                            better than a nose curved down? Uncleanly? What a charge to be made by the smoking Gentile
                            nation. Think of the floating pigsty attached to all railroad trains, and the gentlemen's
                            cabins in our ferry-boats. Most of the smoke belongs to the new dispensation. The weak point
                            of the Gentile is not washing too much. Look at the city court room after a trial, or a
                            public hall, after a democratic convention, or a republican meeting. Is that atmosphere all
                            Jewish ? Analyze it, and you will find it to consist of 5 parts of<pb n="298" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 29S
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. whiskey, 3 parts of garlic, 1 of cologne and 1 of oxygen. I have
                            baptized people who were so dirty that I was tempted to leave them in the tank. Flash
                            jewelry ! That is not peculiar to the Jews. The American nation is covered up with it. You
                            can get a 'gold' watch for $7,50 in Chatham street. Jewg sell them, but Gentiles buy them
                        !</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vegetarianism" TEIform="index"/> VEGETARIANISM</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Journal of chemistry" TEIform="index"/>Journal of Chemistry</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">There was a discussion on this subject at a recent meeting of the Medical Society
                                    of London. True vegetarians, it was urged, eat neither butter, eggs, nor milk. Sir
                                    Joseph Fayrer related his experience of the effects of this diet among the natives
                                    of India, and said he had no doubt that people could live on vegetables alone. He
                                    had seen some of the finest specimens of the human race as regards strength, power
                                    of endurance, and physical development among the inhabitants of the northwest
                                    provinces of India, who were pure vegetarians ; but he accounted for their condition
                                    from the fact that their food consisted chiefly of leguminous seeds, such as peas,
                                    beans, and the like, which contained a larger amount of nitrogen than other
                                    vegetables. The president, Dr. Buchanan, remarked that in the discussion several
                                    factors should enter; as age, which was a considerable element, as no doubt people
                                    advanced in years appear to thrive on a vegetable diet, whereas children require
                                    almost a pure animal diet. Again, climate was a great factor ; and in the treatment
                                    of disease it could be strongly advocated ; while, lastly and chiefly, temperance
                                    must be strictly enforced, avoiding excess in the use of animal food, and taking, in
                                    fact, a middle course.</quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Clean out of Egypt" TEIform="index"/>CLEAN OUT OF EGYPT</head><p TEIform="p"> The necessity of a separation from the world, or worldly practices, has ever been a peculiar
                            demand of the higher powers, upon those who felt it to be duty to live better than the
                            world. Such was the call to Israel of old; first to free them from unreasonable, slavish
                            bondage to Pbaraoh ; but last and best, to put between them and their resorts to
                            ungodliness, an impassable barrier—the Red Sea. In their eagerness to get away from their
                            human tyrants, they thereby cut themselves asunder from opportunities of indulging passional
                            proclivities, far baser and more tyrannical than Pharaoh's overseers. Cut off from the
                            display of pride, vanity, and excess in worldly station. Broken away from flesh pots, and
                            from opportunities to engage their inordinate appetites for unnatural foods and drinks.
                            Forced to the simple labor of each earning his or her livelihood, by gathering what each
                            needed of simple, wholesome food. Drink from the waters that flowed as a spring from a rock
                            was offered, with no apparatus at hand to corrupt tlnse into unnatural, death-dealing
                            fluids. Compelled by the force of circumstances to be a separate people, and to relinquish
                            the good as well as bad habits of the Egyptians—so with the peculiar people of God wherever
                            they may be located.<pb n="299" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 299 Free from both bad and
                            good, worldly habits. Celibates, not from selfish motives, but "for the kingdom of heaven's
                            sake;" forsaking even the small good that is left amid the very gulling and corrupting
                            conditions of married selfishness. "Buying and selling" but "as though not doing so,"
                            because not for "me and mine," but for "those who believe," and "are gathered together." The
                            glory of worldly strife left behind, peace takes up its abode ; and the worldly necessity of
                            wars, and destruction by war uncalled for. Clean out of the Egypt, means more good than the
                            best of worldly good—better than its best in all that concerns our physical habits, and our
                            spiritual impulses and ministrations'. Let us be so lifted vip in godliness of our lives
                            that we shall draw many unto us from their Egypt.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give us a hearing" TEIform="index"/>GIVE US A HEARING</head><p TEIform="p">If those sincere religionists, whom we 80 largely respectfor their sincerity, would but give
                            us a hearing before they refuse us recognition as Christians, or other than unreasonably
                            fanatical in our testimony, we should be greatly relieved from temptations to become
                            impatient; while they could not better evidence the Christian characteristic of forbearance.
                            Tell us, dear friends, wherein our testimonies or lives differ from the same of Jesus, or
                            those taught by the little, model Primitive Christian Church? You ask why we deal with
                            institutions, considered sacred by your churches, as unchristian institutions? with
                            marriage, the private family, personal property, etc. ? We have only one answer to these
                            questions: Because we nowhere find any of these in Christ. Jesus not only remained a
                            celibate virgin, but taught this as right for His followers, and for all who would be chil-
                            dren of the Resurrection—which He wa3. Are we too stringent then with ourselves in our
                            abstinence of marriage ? or was Hk too stringent? Some of his immediate disciples were
                            married mea ; Peter for instance : but after his conversion to Christ, he "led his wife as a
                            sister," no more as a wife. Paul, while permitting marriage, which as a follower of Christ
                            himself, he had no right todo, yet lived above marriage. As did the early disciples with
                            their "possessions and goods/'we aim to do like them, not only because they did, but because
                            it is less selfish and most right. Do we preach or practice peace any more radically than
                            did Jesus? Who then will blame us for our unwillingness to fight? Hear us, friends: We have
                            done with Marriage, War, Private property, politics, and the bad and good of selfish lives,
                            just as Jesus did. If we claim him as a leader, and to follow him, can we do differently?
                            And are you as willing to give us as much credit for so doing, as you extend to Him of whom
                            you also profess discipleship?</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial Notes</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Close of volume eight" TEIform="index"/>CLOSE OF VOLUME EIGHT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">With this number, closes the eighth volume of our Monthly,—the ninetysixth issue of the
                                Shaker, Shakeress and Manifesto. It is circulated to and<pb n="300" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 3OO THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. through the world at much less than cost, being largely sustained by
                                the consecrated contributions of a most unselfish people. That it requires more faith,
                                generosity and hope than some have in possession, to see the necessity and duty of thus
                                "casting our bread on the waters" of humanity, with an assurance of "its return after
                                many days, with blessings added an hundred fold," still we mean to live on. We will
                                greet our friends, patrons, and at least a thousand more new readers with the beginning
                                of volume nine—parties outside of our church having volunteered at their expense to
                                circulate so many ! We ask a continuance of kindly remembrance in prayers ; and that
                                these prayers may be so deep, fervent, unselfish and effectual, that they may be
                                feelingly experienced, by cheerful givers to the support and continuance of our one
                                little missionary, The Manifesto ; and we are confident, God will DEAL WITH ITS
                                SUSTAINERS AS LIBERALLY. </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our antidote for sin" TEIform="index"/>OUR ANTIDOTE FOR SIN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The world do not like' Shaker testimony, nor do we think it strange. Radical Christianity
                                never did please the world-loving. "Even so we speak," said the early apostles, "not to
                                please men, but God" by delivering what is best for them., regardless of perverted
                                tastes. But there are thousands on thousands, who feel accordingly grate- ful for our
                                testimony of selfdenial, in the degree they practice it. Thousands now admit, and
                                millions more will do the same, that Selfdenial to worldly lusts, to unmanly and
                                unwomanly perversions in worldly, unchristian pleasures, is a certain antidote to sin ;
                                and without it, there is no Christ in us, no Savior for us, nor salvation unto higher,
                                Christian life. </p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="1880" TEIform="index"/>1880</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">1880. It is worthy of observation and particular notice, that among an unusually large
                                number of prophets and prophetesses abroad in the world, there appears to be a peculiar
                                concentration upon the year 1880 for the consummation of something, that will be
                                extraordinarily awakening in religious circles. It occurs to us, also, that many Shaker
                                prophecies, uttered many years since, come to their conclusion in that year. We shall
                                see : That the world needs a universal revival of genuine religious, Christian
                                practices, in love and purity of life, no one doubts. That Christ will appear in 1880 or
                                sooner, to some and perhaps many individuals we have no doubts whatever; and we would be
                                most happy to chronicle such appearances in 1879, or even give unmistakable evidences,
                                in volume nine that the day of Jubilee would assuredly dawn in 1880! "Oh, that He would
                                come !" </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mountains" TEIform="index"/>Mountains.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> It was Bryant who wrote: "The groves were God's first temples, etc." but our talented
                                sister, M. J. A. of the North Family, Mt. Lebanon, would almost persuade us in her poem,
                                that the mountains claim the distinction of first and best. One reason, and a strong
                                reason too, for our uniting in her opinion is, that the first, best sermon we ever heard
                                of, was delivered "On the Mount." </p></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Deserving praise" TEIform="index"/>DESERVING PRAISE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We would call the attention of our<pb n="301" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 3O1 readers to the
                                first paper of this number, contributed by our young friend, Henry T. Clough; who though
                                lately arrived in his teens, expresses much good judgment and sound sense. We also take
                                this opportunity of returning our sincere thanks for many kind letters received by us,
                                from many of our elderly and young people, but which are too personally respectful to be
                                expressed by type ; but for which we shall ever hold the donors ir happy
                            remembrances.</p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notice" TEIform="index"/>Notice
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Notice. We would kindly give notice, that with the issue of this number of The Manifesto
                                and hence, all communications and correspondence relating to The Shaker Manifesto,
                                should be addressed : "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N. Y." </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Shaker Manifesto : At Freeville, N. Y. Sept. 29th, the writer, in company with Emil                                     Bretzner, attended..." TEIform="index"/>Editor Shaker Manifesto:...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Mount Lebanon" TEIform="index"/> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. Evans</byline><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker Manifesto : At Freeville, N. Y. Sept. 29th, the writer, in company with
                                Emil Bretzner, attended an all day meeting, a sequence of the Watkins Convention. The
                                Watkins Convention was a Liberal League Meeting, the object being to reform and progress
                                the American Government as a Republican Institution, to make it the Utopia of the
                                Reformer and the New Earth of the Theologian. Materialism was in the ascendant, with the
                                leaders, and Spiritualism, with the people. The consequence was, the Spiritualists
                                projected and managed the Freeville meeting in, and to subserve their own interests.
                                Stebbins was Chairman and Peebles a principal speaker. The Shakers had no cause to
                                complain, of want of courtesy, time nor opportunity. It was a pleasant day. The
                                attendance numbered about 2,000, would have been 4,000, had it not rained just at the
                                hour of starting from.the people's homes. As it was, it proved a most harmonious, happy
                                assembly. Cordial greetings and kind wishes were the order of the hour at parting. I was
                                much impressed by the Religious sensation evident among the attendants, particularly the
                                feminines who were seriously and sensibly affected by a certain class of truths
                                pertaining to social life. Many grateful feelings to the Shakers were expressed, with
                                remarks that they should go home and be better men and women, better husbands and wives,
                                better fathers and mothers, than ever before. A John Baptist spirit is evidently at work
                                among Spiritualists. The lectures of some of the feminine Speakers, who have spoken
                                plain truths to plain people, and for which the Orthodox censure them, are producing
                                practical results. A Christ Baptism will be in order, when the way is more fully pre-
                                pared. Jeremiah, 51 : 21, "Israel is my battle-axe and weapon of war. With thee will I
                                break in pieces the husbandman and his yoke of oxen—private property, the captain and
                                ruler, the war power—Man and Woman, the young man and the virgin—the marriage re-
                                lation. With thee, I will dash nations together and destroy kingdoms." It might be ad-
                                ded, With thee, I will build the waste places and comfort those who mourn. With thee, I
                                will restore again, in a Religious Community, all the good, minus the evil, of
                                individuality. The reproductive order will be supplanted, as Jacob supplanted Esau, by
                                the Spiritual Resurrection of the True Gospel Order. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Help one another..." TEIform="index"/> Help One Another</head><p TEIform="p">The race of mankind would perish did they cease to aid each other. From the time that the
                                mother binds the child's head, till the moment that some kind assistant wipes the
                                death-damp from the brow of the dying, we cannot exist without mutual help. All,
                                therefore, who need aid, have a right to ask it from their fellowmortals ; no one who
                                holds the power of granting can refuse without guilt.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Scott, Walter" TEIform="persName"/>Sir Walter Scott</byline></div3></div2><pb n="302" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people and their critics, ninth paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE: Her
                            work, her People, and their Critics, Ninth Paper</head><p TEIform="p">ANN LEE. Her work, her People, and their Critics. Ninth Paper. "The travels of Mother Ann had
                            ended; and from the time she arrived at Watervliet, until her decease there remained to her
                            only one year and three days. Kest from traveling they did; but Ann Lee and her companions
                            never labored harder for the good of the cause, nor for the particular good of souls, than
                            during the year following her arrival at Watervliet—the last year of her life. Meetings,
                            Meetings, Meetings with and for the enlightenment of visitors and to keep their own
                            religious zeal at a white heat, were the order of the day, and particularly at night, often
                            lasting all night, being still in progress at break of day. On July 21. 1784 William Lee,
                            the noble brother of Mother Ann died, more from injuries received at the hands of mobs, and
                            from complete exhaustion than from any other noticeable cause. Immediately after this
                            brother's decease, the physical breaking down of Mother Ann was particularly observed ; and
                            her oft-repeated expressions of "Brother William is calling to me;" and "Yea, brother, I am
                            coming soon," caused ber companions to feel great anxiety, and to question the cause of
                            these remarks. She would answer that she often saw William beckoning her to come, and that
                            she knew she must soon go. She grew weaker and weaker in body, yet stronger if possible, in
                            the encouragement of people to keep the faith, and to be more faithful after she had gone.
                            On the eighth of Sept. 1784, a few minutes after twelve in the morning she said : "/ see
                            brother William coming in a golden chariot, to take me home!" and then breathed her last
                            without a struggle or a groan. Thus closed the life of a remarkable woman—a woman who, if
                            ever there was one acquainted with unmerited grief and worldly persecution, she was that
                            one. Ann Lee was a woman of strong constitution, inclining to exceed the usual size of
                            women; very straight, and generally well proportioned in fcr:r_^ of a light conxolexion,
                            blue eyes, with hair of a light, chestnut brown. Her appearance was rather majestic; and
                            many, other than her faithful followers called her a beautiful woman. She was unlearned: her
                            education was what she could derive from observation and inspiration ; her language was very
                            simple, and so plain was she in speaking to the point of conversation, address or rebuke,
                            that she was, no doubt, often chargeable with bluntness. There was nothing mealy-mouthed
                            about her; yet she never would purposely hurt the feelings of any, even of her enemies. She
                            knew nothing of the school of Chesterfield, nor its inculcations: but she taught in her
                            natural language and life, of principles and power which the most esthetic science would or
                            might fail of being capable; and the results of obedience to her teachings and example, were
                            beautifying to individuals, within and without. Withal she was a meek woman; was never known
                            to act in the least out of humor, angry, nor to exhibit the slightest ruffle at a personal
                            insult. She was powerful in testimony, and the plainest in the denunciation of every
                            passionate impulse leading to the gratification of the flesh; but invariably applied these
                            testimonies to herself as to any others. She was very sympathetic and motherly, making
                            others to feel completely released from condemnation, by drowning them in the depths of her
                            love and affection. Of her plain and stirring instructions we will have more to say in
                            future. At her funeral, there gathered a large concourse of her faithful followers, and very
                            many not of the faith. She had lived an adorable life; and the world seems but just waking
                            up, to give her even a moiety of the credit she deserved. She was buried close by her lowly
                            logcabin ; but a few years after, was disinterred to be placed in the centre of a plain, but
                            convenient cemetery in the centre of the village of Shakers, N. Y. By the enlargement of the
                            burying-ground, its original symmetry has been disturbed, exhibiting now, to the west of the
                            centre, a very plain slab, made of Helderberg flags, rising above the ground about two feet
                            only, and bearing the letters: xM.x _Mother AnrLee. A.</p></div2><pb n="303" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Which shall we honor most, honest infidelity or dishonest christianity?" TEIform="index"/>
                            WHICH SHALL WE HONOR MOST, Honest Infidelity or Dishonest Christianity?</head><p TEIform="p">It is a singular fact, that while the socalled Christianity of popular churches, and the
                            Infidelity of The Boston Investigator type, are at bitter variance concerning theologies,
                            they strike hands as a unit, and are '^as the heart of one" in opposition to PShaker
                            principles. We honor every one for clinging to honest beliefs. Iniidels to Christianity are
                            to be honored, if we can credit their sincerity in opposing Christian principles from honest
                            motives. But what shall we say of those, professing Christianity, who yet as boldly, and
                            more vituperatively oppose, condemn and crucify the lifeprinciples of Christ, than do any
                            infidels ? The Boston Investigator has a correspondent to deal with,—one who wants to live
                            without work—live upon the earnings of others—and who foolishly thinks the Shakers are the
                            people whom he can fleece. We coincide completely in the parting advice to him of the
                            Investigator; but we present its article entire to show how intelligently it speaks of our
                            principles while disagreeing with them ; and to ask particular attention to the fact, that
                            while it opposes, it acknowledges our principles to be very Christian— first class Christian
                            ! While the majority of so-called Christian Churches, not only are dishonest in opposing
                            Shaker principles because of their dislike to practice them, but also call them unchristian,
                            to ease their guilty consciences ! Churchism and Infidelity at one on Shakerism! But which
                            deserves the most honor? </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERISM</head><p TEIform="p">An editor of a paper like the Investigator should k^cv/ a little something ofalmost
                            everything, because Infidels are inquisitive people who are in the pursuit of knowledge,
                            (often under difficulties,) and so they have a proclivity for asking questions considerably
                            more than we know how to answer, though when we do get cornered, we might, if we were pious,
                            satisfy the inquirer by saying, "¦What you can't unravel, learn to trust!" Bat this kind of
                            a manoeuvre would hardly be an answer to "J. G.," who writes us, substantially, that he is
                            thinking seriously of becoming a Shaker; that he cannot seem to succeed as a mechanic, but
                            perhaps might if he were a member of a Shaker community, for he says he has "observed that
                            Shakers are fat and dress well, and don't seem to look as if they worked hard, and this
                            ivitfb me is a great thing I" He finally concludes, after writing about three pages of his
                            history and that of his father, uncle, aunt, and several cousins, (all very interesting—to
                            himself,) that he will try his hand at becoming a Shaker ; "but first," says he, "just tell
                            me, if you please, what Shakerism is?" In a few words, then, and as we understand it,
                            Shakerism, per se, or in itself, is primitive Christianity. Its chief features are,—property
                            in common, unmarried lives, no families, no children, no politics, no civil government, no
                            voting, and no acceptance of office. If this is a correct definition of Shakerism, it may
                            answer for another and a spiritual world, perhaps, but it is not adapted to this earth and
                            to the United States especially, for here we don't want any exclusive religion, neither
                            "primitive" nor otherwise ; but we do want that every man should have a few dollars of his •
                            own, get married, r?ise a family, vote, be i::— MAJNTIIPJCSTO.<pb n="304" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 3O4 THE
                            SHAKER terested in Government, and, if he is honest, capable, and faithful to the
                            Constitution, be elected to office. Conclusion : We would not advise "J. G." to become a
                            Shaker.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>ITEMS OF INTEREST</head><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sometime ago Chicago ejected from its public schools all books..." TEIform="index"/>Sometime ago Chicago ejected from its public schools all books...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Sometime ago Chicago ejected from its public schools all books containing the names of
                                God, Christ, and other religious terms. An effort lately made to repeal such action, was
                                quite unsuccessful. Chicago means to keep Church and State separate, and in this is a
                                model city. </p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Haven's school board, decided..." TEIform="index"/>New Haven's school board, decided...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> New Haven's school board, decided to dispense with the uses of Bible, Prayers, Psalms,
                                Hymns or religious songs in any of the city schools; by so doing it "renders unto God
                                the things that are His" in their proper place.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Here is what Prof. Swing..." TEIform="index"/>Here is what Prof. Swing...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Swing" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Here is what Prof. Swing has to say of the yellow fever: The yellow fever is only the
                                general unreasonableness of city existence. It is a final outbreak of pent up forces.
                                The human constitution can endure dirt and bad food and bad air for a time. A powerful
                                race may resist disease for ten or twenty years, but at last the steps become feeble and
                                the enemy in the air and in the blood makes the assault. We call this enemy yellow fe-
                                ver, or small-pox, or cholera, or scurvy, or plague, but under any of these names it is
                                only the final shape of unwisdom. Man looks after his commerce and neglects his physical
                                laws.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We honor Elder F. W. Evans..." TEIform="index"/>We honor Elder F. W. Evans...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We honor Elder I\ W. Evans for his energetic defense, in the Watkins Convention, of the
                                physical manifestations. A correspondent who was present informs us that Mr. Evans did
                                so "with all the grandeur of an old Roman orator."—Banner of Light.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Doctrine" TEIform="index"/>DOCTRINE</head><p TEIform="p">Jesus was the Corner Stone of a Temple built of Celibates who called nothing their own,
                                they having all property in common, and who would not fight, because they loved their
                                neighbors as they loved themselves. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Prentiss</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker Manifesto for June comes to us full of good                                     things..." TEIform="index"/>The Shaker Manifesto for June comes to us full of good things...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Says the Harbinger of Light, Melbourne, Australia: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Shaker Manifesto for June comes to us full of good things, live ideas and
                                        spiritualizing thoughts. How little the world knows of the principles of these
                                        good people. We should like to get subscribers for their representative paper,
                                        and will send for some specimen copies, to distribute gratis to those who want
                                        to know what the Shakers are.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Harbinger of light (Melbourne, Australia)" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="shaker-press" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following tribute was paid to the cousin..." TEIform="index"/>The following tribute was paid to the cousin...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The following tribtite was paid to the cousin of our Elder H. L. Eades. The additional
                                letter in the latter's name was added by an uncle of theirs : Captain Eads, who built
                                the St. Louis bridge and the Mississippi jetties, has been presented by the Brazilian
                                Minister with an autograph letter from the Emperor Dora Pedro, in French, requesting him
                                to come to Brazil. The Emperor says that the Brazilian government is in need of an
                                engineer experienced in the improvement and navigation of rivers, and highly compliments
                                Eads on his ability.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Perfumed church" TEIform="index"/>A PERFUMED CHURCH</head><p TEIform="p">The wonderful and beautiful building known as the Mosque of St. Sophia, in Con-
                                stantinople, is always fragrant with the odor of musk, has been so for hundreds of years
                                (ever since it was rebuilt), and nothing has since been done to keep it perfumed. How do
                                you suppose this wonder has been performed ? In the year 538—more than a thousand years
                                ago—the mortar with which it is built was charged with musk, and there it is to this
                                day! </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He died rich" TEIform="index"/>HE DIED RICH</head><p TEIform="p">How hard some men strive all their lives to have it said of them when they have passed
                                hence—"he died rich!" Relatives and friends who are left behind seem to consider it a
                                compliment to the dead to dwell upon the theme—"he died rich!'; M^NTF'ES'TO.<pb n="305" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE 3O5 And now comes up the question. Is it an honor to a man to die
                                rich? Is the world any better for a man to die rich than it would 3&gt;e if the same
                                man died poor? Is the man any happier in the next life on account of it? If the spirit
                                is conscious after death, is it any satisfaction to that spirit, in the other life, to
                                know that he left a hundred thousand or two for his relatives to quarrel over, and
                                Jbreak his will over, and on account of which they are to be at swords points with each
                                other through all time?—Hudson Register.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Losing, for the gain of others" TEIform="index"/>LOSING, FOR THE GAIN OF OTHERS</head><p TEIform="p">Reformatory periodicals are nowhere a pecuniary success. If put forth from such motives,
                                failure is the most common of consequences. We publish and circulate The rManifesto at
                                less than cost; and while pleading for an increasing subscription list, T^e mean to
                                return more than we ask. The selfish and self-seeking, are blinded to the fruitful
                                prospects that come from "casting bread upon the waters," because no immediate profits
                                accrue to them. " What have you done for others?" will be very poorly responded to by
                                some, when this question shall ding in their ears in the eternal world, and the answer
                                will be : "Only what I was forced to!'' The Oneida Community published The Circular one
                                year, at a loss of $2400.00; while our loss may yet ' prove more imaginary than
                            real.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Idle boys and girls" TEIform="index"/> IDLE BOYS AND GIRLS</head><p TEIform="p">Idleness is the mother of vice, and a boy or girl who is allowed to grow up in idleness
                                is pretty sure to be a vicious man or woman. The parents of such children have a fearful
                                responsibility resting upon them when they let them run about at late hours of the night
                                instead of keeping them at home, reading good newspapers and books, and training them
                                into moral habits, so as to become respectable, instead of idlers, rum-drinkers,
                                loafers, and gamblers, and worse which are sure to be the case vith the night-runners
                                and day-idlers, and then the responsibility is increased. Give the children plenty to
                                do, and you will preserve their morals. Better ¦a tired body than a vitiated
                            mind.—Ex.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer and potatoes" TEIform="index"/>PRAYER AND POTATOES</head><p TEIform="p">An old lady sat in her old arm-chair, With wrinkled visage, disheveled hair, And hunger-worn
                            features; For days and for weeks her only fare, As she sat in her old arm-chair, Had been
                            potatoes. But now they were gone ; of bad or good, Not one was left for the old lady's food,
                            Of those potatoes; And she sighed and said, "What shall I do? Where shall I send, and to
                            whom shall I go For more potatoes?" And she thought of the deacon over the way, The deacon
                            so ready to worship and pray, Whose cellar was full of potatoes, [come, And she said, "I
                            will send for the deacon to He'll not mind much to give me some Of such a store of
                            potatoes." And the deacon came over as fast as he could, Thinking to do the old lady some
                            good, But never, for once, of potatoes; He asked her at once what was her chief want, And
                            she, poor soul, expecting a grant, Immediately answered, "Potatoes." But the deacon's
                            religion didn't lie that way; He was more accustom'd to preach and to pray Than to give of
                            his hoarded potatoes ; [said So, not hearing, of course what the old lady He rose to pray
                            with uncovered head, But she only thought of potatoes. He prayed for patience and wisdom and
                            grace, But when he prayed, "Lord give her peace," She audibly sighed, "give potatoes;" At
                            the end of each ].rayer which he said, He heard, or thought that he heard in its stead The
                            same request for potatoes. [do, The deacon was troubled; knew not what to 'Twas very
                            embarrassing to have her act so About "those carnal potatoes." So, ending his prayer, he
                            started for home, But as the door closed, he heard a deep groan, "Oh, give to the hungry
                            potatoes." And that groan followed him all the way home In the midst of the night it haunted
                            his room, "O, give to the hungry potatoes !" He could bear it no longer, arose and dress'd,
                            From his well-filled cellar taking in haste A bag of his best potatoes. SI-IATiKJR
                                M-AJSTrFICSTO.<pb n="306" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 3O6 THJE SHAKBE Again, he went to the widow's lone
                            hut; Her sleepless eyes she had not yet shut; But there she sat, in that old arm-chair,
                            [air, With the same wan features; the same sad And, entering, he poured on the floor A
                            bushel or more from his goodly store Of choice potatoes. TIih widow's heart leaped up for
                            joy, Her face was haggard and wan no more. "Now," said the deacon, "shall we pray?" "Yes"
                            said the widow, "Now you may," And he kneel'd him down on the sanded floor, Where he poured
                            this goodly store, And such a prayer the deacon prayed As never before his lips essayed; No
                            longer embarrassed, but free and full, He poured out the voice of a liberal soul, And the
                            widow responded a loud "Amen," But said no more of potatoes. And would you who hear this
                            simple tale, Pray for the poor, and praying "prevail," Then preface your prayers with alms
                            &amp; deeds ; Search out the poor their wants &amp; their needs, Pray for peace, and
                            grace, and spiritual food, [good, For wisdom, and guidance, for all these are But don't
                            forget the potatoes.</p></div3><div3 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good law" TEIform="index"/>A Good Law</head><p TEIform="p">The State of Indiana made a law in 1835, that for every profane and blasphemous use of the
                            name of God, Jesus Christ or other sacred names, a fine of not less than one, nor more than
                            three dollars shall be levied. Good; now let this law be attended to, or let its swearers
                            pay off its share of the National debt.</p></div3><div3 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good reminder" TEIform="index"/>A Good Reminder</head><p TEIform="p">The earliest converts to Christianity in Africa, were very earnest and regular in their
                            private devotions. They had no closets, rooms for retirement, but each had a separate spot
                            in the thicket, to which he used to go. The several paths to these little Bethels became
                            distinctly marked; and, when any one began to decline in the ways of God, it was soon
                            manifest to his fellows, and they would remind him of his duty, by saying, "Brodder, de
                            grass grow on your path yonder." The World of Anecdote. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talk from a public paper" TEIform="index"/>Plain Talk from a Public Paper</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The diversion of thought and energy toward these dreams of a king coming in
                                        the clouds is a waste of spiritual force which the community cannot afford. The
                                        community just at this time needs all the service the Church can give in
                                        training men in fidelity to their duties here and now. The sober fact that
                                        should force itself on religious men is that the churches have largely failed in
                                        training their members in the virtues which are most essential to a society like
                                        ours. . . The hard fact which every week's news bring home, is that church
                                        membership is no guarantee that a man is faithful in public life or upright in
                                        business. But it ought to be. The Church is bound to show that it does not hold
                                        devotedness and liberality to be in any sort substitutes for integrity. Its
                                        teach- ers are bound to preach honesty and faithfulness, not merely in general
                                        propositions, but in practical, searching demands. What does honesty require of
                                        a salesman? How far ought one to consider his customer's interest in a bargain?
                                        Does a man owe his creditors anything beyond what the law will exact? What are
                                        the moral obligations of a holder of trust funds? How far are the accepted
                                        methods in politics consistent with high prin- ciple? These are the things the
                                        ministers should concern themselves and their hearers with, for these are
                                        matters of daily duty,— vital if Christ were coming to-morrow, vital if He
                                        should never come at all among clouds and angels.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Springfield republican" TEIform="index"/>Springfield Republican.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="history" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Martyrdom of Huss" TEIform="index"/>The Martyrdom of Huss</head><p TEIform="p">The martyrdom of John Huss is thus related by Draper: "He was then made to kneel down and
                                receive his sentence. It condemned his writings and his body to the NL .AJSHGET'ESTO.<pb n="307" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> the; shakee 3O7 flames. He was then degraded and despoiled of his
                                orders. Some of the bishops mocked at him; some merciful, implored him to recant. They
                                cut his hair in the form of a cross and set upon his head a high paper crown on which
                                devils were painted, 'We devote thy soul to the devils in hell.' 'And I commend my soul
                                to the most merciful Lord Christ Jesus.' He was then led'forth. They passed by the
                                bishop's palace -where Plugs' books were burning.. As they tied him with a piece of
                                chain to his stake the painted crown fell off, but the soldiers replaced it. 'Let him
                                and his devils be burned together.' As the flames burnt over him he chanted psalms and
                                prayed to the redeemer." Can that be true which requires for its support the murder of a
                                true man?</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Funeral euglogies" TEIform="index"/>FUNERAL EULOGIES</head><p TEIform="p">Said a certain man of parts and great vices : 'Do not let such a minister speak at my
                                funeral, for he will lie in my favor : nor such a one, for he will gloat over my sins ;
                                but get a man of sense, that will leave me with God and posterity and say a tender word
                                to my family.' The praising of bad or equivocal men by the press or the pulpit has a bad
                                effect on youth, by instilling into their minds the feeling that there is, after all, no
                                radical distinction between the good and the bad. </p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We live in an age of pleasant frauds..." TEIform="index"/>We live in an age of pleasant frauds...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">We live in an age of pleasant frauds. Russia leather is made in Connecticut, Bordeaux
                                wine is manufactured on Kelley's Island, French lace is woven in New York, Italian
                                marble is dug in Kentucky, Marseilles linen is produced in Massachusetts, English
                                cassimere is made in New Hampshire, Parisian art work comes from a shop in Boston,
                                Spanish mackerel are caught on the New Jersey coast, and Havana cigars are xrolled by
                                the million in Detroit. And for practical purposes it is of small account. "A rose by
                                any other name," etc. But if one is troubled by a notion that things are only valuable
                                if genuine—that shams are inherently and forever wrong and annoying—why then he must
                                cultivate exceeding shrewdness, and nqt hope to get things "cheap."</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God bless our home" TEIform="index"/>"god bless our home."</head><p TEIform="p"> It is well enough to hang up a chromo with "God Bless our Home" on it, but it will do no
                                harm to help on the matter by a little less fretting. A great many people ask the Lord
                                to do what they won't lift their little fingers to do themselves.</p></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why the world hates christians" TEIform="index"/>Why The World Hates Christians</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">It is an utter delusion to suppose that there is any innate response to the
                                        perfect moral purity, or any innate admiration of ' 'the true, the pure, the
                                        just, the kind, the good, and the beautiful," in the heart of man. God gave man,
                                        1,800 years ago, a perfect pattern of purity, truth, and love, in the person of
                                        our Lord while he was upon earth. And yet we are told he was "hated." True
                                        Christians must never be surprised if they are "hated" like their Lord. "The
                                        disciple is not above his Master."—"Marvel not, my brethren, if the world hate
                                        you." (Matt. x. 24; John iii. 13.) In fact, the more like Christ they are, the
                                        more likely to be "hated." Moreover, they must not be cast down, and make
                                        themselves miserable, under the idea that it is their inconsistencies the world
                                        hates, and that if they were more consistent and lovely in life, the world would
                                        like them better. This is a complete mistake, and a common delusion of the
                                        devil. What the world hates about Christians is neither their doctrines nor
                                        their faults, but their holy lives. Their lives are a constant testimony against
                                        the world, which makes the men of the world feel uncomfortable, and therefore
                                        the world hates them. Let us note, that unpopularity among men is no proof that
                                        a Christian is wrong, either in faith or practice. The common notion of many,
                                        that it is a good sign of a person's character to be well-spoken of by
                                        everybody, is a great error. When we ^see how our Lord was regarded by the
                                        wicked and worldly of His day, we may well conclude that it is a very poor
                                        compliment to be told that we are liked by everybody.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Montreal star" TEIform="index"/>Montreal Star.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><pb n="308" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sowing and reaping" TEIform="index"/>Sowing And Reaping</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Proctor, Adelaide" TEIform="persName"/>Adelaide Proctor</byline><p TEIform="p">Respectfully referred to every Shaker Society. Sow with a generous hand, Pause not for toil
                            nor pain; Weary not through the heat of summer, Weary not through the cold spring rain; But
                            wait till the autumn comes For the sheaves of golden grain. Scatter the seed, and fear not,
                            A table will be spread; What matter if you are too weary To eat your hard earned bread! Sow,
                            while the earth is broken, For the hungry must be fed. Sow,—while the seeds are lying In the
                            warm earth's bosom deep, And your warm tears fall upon it,— They will stir in their quiet
                            sleep; And the green blades rise the quicker, Perchance for the tears you weep. Then
                            sow,—for the hours are fleeting, And the seed must fall, to-day; And care not what hands
                            shall reap it, Or if you have passed away Before the wraving corn-fields Shall gladden the
                            sunny day. Sow; and look onward, upward, Where the starry light appears,— Where, in spite of
                            the coward's doubting, Or your own heart's doubts and fears, You shall reap in joy the
                            harvest You have soAvn, to-day, in tears. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Obituary</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lowe, James (Jeremiah)" TEIform="index"/>James (Jeremiah) Lowe
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., Oct. 21, <persName reg="Lowe, James (Jeremiah)" TEIform="persName">James (Jeremiah)
                                Lowe</persName>, aged 82. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Schernberg, Theophilus" TEIform="index"/>Theophilus Schernberg
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., Oct. 1, <persName reg="Schernberg, Theophilus" TEIform="persName">Theophilus
                                Schernberg</persName>, aged 62.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goodwin, Marietta" TEIform="index"/>Marietta Goodwin
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., Oct. 12, <persName reg="Goodwin, Marietta" TEIform="persName">Marietta Goodwin</persName>,
                                aged 13. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dean, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Dean
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., Nov. 1, <persName reg="Dean, Sarah" TEIform="persName">Sarah Dean</persName>, aged 79
                                years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tarbox, Jane" TEIform="index"/>Jane Tarbox
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Alfred, Me., Oct. 22, <persName reg="Tarbox, Jane" TEIform="persName">Eldress Jane Tarbox</persName>,
                                aged 86 years. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vance, Shubal B." TEIform="index"/>Shubal B. Vance
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Alfred, Me., Oct. 23, <persName reg="Vance, Shubal B." TEIform="persName">Shubal B. Vance</persName>,
                                aged 76 years.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="home" TEIform="index"/> HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for chapped hands" TEIform="index"/>Cure For Chapped Hands</head><p TEIform="p">A solution of cider vinegar and pure glycerine in equal parts will cure the most stubborn
                                chapped hands on even the thinnest skin.</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Delicate alkali" TEIform="index"/>Delicate Alkali</head><p TEIform="p">A small piece of chalk put into a pitcher of water, without imparting any taste whatever
                                to the same, will yet exercise a corrective effect upon the stomach of any one afflicted
                                with acidity, or heartburn, as it is familiarly called.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homemade court-plaster" TEIform="index"/> Home-Made Court-Plaster</head><p TEIform="p">The following recipe comes to us well recommended : One ounce of French isinglass ; one
                                pint of warm water; stir till it dissolves; add ten cents' worth of pure glycerine and
                                five cents' worth of tincture of arnica; lay a piece of white or black silk on a board
                                and paint it over with the mixture.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prepared glue" TEIform="index"/> Prepared Glue</head><p TEIform="p">In half a pint of water in a wide-mouthed bottle put eight ounces of best glue, place the
                                bottle in water, and heat until the glue is dissolved. Then stir in slowly two and a
                                half ounces of strong nitric acid. Cork tightly. Glue thus prepared is always ready for
                                use, and may be applied to mending furniture, broken vessels, and other articles not
                                exposed to water. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New fruit" TEIform="index"/>A New Fruit</head><p TEIform="p">A novel freak of nature was lately shown us by D. A. Buckingham, the venerable elder of
                                Watervliet Society at Shakers, N. Y. It was about eighteen inches of grape vine, of
                                Delaware variety, upon which he had, early in the spring, stuck an early Rose potato to
                                prevent the vine from bleeding. The vine ¦had grown fuur or five feet from the ground,
                                and the potato had sprouted, and maintaining its vitality had grown nearly all over its
                                surface, curious mongrel fruit resembling equally well, potatoes and grapes, perhaps to
                                the number of fifty. The green foliage around the fruit was equally mixed, half and half
                                of potato and grape leaves. It is the purpose M.AJSTIWttS'FO.<pb n="309" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHARER 3O9 of the Elder, we learn, to try his hand at bringing into use, either a potato
                                with a grape skin, or a grape as large as a potato; and we wish him success in either
                                case. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oatmeal as an article of diet" TEIform="index"/>Oatmeal as an article of diet...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Oatmeal as an Article Of Diet.—It is surprising how enormously the consumption of
                                oatmeal has increased in our cities within the past few years ; but we suspect that its
                                merits as a cheap and highly nutritious food are not so generally appreciated in the
                                country. Every one knows how generally it is eaten in Scotland, and in some parts of
                                England it is equally popular as an article of diet. A correspondent of an English paper
                                says : "In West Cumberland, Westmoreland, and North Lancashire, especially in the rural
                                parts, it forms the staple of our food, not only amongst the laboring classes, but also
                                in the families of tradesmen and the well-to-do; the children of most of them have
                                porridge at least once a day. For the past forty years I have made my breakfast of a
                                pint of oatmeal porridge, with very rare exceptions, and nothing else, fasting for four
                                hours afterwards. If, however, I take any other form of breakfast, I find myself very
                                hungry before the next meal, which is never the case when I have had my porridge. I feel
                                assured that if the laborers of the southern counties, with their children, w uld but
                                take a basin of oatmeal and milk porridge night and morning, with such other food as
                                they can procure in the interval, we should have a much stronger and healthier race of
                                men and women than now exists. A few years ago I had a Devonshire girl living with me as
                                a servant. The girl was willing enough to work, but had not the stamina to perform it.
                                This I found, on questioning her, arose from the deficient and ill-advised diet on which
                                she had been reared. She shortly began to take her porridge night and morning, and this,
                                with a daily mid-day meal of meat, enabled her to perform her duties with ease,"</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A very fair oak stain may be produced by..." TEIform="index"/>A very fair oak stain may be produced by...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A very fair oak stain may be produced by equal parts of potash and pearlash, say two
                                ounces of each to about a quart of water. Keep it corked up in a bottle, and it is
                                always ready for use ; if it strikes too deep a color, add more water. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter XI" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR, CHAP. XI</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/>WILLIAM G. LIBBEY</byline><p TEIform="p">The reason of my leaving Eimeo was from an unrest that came upon my mind. The cause of
                                which I have never been able to understand. I had previously been quite contented, and
                                was fast becoming a native in every respect even the color of my skin changed by
                                exposure. I was acquiring their language, ate their food with good relish, whether
                                cooked or raw. In truth, I loved the natives and their pleasant island home. It was the
                                goal of my long cherished hopes. Yet when the unrest came over me, suddenly, like a
                                pall, my joy was gone forever ! Although my brother had not become reconciled to the
                                natives or their islands, yet he was not prepared for the sudden start which I urged. He
                                said : "What use to be in such a hurry?" I could assign no reason only, that I felt
                                impelled to leave the islands. Although in love with this easy half civilized life when
                                in Eimeo, I can now see very clearly what its effect would have been on my life,—our
                                northern energy would soon have been conquered by the influence of a tropical climate
                                and we should have become Tahitians in indolence at least. But I am grateful to akird
                                Providence for "whipping me out of this lazy Utopia." As our companions were going in
                                their boat with a load of sweet potatoes to Tahiti^ we went with them. Soon after our
                                arrival, Capt. Ray of the barque Draco of Fairhaven, a whaler, being in want of men,
                                asked my brother and myself to go with him. Accordingly, we shipped to be discharged in
                                Talcahuano in Chili. In a few days, we were again on the great south Pacific ocean,
                                cruising for whales. Now my kind young friends who have patiently followed us from
                                Fanning's island to the deck of the pleasant old Draco, I mmt mlajsteepe: sto*.<pb n="310" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 31O THE 8HAKBE reluctantly yield to the necessity of skipping
                                over minute details of this my last cruise in a whaler. Thanking the Editor and
                                Publisher for their lengthened patience I will try to close with the year 1878. The
                                officers and men on board the ship were agreeable companions. Nothing occurred for
                                several months to disturb the quiet routine of daily life at sea in the South Pacific.
                                The weather was uniformly good, time passed pleasantly, and we found no reason to regret
                                having joined the good old ship. On the last day of the year 1842, I came very near
                                losing my Brother. We had lowered our boats for a number of sperm whales that came near
                                the ship. The boat to which I belonged fastened to what whale-men call a forty barrel
                                bull,—considered the most dangerous kind of sperm whale. The chief mate had lanced him
                                and he was spouting blood, an indication that he was mortally wounded and would soon be
                                ours. Just then one of the crew of the second mate's boat said to that officer: ''Let us
                                go down and have a finger in that pie." Poor man! I think these were his last words, for
                                the second mate taking his lance, the harpooner, the steering oar, his boat came down
                                before the wind striking the whale on the windward side. As the boat struck, the second
                                mate gave him a lance which would have killed him, but the whale turned suddenly,
                                striking the boat and crushing it to pieces ! As I looked, it seemed the boat's crew
                                were all lost. A feeling of terrible anguish came over me,—my brother ¦was one of that
                                crew, and I thought had gone from my sight forever! But hope revived when I saw several
                                men rise to the surface and swim toward our boat. The line that held us to the whale was
                                cut, and seizing our oars, we pulled to the rescue of our struggling shipmates. The
                                carpenter who suggested going on to the whale, was never seen again. He pulled the
                                midship oar and was no doubt instantly killed as he was seated directly under the
                                fearful stroke. We saved the whale, and as I was helping under the main top to get up
                                the tackle for hoisting in the blubber, I noticed it was growing quite dark, on enquiry,
                                I learned that there was an eclipse of the Sun. This with our terrible accident made the
                                day a gloomy one indeed. Nothing remarkable occurred during the remainder of this
                                cruise. When we arrived at Talcahuano, after our six month's voyage in the old Draco,
                                the captain discharged us according to previous agreement. At this place I parted
                                company with my brother,—he shipping in a homeward-bound whaler, while I joined a
                                Chilian ship belonging to Valparaiso, in which I remained about six months, suffering
                                the same unrest I had first felt at Eimeo. Leaving the Hermosa Chilona at Valparaiso, I
                                shipped in an English brig bound for Swansey in Wales. On getting out to sea in this
                                vessel, she was found to be unseaworthy, and the crew headed by the carpenter, forced
                                the captain to put back at Valparaiso. Here I was taken sick and went to the American
                                hospital where I was treated very kindly by the English steward. This hospital was on
                                high ground overlooking the harbor and as I recovered from my sickness I kept a bright
                                look-out for ships bearing the American ensign. The very sight of the old flag with its
                                stars and stripes in that far land, was a comfort to me. I had no definite course in
                                mind to pursue,— my only thought was to go to sea in some merchant ship. I was resolved
                                on going in no more whalers. One day as I sat watching the shipping as usual, the
                                thought came suddenly to my mind : "I will go to the Shakers!" Now nothing was more
                                foreign to my previous plans. I instantly rejected it; yet so very strongly was the idea
                                presented, that I began to reason. Well, it is a good place in which to prepare for the
                                future life, and now the opportunity is offered me, I will accept it. It seemed that I
                                could not withstand the impression. As soon as I yielded, a joyous thankfulness filled
                                my heart, and I fell upon my knees to thank God for the bright prospect that opened
                                before me. The unrest vanished! The cause of which change I have yet to learn. But how
                                should I reach there? Would the Lord provide? In a few days to my surprise the United
                                States frigate "Constellation" came into the harbor and I was sent on board to go home
                                in her, with some other men who were at the hospital. Soon after going to ea I fully
                                recovered my health, and put my MLAJSrUPESTO.<pb n="311" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER 311 name
                                on the shipping articles for the remainder of the cruise. She had then been from home
                                over three years. We went to Peru, then around Cape Horn to Rio Janeiro, from thence to
                                Norfolk, Virginia. We entered Gosport navy yard, where the crew were finally paid off. I
                                reached Canterbury in safety, accompanied by a shipmate, one of the Constellation's
                                non-commissioned officers, a noble generoushearted sailor who died about one year since,
                                strong in the faith of the Shaker religion. When we .first reached Shaker Village, N.
                                H., I went to the Novitiate order and told the presiding Elder, Robert Fowle, that I had
                                come all the way from Valparaiso, Chili, in South America to be a Shaker. He then told
                                me that the first step toward this end would be to honestly confess my sins, and thus I
                                should be made able to live free from sin. He remarked that the gospel of Christ in this
                                second manifestation would save all who would obey it and enable them to live a pure
                                life, free from the lusts of the world. His words have proved true, and I have never for
                                one moment regretted obeying the sudden impression received on the high lands back of
                                the port of Valparaiso ! Thanking all my young friends who have followed me through my
                                wanderings from Fanning's island to the quiet Shaker Village among the hills of New
                                Hampshire, I bid you a kind adieu. (the end.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Farm and Garden</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farmers" TEIform="index"/>Farmers</head><p TEIform="p">In comparison with the longcontinued prostration of other industries and the severe
                                depression of general business, farmers may congratulate themselves that at least,
                                through long hours of toil and the practice of close economy, they have been able to
                                secure the necessaries of life for the support of their families and themselves. A
                                bushel of corn is worth just as much to-day in the feeding of a family as ever it was,
                                while it will buy as much sugar or as many yards of cotton cloth as in the average year,
                                and it is only when sold for cash, or when applied to the payment of old debts, that the
                                farmer really suffers from its low market value. Brighter days are coming, and the
                                severe lessons of economy and struggle with debt will have a salutary effect in avoiding
                                new liabilities in the future, and in making all classes more cautious and more thought-
                                ful in their plans.—Com Adv. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wintering calves" TEIform="index"/>Wintering Calves</head><p TEIform="p">The most difficult portion of cattle kind to keep through the season of the year of farm
                                stock that has to be fed are the calves. Every farmer possesses more or less of these,
                                and as it is designed for them to grow up and become of large size, every possible means
                                should be adopted to raise them to the greatest perfection. If they are not handled with
                                great care and the strictest attention paid to their welfare, their growth is liable to
                                be arrested, and such an injury received thereby as cannot be easily, if ever fully,
                                repaired by the best of treatment afterwards. Cattle are like everything else; if they
                                are stunted when young and their growth checked, they can never afterwards be made to
                                grow so thriftily as they would have done; and, therefore, too much pains cannot be
                                taken with them while calres to give them a good start. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Untidy barnyards" TEIform="index"/>Untidy barnyards
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Untidy Barnyards.—We desire to call the attention of some farmers—there are doubtless
                                but a few—to the untidy condition of their barn and stock yards. In some cases they are
                                filled with broken and disused machinery, rails, pieces of boards full of nails, clubs,
                                etc. We are reminded of this by hearing a farmer remark that he had lost a good colt by
                                its stepping on a rusty nail. There are many animals annually lost from this cause.] The
                                owners, however, are not entitled to sympathy; for a farmer who leaves boards, with
                                nails sticking up, lying around where stock is liable to run, deserves to lose his
                                cattle and colts. See to it at once that all such dangerous articles are piled up where
                                they may dry out and be used for kindling.— Chicago Tribune.</p></div3></div2><pb n="312" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Haven of rest" TEIform="index"/>HAVEN OF REST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. 1. O glorious haven of eternal rest, Where 2. This beautiful haven
                            of rest is prepared For weary so journers with all who in meekness of sorrow spirit oppressed, May have shared The find from their wand'rings a blissful repose, Where
                            suff'rings of Christ as becoming their lot, And MANIFESTO. HAVEN<pb n="313" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER 313 3. Such surely are numbered as servants of worth, Though clothed for a season
                            with vestments of earth, A blessing shall follow their faithful career, And rays of bright
                            glory their pathway will cheer. 4. Administ'ring guardians will stand by their side,
                            Upholding through dangers that often betide, Protecting and cheering with comforting love,
                            While nearing the portals of glory above. 5. Take courage, good pilgrims, in faith be ye
                            strong, A host is inviting and helping along, The progress is sure and you soon will be
                            blest, With blissful repose in the haven of rest. 6. There, there with the blessed Redeemer
                            to reign Supremely in glory,—thy infinite gain Will bring thee rejoicing and comfort
                            sublime, And mist in oblivion the sorrows of time. MANIFESTO. bloometh the lily and sweet,
                            fragrant rose, counted the same as a part wisely sought.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p28"/>
                        <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Editorials"/>Editorial Notes</head>
                        <div3 type="editorial">
                            <head>
                                <index level1="We are using a number of the Bickford Knitting Machines..."/>
                            </head>
                            <byline>
                                <persName reg="Editor"/>
                            </byline>
                            <p>We are using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory indeed, Being among
                                "the wonders in this age" of machinery. Their utility and expedition in business should be experienced by
                                all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of wood variety is getting scarce. "We must soon accept the
                                alternative of no fences, or rely on the metal ones offered us by Washbubn, Moen Co. We are at a loss to
                                speak as yet, of the best Water Wheel; but we are at no loss to say that the firms oi Leffel & Co.
                                and N.F.Burnham, who enter into friendly competition in our columns, are both most honorable. We find
                                Stinson and Co. very honorable in their dealing. Try them. We hope "everybody and his neighbor" will send us
                                six cents for a copy of "Plain Talks;" or ten cents, for two copies post paid. It is a pretty book. Please
                                procure it and present it to your friend. We would call especial attention to the new advertisement of N. F.
                                Burnham. As enterprise is ever praiseworthy when applied as they apply it, let every one lend this firm a
                                token of praise. If any can do better for the furnishing of Dry Goods, etc. than can be done at Wni. M.
                                Whitney & Co., we would be pleased to hear from such party. Take choice and choose soon from among
                                the most beautiful musical instruments advertised in our columns. Quite a number of families are the happier
                                to-day for taking our advice, and buying their Organs and Pianos of well "read and you will know.' D.
                                II. Fonda, the most enterprising of Druggists, etc. can be relied upon by parties, near by or distant, who
                                are in want of anything m his line, wholesale and retail. Try him, prove him. ¦ Any parties who would learn
                                how we make such good, "gilt-edged" butter, must read an article entitled " Gilt-Edged Butter Maker"
                                Gillott's Pens are unequaled by any other steel pen; and we deem his No. 332 equal in every thing but wear o
                                the best gold pen. Get Gillott's Pens. —Who is powerful? He who can control his passions.—Who is rich? He
                                who is contented with what he has.</p>
                        </div3>
                    </div2>
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>