<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0802" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">36</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">N. A. Briggs</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">8</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">2</biblScope><date value="18780201" TEIform="date">February 1878</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-52</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="8" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="2" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--  
                        <pb id="p1"/>
                        <p> Vol. VIII. NO. 2. FEBRUARY 60 Cts. per Annum, POST PAID. THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.)
                        PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES, OUR HOME AT CANTERBURY, N. H. GO PREACH THE KINGDOM OF GOD." 1878. PUBLISHED AND
                        PRINTED AT SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H. N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher. </p>
                    <pb n="24" id="p2"/>
                    <p> Are the Shakers Christians? Character Christian Culture No. 9. Facial Influence Sin No. 2. ... Shaker Criticism
                        Selfish PropertyDeath of the Wicked Sun-rise . ... Address to the Young Innocence Salvation Hang out the Lights Our
                        Activities . . , Indians No. 1. Warning . Plain Christian Dress 25 New Year's Greeting 37 . 2G Ann Lee . 38 . 27 Dr.
                        J. M.Peebles . . . 40 . 28 Correspondence. 40 . 29 Let us earn our Pay . 41 30 The Shaker Manifesto :Its Wor6t . "
                        Enemies 41 31 Editorial Notes . 43 For the Children 46 32 Farm & Garden 47 . 33 Home Topics . . 48 " Society
                        Record . 48 . 34 Book Table 49 Music .... 50 . 35 Selected . ¦ . .51 . 3G Obituary TERMS OF ADVERTISING. For one
                        inch, one insertion $ 1. 00 " one half column, " " $ 3. 00 one " " f $6.00 page, " " $12.00 Continued insertion for
                        three months, 20 per ct. discount. " six " 25 " " " one year, 33£ " " Subscriptions, Sixty cents, per year. Address,
                        N. A. Briggs, Shaker Village, Mer. Co., N. H. Subscription will begin when order is received.—No back numbers.
                        CONTENTS </p> --><pb n="25" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER MANIFESTO AN OFFICIAL MONTHLY. G. A. LOMAS Editor. Shakers, N. Y. VOL.
                        VIII.—FEBRUARY, 1878.—No. II. </p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Are the Shakers Christians?" TEIform="index"/>ARE THE SHAKERS CHRISTIANS?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName">ELDER ABRAHAM PERKINS
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> In a recent number of The Shaker, I was peculiarly impressed with the question in one of its
                            columns : " Was Jesus of Nazareth a Shaker?" The interrogatory was clearly, candidly and
                            ably answered. From it, grew the thought, that the question should be reversed; that the
                            subject should be investigated, and proclaimed what the Shakers are ; whether Christians or
                            infidels. To the Shaker sect, the terms Shake r and Christian are synonymous. If Jesus was a
                            Shaker, a Shaker is a Christian. The life and doctrine of the Nazarene are precisely what
                            the Shakers consider necessary to produce Christianity. He was a celibate ; and in his life
                            he practically carried out purely virgin principles. So do the Shakers. He was the Prince of
                            Peace, ignored war, declaring that those who used the sword should perish by it. The Shakers
                            are peacemakers and take no part in shedding human blood. Whereas the first Christian church
                            formed at Jerusalem was established on communistic principles, agreeably to the practice of
                            Jesus and his disciples previous to the organization of a church, thus is the Shaker church
                            established. Confession was practiced in the apostolic church ; the same ordinance is
                            required and carried out in the Shaker church. The primitive church took no part in earthly
                            governments ; so the Shakers accept no office of State, side with no party nor meddle with
                            politics. As in the days of the early Christians it was a requirement that they should owe
                            no man aught but love and good-will, so it is a violation of Shaker principles to vary from
                            that principle. Jesus required justice and honesty in all the dealings of life. So do the
                            Shakers. Meekness, gentleness and truth marked the life and character of Jesus : so do these
                            graces conspicuously adorn the life of the Shaker. Simple language, plainness of speech,
                            free from vulgarism and profanity characterized the habits and manners of Jesus: so they do
                            the same of the Shakers. Temperance was the doctrine of Jesus: it is also that of the
                            Shakers. Pride, arrogance, selfishness, error and vice of every kind was wholly abrogated by
                            Jesus ; so they are by the Shakers; and whoever of the sect varies in any one of the
                            principles, as lived by our Master, fails in sustaining Shaker life,<pb n="26" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKEE ML^JNTIIPESTO. however strongly he avows Christian principles or however much he
                            glories in the name of Shaker; and in his disobedi- ence, he deservedly merits the severe
                            rebuke both of his own order and the outside world. What then are our obligations ? Simply
                            to live soberly, honestly, justly, truthfully. "Be what we seem to be, and seem to be what
                            we really are." Not clouds of darkness, obscuring the sunlight of truth ; obstacles in the
                            way of reformation and hindrances to progress : deceivers, truce-breakers, liars and mockers
                            of God. And would we see the progress of souls in gospel travel, we would be strenuously
                            exacting in our lives, giving no place for Satan to work destruction and loss. This is
                            consecration: no other than Shaker life, Christianity. Can we be Christians in the truest
                            sense, but in squaring our lives by these principles? "He that hath ears to hear, let him
                            hear:" and he that will live in Christ, let him bring himself strictly to the spirit of his
                            life and example, and depart from all iniquity. Enfield, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Character" TEIform="index"/>CHARACTER</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Sarah A." TEIform="persName">SARAH A. NEAL
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> To improve character requires something more than the simple desire to become better. Our
                            ideal of a true character may be of a very exalted type, and we may desire to become like
                            unto it; but unless we plant four desires in the soil of active services where they can grow
                            unto fruitfulness, we shall realize to our sorrow that blight will soon bring them to death
                            and decay. Actions form the character; while desires often vanish with the sounds which give
                            them expression. Character, like principle, maintains a positive indifference to all things
                            save facts and realities ; and though we may often attribute our neglect of character to
                            those peculiar influences which circumstances sometimes associate with us, yet those who so
                            love their character as to live for it, guard it so well, that circumstantial influences
                            cannot improperly affect it. AH have not sufficient moral courage to do this ; but such as
                            have not, live largely for reputation, leaving character in the shade of careless neglect,
                            only to be regretted in the near future. The acquisition of a true character is no mere
                            business speculation, neither does it particularly embody political policies ; but embraces
                            in life the verb to do something, with an honesty of purpose that will stamp indelible
                            impressions of goodness on our entire life-record; and thus character becomes the volume
                            that contains this record; for on its sad or pleasant pages we find the impress of our
                            thoughts and actions; and those who would review a delightful account therein, must live a
                            righteous life. Character is eternal; it lives when all finite forms turn into dust; hence
                            the necessity of commencing in childhood, continuing in youth, nor forsaking in more mature
                            years, that life which will cause us to feel, as the shadows of age creep over us, and the
                            evening of our earth-life draws near, that we have in possession, a character free from all
                            blemish—one that will recommend" us to friends above, and by which we shall be recognized as
                            members of that home, wherein dwell the pure in heart who always see God. Shakers, N. Y. 26
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 9" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN CULTURE. No. 9</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H." TEIform="persName">WM. H. BUSSELL
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Reason : This may be denned as the power of perceiving truth. It matters not whether the
                            perception be immediate or the result of long investigation. The infinite Mind is the
                            infinite Reason; for "all things are open to him." The human mind is necessarily limited and
                            perceives truth only by degrees. The plain inference, therefore, is that the human reason is
                            the subject of culture. An essential requisite of correct reasoning is knowledge. "Of God
                            above or man below, What can we reason but from what we know ?" The child and the savage are
                            alike at fault, often, in their inferences drawn from objects of sight. They need to correct
                            them by ^heir individual experience. But the lapse of years, and sometimes of ages, is
                            necessary before that can be done. But it matters not. Truth will finally reward her
                            votaries. "The eternal years of God are hers." The heaven in which the star-gazers of olden
                            time located sun, moon and stars, was too far away for them to be able to rectify any
                            mistakes of their untutored reason. It was reserved to the modern astronomer, aided by the
                            enlarged vision which the telescope has given, to show that the heaven of the ancients, gods
                            and goddesses all, has been removed "beyond the bounds of time and space," where a poet of
                            modern orthodoxy has located "the saints' secure abode." But though that "heaven has fled
                            away," yet the sun, moon and stars shine with no less brilliancy than ever. The sun of truth
                            remains steadfast, whatever human conceptions of it may be, showing itself little by little
                            through cloud and mist, over hill and mountain, and will con- tinue until the effulgence of
                            high noon shall illuminate the enraptured soul on the plains of immortality. The human
                            imagination is fertile in inventions. Reason is too slow for it; all its deductions are
                            speedily outrun. The thousand and one fables of Arabian story bear no comparison in
                            absurdity to those which have been imposed upon human ignorance by persons professing to be
                            teachers of truth, especially religious truth. And what seems the strangest of all , there
                            has been no invention of hea then priests, however absurd and horrible, but has been more
                            than matched in absurdity and horribleness by many who have claimed to occupy the seat from
                            which Jesus dispensed the teachings of divine love. There is no need of quoting passages to
                            prove this assertion; they have been repeated so often within the present century by the
                            opponents of such doctrines that the ear has become weary of hearing them. In fact, the
                            legitimate successors of those who once used them so freely now rarely even "mention hell to
                            ears polite," much less depict it in its formerlu rid colors. What then ? Is the imagination
                            a useless faculty in the human mind? Rather, has it not, like all the other faculties, often
                            been perverted from its normal condition and use ? When not controlled by reason, it is fond
                            of extravagant things. It loves to conjure up "Gorgons and hydras and chimseras dire." It
                            resembles then the perverts ed physical appetite; the more injurious to the health that
                            which is taken into the stomach, is the greater the craving for it. The healthful appetite
                            is satisfied with that which maintains health; that which is perverted never is satisfied.
                            The mind fond of strange imaginings is, to say the least, partially insane. This will
                            account for many of the outrageous superstitions and fanaticisms among savage tribes. These
                            have been imposed upon ignorant minds by the terror that half insane talent knows how to
                            excite, more especially when it professes to have intercourse with the gods. So among many
                            of the Christian sects, the most excited and loud-mouthed revivalist has created the
                            greatest furor among excitable people But there may be enthusiasm and yet not extravagance.
                            The mind governed by the principles of the soundest reason may be also actuated by the
                            warmest and kindest feelings. Some have represented reason as cold, stern and repulsive. But
                            this is altogether misrepresentation. Reason is allied to the highest and purest love. It
                            walks hand in hand with humility. It is the companion of gentleness. It is the most ardent
                            lover of the beautiful. 27<pb n="28" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 28 THE SHAKER MLAJNTIIEPICSTO. It is the
                            enemy of tyranny and slavery of every kind. It is the opponent of wars and contentions among
                            men. There is no genuine reform that it does not favor. Let it be untrammeled by ignorance,
                            bigotry and hatred, and soon it would make the earth the garden of God. Thomas Paine, in the
                            last century, styled his book which created such a furor among theologians "The Age of
                            Reason." But it was rather a herald announcing a stern conflict about to arise. The age of
                            reason has not yet commenced, if we are to judge by the wars and strifes yet prevalent. Yet
                            its precursor has come. Passion still bears sway in multitudes of minds, but principle is
                            beginning to assert its rights. There is no longer the ''darkness that may be felt," but
                            such an intermingling of the light with it that objects may be distinctly seen. One may, if
                            he will, distinguish truth from error, though Paine's book scarcely aids him to do it. It
                            lacks discrimination. It aimed powerful blows at theological errors and thereby aroused the
                            ire of their defenders ; but he made an indiscriminate slaughter of innocent and guilty. It
                            is the province of reason to discriminate between the precious and the vile ; to spare the
                            truth when aiming to destroy error. What matters it to the gold-seeker if the precious metal
                            be found mingled with the hardest granite or various other minerals and metals? When he has
                            discovered it, he knows how to free it from all alloy. This is his reasoning process. The
                            moral reasoner as well as the scientific should be able and candid enough to acknowledge
                            every truth and see that it does not suffer by his manipulations. Groveland, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Facial influence" TEIform="index"/>FACIAL INFLUENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Neal, Emma J." TEIform="persName">EMMA J. NEAL
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Meeting a friend not long since, I remarked to myself as I passed: "What can be the matter
                            with sister S. ! she looks so gloomy, and acts in such a reticent manner, when we are such
                            genial friends and our tastes so generally concur ? What can this mean ?" A voice seemed to
                            interrupt my ponderings saying; "You beheld the visage of your sister: had you been able at
                            that moment to have seen your own countenance, I think the sight would respond to your
                            inquiry. At this kind admonition of my mental guai-dian, I tried to reproduce the tenor of
                            thought, in which I was occupied when passing my sister ; and soon succeeded in painting the
                            whole scene that was then agitating my brain. I hastened to my room; placed myself before
                            the mirror, and strove to repeat the expression of countenance, which I imagined to have
                            seen, to see how I should be affected at a sight of my real self; but dear reader I need
                            hardly tell you the result. In entire disregard of my efforts at self examination,
                            mirthfulness predominated ; and if sister S. had seen me, the seeming coldness would have
                            melted into a genial laugh, at the strange contortions of the facial muscles, first moulded
                            by mj former thoughts, then suddenly twisted into a broad grin, at the real sight of my ugly
                            self. It is in this way, great evils are often created; and many friendships broken or
                            cooled ; being unmindful of the influence that even a look may sometimes have upon our
                            surrounding friends. While our faces should ever be set as a flint against wrong, and the
                            flatterer's smile, we should be careful not to rob them of the sunshine of virtue, as we
                            may, by a sullen countenance, and thus, unintentionally perhaps, close the avenues of love ;
                            but on the contrary we<pb n="29" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 29 should create affection,
                            by kindly words seasonably spoken. In all the great duties of life, let us be mindful that,
                            "Sands form the mountain and little acts make up the sum of life." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sin, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>SIN. No. 2.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName">
                                ALONZO
                                HOLLISTER
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> WHOM DOES MAN INJURE BY SINNING? Not that Almighty who dwells in in- accessible light; which
                            no earthly man can ever approach unto—and in whose power the united strength of the
                            inhabitants of earth is reputed as nothing— and to whom mere mortals are "unprofitable
                            servants," after doing all that lies in their power! What can a man do tilting against the
                            Sun ? Nay, against the wind ? Then how much less against the infinite and viewless One,
                            whose servants these are! The soul that sins, 13 injured by transgression, and also the
                            interest of his neighbor, who is entitled to our sincere confidence and service ; to our un-
                            blemished gifts and untarnished sympathies. And since without him, we cannot hold relation
                            to God, common wisdom teaches that here is where the wrong must be repaired, and the best
                            relations cherished, that can be, in our rudimental conditions. From whom does the
                            transgressor seek to cover his sins? Not from the omniscient One, whom man places so far
                            distant in his fancy that the thought of Him has no place in the mind, in transgression, and
                            therefore cannot exert restraining power, although He is abstractly believed to be
                            everywhere present, "beholding the evil and the good." It is evident that the sinner fears
                            the detection and scrutiny of just men, more than God ; and so long as he has any sense of
                            propriety left, or fear of punishment, he seeks, to hide from men, his low, mean, dirty acts
                            ; particularly those beastly acts of uncleanness, which tend to destroy all self-respect,
                            self-confi- dence,—undermine self-hood, dethrone intelligence, and stamp the visage with an
                            idiotic stare. Such cannot know God, except through the distortion of a corrupted fancy,
                            until the covering of hypocrisy is taken off, and the criminal returns to the rule of a pure
                            conscience ; not until by suitable atonement, he re-establishes true and healthy relations
                            to the general economy of universal life, to which he is justly indebted to the extent of
                            his active powers of service. All sins are works of darkness, which league the sinner with
                            the power8 of darkness, and bring death not only upon the doer, but also upon those with
                            whom he is socially connected, until the evil is put away by confession and repentance.
                            Hence it is the right and duty of the children of God, to know those whom they receive into
                            their communion ; both their internal and external history, and how far they can be trusted
                            ; what their weaknesses are, and wherein they need assistance, as much as it is for a
                            physician to know the habits, constitution, and irregularities of his patient; and if these
                            have been wrong, he is expected to change. "God is Light, and in Him is no darkness," and
                            those who dwell with God, dwell in light, and have no fellowship with works of darkness, but
                            rather reprove them.<pb n="30" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 3O THE SHAKEE MAOTFESTO. And "if we walk in the
                            light, we have fellowship one with another," with Christ, and with God. And the life of the
                            infinite and holy One, flows through us, and cleanses and nourishes us in the growth of
                            God's kingdom of eternal peace and righteousness. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker criticism" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER CRITICISM.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName">
                                ELDER
                                F.
                                W.
                                EVANS
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Winter Shakers and temporary Shakers, still seek a place in Shaker Communities. They come,
                            desiring the advantages of the Community without obeying its Rules and Orders, or really
                            believing in its principles. Were there not a spiritual power, behind the throne of
                            government in the Society, its extinction, so often predicted by outsiders, would speedily
                            occur. Here is a man of large, worldly expe- rience who possesses a little personal
                            property, but he clings to it as with the grasp of death. He wants the individual freedom of
                            a worldly man; and also to enjoy the collective results flowing from individual sacrifices,
                            made by other and nobler souls. He wants to be served by two masters, whereas, masters
                            expect to be served. He does not yield himself to serve either. The Elder appeals to a
                            higher powerto the Spirits—for help. They impres another person, who knows nothing oi the
                            circumstances, with the following communication. We withhold the names of the person who
                            took part in the following visionary dream, because they are so graphically represented and
                            well known. Their fac-similies exist in many families, if no in all Communities. A very
                            little pri- vate interest like what Achan reserved, may cause much trouble, in a family
                            where all things in common is the organic Law. Be what you seem or profess to be, and
                            profess and seem to be what you are, is wisdom for Believers. Then, the windows of heaven
                            may be opened, and blessings unnumbered flow from companies of redeemed men and women in the
                            Spirit world—like showers in early Spring. Here follows : </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Selfish property" TEIform="index"/>Selfish Property</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Shaker Sisters" TEIform="persName">A Visionary Dream by one of the Shaker Sisters</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> It seemed the family were in meeting for worship, when suddenly there came something like a
                            tidal wave of spirit power, which spread over the whole assembly. Some who had never before
                            been baptized, were touched, as with a live coal from God's burning altar of truth. I
                            noticed one particularly, who was shaken powerfully. He seemed something like a whipped
                            child half subdued, wondering whether it would be better to give up his will or retain it.
                            He fell back against the wall and cried bitterly, his secret feelings, unbidden, came to the
                            surface, and he was forced to express them. He said, "Here I am, I have forsaken father,
                            mother, wife, children, houses and landa, everything, and have worked well;" then holding
                            forth both hands, in which were $2.25, he said, "See, this is all the reward I have
                            received!" He cried with a loud voice, "Is this just? Can I bear it?" One of the sisters
                            said, "You are mistaken; that is not the kind of reward offered. Were you even a happy,
                            contented man while in possession of earthly riches and friends you talk about?" He said,
                            "Nay, but I have given up so much for so small an equivalent!" The sister replied, "It was
                            the lusts, inseparably connected with the generative life and order, that made you an
                            unhappy man there. The<pb n="31" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 3X reward offered in this
                            gospel, to those who forsake that order, is not the paltry sum of $2.25,—not even one cent,
                            as private, individual property—but the fire of truth, that will burn up the lusts
                            pertaining to that order, that make you and are still making thousands of others unhappy.
                            Dry up your tears, turn your thoughts away from dollars and cents, and be consistent. Cease
                            mourning for the past and doubting the present, be willing to accept God's terms and the
                            reward He is pleased to give, if you would be happy." Mt. Lebanon,N. Y. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Death of the wicked" TEIform="index"/>Death of the Wicked</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName">
                                JAMES
                                G.
                                RUSSELL
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> The wicked must die—is the warning decree, For death is the price to be paid;— Tho' many
                            would seek from its grasp to be free, The summons they cannot evade. O'er mountains, thro'
                            valleys, o'er rivers and seas, In hamlet, in desert, or cave, The guilty may wander, their
                            fears to appease, From death no endeavor can save. Yet God hath declared that no pleasure he
                            hath In death of the wicked, but would That sinners return to the straight, narrow path,
                            That leads to the fountain of good. The caviler—heretic like—may deny That death is the doom
                            of the vile; "But Christian and sinner as equals must die, Though workers of goodness or
                            guile. For God sendeth rain on the just and unjust, His sun shineth clear upon all; That we
                            are his children—created of dust; He careth for great and for small I" Then how may we know
                            that the wicked must die&gt; Though wicked indeed they may be? How may we the
                            interpretation apply, That all may discern and agree ? "The wicked shall not live out half
                            of their days," "We read in the Record of Truth : That such as persist in their own evil
                            ways, Shall die, though in spring-time of youth. In what, then, doth wickedness really
                            consist? The word is in meaning defined As Zaw)-violations; those laws which exist Of God
                            and His nature, combined. We cannot the laws of our being discard, Whatever our reasons
                            might be; We know that the way of transgression is hard; That in it we cease to be free. Our
                            penalties correspond with the offense : If mental transgressions are ours We suffer with
                            mental prostration, and hence, Our shipwreck of reasoning powers. The body, at alliance
                            close with the mind, Must share the affliction in part; Our physical organization we find,
                            Is destined to suffer the smart. Again, do we violate physical law, Inhaling unpurified air;
                            Betimes from the fount of Intemperance draw. Thus death-dealing weapons prepare! With
                            appetite morbid, and brain all ablaze, Indulgence, then darkness and gloom! Thus life being
                            spent in intemperate ways, Destruction is surely the doom. "The wicked must die" then, the
                            penalty's sure,. The reason we plainly can see, If we to our full term of years would
                            endure, We must from transgressions be free. The laws of the spirit, the body, or mind, If
                            we with indifference slight, Afflictions—diseases of every kind, Our ev'ry enjoyment will
                            blight. Perfection consists in maintaining the right, In body, in mind, and in soul; Thus
                            living, our days will be happy and bright. And Death will resign its control. Enfield, N. H.
                        </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sun-rise" TEIform="index"/>SUN-RISE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Caswell, Edith D." TEIform="persName">EDITH D. CASWELL </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> It was my good fortune not long since, to witness a most glorious sun-rise; and although
                            this is by no means a rare opportunity for early risers, yet, my attention was unusually
                            held to the phenomenon. As I observed its slow but sure ascent above the horizon I thought
                            thus : "This glorious sun but symbolizes the testimony of truth which I, with many other
                            companions, have been early blest to understand. A testimony which in spiritual power and
                            brightness, by far exceeds yon rising sun, whose beams will one day illumine the darkest
                            portions of the moral and religious world. A testimony which has power to justify the good,
                            or condemn the bad. 0 that I may be as steady in my upward progress, as fixed in holy
                            purpose, as the sun appears, to me, in its course—that I may fully perform the mission to
                            which I have been called is my prayer; and here, let me pledge before God, that I will never
                            yield the strife against evil, nor cease to watch and pray till I rise in purity to my
                            heavenly home ; where my freed spirit shall shine by the light of truth, as clearly as the
                            sun, which so enchanted my vision. Canterbury, N. H.<pb n="32" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 32 </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Address to the young" TEIform="index"/>ADDRESS TO THE YOUNG.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName">
                                ELDER
                                HENRY
                                C.
                                BLINN
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> It is with much satisfaction and pleasure that I take the present opportunity to address
                            you. Designating me, as you are pleased to do, a gospel parent, I shall speak as to beloved
                            children in the Lord's House, those who have shared in the privileges and benefits of a
                            beautiful, Christian home. Although you are still young, and your baptism into a spiritual
                            experience correspondingly limited; yet I have the assurance in the manifestations of your
                            lives, that you most fully comprehend the order of the work into which you have been called.
                            You have proved by many trials that you are able to conquer the adversary of your souls.
                            Therefore, rejoice in holy trust, while pass- ing through the flames, that they cannot
                            consume, and through the waters, that they cannot overwhelm. It is not well to think too
                            much of the errors and troubles of the past; learn from them a lesson, and watch well the
                            course of present action. See that pure aims underlie every undertaking in life. You have
                            many years before you, in which to do good and to be good. Let me advise you to accept the
                            kind word of the poet: "Look on the sunny side, ye who are youthful, Gather the light that
                            will ever abide; The way to be hopeful, and healthful, and happy, Is to keep right before
                            you, the bright sunny side." The traveler who ascends the lofty mountains, does it at the
                            peril of his life. His triumph is to overcome alla obstacles. When he has reached the
                            anticipated height, all that he has passed through, is considered of the least consequence.
                            The separation from near and dear friends, the fatigue, the deprivations of the comforts of
                            life, are now all lost in the attainment of the one great object. It should be the same in
                            your case. Keeping your union in the pure spirit of Christ's testimony, carries you above
                            the elements of a mere worldly life, where you may stand in confidence with all your
                            beloved, Christian friends. Do you not remember the journey of our old brother Pilgrim, who
                            was beset with al- most every conceivable temptation and trial, while on his pilgrimage to
                            the kingdom? Indeed, it would be difficult to determine which in the extended list was the
                            worst! One may be as effectually ruined in the building of air castles, as in the commission
                            of some crime; through ignorance, as through willfulness. Any trespass against the spiritual
                            convictions which one has received, if persisted in, would ultimate in the ruin of the soul.
                            It matters not whether it is a transgression that has received an opprobrious name, or a
                            trespass that may be looked upon with seeming indifference. Read what the apostle says
                            concerning the commandments: "If we break one, we mar the beauty of the whole law." But my
                            beloved young friends, you are learning to beautify your lives by carefulness ; to make
                            perfect the spirit-offering which it is yours to give. In our seasons of worship, I listen
                            with great pleasure to your renewed resolutions to walk more circumspectly before God and
                            your associates and seniors, thus living so as to develop substantial characters. I know
                            full well how essential all this carefulness is, to insure your protection in the Christian
                            strife. These testimonies and the many good works which they inspire, are the power of
                            preservation which serves you for the time being, and inspires you to look forward with joy
                            and love, to a day of greater light, and to a deeper understanding of the work of the cross.
                            I am impressed to speak as I do, because of the earnestness which you manifest to maintain
                            your rectitude and pure association. You certainly will never have reason to regret your
                            steadfastness. All the treasure of this world could never purchase for you a pure spirit, a
                            life in God. Whatever it may have the power to give, it also has the power to take away. Be
                            very careful how you ac- cept of its many flattering gifts. So far you have kept good faith;
                            for it is nothing less than faith in God, and in the spirit of goodness, that can work so
                            effectually for good in your youthful minds. To the young, the buoyant and hopeful, it is by
                            no means strange that mysterious phases should arise in the MAJSTZEPIESTO.<pb n="33" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 33 mind, as the most gorgeous phantoms present
                            themselves for acceptance. "How smiling the world's prospect lies, How tempting to go
                            through! Not Canaan to the Prophet's eyes, From Pisgah, with a sweet surprise, Did more
                            inviting show." How fondly we may stretch forth our hands to receive this world's proffered
                            gift; but we reach only to grasp the air. You have already gained too much, have been too
                            deeply engaged in the angel work of harvesting the eoul from the earth, to have all this
                            precious treasure and labor lost. "Hold fast that which thou hast gained, and let no man
                            take thy crown." As trifling as the gain may be, it is your crown of life. It is the
                            consciousness of doing right before God, regardless of the frowns or flattery of this world.
                            By and by, the force which these may now have, will all fade away, but the maintenance of
                            the principles of truth and right, will dwell with you, an everlasting reward. This same
                            truth you must be able to give to others, quickened into life by the testimony of a pure
                            spirit, as it has through the testimony of the cross been given to you. For the consummation
                            of this spiritual gift, to the renewal of your whole life, and to the establishing of your
                            feet upon a permanent foundation, I shall earnestly pray. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Innocence" TEIform="index"/>INNOCENCE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="E." TEIform="persName">E.</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Innocence! a brighter pearl Than ever Monarchs wore; A treasure for surpassing The earth's
                            most valued ore. I'd not exchange thy beauty For purple robes or gold, To wield a kingly
                            sceptre Or his vast riches hold. When done with transient glories These all must be
                            resignedt The soul will be divested The tenement consigned; But innocence and purity
                            Retained, will sit enthroned Forever, throughout ages— A living virtue crowned. Canterbury,
                            N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salvation" TEIform="index"/>SALVATION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Danford, Nancy G." TEIform="persName">
                                NANCY
                                G.
                                DANFORD
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> There seems to be an idea, prevailing in many minds, of saving the soul independently of the
                            body. This is erroneous, as it can never be done while we dwell in clay tenements. When the
                            soul is saved from all sin, the body will also be saved from the indulgences of low
                            passions, and appetites. Not only will it cease to be an instrument or medium for the worst
                            vices, but every wrong habit will be laid aside. With this view of the subject, it will
                            readily be seen by every one who realizes how hard it is to leave old practices, which may
                            have been strengthened by the growth of many years, how impossible is instant salvation. The
                            conviction that some favorite pleasure is wrong, may be, and often is, instantaneous; but
                            the power to leave it forever, comes by slow growth attained through sacrifice, attended by
                            constant watchfulness and prayer. When we have gained power sufficient to keep us from
                            falling into temptation, this may be called salvation, but not redemption. This is only
                            obtained when we have so far overcome the world, that we cannot be tempted of evil. When
                            Satan cometh and can find nothing in us, whereby he can excite evil desires, then shall we
                            become like our Lord and Master. When the love of God reigns supremely in the heart, it will
                            manifest itself by love and kindness to those around us, thus inspiring them to love and
                            good works. In this way shall we see salvation wrought out through the organism of the
                            physical body. Hence our faith in the resurrection of the body from all evil and wrong
                            habits, pertaining to the laws of this life, and through this medium, can the soul be
                            resurrected to that which is higher, even unto life eternal. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Life" TEIform="index"/>Life</head><p TEIform="p">The secret of prolonging life is not to abridge it by any excesses. Live regularly, eat
                            regularly and slowly. Take enough sleep; most people require ight hours, at least, of sleep.
                            Don't eat just before retiring to rest. </p></div2><pb n="34" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hang out the light" TEIform="index"/>"HANG OUT THE LIGHT"</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Ware, Josephine E." TEIform="persName">
                                JOSEPHINE
                                E.
                                WARE
                            </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> Once upon a dark, rainy night, two of my younger sisters after completing their day's toil,
                            were about to repair to their rooms in a distant dwelling. The way leading thereto being
                            over a somewhat dangerous path, they desired me to stand in the doorway till they had
                            reached their destination ; that, at least, they might realize my presence, although they
                            could not see me. I readily complied with the innocent wish, and while I thus stood gazing
                            into a darkness that might be felt, yet seeing nothing and only faintly hearing their
                            quickly receding footsteps, I chided myself severely, as well as others of our household for
                            neglecting to '•'¦Hang out the Light.'' Finally, I began soliloquizing thus : Indeed ! how
                            often we poor short-sighted mortals fail to uHang out a Light," to illumine the path of our
                            own dear friends ; and meantime render the same more cheerful for the lonely stranger al-
                            so, who may chance to pass us by,—one who may have neither friends nor home, but to whom a
                            faint ray of light even, is such an expression of benevolence and friendship, that perchance
                            his memory shall not only carry this fact into the dim future, but persuade him to believe,
                            that real friends do yet exist. And how often may he revert to the pleasing incident, so
                            glad a thing is a beam of light to the benighted traveler ! As I still remained standing,
                            surrounded by darkness, my thoughts again turned to my sisters, and I mentally exclaimed :
                            Shall I be blessed to wait and watch for them thus, in the spirit land? Can I be to them as
                            a spiritual beam of joy and gladness? O can I? But list! from out the darkness comes a
                            welcome sound: "Safe over ! All's well!" A thrill of gladness entered my heart, and with
                            tearful eyes and deep-drawn breath, I closed the door, thinking, how thrice welcome will be
                            the sound of their voices to me, when haply I shall stand in the doorway of my "Father's
                            House" and discern by the light of heaven, these dear companions coming home ! These, whom I
                            have known from childhood to maturity ; have seen them climb bravely up, by the plain cross
                            and self-denial, to a more exalted condition than nature ever knew. When I shall realize
                            that "all is right" with them, and they are safe in heaven, what a bliss will be mine ! Let
                            me not fail, then, always to "Liang out the Light." It costs but little ; it blesses many ;
                            and this life is too short, and much of it is rendered far too bitter, to those who live for
                            self alone ; or who fail to hang out a light fed by the oil of good influences, and a
                            Christ-like example. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our activities" TEIform="index"/>OUR ACTIVITIES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="F." TEIform="persName">F.</persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> While reading the beautifully written ideas under the heading of "Be good and do good," the
                            thought was suggested that it was by and through our activities that we accomplish the
                            little deeds of goodness, and by which we shall consummate the great good of our life. When
                            we admire the finely wrought golden chain, do we sufficiently appreciate the thought that it
                            is by successive, tiny links, the perfect chain is formed? Just so our lives are but a chain
                            wrought of the little activities, the kind deed, the genial 34 m: .ajsttfte sto .<pb n="35" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKBE M^JSmrESTO. 35 word, the cheerful smile, the emanations of a pure,
                            unselfish heart. Being one of the youthful readers who has taken much pleasure and derived
                            lasting benefit from "Notes by the Way," I value it as a privilege to tender mine and our
                            grateful thanks to the author of these gentle refreshings. May he reap in return the
                            richness and fullness of heaven's blessing now and forever, is the prayerful wish of one of
                            his daughters. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Indians, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>INDIANS. No. 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prescott, James S." TEIform="persName">
                                JAMES
                                S.
                                PRESCOTT
                            </persName>.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Who will plead the cause of the Indians ? Many were raised up to plead the cause of the
                            Africans ,and continued for a long series of years, until it ultimated, in the entire
                            emancipation of 4,000,000 of the race, from bondage and oppression to the rights of
                            citizenship under a free government. But who will plead the cause of the Indians, against
                            their oppressors ? Were they not the original proprietors of America? Are they not entitled
                            to the sympathies of every one located on their soil ? It is called free soil of America. If
                            it is free soil, then does it not belong to the Indians, as much as to the whites? Which was
                            it, by right of discovery, or by conquest, or by purchase that the whites first claimed the
                            soil? or, was it by the wrong of power and might over right, that the whites first took
                            possession and still hold it, without rendering an equivalent, or a just compensation? If it
                            was the latter, then the Indians still have a just right to the free soil of America. It was
                            indeed free soil before the whites took an illegal and an unwar- rantable possession of it;
                            and monopolized it to their own selfish purposes and aggrandizements. But this is not all,
                            of which the red man complains. It is the bad faith, broken promises, and the treachery of
                            the U. S. agents, employed to deal with them. Who are the Indians ? Are they not human
                            beings, a distinct race, as much as the Africans? possessing redeeming qxialities, capable
                            of improvement, selfculture, and progressing from lower to higher conditions? Have they "no
                            rights that white men are bound to respect?" Must they be annihilated, or crushed out of
                            existence, because they are in the minority, weak and powerless ? We answer emphatically,
                            Nay ! Unless there is a change of policy of the U. S. Government towards the North American
                            Indians, the invisible hosts will fight their battles for them, and will prevail, as they
                            did when the late Gen. Custer was slain, whose untimely death was so deeply felt and
                            lamented by the U. S. officers and their subordinates. But, Gen. Custer returns and speaks
                            for himself. Hear him : "I now return to send a warning to our people and nation, and urge
                            them to deal justly by the Indians, or they will do more mischief to the whites. The
                            warriors in spirit life are inspiring their brethren to resist and avenge the wrongs
                            perpetrated on their race. Do not seek to annihilate them, but try to make them better if
                            possible." Who made the Indian ? Did not the same God that made the white man, make the
                            Indian also ? And is he partial towards any part of his Creation ? Societies are formed and
                            forming extensively in our country and throughout the world, receiving legislative aid, and
                            are beginning to become national, for "The prevention of cruelty to Dumb<pb n="36" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 3*3 THE SHAKEE Animals." This is right; showing that the Angel of Mercy is at work—we
                            rejoice in it—we hail it as the harbinger of a better day, wherein "nothing shall hurt nor
                            destroy in all God's holy mountain," not even the Indians beyond the "Rocky Mountains," nor
                            this side of the same. Why cannot similar societies be formed for the prevention of cruelty
                            to the Indians, as well as to our Dumb Animals? What have the Indians done that they cannot
                            be forgiven and receive mercy, as well as the brute creation? When Gen. Custer entered the
                            spirit world he saw his mistake, that he had been engaged on the wrong side—he repented and
                            said, "I have wronged my red brothers, and I am sorry for it." Here is something which
                            speaks volumes in favor of the Indians. How quick did they forgive him, and opened their
                            ranks to the right and left, permitting him to pass through their midst unharmed. Why cannot
                            white people professing to be Christians, and civilized, be as magnanimous towards a
                            vanquished foe as those called the wild savages of America, and forgive the poor Indians and
                            stop killing them? Fair dealing, generosity, and kindness, will do more towards conquering
                            the Indians and making them our fast friends, than all the armies of a Napoleon. North
                            Union, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Warning" TEIform="index"/>WARNING</head><p TEIform="p">Impressed by a Father's Spirit Why clad in sackcloth—sorrow's garb— When God's free light
                            encircles thee? What sin has so defiled, or marred, That God, in truth, ye no more see? What
                            snares have thine own fingers wrought To rob thee of thy robe and crown? Is not my love of
                            greater worth Than all earth's wealth—could it be found? O brother, sister, where art thou ?
                            Still wrestling for thy sordid self ? Art thou so fattened in (his love, Thy birthright goes
                            for worldly pelf ? Look yonder—canst thou bear the sight— Thy name wiped from the Book of
                            Life— Because thou didst not strength implore, And weakness conquer, in the strife? O
                            favored child! confess, repent! And Jordan's waves will make thee whole; Fear not to plunge,
                            throw off thy weight, And thou shalt save thy sinking soul! O, if the wretched lives of
                            those Who've put afar the evil day, Could be unrolled, what deep regrets Those truthful
                            records would convey! Justice may wait; yet sure as God Has called souls from the broad
                            highway, So sure, will his unchanging law Be felt by all who disobey. Life unto life, death
                            unto death, The savor of his work shall prove; This joy, or wail, shall yet be heard From
                            all who've shared his boundless lore. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain, Christian Dress" TEIform="index"/>PLAIN, CHRISTIAN DRESS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Ruth" TEIform="persName">RUTH WEBSTER </persName></byline><p TEIform="p"> A modest unassuming woman clad in simple apparel is like a beautiful flower whose perfume
                            gladdens the sense of the beholder ; but a woman who wears unnecessary trimmings and
                            ornaments, is like the artificial flower ; it may please the eye, but it yields no perfume.
                            The outward adorning is a pretty sure index of that which is within. Tf in our dress we
                            conform to the fashions of this world as nearly as we can, does it not show the state of the
                            heart? It is commendable to give as much attention to dress as the nature of the case
                            requires ; but as there is but a step between virtue and vice—between the sublime and the
                            ridiculous ; would it not be well to watch closely, lest we over step the mark ? I am
                            reminded of an anecdote which MAJSrnr'ZESTO.<pb n="37" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MAJSXE^ESTO. I
                            will repeat: Some years ago when our Methodist friends dressed much plainer than now, a
                            young lady came to an aged minister and asked him if he thought it any sign of pride for her
                            to wear a feather on her hat? He made this reply: "When I was a young man I used to go fox
                            hunting. When I came to a hole and found the fox's tail hanging out I was pretty sure that
                            the fox was there !" Beware of the little foxes for they have ruined many a flourishing
                            vine. Union Village, Ohio. </p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Brother Albert. We know our manuscript is late..." TEIform="index"/>Brother Albert. We know our manuscript is late...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Brother Albert. We know our manuscript is late, having stepped over the threshold of 1878 ;
                            yet we have felt the desire to greet our Parents of the Household of Faith, with A Happy New
                            Year.</p><p TEIform="p">Worthy Fathers and Mothers, Greeting; Let us wish you a Happy New Year. Not the repetition of
                            a stale hackneyed phrase, but a bright, honest expression of soul-love welling up from the
                            filial hearts of your many dutiful children. Most glorious parentage ! Again and again we
                            come to the salute, and ring out in these cheery words the issue of our fervent prayers and
                            hopes for your comfort and preservation throughout the year, which is so kindly opening to
                            the household, with full sheaves of love and confidence between parents and offspring. Look
                            up, dear ones, from your several localities in Kentucky, Ohio, New York, Massachusetts,
                            Connecticut, Maine and New Hampshire, and catch the silvery tones as we repeat, God hless
                            you, a Happy New Year! Let us beseech you to treasure the essence of our words in your
                            hearts' tem- ples, sacred to prayer, in our behalf as an abiding rest, as a joyous song
                            agreeably to the text: ''Rejoice, thou barren that bearest not; break forth and cry thou
                            that travailest not: for the desolate hath more children than she which hath a husband."
                            Gal. iv. 27. "Sing, O barren, thou that didst not bear ; break forth into singing, and cry
                            aloud, thou that didst not travail with, child : for more are the children of the desolate
                            than the children of the married wife, saith the Lord." Isaiah liv. 1. As an invigorating
                            cordial let us press the inspiration of our love to the lips of those valiant souls, who
                            have wrestled, and suffered more than physical pain, while watching and waiting our
                            maturity, never once distrusting the genuineness of our efforts to attain to full stature in
                            Christ, or their ability to bring forth sons and daughters unto God, worthy heirs to greater
                            than earthly inheritance, loyal standard-bearers of higher than ma-nmade creeds. What an
                            impression that unshaken, confidence has made upon otir souls! "My Fathers and Mothers
                            expect me to conquer." How we have broadened and deepened to meet this expectancy! You have
                            given us the benefit of your experience, precept and example, and ask in return that we add
                            thereto the outgrowth of our stewardship, so inwrought with the truth of the past, that a
                            perpetual increase may be ours, and we be able to present an untarnished name for integrity
                            and obedience, to the sacred faith committed to our trust. And shall we disappoint you?
                            Disappoint God? For, to what pther source shall we ascribe the paternal and maternal
                            principles which have been our nursing fathers and mothers, until we have found 37<pb n="38" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 38 THE SHAKER MLAJSTEETESTO. the new birth, or life in the spirit ? Nay !
                            never! Fathers and Mothers of the South, you expect your children at the North to keep their
                            garments "unspotted from the world." We will ripen this expectation into a reality. Fathers
                            and Mothers of the North, you ask like honor and victory, from the warm hearts of our
                            comrades in the South. Hear the response : We have accepted our measure, and will not be
                            found wanting. We come as so many rays of love, light and truth, to be caught and held in
                            the prism of your affection. Ah ! this mutual confidence will outlast the perils of '78,
                            upon which we enter with true humility and undaunted courage. One more word, or gentle
                            entreaty, and we will away to the battle of life. Don't make haste to go among the
                            evergreens on the other shore, as our brother Albert terms the closing of life. Are there
                            more beautiful evergreens than your own children ? Associations dearer than those you have
                            helped to create around you? Wait with all patience and cultivate perpetual youth, and a
                            growth of evergreen principles here on earth. While working—not waiting—should the reaping
                            angels require your aid in other portions of the vineyard,—arid we can't blame them for
                            wranting our parents, if they have learned your wrorth, for "there are none like unto
                            you,"'—remember we part not, but ask your continued remembrance of us in our varied duties
                            until we, too, have taken our measure of trial in this sphere, and have thereby ripened for
                            service in the land beyond. In behalf of Jhe children.</p><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Canterbury" TEIform="index"/>Canterbury, N. H. </dateline></div2><div2 type="aphorism" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Suffer little children to come unto me and forbid them not for of such is the kingdom of God" TEIform="index"/>Suffer little children to come unto me and forbid them not for of such is the kingdom of God
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Suffer little children to come unto me and forbid them not for of such is the kingdom of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="[Jesus]" TEIform="persName"/></byline></div2><div2 type="ann lee" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ann Lee: her work, her people, and their critics, first paper" TEIform="index"/>ANN LEE. Her
                            Work, her People, and their Critics.</head><p TEIform="p"> FIRST PAPER. I purpose to write a few, short papers upon the above subjects, believing the
                            information they will contain, to be timely and desired. Out from the mists of obscurity
                            hare arisen many of the world's workers and saviours; and out from the mills of Manchester
                            came "a good thing"—one, of whom, we feel warranted in speaking by quotation: ' 'Many
                            daughters have done virtuously; but thou excellest them all." It is an easy matter to
                            chronicle the past; to state the beginnings of eras, and of consequences as they have
                            occurred, and occur up to to-day. Who shall tell us all that may result from the smallest,
                            humblest beginnings ? The most meek of men became leader of Israel's hosts! a peasant girl,
                            Maid of Orleans, rising out of seclusion, dons an almost superhuman power, and baptizes an
                            army of men with an irresistible force ! and within the memory of our children yet in their
                            teens, a long, lank, homely member of the rail-splitting department, rises to sit at the
                            head of affairs of our nation; to be the adored of the people ; and completing the grand act
                            of emancipation, is called unto and crowned by the angels ! Going back again in memory, and
                            we recall the familiar sayings of ' 'the Carpenter's Son" in all their wonderful and
                            powerful simplicity; and now witness millions praise-struck at the name of Jesus! nor would
                            we be unmindful of the efforts for the world's good—the accomplishments of a Blacksmith's
                            beautiful daughter in behalf of mankind. For so sure as "ever the right comes uppermost, and
                            ever is justice done," so shall this daughter receive her "recompense of reward." Who was
                            Ann Lee? She was the daughter of very poor, humble, but industrious parents ; who came hon-
                            estly by their ignorance, and transmitted the same "bliss of ignorance" to a large family of
                            children. Ann was early placed in a factory, where she soon earned and more than earned her
                            own livelihood ,but always remained quite ignorant of letters.<pb n="39" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER 39 She was a staid, quiet girl, not given so much to play, common to children of her
                            age, but chose in preference a retirement from her mates, where, removed from public gaze,
                            she became the subject of heavenly visions, many of which were far above the comprehension
                            of her juvenile mind. In these visions, being instructed of the depravity of human nature,
                            in mankind generally, and that God would soon open away for the deliverance of the people—a
                            rest for the weary and heavy laden—she would go to her mother, tell of her visions, and
                            sobbing, as with a breaking heart, ask her to explain them. Her mother, mother-like, tried
                            hard, and variously, to dispel these vagaries of a distorted imagination, at the same time
                            joining her daughter in tears, that told of the truths of vision, active in her own, daily
                            experience. While there was no cessation of these visions, her parents and friends coun-
                            seled marriage to change her thoughts, and give a new and they hoped a happier phase to her
                            existence. She was married to Abraham Stanley, a blacksmith by trade. From this union four
                            children were born; all, however dying while infants. Her married life was aught but happy;
                            but not on the very common ground of incompatibility of temper, but because she now began to
                            experience the fulfillment of many of her visions; and hers became a troubled soul, and she
                            an earnest seeker for a refuge from a life that brought her spiritual freedom under a
                            bondage, worse than physical slavery,—the engagements in lusts of the flesh, that were
                            "death unto death" to her already quickened conscience. The story of her spiritual
                            sufferings about these times, as given by her own mouth, were so graphic and affecting, as
                            to cause all who heard her to wonder and weep ! A woman, called to such spiritual
                            experiences, should never marry nor engage in any passionate indulgence. We herewith add our
                            sincere commiseration for her kind hearted husband, and the same for any having a wife
                            spiritually affected as was Ann Lee! He was, from all accounts a sympathetic husband;
                            considerate of what he deemed her hallucinations; charitable to what he deemed her whims ;
                            and yet, while being the exalted prophetess, she made a very disagreeable wife ! He was a
                            worldly man, having hopes of increasing worldly prospects, and to a long life of worldly
                            happiness with one of the kindest, prettiest of nature's noblewomen. She was a woman of
                            medium height, rather robust, sound in health, capable of great endurance, and quick to
                            recuperate after extreme exhaustion. There was no reason why she should not have been the
                            mother of healthy and long-lived reproductions, unless that reason is found, in the positive
                            incompe- tency of an extremely spiritually-minded woman to reproduce healthy earthly
                            offspring, regardless of the adequacy of every other essential necessity therefor. Stanley's
                            prospects, so far as Ann was concerned, were ruined; and he shall have for this period of
                            his life our sympathetic memory. About this time, there was a class of revivalists active in
                            Manchester—comeouters from the Quaker Order—under the leadership of a man and his wife,
                            named Wardley. The revival seemed to embrace the necessity of all would-be Christians,
                            returning to the government and life of the primitive Christian Church. And when Ann learned
                            that the Wardleys and their followers—called "Shakers"—(by which it will be seen that Ann
                            Lee was not the first, so called,) lived in virgin celibacy, confessed and forsook sin,
                            etc., she was moved in spirit to come into close communion with them, and by the consent of
                            her husband united herself to them. Now, Stanley had a deal of trouble with Ann. Ann asked
                            her elders how she should live with Stanley and keep her faith? Jane Wardley said to her :
                            "I am James' wife; we lodge together; but we no more touch each other sexually, than we
                            would handle coals of fire!" Ann was happy and determined; while Stanley now, was a most
                            miserable husband. * (continued.) </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Rise early, if you wish to become rich..." TEIform="index"/>Rise early, if you wish to become rich...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Rise early, if you wish to become rich and conquer an enemy. What is the most beautiful
                            thing? The universe. The strongest? Necessity. The most difficult? To know ourselves. The
                            rarest? A true friend. </p></div2><pb n="40" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chauncy Dibble, Friend, Your letter of the 22nd. ult. is at hand..." TEIform="index"/>Chauncy Dibble, Friend, Your letter of the 22nd. ult. is at hand...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Michigan, Augusta, December 12, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Augusta, Mich, 12th. Mo. 1877</dateline><p TEIform="p">Chauncy Dibble, Friend, Your letter of the 22nd. ult. is at hand. I see you are one of
                                those candid seekers after truth. We are all subject to its divine laws, and must answer
                                for our own conduct individually. Our relation to Deity is found by humble prayer, which
                                is the key to heaven. None but the virtuous and godly can enter there. You ask my idea
                                of the unregenerate in the other existence. If there is a condition of salvation, there
                                is also a place of destruction to be saved from. There is a burning of soul to all who
                                reject the truth. There is no device nor repentance in the grave. No returning to
                                acceptance with God after death. It is casting a stigma to insinuate that our time of
                                probation here is insufficient. It is no injustice if a soul is tormented in hell; for
                                we all have our own choice. We make our own condemnation; we are judged according to the
                                deeds done in the body; they that are wise are wise unto life eternal. The wicked go to
                                everlasting punishment. The doctrine of repentance in the future was invented by man,
                                and suits his animal nature. It prevents many from obeying the spirit of truth now. All
                                of every nation are invited to partake at the spiritual fountain—the living Christ—the
                                inward Teacher—the only begotten of the Father. Born in our souls this spirit enables
                                man to comprehend things divine. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Griffin, A. L." TEIform="persName">A. L. Griffin</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A. Griffin, My friend:—Yours of 4th ult. is at hand..." TEIform="index"/>A. Griffin, My friend:—Yours of 4th ult. is at hand...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Shakers, January 1, 1878" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y., Jan. 1, 1878</dateline><p TEIform="p">A. Griffin, My friend:—Yours of 4th ult. is at hand. There seems a decided difference in
                                our views, of the condition of the people of the other world. The future destiny of the
                                innumerable multitudes each with souls as precious as ours, is a subject too vast to be
                                decided by the dogmas of the past. Heathens, Idolaters and religious persecutors, have
                                their hells of retribution as a weapon to frighten sinners into the church. The
                                character attributed to Deity by such, is outrageously disgusting and has made more
                                self-righteous hypocrites, and infidels than it has saved souls. That Jehovah was a man
                                of war; inspired his servants to persecute heretics; instituted a church to damn all who
                                did not belong to it; that He has created a heaven at some extreme height to which all,
                                who belong to the church, or have faith in imputed righteousness, are wafted at death,
                                there to exult in the eternal misery of the wicked—these are doctrines too crude to have
                                a place in an enlightened mind. _ God will never deprive man of the gift of free agency;
                                yet all who willfully transgress, must learn obedience by suffering. The attributes of
                                Deity are parental. He is not limited in the exercise of his mercy to ten years or an
                                hundred years. He ia the same God in the future. The separation of the spirit from our
                                bodies does not change our relations to Him nor our own moral conditions. Spirits out of
                                the body may still be virtuous or vicious ; and their heaven or hell will be as they
                                make them. We cannot indulge our selfish propensities here, and be wholly released there
                                ; only so far as we have purified our hearts by abstinence from fleshly lusts. Yours in
                                love, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName">Chauncy Dibble </persName></byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. J. M. Peebles" TEIform="index"/>DR. J. M. PEEBLES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peebles, J. M." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> We have received a letter from Bro. Peebles, from Madras, in which he expresses his
                                delight with the amount of mediumship, magic, and psychological phenomena he has
                                witnessed. "</p><p TEIform="p">Casting out devils." he says, "It is as common in Southern India as it used to be in
                                Palestine in Jesus' time." He is much saddened by the sights of suffering incident to
                                the prevailing famine, and expresses his deep sympathy for the sufferers.</p><p TEIform="p">The following is from the Madras Daily Times:</p><p TEIform="p">"Three weeks ago we announced the arrival in Madras of Dr. J. M. Peebles, formerly an
                                American Consul in Asiatic Turkey, and the author of several books. During the period
                                that he has been in Madras he has M^nsriiPESTO.<pb n="41" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                MANIFESTO. ¦4,1 \been most industrious in obtaining information from all sources, and
                                the chapters of hi forthcoming work, devoted to Southern India, should be most
                                interesting. Dr. Peebles flails on Monday next by the Suffolk for Natal and Cape Town,
                                en route to England. The Doctor, during his stay here, has exhibited that push and
                                energy which is characteristic of Americans. Though he has been, as we have said, hardly
                                three weeks in Madras, he has managed to visit the famine camps, the Leper Hospital, the
                                museum, libraries, all the public buildings and burning ghauts. He has witnessed the
                                clever feats of magicians, seen the devil priests professedly cast out demons, looked
                                into a higher class of psychological phenomena, difficult to get at and more difficult
                                to comprehend, and met a good many native gentlemen of various castes. He has also
                                received from the Chief Secretary to Government much kindness in the way of a sight of
                                public documents, and in every conceivable way has had the opportunity of seeing all
                                sides of our social life. Dr. Peebles was at the breakfast in the Banqueting Hall
                                yesterday in honor of the Viceroy, and was charmed with the almost Republican freedom
                                evinced. They have nothing of the kind in the West, he says, and he thinks he has a
                                wrinkle from the ancient civilization of India to bring before the century-old Republic
                                of the New World. We shall look forward to the publicaton of Dr. Peebles' forthcoming
                                work with interest." </p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us earn our pay" TEIform="index"/>Let us Earn our Pay</head><p TEIform="p">A common share in the toils and [burdens of life, whether of a temporal or spiritual
                                nature, always enhances our happiness. This is a life of toil; let us not leave our
                                portion for the ever burdened. Let us each make the most of our own capital, that we may
                                not have to beg, borrow, nor steal. Let all that we possess be justly and truly earned.
                                Then we shall have nothing unpleasent to reflect upon when our accounts are cast up. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bathrick, Eunice" TEIform="persName"/></byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Harvard" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass. </dateline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Manifesto:--Its worst enemies" TEIform="index"/> ITS WORST ENEMIES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert" TEIform="persName">GEO. ALBERT LOMAS</persName>, EDITOR. SHAKERS, N. Y..</byline><p TEIform="p"> That Christianity finds its worst enemies among those professing the strongest and most
                            affectionate allegiance to it, is our assertion, and our most sorrowful regret. That there
                            are differences of opinions, theologically, will never be matters of surprise, when our
                            various organizations and constitutions are duly considered. Theology is a talk upon God,
                            dictated by the mind of him or her who possesses ideas of theology. Hence, it is not
                            strange, that there are as many theological mills, and roads thereto, as there are
                            individuals with theological grists to be ground. Theological differences may always exist,
                            and none be harmed thereby; for whether this or that is the best theology, we opine God
                            cares very little. With religion, and religious life, the results are very different; for
                            theology and religion are but distant relatives at best. The advent of Christianity into the
                            world, was to bring new, practical lessons for its believers to learn and obey. The lessons
                            prior to its coming had been good; sufficient for the progress of the people, who knew not
                            of any pleasures above the world of fleshly indulgences—who were truly a carnal people, and
                            justified, in the absence of Christianity, in all their regulated carnality. Now, let any
                            man or woman, or they twain, engage, as did the children of<pb n="42" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> THDEC
                            SHAK1E MANIFESTO. Israel, in all the gratifications permitted and restricted by their
                            God—let them learn and sing the song of Moses to perfection—and they are only good and
                            perfect Jews at best. Will any rational thinker presume to say, that there is only an
                            additional theology, belief or admission to be made by these parties, that they may be
                            Christians? That merely acknowledging that Christ came to save sinners ; and believing in
                            the super excellency of his blood, will change them from good Jews to good Chris- tians? Can
                            it be, that such acknowledgement and belief are the means of building up a "New Creation of
                            God?" Such is the sincere teaching of the vast majority of the clergy ; who, however
                            sincere, are the worst enemies of the Church of Christ! We wonder not at the differences of
                            opinion, active among the apostles in their day ; and did we know of more of such
                            differences we should not be surprised. That Paul overcame Peter'6 scruples of religious
                            Christian life, was the most natural thing in the world; but at the same time, it was the
                            triumph of darkness, which blotted out the pure, practical elements of primitive
                            Christianity; hence, the "falling away!" We say, "most natural-" we add, the most
                            unspiritual circumstance of seventeen hundred years, was the conversion of Peter from
                            following the life of Jesus, to engage in the philosophical reasonings, apologies, and
                            wholesale conversions after Paul! Had Swedenborg, with his eloquence, learning, tact and
                            reasoning ability, converted Ann Lee from the necessity of such a degree of purity of life;
                            such denials to general human selfishness; and permitting such licenses, that human nature
                            should not feel pressed, restricted unto the death of the works ov the old creation, there
                            would be nowl the same "darkness covering the face of) the earth" that accompanied the
                            falling away of the first Church. Swedenborg, was undoubtedly the most superior man of his
                            day, in intellectual and moral attainments. There were elegancies of diction and habits
                            about him, that wrought great attractiveness among the early disciples of Mother Ann Lee. So
                            much was this the case, that under the slow progress* of Shakerism-; under its severe
                            crucifixions of the flesh, and iconoclasm of the old domestic relations, many recurred to
                            the easements, letups, and half-way crosses of Swedenborg ; and consequently, for fifty and
                            more years—until the efficacy of a full cross against the flesh and its concomitant
                            relations was satisfactorily established, Swedenborg and his writings, were kept "without,"
                            among the sorcerers. We have paid Paul's life, the high tribute of being very superior to
                            his unchristian theology—his life was closely following that of Jesus. His victory over the
                            "head of the Church"— Peter—and the rest of the apostles— unless we except Jamesf—has given
                            *The progress of the Shakers is necessarily slow, as they take up a cross too heavy to be
                            borne by ordinary men and women of the world.—Henry Vincent. fBut Luther far surpassed the
                            zeal and confidence of his fathers, in changing and corrupting everything sacred. In order
                            to maintain his inconsistent and pernicious solijidian system of Imputed Righteousness, he
                            rejected the whole epistle of James, and called it "aw epistle of straw." See the beginning
                            of Luther's Works, Barclay's Ap. p. 80, 81. Armi. Mag. Vol. II. p. 288. 43<pb n="43" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE 4,3 Ithe clergy of today, the opportunities of toeing apologists
                            for all fleshly indulgences, through unchristian marriages, private possessions, with their
                            ever-accompanying catalogue of contingences ; and with only the fear of a future— "the time
                            will come when these things will be done away"—and with the apparent encouragement of "Go
                            it, while you may!" And the clergy are unhesitatingly selling Paul's permissions, while
                            their multitudinous followers are most eager to buy ! But there is no Christ in these
                            indulgences. Every marriage, however proper for the world, and its children, crucifies
                            Christ afresh; every sexual congress of the twain, however necessary for the peopling of the
                            earth, pollutes the Christian temple; every departure from "all things common and equal,"
                            and to private, personal, selfish aggregations, drives the third nail, by which the
                            life-blood of Christ—the true Christian religion—ebbs entirely away ! These same clergymen
                            (honorable in their sincerity, zeal and fervency ; but how inconsistent and cruel
                            practically !) do not differ with us, regarding what the life of Christ Jesus was ! They
                            admit its virgin celibacy ; they know of its living testimony of abstinence from sexual
                            conbinations and lusts ; they are one with us in admission and admiration of the plainness
                            of Jesus' dress and habits; they differ not that "they were together and had all things in
                            common ;" they are our equals in speaking of his peaceableness, in crowning him the Prince
                            of Peace ! in keeping himself and little Church distinct from the "manners" and
                            governments** of the **Luke xx: 25. world, and in praising. Now, why all this "beating round
                            the bush?" Why not come out boldly, and say: uSuch was the life of Jesus Christ, we know;
                            but we cannot live it; our congregations will not live it! hence, while admitting such to be
                            genuine Christianity it is too onerous, too crossing for us to bear! Some noble clergymen,
                            have come out thus boldly, and have renounced the name of ''Christian," even as their lives
                            are not. But knowing the grand contrast between the life of the world, and the life of
                            Jesus, the Christ; realizing that the people will stay in Egypt, indulging in the world,
                            flesh and devil; the clergy, in evading the commands of the Christ, to teach his words, and
                            to "follow him" in life, do so under the encouraging applause of the people and the pay of
                            the devil! And amid their own desires for human, but unchristian pleasures ; Paul's
                            permissions to be halfway Christians; and the unreserved consecration of the entire life of
                            Jesus, the Christ, all looming up to be chosen from : "Choose ye !" And while continuing to
                            hold the pure, peaceable, unselfish, unworldly life of Christ, a subject of admiration, and
                            not as a life-like pattern for all true disciples, we arraign such clergy and
                            converts—professors of Christianity—as inimical to the cause of Christ, and the worst
                            enemies that it has. * </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Children's friend — Bro. Wm. G. Libbey" TEIform="index"/>Children's friend — Bro. Wm. G. Libbey
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> The children's friend—Bro. Wm. G. Libbey, will continue to accompany us through the
                                year. Although he will prove no '•'•Robinson Crusoe," nor '•'•Roderick, the Rover," yet
                                he will be an entertaining and instructive story teller ; and the best things about his
                                stories are, they are all true to life. We hope also all will be pleased to read and
                                remember the beauties of Elder H. C. Blinn's "Address." </p><p TEIform="p"> We deem there are limits to the propriety of free speech—a time when freedom of speech
                                may be abused, by the utterance of profanity or obscenity—but we feel assured, from
                                certain, recent arrests, that a spirit of hate, from antitheological reasons, has been
                                aroused ; and the consequences will be a repetition of Inquisitorial times and deeds,
                                unless this spirit and its agents are rebuked; It is one feature of the combination, ana
                                mal-administration of Church and State governments. To this combination we are eternal
                                opponents. Keep the governments of Cesar and God apart forever ; while rendering to each
                                its just dues. Our Shaker testimony cuts crosswise many of the world's idolatrous prac-
                                tices ; and for this testimony, uttered with respectable, dictionary language, are we to
                                look for arrest, incarcerations and fine? Again, we call on American citizens, to awake
                                to the positive necessity, of keeping Church and State forever separate ; to keep God,
                                Christ, Virgin Mary, Ann Lee, and every other theological representation out of the
                                Constitution of our United States, and to give to every other the same rights to "life,
                                liberty and pursuit of happiness," which we desire to exercise for ourselves. </p><p TEIform="p"> We call particular attention to Elder A. Perkins' article uAre the Shakers Christians?"
                                As a definition, of what used to be duly considered Christianity, it will be difficult
                                to excel. The points raised, are well cleared up : Was the life of Jesus, that of a
                                virgin celibate? So is that of all true Shakers, or Christians. Was his household
                                government based on an equality of goods? Was he a peacemaker? Did he and disciples
                                separate themselves from the social and sexual practices common to the world ? Thus do
                                the Shakers live. Until we are convinced that the coveted practices of the world—the
                                congress of sexes for propagation or mere pleasure ; personal riches, inequality of this
                                life's good things; controversies, contentions and wars; and the general engagements of
                                44 MANIFESTO.<pb n="45" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE MLAJNTTFEISTO. selfishness are Christian or best,
                                we mean to be Shakers, and hurl against these principalities of the world our Christian
                                testimony. </p><p TEIform="p"> The works of scientific men, reformers, ecclesiastical canons, and such new lights and
                                liberals, as prefer the spirit of truth to theological errors, are creating a Babylon—a
                                confusion—among so-called "orthodox" creeds. Robert Ingersoll is doing his iconoclastic
                                work well; Merriam is already very heretical to early, established opinions; Canon Farar
                                wipes out, with his linguistic lore, "hell, damnation and everlasting torment" from
                                future editions of the revised, sacred scriptures; Sir Draper adds a liberal page to
                                present church doctrines, thereby throwing a bomb among ecclesiastics, making confusion,
                                worse confounded, and an irremediable rent to the erroneous philosophies of religious
                                opinions ; then come Munger, and ex-president Hopkins disavowing what they early 6wore
                                to believe and sustain ; only to be excelled by the Beecher, into an extensive tumble-up
                                into very much more liberality, almost amounting to Universalism! "Let us be patient,
                                these severe afflictions "Not from the ground arise; "But oftentimes, celestial
                                benedictions "Assume this bright disguise." Let us be prayerful: "Thy kingdom come ; thy
                                will be done on earth," just as angels and just men and women are doing, wherever
                                heavenly conditions are. While the old creation is toppling and falling; while the old
                                theological arks have lasted out their latest endurance ; let us be wise in the
                                presentation of principles, of a never-fading character—of Jesus, the Christ. A virgin
                                character ; eternal Peace ; the communal relations of brethren and sisters in the spirit
                                of Christ,—these form the heavens, there is no progress without them, and though the
                                heavens and earth pass away, these will endure forever ! </p><p TEIform="p"> We cannot rejoice, that so many are agreeably roused to the belief, that there is no
                                hell. The tidal waves of mind are likely to dash against the real truth of the case, for
                                some time to come, because so much infidelity of there being a hell in the great
                                hereafter, is being sown with unsparing voices and hands. There are hells upon earth;
                                there will be hells in the future ; and as well may any deny that effects follow their
                                causes, as to deny that evil thoughts, words and acts are followed by the most
                                uncomfortable conditions. There are hells ; and the escape therefrom, is to flee from
                                the conditions that make us uncomfortable, here and hereafter. We do rejoice, however,
                                that this subject is awaking in many thousands, the blessed hope, belief, and the
                                certainty of all having as long a probation in the future, as they may desire to live in
                                tormented conditions. That here, and hereafter, there is a way out of sin and its
                                effects. And just as soon as we are willing to cease to do evil, learn to do better, and
                                turn our faces away from the hellish conditions of worldly life, then will we ever and
                                for- ever, time, and eternity without end, realize a loving parent, ready to fall on our
                                necks, forgive us and redeem usThanks to Almighty God, that this glorious light of truth
                                is so fast breaking upon the people! Its effect upon the man-made theologies of the
                                churches will be immense ; to the falling off of 45 SHAKER<pb n="46" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 4,6 THE
                                SHAKER all other shackles, until the gospel will be emancipated from every thing that
                                does not indicate the pure life*of Jesus, the Christ, a positive necessity of heaven and
                                for the absence of hells. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>For the Children</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quondam sailor, chapter II" TEIform="index"/>QUONDAM SAILOR CHAP. II</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Libbey, William G." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> I was rather pleased to find my brother so willing to keep me company, in my long
                                cherished desire to find a home on some lone island of the Pacific Ocean, and we made
                                what preparation we could, which was not much, for we had to be very careful not to
                                excite suspicions of our intention to leave the ship. Our outfit consisted of needles
                                and thread, fish-hooks and lines, a small hammer without a handle, a pair of pincers,
                                and a sun-glass. The latter proved a most useful article, without it we should have had
                                no fire, and been forced to eat our meat and fish raw. All the reading matter we
                                ventured to take, was one small Bible, and a Shaker poem given us when we visited the
                                North Family, at Shaker Village, N. H. in the autumn of 1841. On our approaching the
                                island, the wind died away, leaving us becalmed, five or six miles from land. A boat was
                                then sent ashore to look for a place to land; it being late in the afternoon, she soon
                                returned. The boat's crew gave a very pleasant account of what they had seen. They told
                                of cocoa- nuts in abundance, and of mullet, a fine fish, which were plenty, in small
                                creeks that run in the shade of the cocoa-nut trees, and could be caught in the hand.
                                All of these glowing stories of our ship-mates, encouraged us in our enterprise of
                                forming a settlement on this land of promise. The writer had expected the boat to which
                                he belonged would be one to go on shore; and accordingly put some clothes in the bottom
                                of it, under what is called the "head sheets." Thus having made all the preparation we
                                could, we waited, not very patiently you may be assured, for our opportunity. At last
                                the order came to lower away two boats, when to my surprise and disappointment, I found
                                the bow-boat to which I belonged was not going on shore. I went to the third officer who
                                was at work at a turning lathe on the quarter deck, and asked if our boat was not going;
                                he said it was not; and appeared rather cool and reserved, which was unusual for him, as
                                our previous acquaintance had been very cordial. And I have no doubt the bow-boat was
                                kept on the cranes that day for my especial benefit. I think our intentions to leave the
                                ship were suspected, hence the detention of the boat. The larboard quarter boat
                                belonging to the chief-mate, to which my brother was attached, was already in the water,
                                and leaving the side of the ship. Starting to go forward, on reaching the port side of
                                the cook's galley, I found one of our men looking em- barrassed, and anxiously inquiring
                                if some one would go on shore in his place. He belonged to the second mate's boat that
                                was then being lowered away. I think he was inspired to give me his chance to go to that
                                island. He had been in the Seminole war in Florida; was about forty years of age. We
                                remember him with pleasure for yielding to a good influence at that time, and thus
                                becoming an agent, somewhat indirectly, to my being in Shaker Village, N. H., at the
                                present time. Accepting his offer joyfully, and picking up the cook's ax from the deck,
                                with the remark that "It would do to cut down a cocoanut tree," I went into the boat and
                                took the place of my good friend Knop, at the mid-ship oar, which was eighteen feet
                                long, and was to be pulled five or six miles under a vertical sun, in a calm, and with
                                double the amount of clothing usually worn in pulling a whale-boat in this latitude !
                                Added to this was all my personal effects stowed in the bosom of my shirt! I have not
                                preserved an inventory, and may not be able to recall every article of my property; yet
                                there is one part of that day's experience I do remember distinctly, and that is, the
                                very severe and protracted perspiration from which I suffered before reaching the shore.
                                It came to an end at last M^jsTCF'IESTO.<pb n="47" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> TECEC SHAKBE lYLAJNTFESTO.
                                by our boat landing on a beautiful beach of coral sand, on the north side of Fanning's
                                Island. As soon as we landed, our officers, taking their guns, proceeded along the beach
                                to the eastward of where the boats lay, seeming as much delighted to be on shore as any
                                of the boys; thus leaving the boat's crew to do as they pleased. Most of them were on
                                their first voyage, and a place like this had much to attract their attention. While
                                they were examining the natural scenery of the place, the writer i and his brother
                                walked rapidly into the woods. The island was a narrow strip of land, less than a mile
                                wide in the widest part, somewhat circular, in form resembling a horse shoe. The space
                                between the back points or after points as a sailor would term it—formed a passage
                                through which vessels from the ocean outside, passed to the quiet waters of the lagoon,
                                or bay; which is protected from the surges of the ocean waves by the sides of this
                                imaginary horse shoe. The distance across the bay, we should think was five or six
                                miles, as the land on the opposite side of the bay from where our boats first landed,
                                could not be clearly seen without the aid of a telescope. After losing sight of our kind
                                ship-mates, we travelled very fast through a forest of cocoanut trees, until we reached
                                the outer shore of the island; this brought us in sight of our ship which, having taken
                                a breeze, was lying off and on the land, waiting for the boats. I do not think we were
                                seen by any one on board, for a ship can be seen at a distance of six or eight miles by
                                persons on shore, or on another vessel; while a man can be seen only about two miles
                                distant, unless aided by a glass. It was after sunset when we reached the outer shore,
                                and as twilight is very short there, as in all places near the equator, it was dark
                                before we finished our shelter for the night, which we made from the top of a cocoa-nut
                                tree that we had cut down. The nuts we obtained from it, gave us the first food we ate
                                after landing; the green nuts affording a most delicious drink, to satisfy our extreme
                                thirst, after our hard pull in the whale-boats that afternoon. My brother was taken sick
                                in the evening, caused by over exertion, and drinking too freely of cocoa-nut water.
                                There was a medicine chest on board the ship we had left, but neither of us proposed to
                                go in search of it; we had counted the cost and were prepared to abide the result,
                                whatever it should be. There was one remedial agent of which we could avail ourselves on
                                a grand scale, and this was Hydropathy— which means Water Cure—which I applied to my
                                sick brother, by walking with him a few steps into the water and allowing the surf to
                                break over us. And although my companion found relief, we lost some seeds of the
                                crook-neck squash, washed out of our pockets by the heavy surf. I mention this as being
                                a great loss to us at that time, as we were expecting to grow them on the island, to
                                supply somewhat the want of bread. The natives of the Marquesas island grow large
                                quantities of these squashes, which they sell to ships. We have known them to keep six
                                months in the open air, exposed to the rays of the tropical sun. The quality is better
                                than those grown with us. After the bath, we crawled under our shelter of palm leaves,
                                and slept soundly until day-light. (to be continued.) </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM and GARDEN</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fruit" TEIform="index"/>Fruit</head><p TEIform="p"> There is no doubt but that pure fruit acids are excellent for the system. One orange,
                                eaten before breakfast occasionally, without sugar, is recommended by the best
                                physicians as an excellent corrective for the system. </p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Something about eggs" TEIform="index"/>Something about eggs</head><p TEIform="p"> —Eggs, when softboiled, are easily digested; but when hardboiled they require very
                                strong powers of the stomach to digest them. If a person in health is going on a journey
                                where he will will be long in getting food, one or two hardboiled eggs, taken before
                                setting out, will keep off the sensation of hunger for a considerable time. An egg, for
                                a healthy child, 4,7<pb n="48" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> 48 THE SHAKER, is a good article of diet, but
                                ought to be softboiled, and a due quantity of bread eaten with it. In cooking an egg
                                with the shell on, place in boiling water and set off the fire. Let it stand six or
                                seven minutes, when it will be much superior to one that is steadily kept boiling from
                                two to four minutes. Eggs rubbed over with fat or grease of any kind will keep fresh
                                much longer than if this is not done. Perhaps there is no better way to prepare eggs for
                                breakfast than to break them into a large dish, season, pour in a little cream or milk;
                                stir the whole a few minutes, then pour into a hot sauce-pan that has been greased; stir
                                while cooking, and be sure and take off before it gets the least bit tough. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>HOME TOPICS</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Potato croquets" TEIform="index"/>Potato Croquets</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Boil and mash a dozen potatoes; add a piece of butter size of an egg,
                                        tablespoonful of white sugar, a little salt, and two well-beaten eggs. Mix well.
                                        Make them up into Cones; dip them into raw egg, sift on plenty of bread crumbs,
                                        and fry brown like ¦crullers.— </quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Arthur's Mag" TEIform="index"/>Arthur's Mag.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Put a little hand soap on the door hinges..." TEIform="index"/>Put a little hand soap on the door hinges...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Put a little hand soap on the door hinges when they creak. </p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To bore a hole easily through a hemlock knot..." TEIform="index"/>To bore a hole easily through a hemlock knot...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">To bore a hole easily through a hemlock knot, wet the bit or augur in spirits of
                                turpentine. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep polished steel tools..." TEIform="index"/>Keep polished steel tools...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Keep polished steel tools, enwrapped in wool in a closed box. Razors, etc should be so
                                kept, </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We feel it our duty to give a recipe for the cure of the diphtheria..." TEIform="index"/>We feel it our duty to give a recipe for the cure of the diphtheria...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">says: <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">"We feel it our duty to give a recipe for the cure of the diphtheria, which
                                        we know from personal knowledge has cured several severe cases. It is simply to
                                        put some pure tar on a plate and apply hot coals to it, not hot enough, however,
                                        to create a blaze. Then place a funnel upside down over the tar and let the
                                        patient inhale the fumes arising from the burning tar through the spout of the
                                        funnel. It will give instant relief, and may be repeated as often as may be
                                        necessary. Tar spread on a piece of cloth and applied to the throat in
                                        connection with the inhaling process is also good, much better than old flitch
                                        and liniments. It should not be removed until the the throat is relieved of all
                                        soreness."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Huntingdon monitor" TEIform="index"/>The Huntingdon Monitor</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shaker Manifesto, one of our New Hampshire publications, appears in magazine form on..." TEIform="index"/>The Shaker Manifesto, one of our New Hampshire publications, appears in magazine form on...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Shaker Manifesto, one of our New Hampshire publications, appears in
                                        magazine form on the opening number of the eighth volume. This is the official
                                        monthly publication of the United Shaker societies, is published by N. A. Briggs
                                        of the Canterbury family. It is devoted to the defence and advocacy of the
                                        tenets of their belief, but contains much spicy and interesting reading. In each
                                        number appears one or more of their songs set to music, which, from the
                                        popularity of their worsl ip to the Gentile world, ought to be an important
                                        feature in extending its circulation. A few agricultural hints are inserted, the
                                        fruit of their own experience, and we hope to see this department enlarged, for
                                        the Shakers have a reputation of being successful farmers. It appears in new
                                        type, and is the work of Shaker hands alone. We trust that their efforts at
                                        improvement will be attended by remunerative patronage.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="People" TEIform="index"/>The People</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>SOCIETY RECORD</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Eldresses of the Church, Matilda Reed and Ann Maria Greaves. Office Deaconesses : Mary
                                Hazard, Tabitha Lapsley and Florinda Sears. Family Deaconesses : Elizabeth Sears has
                                become the associate of Anna Dodgson and Julia Ann Scott. The Ministry have moved from
                                "The Meeting House," into their new and beautiful Home." The sweet singer, Clark, has
                                been recentlj paying his respects to the people here, through spiritual songs.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Official relations of the Church Order have recently been changed: Aurelia White succeeds
                                Ruth A. Green, deM^JsrimESTO<pb n="49" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MLAJNTCIPESTO. ceased; and
                                Ella Benedict has succeeded Adelaide Ingham. Samantha Bowie remains also at the office.
                                The beautiful Chestnut trees, through which grove so many thousands pass in going to
                                Church at this place, having attained perfection, will be cut down for ship and cabinet
                                lumber, and any wishing such, will do well to order it, in sizes and quantities to suit
                                their purposes. Hon. John E. Page, of Albany N. Y., recently invited, and handsomely
                                entertained a party of thirty of our people, at a lecture upon the Holy Land; made
                                interesting by stereoscopic panorama, by the lecturer, E. W. Clark. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religio-philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bundy, J. C." TEIform="persName"/> J. C. Bundy</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Priest in absolution" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bennett, D. M." TEIform="persName"/>D. M. Bennett</byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> We have received from the U. S. Commissioners of Agriculture, several interesting
                                pamphlet.-; and reports, of the conditions of the country from views taken from an
                                Agricultural standpoint. Those treating upon Corn, Svgar Cane, and Beet Sugar are
                                particularly interesting. We hereby repeat our thanks for the notice. The
                                Religio-Philosophical Journal; J. C. Bundy, Chicago, 111. One of the two most prominent
                                Spiritualistic papers in America, and one that is very worthy of excellent notice,
                                justly faults us for crediting to The Banner of Light, (another excellent medium of
                                spiritualistic literature) an original editorial of the R. P. J. We are sorry that it so
                                occurred; but disclaim any intention of wronging the Journal; and claim it to be a
                                mistake. The article, '¦'¦Form Materialization," was sent to us, cut from some paper,
                                and accredited to the Banner. Asking pardon, we hope others, making the mistake, will be
                                more careful in future. ii The Priest in Absolution:" J). M. Bennett, New York,
                                Publisher; Price 25 cents. Reference has been made to this work by Elder Evans in a
                                previous number of The Shaker ; and in full agreement with his expressed opinions, we
                                caution the introduction of the Confessional into Protestant Churches, until the
                                priesthood embraces an equal repre- sentation of the sexes. The power of the
                                Confessional is as givat today as ever in the past; and abused, as it is likely to be,
                                when used only by masculine curiosity and lasciviousness, is of the greatest detriment
                                to society at large. We believe in the confessional; that it does us good to find a
                                fellow sympathy in distresses we ill can bear alone ; and from which we seek alleviation
                                of pain by sorrowful rehearsal of what we have done wrongly. But let no man assume the
                                unholy power of converting this desirable good to base, perfidious ends! The book will
                                be extensively read, and, may it be properly understood. We have received a copy of a
                                recent lecture by Elder F. W. Evans upon "The Shaker System." It is an ably written,
                                little pamphlet, embodying a host of valuable ideas; and which, to many reformers will
                                be deemed of invaluable worth. TheElder shows but little declension of power or ability
                                to use that power, when crowned as he is with three score and ten honorable years. Send
                                ten cents to Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. for a copy. James Brothers, Publishers, of Cincinnati O.
                                have issued a United States History especially for Schools. It is a unique volume,
                                embracing on "a new and comprehensive plan, all the features of Lyman's Historical
                                Chart." Its maps and cuts are the most accurate we have ever seen. Its language is
                                simplicity itself, and the whole study made like the most interesting of story books. It
                                will teach the history of our country, without a thought of its being a task. Its author
                                is John Clark Eidpath, A. M. We have received from the publishers, S. R. Wells Co. of
                                New York, their Illustrated Annual of Phrenology and Health Almanac for 1878. It is
                                filled with good reading, Irygienic recipes, illustrations of illustrious individuals,
                                and a general information of the principles of Phrenology. Its price is only ten cents.
                                We observe in it also that the price of the Am. Phrenological Journal is reduced from
                                $3.00, to $2.00. This ia ncbly cheap! </p></div3></div2><pb n="50" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beautiful home" TEIform="index"/>BEAUTIFUL HOME</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. There's a home bove, a beautiful home, avvait ing the true the
                            faithful heir; When the battle is o'er, and the victory won, There's a home for the
                            Chorus. soul, heavenly home. Courage! my brothers, each step bears you on, On to that
                            beautiful home; March ye in triumph with victory MANIFESTO. a<pb n="51" id="p29" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 51 2. There are friends we love in that beautiful home, Awaiting us all
                            with anxious care, Let us honor their trust our loyalty prove, And meet in that home, our
                            heavenly home. </p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selected</head><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self-sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>Self-Sacrifice.</head><p TEIform="p"> Down, selfish thoughts that rise, And whisper to my soul, Keep back, O Satan of my life,
                                You shall not have control. O, what am I, I ask, All pleasant things to claim? I bow my
                                head to kiss the rod, And blush for very shame. A little thing from God, Placed here to
                                do His will, To serve my fellows while I may, My mission to fulfil. What if Desire
                                allure My steps to walk 'mid flowers, If duty calls me otherwheres I leave her charmed
                                bowers. Where Pain and Sorrow call, My feet must not be slow, Though into laughing
                                crowds of joy They much prefer to go. Not lost in pleasant dreams, And castles in the
                                air; 'Tis real life demands my aid, With homes of grief and care. Ambition holds her
                                cards To charm my human eyes, But blind to them I still must choose, Humble
                                Self-sacrifice. Content if but at last, At setting of life's sun, I slip from darkness
                                into light To hear the sweet "Well done." </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Peck, Ellen O." TEIform="persName">
                                    Ellen
                                    O.
                                    Peck
                                </persName> [In The Cottage Hearth.]</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Persons, Ann Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Ann Elizabeth Persons
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Persons, Ann Elizabeth" TEIform="persName">Ann Elizabeth Persons</persName>, at Harvard,
                                Dec. 6, aged 49 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Galloway, Achsa" TEIform="index"/>Achsa Galloway
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Galloway, Achsa" TEIform="persName">Achsa Galloway</persName>, at Union Village, Ohio,
                                December 30, aged 90. </p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harris, Chloe" TEIform="index"/>Chloe Harris
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Harris, Chloe" TEIform="persName">Chloe Harris</persName>, at Shirley, Mass. January 9, aged
                                81. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meneeley Co. of West Troy New York..." TEIform="index"/>Meneeley Co. of West Troy New York...
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Meneeley Co. of West Troy N. Y. are competing with, the U. S. government in civilizing
                                the Indians! Goternment sending destructive, horror making cannons; Meneeley Co. sending
                                sweet sounding Church Bell! Meneeley Co. were a long way ahead at last accounts. We are
                                using a number of The Bickford Knitting Machines; and they are very satisfactory indeed,
                                Being among "the wonders in this age" of machinery, their utility and expedition in
                                business should be experienced by all, at so small cost. Material for Fences of wood
                                variety is getting scarce. We must soon accept the alternative of no fences, or rely on
                                the metal ones offered us by Washburn, Moen Co. Please read advertisement of Wasson and
                                Martin several times. They form an enterprising and reliable firm. A Useful Apparatus :
                                JohnBunyan said, that "an idle boy's or girl's head was the devil's workshop^ Get them
                                the "Keystone Self-Inker" with complement of type. See Adv. crowned, Home to a heav en
                                ly home<pb n="52" id="p30" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. Let "Jones of Binghamplon" have a
                                balance and a weigh in your affairs. Comparatively speaking, his weighs are very
                                economical. The Evening Times : Albany, N. Y. The verdict of a political opponent is:
                                "The best family paper; and conducted with most ability of any outside of New York
                                city." The U. S. Piano Co. enter a challenge to other manufacturers and salesmen. We
                                mean to make ourselves more acquainted with their instruments. People will have Pianos,
                                and they will look where to get them, in The Shaker Manifesto. Every farmer will yet be
                                his own Miller ; grinding out his "religious bread" as Elder F. W. Evans would say; then
                                they will send for one of Sedgebeer's "Nonpareil." Send for a circular now. We are at a
                                loss to speak as yet, of the bent Watbb Wheel ; but we are at no loss to say that the
                                firms of Leffel &amp; Co. and N. F. Burnham, who enter into friendly competition in
                                our columns, are both most honorable. By reference to our Br. Philip Smith's
                                advertisement, it will be seen that Farmers, Gardeners, Amateurs, and "the rest of
                                mankind" can get genuine Shaker Garden Seeds by mail, at the very lowest cash prices.
                                Try the seeds, coming immediately from the grower; it will pay you. Van Deusen'sTREE
                                Label and "Business Cards" are a desiderata long looked for. Send for a Circular and
                                sample. The Hon. Clute Bros, of Schenectady, N. Y. present most excellent encouragements
                                for parties wishing Engines, Boilers, etc. We know, also, of the "Cluth Plough" being
                                the best plough yet created, for all kinds of cross ploughing. </p></div3></div2><!-- 
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> For neat, and expeditious printing, of Cards, Envelopes, Letter, and Bill headings ; of receipts and postal
                            cards ; at the most reasonable rates, try our young and enterprising Shaker friend, Washington Jones. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y. SEND FOB HIS CIRCULAR AND PRICE MST, SENT FREE. For sewing machine supplies such as, Needles,
                            Tuckers, Hemmers, Rufflers, Shuttles &c. in fact, for all parts and everything belonging to the above.
                            Send to C. P. BELL Telegraph Block, Nashua, N. H. Orders by mail or express promptly attended to. Also PIANOS
                            & ORGANS. Sold, rented or exchanged. L 53 We have been acquainted with F. T. Van Patten fo more than
                            twenty years, and assure our friends, wh need Broom Machinery, or anything in his line of busi ness, that they
                            will receive the best of satisfaction Send for his Circular. Oftentimes, we are led to regret, that there are un
                            scrupulous persons, who, realizing the solid benefits o judicious advertising, will use it most freely on som
                            useless or worse than useless articles, and soon retir with fortunes of ill-earned gains. But we can still point
                            to thousands who by a wholesome judicious judgment, have used advertising to their exceeding profit! and to the
                            most creditable advancement of useful materials. Such, we believe our patrons to be. We have taken considerable
                            and particular pains to acquaint ourself with Dr. Frazier's remedies, and find from those using them, only a
                            good report. His Bittees are purely medicinal, and not an intoxicant beverage. For months, we have been witness
                            of the workings of Cooley's Creamer, and we know of many who endorse what we have inserted as their
                            advertisement. We are confident dairy people will inquire into the arrangement, and send for Circulars. It will
                            pay to do General FLOUR 3II1L.3L. and T?JLPJER, MILL Machinery. And full line of mill furnishing. The AMERICAN
                            TURBINE WHEEL produces the. best average percentage of any Turbine ever known. Large illustrated catalogue sent
                            free. ADDRESS, STOUT MILLS & TEMPLE, DAYTON,OHIO. viokS" illustrated monthly magazine. Each Number
                            contains Thirty-two Pages of reading, many fine Wood Cut Illustrations, and one Coirored Plate. A beautiful
                            Garden Magazine, printed on elegant paper, and full of information. In English and German. Price $1.25 a year:
                            Five copies $5.00. Vick's Flower and Vegetable Garden, 50 cents in paper covers; in elegaut cloth covers $1.00.
                            Viek's Catalogue, 300 Illustrations, only 2 cents. Address, JAMES VICK, Rochester, N. Y. In ordering please
                            mention the Shaker Manifesto.<pb id="p31"/> $20 KNITTING MACHINE. KThe NEW-BICKFORD FAMILY KNITTING MACHINE all
                            complete for $20, (former lowest Price $300 Delivered at any Express office in the U. S. or Canada Free, on
                            Eeceipt of Eetail Price, Send for New Descriptive Circular, A splendid chance for AGENTS, one wanted in every
                            Town, Exclusive Eight of Sale given FREE. Address, BICKFORD KNITTING MACHINE MFG. CO., Brattleboro, Vt.
                            Kstatolished 1816. The Societies at Canterbury and Watervliet have used this I1VK. for many years, and they
                            unhesitatingly recommend it as a good, reliable article; of good color, flows freely, and does not fade. Maynard
                            «fc Noyes, BostonJ. SEDGEREER'S PATENT NONPAREIL Self - Sharpening, Reversible Motion Crushing and Grinding
                            Farm, Bone and Drug Mills. 12 sizes. Send for free illustrated descriptive Catalogues and Price-list. Address J.
                            SEBGEP.EEB, Paiziesville, O. THE ALBANY ROOFING AND GALVANIZED I EON WOKKS Will furnish on application estimates
                            on all styles of R O O F I N G ! Slate, Tin & Warren's Gravel Roofing. Galvanized Iron Cornices, Window
                            Caps, Conductors, fecLightningKodsJa specialty. A large line of Roofing Material, Sheathing Paper & Felt
                            always in stock. Av^-ssoisr & M^jRTnsr. Nos. 7 and 9 JAMES STREET. §£gp°Answering advertisement: Please
                            mention The Shaker Manifesto. FAMILY SOAPS. By C. BERKLEY JOHNSON, Senior member of the late firm of E. A.
                            & W. WINCHESTER. The character and quality of E. A. & W. Winchester's Soap is fully equal, in
                            every respect, to its former Standard. Its Style is plain. It is not garnished with Showy Labels. It recommends
                            itself by its excellence. It is designed for family use more than for trade. Trade generally demands something
                            cheaper, consequently inferior. Address, C. BERKLEY JOHNSON, IS Chatham St. BOSTON, MASS. THE ALBANY WEEKLY
                            TIMES Is in all respects a PIEST-CLASS FAMILY JOURNAL Devoted to the promotion of the interests of the whole
                            people. It is a large THIRTY-TWO COLUMN PAPER, Well filled with Choice Reading Matter, Literary, Scientific and
                            Political. For its size and the amount of usual reading matter, it is the Cheapest Paper in the Country! TERMS:
                            One copy one year......$1 60 Ten copies one year......10 00 Twenty-one copies one year . . . 20 60 Address THE
                            TIMES COMPANY, 401 Broadway, Albany, N. Y. SHAKER SEEDS BY MAIL! GENUINE SHAKER GARDEN SEEDS. Farmers and
                            Gardeners get your genuine Shaker Gardes Seeds directly from the grower. Send for Catalooitb and Price List
                            ready by Feb. 1. We will send the Best Seeds of all kinds at verj lowest cash prices, prepaid by mail.
                            Attention, Farmers and Gardeners! Try us,—Address PHILIP SMITH. Shakers, N. Y. SEEDSMAN. SHAKER TLA1NELS
                            & KNIT GOODS, CORN BROOMS & BRUSHES. Address, N". J±. Briggs Sliaker "Village, 3NT. H.<pb
                                id="p32"/> broom: machinery AND Wheelbarrow Factory, F. T. VAN PATTEN, Proprietor, MANUFACTURER OF BROOM
                            WINDERS, VISES, SCRAPERS, TRIMMERS, PLANTERS AND WHEELBARROWS. SCHENECTADY,N. Y.. P. O. BOX, 26. NOTE. I
                            desire to call attention to the extreme simplicity of all machines made by me, also to the fact that they are
                            all made by experienced workmen, and from the best seasoned timber. 269 RIVER, St. TROY, N. Y. "Exclusive Agent"
                            for Steinway, Chiekering's & HAINES' PIANOS. & Estey Organs. If in seabch of First Class
                            Bargains in PIANOS, or ORGANS, and desire a choice from the Best manufactured at the most attractive Price for
                            Cash, Do not faO to call upon FOR THAT RHEUMATISM. Try Dr. Dean's Rheumatic'Pills, the old, popular standard and
                            efficacious remedy. Ask for them at your Druggists. MAYNARD& NOYESAgts. BOSTON. SOHENECTADY, TS.Y.
                            Huilders of Marine, Stationary and "Portable Steam JEnffines and ^Boilers. Shaker Broom Handle Lathes, (the best
                            Lathe in Market.) Engines for Farm work, cutting and steaming feed, driving Threshing Machines, cfc, from 1
                            horse, to 10 horse power. Send for IPrice List. A Practical Christmas Present. $2 Self-Inker Keystone Press, 100
                            Printing Letters, Roller, Ink, Reglets, Leads, Cards, Type, and Outside Case. All for $3. Stamp for Catalogue.
                            W. C. Evans, 50 N. Ninth St., Phila., Pa. LEFPEL WATER WHEELS. With recent improvements. Prices Greatly Reduced,
                            7000 in successful operation. FHTZ NEW PAMPHLET JOB 1S77, vent free to those interested. James Leffel &
                            Co, Springfield, O. tog Liberty St., N. Y. City. OUR CORUNDUM POLISHER A Tool for Cutting. Leveling and
                            Polishing Furrows in a Mill Stone. With the use of this tool the miller can make a uniform, level and smooth
                            furrow, and do the work in one-tenth the time required to do it with a Mill Pick. It is acknowledged by millers
                            using them to be the most practical and labor-saving Tool for the miller's use. The frame is iron, with wood
                            handle. The cutting face is a composition of recently dis- covered mineral, the hardest and fastest cutting
                            material known to the scientific world. One of these tools will last, in an ordinary mill, from one to two
                            years, andean be refilled at a cost of $2. By sending amount you will save expense. PEIOE $3. 50, Manufactured
                            by WEED & CO., MENEELY'S BELLS. The genuine TROY CHURCH BELLS known to the public since |826>
                            which have acquired a reputation unequaled by any, and a sale exceeding that of all others. No agencies. P. O.
                            address, either Troy or West Troy, N. Y. MENEELY&CO.<pb id="p33"/> ATLANTIC WHITE LEAD LINSEED OIL CO.
                            EOBT. COLGATE & Co., 287 PEARL ST. N. Y. The Atlantic White Lead is'warranted pure, and is manufactured
                            exclusively from the best selected refined leads and ground in refined Linseed Oil. It is packed in, Casks of
                            200 and 1000 pounds. Kegs of 25, 50 & 100 pounds. Wooden Buckets (with handles) of 12.5 25 & 50
                            pounds. Also n Tin Pails (with handles) of 12.5 & 25 pounds Cans and carefully put up in wooden cases 4
                            or 8 in a case— LINSEED OIL WARRANTED FX7R-E. RAW, BOILED AND REFINED, I2ST CASKS .AJNTD BARRELS. FOR SALE BY
                            ALL THE LARGE DEALERS. Improved Shaker Washing Machines. For Laundries, Hotels, Asylums and other large
                            Institutions. Preference given in Report of Judges at the Centennial Exhibition, Medal and Diploma Awarded*
                            Patented July 23, 1877. N. A. Briggs Shaker Village, N. H.<pb id="p34"/> JOHN WITITEILIE Y. Manufacturer of
                            SHAKER BROOMS, Shirley Village, Mass. ^VGOEINTT FOR "The Shaker"—monthly-60 cts. per annum "The Divine
                            Afflatus"—10 cts. per copy. "The Shaker's answer"—6 cts. per copy. "The Divinity of Humanity"—3 cts. per copy.
                            I^iberal discount in quantities. ¦JK@=Parties answering advertisements: Will you please mention The Shakee
                            Manifesto? OP £IVEEY SIZE, A.JSTT2 VARIETY MADE BT American Tack Co., Faikhaven, Mass. WHEELER & WILSON.
                            IPIROIINrOTTIN CED THE BEST IN THE WORLD. HIOHEST AWARD AT THE CENTENNIAL. "Of all the Machines we tested, the
                            Wheeler & Wilson New Machine was the most com- pletely successful, failing in nothing that was given
                            it." FRED. A. PAGET. £ One of the Centennial Judges of Sewing Machine*. Prom his report to the English.
                            Government. HIGHEST AWAKDS GIVEN THIS AT THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE FAIRS OF 1873,1874, 1875,1878 £ 1877. At the
                            close of the Exhibition of 1877, he Judges announced as their Unanimous )pinion° that this machine has already
                            reeived from the American Institute all the avards and recognition under the rules possile to a Sewing Machine.
                            "We do not hesiate to declare it the best Sewing Apparatus n the world. We recommend for it the highst
                            recognition under the rules that can be avarded— THE SPECIAL' JVIEr^Xj OK1Q7V. AGENTS WANTED WHERE NOT NOW
                            BEPBESENTED GENERAL OFFICE, 4=4 UIVIOjV SQUARE, ]V. Y. BRANCHES 530 BROADWAY ALBANY, 454 FULTON St. TROT. Mt.
                            Lebanon, Shaker Village, N. Y., Sept. 3,1877 Vermont Farm Machine Co.,Bellows Falls Vt. Dear Sirs :—Tlie two No.
                            3 Creameries I purcha ed of you have been in constant use for two month The result has been very satisfactory.
                            It answers fu ly to your guarantee in every particular. You hav not claimed one iota too much in your circular.
                            Wit the submerged cans we have a decided increase o: cream, of a quality far superior to any we have hereto fore
                            obtained by the old method of setting in commo pans. The butter produced from the cream is muc sweeter and finer
                            flavored, and fully sustains the nam "Gilt Edge Butter." Yours Respectfully, LEVI SHAW. Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co.,
                            N. Y., Sept. 21,1877. Vermont Farm Machine Co. Bellows Falls, Vt. Respected Friends—We fully and gratefully
                            endorse all the recommendations we have seen in favor of Cooley's Creamery; believing it to be all that it
                            purports to be in every particular. We feel confident it is the greatest friend that has ever come to the relief
                            of the dairy. Our labors are lightened fully one-half, and the results every way superior to all other known
                            ways of setting milk. We would upon no consideration go back to any of the old methods, but would consign them
                            all with the antiquities of the past. ANN OFFORD, RUTH BARRY, North Family Shakers.<pb id="p35"/> TREE E3Or-AJL
                            NOTICES. LABELS, Patent Mi¦ ca-Faced Labels for Trees, Shrubs, Vines, Plants, etc. Admitted.by leading:
                            Horticulturists, to be the best Label ever invented. Impervious to the weather, and in reality, an excellent
                            article. Price 50 cents per dozen, $3.00 per hundred, all orders to be accompanied by the Cash. Any name
                            desired. Samples sent to parties send- ing two 3 cent stamps. Orders promptly executed. Direct to R. VAN DEUSEN,
                            3mo. Shaker Station, Ct. Nicer than Wise: Those whose prejudice leads them to patronize the old monopolists when
                            they can buy Five Ton Hay Scales for £50. freight paid and no money asked till tested—The Lithograph and price
                            list. Jones of Binghamton, Bingh.am.ton, K*. Y. PRICELESS DISOOVEKY. A SURE CURE FOR PILES. A sure cure for the
                            blind, bleeding, itching, and uleeratrd piles has been discovered by Dr. William, (an Indian remed},) called Dr.
                            WilliamV Indian Ointment. A single box has cured the worst old chronic cases of twenty-live aisel thirty years'
                            standing. No one need sutler five minutes after applying this wonderful soothing medicine. Lotions, instruments
                            and electuaries do more harm than good. William's Ointment supports the tumors, allays the intense itching
                            (particularly at night after getting warm in bed), acts as a poultice, gives instant and painless reli'f, and is
                            prepared only for Piles and nothing else. Thousands of cured patients attest its virtues, and physicians of all
                            schools pronounce it the greatest contribution to medicine of the age. It matte rs not how loi g or severely you
                            have been suffering, you can be cured. Mr. Joseph !V1. Ryder, Cleveland, Ohio, writes: I suffered for years with
                            Itching and Ulcerated Piles, tried remedy after remedy advertised, and consulted physicians in Philadelphia,
                            Louisville, Cincinnati, Indianapolis and this citj-; and spent hundreds of dollars, but found no relief until I
                            obtained a box of Dr. William's Indian Ointment some four months ago, and it has cured me completely. I had a
                            part of the. box left which I gave to a friend of mine who had doctored with many physicians, and as a last
                            resort went to the noted Hot Springs, Arkansas, for treatment. He informs me that the Indian Ointment has also
                            cured him of the Piles. It i« certainly a woudeiful discovery and should be used by the many thousands who are
                            now suffering with that dreael disease. «®-$10.000 Reward will be paid for a more certain remedy. Sold by all
                            Druggists. Dr. G. W. Frazier, sole proprietor, Cleveland, O. DONtFnECLECT A COUCHL or Cold, when 25 c'ts will
                            buy a bottle of Dr. Frazier's Cough Syrup at any drug store. It has wrought a complete change in the Cough
                            Medicines, is pleasant as honey and always cures. TO CONSUMPTIVES. ISfDr. Frazier's Cough Syrup used in
                            connection with Dr. Frazier's Hoot Bitters will cube consumption. Standard Steam Laundry, Cleveland, O., Oct.
                            30, 76. Dr. Frazier. Dear Sir: I feel it a duty I owe to Suffering-humanity to write you. For some time I was
                            sorely afflicted with a cough, raising bad stuff, with every symptom of being a confirmed consumptive. I fried
                            different medicines and cures without finding relief; I also consulted three of our most prominent Cleveland
                            physicians, the last one of which pronounced my case serious, and informed me that I coulel not live more than a
                            few months. About this time, hearing of your wonderful success, I commenced taking your S3'rup in couneclion
                            wilh your Boot Bitters, and was "at once benefiteel, and after using the medicine some two months 1 find rnys'lt
                            entirely cured. TOREXCE DUISTi. J8f#"Mr. Dunn again writrs, uneler date of Aug. 4, 1877,—Dr. Frazier, Dear Sir:
                            I endorse your medicines more strongly than ever from the fact that it is now nearly one year since I was cured.
                            My lungs are to-day strong and sound, having no return of the dise'ase. 4 The above Medicines speak for
                            themselves. DR. G. W. FRAZIER, Proprietor, Cleveland, O. For sals by all Druggists. CQROROOMS & BRUSHES.
                            N. A. BKIGGS, Shaker Village, N. H.. Mention "The Shaker Manifesto" in replying to advertisements.<pb id="p36"/>
                            g It is so simple in construction and runs so easily thaf a child can operate it. 466* It has the straight,
                            self-setting needle, our improved shuttle, with a perfect tension, which does not change as the bobbin becomes
                            exhausted. J6SS" All the wearing points are adjustable^ and it combines every desirable improvement. jg" Every
                            Machine is sent out ready for use, after being thoroughly tested. Notwithstanding the GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICES
                            we continue to use the best material and exercise the greatest care in their manufacture. Western Branch Office,
                            331 West Madison St., Chicago, 111. Washburn & Moen Man'f'g Co. WORCESTER, MASS* Sole Hamifactipers East
                            of Caicago, of A STEEL Thom Hftdge. No other Fencing so cheap or put up eo quickly. Never rusts, stains, decays,
                            shrinks, noi' \varps. XInaSSeoted by fire, wind, or flood. A complete barrier to the most; unruly stock.
                            ImpassaWe by man or beast. TWO THOUSAND TONS BOLD AND PCJT TJP DURING THE LAST YEAR. For sale at the leading
                            hardware stores, with Stretchers and ^Staples. Sead for iUuetrated Pajnnhlct Also j\fanvfactui'ers of all kinds
                            of IRON AND STEEL WME. A Speciality made of TINNED BROOM WIRE. TRY SHAKER'S CORBETT'S SARSAPARILLA, For
                            Purifying the Blood; best Medicine at all Seasons. Ask for it at your Drug-gists. Maynard & Noyes
                            Boston. WE sell a First-Class Plan cheaper than any other house in America. Have no Agents, but sell DIRECT TO
                            FAMILIES AT FACTORY PRICE, and warrant 5 years. Pianos sent for trial at our expense. Illustrated Circular Free,
                            givintj full particulars, and names of over 2,000 Bankers, Merchants find Families using our Pianos in every
                            State and Territory. Address, V. S. PIANO eo., 810 Uroadway, JT. Y. VICTOR SEWING MACHINE CO., PEI17CIPAL 0FFIC3
                            and Manufactories, Hiddetwn, Cone. X. F. BUKXHAM'S 1 S74_'WatexWMEEL Is DKcr>Ai:i;T) the 'STANDARD
                            TURBINE,' by over 000 persons who bought and use them with PART and FtTlX GATE open, illustrated and de-
                            scriptive Pamphletf ree. Address N. F. BURNHAM, P. O. Box 513. York, Pa. Gearing for Factories, Flouring Mills,
                            Puper Mill* tfe Saw mills a specialty by BI100MELL& BURNHAM, Christiana. Lancaster Co., JPa. WHEELER
                            & MELICK CO. MANUFACTURERS OP Threshing Machines, Horse Powers, Shingle Machines, Horse Forks, Sulkey
                            Horse Rakes, &c. ALBANY, Y </p>
                    </div2>
                        --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>