<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0307" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><date value="18730701" TEIform="date">July 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">49-56</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="49" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                    <p>Vol. III. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. "W. EVANS, Editor. MtLebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. July, 1873. No. 7. Fifty
                        Cents per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Heavens" TEIform="index"/>THE HEAVENS</head><p TEIform="p">That the heavens are plural, is as generally an admitted fact as any that can be named. How
                            many heavens there are, is an open question. But the number seven would probably gather to
                            it the greatest number of believers, both within and outside of our Order. " Ye know not
                            what spirit ye are of," said Jesus to his disciples, when they proposed to do as Elijah had
                            done before them, bring from the spirit-world, through the agency of spirits in the second
                            or Jewish heavens, primitive fire to consume the villagers who would not receive and
                            entertain them over night. How was this? What had these people done, or not done, deserving
                            of death, even at the hands of angels, and by fire coming down from heaven 1 The disciples
                            at the time were professing to be Christians, to be under the ministrations of spirits of
                            the seventh sphere ; and were being instructed in " the mysteries of the kingdom of heaven,"
                            which was the dawn of the seventh heaven upon this earth. The angels of the second heaven
                            were still in the life of generation and war. Their Zion on earth was the Jewish temple ;
                            and, under the influence of the religious revival inaugurated by John the Baptist, those
                            angels helped Jesus, by inspiring and using him as a medium, to cleanse the temple of the
                            thieves and robbers, together with the money and the animals, which had turned it into a
                            house of merchandise, instead of " a house of prayer for all nations."* That was war on the
                            Jewish plane, and in the degree represented by Elijah. It was right on the part of those
                            angels in the order and heaven they were in. But it was wrong on the part of Jesus, in the
                            order and heaven under which he was called; and, in the cool of the day, when Jesus came out
                            of his mediumship, and began to feel after the angels of his higher mission, he was humbled
                            by their presence, and fell under judgment and condemnation, which the disciples observing,
                            the prophetic saying came to their remembrance: " The zeal of thine house," in the lower
                            order, " hath eaten " up his life in the Christ heaven; until, in his " humiliation " and
                            repentance, " his judgment was taken away " by a renewed baptism from the seventh heaven,
                            and a restoration to union with his proper ministering angels, which he received, not as a
                            Jew, but as a Christian. Thus was Jesus instructed in the Christian sphere of warfare, which
                            is not physical or carnal, but is " mighty through God to the pulling down of strongholds,
                            casting down imaginations and every high thing * It was at the instigation of the same
                            Jewish spirits, that Jesus attended a wedding, and that he commanded his Apostles to sell
                            their clothes, to buy swords with the proceeds. that exalteth itself against the knowledge
                            of God, and bringing into captivity every thought to the obedience of Christ." It was not
                            carnal, even as pure Jewish wars were not carnal, where no physical violence was done by
                            those in the body, death being inflicted by disembodied warriors. Reproduction of the
                            highest order was the same in the children of promise or premeditation, where offspring was
                            the sole object of sexual intercourse. It was, then, simply as a Jew that Jesus was a medium
                            in the temple for the angels of the heaven who inspired Elijah. And as Jews, his Apostles,
                            who had thus seen Jesus exercise war on the Jewish plane, essayed, in the case of the
                            Samaritans, to follow his example, not yet having attained to the Christ sphere of war.
                            Jesus having received reproof and instruction himself, administered by the Christ angels,
                            administered the same to his Apostles, saying, " The son of man is not come to destroy men's
                            lives, but to save them." That was not to them entire redemption from one sphere to the
                            other ; for they would alternate between the two. When the Christ cross was too heavy, they
                            would drop it, and take up the Jewish cross, as the more natural and bearable of the two.
                            Anon, they would repent, and rise again into their proper order, until they learned to know
                            what spirit they were of, and from which of the heavens their ministering spirits had come
                            to them from their old heavens, which were fast passing away from them, or from their new
                            heavens, in which they were called to form a permanent inheritance. It is the same to-day
                            with the representatives of the various sects and opposers of sects in Babylon, who are
                            called to be Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, and to receive ministrations from the
                            same Christ-heavens from which Jesus and his Apostles received their ministrations ; " God
                            having concluded them all in unbelief, that he might have mercy upon all;" it being a law,
                            that none in an inferior dispensation can sin beyond the power of redemption by that which
                            succeeds and is superior to it; as it is also a law, that those who have attained to the
                            highest degree of spirituality in an inferior dispensation, when conjoined to a sensual,
                            animal life, are more difficult of resurrection than those who live an equally sensual life,
                            but whose spiritual powers have not been quickened to the same degree. In the superior
                            dispensation, the constant tendency of old habits and modes of thought is to attract and
                            bring back their former ministering and guardian spirits; and the last end of such persons
                            is worse than the first, because it is more difficult to convict them of the fact, and
                            convert them the second time; even as it would be more difficult to cause fire to pass over
                            the burnt forest of the West than it was previous to the conflagration. This is one of the
                            stratagems of the enemy, of which the Apostles declared themselves to be not ignorant. "
                            There is a way which seemeth right to a man, the end whereof is death." Nothing so confirms
                            a person in the correctness of his ideas, or positions, as the impress of the spirit who is
                            in the same mental and spiritual condition. It becomes " confirmation strong as proofs from
                            Holy Writ." " Beloved, believe not every spirit, but try the spirits," and seek to know to
                            what order they belong, and from what heaven or hell, or intermediate sphere they have
                            proceeded — whether from the old heavens, from which you used to be inspired when living in
                            the world, or from the new heavens whence alone inspirations may come that will create you
                            anew — make you a new creature. As of old, the spirits that acknowledged that Christ had
                            come to men and women in the flesh, in the persons of Jesus and Peter and his successors,
                            until the Church fled into the wilderness ; so also, in our day, those spirits who
                            acknowledge that Christ has come in Ann Lee with equal power, and to her successors with as
                            great authority as they appeared in those whom Jesus sent, are true Christ Spirits.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Community" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNITY</head><p TEIform="p">A Shaker Society is not one great Community of temporal interests, as is so generally-
                            supposed by outsiders. In each Society there are several Communities, or Families. The
                            members of every Family have "all things common" secured by Covenant. Agreeable to its
                            provisions, executive officers are appointed from Elders and Trustees down to the minor
                            officers — care-takers and burden-bearers, "helps in Government." In it, there are no
                            invidious distinctions of rich and poor, male or female; all fare alike in food and
                            clothing, and all are equally eligible to office, the government being dual. Families in a
                            Society may differ in their temporal conditions, from fortuitous circumstances, such as
                            location, the business they chose to adopt, the ability to conduct affairs, the number of
                            members, and from many other causes of a temporal and spiritual nature — the same
                            contingencies as those to which Societies are subject. Hence Families, or Communities, and
                            even Societies, which are aggregations of Communities, may be, comparatively, rich or poor.
                            But, in a poor Family, the poverty is entirely nominal, inasmuch as, so long as the
                                organi<pb n="50" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> zation lasts, the physical wants of such are quite as amply
                            provided for as are those of a rich Family or Society. Indeed, as a general rule, the poor
                            among Shakers are those who live the fullest, and that is one means of their poverty. And
                            the worst that can happen is, that the waning Family becomes broken up, and its members
                            absorbed in other Families of the Society. Then they are as rich as any other of the
                            members. " And the children of Israel gathered some more, some less of the manna; and, when
                            they did mete it with an omer, he that gathered much had nothing over, and he that gathered
                            little had no lack. They gathered every man according to his eating." (Ex. 17: 18.)
                            Consequently, it is not the county-house door that stands open before the poor Shaker, but
                            the door of and into some other of the several Communities, where they are made heartily
                            welcome as to their own. It is thus that the abstract idea of equality is realized
                            throughout the Order, consisting of some sixty Communities, and that the fear and dread of
                            poverty, of sickness, and of old age, so potent in the world, is entirely removed from every
                            true and faithful member of the Organization.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Zion's youth" TEIform="index"/>ZIONS YOUTH</head><p TEIform="p">"Young men (and women) be strong; for ye are able to overcome the wicked one." --o— FitOM
                            observation and experience we are inevitably led to conclude, that this is a world of
                            rudiments. All things, including religion, seem to be in an incipient stage of develop-
                            ment. When we first become conscious of existence, as moral and spiritual beings upon this
                            earth, what very rude and crude patterns of men and women we find ourselves to be. With this
                            painful discovery comes an inward longing for something better and more happifying; and we
                            look about us for some path by which we may reach that better and happier estate. This
                            uneasiness and discontent are the good soil wherein the seeds of a holy inspiration from on
                            high may be sown ; and, if carefully watered by the tears of a salutary repentance, and
                            cultivated by a sincere discipline of the mind in practical holiness — personal
                            righteousness — will yield harvest after harvest of permanent peace — continual atonement —
                            with God forever. It is of the utmost importance that an individual commencing such an
                            existence, which must be eternal, should know, and solemnly ponder these things as early as
                            possible. For, without this knowledge, one may go on for many years in a path directly away
                            from permanent happiness and peace; every step of which must finally be retraced with godly
                            sorrow, as so much time and labor lost, before the spiritual journey, which should have been
                            undertaken long ago, can even be commenced. This is not the worst. Habits of thought and
                            action, which have been contracted in the wrong direction, and greatly to the disadvantage
                            of persons so unfortunate as above stated, often cling to them for long years after they
                            have found, and sincerely entered upon, the bright path of regeneration. How happy and
                            fortunate, then, are those who can say, in the words of the sacred hymn : "The holy Redeemer
                            arrested my soul, When ruinward I should have gone, [roll'd And calm'd the high waves of
                            temptation that And beckon'd me lovingly on." Now, if the giddiness of youth, and "the
                            pleasures of sin for a season," are allowed to take precedence of the higher interests of
                            man in the commencement of his career, then, when years shall have been wasted and gone, to
                            return no more forever, he will look back upon them with bitter grief, and will remember a
                            fearful catalogue of sinful derelictions, words and acts, blasted hopes, and a wounded
                            conscience, which will be as so many broken reeds upon which he cannot lean, and will find
                            himself " pierced through with many sorrows" and agonies which will not be hushed. O what an
                            asylum from evils is a sweet, pure home among Believers, if it is wisely appreciated. I know
                            this by experience, having been in the enjoyment thereof for over half a century, and ever
                            since I was five years old. I began quite early to think of these things. There was
                            something floated across the disk of my mind—a kind of awful, ominous shadow. My conscience
                            seemed to anticipate the terrible wreck of all my peace, should I yield myself to sensual
                            delights. An undefinable terror seemed to seize me, whenever any image of impurity opened
                            the door of my mind, and looked in upon me. For a long time, I was daily in tears,
                            agitations, and prayers, lest I should one day fall by the hand of one of these Sauls of
                            sensuality. But, after a time, I was enabled to fully triumph over them. I rejected the
                            temptation, and, from that day to this, I have never yielded. The great and all-important
                            inference to be drawn from this, which I desire should be received by every youth in Zion
                            is, that, if he or she would take the shortest and least sorrowful road to invulnerable and
                            solid peace, let him or her, after commencing the conflict, resolve firmly to never yield to
                            the enemy one single time. In rolling a heavy stone up a steep hill, if we let it get out of
                            our hands and roll to the bottom, or only part of the way, we not only lose all, or at
                            least, a great portion of what we had gained, but must be at the expense of immense fatigue
                            to regain what we have lost; and the consequences of this vacillating manner of operation
                            are, a vast accumulation of sorrow, weakened resolutions, and waste of time. Not that we
                            would have any become discouraged at any amount of halting, or even yielding, for a time, to
                            adverse influences. For, as Father James once said, " Howsoever low we may fall, it is never
                            too late to cry to God." Blessed sentiment of everlasting charity ! Worthy indeed of the Son
                            of a God whose prime elements are sovereign Love and supreme Wisdom! We only sincerely wish
                            to encourage all our youths to take the easiest, shortest, and most successful path to a
                            state of perennial spiritual serenity and peace — eternal life. And let us all remember,
                            that we have no continuing city, therefore let us seek, among the bright fields of Progress,
                            a better and more enduring habitation; one where joy and happiness, and the peace that
                            passeth our present understanding, may not be shaken to pieces by every misfortune, or
                            adversity of life, as is the fate of all earthly pleasures. Let us not forget that beautiful
                            Bible precept: " Remember now thy Creator in the days of thy youth, before the evil days
                            come, and the years draw nigh, when thou shalt say, I have no pleasure in them." And that
                            sweet inspiration, breathed by the rapt Seer of Babylon: " They that be wise, shall shine as
                            the brightness of the firmament; and they that turn many to righteousness, as the stars
                            forever and ever."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>Oliver Hampton, Union Village, 0.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Orthodoxy vs. science" TEIform="index"/>ORTHODOXY vs. SCIENCE</head><p TEIform="p">" I am now advised that a new astrologer is risen, who presumeth to prove that the earth
                            moveth and goeth about, not the firmament; the sun and moon, not the stars — like as when
                            one sitteth on a coach, or in a ship that is moved, thinketh he sitteth still and resteth,
                            but the earth and trees do move and run themselves. Thus it goeth; we give ourselves up to
                            our own foolish fancies and conceits. This fool (Copernicus) will turn the whole art of
                            astronomy upside down ; but the Scripture showeth and teacheth another lesson when Joshua
                            commandeth the sun to stand still, and not the earth."</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Luther, Martin" TEIform="persName"/>Martin Luther quoted in " Exeter Hall."</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ohio has a new jury law, omitting the word 'white'" TEIform="index"/>Ohio has a new jury law, omitting the word 'white'
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ohio has a new jury law, omitting the word " white."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bi-sexuality of God" TEIform="index"/>BI-SEXUALITY OF GOD</head><p TEIform="p">It is a very strange thing to the outside world, that the Shakers, who have never made much
                            pretension to a knowledge of Hebrew and Greek, should have lit upon the idea of the
                            bi-sexuality of God, manifesting Himself in the flesh, first in the male, and then in the
                            female—Jesus and Ann. The Hebrew word "El" is the radical meaning of God the Creator. The
                            word " Ann " signifies a Mother. If, then, the word " Elohim," God, is a compound of these,
                            it expresses the idea of Bi-Sexuality — Father and Mother God. The Greek word " Theos," God,
                            according to Bretschneider's Lexicon, is both masculine and feminine, and conveys the idea
                            of the Hindoo theology, the oldest on earth, that the sexes unite in the great First Cause.
                            It may seem to strengthen this conception of the Divine Bi-Sexuality, when we contemplate
                            the fact, that the Shakers never got it from books. It seems to have been breathed upon them
                            by the Spirit of God, through Angels and glorified spirits, according to the Greek word "
                            theopneustos," which expresses this very thing. You are aware that Mr. Darwin maintains that
                            the human race was once androgynous; that is to say, the two sexes were united in the same
                            person. Physiologists find proof of this in the rudimental organs; those organs which, in
                            both sexes, are of no use to them now, but which were in use in those far back times, when
                            the race was in its primitive condition of development. However this may be, it cannot be
                            doubted, that the finest human characters among men, are those which blend the strength of
                            the male with the purity and gentleness of the female. And the finest female characters are
                            those which blend the conscious self-reliance and self-respect of the man, with the
                            instinctive gentleness and delicacy of the woman. A man all male does not command our
                            sympathy and confidence. A woman all female has always been the symbol of weakness, and an
                            object of commisseration. Yet it does not take away from the manliness of a man, that there
                            is a broad stripe of the woman woven into his character. Nor does it rob a woman of her
                            chief glory, because she has the firmness, the perseverance, and self-reliance, of her
                            brother, joined with the loveliness that is essentially feminine.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bradford, A. B." TEIform="persName"/>A. B. Bradford</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vitality" TEIform="index"/>VITALITY</head><p TEIform="p">I have turned my attention to the consideration of the circumstances under which seeds will
                            retain their vitality; and to ascertain the length of time in which they will remain dormant
                            without losing their power of growth. I have read some very interesting cases of seeds which
                            have been brought to the surface of the earth from 300 feet below, and yet germinated, and
                            which, it seems, were buried some thousands of years. I quote from Professor Gray: " It is
                            well known, that seeds which have been kept for sixty years have germinated; and, it seems,
                            that grains of wheat, taken from the ancient mummies, under circumstances which leave little
                            doubt of their high antiquity, have been caused to germinate ; but in these cases, there are
                            several sources of possible deception." " Dr. Lindley records the remarkable cases of some
                            raspberries raised, in the garden of the Horticultural Society, from seeds taken from the
                            stomach of a man, whose skeleton was found thirty feet below the surface of SHAKER A.ND 5O
                                <pb n="51" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEKESS. 51 the earth, at the bottom of a barrow, which was
                            opened near Dorchester. He had been buried with some coins of the Emperor Hadrian ; it is
                            therefore probable that the seed was sixteen or seventeen hundred years old. Most seeds,
                            when buried deep in the soil, where they are subject to a uniform and mod- erate
                            temperature, and removed from the influence of the air and light, are in a favorable state
                            for the preservation of vitality, and will germinate when brought to the surface, after a
                            long interval." If it should hereafter be demonstrated, that the vegetable and animal
                            kingdoms were only organized to propagate a specified number of generations; still, we need
                            have no immediate fear of our cultivated plants failing for a long time, if due care be
                            taken to hold. a sufficient quantity of seeds in reserve for future use. It is, therefore,
                            particularly recommended that a proper understanding of this subject be cultivated by
                            Believers. So much for the propagation of plants. I will now introduce another subject. The
                            generations of mankind pass through the same regular course of changes as do individuals ;
                            and, therefore, as an individual is "once a man, and twice a child," the same condition of
                            dotage is destined to befall mankind as a generation. For, in his generations, man has
                            passed through the stages of childhood, youth, manhood, etc., and it would now seem that he
                            is nearing the stage of old age. In early days and times, he had not the capacity of
                            comprehension that he now has. So that, if an angel who was master of the arts and sciences,
                            as now understood by the literati, had, at that period, come down to earth to teach them, he
                            (the angel) would have found the capacities of the human race too weak and feeble for the
                            study. But now look at the capacity of man ; see what great discoveries he has made, and
                            what understanding he has acquired 1 Think of the tele- graph, the railroad, and the
                            numerous other inventions extant; and thereby obtain an idea of his development. But old age
                            must put a stop to his inventions ; and he, as a race, must depend on the acquirements and
                            knowledge that have been gained during his manhood state. I will now bring this article to a
                            close; but will, perhaps, resume it in a short time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Poole, J. B." TEIform="persName"/>J. B. Poole, Hancock, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work" TEIform="index"/>WORK</head><p TEIform="p">The parable concerning the servants to whom certain talents were delivered, is very instruc-
                            tive. When they had received each their talents, their lord said, " Occupy (or improve) till
                            I come." He did not say, " occupy till you get tired, and then lay by ;" but, " occupy till
                            I come " and call on you. This teaches us, that we are not to lay down or give up any
                            talent, or gift given us to improve ; but that we must hold on and faithfully and patiently
                            work, till the authority which bestowed the gift shall release us. Self must not dictate in
                            this. To him who had received five, and gained other five talents, that is, doubled his
                            capacity and gift for usefulness, it was said: " Well done, good and faithful servant, thou
                            hast been faithful over a few things;" thou hast established thy character for faithfulness
                            and integrity, and at the same time hast so improved thy gifts and ca- pacity for further
                            usefulness, that thou canst now take and bear a much heavier burden. I therefore now appoint
                            thee to take the burden, care, and government of " ten cities." Thus we see that the good
                            lord of this good and faithful servant did not now release him, saying, You have done very
                            well; go now and loll, and take your ease ! Instead of this, you see, he appointed him a
                            tenfold burden, and a more arduous duty; and this, for the very good reason, that his
                            increased experience and skill well qualified him for the performance of this extra service.
                            The same is true of the other servants who had faithfully improved their gifts, however
                            small. Each received additional burdens, in proportion to what had been given and improved.
                            What is remarkable, and most worthy of imitation in all those who are called good and
                            faithful servants, we do not hear of their ever complaining or expressing any
                            disappointment. Each took his increased burden and went on cheerfully doing the will of his
                            lord. They did not say, " Why, I think I have served long enough ; and I certainly expected
                            that you, my lord, would release me now, and let me take my ease." No such talk as that
                            proceeded from the mouths of those devoted servants, who had no motive nor any higher source
                            of joy than to be employed in promoting the work and kingdom of their lord. It was their
                            meat and drink to do his will. And they did not wish to be released from sitting at their
                            lord's table, nor did they desire to cease from doing his work. This looking for releasement
                            and ease would have approached too near to the character of that lazy servant who buried his
                            talent. All the difference there seems to be in the two characters, is merely of time. The
                            slothful servant buried his talent and commenced his life of idleness and ease immedi-
                            ately, while the other went to work only for a time, and then quitted labor and his lord's
                            interest, and commenced the same life of ease and indolence that the other did in the start.
                            Neither of them devoted himself to his lord and his work, soul and body, for time and
                            eternity, like the good and faithful servants. In the Church of Jesus Christ, there is, sub-
                            stantially, but the two characters: The good and faithful servant, who, without reserve,
                            devotes himself wholly and forever to his Lord's service, and goes on improving his talents
                            for usefulness, and increasing his burden and service as his talents increase ; and the
                            slothful servant, who either refuses to work, or, if he begins, reserves the right to quit
                            when he pleases ; and, consequently, soon demands to be released, and joins the other in a
                            life of ease and idleness. Or, if he works at all, must do his own will, and pick and choose
                            for himself what he will condescend to do! He who takes this latter course is not serving
                            his Lord and doing his will, but serving himself and doing his own will. There may be some
                            who will readily agree with all that has been said, and with great liberality give it all
                            away to the official members of the body — the Ministry, Elders, Trustees and Deacons. They
                            must all stand up to the work, and never flinch, or lay down their gifts! But the ox driver,
                            the horse teamster, the cow tender, the carpenter, shoemaker, farmer, or gardener, or
                            broom-maker, they may all, or any of them, throw up their work just when they please, and
                            say: If the Elders and Deacons don't release me, I'll do something else ! Who made this line
                            of distinction between those called officials and others, that the first should be bound
                            always to do their Lord's will, and the latter to do as they please 1 Is the Gospel
                            requirement partial ? We do not believe that. Every one of us, from the least to the
                            greatest, is equally bound to improve the gifts committed to us, whether few or many, great
                            or small. If you faithfully improve, and steadfastly continue to go on, you will gain and
                            deserve the character of " good and faithful servants." If you refuse to do this, and set up
                            your own wills and lay out for yourselves, you will inevitably be classed with the slothful
                            servant, and share the awful fate apportioned to him.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church property and taxation" TEIform="index"/>CHURCH PROPERTY AND TAXATION</head><p TEIform="p">When a principle is set in motion, we may not find it stopping when we order a halt, says one
                            of our exchanges. It goes on, embodying itself in new forms, and suggesting fresh
                            applications. We have protested against the union of Church and State. We have insisted that
                            the State should not support sectarian schools. Now the question comes up, Should the State
                            show special favors to religious corporations 1 And a negative answer seems to imply that
                            Church property, in the form of meeting-houses, parsonages, etc., ought to be taxed like any
                            other real estate, since declining to lay a tax of $100 on a meeting-house is substantially
                            the same thing as giving the society that holds it the sum of $100 a year to aid it in its
                            general and special religious work. — Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obscene literature" TEIform="index"/>OBSCENE LITERATURE</head><p TEIform="p">Is it not a novel idea to commence the suppression of obscene literature, by incarcera- ting
                            in the Tombs those persons who, of all others, except the Shakers, are the most fear- less
                            and unselfish exposers and denouncers of the "social evils," from which the obscene
                            literature proceeds ? This is akin to the St. Louis legislation where men enact the most
                            abominable obscenity, enforced by the most outrageous violation of individual rights, that
                            it is in the power of men to inflict upon women, who, in all respects, except physical
                            might, are their equals. In both cases the " social evil " is increased, and its abettors,
                            Avho occupy high places, shield themselves by persecuting their prosecutors. The Mormons Are
                            one step in advance of popular Christia.nity, in solving the sexual problem. They have gone
                            back to Judaism, out of which Christianity arose. Marriage, combined with the " social evil"
                            practices of the popular Christians, is further from Christianity — Shakerism — than is the
                            polygamy of the Mormons, combined with the absence of the " social evil " habits of
                            Washington, New York, or Boston. Prostitution of adults, and masturbation of juveniles,
                            being unknown in Utah, except so far as they are introduced by the influx of monogamic
                            Christians. Wherein is the moral superiority of the St. Louis Christians, who legalize
                            prostitution and raise revenue from it, over the Mormons, who legalize polygamy and suppress
                            all other forms of the "social evil?" The servant of G-od should be of " quick understanding
                            in the fear of the Lord; and he shall not judge after the sight of his eyes, neither reprove
                            after the hearing of his ears; but with righteousness shall he judge the poor, and reprove
                            with equity for the meek of the earth: and he shall smite the earth with the rod of his
                            mouth, and with the breath of his lips shall he slay the wicked." Is. xi. 3 &amp; 4.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Effects of bad habits" TEIform="index"/>EFFECTS OF BAD HABITS</head><p TEIform="p">We have the fullest assurances from our spirit friends that the effects of bad habits in
                            life, and of some diseases, linger on the spirit after the body dies in which they were
                            engendered. The burning hankering after liquor, that is the effect of drunkenness, we are
                            assured, does not stop suddenly at death, but, for a time, torments the spirit as it did
                            while in the body ; and we are also assured that it is the same with a love of tobacco, and
                            that it is as easy to break off and conquer these habits here as in the spirit-world.
                            Whenever any effect is wrought into the mind, as a consequence of indulgence in any inj
                            urious, pernicious, or wicked habit in life, that effect has to be outgrown, even after the
                            cause that first produced it has ceased, as in the case of drinking or chewing tobacco.
                            Profane swearing, also, which unfits a person for refined society, does not always stop at
                            death, and the spirit is thereby left out of that refined society which rises and lives
                            above its use. If all people could fully realize the necessity of fitting here for the
                            society they would choose in the next life, we feel sure more would reform and refine
                            themselves, and more would cure themselves of the injurious effects on the mind, arising
                            from the teachings of a false theology, that has taught us that it is not that which enters
                            in at the mouth that defileth the man, and that death would wholly and totally change us
                            from our earthly wants and habits, etc.</p></div2><pb n="52" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Farmecopœia" TEIform="index"/>FARMECOPŒIA</head><p TEIform="p">Latest in the series of the Detroit Tribune's very characteristic " Farm Ballads" is this
                            autograph of the medical country practitioner upon the assumed professional wisdom of some
                            folks: THE DOCTOR LOQTJITOR. I. Good folks ever will have their way — Good folks ever for it
                            must pay. But we, who are here and everywhere, The burden of their faults must bear. We must
                            shoulder others' shame — Fight their follies, and take their blame; Purge the body, and
                            humor the mind ; Doctor the eyes when the soul is blind; Build the column of health erect On
                            the quicksands of neglect; Always shouldering others' shame — Bearing their faults, and
                            taking the blame ! II. Deacon Rogers, he came to me ; " Wife is a-goin to die," said he; "
                            Doctors great and doctors small, Havn't improved her any at all. " Physic and blisters,
                            powders and pills, And nothing sure but the doctors' bills ! " Twenty old women, with
                            remedies new, Bother my wife the whole day through ; " Sweet as honey, or bitter as gall —
                            Poor old woman, she takes 'em all; " Sour or sweet, whatever they choose, Poor old woman,
                            she daren't refuse. " So she pleases whoe'er may call, An' death is suited the best of all.
                            " Physic and blister, powder an' pill — Bound to conquer, an' sure to kill!" in. Mrs. Rogers
                            lay in her bed, Bandaged and blister'd from foot to head. Blister'd and bandaged from head
                            to toe, Mrs. Rogers was very low. Bottle and saucer, spoon and cup, On the table stood
                            bravely up ; Physics of high and low degree ; Calomel, catnip, boneset tea; Everything a
                            body could bear, Excepting light, and water, and air. IV. I open'd the blinds; the day was
                            bright, And God gave Mrs. Rogers some light. I opened the window; the day was fair, And God
                            gave Mrs. Rogers some air. Bottles and blisters, powders and pills, Catnip, boneset, syrups,
                            and squills; Drugs and medicines, high and low, I threw them as far as I could throw. " What
                            are you doing ?" my patient cried; " Frightening Death," I coolly replied. " You are crazy,"
                            a visitor said; I flung a bottle at her head. V. Deacon Rogers, he came to me ; " Wife is
                            a-comin' around," said he. " I re'lly think she will worry through ; She scolds me just as
                            she used to do. " All the people have poohed an' slurr'd — All the neighbors have had their
                            word ; " 'Twas better to perish some of them say, Than to be cured in such an irregular
                            way." VI. " Your wife," said I, " had God's good care, And his remedies— light, and water,
                            and air. "All of the doctors, beyond a doubt, Could not have cured Mrs. Rogers without."
                            VII. The deacon smiled and bowed his head ; " Then your bill is nothing," he said. " God's
                            be the glory, as you say 1 God bless you, Doctor! good day! good day!" VIII. If ever I
                            doctor that woman again, I'll give her medicines made by men.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carleton, W. M." TEIform="persName"/>W. M. Carleton</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman suffrage a success" TEIform="index"/>WOMAN SUFFRAGE A SUCCESS</head><p TEIform="p">WyomingTerritory was almost the pioneer in making the experiment of woman suffrage, and now
                            comes testimony of the most important character, as to how the thing works in that Rocky
                            mountain region, from an Associate Justice of the United States Supreme Court of that
                            Territory, Hon. J. W. Kingman. He records his observation (says the Boston Journal), for the
                            benefit, it is true, of the Pennsylvania Woman Suffrage Association, but his judicial
                            character ought to save him from the suspicion of coloring his account out of compliment to
                            his correspondents. " It has been three years (he says) since the political rights of the
                            women of Wyoming have been made equal with those of the men; and, although some do not yet
                            approve of it as a principle, none will deny that it has exerted a purifying and beneficial
                            effect in practice. For instance, everybody in the Territory used to carry arms, and
                            altercations were frequent, while juries of men never convicted either party for shooting at
                            each other, even in a crowded room, if no one was killed; or for killing any one, if the
                            victim was armed. But (says Judge Kingman) with two or three women on the jury, they have
                            never failed to follow the instructions of the Court. So, too, with regard to the
                            enforcement of the laws against drunkenness, gambling, houses of illfame, and the like,
                            neither grand nor petit juries could be relied on," but a few women on either panel changed
                            the face of things at once." The Judge affirms that not a single verdict, civil or criminal,
                            has been set aside, where women have composed a part of the jury ; and that they make more
                            attentive and impartial jurors than men, on the average. Another thing, which may be of less
                            importance, but is still worthy of being taken into account, is the influence women have had
                            on deportment in the court room. " The spectators come there better dressed, chew less
                            tobacco, and spit less, sit more quietly in their seats, walk more carefully over the floor,
                            talk and whisper less; and in all respects the court room assumes a more dignified and
                            business-like air." The same improvement is witnessed at the polls, the women voters being
                            uniformly treated with respect, and the old scenes of noise and disorder having disappeared.
                            Many women refuse to vote as their husbands do, but, says the innocent Judge : " I have not
                            heard of any domestic discord or trouble growing out of such a course." — Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to break off bad habits" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO BREAK OFF BAD HABITS</head><p TEIform="p">Understand the reasons why the habit is injurious. Study the subject till there is no
                            lingering doubt in your mind. Avoid the places, the persons, and the thoughts that lead to
                            the temptation. Frequent the places, associate with the persons, indulge the thoughts that
                            lead away from the temptation. Keep busy ; idleness is the strength of bad habits. Do not
                            give up the struggle when you have broken your resolution once, twice, a thousand times.
                            That only shows how much need there is for you to strive. When you have broken your
                            resolution, just think the matter over, and endeavor to understand why it is you failed, so
                            that you may be on your guard against a recurrence of the same circumstances. Do not think
                            it an easy thing that you have undertaken. It is folly to expect to break off a habit in a
                            day which has been gathering strength in you for years. — Ex. Dr. Chalmers beautifully said:
                            " The little that I have seen in the world, and known of the history of mankind, teaches me
                            to look upon their errors in sorrow, not in anger.— When I take the history of one poor
                            heart that has sinned and suffered, and represent to myself the struggles and temptations it
                            has passed through — the brief pulsation of joy; the tears of regret; the feebleness of
                            purpose; the scorn of the world that has little charity; the desolation of the soul's
                            sanctuary, and threatening voice within; health gone; happiness gone — I would fain leave
                            the erring soul of my fellow man with him from whose hands it came." — Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why do we take medicine?" TEIform="index"/>WHY DO WE TAKE MEDICINE?</head><p TEIform="p">Because the doctors prescribe it. But why do they prescribe it ? It is none of our business
                            to ask. And yet it is very refreshing to hear the doctors themselves asking each other, as
                            Dr. Robert Bartholomew does in his recent introductory address before the Medical College of
                            Ohio : " Cui bono ? What is it all worth ? What is the value of the work in which we are
                            engaged as students and practitioners ? Is this business of ours a mere sham ?" It is really
                            hopeful for us who are alive and well, but expect some time to be sick, to see a doctor come
                            out of that owl-like inscrutability of wisdom which characterizes the average physician, and
                            talk right out in meeting with common sense, frankness, and lucidity of statement. After
                            showing how " fallacious medical ' experience' is, when nothing more than 'the expression of
                            preconceived opinions, or the prejudices engendered of fixed professional usages and current
                            belief/ Dr. B. declares that ' ignorance renders the most persevering observation nugatory.
                            If a man does not know what it is he sees, of little value to him is experience. The
                            sympathetic power of Sir Kenelin Digby, the elixir of Paracelsus, the thirtieth potency of
                            Hahnemann, have been supported by the experience of vast numbers. The former unanimity in
                            favor of the efficiency of bloodletting in fever, of calomel in certain inflammations, is
                            only equaled by the present disbelief in the reality of those experiences." "How then," Dr.
                            Bartholomew inquires, " shall we ascertain the worth of our remedies 1" His answer is, that
                            the doctors must apply the scientific tests, which in other departments of knowledge, yield
                            exact results. He ingenuously confesses that " if our so-called therapeutical facts do not
                            respond to scientific questions ; if we have no other arguments in support of them than
                            faith, and an experience, as vague as it is uncertain and delusive, then may our souls be
                            possessed with the fear that drug-giving is a hollow mockery." That is just the
                            uncomfortable fear which does sometimes possess the souls of us laymen who have to send for
                            the doctor.—Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Church and state" TEIform="index"/>CHURCH AND STATE</head><p TEIform="p">I vert largely attribute the decline of religious interest in some directions to the interest
                            which has been taken in the questions which naturally arise out of the adulterous connection
                            at present existing between religion and the state in this land. We should never be
                            satisfied until we stand upon an equal footing, all of us in matters of religion. An
                            Established Church is an established tyranny. We wear upon our wrists each one of us, as
                            dissenters, fetters that gall us worse than if they were made of steel. We have to support a
                            church whose business it is to oppose the truth we try to preach ; we have to maintain an
                            institution which tries to pull down that which we would be willing to die to maintain.
                            Popery is this day paid for in this land; that which our fathers died and rotted in prison
                            to put down, we have to contribute to support, and we cannot help feeling indignant — we
                            should be less than men, certainly less than the sons of the Puritans who made the Cavaliers
                            feel the strength of their right arms, if we do not feel in our souls that we cannot long
                            submit to the tyranny which galls us every day. Down with it! Down with it 1 We will be
                            free, as God lives. This question must be answered and settled once for all, and the sooner
                            it is done with, the better; and we mean that it shall be done with, by God's help, ere
                            long.</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="Spurgeon" TEIform="persName"/>Mr. Spurgeon on the Disestablishment of the English
                        Church</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What we want" TEIform="index"/>What We Want.</head><p TEIform="p">We want an atmosphere of pure, solid truth. We want preachers who will tell what they think
                            without reserve. We want physicians who will disclose the laws of health in the simplest
                            words. We want lawyers, who will execute law with a leaning all the time to justice and
                            morality. We want politicians who love our republican institutions, and sincerely desire to
                            preserve and improve them ; who will not falsify, or allow others to do so in their behalf,
                            without instant correction. If we can have these things, our liberties are assured forever.
                            If we cannot, they are endangered every day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName TEIform="persName">Ex.</persName>Ex.</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Head, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eliza Head
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Head, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eliza Head</persName>, aged 29 years; Union Village, O.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Palmer, Charity" TEIform="index"/>Charity Palmer
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Palmer, Charity" TEIform="persName">Charity Palmer</persName>, aged 84 years and 5 months;
                                New Gloucester, Me.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pendleton, David" TEIform="index"/>David Pendleton
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Erratum. — <persName reg="Pendleton, David" TEIform="persName">David Pendleton</persName> was 87, not
                            37.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dean, John" TEIform="index"/>John Dean
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Dean, John" TEIform="persName">John Dean</persName>, aged 76 years; May 28th; Mt.
                            Lebanon.</p></div3></div2><pb n="53" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: conscience" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: CONSCIENCE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">Is there any thing that an intelligent human being should desire more than a healthy con-
                            science? The Creator of the Universe, of mind and matter, the great Designer of all things
                            in the visible and invisible worlds, subjected all things to law and order, and placed
                            conscience in the human soul as a guide and dictator of the actions of life. However lengthy
                            the period of time may have been in bringing the component parts together, bo as to form a
                            perfect whole in the macrocosm or microcosm, it is evident that a superior Power and
                            Intelligence comprehended the end from the beginning, and had one object and purpose in
                            view. Some of the ancient Seers, when under the beautiful inspiration of the Spirit, said, "
                            Just weights and measures are the Lord's. He measured the waters, weighed the mountains in
                            scales, balanced the hills, and meted out the heavens;" from which, we may understand that
                            there was an original design to bring all parts together into a compact body, that they
                            might be fitly joined together, every joint supplying its proper place; thus forming one
                            glorious temple in which God should dwell as the central Light — the Soul and Animus of all
                            things. We read of denied, and evil, and weak consciences; and also of pure and good con-
                            sciences. If the conscience be pure and good, then reason will take its proper place, and
                            act in consonance: Reason will suggest and conscience decide. If conscience be right, the
                            reasoning powers in man and in woman will be turned Godward. In this they have the
                            pre-eminence over the lower orders of the animal creation, which are ruled by instinct.
                            Conscience and reason are God's crown and seal to humanity, and the express manifestation of
                            his love. How can we ever be guilty of abusing such noble gifts, and of turning such
                            blessings into curses? That there has been a great departure from the original design; that
                            conscience has been violated, reason dethroned, and statutes broken, none will undertake to
                            deny. Yet there is hope for humanity! The spirit of prophecy is again poured out upon the
                            present generation to an extent never before known. The condensed history of the ancient
                            Prophets that has been handed down to us, extended through long periods of time. It would
                            appear that there were seasons when the prophetic spirit was rife among the ancients, and
                            that it was not exclusively confined to those who were the most holy in life and character.
                            Instance: At the same time that the seventy elders, whom Moses gathered about the
                            tabernacle, prophesied, Saul's messengers caught the spirit and prophesied also; and even
                            Saul, himself, was found among the prophets. At a later period of time the prophetic spirit
                            was confined to a few mediums. When the persecuting power, justly called " the reign of the
                            beast," bore rule, then sorrowing witnesses prophesied in sackcloth and mourning. But the
                            ages have rolled on, and the spiritual forces have been at work preparing the way for the
                            present time, in which the spiritual progressive elements, could give birth to a New Era;
                            and it is a most marked epoch in the world's history. And, as the rain-clouds when formed in
                            the natural heavens, descend upon the just and the unjust; so it is in the spiritual
                            elements ; the gifts of God are given without repentance, to lead souls thereunto that all
                            may be left without excuse. Some receive the gifts of the Spirit and consume them upon the
                            animal, sensual appetites, and thereby " turn the grace of God into lasciviousness ;" and
                            light in them becomes darkness, which is dense. Such gather around them false, deceiving
                            spirits, who prophesy falsely, and fill the minds of many with doubt and confusion. Water,
                            to be sweet to the taste, must be conveyed to us in clean vessels. However pure it may be
                            when it issues from the fountain, unless the channel through which it flows to us is pure,
                            it is neither healthful nor pleasant. So it is with the gifts of the Spirit. If mediums of
                            communication from the inhabitants of the Spirit-spheres to mortals are truthful, just, and
                            pure in their lives, then messages borne by them will be reliable, and will give life and
                            health to the receiver, and will be like pure water through a clean vessel to the parched
                            lips of the thirsty soul. Messengers sent from the higher spheres will always shed a Divine
                            influence that Avill elevate and guide the feet of the Heaven-bound traveler into the
                            highway cast up for the ransomed of the Lord to walk in, and will aid them in keeping a good
                            " conscience, void of offense toward God and all men."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Undefiled religion" TEIform="index"/>UNDEFILED RELIGION</head><p TEIform="p">To live righteously, love mercy, to exercise charity one toward another, to withdraw our
                            affections from all inferior objects, and to love the Lord our God — "our Heavenly Father
                            and Mother "— with all our mind, might, and strength, and our neighbor as ourselves, is
                            practical Religion. And when under the influence of this pure spirit, we shall, under all
                            circumstances, do by others as we would have them do by us. Those who form the true
                            Christian character, must rise above the work of reproduction, and become "holy in both body
                            and mind," keeping their physical bodies pure — "fit temples for the Holy Spirit to dwell
                            in; and they will meditate on those things which elevate the mind above sensuality. Those
                            who thus turn their thoughts and feelings from, earthly to heavenly things, will go out, in
                            spirit, seeking draughts of inspiration from fee Fountain of goodness, to water and keep
                            alive the germ of immortality which is placed in every human soul. The living spirit in man
                            and in woman yearns for immortal food to sustain it; it " cannot live by bread alone," nor
                            be content to feed on material things; but it must have the "living bread which cometh down
                            from heaven" to subsist upon; and it needs the breath of Divine inspiration to fan the
                            celestial fires of truth, that they may ever keep burning in the soul. There are different
                            degrees of goodness and truth on the natural plane of life ; and they who live the nearest
                            to the Moral Law, which was given to regulate man and woman in the work of reproduction,
                            approach the nearest to the spiritual and Divine Order. But those who possess " pure and
                            undefiled religion" will keep themselves unspotted from the world. The world here alluded
                            to, is the " lusts of the flesh and of the mind," and are the founda- tional principles of
                            the worldly life which all human beings inherit from their earthly pro- genitors ; but they
                            never came from our Heavenly Father and Mother. There is a plain line of demarcation drawn
                            by the Apostle Paul, in his epistle to the G-alatians, between the worldly and the Christian
                            life. The manifest works of the flesh are " adultery, fornication, idolatry, hatred,
                            envyings, murders," etc., etc., with a long train of evils too numerous to mention in our
                            space. While the fruits of the Spirit produced by those who live clean, chaste lives, are "
                            love, joy, peace, long-suffering," etc., with other accompanying virtues. They who " live in
                            the flesh cannot please God," because they are under the influence of " the carnal mind,
                            which is enmity against God." Jesus said to his disciples, " In the world ye shall have
                            tribulation; but be of good cheer, I have overcome the world. How did he overcome the world
                            ? Was it not by a total abnegation of the generative, lustful nature within ? When tempted
                            by the adversary, he bowed not at the shrine of sensual indulgence; but persistently said to
                            his enemy, " Get thee hence, Satan." His religion was " pure and undefiled; " and all his
                            true followers have done, and are doing as he did; i. e., "crucifying the flesh with all its
                            affections and lusts'' — keeping their bodies and souls pure ; and are making room in their
                            hearts for the Holy Spirit, the Heavenly Dove to dwell in. So let none become weary in
                            well-doing, nor grow faint or feeble while running the Gospel race; for if in "patience we
                            possess our souls," all will be well. " Whatsoever we sow we shall " certainly reap." If we
                            are careful to "sow to the Spirit," and reject all that is false and vain, and hold fast
                            "pure and undefiled religion," we shall " reap life everlasting."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reed, Polly" TEIform="persName"/>Eldress Polly Reed, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Woman" TEIform="index"/>WOMAN</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">People have glanced carelessly at the question of woman suffrage, and turned away
                                    with the idea that it would give undue influence to women of impure lives; but the
                                    reverse is the case. Women of impure lives govern us now, through their impure
                                    influence of legislatures, judiciaries, and juries, exclusively masculine; and
                                    nothing but women in authority can remand them to their proper sphere, if they have
                                    any. The influence they could exert through the ballot by force of numbers would be
                                    unappreciable, being more than neutralized by the votes of decent women, who would
                                    make a point of consigning to political graves all politicians known to be
                                    influenced by them, and only juries composed wholly or in part of women ever will do
                                    them justice. Were the political influence now wielded by courtesans of this country
                                    divided into as many equal parts as there are women in the United States, it would
                                    give every one a vote, and place the regulation of the dram-shop and social evil
                                    questions under the control of the decent portion of the community. It is only when
                                    men consult with women whom they respect, that we can hope they will be influenced
                                    by those they do not.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Independent" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Swisshelm" TEIform="persName"/>Miss Swisshelm in the Independent</byline></div2><pb n="54" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reading" TEIform="index"/>READING</head><p TEIform="p">Knowledge is essential to the growth and development of the human intellect, its proper
                            aliment and nutrition; yet it is as possible to gorge the mind as the stomach ; the result
                            is as deleterious. " Man cannot live by bread alone " (physically) ; nor can he live by
                            books alone (mentally) ; variety of food is required, to stimulate the normal action of all
                            his faculties. He who always feeds on the thoughts of others, is sadly neglecting the use of
                            his own, thus stifling the sources of mental vigor and unfoldment. Book-learning is merely a
                            matter of memory, only calling into requisition one of the many God-given powers possessed
                            by all intelligent beings. Observation and reflection are stepping stones to independence
                            and strength of character ; it is the prerogative of every individual to use them, and thus
                            preserve their own identity and originality. Human nature is an ever open volume, for study,
                            analysis, and discernment, requiring the exercise of the perceptive faculties. First " know
                            thyself," then is the grand mystery unsealed, and we can read, understand, and judge
                            correctly of the motives and actions of others. Every day brings us rare and gifted
                            opportunities for the acquisition of such knowledge as books can never give, and which those
                            who seclude themselves in a library never acquire. Life is fraught with useful lessons that
                            we need to learn preparatory to entering a future state of existence. If we have no definite
                            object or aim in reading, what shall it profit 1 If merely for amuse- ment, to pass away the
                            time, or for sensual pleasure, then it would be infinitely better to put our hands to work,
                            and engage our slumbering faculties in some noble and useful pur- suit, or calling; thus
                            fitting ourselves for a sphere of activity, in which we can be a blessing to others, and not
                            continue as mere drones in the hive of creative existences. We live in an age of reading;
                            books are multiplied as the sands on the sea shore. All classes have access to the means of
                            knowledge, that was only granted the privileged few, less than a century ago. Public
                            libraries, free schools, and daily prints, proffer the boon of education to the lowest and
                            most ignorant; but, with the good, there comes a greater evil. A light, trashy literature,
                            in the form of cheap novels and low love stories, floats upon the surface of society, like
                            scum on a stagnant pool, which is exceedingly pernicious, and as infectious as a deadly
                            miasma ; especially to the minds and morals of the young and inexperienced ; increasing the
                            " social evil" to a great extent, withdrawing their interest from high mental culture,
                            ennobling discipline, and objects of intrinsic moral and spiritual worth. Very few young
                            persons, in this day, will confine their attention to solid reading ; it is irk- some, dull,
                            and uninteresting; they want something sensational, and exciting, the very tendency of
                            which, is to arouse passions that ought to be subdued, to set on fire lusts of their lower
                            nature, the products of which, are haunts of vice, misery, a prostitution of virtue, and an
                            increase of crime, not only in low, but in high places. Some time since I was particularly
                            impressed with this fact. We were traveling by rail a short journey eastward. Two young
                            women entered the car and were seated opposite, in front view; the youngest (of rather
                            prepossessing appearance) drew from her valise a large pamphlet, and commenced reading with
                            apparent absorption of mind. The book had the appearance of a novel; a glance revealed it. "
                            Foul Play" was the startling title, clearly intimating its contents and character. I watched
                            her as her interest deepened; and, on that would-be lovely face, traced the imagery of
                            pictures base, that were stamping an indelible impress on her very soul. I turned away with
                            saddened thought and feeling, having read a lesson of life blighted while yet in blossom. A
                            few moments after, a news-boy threw into my lap an illustrated paper; a cursory view
                            disclosed the fact that it contained little else than nonsense ; it was cast aside in
                            disgust, with the sober conclusion, that good thoughts were better company than unprofitable
                            reading. I love good books, they are companions in solitude, and shed a light in dark places
                            ; but, would forever forego the pleasure of reading, rather than cover the chamber walls of
                            my soul with reflective pictures, that will pain the spirit in future, when life's drama
                            shall be reviewed; or poison the fountains of existence with the foul infection of mental
                            and moral disease. O that youthful minds would consider well the injunction of the wise man:
                            "Buy the truth (not fiction), and sell it not, also wisdom, instruction, and understanding;"
                            and desire, above all things, knowledge that will result in future happiness, rather than
                            momentary pleasure ; discerning between right and wrong, good and evil, through the exercise
                            of the superior endowments of reason and conscience.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>Martha J. Anderson, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Chaff" TEIform="index"/>CHAFF</head><p TEIform="p">Beloved Editress : I know it is true that, " without the chaff there can be no wheat;" and I
                            have been ruminating in my mind, whether I was willing to be used as such. It is, you know,
                            a fundamental principle in Shakerism to pay all just dues. I am indebted to many dear
                            friends who have contributed so freely to the maintenance of our little Monthly which is
                            sent out from the Gospel Ark over the dark and turbid waters, bearing the olive-branch of
                            hope and peace to struggling sin-bound souls. I would gladly cancel this debt were I able,
                            but the question is, What have I to give ? Have I nothing but chaff'to give in exchange for
                            good wheat ? I have concluded to give the best I have to-day, and will try to gain something
                            better for to-morrow. I feel a great interest in the prosperity of this truth-bearing
                            messenger ; and those who are willing to forsake the natural, and rise above the animal
                            plane of life, into the superior heavenly state, will welcome it as a harbinger of blessing
                            to their souls. I remember that, when I was a child, I read and heard much about the
                            judgment day, when a separation would be made between the righteous and the wicked ; that
                            the righteous, in that day, would be caught up to meet the Lord in the air, and that the
                            wicked would be left to the flames which would continue to burn without consuming them. The
                            thought to me was terrible! I knew that I was a sinner, and was glued as it were to the
                            earth by unhallowed desires, and strong selfish affections ; and I could not see how I could
                            find power to break those ties, or get angel wings to rise above them. In this condition I
                            remained many years. But at length I was led, by the providence of God, to this people; this
                            Zion of God upon earth. Here I found a home for both body and soul; and by confessing and
                            forsaking sin, the judgment thereof was taken away; and, by receiving the truth in the love
                            of it, I found that it contained enough of the Refiner's fire to consume the dross that
                            remained; and the belief in, and dread of, a literal fire, was banished from my mind ; and I
                            also found that, by faith and good works, I might rise with the saints into the divine life;
                            which, before, I had thought an impossibility. And, should there be any in the dreary wTilds
                            of nature, who are encircled by the dark mists of error and false teaching, who are
                            suffering as I have suffered, and who desire to escape therefrom, I would kindly invite them
                            to our Zion home, where they wrill find the Comforter, the Spirit of Truth, to lead and
                            guide them ; and where they can commence the immortal life, and enjoy the liberty of the
                            sons and daughters of God, and join in the song of redemption, sung by those who are washing
                            their robes and making them white by living as Jesus lived, and bearing the same cross that
                            he bore.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Sarah" TEIform="persName"/>Sarah Hollister, Canaan, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Salt 'losing its savor'..." TEIform="index"/>Salt 'losing its savor'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Salt " losing its savor," and being " trodden under foot of men," arose from the fact that
                            the salt that was used by the ancients did lose its savor, and was then used for walks.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>"SHAKER AID SHAKERESS."</head><p TEIform="p">Go forth, thou heavenly messenger, into all the earth, bearing glad tidings of truth and life
                            to all people. Say to those who make idols of earthly riches, and who suffer worldly
                            treasures to gain control over the mind, and blind the sight to things of supreme worth,
                            thus paralyzing the forces of the whole being, " It is impossible to serve God and mammon."
                            Those who turn all their energies to accumulate wealth for selfish indulgence and aggran-
                            dizement, and who neglect to lay up treasures for the immortal part, which must exist in the
                            life beyond this, will be dwarfed in spirit. Some think that a religious life, by reason of
                            the cross imposed, is hard, and that a worldly life is easy; but the yoke of Christ, to
                            those who are reconciled to wear it, is far easier than the yoke of sin. Those who profess
                            the Christian life and character, should give a practical illustration of their profession
                            in all their acts and walks of life, and beware of the deceitfulness of sin, whether in
                            riches, or in the lusts of the flesh or mind, which, if entered into, will choke the word of
                            life in the soul. Jesus said to those who were bound by earthly riches, " Sell that thou
                            hast, and give alms, and lay up treasures in heaven." Those who do this will find that they
                            have made a sure and safe investment. But very few are willing to trust the Bank of Heaven!
                            God has intrusted the perishable things of time to mankind to use and not abuse, and as a
                            means to prove his integrity; not as a power to oppress and grind the poor, and to exalt and
                            glorify self, by defrauding his neighbor. The earth and all that is therein belong to God;
                            the gold, and silver, and precious stones, all belong to Him; and the cattle upon a thou-
                            sand hills are his own. Man holds them in trust; they are blessings lent, and he will be
                            held to a strict accountability for the use of them. Those who possess the means to relieve
                            the destitute and suffering, and thus use them, will be a blessing to humanity, and will
                            draw down blessings upon themselves, till "their souls are as a watered garden whose beauty
                            fadeth not." Christ's sermon on the Mount plainly shows the line of the blessing. Those who
                            are " poor in spirit (humbly relying on God, seeking aid and strength from Him), theirs is
                            the kingdom of heaven." " The mourner (the penitent soul who sorrows for sin) will be
                            comforted." " The meek (those who are loving and forgiving) and the pure in heart" are all
                            promised a special blessing. The more we perfect the Christian character, which can only be
                            attained by earnest effort, the better able we shall be to intelligently understand the real
                            worth of the above-named blessings. Little by little we gain self-control; step by step we
                            march onward to the heavenly goal, where the victor dwells. A full surrender of the soul to
                            God is the Christian's duty; it does not profit to retain part for self. " They who sow
                            sparingly shall also reap sparingly;" our reward will be according to our works. Self-
                            denial and the cross is the pathway that leads to eternal life ; because of this, few will
                            seek it; for self will always strive for the mastery, and always stands in opposition to the
                            searching power of truth, that will bring the affections and the very thoughts into
                            obedience to the law of Christ, who said " Why call ye me Lord, Lord, and do not the things
                            that I say ? " But, 0 how blessed, how noble and glorious, are those who come forth to the
                            judgmentwork in this life, showing their deeds and washing in Jordan's river till they
                            become clean and pure, that the Divine image may be formed in them. Long live the " Shaker
                            and 87iakeress ! " and may it afford a healing balm, and be a guiding star to suffering
                            humanity.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Randall, Joanna" TEIform="persName"/>Joanna Randall, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If we would not blush when reading the record of our lives..." TEIform="index"/>If we would not blush when reading the record of our lives...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">If we would not blush when reading the record of our lives, let them be in harmony with
                            divinity ; have our deeds wrought in purity. Then they will be daguerreotyped in beautiful
                            colors that, beneath the golden rays of the sun, will not fade, but blend with those of the
                            spheres above, and upon our hearts will be reflected their glorious shades, causing us to
                            glow with angelic beauty, and show forth the image of the heavenly.</p><byline TEIform="byline">— <persName reg="B., Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte B.</byline></div2><pb n="55" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">When Jesus was about to part with his disciples, he gave them a " new commandment," that they
                            should love one another as lie had loved them. He said, " By this shall all men know that ye
                            are my disciples, if ye have love one to another." The love which Jesus felt for his
                            disciples was pure and unselfish ; it was not emotional and circumstantial; but he loved
                            from principle. At times, his language to them was gentle and persuasive. He also manifested
                            his love toward them by stern rebukes, for lack of faith ; and James and John for the spirit
                            of retaliation they possessed, when they thought to call down fire from heaven " to consume"
                            the Samaritans who would not receive him. To Peter, when he reasoned as a natural man
                            against the revelation made to Jesus, he said, " Get thee behind me, Satan; thou art an
                            offense unto me ; thou savorest not the things that be of God, but those that be of men."
                            Probably all persons feel it difficult (more or less) to extend love and sympathy where it
                            would not be appreciated. But, by reflecting on the goodness of our Eternal Parents, we
                            shall clearly see our duty — not, indeed, to do other persons' work in their stead ; but to
                            willingly become helpers, or co-workers with Divine Wisdom, in redeeming our fellowbeings
                            from sin and misery, by practical kindness and love. True love is eternal, enduring, and as
                            unchanging as the sun in its course. Amid joy and sorrow, clouds and sunshine, prosperity
                            and adversity, it remains unshaken, unblemished by the stains of selfishness, and unsullied
                            by the blight of envy and jealousy. Ever mindful of the best interests of others, true godly
                            love is anxious to relieve every affliction, even though surrounding circumstances may
                            render it difficult and discouraging ; and it will manifest itself in various ways, in order
                            that its great object may be accomplished. The grace of God in the heart will teach us how
                            to love; and the words we speak will give unmistakable evidence of sincerity. If we would be
                            God's " peculiar people," we must zealously show our'' faith by our works," and manifest our
                            love to our brethren and sisters by relinquishing all kinds of selfishness ; and, in the
                            true spirit of consecration, be willing to toil for the general good. By suitable reflection
                            upon this subject, we may so direct our words and actions, that they shall convey the true
                            love and interest existing in our hearts for our loving Gospel kindred and friends, as well
                            as for the erring, who most need a helping hand; and that thereby they may be inspired with
                            courage to withstand temptation, and become victors over all the powers of evil. Thus, in
                            our social and religious communings, we shall feel peace and satisfaction, and shall drink,
                            from the pure Fountain of heavenly love, the crystal waters of eternal life, which will flow
                            to our souls, baptizing us into one spirit, that we may be of one heart and mind. If we
                            really love, in full accordance with the " new commandment," as Jesus loved, that is, have
                            our love grounded in the principles of truth, purity, and goodness, then it will endure,
                            and. even death itself cannot destroy it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Haskins, Lucy A." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy Haskins, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Jesus of Nazareth..." TEIform="index"/>Jesus of Nazareth...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Jesus of Nazareth, who once dwelt in a tenement of clay, and walked on the earth among men,
                            was undoubtedly the chosen Medium to receive the Anointing Spirit — the Christ of God. And,
                            by steadfast adherence to that anointing power bestowed upon him, he traveled into the life
                            Divine. Since his. day, thousands, by the power of the same Spirit, and in obedience to his
                            precepts, and through the influence of his holy example, have also attained unto the Divine
                            life, and are now with him in the kingdom of heaven. The principles which constitute the
                            kingdom of heaven are eternal, and admit of an everlasting increase, whether commenced on
                            the earth or in the heavenly world ; and the will of God may be done on earth as really as
                            in heaven. And all who are called into this kingdom— this Zion of God on earth — should
                            wisely consider their high and holy calling, and the great responsibility which rests upon
                            them to be faithful; for they are not only called to work out their own salvation, but are
                            also called in relation to the whole human family ; and they should so live and walk that
                            they may become Saviors to other souls, and be truly " a peculiar people, zealous of good
                            works," and possess the inheritance promised to the meek. Every Christian virtue will shine
                            forth in their lives, and, by obeying the behests of conscience, they will indeed be a '
                            city set on a hill, whose light cannot be hid," raising an ensign of freedom. May the good
                            Spirit hasten the time when the banner of Freedom from Sin shall wave gloriously over
                            Columbia's soil, is the prayer of</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hooser, Hortense" TEIform="persName"/>Hortense Hooser, Pleasant Ejll, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inspiration" TEIform="index"/>INSPIRATION</head><p TEIform="p">As we trace the Scriptures from Genesis to the Revelation, we see that, from time im-
                            memorial, there has been a constant stream of inspiration poured out upon those who were so
                            organized as to receive it, and they were commissioned to impart it to others. The portals
                            of heaven have been opened to mortals, and rich stores of Divine love, and rays of heavenly
                            light, have been given to mankind, as a beacon, to guide and direct their footsteps. The
                            Prophets of old were chosen vessels, or inspired mediums, through whom God revealed his
                            will. And, at a later period, Jesus and his disciples were chosen mediums; and, as they were
                            ministered unto by spirits from a more interior sphere than were those who preceded them, so
                            they became mediums of higher truths. Inspiration did not die, or cease to flow, when they
                            passed from the earth-sphere, and the Church, of their day was disorganized; but God
                            continued to raise up witnesses, who testified to the truth, down through a long night of
                            spritual darkness. According to Sacred Writ, there was a promise given, that Christ would
                            appear again on the earth, and, as Jesus was visited by the male Christ Spirit, and anointed
                            to be " the firstborn among many brethren," so was Ann Lee visited and anointed by the
                            female Christ Spirit, to be the first-born among many sisters. And why not ? If Jesus was
                            Divinely inspired, why could not Ann Lee also be thus inspired ? Their teachings were the
                            same, and the fruits brought forth by their followers are the same. All religion has its
                            origin in Divine inspiration, and all true doctrine is derived from the same source. And
                            those who follow Jesus and Ann — live the same life, and bear the same cross which they bore
                            — " will know of the doctrine " which they taught. Jesus declared his mission to be, to
                            reveal the Father; Ann also testified that it was her mission to reveal the Mother. If the
                            fruits brought forth by them were the same, and we are to judge a tree by the fruit that it
                            bears, then, why should we doubt the cause, when the effects produced are one in kind. There
                            has been a continuation of Divine and heavenly gifts, from Mother Ann to the present time,
                            operating both internally and externally, in the Church of Christ's second appearing, to
                            enlighten the understanding and strengthen the feeble, and to confirm the weak in faith, and
                            to edify the faithful; which has enabled them progressively to move forward in a united body
                            and grow in grace and in knowledge, and gain the treasures of the Gospel of salvation for
                            themselves and other souls. We know the great Eternal One Has not seal'd up the gates of
                            heav'n, That man no more of truth may learn Than what one sacred Book has giv'n: Nor has
                            pure Wisdom's mighty fount Exhausted all her precious store ; Nor is man deem'd of
                            lessuiccount Than In the brightest days of yore. Union Village, 0. Heavenly wisdom is a
                            talent from above which must be improved to make it abiding In so doing it confers a
                            happiness that satisfies the soul.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER AND SHAKERESS</head><p TEIform="p">Blest Angel of comfort, I welcome you here ; Your mission is holy; 0 be of good cheer: The
                            tidings, so truthful, you bear on your wings A halo of gladness around the heart flings.
                            Move on through the land, diffuse light as you go, Alleviate sorrow, assuage pain and woe;
                            Give joy to the mourning who 're bow'd down with grief, Who fain would from sin and its
                            bonds find relief. A blessing on all, do most freely bestow, As 'round on your errands of
                            mercy you go. 0 bless all truth-seekers who listen to hear A voice from the throne, saying,
                            Come ye up here. 0 bless the truth-loving, and guide them along, To feed in green pastures
                            with Mount Zion's throng. 1 love you, blest Shaker, to me you are dear; I love your
                            companion who's standing so near The Shakeress Virgin ! may she at your side In her comely
                            raiment and meekness abide. For since you are dual, you've surely become A New Thing of
                            Beauty to gladden our home. And should I outlive you, I'll weep at your tomb, There, cull
                            the sweet flowers that over it bloom. Ride on in your majesty, power, and love ; Bear with
                            you the message received from above, That Saviors have now on the earth-plane appear'd, And
                            thousands of souls by their presence are cheer'd. The saints have ascended to clouds of pure
                            light, And still will mount higher to view Heaven's hight.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Jane Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Jane Emily Smith, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Inheritance" TEIform="index"/>INHERITANCE</head><p TEIform="p">The Spirit spoke by the Prophets, and again by Jesus Christ, saying, " The meek shall in-
                            herit the earth." Now we have the perfected order of the revelation of God through the
                            Shepherd and Shepherdess of Zion, and the text is read thus : " Blessed are the meek ;" for
                            they shall have an inheritance in the mansions of the pure. We have also received additional
                            blessings, which will happify and adorn the receivers of the word, who alone are doers of
                            the work. Blessed are those who have a continual controversy with the powers of sin and
                            darkness ; for theirs is eternal life. Blessed are those whose eyes are fixed on the mark of
                            the prize of their high calling; for they shall inherit the true riches. Blessed are those
                            who abide in the truth ; for they shall be the light of the world, and the glory of heaven.
                            Blessed are those who watch, that no concealed evil or wrong habit mar their uprightness ;
                            for they shall be clothed with honor and beauty. Blessed are those who seek wisdom; for
                            their lips shall communicate excellent things. Blessed are the prudent, in whose storehouses
                            are garnered treasures with which to help the needy; for out of their abundance shall the
                            multitude be fed. Blessed are those who are slain by the sword of the testimony; for they
                            shall live, and never die. Blessed are those who are baptized with the power of repentance;
                            for their iniquity shall be blotted out. Blessed are the wise virgins who are ready, and who
                            come when called; for with such the Lord is well pleased. Blessed are those whose kindred
                            and relations are the followers of the Lamb ; for they shall move in the Angelic ranks, and
                            sing the song of the redeemed.. Blessed are those who bear the rod of correction and endure
                            ; for out of the bosom of their souls proceed strength.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Bhoda Blake, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="56" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Eden of to-day" TEIform="index"/>EDEN OF TO-DAY</head><p TEIform="p">1. Shall we wait for the morrow of promise, To brins; us the kingdom of life ? Shall we pause
                            for the soul-thrilling future To prompt us to enter the strife? 2. Nay, we know that the
                            germ of salvation Hath growth in the toil of today; While the vows for futurity's action,
                            Sweep blossoms of vigor away. 3. We will reign o'er the errors prevailing, And stem the wild
                            current of wrong, Tor the life giving now spend our labor, And still be advancing along.
                            Shall we rove in the fancies that please us. And think through their guidance to win The
                            virtue of immortal knowledge, That lifteth from darkness and sin? And we fail in the noblest
                            of purpose, We're lost in the shades of the past, While thoughts of life's imperfect duties,
                            The deepest of gloom o'er us cast. Thus prepared for the increasing glory, The spiritual
                            Eden of light, We'll enter the courts of Redemption, In triumph o'er earth's darkest
                        night.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mother's day" TEIform="index"/>MOTHER'S DAY</head><p TEIform="p">0 let it be, throughout the whole fair land, A day whose shining shall illume the year; A
                            time of aspirations pure and grand, Of thoughts unselfish, and of vision clear. The costly
                            robe from human fiber spun, And gems condensed from sorrow's briny flow, Let them not
                            glisten in that equal sun, "Whose healing wings shall no distinction know. Let Pride and
                            Fashion (cowering) stand apart, "While Woman, clothed in majesty and grace, Brings forth the
                            jewels hidden in her heart, To wear them calmly with uplifted face; With face uplifted by
                            the power of hope,— That hope which conquers in its onward way, And gives the present all
                            its narrow scope, Nor from the past subtracts one single day, But turns to profit all that
                            is and was ; Draws from the future pure, prophetic light, To aid and strengthen Truth's
                            ennobling cause, And fill her vanguard with angelic might. The road of Woman is a thorny
                            steep, And she has climb'd it, borne with heavy chains, When only dews have help'd her soul
                            to weep, And midnight moanings echo'd back her pains. The vulture's eye hath never seen her
                            there; Nor hath the lion's foot her pathway trod: Her balmless anguish, and her voiceless
                            prayer, Have reached the Spirit of her Mother—Gob. 'Twas man that sought Divine Paternal
                            lead,— Ask'd light and wisdom at His throne above; But woman, through her soul's unanswer'd
                            need, Hath found her Mother, the Maternal Dove. No more half-orphan'd shall the race be made
                            : Beneath our Mother's standard, Home shall rise: May its foundations on this day be laid,
                            Before the Angels' glad approving eyes. O Day momentous! may thine altar's fire Consume the
                            burdens of the sore oppress'd: May ev'ry noble soul with pure desire Approach thy shrine, to
                            be inspired and bless'd. If some should come with spikenard and with tears, O may their off
                            'rings be in love received, And Woman, as their Savior, quell their fears, And guide them
                            upward till they are relieved. There is no human ill beyond control; No dark decree of
                            unrelenting Fate; For God hath made provision for the soul; And we will toil, and for the
                            harvest wait.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecilia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecilia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hour of prayer" TEIform="index"/>HOUR OF PRAYER</head><p TEIform="p">Listen from the higher spheres, Angels whisper " we are near ; We've come to raise your souls
                            from earth, To taste the joys of greater worth, In this the hour of prayer." Come, leave
                            awhile all toil and care, With God commune who heareth prayer ; For He who doth the ravens
                            feed, All humble souls will bless indeed, While they bow low in prayer. We hail your
                            influence, angels bright, While looking to the Source of light, It gives us courage by the
                            way, To constant watch, and hourly pray ; To keep the gift of prayer. 'Tis prayer that keeps
                            the soul from sin, And makes it light and pure within; Then let us watch and pray forever,
                            Ceasing not from strong endeavor, In this, the hour of prayer. What consolation prayer
                            imparts, How sweet the peace that fills our hearts, When we can meet in that pure love,
                            Which blends the angel hosts above: Thrice blessed hour of prayer ! O righteous Father, may
                            we be Forever clothed with purity : Only the pure thy glory see, Dwell in thy light
                            continually, And seek the hour of prayer.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Haskins, Lucy A." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy A. Hasking, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Past and present" TEIform="index"/>PAST AND PRESENT</head><p TEIform="p">In the region of Jewry, and coasts round about The river of Jordan, did come A people, to be
                            in its water baptized, Confessing their sins unto John. But a greater than he in their midst
                            then did stand ; The same has come forth unto us ; Who baptized their souls with the spirit
                            of fire, And gave them the true Holy Ghost. In that dark, cloudy day, although great were
                            his works, Were many the Lord did not know; While sunny our day, and quite equal its work,
                            Yet many are ignorant now. As then, so it is now; they the water did choose, And shunn'd the
                            baptism of fire; They, John and the Prophets did very well know, But Jesus they did not
                            desire. They then persecuted, and persecute still; E'en 'mong the disciples found place That
                            spirit which now maketh desolate homes, And many a heart layeth waste. There is no more a
                            willingness now to admit The truths of a progressive day, Than was found when Jesus did walk
                            upon earth, And taught man the new living way. Man is obstinate now, as in days that are
                            past To oppose and resist ev'ry law Subserving to bring the subversion of sin, From
                            destruction his aid to withdraw. From this age of the world, and the light which is given,
                            How much can humanity boast ? There is more cause to-day to hide in our shame, Than glory in
                            such depths of loss. God's work must go on, we have bided it long; And what has been found
                            by the way ? A curse ov a blessing awaits ev'ry soul: That's final — the great judgment day.
                            In a summary manner, with every man, The work of decision is left; Heaven's offers accepted,
                            the kingdom is his ; Rejected, of mercy bereft.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, A." TEIform="persName"/>Elder A. Perkins, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Deeds of kindness" TEIform="index"/>DEEDS OF KINDNESS</head><p TEIform="p">Will deeds of kindness perish, And fall unheeded by the way, Like flowers early gather'd That
                            droop before the close of day ? Or like the young child's picture Impress'd upon the snow's
                            white crust That warming sunbeams (kissing) Blend snow and picture both in dust ? Are words
                            of love, once utter'd [heal'd, Which like sweet balm some wound has Of little worth — to
                            perish; Nor yet their own soft incense yield ? Nay, verily ! Such sowing Of seed immortal
                            cannot die ; But life, in rich profusion, Will bloom to greet and cheer the eye. Each act of
                            kindness given, Each utter'd word of tender love, Each injury forgiven, Gleams like the
                            golden rays above. A sigh for others' sorrow, A smile when frowning glances fall, Are pearly
                            tear-drops gleaming. These write a true reward for all. The instruments of heaven, Whose
                            strains vibrate through courts above, Give forth their sweetest music When gently touch'd by
                            deeds of love. The song of grateful praises That wafting breezes bear aloft, Floats out o'er
                            fields Elysian, And mingles with their music soft. 'Tis angels' work we're doing, When
                            ministries of love we fill; 'Tis angel strains we're swelling, When breathing forth "Let
                            come who will." Be mine the mission ever To pour sweet balm on hearts distress'd, And, o'er
                            life's stormy ocean, In his name whisper " Be at best."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wheeler, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Wheeler, Union Village, O.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He who hideth 'his talent in a napkin,' and buries it six days deep in worldly and selfish pursuits..." TEIform="index"/>He who hideth 'his talent in a napkin,'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He who hideth " his talent in a napkin," and buries it six days deep in worldly and selfish
                            pursuits, will not find one day in seven sufficient to balance the account, and will make to
                            the merciful Donor many ungracious complaints of hard fare and poor pay.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. H.</byline></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>