<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0311" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18731101" TEIform="date">November 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">81-88</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="81" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                        <p>Vol. III. No. 11. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY Mt. Lebanon, Ool.Cc N. Y.November, 1873.</p>
                    --><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Americanism" TEIform="index"/>AMERICANISM</head><p TEIform="p">Ulysses Gkant, as a mere man, may be a Methodist, as he is a General; yet, as President of
                            these United States, this gives him no right to obtrude either of those upon the American
                            public, who are neither Methodists nor Generals. Were he an atheist, like Bradlaugh, or a
                            Roman Catholic, or an Episcopalian, or a Jew, or a Hindoo Mahometan, or a Chinese Confucian,
                            or a Persian follower of Zoroaster, or a Buddhist, it would be, in him, as great a violation
                            of good taste, as a citizen; and of Americanism, as a statesman, to project his personal
                            theological views upon the public, as it is for the President to officially sanc- tion
                            Protestantism, by inviting the members of the " Evangelical Alliance," from New York to the
                            American Capitol. Washington declared, in his official capacity, as President, that the
                            United States Government was not a Christian Government. Thomas Paine, or Thomas Jefferson,
                            might, with equal propriety, and with equal law, have incorporated their Deism into their
                            public services due to our common country, as for Ulysses Grant to thus ally himself to the
                            Protestant Alliance. The Constitution of these United States is eminently cosmopolitan; and
                            he or she, in the past, or present, or future, who shall have been, or shall be,
                            instrumental in putting the Protestant Bible into public schools, or theological chaplains
                            in the Army or Navy, or into the Halls of Legislation, have thereby constituted themselves
                            judges of other persons' consciences; and, so far, are religious bigots, and superstitious
                            persecutors — enemies to Americanism — to perfect liberty and equality of colors, races,
                            sects, creeds, and sexes; — and to the right of each human being to believe or disbelieve,
                            according to evidence presented, any proposition, philosophical or theological, possible for
                            the human mind to conceive and construct. Even Gentile Christians, Catholic and Pro-
                            testant, who, like Ulysses Grant, hold to war and passional marriage, and who swallow the "
                            Atonement" as they would a drug, to cure them of the sins arising therefrom, have the same
                            civil rights to protection of life, liberty, person, and property, as had Jefferson, the
                            infidel author of the Declaration of Independence, himself; or as had the still greater
                            skeptical originator of the Emancipation Act, by which millions of human beings were
                            restored to those civil rights of which the Gentile Christian kidnappers, and slave-hold-
                            ing masters and mistresses had so long deprived them. Lincoln, like Thomas Paine, and all of
                            the Founders of our Government, were infidels to all the theologies of earth. But they were
                            friends of humanity; and as such, and for which, God "first loved them," until, by
                            Spiritualism and Shakerism, they should learn to love and honor Him and Her as the Foun-
                            tain of all practical good to their own offspring— man. Let us all unite to keep intact and
                            immaculate our American Constitution, into which shall enter no theological tenet against
                            which a single citizen shall protest — I do not believe it!</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Infidels versus christians" TEIform="index"/>INFIDELS VERSUS CHRISTIANS</head><p TEIform="p">There is nothing more common than for infidels and liberalists to be held up by the clergy
                            and members of the church as the vilest of the vile, and to be denounced in unmeasured terms
                            as bad and dangerous men. This, to say the least, is extremely unjust. It is quite possi-
                            ble that some infidels may have been unworthy men; but, so far as our observation has ex-
                            tended, we have found them to be good moral citizens, well and peaceably disposed, honest in
                            their dealings, upright in their intercourse with their fellow-men, and as freely disposed
                            to open their purse to the call of the needy as any other class of men. Many of the first
                            minds and best men of our country were infidels. Benjamin Franklin, Thomas Jefferson, George
                            Washington (so claimed by Jefferson), John Adams, Ethan Allen, Thomas Paine, and many others
                            of the cotemporaries of their times, belonged to this class. In our own times we will
                            mention the name of the great and good Lincoln, whose heart was singularly ingenuous and
                            free from guile — the emancipator of 4,000,000 slaves, and the author of the noble
                            sentiment, " Charity for all, and malice toward none " — he was an infidel. In the same
                            category may be ranked Humboldt, Combe, Darwin, Huxley, Buckle, Froude, Tyndall, Grote,
                            Weisse, Lechey, Spencer, Stuart Mill, Bismarck, Liebig, Bradlaugh, Garrison, Philips,
                            Emerson, Knee]and, Parker, Sumner, Con way, and a host of other brilliant minds in the walks
                            of science, statesmanship, letters, and theology. These men are distinguished not only for
                            their science and education, but for the morality and purity of their lives. To say the
                            least, they will compare favorably with the clergy of the day, who seem to be quite as full
                            of infirmities and fallibilities as any class of men we have. A friend of ours has kept an
                            account of the members of the clergy who, within the last twenty years, have been ar-
                            raigned before the courts of the country and their own churches for crimes and misdemea-
                            nors, and that number has already reached over fifteen hundred. And more than half the
                            piccadillos are never brought to the light, but are " hushed up" for the good of the cause,
                            and to save disgrace to the church. It was recently admitted by a divine in this vicinity
                            that the clergy were as well represented in our penitentiaries and State prisons, in
                            proportion to their numbers, as any class of the community ; while it is seldom that an
                            infidel is found there. It is reported that in the State prison at Auburn, New York, there
                            are twenty members of the clergy confined for the crimes they committed. Are these indeed
                            not a pretty class of men to cry out against the immorality of infidels ? — Truth
                        Seeker.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bread" TEIform="index"/>BREAD</head><p TEIform="p">Bread is called the " staff of life." Its importance in dieting cannot be over-estimated. The
                            bread of a people determines largely the character of that people. First. Of what material
                            shall the bread be composed ? Potatoes principally, are the bread of the Irish, at home. It
                            has this good quality: it is not separated part from part in the process of preparation.
                            This used to be the case writh Indian corn and rye. The Americans have been termed a
                            toothless, dyspeptic nation. They might be termed a physic-taking nation, as, instead of "
                            throwing that article to the dogs," it is adopted as food, by the nation at large, and taken
                            daily. This is no more wonderful than it is horrible. Is the American superfine bolted flour
                            the primary cause of national dyspepsia, and also of the loss of teeth ? or must we look to
                            other sources for the origin of these national evils ? That the teeth are lost, first, from
                            want of use ; and second, from the condition of the stomach, or rather, the "digestive
                            tube," would be generally admitted by physiologists and dentists. The people have never
                            progressed beyond the condition of children, as to their food; it is fluid and pap all the
                            way through. Potatoes are either mashed or fried. Wheat is ground to death, and then
                            quickened into life with yeast, and that again is neutralized with pot-ash, under different
                            names and forms of preparation, which leave it as they found it, pot-ash; whose nature it is
                            to decompose animal tissue, and to disintegrate bones and teeth. Kottenness enters into the
                            skeleton, or frame-work of all those who use it, and by it the functions of the inside skin
                            are rendered quiescent. Again. After the wheat (which of all food contains all the
                            properties, and in the proportions, of the component elements of the body) has been " killed
                            " in grinding, these elements are separated, and some of the most essential are thrown away
                            entirely ; the remainder is made into enervating, constipating, dyspepsia- creating,
                            superfine white bread: the tables — a blessing — turned into a curse. And, inas- much as
                            bread is an article of universal use, so are the evil effects of the use of unphysi- <pb n="82" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 82 ological bread universal, creating a dyspeptic, toothless nation. It
                            is only the constant infusion of foreign blood that continues the present race of native
                            Americans. Dr. Allen thinks a hundred years would terminate the pure Yankee race, if left
                            with all its tendencies to itself, and he attributes this mainly to the use of white bread.
                            Wheat should be used in whole, and ground coarse. How coarse would be the best for ten
                            thousand persons is an unsolved problem. Taking as data, the history of man before "the
                            mills ground so exceedingly fine," we may logically conclude, that, with good teeth, the
                            whole wheat, as eaten by Jesus and his Apostles, could be safely used. After that, all de-
                            grees, down to the size of manna (coriander seed) is admissible, and nothing finer than
                            that, as bread, should be eaten by human beings. That the inside skin requires friction to
                            keep it thick, active and clean, there can be no doubt, from the facts within our reach.
                            Grapes are said, by Dr. Rose, to never injure the eater even when taken in the most absurd
                            quantities, as proved by the people of California, and confirmed in his own personal
                            experience. The seed of the grape is whole. Currants, in our own clime, are nearly as
                            innoxious as the grape in its proper home. Here again is the seed, which is probably very
                            seldom broken by the teeth. Before Graham bread became popular, mustard seed was a common
                            specific for dyspepsia, but to its coarseness was not the curative property credited. All
                            forms of berries owe their healthfulness to the same cause — the seed. Thus does nature
                            teach, and thus are we slow to learn, that no flour should be ground so fine that the teeth
                            have no office left them to perform, and they drop out for want of exercise; and the inside
                            skin would not be inert and cloggy with mucous ; and indigestion, with its mental phenomena,
                            would be as rare in America as it is in Ireland, with its potato ; Scotland, with its
                            oatmeal; Germany, with its cabbage, or in England with its good, strong common sense, as
                            applied to diet, dress, and exercise, by the mothers of the people, beginning with the
                            Queen, who, during some part of her reign, prohibited absolutely the whole royal household
                            from using a single loaf of bread made from superfine ground and bolted wheat flour — white
                            bread.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Teeth" TEIform="index"/>THE TEETH</head><p TEIform="p">Every organ of the body needs its proper attention and exercise, in order to attain to per-
                            fect natural development and retain the powers and the healthful conditions necessary for
                            the performance of its duties. The teeth are more subject to neglect in that respect than
                            any thing else, perhaps; and the sufferings, consequent upon such negligence, are very
                            great; the expenses for alleviating those pains, by removing their causes, and then pro-
                            curing artificial substitutes for the extracted natural teeth, are also considerable. Yet
                            all these evils can be avoided. In some of the northern countries of Europe, it is a
                            comparatively-rare occurrence to meet persons who have lost their teeth, except when quite
                            aged; and the reasons for that are the superior dietetic habits of the people, by which
                            sufficient exercise is afforded those organs. The bread that is most generally used, is
                            somewhat peculiar. It is made of unbolted rye flour, formed into large, round cakes, of
                            various thicknesses, with a hole made through them, by which they can be hung up to dry
                            after they have been baked. When all the moisture contained in them has evaporated, they
                            become hard and very brittle, if they have been properly made. If not, then they are hard
                            and only hard ; in that case they are horrible to meet with, especially for a person who is
                            not accustomed to them. But there is none in those countries who is so unfortunate. That
                            bread is eaten at all tables in connection with other food, and the benefits resulting
                            therefrom, are easily seen. It necessitates slow eating and thorough mastication, and would
                            be, a most excellent thing for Americans, who are in the habit of bolting their food in five
                            or ten minutes, and then run to the doctor to complain of indigestion, or to the druggist
                            for some pills. It would be much better if they would stay at the table at least half an
                            hour, and attend to their digestion themselves, by eating proper things in a proper manner.
                            This would also give the doctors and druggists an opportunity of earning their livelihood by
                            some kind of honest work.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bretzner, Emil" TEIform="persName"/>Emil Bretzner, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Oatmeal" TEIform="index"/>OATMEAL</head><p TEIform="p">Oatmeal, Bone, and Muscle. — Liebig has shown that oatmeal is almost as nutritious as the
                            very best English beef, and that it is richer than wheaten bread in the elements that go to
                            form bone and muscle. Prof. Forbes, of Edinburgh, during some twenty years, measured the
                            breadth and height, and also tested the strength of both the arms and the loins of the
                            students of the University — a very numerous class, and of various nationalities, drawn to
                            Edinburgh by the fame of his teach* ing. He found that, in height, breadth of chest and
                            shoulders, and strength of arms and loins, the Belgians were at the bottom of the list; a
                            little above them, the French; very much higher, the English; and the highest of all, the
                            Scotch and Scotch-Irish, from Ulster, who, like the natives of Scotland, are fed, in their
                            early years, with at least one meal a day of good milk and good oatmeal porridge. Speaking
                            of oatmeal an exchange remarks that a very good drink is made by putting about two spoonfuls
                            of the meal into a tumbler of water. The western hunter and trappers consider it the best of
                            drinks, as it is at once nourishing ; unstimulating and satisfying. Ex.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Signs" TEIform="index"/>SIGNS</head><p TEIform="p">Jesus upbraided the Jews, who could foretell the weather by the face of the sky, for not
                            discerning the time of their visitation. By this we learn that the signs of the work of God
                            are as plainly visible to those who are rightly exercised, as are the signs of the weather.
                            Signs have their purpose, and, if truly interpreted, may lead to conviction, strengthen
                            faith, and awaken those who have not entered the real work, where internal evidence exceeds
                            all other. As " the kingdom of heaven cometh not with outward show," but increases gradually
                            from a small beginning, like the growth of "a grain of mustard seed," the predictions
                            relating to that event cannot be fulfilled all at one time, but must occur in succession, as
                            the work unfolds. When Jesus was about to be separated from his disciples, he said to them,
                            " The world seeth me no more, but ye see me." Consequently, after his resurrection, though
                            "he shewed himself openly, yet (it was) not to all people, but unto witnesses, chosen
                            before, of God." Only disciples saw his ascent; and only those who believed their testimony
                            could ever know the fact. If he comes in like manner, it must be in the presence of
                            witnesses, prepared and chosen of God; and though every eye shall see him ere this
                            dispensation closes, it cannot be with carnal, but with spiritual sight, if it so be that "
                            the world seeth " him no more. Witness is in Greek, martys or martyr, and signifies " one
                            who gives testimony to the Truth at the expense of his life." Such, at least, were the
                            witnesses of Christ's first appearing; they gave testimony to the truth at the expense of
                            their physical lives. The true witnesses of Christ's second appearing, bear testimony to the
                            truth now revealed, at the expense of their carnal or generative lives. The former is a
                            significant type of the latter. We read in Revelation that, after the resur- rection of the
                            witnesses of Christ, " they heard a great voice from heaven saying unto them, Come up
                            hither, and they ascended up to heaven in a cloud." The testimony of the witnesses slain
                            proceeded from the dispensation of Christ's first appearing. The resurrected witnesses began
                            to catch the inspiration of the gleaming future, which was the voice they heard from heaven.
                            The first Quakers, about the middle of the seventeenth century, began to prophesy the
                            approaching end of the kingdom of the beast, and the extinction of all the corrupt systems
                            and false professions of Christianity then existing, because the coming of Christ to judge
                            the world in righteousness, and to set up on earth his everlasting kingdom, was near at
                            hand. This testimony was revived with increasing power in the French prophets, who arose in
                            1688, in the south-east part of France (the same districts where, 450 years previously, the
                            Albigenses, a numerous sect of non-resistants, were extirpated by spoil, banishment, and
                            murder, a million at once, by their pretended Christian neighbors.— Jones' Church History).
                            In 1706, a few of them spread their testimony in England, where they had taken refuge, and
                            it culminated in the society of James and Jane Wardley. With these Mother Ann united in
                            1758, and there received the baptism of the Holy Spirit, which constituted her the second
                            Eve. Mother Ann, and after her, Father William Lee, and Father James Whittaker, came forth
                            with the testimony that Christ had appeared the second time to put an end to sin and bring
                            in everlasting salvation, and they were his witnesses. Many received their testimony and
                            became witnesses in turn. This testimony continued, with increasing evidence and power,
                            until the Church of Believers was progressively organized and established between 1787 and
                            1792, under the ministration of Joseph Meacham and Lucy Wright, upon the principle of a
                            united and consecrated interest in all things. Here was a gradual ascent of the witnesses,
                            until the second Gospel Temple, or visible order of the kingdom of heaven was established in
                            a heavenly cloud, or multitude of witnesses, in an order and power above the generative
                            plane of the earthly man. " And their enemies beheld them," because their order was visible
                            to men on earth. But they could do them no harm, because the persecuting dragon was bound by
                            the " great chain" of events and liberal principles that inspired the patriots of the
                            American Revolution, and by the institution of the U. S. Government, which secured rational
                            liberty and freedom of conscience for the first time in the history of man. The Government
                            under the present Constitution of these U. S. first went into operation while the Church ot
                            Christ's second appearing was undergoing organization. An event of such importance SBCA-KEIl
                            J±NT&gt; <pb n="83" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEEE8S. 83 to the interests of humanity, and planted as
                            a seed in the vital elements of this world, to effect the final overthrow of all false
                            systems, did not take place without the latter showing symptoms of their decreed destiny,
                            described by the spirit of prophecy as follows : " And the same hour was there a great
                            earthquake (concussion or shaking — meaning civil com- motions), and the tenth part of the
                            city fell ; and in the earthquake were slain of men (sects) seven thousand, and the remnant
                            were affrighted, and gave glory to the God of heaven." France was one of the ten kingdoms
                            into which the Roman empire was divided, con- stituting the toes of the image described in
                            Daniel. It therefore formed a tenth part of "the city" — mystic Babylon. The Trench monarch,
                            for his zeal in support of the Roman Catholic religion, was styled " the eldest son of the
                            Church." In July, 1789, the French revolution was inaugurated by the oppressed citizens
                            destroying the Bastile, a stronghold of kingly tyranny. In the year that the Church of
                            Christ's second appearing was fully established in order, 1792, the French National Assembly
                            abolished the monarchical form of government in France, and declared a republic; and the
                            same year commenced a series of sanguinary wars, that convulsed Europe with terrible
                            shaking. The clergy and nobility, " men of name" —i. e., titled dignitaries, were slain like
                            so many cattle ; and the order of nobility was abolished. The Sabbath, and all the signs and
                            symbols of the Christian religion, were also abolished, and a revolutionary tribunal
                            established, which inaugurated a "reign of terror." Thus "the tenth part of the city fell"
                            from priestly influence. And though the people were frightened by such a riot of blood, and
                            again resorted to their temples for religious worship; and though a part of them vainly
                            wished to restore the former things of the ancient rule; and though Napoleon, the most
                            conspicuous actor of the time, attempted to build again the things he had destroyed, and
                            thereby became a transgressor against the providential work he was raised up to perform
                            (which occasioned his fall), the shaking continues ; and France will continue falling until,
                            by the es- tablishment among her people of free and liberal institutions, under a Republican
                            Gov- ernment, guaranteeing the just, civil and religious rights of man, that nation is
                            prepared to receive the mission of the "Angel flying in the midst of heaven, having the
                            everlasting Gospel to preach to them that dwell on the earth," by whom "the remnant" will be
                            taught to give glory to G-od, by ceasing to do evil, and learning to do well. May God in his
                            mercy hasten the day. Observe, this is the first time any judgment is represented as causing
                            men to repent so as to give glory to God. Therefore it is evident that a greater work of God
                            is to take place from this period hence, than ever took place before, through which all men
                            will be compelled to acknowledge the hand of God, even if it be as with the magicians of
                            Egypt.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo" TEIform="persName"/>Alonzo Hollister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Opium seems to be the continuing and increasing curse of China..." TEIform="index"/>Opium seems to be the continuing and increasing curse of China...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Opium seems to be the continuing and increasing curse of China. Dr. Legge, who has been
                            traveling from Peking to Shanghai, with a view to ascertaining the condition of the people
                            of Northern China, makes the melancholy report that the growth of opium in that country is
                            increasing at a prodigious rate, to the exclusion of the cultivation of food. In one
                            district large tracts of land were entirely covered with poppies, and the doctor was in-
                            formed that the cultivation only began last year. Some land will yield a profit by opium
                            greater than that of wheat by two, three, four and even six times. The Chinese peasant's
                            love of the debasing drug is attributed to his being '' tied down to the soil of his own
                            district and shut out from intercourse with his fellows by unjust regulations of every
                            sort."</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="English letter" TEIform="index"/>ENGLISH LETTER</head><p TEIform="p">Mount Lebanon, Columbia Co. N. Y. IT. S. A. October 8th, 1873. Ellen Brown : Last Sabbath
                            afternoon, my dear Mother, I got ruminating. Said I to myself, " By this time your mother
                            has probably received the ' Shaker and ShaJceress,' which will enable her to make a pretty
                            shrewd guess how the land lies. But, not being a Yankee, she is not much given to
                            'guessing.' Write, therefore, and tell her plainly where you are, and what you are doing."
                            After some little thought, I concluded to tell you briefly " what I have found amongst Be-
                            lievers." Accordingly I drew up, and then reduced to shape, the inclosed MS. Read it, and
                            you will see that a Free-thinker, a Spiritualist, a mourner over the fearful evils ex-
                            isting in society — War and Bloodshed, Capital Punishment, Slavery in all its forms,
                            Poverty, Prostitution—a Communist, a Republican, a Woman's Rights advocate, a Truthlover ! —
                            and all this you well know me to be — will necessarily find amongst the Shakers much that is
                            congenial. I have not included Hygiene and Vegetarianism in the list, because these are not
                            yet incorporated into the Society, although beyond all doubt they are destined some day to
                            become so. But in our Family there are quite a number of vegetarians, and I enjoy the
                            privilege, which I dearly prize, of eating at a table bounteously spread with good
                            nourishing food, but unpolluted with the products of the shambles in any shape or form.
                            Elder Frederick, the chief of our Family and Order, a leading spirit of the Society, and a
                            man of grand and advanced ideas, has been a vegetarian for forty years. He is also fully
                            alive to the truths of Hygiene, and the evil and absurdity of drug-medication. Are you
                            surprised that I find myself at home here ? I bless my home, and am child enough to
                            acknowledge, a deep attachment to it, and for the beautiful souls in whose company I am
                            privileged to dwell. My prayer is that I may, through labor and earnest effort, become
                            worthy of the love of those who call me by the endearing name of "Brother." PS. Thank you
                            very much for" the " Westminster" and the "Illustrated." Perhaps you will occasionally
                            remember me in that way. A copy of the " Daily News" also came to hand yesterday. Am glad to
                            hear you still receive the " Laws of Life." I renewed your subscription last March. I have
                            also placed your name upon the subscription list of the " SJiaker and Shakeress," so you
                            will have ample opportunity of studying our views, doctrines, and manners. I trust you and
                            Aunt E. are enjoying comparatively good health. Accept my love. WHAT I HAVE POUND AMONGST
                            BELIEVERS. I — Males and females, of all ages, lodging under one roof, eating at one common
                            table, and — unrestrained by jealous locks, or suspicious bolts and bars, but enjoying free
                            social converse—leading pure, clean, and chaste lives! II — Hatred of cant and hypocrisy. A
                            keen perception of the utter worthlessness and the hollow trumpery of the Doctrines of
                            Orthodoxy, and the wordy nonsense of the prayers, sermons and liomilies thereon constructed.
                            Testimony against the folly of worshiping a Book which shows on every page glaring evidence
                            of error and imperfection, notwithstanding that it does also contain much that is good,
                            true, and beautiful. III — A devotion to Truth in all its phases, scientific, moral, and
                            spiritual. When Religion, for fear of cracking a crystalized creed, carefully avoids the
                            blows of the geologist's hammer, or the testing heat of the chemist's crucible, and,
                            willfully shutting her eyes to well-ascertained facts, denounces science as dangerous and
                            damnable, be sure that such Religion lacks truth, for truth cannot contradict itself. A
                            rational religion does not oppose truth, but embraces it; and, fearless of aught save error
                            and ignorance, is ever ready to welcome fresh discoveries in any field of human inquiry.
                            Such, a religion is Shakerism. IV — Contempt for thrones, scepters, and crowns — not as
                            emblems of authority, for leaders are necessary, and an active, cheerful obedience to just
                            authority a rare but beauteous virtue, but — as emblemm of the abuse of authority, and of
                            tyranny and class-oppression. A testimony against the incestuous union of Churcli and State.
                            A belief in Republicanism as the best form of government for the " Nat- ural (or Generative)
                            Order," and the only form of government under which the existence of a " Spiritual Order " —
                            true followers of Jesus — is possible. V — Contempt for the idle conventionalities of
                            society, and the senseless worship of Fashion, whose votaries little trouble themselves
                            about the right or wrong, the wisdom or folly, of her imperious behests. VI — An effort to
                            supplant the type of social life prevailing in the world, where unqualified Selfishness
                            rules with a rod of iron, by a system the ruling principle of which is Love, and under which
                            it is " more blessed to give than to receive." VII — Testimony against the atrocities of
                            Capital Punishment, Human Slavery in all its forms, War and Bloodshed, Poverty,
                            Prostitution, and the botching and tinkering of crafty class legislation, which, making a
                            great show of grappling with effects, leaves the prolific causes of social evils unchecked,
                            to breed and hatch their brood of miseries. VIII — A knowledge of the world of spirits, of
                            the communion of mortals with immortals, and of present inspiration. IX — The belief that "
                            salvation " is gained through individual effort — through spiritual labor. A good life is
                            the best preparation for eternity, and the mere intellectual acceptance of creed, dogma, or
                            doctrine, comparatively unimportant. X — Woman the acknowledged equal of man, and enjoying
                            equal privileges. XI — A cleanliness, neatness, order, sobriety, frugality, industry,
                            charity, and benevolence truly beautiful; and, in some of my more travailed brethren and
                            sisters, a selfcontrol, a spirituality and goodness truly angelic and enrapturing. XII —
                            Lastly, I have found amongst Believers a peaceful, beautiful home; and, through patient
                            cross-bearing and earnest labor, I hope to merit, and inherit, a final home in heaven.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Hewson" TEIform="persName"/>Hewson Brown, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritualism, as a science, has no more claim..." TEIform="index"/>Spiritualism, as a science, has no more claim...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Spiritualism, as a science, has no more claim upon mankind than has geology or astronomy or
                            any of the intervening sciences, for the reverence and respectful devotion which properly
                            belongs to religion.</p></div2><pb n="84" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Three stages" TEIform="index"/>THREE STAGES</head><p TEIform="p">First.— Fear and love. Children obey through love and fear of ultimate physical punishment.
                            Second.— Youth obey through love, self-respect, and the ultimate fear of grieving and
                            offending. Third.— The adult obeys from love, self-respect, from a desire to excel and do
                            right, and, finally, from the ultimate fear of selfcondemnation. The same stages of progress
                            may be traced and observed in the religious travel of souls. The Law, written upon stone: "
                            Thou shalt" do thus and so, or die physically. The First Gospel. — A call to such as were
                            prepared to believe and obey, or be " damned " — condemned — spiritually. The Second Gospel.
                            —An invitation: " The Spirit and the Bride say Come, and all who hear say Come and be free!
                            ! Perfect love of truth, of good, of Gfod, hath cast out all fear of physical death, and all
                            of spiritual condemnation, and all fear but the one fear of Grod — the fear to offend
                        Love.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sanitary influence of sunlight" TEIform="index"/>SANITARY INFLUENCE OF SUNLIGHT</head><p TEIform="p">The importance of sunlight as a curative agent is not sufficiently appreciated. Sir James
                            Wylie, late physician to the Emperor of Russia, made a careful study of the effect of light
                            as a curative agent in the hospital of St. Petersburg. He discovered that the number of
                            patients, cured in roonis properly lighted, was four times as great as it was when they were
                            confined in dark rooms. This led to a complete reform in lighting the hospitals of Russia,
                            and was attended with the most beneficial results. In cities visited by the cholera, it has
                            been found that the greatest mortality has taken place in narrow streets, and on the sides
                            of those having a northern exposure where the rays of the sun are excluded. The inhabitants
                            of the southern slopes of mountains are better developed and more healthy than those who
                            live on the northern sides. The inhabitants of secluded valleys are often subject to
                            peculiar diseases and personal deformities, partly caused, probably, by the want of direct
                            sunlight. So far has faith in the efficacy of sunlight been carried, that its advocates have
                            proposed to build sanitariums of glass on the upper stories of houses, where patients,
                            divested of clothing, can take daily sun-baths. One reason given for the decrease of
                            population in the Sandwich Islands, is the adoption of civilized habits, and the unhealthf
                            ul restraint of clothing upon the limbs accustomed to light and air. Great improvement can
                            be made in ordinary practice without carrying the remedy to extremes. The most sunny and
                            light part of the house should be occupied by the household, instead of being kept for
                            occasional guests. Persons should sit at the windows where the sunshine comes directly upon
                            them and all the sunshine and air possible should be admitted within doors. Instead of this,
                            heavy draperies, shades, shutters and blinds shut out the life-giving influence. Reception
                            rooms even in these enlightened days, are oftentimes kept so dark you cannot see where you
                            stand ; and as you enter them from the warm sunlight, the close damp air sends a chill
                            through your whole frame, which has, doubtless, by a sudden check of perspiration been the
                            cause of much illness, and the loss of many valuable lives. This is especially the case at
                            this season of the year. The mornings and evenings are chilly, and the doors and windows,
                            after the morning airing, are kept tightly closed to keep out flies and mosquitoes, while
                            the dwellers sit wrapped in shawls in their gaudy and stately prisons. A little pains-taking
                            will obviate these troubles. Almost all houses, imperatively those shaded by trees, need a
                            little fire at morning and evening. It will make trouble and dust, but that will be of no
                            consideration. Then let the draperies be taken down, and open blinds and windows to let in
                            the sanitary sunshine. Protect the windows with screens of lace or wire, to keep out the
                            troublesome pests that are the bane of the careful housekeeper, and let in the priceless
                            wealth of pure air. Let the carpets fade and the upholstery grow dim. Nothing should be too
                            costly for careful use; of what consequence is furniture, when health and life are weighed
                            in the other scale ? We know of deluded individuals who sit all through the summer days in
                            darkened rooms, where plants would either die or lose entirely their green color. We know of
                            houses that send a chill through you like being in a cellar, when you cross the threshold.
                            We know also of sunny homes, where sunlight and fresh air play through the spacious halls,
                            where the windows are thrown open to all healthful influence, and where, on chilly mornings
                            and evenings, provision is made for that blessed influence, an open fire, cheerful,
                            mirth-provoking, and healthful sunlight and pure air. It is said that during one day's
                            healthful existence, sixty hogsheads of pure air should enter the human lungs. It would be
                            an interesting problem to find out what proportion of the inhabitants of this city obtain
                            the quota of pure oxygen necessary for keeping the lungs in the most healthful
                        condition.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Devotion and love" TEIform="index"/>DEVOTION AND LOVE</head><p TEIform="p">I WOULD, says one, deny myself of such and such indulgences, if I thought God would love me
                            any better for it. O brother, remember " God is Love." He loves thee well enough already ;
                            but thou dost not sense his love ; thou dost not love Him. Thy heart and affections are on
                            thy idols—thy indulgences. Deny thyself of these, that thou mayest give thy whole heart to
                            God ; not that thou mayest purchase his favor, or hire Him to love thee ; but that thou
                            mayst love Him, and make room in thy heart for the constant sense and enjoyment of his love.
                            " God so loved the world," while it lay in darkness and rebellion," that he gave his
                            wellbeloved Son " to redeem it. We need not, therefore, think to do something to excite Him
                            to love us ; but may understand, that all our prayers and penances, services and
                            self-denials, are intended to remove the obstacles in ourselves which hinder us from loving
                            Him with all our heart, and our neighbor as ourselves. No forms, ceremonies, or
                            self-denials, are of any service any further than they serve to promote this end ; for "
                            this is more than all burnt offerings," is the end of the whole Law, and is the Gospel.
                            Grant, O heavenly Father, that I may fear nothing but sin ; hate nothing but self ; love
                            nothing but Thee and thine ; speak well of all; do good to all, and ill to none. " Are not
                            two sparrows sold for a farthing ? Yet, not one of them falleth to the ground without your
                            Father. Of how much more value are you than many sparrows V So taught Jesus ; and 0 that I
                            had like precious faith ! O that I fully believed and confided in his word! I then should
                            have habitual and unshaken confidence that all things are under the inspection and control
                            of an infinitely-wise and merciful heavenly Father, and should enter fully and cheerfully
                            into his designs, and be reconciled to all events ; doubting not that " all things shall
                            work together for good to those who love Him." I know that the kingdom of heaven must be
                            within me, and there must be the place of thy throne, O God ; and in my spirit must thy
                            worship be celebrated, if ever I become redeemed from the outer darkness of the external
                            world, of empty forms and fleeting shadows. I cannot enter into the inner court—the kingdom
                            of heaven — but "through great tribulation ;" and, if the hour is come, O righteous Father,
                            give me patience, faith, and fortitude, to endure whatever is necessary for my purification.
                            It requires but little exertion, and, consequently, can be but a small exhibition of virtue,
                            to love those who agree with us in sense and sentiment ; but to cherish real love and
                            affection for those who in their turn are naturally different and very disagreeable to us,
                            requires a mighty effort— a great change in our nature, which affords proof of the
                            attainment of a sublime degree in Divine virtue. To what intent are profound thoughts, depth
                            of mysteries and extent of knowledge, if we are destitute of that simple wisdom which should
                            direct our spirits aright in the little and common occurrences of every day ? O for that
                            watchful, careful, prayerful spirit, which has reference to the will of God in all things,
                            and at all times.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, R. W." TEIform="persName"/>R. W. Pelham, Union Village, Ohio</byline></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Most of our periodicals have matter enough..." TEIform="index"/>Most of our periodicals have matter enough...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Most of our periodicals have matter enough on hand to supply them for the next two years, if
                            all the contributors should strike work in the meanwhile. A gentleman, who contributed last
                            year to one of our youngest magazines an'article of three pages, which was promptly
                            accepted, had it inserted as a special favor at the end of seven months; if it had waited
                            for its regular turn, it would have appeared at about the end of the year. We have known of
                            an instance where an article has waited over fifteen months for its turn. The necessary
                            delay suggests the question — how long a magazine article can keep ? In the case of some
                            other "articles" — fish and vegetables, for instance —the time may be calculated to an hour.
                            Seriously speaking, it is possible that valuable information may sometimes be lost to the
                            public, from the impossibility of finding immediate room for it, even in that immense
                            general receptacle, the daily press. A natural inference would seem to be, the necessity for
                            the utmost condensation on the part of all writers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., H" TEIform="persName"/>H. H., Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Great Britain is very angry with Little Ashantee..." TEIform="index"/>Great Britain is very angry with Little Ashantee...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Great Britain is very angry with Little Ashantee, and Queen Victoria is about to wage war
                            with King Cuffy. A leading English journal says : " Our troops would have no difficulty in
                            destroying the Ashantee capital. Tiie houses are built of combustible materials. We find no
                            satisfaction in the contemplation of hostilities carried to such lengths as the burning of
                            towns and villages. But a war has been forced upon us," etc. And, further on, the same
                            journal announces the departure for the scene of operations of the transport "Adela," loaded
                            with military stores, and continues: " In the garrison churches at Woolwich, about the time
                            the Adela sailed, the hymn usually sung when the troops are at sea was given, the chorus — O
                            hear us when we pray to Thee For those in peril on the seabeing sung with deep feeling." Man
                            ever makes God in his own image. Fighting, warring " Christians " naturally invoke a
                            blood-thirsty, war-loving Deity. This is the same God that our Modoc-murdering " Christians
                            " want to get into the U. S. Constitution! Keep him out!!</p></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The 'cry of the children'..." TEIform="index"/>The 'cry of the children'...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The "cry of the children" of the female gender in China must be vociferous indeed if, as says
                            the Chinese Provincial Treasurer of Hupei, their parents drown them at the rate of 80 per
                            cent. This personage has issued an edict to his people forbidding this method of thinning
                            out the female population, and plies them with various arguments and threats to induce them
                            to desist from the inhuman practice. Among othei convincing appeals he remarks that the
                            children can be sent to a foundling hospital; that they will find husbands if allowed to
                            live. He also threatens them with the vengeance of heaven, and finally with punishment for
                            willful murder.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Argus" TEIform="persName"/>Argus</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Felons and rusty nails" TEIform="index"/>FELONS AND RUSTY NAILS</head><p TEIform="p">For the past ten years, we have treated cases of Felons with hot water, and with unerring
                            success. No cutting, no blistering, no any thing, but immersing the finger, hand, or even
                            the whole arm if necessary, in water as hot as can be borne, until the pain is gone and the
                            core is loosened and drawn from the bone. When rusty nails have produced wounds, the same
                            course has been pursued. If on the hand or foot, keep it in hot water. If elsewhere, apply
                            hot cloths with dregs of No. 6 on them.</p></div2><pb n="85" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: words fitly spoken" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: WORDS FITLY SPOKEN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">How shall words be so fitly spoken, that they will be as " apples of gold ? " To whom should
                            we look for words so virtuous and true, and so appropriately spoken, that they will convey
                            spirit and life to the hearers ? If the answer be, Look to the spiritual teachers and
                            learned divines of our day, then we again ask, " If all the words spoken for the space of
                            one year, by professed ministers of the Gospel of Christ throughout the civilized world,
                            should be gathered and printed in one great volume, how much of the quickening Spirit of
                            Truth, that would lead souls to repent of sin and wrong doing, and to a practical life of
                            holiness, would it contain ? " Who is able to compute the number of churches in Christendom—
                            their cost — and the annual stipends of the hired priests who occupy the pulpits of those
                            costly edifices, and to define how much of that great expenditure is either directly or
                            indirectly wrung from the hard earnings of the poorer classes of honest laborers, who,
                            perhaps, would not be allowed a seat in some of those fashionable temples ? Texts from the
                            Old, and what are called New, Scriptures, are selected by the professed lights of the world,
                            to prove the diversified tenets of the numerous sects in Christendom, which is now full of
                            names, and all profess to believe in Jesus; though but few have the audacity to claim that
                            they really follow him; for, in this enlightened age, they know that war, generation, and
                            individualism in form of private property, belong to the old Adamic order, and not to the
                            New Dispensation which Jesus Christ came to inaugurate, the principles of which he
                            illustrated and exhibited in his self denying life. Whatever the differences of opinion may
                            be which divide the (so-called) Christian sects into many classes, in practical life they
                            are so much a unit, that one plea answers for nearly all of them; that is, We are
                            mortal—finite; he was God — Infinite. It is said that " the letter killeth, but the Spirit
                            giveth life." Many, at the present time, consider that the Scriptures written anterior to
                            the four Evangelists — Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John — are a dead letter now; that they were
                            only applicable to the followers of Moses, and that we have outgrown them. Again, we would
                            ask, Have not the Scriptures which were written by the Evangelists and Apostles of Jesus
                            Christ, been so weakened by translations, and so corrupted through the vain and false
                            interpretations of the clergy (who, with smooth and pleasing words, seek to allure and
                            charm, having a far greater desire to fleece than to feed the flock over which they
                            preside), that the people of this generation need to be revisited by a spirit, or spirits,
                            from the Christ heavens ; and, by the same inspirational power, receive a new and clean
                            revelation — a newer testament — containing the will of God that will meet the conditions of
                            the present age 1 The Shakers find oil and wine in all Scriptures written by true
                            inspiration, in every age, and in different nations ; and also find that they are profitable
                            to the man and woman of God, who are willing to be reproved, corrected, and instructed by
                            them, regardless of individual sacrifices which they may require. And yet there is no people
                            who pray more fervently for new openings of Divine truth, and for the living Word, that is "
                            Spirit and life " — which no book can contain, however sacred it may be — than do the
                            Shakers. Their earnest cry is, " Lord, give us this day the living bread which cometh from
                            the resurrection heavens ! Baptize and rebaptize us with power from on high! Fill us with a
                            Divine afflatus that will energize the whole being anew." When under such inspirational
                            power, words will be spoken so good and true, that, in value, they may well be compared to "
                            apples " or nuggets, " of gold, in basins of silver." How can any one ever attain to that
                            condition while seeking pleasure through the medium of the outward senses, and in the
                            gratification of animal desires ? If the heart is void of true purity and practical
                            goodness, it cannot minister to others what itself does not possess. Men (and women too) may
                            speak as with the tongues of angels; but, if their words are unattested by the seal of
                            Christianity, which is to " depart from all iniquity," they will be but empty sounds ; while
                            words proceeding from a pure heart, though simple in style, will be fraught with power,
                            beauty, and grace. A noble life is made up of noble deeds ; it does not consist of many
                            words, or length of years. The external is a reflex of the internal, and like produces like
                            in kind. Many are anxiously inquiring, Whither are the nations of the earth drifting at the
                            present time 1 for the social, moral and spiritual conditions of the people are fearful! We
                            answer, Nothing short of a power that is stronger, purer, and more just than men, can stay
                            the tide of iniquity that threatens to deluge the land and carry the nations back to
                            barbarism, or annihilation.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quench not the spirit" TEIform="index"/>"QUENCH NOT THE SPIRIT."</head><p TEIform="p">Among the many injunctions given in Holy Writ, perhaps none are more essential to the growth
                            and spiritual progress of the human soul than the one above quoted. The present tendency of
                            the age (owing to perverted conditions) is downward to the earth, seeking to satisfy desires
                            through the medium of the senses. Thus, from childhood to riper years, unless influenced and
                            guided by a spirit power that is superior to the natural, the mind leaps from one thing to
                            another, in search of pleasure, and rushes down the current of passional emotion, which
                            leads to sensuality and from God. But there is a germ of spirituality in every human being
                            which can be reached and quickened by divine power; and, if the Spirit of Truth, which
                            speaks to the conscience of every intelligent soul, is not quenched, then, by degrees, the
                            thoughts, desires, and affections, will turn to a higher and spiritual life. It is true,
                            that the path which leads to the summit of the hill of redemption is " straight and narrow,"
                            yet it is beautiful and pleasant, and those who are weary of a worldly life, and sick of its
                            sins, and have commenced to travel in this narrow way, find peace and rest therein. Such
                            find fountains of living waters from which they can drink, and in which they can bathe and
                            cleanse their souls from all sin. And the good Spirit, which we are exhorted not to quench,
                            is ever teaching purity of life, the putting away of foolish imaginations, vain thoughts,
                            idle words, and wicked deeds ; all of which tend to grieve the Holy Spirit. There are many
                            ways by which the Spirit is quenched. If we cast our eyes abroad into society as it now
                            exists, we see that, through trade and traffic, and giving the mind to avarice, the Spirit
                            is quenched. "The flesh always lusteth against the Spirit," and would not only quench it,
                            but would kill it. The Spirit of Truth is quickening in its operations, and if we delay when
                            it calls, and wait our own pleasure, giving to the inferior time to gain strength, tJiat
                            also grieves the good Spirit! If Jesus addressed the people of his day as " a wicked and
                            adulterous generation," can we not justly apply the same language to the present generation,
                            and ask : Why will ye fill this beautiful earth with violence, bloodshed, and murder,
                            thereby grieving the Holy Spirit, and stifling the sweet voice of conscience ? Conscience,
                            if listened to, would stop the ears from even heaving of bloody wars, and would close the
                            eyes to the follies and vanities of this world; it would check the tongue that would speak
                            evil; stay the hand that would do wrong; and would guide the feet into the highway of
                            purity. God designed that his creature man should be happy, and He has given to him
                            physical, moral, and spiritual laws, to guide and control him in all the acts of life. When
                            those laws are observed, happiness is the result; and, were they all strictly obeyed, heaven
                            would be brought down to earth, and the waste places would be filled and become fruitful
                            fields ; for all would have a right to the soil. Instead of a few green spots here and
                            there, testifying that a new earth and heavens are forming, the whole earth would give
                            evidence that a redeeming power was at work. Instead of sorrow and mourning, joy and
                            gladness would break forth as the noon-day sun, and the sweet song of praise and prayer
                            would reverberate through the heavens ; mercy and truth would meet together, righteousness
                            and peace would kiss each other, and the jubilee, or sabbath of sabbaths, would be
                            multiplied. Already the Spirit is brooding upon the waters, light emanates from the
                            resurection heavens, whence the Angel of conviction will go forth, and, with the torch of
                            truth in hand, will touch the heart that hungers and thirsts after righteousness, awaken the
                            conscience, and kindle therein a fire that can never be quenched.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elevation by reformation" TEIform="index"/>ELEVATION BY REFORMATION</head><p TEIform="p">That a general reformation or transformation is needed, to better the condition of the hu-
                            man race, few will deny; but to define when and how it shall be accomplished, seems to be a
                            difficult task. There are many wise men and women who can discern the face of the sky, and
                            tell from outward signs what the weather indications are, with far greater precision than in
                            the days of Jesus. Progress in natural science has effected much in this direction; but,
                            where shall we find minds so spiritually progressed that they can foretell, with equal
                            clearness, the great changes that await humanity, in a moral and spiritual point of view;
                            when the love of right and justice, and not policy and pleasure, will bear rule ? The cruel
                            tyrant, Fashion, has assumed large proportions, and false delicacy sways the scepter over
                            multitudes at the present time ; and, while physical laws are disregarded — the law of
                            chastity violated — the comfort and ease of individuals are sacrificed to the monster
                            Fashion, who holds them in her grasp ; and many, who should retain and show forth the image
                            of the Creator, are dwarfed and compressed into wasp-like forms. While those things absorb
                            the attention, and continue to claim the affections of females, there will be but little
                            hope of radical reform. But, when Woman shall have religious conviction, and moral courage
                            enough to throw off the yoke of bondage, which now holds her in slavish fear of the opinions
                            of others, and will come forth and occupy her proper sphere, then she will be an instrument
                            in the hands of angels, to work for the emancipation of man from every form of slavery —
                            from the power of tobacco and alcoholic drinks; and to turn his feet from brothels, and help
                            him to regard natural law. Then may we hope that infanticide will flee the land; and that
                            children will be born and reared under healthful, moral influences. Then many hearts that
                                <pb n="86" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 86 SHA.KER AND have grown old with sorrow, because of the
                            degeneracy of the people, will be rejuvenated, and a new era will commence in the Christian
                            world. Then we may look for the waste places in Zion to be filled with honest souls, who
                            will gladly leave the world for the treasures of the Gospel. Those who honor God, He will
                            honor! And our prayer is, Speed the day, O King and Queen of Righteousness, when the nations
                            of the earth shall know and do thy will! May living truth extend from pole to pole; and may
                            many souls bow to its scepter of peace and love, and learn to live to God, and die to sin.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morse, Rosie" TEIform="persName"/>Rosie Morse, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Neither do I condemn thee" TEIform="index"/>"NEITHER DO I CONDEMN THEE."</head><p TEIform="p">Words of charity unequal'd, Breathed by one who bore the cross, Who had fathom'd human
                            sorrow, And could feel for human loss. How like the balm they must have fallen On the poor
                            transgressor's heart, Courage to her soul imparting, Ne'er from virtue's way to part. O that
                            all the fallen mortals, Dwelling on this earthly shore, By these words might be encouraged,
                            And go forth and sin no more. But, alas ! the cold world hearkens Not to their deep cries of
                            woe ; They have fallen, and are trodden Down to earth by high and low. Hear ye not their
                            bitter wailing, You who boast of Virtue's gift ? Pride or hatred will not raise them, Only
                            love their souls can lift. Shall we mortals, prone to evil, Slight, despise, or censure them
                            ? Shall we crush, adjudge, or injure Those whom Christ did not condemn ? Place ourselves in
                            their condition, Just imagine for awhile, "Were we earth's poor outcast children, With no
                            friend on us to smile, Would it prompt us to seek virtue, If all hearts had callous grown,
                            And exulted in the contrast Of their station with our own ? Nay, one kindly proffer'd
                            feeling, E'en a word or look of cheer, Oft will turn a soul from evil That would sink were
                            we severe. Think of men engross'd in business, False unto the very core, Holding up their
                            heads in honor, Welcome guests at every door. While their feeble, helpless victims Are
                            rejected and cast down, They are courted, they — the spoilers — Never meet the sneer or
                            frown. God is just: his mercy floweth Not to person, name, or sect; In his eyes all sin is
                            hateful, But the truth He doth respect. Those who (sin-sick and forsaken By their fellow
                            mortals here) Seek the Lord, He will protect them; For to Him all souls are dear. Then
                            arise, O sinning sister, Knock at Virtue's pleasant door, Christ, your Savior, will receive
                            you, Enter in, and " sin no more."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Morse, Rosie" TEIform="persName"/>Rosie Morse, Shirley, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parable of the talents" TEIform="index"/>PARABLE OF THE TALENTS</head><p TEIform="p">This important subject has often engaged my attention, and made a deep and lasting im-
                            pression upon my mind; for God is the Giver of all good, and we are his servants, who, in
                            various ways have received abilities that will fit us for the duties of life which we are to
                            perform ; and it should be our highest aim to make a wise and prudent use of all those fac-
                            ulties with which we are endowed; and we should likewise consider that these faculties, or
                            talents, are given us on trust, and that we are accountable to the Giver for the improve-
                            ment we make of them. The following parable or metaphor is designed to meet our con- dition,
                            and teach us to improve, increase, and faithfully acquit ourselves of this probationary
                            charge. • The Savior said: " The kingdom of heaven is as a man traveling into a far country,
                            who called his servants and delivered unto them his goods. To one was given five talents, to
                            another two, and to another one ; to every one according to his several abilities. And he
                            that received five went and traded with them, and gained other five. He that received two
                            gained other two. But he that received one went and digged in the earth and hid his lord's
                            money. After a time, the lord came and reckoned with the servants. So he that received five
                            talents, brought other five talents, and received the reward, etc. He also that received
                            two, gained other two, and was likewise called a good and faithful servant. He that received
                            the one talent came before his lord with accusations, saying, I knew that thou art a hard
                            man, reaping where thou hast not sown ; and he hid the talent in the earth, and said, Lo,
                            there thou hast that is thine." Now, what is this one talent which some unwisely have hidden
                            in the earth ? All mankind were created with a physical body, of earth, and a spiritual body
                            or soul, which is also subject to death by sin ; and into this body was breathed soul-life,
                            or spirit. This one talent may be hidden, or lost in the earthly nature, and the soul left
                            destitute, by neglecting to use this living spirit, and thus double its capacity ; for it
                            should increase, and progress in spiritual light and knowledge, and have a continual
                            inspiration of the Spirit of God. The very life our souls should have is the spirit life and
                            element for its director ; or it is but earthly, and buried in the constant cares for the
                            body. O how inconsistent it is to murmur, and return to the Giver nothing but the one
                            talent, saying, Here I am, even as I was created; take the soul, it is thine. In this way,
                            the power to co-operate with the spirit life is destroyed, and the faculty to cultivate and
                            improve the situation is thrown away. We have received abilities equal to the service
                            expected ; but, if we are idle, and do not increase the spiritual life of the soul, the
                            Giver will recall the desire, or even the power to double its value, as the Savior said, "
                            Take, therefore, the talent from him, and give it to the one that hath ten." He was
                            industrious, and energized his soul; for every one that works, shall have abundance in
                            spiritual things, as well as earthly substance. But the unprofitable servant Avas cast into
                            outer darkness, where there was " weeping and gnashing of teeth." But it was said to them
                            that doubled the gift, " Well done, thou good and faithful servant, thou hast been faithful
                            over a few things, and I will make thee ruler over many ; enter thou into the joy of thy
                            Lord."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Blake, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dress reform" TEIform="index"/>DRESS REFORM</head><p TEIform="p">In the September number of the "Shaker and ShaJceress," an article appeared under the head of
                            " Plain Dressing for Meeting," by our good sister, H. L. Hastings, of Canterbury, N. H. I
                            wish to express my hearty approval of the sentiments therein contained. Certainly every
                            lover of virtue has a duty to perform in testifying, by word and example, against the per-
                            verted condition of society at the present time; and the prevailing desire for extravagant,
                            fashionable dressing is an unmistakable proof that the hearts of the people are corrupt; for
                            " out of the abundance " of their hearts, men and women " speak " and act. It is said that
                            women should be ornaments in society. We would ask, Is there a sensible man, or woman, who
                            really thinks that the huge pile of stuff, called hair, worn upon the heads of women, is
                            either healthy or ornamental? And the high crown hats, loaded with artificial and
                            superficial trimmings, do they make woman beautiful and cause her to ornament society? The
                            hitch-ups on their dresses, with the protruding bumps, and overlengthy skirts, dragging
                            around in the dirt, are they ornaments, or a manifestation of good common sense ? If some
                            men consume two or three dollars worth of cigars in a day, and chew the vile weed until
                            their systems are saturated with the poisonous j uice, and then fill their stomachs with
                            alcoholic drinks; women ought not to complain, so long as they indulge in such ex-
                            travagance in jewelry and other useless appendages. They who give their attention so much to
                            the exterior are sure to neglect the mind which needs to receive proper and healthful food ;
                            they do not remember that the " beautiful lives in the depths of the soul." If woman better
                            understood her true position, she would scorn the idea of being a mere ornament in society,
                            to be flattered and admired. She would feel that she has powers and faculties that were
                            given to her for use, and that it is her right and duty to exercise those powers for the
                            elevation of the race. But Fashion sways her scepter over all classes, from the queen's
                            palace to the humble peasant's cottage, and the people wander after that great goddess, and
                            pay homage at her shrine. There are many persons who see the evil that results from
                            following the fashions of the day, and they feel the bondage thereof, but have not the
                            courage to assert their freedom ; they fear the prudery of the scornful, who would place a
                            mark upon them. But may we not hope that, ere long, some women from influential circles will
                            have the true moral fortitude to come forth, and, upon an independent platform, inaugurate a
                            new dress reform, and attire their own persons in a plain, modest, healthful, and convenient
                            style, and set an example worthy of imitation ? If such a reform were started by some who
                            are wealthy and popular, it would effect a greater change in, and give more relief to,
                            society than all that can be said or written upon the subject. For they who practically
                            adopt whatever is true and just in a physical or spiritual point of view, will accomplish
                            the greatest amount of good to themselves and others ; and are worthy to be called
                            Reformers.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Betsey" TEIform="persName"/>Betsey Johnson, Tyringham, Mass.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ruling spirit of the age" TEIform="index"/>RULING SPIRIT OF THE AGE</head><p TEIform="p">The ardent, youthful mind, full of thought and life, is more apt to glance hastily, and take
                            particular views of the future, than to reason dispassionately. The imaginary idea of
                            freedom controls, and any power which holds, restrains, and admonishes, is galling to it.
                            Insubordination to parents and guardians is the ruling spirit among youth and children of
                            the present day. They complain that the sphere allotted them to move in is too limited <pb n="87" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> and narrow; and they feel anxious to throw off all restraint, and even
                            to forsake the watchful care of guardian friends, which would form for them a covert from
                            the rude storms of life. Thus, they soon become independent, and are unwilling to receive
                            instruction from those who are self-governed, and are older and wiser than themselves. And
                            this element seems to pervade all ages, classes, and conditions in society, from the small
                            child's-play circles, to civil conventions, and the council halls of the nation. In passing
                            through the streets of our large cities, and even country villages, how often we see the
                            little trotter just able to articulate the alphabet instinctively manifest a restless,
                            dissatisfied feeling — a reaching after something it does not possess. I want this — I want
                            that ; and if the want is indulged, it soon grows into — I will have it — 1 cannot, will not
                            do without it! This persistent spirit grows so strong, that it is their constant life
                            attendant; and to have the propensity desire indulged, is the one great object of their
                            lives; and how to remove every obstacle that would obstruct the course of their wild,
                            unsubdued passions, becomes their chief study. This is often carried to such an extent,
                            that, if parents stand in the way, they wish that themselves, or their parents, were dead,
                            or could be annihilated, and be out of the way, so that they could do as thejr please. And
                            many from this cause commit parricide outright; while others, by their reckless, unsubdued
                            course of action, bring their parents to a premature grave. The germs of this spirit are in
                            every human heart. In the poorer and more ignorant classes, it manifests itself in grosser
                            forms; the more refined and educated, and the more respectable the parentage, the more
                            subtle it works, and the more it is glossed over. Many parents neglect the early training of
                            their children; and, when the golden moment is passed, and it is too late to restrain them,
                            and throw a protective influence around them, then they feel sorrow, and their hearts are
                            pained when they feel their ingratitude and want of appreciation. And parents, failing in
                            every attempt to induce them to accept of proffered instruction from them, turn to Be-
                            Meiers for help, and ask their fostering care — their moral and spiritual influence — in
                            behalf of their children. When Believers are moved, through feelings of charity, and a sense
                            of the worth of immortal souls, to take children under their especial charge, and become
                            their guardians, they suffer for them as the natural parent is not capable of doing; they
                            grieve selfishly because he, or she, is their own offspring ; their love is partial. But
                            love that is grounded in truth, in God, is unselfish and universal in its nature, and flows
                            to humanity at large. This is the love that Shakers claim to possess. And, inasmuch as they
                            have this love to rule their course of action, they become spiritual parents to souls, and
                            suffer for them in spirit, as Christ suffered for his flock. In faith and hope they toil and
                            spend their lives for others; and their constant prayer is, that a soul-saving baptism may
                            fall mercifully upon the hearts of the young to subdue and bring all their thoughts and
                            feelings into subiection to the law of Christ — the power of love. As spiritual guardians,
                            they keep a diligent watch, and strive to be as Angel guides to them on the journey of life,
                            and to save them from the destructive elements of their perverted natures ; thus, in
                            self-abnegation and soul-suffering, they give their lives fo*r others. Some parents realize
                            this in a degree, when they seek to place their children with Be- lievers, and feel
                            confident that they will receive a higher and more spiritual discipline than themselves are
                            able to give, and that thereby their children will be saved from im- pending ruin. But, at
                            the present time, the self-willed, insubordinate spirit is so rife that it cannot be quelled
                            by merely living with God's people. There must be a spiritual bap- tism of Divine power that
                            will enable them to practise self-denial, and to accept counsel and admonition from those
                            who are capable of giving it. Many hearts have been wounded by the ruthless inattention of
                            some of the junior class, for they have returned " cursing for blessing." While consecrated
                            souls have watched and toiled, and fasted and prayed for them, they, in return, have
                            rendered ingratitude. But the labor spent on such unprepared material will not be lost; it
                            will have its effect; no good deed will ever be lost; but will be gathered by higher
                            intelligences into the great store-house of truth, as gifts for those who are prepared to
                            receive them with grateful hearts. Yet the aged, as well as the middle-aged, have often felt
                            sad to see their best efforts slighted. They have toiled with unselfish devotion to prepare
                            a home for the rising generation, and for all who may be called into the spiritual work of
                            God, to consecrate their all to honor Him, and serve their brethren and sisters of the
                            household of faith, in love, and to do good unto all mankind as opportunity serveth. We
                            rejoice to say that there are some who can and do appreciate the blessing of the protection
                            and care which they find in their Zion home; and they honor, love and bless the aged who
                            have spent their lives in doing good; and they delight to show kindness and bestow affection
                            upon them, by attention to all their wants, and will never be guilty of wishing them away.
                            My heart is glad when I can alleviate the feelings of those who are older than myself. The
                            aged in Zion are my blessing. They have beautified my home, and have caused me to become
                            established in the truth, and to feel the importance of true life-deeds. And I know that
                            their greatest joy and comfort is to see the youth in Zion love and appreciate their Gospel
                            home, and the laws which are necessary to guard all within its precincts; so that their "
                            hopes may not melt as the winter's gray frost, or run away as unprofitable water."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>Charlotte Byrdsall, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="world-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hungry Queen" TEIform="index"/>A Hungry Queen.</head><p TEIform="p">At a late public reception of the Shah of Persia, while waiting in her carriage for some
                            evolution, the Queen became hungry and ordered lunch, which she received by spreading her
                            handkerchief in her lap and eating to her own satisfaction, but to the great discomfort of
                            the dowdy aristocracy.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The influence of the censorious critic is more favorable to                                 character than that of the flattering panegyrist." TEIform="index"/>The influence of the censorious critic...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The influence of the censorious critic is more favorable to character than that of the
                            flattering panegyrist.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Death" TEIform="index"/>DEATH</head><p TEIform="p">What is it, bat the gateway to Life? And we know not how many similar changes the Spirit must
                            pass in the journey of Eternal progression. And though the sense of sight may, for the time,
                            be closed to the presence of our friends, yet, have we not others which may be employed in
                            its absence ? Hearing and consciousness are as active in darkness as in light, and
                            frequently form the only means of communication, as in cases of total blindness, and utter
                            darkness. What is it, then, but the effort of the spirit striving to make its presence known
                            through accessible means. By such means I claim to have received the following lines from
                            the Spirit of Elder Jonas Nutting, who deceased at Shirley, August 26, 1873, being thrown
                            from a carriage and almost instantly killed: SWEET REST. Adieu to Earth! By Angel wings
                            Upborne, I seek my rest: For me its pains have lost their stings; Its pleasures all their
                            jest. The brittle thread which held me here, So rudely snapt in twain, Was not the cord I
                            prized most dear, Or wished to long retain. My spirit feels not one regret, That thus I'm
                            called away; Or that my sun on earth has set, To rise in realms of day. No sever'd ties of
                            Gospel friends The heart need ever know, Love's cable to that world extends, Where joyfully
                            I go. Though you, ray friends, who tarry still, May miss an absent face, And look in vain
                            for one to fill, On earth, a vacant place ; I know that God will guard his own, And, with
                            his strong right arm, Until his will can be made known, Shield you from every harm. Place
                            not your trust in mortal power, Nor yield to grim despair ; Should this but prove your
                            darkest hour, Your sky will soon be fair. Let Hope not droop her wings too low, Nor Faith
                            resign control; These clouds will silver linings show, And vanish like a scroll. With you I
                            've prayed that Truth extend, And flood the earth with light; I still shall labor to that
                            end, Unceasingly with might; Still of your burdens bear a part: My soul cannot divest Of
                            that which lies so near my heart; Inaction is not rest. The path of Progress now I see Is
                            all illumed ahead ; For every one the path is free : Here still, my feet shall tread. The
                            seeds we sow in earthly life, With fruitage here are blest, And those who never yield the
                            strife, Are those who' find Sweet Beat. Harvard, August 31,1873.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Persons, A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. PERSONS</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular errors" TEIform="index"/>Popular Errors</head><p TEIform="p">To think that the more a man eats the fatter and stronger he will become. To believe that the
                            more hours children study the faster they will learn. To conclude that if exercise is good,
                            the more violent it is the more good is done. To imagine that every hour taken from sleep is
                            an hour gained. To act on the presumption that the smallest room in the house is large
                            enough for a bed-room. To argue that whatever remedy causes one to feel better is good for
                            the system, without regard to more ulterior. To eat without an appetite, or to continue to
                            eat after it has been gratified. To eat a hearty supper for the mere pleasure experienced
                            during the brief period it is passing down the throat, at the expense of a whole night of
                            disturbed rest, and a weary waking in the morning.</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The more light admitted to apartments, the better for..." TEIform="index"/>The more light admitted to apartments, the better for...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The more light admitted to apartments, the better for those who occupy them. Light is as
                            necessary to sound health as it is to vegetable life. Exclude it from plants, and the
                            consequences are disastrous. They cannot be per fected without its vivifying influence. Let
                            in the light often, and fresh air, too, or suffer the penalty of aches and pains, and long
                            doctors' bills, which might have been avoided by more light.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The 'Witnesses,' who existed during the 1260 years..." TEIform="index"/>The 'Witnesses,' who existed during the 1260 years...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The "Witnesses," who existed during the 1260 years, as individuals, have become a "cloud,"
                            having ascended into an organization — heaven upon earth.</p></div2><pb n="88" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Promise" TEIform="index"/>PROMISE</head><p TEIform="p">1. We'll breathe the words of holy joy, To spirits who are cast 2. We'll guide you to the
                            glad some sphere, Where purest toils abound, 3. And you shall see we are not bound By
                            selfishness or pride, Up on the And show to But self de sorrow'd waves of life, Where
                            bitterness doth last; you the heavenly truth Our pilgrimage hath found; ni al is the power
                            In which our souls abide; We'll tell We'll ope That all you the we of a happy home secret of our joys, have is spent for God, Beyond the strife of care, Where love is reigning
                            in each heart, And deeds are wrought in prayer. The pleasures of our day, And give you
                            from our treasury, Till grief shall pass away. To aid the fallen race, And make this
                            earth, on which we live, A paradise of grace.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sacrifice" TEIform="index"/>SACRIFICE</head><p TEIform="p">O Zion, thou beautiful city of God ! What off'ring will win in thy courts an abode ? A heart
                            that is chasten'd and sick of its sin,— Will that at thine altar the precious boon win ? Ah,
                            yea! if thy vineyards and orchards so fair, And gold-waving harvests, the needy may share;
                            If they will but sacrifice all that is vain, To them shall the hundred-fold blessing remain.
                            Thy order and beauty the angels have wrought; To thee shall earth's treasures in fullness be
                            brought; Of gifts and of sacrifice, choicest shall be Prom souls consecrated to true purity.
                            Then, come to the waters, so cleansing and clear; The angels are troubling them, come
                            without fear; For God's power is able the heart to sustain That lays down its life, Life
                            Eternal to gain.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham, Enfield, Conn.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker home" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER HOME</head><p TEIform="p">Sweet my home, with its attractions From the sphere of spirit life, Where the pow'r of love
                            is ruling, And where never enters strife. Quiet, safe, and ever pleasant, Lighted by
                            contentment deep ; Sacred influence, ever present In true hearts that prayerful keep.
                            Guardian friends, like angels holy. Sainted friends, who 've left the form, Bless the
                            dwellings of the lowly, And protect from every storm. Here is Freedom's banner gleaming, Joy
                            and love its folds display ; And the star of Truth is beaming On my Shaker home to-day.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Jones, Phebe A." TEIform="persName"/>Phebe A. Jones, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let men laugh when you sacrifice desire to duty if they will. You have time and eternity to                                 rejoice in" TEIform="index"/>Let men laugh when you sacrifice desire to duty if they will...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Let men laugh when you sacrifice desire to duty if they will. You have time and eternity to
                            rejoice in.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Parker, Theodore" TEIform="persName"/>Theodore Parker</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Faith's reward" TEIform="index"/>FAITH'S REWARD</head><p TEIform="p">Our earth life is fleeting, and passes away, As mists of the morning in brightness of day,
                            The few pleasure moments allotted us here, Come sparkling like bubbles, and then disap-
                            pear. The friends whom we love, that "we fold to our hearts, Pass from us as glory of
                            evening departs ; And though by their presence our spirits are blest, We cannot retain them
                            from angelic rest. We pluck the sweet flower, and behold its fair form Soon withers and
                            droops, as if torn by the storm ; And, while we are seeking our sorrow to hide, We ask, in
                            our hearts, is there naught can abide 1 A brightness comes o'er me, a soft whisper near, It
                            says, Child of earth, 0 dispel doubt and fear. The spirit, released from its casket of clay,
                            Aloft soars in freedom to bright realms of day. The loved ones you cherish, the friendship
                            so dear, Shall yet be your treasure in yon happy sphere. No sin, nor affliction, can find
                            entrance there, For deep love and wisdom pervade everywhere. The delicate flower, so
                            fragrant and sweet, Will bloom with new life, and with beauty replete; No mildew nor blight
                            in the bud can destroy The fruit or fair blossoms of that land of joy. Then toil on with
                            ardor, with hope ever rife, Before us are riches of immortal life ; Our Heavenly Father and
                            Mother will crown All those who in faith have their own lives laid down.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Rhoda" TEIform="persName"/>Rhoda Hollister, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="They who talk much should beware of those who listen attentively" TEIform="index"/>They who talk much should beware of those who listen attentively
                        </head><p TEIform="p">They who talk much should beware of those who listen attentively.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts of life" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS OF LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">O, if every one were happy, Joyful — happy — I would be ; But the sufl 'rings of another Ever
                            take my joy from me. What a world of bitter anguish I What distressing scenes of woe,
                            Mortals born in pain to languish. And but slight releasement know. Just the best, and the
                            most holy, Are afflicted and oppress'd ; Just the kindest, and most lowly, (Seemingly) are
                            most distressed. As I find of pain each token Sadden'd, I behold the cause ; For, in depths
                            of ill unspoken. Much is ours through broken laws. Violation of the Spirit, And of Nature's
                            perfect way, With the weakness we inherit, How proceed the debt to pay ? Toils that seem to
                            yield but little (While we walk in present light) Shall fulfill each jot and tittle, And
                            establish truth and right. Mountains are composed of atoms, And by atoms worn away : So, by
                            little acts, we render Righteousness for future day. Let us labor for salvation; On the
                            present it will tell; Add to every generation Something more, till all is well. Till the
                            work of God's completed, And a new relation given, Where the laws of life are meted With the
                            blessed peace of heaven. Keep thy calling, O Mount Zion ; Keep thine inner life secure ;
                            Draw the power thou canst rely on, To protect from the impure.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>Mary Whitcher, Canterbury, N. H.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My Father, I see where the error lies..." TEIform="index"/>My Father, I see where the error lies...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">My Father, I see where the error lies: It is in offering only half to Thee ; When all is
                            brought to win the highest prize, Thou wilt return a fullness unto me.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="W., M." TEIform="persName"/>M. W.</byline></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>