<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm0910" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title><editor role="editor" TEIform="editor"><persName reg="Lomas, G. A." TEIform="persName"/></editor></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><date value="18791001" TEIform="date">October 1879</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">217-240</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> OCTOBER, 1879. 60 Cents Per Annum MANIFESTO. (OFFICIAL MONTHLY.) G. A. LOMAS, Editoe. Published by the United
                        Societies. OUK HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony '' Go preach the Kingdom of God !
                        " ADDRESS ALL COMMUNICATIONS TO G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER. 1879. Vol. IX. } No. 10. j The Shaker " The Shaker
                        Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="217" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision" TEIform="index"/>A VISION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byrdsall, Charlotte" TEIform="persName"/>CHARLOTTE BYRDSALL</byline><p TEIform="p">I looked upon the wide, wide world, - Its anguish, and its woe, I saw the flood of human
                            wrath, With mighty current flow. I trembled, lest its strength might break, And flood the
                            earth once more, With fearful doom of olden plagues, With judgments as of yore. I asked in
                            faith — as if to glean One ray of living hope, How long ! how long ! will darkness rule And
                            souls within it grope ? O, Father ! lift the cloud of night, And let the day begin, Let
                            Freedom have her perfect work, And heroes to her win, Methinks I hear the throbbing ones,
                            That yet in bondage lie, My heart's pulsating knows a pause, Beneath the sufferer's cry. Are
                            not the nations ripe in death ? When will the sickle gleam ? Where the deliverance long
                            foretold ? Or is it but a dream? Where is the inspiration lyre, That sung of happier climes
                            ? Where are the prophets and the seers, That read the future times ? All silent are the
                            harps of old, And hushed the tuneful song ! But hark ! my spirit waiting, hears, A whisper,
                            low but strong. It tells me good is not afar, And truth is mighty still, The inner forces
                            gather strength, The darkened world to fill. The earth seems brightened to my gaze Her
                            children glad and free, I see the streams that frozen were, Gush forth in liberty. I hear
                            the sounds from other shores, Of happy heart and soul, Life's tide toward an equality,
                            Unbroken seems to roll. I see a wave of tender love, Sweep over land and sea, The white
                            robed angels cover all, With Christian purity. The altars that were dimmed by strife, With
                            varied offerings shine, Again the harps of holy joy Are tuned to peace divine. I see the
                            mystic power that turns, The river to its course, That stems the flood of human wrath, And
                            quells the breaking force. It is a brotherhood of love, Void of all creed and cant, It is a
                            sisterhood of peace, That might cannot supplant. It is not thraldom rule nor fear, That
                            brings this change of life. But lowliness to see and learn, The errors causing strife. Mount
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Progress of evolution" TEIform="index"/>THE PROGRESS OF EVOLUTION Read at the Grand Annual
                            Social Gathering at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Doolittle, Antoinette" TEIform="persName"/>ANTOINETTE DOOLITTLE</byline><p TEIform="p">I would salute all my brethren and sisters here assembled this morning with love, fervently
                            wishing that peace and fraternal feelings, such as belong to the family of Christ, may flow
                            from heart to heart on. the present occasion. We have been blest many times in coming to
                            this pleasant little spot, secluded from the gaze of those who revel in worldly pleasure and
                            worship at the shrine of fashion. Hither we come in simple, plain attire, bringing our
                            little gifts with us as love tokens to offer to our dear Gospe] companions—diamonds—though
                            small, yet not without luster and merit. Looking beyond the exterior, we find a soul in the
                            contributions here made, a substance of much that has been looked forward to in the
                            fulfillment of prophetic vision. We have planted and sowed in tribulation, in hope and in
                            faith, and in a spirit of thank <pb n="218" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 218 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. fulness we
                            acknowledge that the angels have watered, and God has blessed us with an increase. Centuries
                            have come and gone since the historic Jewish groves and altars, dedicated to idol worship,
                            and by decree of some inspired kings were cut down, broken in pieces and made as dust, while
                            the worshipers were humiliated in judgment. Days of mourning for such like idols, if they
                            ever existed with us, are ended. We are indebted to the law of evolution, which has wrought
                            industriously through all the ages to bring about changes, and progress the race from
                            barbarism to civilization, from idolatry to true Christian worship. Step by s»ep men and
                            women with true desires and holy aspirations have ascended the ladder which leads from low
                            to higher conditions of morals, science and religion. The pilgrim's path has been fraught
                            with danger, been steep and rugged, and not traveled without pain and difficulty.
                            Persecution's keen-edged sword impending over their heads caused them to seek shelter in
                            uninhabited deserts, in dens and caves and subterranean vaults, where myriads have finished
                            their course in time, and left the earth-caskets within those walled sepulchers to return to
                            dust, whence they came ; while their freed spirits arose, and on wings of the morning of a
                            new day sought home and friends in a better and purer clime than this sin-polluted sphere.
                            While in solitude, secluded alike from the world's persecution and its friendship, voices of
                            invisible beings whispered to listening souls that spirits were immortal and would one day
                            awake in a, celestial home, where sorrow and sighing would flee away and oppression cease.
                            Those voices are still heard; wheresoever we are, whispers come to us from the veiled and
                            unseen infinite, and our faith in the presence and perpetual active agency of spirits is
                            distinct and positive. If we do not exactly comprehend how they come, we feel their power,
                            and we know they visit us. Do we realize how much vye are indebted to those suffering
                            witnesses who have preceded us in the work of human emancipation from the thraldom of
                            ignorance and base passions ? They who were evidently chosen agents to co-operate with the
                            law of evolution, which is ever at work to roll onward the wheels of progress? Are we not
                            liable at times to look upon the law of evolution and its operations as an enemy rather than
                            a friend, when it causes great upheavals in society, in the physical, political, moral and
                            religious world ? Did we better understand the creative laws of the universe of mind and
                            matter, and the forces which give effect to those laws to hasten the world's growth and
                            prepare it for the harvest period, we might view it in a different light from what we now
                            do. Even the hand that bore the torchlight to kindle the persecutor's flame may have been
                            permitted under the same law in the dark ages to stimulate to action. Let us hope that the
                            perpetrators of those diabolical deeds, however bitter and relentless the spirit that
                            instigated them to torture heretics, may meet the same consideration in the final judgment
                            that the Jews received in the prayer of Jesus, when they led Him to the crucifix: " Father
                            forgive them, they know not what they do." Those words, as they fell from his lips, were
                            precious as "apples of gold." Can we too highly appreciate the auspices under which we have
                            met in this beautiful grove to-day ? Whence came this holy bond of union which holds us in
                            one brother and sisterhood, and enables us to gather around a communion table and enjoy such
                            a feast of good things at this time ? We are enabled not only to preserve our integrity, but
                            to increase the strength of pure gospel love and affection, purged from selfish alloy with
                            which worldly love is so interblended. Not alone by our own toils, self-denials, exertions
                            and prayers has it been attained; it is the product of the ages, the fruition of prophecy.
                            It is stated that the Essenes of olden time aspired to a life of holiness, to be pure and
                            unselfish, but were unable to resist the temptations presented to them by a marrying,
                            warring, pleasure-seeking world, and they sought seclusion in the mountain ranges, and
                            formed communities in large numbers, and there maintained the princi <pb n="219" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 219 pies of peace and celibacy. The world was then comparatively
                            young, and there was not strength to face its cold frowns, nor its alluring and deceptive
                            smiles. I am reminded on this occasion of one of the visions of St. John, who in spirit saw
                            '' an innumerable company that no man could number, of all nations and peoples ; they were
                            clad in white robes, bearing palms in their hands; and they bowed and worshiped God." In
                            answer to the query, " whence they came," it was said they "came out of great tribulation,
                            having washed their robes and made them white." I am impressed that could our interior
                            vision open upon the company of invisibles who have met with us to-day, we should behold
                            many ancient prophets and martyred saints of past centuries, as well as the disciples of
                            Jesus who lived in the first Christian dispensation, who saw in part and prophesied of the
                            good time coming, when the dual Christ in the order of male and female should stand upon
                            Mount Zion with a virgin band, singing a new song, which none others save the virgin
                            followers of the Lamb could learn. Will not those bright spirits rejoice with us and strike
                            their golden harps anew, and bear witness that " Now has come salvation and strength ? " The
                            suffering witnesses of God who have passed on to their reward, and who helped to cast up the
                            highway of truth, and gather out the stones that would impede the travel of those who should
                            come after them,would impress upon our minds today that it was their lot to " sow in tears,
                            ours to reap in joy." They make us welcome to our inheritance, and would enhance our joy.
                            This is not a myth—a phantom of the mind, it is real substance.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communism" TEIform="index"/>COMMUNISM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>EMILY OFFORD</byline><p TEIform="p">The subject of Communism is claiming the thoughts and attention of the thinking and suffering
                            classes of people at the present time, and great efforts are being put forth to solve the
                            problem of Co-operation, Socialism, and Communistic principles ; but, generally speaking, it
                            is more from a financial point of view, than from a religious basis. Those who inherit
                            wealth, and can live without labor, and are satiated with the things o.f this world, give
                            but little thought to the underlying causes of the great evils of society at large, and
                            become indolent in mind, as well as in body, and heed not the sufferings of the less
                            fortunate—the downtrodden and oppressed. It is a trite old maxim that " necessity is the
                            mother of invention," for we often see that deprivation, suffering, want and pain, serve to
                            awaken latent powers and energies of the human mind, and lead it to search out the true
                            causes which produce such baleful effects. Many who have lived under monarchical forms of
                            government, and have suffered under the iron rule of caste and class, have sought wiays and
                            means to ameliorate their condition, by combined effort in forming social and co-operative
                            communities. They are Indicators and give signs of progress in the right direction, and
                            point to a revival of the true pentecostal spirit which will lead those who possess temporal
                            wealtli to share with those who are needy, and to create one common fund—thus to form
                            Christian Communities based upon true principles and from higher motives, than of merely
                            supplying temporal needs—that of love to God and love to humanity, which would cause all to
                            toil together unselfishly, for the mutual wealth and happiness of each other, in spiritual,
                            as well as in temporal things. But so long as selfishness is the underlying principle that
                            prompts to action merely for the sake of aggrandizement and accumulating greater individual
                            wealth and power in the narrow domestic family relation, Communities will not be enduring.
                            They may prosper for a time—after having started with good and honest motives— but as
                            experience has shown, they soon pass away; the foundations are not right ; self
                            predominates, and some whirlwind of passion scatters and divides, and they fall back into
                            old conditions, each " seeking gain from his own quarter." Selfishness, the great leader and
                            controller of the human family, rules so completely, <pb n="220" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 220 THE SHAKEE
                            MANIFESTO. that virtue bends beneath her iron rod, and relinquishes reluctantly footholds in
                            her domains. This evil, so regnant in the human heart, has not only brought misery on
                            individuals, families and communities, but it has been the means of destroying cities, and
                            laying empires in ruins. It is inherent iii the king as well as the beggar. In order then
                            for people to live in harmonious social relation, this propensity must be subdued and the
                            higher law of love take control. This seems to be the solution of the question, that it is
                            not possible for those who merely live a natural, generative life, to attain to that
                            condition of unselfishness necessary for true communal relationship. Many have tried it, and
                            are still stri ving to have it prove successful; but failure seems to be stamped on the very
                            basis ef every attempt. That it is attainable by those who have progressed beyond the
                            prescribed limits of me and mine, and have a broader view of life than that which pertains
                            to the external; has already been satisfactorily proved by the founding and continuance of
                            Shaker societies during the past century. Through the revelation of heavenly principles, the
                            force of conviction, and patient perseverance in well doing, a simple, honesthearted people
                            have been gathered, supported and held together in a collective body; without a spiritual
                            basis they must have failed long ago. Human nature is weak and " prone to evil as the sparks
                            that fly upward;" then how futile on our part is every effort toward advancement in
                            spiritual light and truth, unless guided and supported by that overruling power which marks
                            our future destiny, and aids us in the work of subduing selfishness, and every evil
                            propensity. It is written that " where there is no vision the people perish." Then how
                            important that the interior soul senses should be quickened to a perception and acceptance
                            of those heavenly revelations from the inner spheres which God in love and mercy through His
                            faithful messengers may send. Frequent revivals of the religious element in the soul are
                            absolutely requisite to keep it alive in the gospel work, and to this end are the meetings
                            of Believers, Shakers, especially adapted. Their mode of worship is expressive of full
                            consecration of body, soul and spirit; and affords precious seasons for spiritual communion
                            with visible and invisible beings, holding the lower sensual elements in subjection, and
                            enlivening the higher and better part. Were it not for such seasons and revivals of
                            baptismal and pentecostal power Shaker societies would leaven back into worldly customs and
                            practices ; for these are the secret life-giving springs of our communal existence. Then,
                            how sacredly should they be held, how zealously improved, that we may draw strength from the
                            higher spheres, and gather a substance of good* that we may have something to impart to
                            hungry, truth-seeking souls, who will yet turn to Zion to partake with us of the heavenly
                            communion. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is true religion, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS TRUE RELIGION, NO. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p">True religion is love to God through love to man below. It is a baptism of soul life, a
                            sensitiveness to, and perception of righteousness so keen, bringing conviction for sin so
                            piercing as to turn the sinner short about into the heavenly road. It is a mirror, showing
                            to its possessor such a vision of his deformities as to take the self-conceit all out of
                            him. It is the law of truth graven by the finger of God on the tablet of the soul so
                            indelibly that the copy is ever revealed by the tongue. It is a light which peers into the
                            deep recesses of memory, and reveals, by the tongue of confession, deeds which have been
                            smothered for years or ages in the dust of deception and hypocrisy, and, perhaps, long
                            forgotten. It is an altar for sacrifice that answers by fire—the fire of truth—and blesses
                            the soul in its crucible by its refining process. It is a plough-share that breaks up the
                            fallow ground of the heart, and prepares the soil for the reception of the seeds of all the
                                <pb n="221" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 221 plants of grace and loveliness which
                            germinate in the garden of God. It is the sword of God that takes the carnal life of man,
                            and guards the entrance to the tree of life that stands in the Paradise of God. It is a new
                            birth, out of the worldly sphere into the Kingdom of Heaven. It is the fruit of the spirit,
                            food for hungering souls in every situation of need. It is garments of righteousness, a
                            clothing to the naked, a vesture of untarnished purity. It is the language of love,
                            refreshing as the evening dew, and gentle as the soft fall of a snow-flake, and charity that
                            never offends, nor wounds but to heal. It is sympathy so deep that it lays down one's life
                            for the good of humanity. It is affection so tender that it would cheerfully help to lift
                            the load of sorrow off the heart of a suffering pilgrim. It is benevolence that seeks out
                            the hungry and bestows food ; the naked, and clothes them ; the thirsty, and gives them to
                            drink of the wells of salvation. It is the power of God that turns the world upside down,
                            makes man a new creature—the compeer of the angels of God. Mount Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judgement of sin" TEIform="index"/>THE JUDGMENT OF SIN. NO TUTELARY DEITIES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eads, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER H. L. EADS</byline><p TEIform="p">Text-—For the Son of Man shall come in the glory of the Father, with His angels, and then He
                            shall reward every man according to his works.—Matt. xvi. 21. Before entering on the main
                            subject of my discourse, I will offer, by way of prelude, a few remarks concerning tutelary
                            deities. It would seem that some minds of ordinary intelligence have imbibed the idea that
                            there are grades of deities in the spirit world who are sent to this planet as occasion
                            requires, to occupy God's place in certain emergencies, while the Almighty absents Himself;
                            that is to say, when God finds His people too rebellious to be guided by Him He retires
                            after appointing a tutelary deity to occupy His place for the time being! Such ones cannot
                            see how imperfect counsels can come from Deity, and think in this way to exculpate Him Hence
                            we hear it said that the God of Israel was not the God of the universe, because we now see
                            that some of those counsels were not up with our present standard of perfection, by which
                            rule of judgment, if carried out, we should have a different God for all denominations of
                            people and exclude Deity from our planet ! Each denomination, however, would claim theirs to
                            be the true God and consider all others substituted, while it is the same God for each and
                            all, operating on their present unfolded conditions. It is even so in the smallest
                            animalcule, the lowest savage up to the highest archangel. There are some things which are
                            impossible to the Infinite, and one is, He cannot absent Himself from any point in space
                            without losing His infinity. Even Mahomet spoke truly when he said : " There is no God but
                            God. Will they give to God companion deities ? " The idea is heathenish and came from
                            heathen land. There can exist no such beings as tutelary deities in an independent sense. A
                            tutelary is a guardian, and it is unwarrantable to apply the term Deity to such, as Deity
                            signifies the attributes that constitute the Supreme Being. It is wholly unnecessary, as
                            some have contended, to have recourse to what they term tutelary deities, or God-appointed
                            Gods, to account for erroneous commands, passional display or defective counsels to God's
                            people. These can be accounted for in a much more reasonable way. It should be remembered
                            that the Infinite God of the universe does not operate retroactively upon any object,
                            spiritual nor material. He does not, as Professor Bush says, " roll up planets like ball. [I
                            quote from memory] and toss them from Himself as the child does his football." God is not
                            dependent on any thing to make known His will ; He has but one mode of operation. He
                            evolves, unfolds, within — peaks within the soul of man. The proof of this rests on the fact
                            that any other mode would involve retroaction and make him a dependent being. It discovers
                            NO INCONSISTENCY IN DEITY ; that what is given with the unfoldment of <pb n="222" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/>
                            222 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. to-day may be superseded to-morrow ; or that what is sinless with
                            the light of to-day may be sinful with the light of to-morrow. If we are faithful to listen
                            to and obey the monitions within, ours will be a perpetual increase in the light and
                            knowledge of God, because He operates on the unfolding of every day, every hour, every
                            minute and every second of our existence, so that in the passing of one moment it may be
                            sinful to repeat what was sinless a moment before. In this consists spiritual progression.
                            Today, if your highest light directs you to engage in generation, it were sinless to obey.
                            If at this instant your light increases, by the unfoldment of God's evoluting power, or by
                            the teaching of His agents, enabling you to see the beauties of the Christ-life of
                            regeneration, that it is a higher, more angelic and more godly condition, your duty then
                            calls you out of the world and former life into the new and superior condition, because now
                            to practice the old would be sinful, bring compunction and God's displeasure. If not, why
                            should the higher light ba given ? It is then clear that what may be sinless and right for
                            one person, or a body of persons, to-day, may at the same time be sinful to another person
                            or body of persons, without involving change, vacillation, or any inconsistency in Deity.
                            Finite beings only operate externally to, on and with each other. All words or sounds that
                            are, have been, or ever will be conveyed externally on waves of the vibrating atmosphere to
                            human ear, come, came, and will come from finite agencies or matter in motion. Who ever
                            hears spirit voices or sees spirit forms must first be spiritually conditioned to enable
                            them to do so. But spirits do speak by the organs of conditioned mediums and give us news
                            from beyond the vail. Normally the minds most unfolded in the body speak the more perfect
                            word to the less unfolded, while God is within them both. Hence by God's unfolding the
                            normal mind, and by inspirations from angels above, He has established His order, by
                            obedience to which ALL ARE BROUGHT INTO HARMONY with Him exactly in proportion as they
                            conform to it. Thus we see He has law and order in all things — order in the universe, order
                            in creation, order in the human race ¦— which order is His judgment seat, and by which
                            tribunal all have to be tried, judged and condemned, or acquitted. This "has been the case
                            in all past history, from Adam to Noah, to Abraham, to Moses, to John the Baptist, to Jesus,
                            to Ann Lee, in His second appearing. So that all the teachings of God's appointed agents,
                            which have been and are uninfluenced by the selfish animal or passional nature, have been
                            and are from God, and adapted to the state and unfolded condition of the race, which to obey
                            in the day and time given is to obey God and insure present harmony with Him, consequently
                            present peace and happiness. In the advanced stage of humanity many things would be defects
                            now that were not defects then, and many things, that now seem perfect and are best for the
                            present conditions may, in the future, be quite imperfect and even sinful. I repeat that God
                            cannot withdraw from any point in space at any moment. To say that a man or woman, or a
                            people, is or are God-forsaken, does not mean that Deity is absent, but God, for the time
                            being, ceases to strive with those who persist in disobedience— disregarding the monitions
                            of conscience. It may be said of such that God has withdrawn or left such ones to reap the
                            reward of their disobedience. Still " God is present everywhere, beholding the evil and the
                            good." " He warms in the sun, refreshes in the breeze, Glows in the stars and blossoms in
                            the trees, Lives thro' all life, extends thro' all extent, Spreads undivided and operates
                            unspent." Should we deny, as some do, that the God of the universe was the God of typical
                            Israel, we in the same breath and for the same reason, deny that He is the God of the
                            Shakers, or that He has been at work in man from Adam to our day, or is at work in His Zion
                            now. On the same grounds He is denied of one He is denied of all. If our God is the God of
                            the universe, and Israel's God was not, there could be no agreement between law and gospel —
                            type and antitype, and we should thus limit Him, who is unconditioned as to space, and
                            therefrom omnipresent, and unconditioned as to time, and therefore eternal and unchangeable.
                                <pb n="223" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. 223 THAT GOD IS OMNIPRESENT and
                            unchangeable, all philosophers of note affirm. Locke says : " Motion cannot be attributed to
                            God, because He is infinite spirit." But all nations and all peoples, by their greatest
                            minds, unite on one invisible, omnipotent, omnipresent and unchangeable Deity, and, how much
                            soever atheistic infidels strive to doubt, there is a force and power that make them realize
                            the fact that there is a cause of their being and of their intelligence and for the
                            existence of the harmonious universe ; and the power within that forces this confession must
                            be the operation of that inexplicable something that the world calls God. If then we
                            predicate, as we are forced to do, unchangeability of this ever present Deity operating
                            within it becomes impossible for Him to operate directly on objects from without. Without
                            and within are contradictory. This, then, being impossible, it follows that He cannot
                            focalize Himself external to man, ascend a great white throne and occupy a judgment seat,
                            hear evidence for and against and acquit or condemn the human race. Hence the great day of
                            judgment so much spoken of by pulpit orators, at which time the infinite God is to sit as
                            Judge, becomes an impossibility. But " the Son of Man shall come with His angels " for this
                            purpose. Christ Himself gave us the key to unlock the mystery of the judgment when He said
                            to His disciples : " Whosoever sins ye remit, they are remitted unto them ; and whosoever
                            sins ye retain, they are retained." —John xx, 23. This, then, was God's judgment seat, and
                            verifies God's order before spoken of. It is now His judgment seat, for God will not have
                            two j udgment seats, and the great judgment day will come to each one " in the twinkling of
                            an eye." It follows from this that Deity alone cannot forgive sin. Why ? Don't be startled.
                            Because He has established an order among finite beings for that purpose, and being
                            changeless, He will not disestablish it. Hence no souls can be fully and finally forgiven
                            nntil they have found God's order and come to His judgment there. It becomes a matter of
                            importance, then, to each and all to seek until they find this order, if such order has an
                            existence. But this does not deny THE PRESENCE OF THE SAME GOD in all sects and
                            denominations to whom invocations are made and worship is given. But their name is legion
                            who '' ask and receive not, because they ask amiss that they may consume it upon their
                            lusts." — James iv, 3. If sin can be forgiven as well and as fully by God witliout His order
                            as with it, the order would then be useless; but all history shows that God has ever had His
                            order for the time being among men. His final order for full restoration is in Christ, both
                            in His first and second appearing. To this order and seat of judgment all must bow, of
                            angels or men. Here at this throne of judgment, all mountains sink and valleys rise (the
                            high and low are brought on a level), forming " as it were a sea of glass mingled with fire,
                            and them that had gotten the victory over the beast and over his image, and over his mark,
                            and over the number of his name stand on the sea of glass (all on a perfect level), having
                            the harps of God." — Rev. xv, 2. This order of God was the sign seen in Heaven by the
                            revelator, when all the high and lofty, the Kings, Queens, lords, ladies and gentlemen,
                            stand on a level with the lowest peasant. All such as come to this seat of judgment in time
                            " their sins go beforehand into judgment" and " their sins and iniquities, saith God, will I
                            remember no more." — Heb. x, 17. How merciful is God! But I hear it said: If I cease from
                            disobevinar God and of committing sins which I have been guilty of, what good can it do for
                            me to make them known to another? Answer. It is impossible for them to be forgiven until the
                            forgiving power knows what they are. God has established the seat of judgment and appointed
                            the Judge, who is the light of the world, to whom the deeds must be brought, and your
                            disturbed harmony can never be restored without doing so. Still if you so elect, you may
                            cease committing certain sins and carry them concealed in your bosom for years, employ your
                            talents in God's service, be respected and loved, yet to this light they must finally be
                            exposed, or complete salvation will be unattainable. God has settled this question. <pb n="224" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 224 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Tlie truth of this is based not duly on the
                            Scriptures, but on the predicate acknowledged by all of the stability and unchangeability of
                            God, and there is NO WAY OF EVADING IT any more than there is of dodging the tomb. Black as
                            are your sins, to this light they must finally be exposed, and, though we cease to commit
                            them, those that remain unconfessed will be leaden weights on the soul; besides, " He that
                            covereth his sins shall not prosper, but whoso confesseth and forsaketh them shall find
                            mercy." (Prov. xxviii, 13.) If covered sin in one individual prevents his prosperity, what
                            will it be to a family or body where there are ten, twenty, fifty or one hundred and fifty
                            out of two hundred that have sins of any kind willfully covered ? They may mingle together
                            and come and go and walk and talk and sing and pray and work and play and eat and sleep, but
                            spiritual prosperity for such family is impossible. To prosper such body spiritually is an
                            impossibility with God. But if they confess and forsake they shall find mercy, they shall
                            find prosperity. Now, I defy the whole world of religion, philosophy, reason or logic to
                            disprove the conclusion arrived at on the judgment seat of God, while admitting Deity to be
                            omnipresent and changeless. I do not say it boastingly, but to fasten it as with steel
                            rivets on the mind. Let me still make it plainer. Any sin committed by an individual, secret
                            or otherwise, destroys the harmony between him and God, his maker. Heaven is lost; but a
                            merciful God has established the plan by which this harmony can be restored. If, through
                            weakness or want of watchfulness, a sin should be committed, compunction follows. If God
                            without, in the visible order, be ignorant of the transgression, God within knoweth and
                            reproacheth, and the soul finds no abiding peace until repentance is found and confession is
                            made in God's appointed order — restoration made and satisfaction given to an injured party,
                            if any. When this is done, forgiveness and acceptance are obtained, and the broken harmony
                            is again restored, both in the visible and invisible relation, because they are blended — "
                            their wings touch each other." When the soul has done this, God Himself, and heaven, and
                            angels can require no more. The sin is forgiven. THESE VISIBLE AGENTS OF GOD, perfect in one
                            sense, imperfect in another, always teaching as they are taught of God, according to their
                            unfoldment and powers of receptivity, do administer to those below them; thus, what the
                            finite does the infinite does — simply because it is His operation on their highest
                            unfoldment. So it has been, so it is now, and so it ever will be through all time and
                            eternity — men and angels always approximating, but never reaching, the entirety of the
                            infinite; ever having the great God to worship and adore; themselves changing from bad to
                            good, to better, while God remains changeless. Thus agent after agent, in all the cycles of
                            time, with greater unfoldment of additional light, will teach as they are taught of God ;
                            and thus, instead of having God absent, we do away with independent tutelaries and foreign
                            Christs, and so preserve reason, consistency and truth. It is improper to say God permeates
                            all things as light permeates glass. This would imply change and retroaction, which are
                            denied ; but He is in all things, " as perfect in a hair as heart." But should it be
                            insisted that God operates from without externally on objects, like men and angels do, by
                            sound or otherwise, this would place Him under necessity. He would then have need of
                            atmospheric air or other medium to convey His word and will, and His infinity would thus be
                            destroyed. Again, if He has the external action and is omnipotent, this would obviate the
                            necessity of any agent or order either with men or angels on earth or in heaven. He would be
                            all-sufficient. But that such external order and agents do exist and have existed — are and
                            have been appointed and commissioned from the earliest history of the world —is proof
                            positive that God does not operate externally ; and since He does not, herein lies the
                            absolute necessity of a visible order and seat of judgment, and confirms the declaration
                            that all ex- <pb n="225" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKEE MANIFESTO. 225 ternal operations are those of
                            finite agencies, either spirit or mortal. This point, then, I think, is proved. I am still
                            asked, how are we to know that such and such agents are God-appointed? That is just what
                            cavilers said to Christ — "Is not this Jesus, whose father and mother we know ? " — John vi,
                            42; and " Master, we would have a sign from Thee." But He answered and said: " An evil and
                            adulterous generation seeketh after a sign, and there shall no sign be given it." I would
                            say, let their life and testimony be the sign. If they ask you to vary from the. life of
                            Christ, you need not obey ; but if they ask you to live the Christ life, and you will do it,
                            you will not want a sign. Persons finding the visible order of God, and seeing His
                            attributes externally manifested by finite agents to them and to the world in a higher
                            degree than they have attained to, who, through pride or any of the lower impulses, refuse
                            to acknowledge, yield to and be led by it, are foolish indeed. This would be trifling away
                            their day, call and opportunity. But still more foolish are those who, having seen, blended
                            with and "tasted of the good things of God and the powers of the world to come" [Heb. vi, 4]
                            revealed to them in and through the visible order, turu their backs upon it because their
                            ideal of perfection is not found in it, constitute themselves judges, and say: " Who is
                            Moses ? Are not all God's people holy?" The same that existed in the type appears in the
                            substance, as some even of authority say of the anointed Lead: " Who are they more than
                            others ? Are not others as good as they? Does not the Christ-spirit dwell in and administer
                            to all the good ? I do not believe in one worm of the dust bowing before another worm of the
                            dust " — forgetting the gracious words of Mother Ann Lee, who, when some would do her
                            reverence, said: " It is not me you love, but God in me." The mere persons of the anointed
                            first Lead neither want nor deserve more reverence than other persons equally good. But God,
                            in His order visible, must be reverenced or the invisible God will not accept your
                            reverence. So it will be wasted adoration. The Apostle Paul says it is impossible to renew
                            such to repentance, because they have crucified to themselves the Son of God afresh and put
                            Him to open shame. Heb. vi, 6. Such ones, at least, prepare themselves for the earth
                            (earthly nature) to open her mouth and swallow them up, though in tears and mourning, as was
                            done in the type. They seem not to realize the fact that to reject the visible is also to
                            reject the invisible and leave them without hope in this or any other world! They may look
                            up and strive to see the great God in whom they trust, but this sight is only RESERVED FOR
                            THE PURE IK HEART, few as they are, and these can only see Him in the spirit faces and life
                            of His order of appointed agents and people. So, let the " exalted imagination " come down
                            and look for God where He may be seen — where He is pleased to manifest Himself. I repeat
                            again, here is His judgment seat before which all must bow, of angels or men —. for it is
                            impossible that a changeless God should establish an order of judgment with exceptions to
                            it. So, then, it follows that obedience to this order when found is man's only chance for
                            full redemption. I cannot too often repeat that it is impossible for a changeless Infinite
                            Being to focalize and show Himself external to man, only as He is pleased to reveal Himself
                            through the finite. " They that have seen Me," said Christ, "have seen the Father " — seen
                            the attributes of the Father manifested to them. By seeing Christ they did not see the
                            Infinite wholeness. This, Christ Himself, never saw, nor ever will see. " No man hath seen
                            God at any time, the only begotten Son, who is in the bosom of the Father, He hath declared
                            Him." — John i, 18. But Christ was His judgment seat; after Him His disciples were — "All
                            that my Father hath given me have I given them;" next, " The saints shall judge the world "
                            — 1 Cor. i, 2; " For behold the Lord cometh in myriads of His saints to execute judgment
                            upon all, and to convince all that are ungodly amongthemof all their ungodly deeds which
                            they have ungodly committed, and of all their hard speeches which ungodly sinners have
                            spoken" —¦ <pb n="226" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 226 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. Jude 14 and 15 ; " and the
                            kingdom and dominion and the greatness of the Kingdom under the whole heaven shall be given
                            to the people of the saints of the Most High;" "and the judgment was set and the books were
                            opened."—Dan. vii, 10 and 27. Do not now, with Pope, begin to doubt saying: ------"I know
                            The saints must merit God's peculiar care, But whom but God can tell us who they are!''
                            "Seek and ye shall find; knock and it shall be opened unto you." — Matt, vii, 7. "For the
                            time is come that judgment must begin at the. house of God, and if it first begin at us,
                            what shall be the end of them that obey not the Gospel of God ? " — 1 Peter iv, 17. Thus
                            have I shown you from sacred writ what the judgment is, and what its purposes are. I have
                            also shown you that it accords with philosophy, reason, logic and sound sense—have made it
                            plain to the common and uncommon understanding. I have shown that God cannot forgive your
                            sins without confession, and that to His visible order. Then, as you value your soul,
                            hesitate not, but come at once to the judgment that your "sins may be blotted out," and the
                            angel life attained to in this world. Lo, then, let all who hear—let all who read this in
                            any part of the world, of any nation, kindred or tongue—consider themselves invited to come,
                            with a life insurance in God's kingdom on earth. All that are sick of the world and world of
                            sin, all who desire a higher and better life than the world affords, all who feel that they
                            have a soul to be saved or lost, all, all may consider themselves invited. Are you a King,
                            or are you a Queen? Consider yourselves invited. Are you Emperor or Empress, or President,
                            statesman or lawyer, doctor or religionist of any denomination? You are invited. Are you
                            rich, or are you poor ? Are you male or female, white, black or yellow ? You are invited to
                            come. The gates stand ajar waiting your arrival. Come to a merciful judgment, and it will
                            soon be known whether you are a fit subject for a seat in the kingdom. " Come now, let us
                            reason together," saith the Lord. " Though your sins be as scarlet, they shall be white as
                            snow • though they be red like crimson, they shall be white as wool. If ye be willing and
                            obedient, ye shall eat the good of the land."—Isa. i, 18,19. Come now, " consult not with
                            flesh and blood." Are you married ? " Come, let your eyes be made single that your bodies
                            may be full of light, for while it is evil (double), the body is full of darkness." — Luke
                            xii, 34. Are you single ? Come, that you may be married to Christ. Are you athirst? Come,
                            partake of the waters of life, freely and live. Come, I say again, to God's merciful
                            judgment, for know ye of a certainty that at some time every one of you must be judged for
                            the ''deeds done in the body, whether they be good or whether they be evil." "For the Son of
                            Man shall come in the glory of the Father with His angels, and then He will reward every man
                            according: to his works." Amen !</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cursedness of war" TEIform="index"/>THE CURSEDNESS OF WAR And The Good Time Coming</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON</byline><p TEIform="p">I looked across the desert wastes of life, The world's great field of carnage, blood and
                            strife, And thought of all the treasure turned to dross; The dire affliction brought through
                            human loss ; The homes made desolate, the brokenheart, The bitter woe where ties were rent
                            apart ; The mental wealth that all the world should bless, Spent on the worst of crime and
                            wickedness ; The springs of love turned back unto their source, And streams of hate pursuing
                            in their course; O tide of life ! how dark thy currents flow, Black as the stygian waves
                            that roll below; When nobler impulse yield her sweet control, And war's stern passion
                            overcomes the soul; Fair history's page through all the years of time, Was stained with
                            darkened deeds of heinous crime ; The lusts of men engendered low desire. And filled their
                            hearts with war's insatiate fire ; Thus love of power in vain ambition's van, Ne'er heeds
                            the sacred rights of fellowman ; But in her conquest overrules all right, <pb n="227" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKES MANIFESTO. 227 By force of strength, supremacy of might; Thus
                            kingdoms rise and hold the reins of power, Thus empires glory but for one short hour ; Their
                            prestige gone, they crumble into dust; Because not based on laws exact and just. Oheroes
                            vain! the laurels that ye wear — The boasted name and honors that ye bear— Came through the
                            orphans' tears, the widows' pain, The moans and cries of those in battle slain , The time
                            will come when only he who stands, With courage fortified, and outstretched hands; To fight
                            all giant wrongs, and meet man's needs, With honest words, and love's heroic deeds; W'ill be
                            the hero of immortal fame, And in the nation's heart hold dear his name. The right! the
                            right! I see it grandly rise, Triumphant o'er the world's great sacrifice ; Sustained by
                            justice, linked to truth's great cause; It teaches men to frame diviner laws, Than those
                            which now appeal to instincts base, The laws that elevate and bless the race ; And peace
                            angelic spreads her snowy wings €rlad tidings to this blighted earth she brings ;
                            Proclaiming in her heaven-commissioned flight, " Forever fled is error's ebon night." The
                            day has dawned whose brightness has no bound, Whose golden circle shall the earth surround ;
                            'Till every nation, kindred, tribe and clan, Shall learn to love in truth, their brother man
                            ; Then navies with their whitened sails unfurled, Shall bear the commerce of a busy world ;
                            And forts and arsenals be turned to marts, Where industry her peaceful life imparts; For
                            peace and labor clasp fraternal hands, And justice in their counsel chamber stands; No war
                            to scourge, no poverty to blight, Love rules by the eternal lawof right. Not dreams Utopian
                            bring this vision grand ! Upon the mount of prospect now I stand ; And see the world
                            progressing to that end, Where all in unity and peace shall blend ; When governments shall
                            seek each nation's good, Thus form a universal brotherhood. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="United States church" TEIform="index"/>"THE UNITED STATES CHURCH."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Overton, C. M." TEIform="persName"/>C. M. OVERTON</byline><p TEIform="p">When you have a vehement desire to convert some creature, you must remember that may be God
                            has reserved his right of illuminating the poor fellow's mind. We learn that there is an
                            organization with the above name at Joliet, 111., a woman ¦—"Rev. Buffam" being pastor or
                            godmother — having felt for a long time that there was need of an inner organization whose
                            function should be to assist the Republic to a realization of her own ideal (and that the
                            Shaker Church would in some way supply that need), I sent a note to Rev. Buffum. Getting in
                            reply no hint of Creed, Catechism, nor Constitution, I am left to gather what I may from
                            surface indications as to the " true inwardness " of the institution. And I find myself
                            wondering how any one who has brains enough to conceive the idea of an American Church,
                            should not also see that such a church could have no use for a " Reverend," as a prefix. The
                            penchant of girls (and savages) for gewgaws is understood; but why should a woman essay such
                            indulgences ! The editor of the Index once said : " My name is Francis E.Abbott." And he
                            warned the knights of the paste-pot : " Paste no bills on my premises or person." Not even
                            for a shilling an hour would he advertise his own piety by walking the streets labeled "
                            Reverend." Beecher, when the dignitaries appended to his name a " D. D.," cried out: " Hang
                            none of your pinchback on my nose. Some of the brethren might value it. But you don't'
                            Mister ' a Washington. And please remember that a Beecher's name ' when unadorned is adorned
                            the most.' " Whether as aristocrats or democrats, from pride or principle, contempt for
                            mediocrity, sham and shoddy, or reverence for manhood, men of sense and character choose to
                            stand on their own merits. While women — I beg pardon of the whole sex — a woman bows her
                            head to receive the cast-off honors, placards her own pretensions, and bears them aloft with
                            her own hands. I hardly know what emotion befits this case. As to the army of male
                            Reverends, I know them as the enemies of my country and my race, I know them as the enemies
                            of all reforms, the foes of progress and en- <pb n="228" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 228 THE SHAKEK
                            MANIFESTO. lightenment. I know them as the supporters of slavery, physical, mental,
                            spiritual ; the natural allies of despotism, the defenders of aristocracy, caste, and
                            privilege. The men who always stone the prophets and crucify the christs. I know them as
                            traitors who are now plotting to rob this government of its chief virtues — men whom the
                            Republic will have to crush, or die. But this feminine pretender, with no following to
                            awaken a fear for human liberty, one cannot be indignant and dare not be amused ; for this
                            were uncourteous. Being philosophical he cannot despise any thing. We could be pardoned a
                            contempt of court, if we knew that the court was contemptible. But how can we know but that
                            that title, reverend, was assumed on purpose to bring the whole thing into ridicule! Assumed
                            in a vein of exquisite irony, a monkey or a king's fool might take the cap or the crown of
                            his master and clapping it on his head cry out: " Now take a look at your, self, old fellow
                            ! " Till we know the motive to this coronation, we cannot know whether this " Reverend "
                            woman is a friend or a foe — whether the world has gained a savior, or Illinois has lost a
                            lunatic. Poised thus on the sharp edge of suspense, torn by conflicting emotions, I am at a
                            loss to know how I ought to be exercised in this case. Will not "Reverend" Buffum rise and
                            explain that ornamental frontispiece of hers, and oblige. North Union, 0.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak kindly to the erring" TEIform="index"/>SPEAK KINDLY TO THE ERRING</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, Oliver" TEIform="persName"/>OLIVER PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">" And it repented the Lord that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him at the
                            heart."—Gen. 6-6. " Though he were a Son, yet learned he obedience by the things which he
                            suffered." —Heb. 5-8. Passing reverently by the Gods, we will say, and speak advisedly : If
                            the damned in hell are ever lifted to higher planes of being, it will be by words of
                            kindness and confidence reposed. In my three score and 21 years' acquaintance with humanity,
                            I have not met the man so debased, so degraded, that kindness would not vivify the (germ of
                            divinity in his make-up — his birthright inheritance. The apostle James, Gov. Seymour, and
                            others, have made the sublime discovery that " the wrath of man worketh not the
                            righteousness of God." lit. Lebanon, _ZV. T.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True source of happiness" TEIform="index"/>TRUE SOURCE OF HAPPINESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>ANNA WHITE</byline><p TEIform="p">It is almost universally admitted that there never was a period in the world's history, when
                            the desire to travel somewhere — to see something new, was so great as at the present time.
                            It seems to be the ruling spirit, almost amounting to a mania. Homes are broken up thereby,
                            and parents and children, old and young, wander the wide world o'er in quest of happiness.
                            No matter to what inconvenience they may be subjected, go they must. It is the fashion to
                            travel, as much as it is to compress the waist and lungs — so as to resemble a wasp as much
                            as possible — and nonconformity thereto is simply out of the question. The rising
                            generation, in a particular manner, are not satisfied to remain at the old homestead (if
                            fortune has favored them with one) after the rigid Puritanic system, and learn of their
                            parents the practical lessons of life. They chafe under restraint, and shirk duties and
                            responsibilities, that would otherwise serve to develop them into man and womanhood. Manual
                            labor, among aristocratic people, is counted undignified — menial — unless it be some light,
                            genteel employment. Such have an eye to (so-called) refinement in a degree that is painfully
                            distressing; and this idea culminates in uninterestedness and idleness, that create unrest
                            and dissatisfaction ; hence the desire to roam over land and sea, from continent to
                            continent, ever seeking but never finding happiness. There is "no effect without a cause."
                            The foundations of society are out of course, and as it now exists is full of festering
                            sores, that breais out in family broils, that often terminate in <pb n="229" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 229 murder, suicide and unnumbered evils, that gnaw like a canker worm at
                            the very vitals of society. True, there are noble-hearted, pure-minded men and women, who
                            are striving by reformatory efforts to avert those evils ere they deluge the land from pole
                            to pole. Shakers are called to stand upon an eminence, overlooking all those unrestful,
                            unholy and dissatisfied conditions ; but they are so nearly allied to the outside world,
                            that whatever spirit rules there, always affects them more or less. Hence, many at the
                            present time urge the necessity of traveling for health. We all admit that change
                            occasionally is conducive to health; but traveling over dusty highways, and in illventilated
                            cars, and sleeping in beds, and rooms, devoid of home comforts and cleanliness, perhaps is
                            not the surest way to attain it. According to recent sanitary reports, the popular hotels in
                            many country places should be subject to inspection, as well as densely packed tenement
                            houses in cities. Report says : " People leave the cities for country resorts in blissful
                            unconsciousness that undrained soil, polluted water, and festering cesspools, will in all
                            probability be found the sure adjuncts of rural life and delights. When they return to the
                            city, bearing the seeds of malaria, their eyes will doubtless be opened and the reflection
                            may occur, that going into the country is an expensive and dangerous luxury." Many places
                            even on the sea-shore, once favorite resorts, are now deserted ; for they had become
                            hot-beds of disease. Visiting among Believers is profitable, if ordered aright ; because it
                            enhances the happiness of both parties, and cements the cords of love and gospel affection,
                            lasting long after the spirit has fled from its earthly tabernacle. The security that one
                            feels, too, in treading on consecrated soil, and partaking of the fruits of consecrated
                            labor, gives rest, recuperates the body, and yields real soul-happiness and pleasure. The
                            pure union existing between gospel brethren and sisters of the spiritual household of faith,
                            is precious and heavenly; and is unequaled by any of the relationships of earth, that have
                            been, or can be produced; but an unregenerate human heart is always in danger; and, if not
                            wholly "crucified to the world," will be more or less subject to its pressure. We sometimes
                            hear the expression (from the lips of a few), " We want to have a good social time,
                            unrestricted ! " Unrestricted from what?" Why, the very thing that holds together the walls
                            of our spiritual edifice. Union that amounts to undue familiarity, bears the sting of a
                            serpent and the poison of an adder. Therefore, the union of Believers — sweet and sacred as
                            it is— is only safe when under the restriction and guidance of gospel order and religious
                            discipline ; for this cause I rejoice to meet with gospel kindred, and to greet them always
                            with blessing and love.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker blessings" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER BLESSINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Elvah" TEIform="persName"/>ELVAH COLLINS</byline><p TEIform="p">Full of the sweets of heaven are the hours of enjoyment spent in this first Temple of God,
                            where blessings fall at our feet like a shower of dew-drops, filled with nectar; the soul of
                            which steals into the chambers of our hearts, and frames pictures upon its walls for the eye
                            of the inner being, and of thought to revert to, in the ever-existing future. Much has been
                            written, sung and spoken of the beauties that surround us- but I have never before taken
                            such deep sense of our Heavenly Father's and Mother's care, and interest in the happiness of
                            their children, as are here manifest. The pillars of the grove, with their shading foliage,
                            the welcome zephyrs that play upon the leaves and branches, fanning our brows and kissing
                            our cheeks with a fairy touch, the emerald carpet that bends to the silent tread of
                            foot-steps, have all been brought to mind and expatiated upon through a countless round of
                            years; and yet they have never lost their beauty, nor failed to throw a charm over the mind;
                            as in the past, so will be the future, and so is the ever present: for with every revolution
                            of time, cometh an inspiration—-an adaptation of feelings and senses—to enjoy every season
                            as it rolls to us in the unending circle of life. But best and sweetest of all, that which
                                <pb n="230" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 230 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. makes our gathering together pleasant,
                            is the union and relation that we hold; angelic in nature, because founded and perpetuated
                            in principles unchanging, notwithstanding the cup of human life is ever giving and ever
                            receiving time's rollingHow striking the contrast between our associations together, and
                            social life sustained the world over, where self-interests are the subject predicate; the
                            object of each one striving to build his own house with the timbers of another's. " If we
                            have not love for each other when in daily communion, how can we love God whom we have not
                            seen " Deep affection, spontaneous in our hearts, is the stimulus to our efforts for the
                            happiness of each other. As every thing outward must correspond to the inward, it affords
                            real pleasure, on occasions like-the present, to witness the grand outgrowth of the truths
                            that have come to us through true and dear friends (martyrs to the cause), and have taken so
                            many forms that meet the approval of conscience, and of our highest reason. The simplicity
                            of our costume modestly rebukes the extravagance heaped upon diseased human deformities,
                            that flutter like butterflies from flower to flower (promised pleasure), for sweets that
                            prove bitter and unsatisfactory; while the plainness of speech that should and does flow
                            from the lips of a Believer, has more weight of power, more keenness of penetration—a few
                            heart-felt words, than many more elaborate productions on paper, or uttered by occupants of
                            velvet-cushioned pulpits, whose smooth and honeyed words (many times the antipodes of words
                            used in private), can ever have. Often words thus uttered are a mockery of God and truth.
                            So, also, with the customs and habits of Zion's children, when compared to the confusion,
                            disorder and filthiness of worldly habits ; the order and cleanliness throughout our
                            borders, when contrasted, appear as the light of heaven on one side, and the darkness of
                            hades on the other, formirg a chasm too wide to bridge over by compromise, and retain intact
                            the principles of virtue that create the difference. Purity of life, the rock upon which our
                            feet are planted with decision, sends its magnetic power through soul and body ; and from
                            thence its emanations go forth to all around, a blessing to lovers of purity, or a reproof
                            to the sin-loving. How can a tree, receiving its vitality from so divine a source, fail to
                            yield the abundance of golden fruit which we are daily gathering from its branches? No wars
                            at large, nor petty feuds find place within the precincts of our hallowed homes. No reeling
                            drunkard disgraces the paths we are wont to walk, nor evil-doer allowed to devise dark
                            deeds, nor to shoot the poisoned arrow that would wound a brother. Should not these
                            reflections unseal new fountains of gratitude in our souls, that there are some spots on
                            earth that God has retained in His own keeping, to represent His Order, and the revelation
                            of His goodness to lost humanity ? It is ours to increase the " little stone cut out of the
                            mountain without hands," till it shall become a mountain of itself, so vast, that it may be
                            a central home for all nations, peoples and kindred, when God shall gather His own. It is
                            ours to stand upon the towers, and wait, and watch the advance of truth in its onward march;
                            to scan the old heavens and trace the many meteors and shooting stars, that give light—for a
                            season, then to fall from their orbit to rise no more. We see and feel the struggles of
                            suffering souls, who toil single-handed to put down wrong, and establish reforms in the many
                            by-paths where sin is the "golden calf" set up, unto which thousands bow in menial
                            servitude. It is ours to bless every worker in a good cause even though we see that the evil
                            cannot be banished till the root is reached, and the cause put away. Dear young friends, let
                            us so live that nothing shall dim the lights we hold in our hands ; but let them so shine
                            that they may gleam across dark waters, and guide some poor brother or sister struggling
                            with the billows on time's troubled ocean, seeking a haven of peace and happiness, where
                            there is rest for the weary. In this labor I would devote my little all in the spirit of
                            true love which comes from <pb n="231" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 231 above ; knowing
                            that if I sow a few grains, God will increase, even to a hundred fold ; and the fruits of my
                            harvest will more than repay for a few years of patient waiting.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Religious freedom" TEIform="index"/>RELIGIOUS FREEDOM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Berger, Sarah Jane" TEIform="persName"/>SARAH JANE BERGER</byline><p TEIform="p">In ancient Persia, the people were held under the rule of a despotic and tyrannical
                            government, whose laws were unalterable. Having control of the religious element, its power
                            was strong. Mere difference of opinion often created holy wars, wherein thousands were
                            slain, and many, falling victims to the caprice of the monarch, were put to some horrible
                            death, because they would not bow down to the national objects of worship. Thus it was with
                            Daniel and the three Hebrew children, who, by the interposition of divine power, escaped,
                            unharmed, from great dangers, though they would have suffered martyrdom, rather than disobey
                            their highest ideal of right. But Daniel's integrity and uprightness favorably impressed the
                            king-—and through his influence, the religion of the government was modified. And thus we
                            see it has been with Catholicism. It has assumed the control of church and state, wherever
                            it has obtained a foothold. Rome is its great central power, and in the Papal head is vested
                            supreme authority Its wonderful spread, in days of its early history, was mainly due to
                            physical force and barbaric cruelty, as its wars and inquisitions fully attest. England was
                            formerly under its rule. Protestantism, too, has had its phase of tyranny and injustice,
                            especially when it combined church and state. The Quakers were martyrs under the cruel
                            treatment of the exponents of its credal faith. The Shakers, also, suffered under its
                            persecuting spirit, till they were obliged to seek refuge under the prospective flag of
                            American freedom, which was not fully unfurled until after the Eevolution and the
                            Declaration of Independence. And not until they had felt the persecuting power Of its
                            religious organizations, were they permitted to live in peace and enjoy the rights of
                            conscience. So we pee, through all history, that might, and not right, has ruled the nations
                            of the earth. The struggle of the Israelites, to get free from Egyptian bondage, is an
                            experience that has been repeated, in many forms, since that ancient day. Governments usurp
                            power that does not rightly belong to them — power to control the minds, or souls, of the
                            people. Waves recede to dash with greater force against the rocks. And so with this our
                            Government, founded upon the grand principles of human rights and equality, the tide of
                            religious bigotry, had it the power, would again sweep away all its battlements of strength
                            and submerge it into a church and state institution. But, will not those who love their
                            consecrated liberties, given them by Infidel founders, rise in indignation against such evil
                            machinations ? What we want is freedom of speech, of the press, and liberty of conscience
                            continued to all. So long as America exists, let her be " the land of the free and the home
                            of the brave " — a refuge and asylum for the oppressed of all nations — and may the state be
                            governed by noble men and women, in whose hearts reign justice and peace, regardless of any
                            religious tenet or creed. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="science" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Stars" TEIform="index"/>THE STARS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy" TEIform="persName"/>LUCY BOWERS</byline><p TEIform="p">What and where are the stars ? Who can tell ? A child is reported as saying: " They are
                            gimlet-holes to let the glory through," Another as saying : " If the wrong side of heaven is
                            so beautiful, what must the right side be?" More orthodoxy here than philosophy. Astronomy —
                            sun, moon and stars — has been the study and admiration of many minds for ages. Long before
                            the Christian era, there were wise men, who, by their pro- <pb n="232" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 232 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. found learning1 and lofty virtues, gathered many disciples and founded
                            schools in which astronomy was taught, discoveries and in" yentions made — some true, and
                            some false — yet all, in degree, adding to the wealth of human knowledge. Thales, a
                            philosopher, more than 500 years before Jesus, by his study of astronomy, calculated
                            accurately a solar eclipse. Pythagoras traced the true solar system, and, in later days,
                            Copernicus, based upon the simple ideas of the latter, removed, after twenty years'
                            investigation, from the machine of the universe, the cycles and epicycles of former
                            astronomers, and placed the sun in the center to illumine and control the whole. And many
                            others, known to us through history, have made pleasant and instructive observations. By the
                            Gree ks the stars were named, and worshiped as Gods. But mythology wraps them in obscurity
                            and seeming lack of truth. To the poetic, inquiring mind, the overhanging vault is filled
                            with myriads of richly-invested forms and hidden wisdom, which penetrate, with viewless
                            track, the limitless space beyond. And eye hath not ceased to see, ear to catch the thought
                            conceived in silence, nor mind to comprehend the glowing life shown in its changeful
                            twilight panorama. What glimmering, a speck though it be, that has not received, from
                            earth-bound visionists, some name, pronounced course of action, mode of revolution and
                            almost destination, and which, taken in geometrical connection with curves and positions,
                            has failed to represent the outlines of some living object with which we are more
                            satisfactorily acquainted. Who can say that some other worlds have not developed intellects
                            like, or unlike our own, that have fashioned, named and formed, according to their
                            comprehension, every dark and glowing object which sight can reveal to them ? Thoughts
                            wrought in argument and mere conjecture, that flit through the brain, are as the threadless
                            shuttle across the web — work aimed at, but unaccomplished. Science has taught much, and
                            blessed be investigation through which facts are revealed. Much is yet unknown of latent
                            growth and secret forces, even to superior minds — and enough for minor capacities to seek
                            and grasp the simpler truths which surround us in God's boundless creation. The heavens
                            please us with undiminishjng attraction, even though heavy masses of vapor float beneath its
                            canopy. The great solar lamp, that illumines for millions of miles around, dims only in
                            alternate seasons, the lesser lights which cluster within its ray ; and there are stars
                            which never sink below the horizon — supposed suns, which brighten the still deeper recesses
                            of the upper regions where our view fails to extend, and make visible the existence of
                            things at almost unappreciated distances. What a phenomenon is nature, controlled by laws of
                            attraction and repulsion, with forces of unabating strength and regularity ! The earth we
                            inhabit revolves daily and annually among these heavenly scenes, and if all with which it
                            comes in contact are equally as grand and beautiful as our own, be their density and
                            composition what they may, what a wonderful performance of the Infinite Mind the whole must
                            be !</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our home" TEIform="index"/>OUR HOME. AN ACROSTIC</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stephens, Annie" TEIform="persName"/>ANNIE STEPHENS</byline><p TEIform="p">Mount of the orient, rising in grandeur, Over thy snow peaks, the sunny beams fall, Up from
                            thy valleys the cedars are towering, Noble in beauty, majestic, and tall. Time in his onward
                            march, left us the record, Lighted with deeds which the martyrs have done, Earnest their
                            work, for a truth they were growing, But we must toil till an increase is won. As o'er thy
                            hill tops the sun rose in splendor, Night stars receded from Heaven's blue arch, Over them
                            still shines the light just as clearly, Night stars sing sweetly, as then, on their march. O
                            ! while we're thinking of efforts of past time, Uplifting our spirits in praise for the
                            true, Revering the martyrs whose lives were devoted, Have we not a work in the present to do
                            ? O ! yea, we must build up the city eternal, Make ready for souls that would dwell in
                            accord, E'en now it appears as a light to the nations, OUR HOME is exalted, the Mount of the
                            Lord.</p></div2><pb n="233" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Change of heart" TEIform="index"/>CHANGE OF HEART</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>E. MYRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">Bro. H-----, of L-----, of untarnished character, esteemed for his impartial charities; loved
                            and respected most by those who knew him best, was an infidel — made no creedal profession,
                            belonged to no church, nor sect. He must be converted—must attach to some form—"belong to
                            some meetinghouse." All wanted such a member, he had money, was generous, kind, benevolent.
                            Ministers in turns used their persuasions, pictured to him heaven and its antipode (with
                            which they are so familiar). At length being so closely invested he surrendered. He joined
                            the church; said he had experienced a "change of heart." He had faith. He " believed." He
                            attended church, and bowed reverently to the parson, paid tithes; what lacked he then ?
                            After the lapse of a few months, inquiry arose as to what change there was in Brother H.
                            since he joined the church? None had been observed, except by one of his nearest neighbors,
                            who, in answer to the inquiry, re. plied, "I have observed a marked change.'' " What may it
                            be?" " Well, before he joined the church, when he went to salt his cattle on the Sabbath, he
                            used to carry his ax on his shoulder to repair the fence if need be. Since he experienced
                            religion he conceals his ax under his overcoat." Think of it, an honest man converted to a
                            pious fraud! Joining the Shaker church is a conversion to confession of all sins and
                            dishonesty ; restitution and repentance ; and thenceforth lead an honest, pure and divine
                            life. This i: a " change of heart " to some good purpose.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Trinity of wrongs" TEIform="index"/>A TRINITY OF WRONGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Prentiss, O." TEIform="persName"/>O. PRENTISS</byline><p TEIform="p">Running in debt. Claiming land outside the home farm. Usury. Unless our Beloved Zion arise,
                            and shake himself clean from the above wrongs, God will have a Zion—composed of new
                        material</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hands to work and hearts to God" TEIform="index"/>"HANDS TO WORK AND HEARTS TO GOD."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Green, Louisa E." TEIform="persName"/>LOUISA E. GREEN</byline><p TEIform="p">" Hands to work and hearts to prayer." That was a maxim taught by our first founder on the
                            earth, and is it not as necessary now, to-day, as it was then ? And how can we put it in
                            practice that we may reap the most benefit therefrom in a Community ? It is certainly not by
                            standing still and waiting for the tides of life to turn, expecting something that will
                            please our fancies, or yield the most enjoyment to self. It is not by sitting with our hands
                            idly folded, and seeing our brother or sister lifting the heavy loads of care, without
                            rising to duty and rendering our assistance, thus failing to call into action the Golden
                            rule. It is not by finding fault with another for not doing what we do not like to do, but
                            what is our duty to do ; nor by leaving the stern battle of life for one or two to fight,
                            and then expect a share of blessing in the victories won. Ah, nay ! If we would be noble men
                            and women in the new creation, true brethren and sisters in Christ, we must together toil
                            for the upbuilding of our homes, feeling that it is our home, we must together face the
                            duties of life, lift the burdens, and lighten the cares, together seeking each other's
                            comfort and happiness, thus securing the same blessing to ourselves. In so doing, we will be
                            living examples of that faith which we profess ; and ours will be the inheritance of that
                            Peace, which the world know not of, because we have sown the seed, nourished the plant, and
                            finally reaped the harvest of patient toil and labor in Zion's cause. And thus will we be
                            practicing the blessed injunction of our Mother, Ann Lee : " Hands to work and hearts to
                            Prayer," and our very lives will be the essence of praise to God. Canaan, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very near together are hearts that have no guile" TEIform="index"/>Very near together are hearts that have no guile
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Very near together are hearts that have no guile.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Confucius" TEIform="persName"/> Confucius</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The New Orleans Picayune thinks that the name of the doctor..." TEIform="index"/>The New Orleans Picayune thinks that the name of the doctor...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The New Orleans Picayune thinks that the name of the doctor should be attached to all death
                            notices.</p></div2><pb n="234" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Substantiability of Christ" TEIform="index"/>THE SUBSTANTIABILITY OF CHRIST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">It is worthy of notice that the majority of texts used by the ministerial profession, for
                                subjects of religious addresses, are found and taken from without the sayings of Christ.
                                By far, Paul is the authority in the selection of texts, in excess of Jesus. Why is this
                                ? Was Paul a model teacher of Christ's life and testimony? We demur ; we deny. Paul was,
                                with ¦ out exception, an unequaled character, inasmuch as his life was far more
                                Christian than his teachings; and especially were his permissions unchristian. It is not
                                well known, but may be so, that Peter contended long and late in life for the
                                maintenance intact of the essential principles of Jesus, the Christ. He was confronted
                                by Paul, in that the people would not, could not accept the fullness of Christ's
                                testimony, and that permissions, to ease the crucifixion of selfish, worldly lusts were
                                felt to be needed, demanded, or all would turn away from the church. It is the most
                                lamentable truth we ever penned, that Peter was over-persuaded, and permitted the
                                radical purity and unselfishness of Christ's testimony to trail in and become besmirched
                                by human lusts, to an extent that not only brings the radical truths of Christ into
                                complete disregard, but the very opposite of the testimony and life of Christ is
                                contended for, and substance for the arguments, in plenty, is found in the permissions,
                                not in the life of Paul. If Paul had maintained Christianity intact, by issuing the
                                unbending counsel: Follow me, as I follow Jesus Christ f and left the permissions to
                                marry and to otherwise live unlike Jesus, there would have been no need of any falling
                                away of the Primitive Church of Christ. But " becoming all tilings to all men's" lustful
                                entreaties; and soothing their fleshly crucifixions by a permission to do and live
                                unlike Christ, he gained none to Christ, but encouraged, and still encourages more than
                                all else to-day, departures from the life of Christ! Not so with Jesus: This is the
                                testimony: "I am- the (pattern of) the way," you should walk; " of the truth" you should
                                learn, "and of the life " you should live. " No one can come to the Father but by this
                                life." " If ye love me keep my words " and live like me. "Why call ye me Lord, and do
                                not things" of which my life and testimony are a sample ? Jesus was unyielding and
                                substantial; founded upon the progressive truths of a newer dispensation than the gospel
                                of Moses, he taught by example, and no permissions ever passed his lips to live
                                differently, and still retain a discipleship ! Not so; but there was a positive,
                                substantial, immovable truth in the solemn declaration: "lie cannot be my disciple"
                                without the same renunciations I have made, and adhesions to the same principles which
                                my life illustrates— Virgin Purity ; Peace; Universal, brotherly love; Unspottedness
                                from the tuorld. What do we see to-day ? Mareiage made a sacrament by churches
                                professing Christ! War encouraged under the most trivial excuses, and ministers,
                                professing Christ, enlisting themselves as chaplains to encourage SAitori*!. <pb n="235" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 235 carnage, and appeal for help from Him who loves
                                peace only, not war! Every unchristian 'practice named in the Christian catalogue as
                                such, is clung to with the tenacity of life, and while receiving from Christ only the
                                holiest denunciations for Christians to practice, are yet sustained by the permissions
                                of Paul to those who will not deny themselves, Christ's life is our Christianity. Any
                                thing not found in his life-practices is unchristian, and who practices it is such. In
                                Christ's Church there is no outer court. There can be no commingling of the flesh and
                                spirit therein. The married, the child-bearing, the lovers and owners of houses, lands,
                                selfish property or selfish life are simply, yet truthfully in these things unchristian.
                                The communists of Oneida have made a departure—a grand departure —and we beg all the
                                world to witness the progressive feature therein. " Complex marriage"—which when
                                practiced in "polite society" has commonly borne another and very disgusting name — is
                                discarded; and monogamy will succeed to those who want permissions to engage in what
                                Jesus, nor Paul could as Christians engage in—sexual loves and lusts. But here is the
                                grand testimony, the great progress, the prodigal's return, the Christian announcement:
                                "Virgin Celibacy is to be greatly preferred!" We may be mistaken in our estimates of
                                human virtue; but we anticipate that a majority of that Community will embrace, and live
                                Virgin Celibacy as well as they are able. We are pleased, more than pleased, with the
                                announcement. With all, and toward all, who, having only one great obstacle between them
                                and the love and life of Christ, and that removed, there must be a growing sympathy and
                                delightful union. But the gennine, radical Church of Christ will accept of no
                                permissions as an easement to human fleshly lusts ; its congregations must "crucify the
                                flesh with its affections and lusts," saving none, and can feel no oneness of fellowship
                                with those who divide between Christ and their affections for at least a measure of the
                                flesh. Christ is not divided; neither the people in His church. As Christ was in
                                principles and in life, so will these in His followers be.</p></div3><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES</head><div4 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our readers will thank us for reproducing in this number..." TEIform="index"/>Our readers will thank us for reproducing in this number...
                                </head><p TEIform="p">Our readers will thank us for reproducing in this number of the Manifesto "The
                                    Judgment of Sin," from Elder H. L. Eads' Book of '' Shaker Sermons." It is a timely
                                    production, and will do any and all great good to thoughtfully study it, and the
                                    great est of good to accept and be governed by it. We offer it as a sample of the
                                    many good fruits to be found in that beautifully interesting volume, now ready for
                                    those who love the best of good things. See notice of the book elsewhere.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Speak the best of neighbors" TEIform="index"/>Speak the Best of Neighbors</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">One of our neighbors has had the name of being stingy and avaricious ; but these
                                    terms are born of prejudice and are not wellfounded. A poor neighbor of his wanted
                                    to borrow a horse to take some things to market; the so-called stingy neighbor not
                                    only lent the horse, but refused to accept of any compensation. Another poorer
                                    neighbor of this so-called avaricious man lately said: " W. is the first to respond
                                    to the calls of the sick or those in want or distress." Another of our neighbors
                                    sent some hams to another neighbor to be smoked, and when done offered payment; but
                                    the one who did <pb n="236" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 236 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. the good deed
                                    declined any pay, saying : " The same smoke that cured my hams, cured yours ; the
                                    curing of your hams cost me nothing, therefore you owe me nothing but thanks." Such
                                    good deeds among neighbors might be multiplied ; and then let such good news
                                    circulate, as deeds to be emulated by all other neighbors, poor and rich alike.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Grand social gatherings" TEIform="index"/>The Grand Social Gatherings</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Some of the pretty and thoughtful contributions to this number were previously used
                                    at Mt. Lebanon, where once a year the three Novitiate Families meet in a grand
                                    reunion ; and where, with invited guests, both inner, outer, and the most spiritual
                                    of man are thoroughly feasted with good things. We speak from the experience of an
                                    unworthy guest; and we but do justice to our readers to let them into a partial
                                    insight of what goes on til ere.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Needed suggestion" TEIform="index"/>A Needed Suggestion</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We are in constant reception of communications from "the household of our faith," in
                                    which, speaking of ourselves—Shakers — the term " Believers" is used. Once we
                                    claimed the equal of a copyright upon this term ; but there are several minor sects
                                    who are now wearing this cognomen ; and besides the term bears upon it no distinct
                                    explanation nor information. Should we add to it " in Christ's Second Appearing" we
                                    would be better understood. But people pretty well understand what the Shakers
                                    believe, who they are and how they live, and why not cling to the honorable name of
                                    " Shakers " which no man has ever counterfeited yet for a denomination, neither
                                    desires to do so, while it may all remain ours for another hundred years without the
                                    least molestation ? We are aware that some, very high in authority among us, do
                                    not'like this appellation. That they avoid its use and evade its address. With all
                                    due respect for such, we have no apology to make to them for this timely suggestion.
                                    For the term " Shaker " means so much — those who shake errors from themselves
                                    first, and then go all over the world with their shaking testimony, to the great
                                    disturbance and eradication of worldly errors and fleshly wrongs. The term is a
                                    righteous one and applies grandly to our profession and testimony. We could not, if
                                    we should all try, get rid of it for one hundred years, and we, for many, protest
                                    against the evasion OR ATTEMPTED DISUSE.</p></div4><div4 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To the generous" TEIform="index"/>To the Generous</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Of course, reader, you are the generous one meant, whoever you as reader may be. We
                                    will not bore you with uninteresting words. We want to state, frankly to you, that
                                    in this enterprise of issuing thousands of copies of The Manifesto, monthly, we are
                                    at large expense, and must rely on every generous heart with whom we come in contact
                                    to help us " bear our burdens." " Let tlie strong (help) bear the burdens of the
                                    weak." At the end of the year we want to be one with our printers. We now owe them
                                    between two and three hundreds of dollars, which we want to pay them as soon as
                                    possible. Will you help us what you are able ? It costs nearly or quite one hundred
                                    dollars to run our mailing expenses on The Manifesto for a year. We neither charge
                                    nor get pay for our services, and although our paper is small, these are not a few;
                                    but of this we will say nothing more. But will those who have generous hearts think
                                    of us to help us ? Shakers should be most generous ; and the generosity comes in
                                    after just debts due are paid. But let every one be generous—kind friends all, help
                                    us keep the good work moving — the sowing of good seed, the reaping of good
                                souls.</p></div4></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Work of consciousness" TEIform="index"/>Work of Consciousness</head><p TEIform="p">— The awe of soul-consciousness breaking into occasional lurid heats through the chasms of
                            our conventionalities has struck me, in my own self-observation, as a mystery of Nature,
                            very grand in itself, and is quite a distinct mystery from conscience. Conscience has to do
                            with action (every thought being spiritual action), and not with abstract existence. There
                            are moments when we are startled at the footsteps of our own being more than at the thunder
                            of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Browning, Elizabeth Barrett" TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth Barrett Browning</byline></div2><pb n="237" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lesson for boys" TEIform="index"/>A LESSON FOR BOYS</head><p TEIform="p">One day a fine Newfoundland dog and a mastiff had a sharp discussion over a bone or some
                                other trifling matter, and warred away as angrily as two boys. They were fighting on a
                                bridge; and being blind with rage, as is often the case, the first thing they knew over
                                they went into the water. The banks were so high that they were forced to swim some
                                distance before they came to a landing place. It was very easy for the Newfoundlander;
                                he was as much at home in the water as a seal. But not so poor Bruce ; he struggled and
                                tried his best to swim, but made little headway. Old Bravo (the Newfoundlander) had
                                reached the land, and then turned to look at his old enemy. He saw plainly that his
                                strength was fast failing, and that he was likely to drown. So what should that noble
                                fellow do but plunge in, seize him gently by the collar, and, keeping his nose above
                                water, tow him safely into port! It was funny to see these dogs look at each other as
                                they shook their wet coats. Their glance said as plainly as words. " We'll never quarrel
                                any more !"</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good prayer" TEIform="index"/>A Good Prayer</head><p TEIform="p">A little boy, the son of a "Friend," about six years old, after sitting like the rest of
                                the congregation in silence, all being afraid to speak first, as he thought, got up on
                                the seat, and, folding his arms over his breast, murmured in a clear, sweet voice, j ust
                                loud enough to be distinctly heard on the fore seat: "I do wish the Lord would make us
                                all gooder, and gooder, and gooder, till there is no bad left." Would a longer prayer
                                have been more to the purpose ? What will People Say.—This question makes the mind
                                homeless. Do right and fear no one ; thou mayest be sure that with all thy consideration
                                for the world thou wilt never satisfy the world. But if thou goest straight forward on
                                thy way not concerning thyself with the friendly or unfriendly glances of men, then thou
                                hast conquered the world, and it is subject to thee. By heeding the question " What will
                                people say ?" thou becomest subject to the world.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Golden rule" TEIform="index"/>Golden rule
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Golden Rule, of Boston, comes to us in its old form : a handsome eight-page weekly
                                paper, conducted by Rev. H. A. Shorey. Typographically it is almost a counterpart of its
                                old self— the change being to a larger type for the body of the paper, making it even
                                handsomer than before. As a literary and religious household journal The Golden Ride was
                                a general favorite, and the new proprietors, in a modestly-worded greeting, propose to
                                maintain its well-earned reputation. The old departments are all retained, and two or
                                three new ones added. An entire page is given to Sunday Schools—-to be edited by Rev. R.
                                R. Meredith and Rev. A. F. Schauffler. A story is promised for each week, the one in the
                                present number being an admirable temperance story by W. M. F. Round. The price has been
                                reduced to $2.00, with special rates to clubs.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wanted" TEIform="index"/>WANTED</head><p TEIform="p">Wanted — a man, good, honest and brave, Who doth all the vices eschew, Who'll battle
                            undaunted his honor to save, To himself and his fellow-men true. Wanted — a woman, no
                            feminine tame, Like fashion and prejudice make, A creature of folly, just woman in name, But
                            a woman, as God did create. Wanted — a friend, that shall stand by our side, When friends
                            and prosperity speed ; E'en faithful through all, though others deride, A friend that's a
                            friend in need. Wanted — a Christian, one who can feel For the sinner, whoever he be, Who'll
                            pray with the sot, with the Magdalen kneel, From schism and hypocrisy free. Wranted — sweet
                            truth, and constancy rare, And faith, of a tangible shape, And justice, and mercy, and
                            charity fair, The earth a bright Eden to make.</p></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="'Truth is mighty' -- mighty scarce" TEIform="index"/>Truth is mighty' -- mighty scarce
                        </head><p TEIform="p">"Truth is mighty" — mighty scarce.</p></div2><pb n="238" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shepherd's fold" TEIform="index"/>SHEPHERD'S FOLD</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline><p TEIform="p">1. Over the land, over the sea Hasten O heavenly dove! 2. Come to a land where waters flow
                            Clear as the crystal sea, 3. Thus shall the wilderness rejoice, Bud and blossom anew, Bear
                            good tidings of liberty, And scatter the seeds of love; Come to a haven of joy below, From
                            sorrows of earth be free; Hills and valleys shall lift their voice, In anthems of praises
                            due; Unto the heavy laden say, Enter a haven of rest, Come to the resurrection morn, Dawn of
                            a glorious day, Righteousness, as a fruitful field, Stay to gladden the earth, Cast the
                            garments of sin away, And with the pure be blest. Peace doth flow to the weary worn, And
                            love doth light the way. War no more will a harvest yield, Or fill the land with dearth. O
                            list to music soft and sweet, From harps the angels hold, While heavenly breezes waft Onward
                            to the shepherd's fold.</p></div2><pb n="239" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>Home Topics</head><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Firm butter without ice" TEIform="index"/>Firm butter without ice
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Firm Butter Without Ice.—In families where the dairy is small, a good plan to have the
                                butter cool and firm without ice is by the process of evaporation, as practiced in India
                                and other warm countries. A cheap plan is to get a very large-sized, porous, earthen
                                flower-pot, with a large saucer. Half till the saucer with water, set it in a trivet or
                                light stand—such as is used for holding hot irons will do ; upon this set your butter;
                                over the whole invert the fiower-pot, letting the top' rim of it rest in and be covered
                                by the water, then close the hole in the bottom of the flower-pot with a cork; then dash
                                water over the flower-pot, and repeat the process several times a day, or whenever it
                                looks dry. If set in a cool place or where the wind can blow on it, it will readily
                                evaporate the water from the pot, and the butter will be as firm and cool as if from an
                                icehouse. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cold slaw" TEIform="index"/>Cold slaw
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Cold Slaw.—Slice one quart of cabbage fine, take one teacup of vinegar, one
                                tableapoonful of butter, one of sugar, one teaspoon of salt, a little pepper; put in cup
                                and cook; it is done when it commences to thicken; pour over cabbage. My husband likes
                                lettuce prepared in same way.</p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cooking potatoes" TEIform="index"/>Cooking potatoes
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Cooking Potatoes.—The potato is more nutritious and more generally used than any other
                                vegetable, and when properly boiled so as to be dry and mealy, it is a real luxury; but
                                when sodden and water-soaked, as frequently we see them, they are indigestible and one
                                of the worst things that are put into the human stomach ; and yet a well-boiled potato
                                is seldom seen at a hotel or restaurant, and the man who would introduce them into the
                                latter would do a public favor and help his own purse. This is the way I would
                                recommend: Let them be put into cold water in a covered vessel, and boiled rapidly until
                                nearly done; then pour off the water and sprinkle a small quantity of salt over the
                                potatoes; put on the cover so as to leave a small open space for the steam to escape and
                                leave the vessel over the fire for a few minutes, and the potatoes will be done.—
                                Germantown Telegraph. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cocoanut drink" TEIform="index"/>Cocoanut drink
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Cocoanut Drink.—To two grated cocoanuts, with their milk, add two quarts of pure water;
                                place over the fire and boil for five or six minutes, stirring constantly with a wooden
                                spatula ; then strain. Add to the liquid twelve ounces of pulverized sugar; mix well,
                                and ice. This is delightfully cooling. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Turkish beverage" TEIform="index"/>Turkish beverage
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Turkish Beverage. — Put ripe grapes, picked from their stems, into an ear-then pan or
                                dish, and cover them with boiling water. Set the pan in a warm situation for four or
                                five hours; then strain off the liquid; sweeten to taste, and place in a freezer and
                                half freeze. Grated pine apple, treated in the same way, forms also a delicious
                                beverage.</p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Iced coffee" TEIform="index"/>Iced coffee
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Iced Coffee. — Make a quart of strong coffee, to which add a pint of simple syrup: mix
                                well and put into a freezer, freezing only so much that it can still be poured into
                                glasses for use.—Confectioner's Journal. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Petroleum has a strong preservative power..." TEIform="index"/>Petroleum has a strong preservative power...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Petroleum has a strong preservative power, converting soft, perishable woods to the
                                durability of red cedar. It improves all farm implements, baskets, all wooden tools, as
                                rakes, hoe handles, common waterpails or any wooden tool which is exposed to the
                                weather. It may be found valuable, also, for rustic work, rustic furniture or chairs
                                left upon a piazza. Give them a good coat of this oil occasionally. It will harden the
                                wood, give them a dark color and make them last longer. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple cosmetic" TEIform="index"/>Simple cosmetic
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Simple Cosmetic.—It is not generally known that the juice of ripe tomatoes is the most
                                simple as well as effective agent for giving a soft, smooth feeling to the hands, adding
                                beauty to the skin and renewed limberness to the joints. </p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gems" TEIform="index"/>Gems
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Gems. — Unbolted wheat or rye flour is mixed up with water and made into a batter a
                                little stiffer than for griddle cakes. It is then dropped into sizzling hot gem pans and
                                baked in a hot oven for about half an hour, or until nicely browned. If not well baked
                                they are doughy and indigestible. </p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Simple remedies are frequently the best..." TEIform="index"/>Simple remedies are frequently the best...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Simple remedies are frequently the best for headache. A cup of sour milk spread upon a
                                thin cloth and applied to the head will many times give relief. Or, a mustard plaster on
                                the back of the neck will often ease the pain.</p></div3></div2><pb n="240" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Potatoes for stock" TEIform="index"/>Potatoes for stock
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Potatoes for stock. — A writer in an exchange says : I have fed all kinds of roots and
                                considerable quantities of tliem to cattle, and among them all I consider the potato,
                                fed raw to cows, the best for quantity of milk or quality of beef. The best beef I ever
                                tasted was fattened on potatoes and meal. My experience is that they should never be
                                cooked for cattle, but always for hogs, and at half the price of corn they are
                                profitable to feed in connection with meal. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Treatment of poultry" TEIform="index"/>Treatment of poultry
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Treatment OP Poultry.—A correspondent writes to the Germantown Telegraph to say that his
                                observation and experience are that thousands of fowls die annually of cholera from
                                neglect. He thus gives his prevention: I never overstock my poultry house. I always keep
                                their quarters clean and sweet. I use plenty of lime and I keep them well supplied with
                                pure fresh water. I feed them morning, noon and evening at regular hours with a variety
                                of wholesome food. A little fresh lime in their water is very good during the summer
                                months, but you must not forget to clean the poultry house every week. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sour milk is one of the best feeds..." TEIform="index"/>Sour milk is one of the best feeds...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Sour Milk is one of the best feeds for poultry, especially for young chickens, that can
                                be given them; and we fear its value is not fully realized by those generally who keep
                                poultry in the country, as we are satisfied much refuse milk goes to waste that might be
                                given the hens as well as not. Young chicks thrive wonderfully upon a diet of sour milk,
                                and it may be given them in place of water to great advantage. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Soaked corn for workers" TEIform="index"/>Soaked corn for workers
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Soaked Corn tor Workers. — The American Express Company is noted for the extra quality
                                and appearance of their horses. It is understood that all of their horses are fed on
                                corn, unshelled from the cob; but the corn is allowed to stand in water for twentyfour
                                hours before it is given to the horses. As much may then be fed to a feeding, with. out
                                harm, as the horses will eat, having fully swelled before going to the horses. We
                                recommend farmers to try this, and report to us. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Parched corn for fowls" TEIform="index"/>Parched corn for fowls
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Parched Corn for Fowls. — Indian corn charred into charcoal is said to be a most
                                valuable condiment for poultry. It will put the hens in good health, and cause a general
                                toning up of the system, that will be shown in more and better eggs. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To agricultural journals" TEIform="index"/>To agricultural journals
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> To Agricutural Journals. — The very plausible recommendation to plant a few kernels of
                                flaxseed with potatoes to repel the potato bugs is proved to be a cruel hoax. We tested
                                it thoroughly, and the bugs seemed to thrive on it—lay their eggs upon its 'leaves and
                                stalks—and our land is too fully seeded with "plants out of place" — weeds—flax by name.
                                We hope all Journals will correct the erroneous advice. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Poor farming and poor religion" TEIform="index"/>Poor farming and poor religion
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Poor Farming and Poor Religion.— A farmer in New England has sixteen harvests of grain
                                and hay rotting in the stacks. At the breaking out of the war he held his crop for
                                higher prices, and with each year and additional advances he waited for more, until at
                                last the current set in the other way, which disgusted him so that he refused to sell,
                                and, continuing to stack and stack, he has now on hand $20,000 worth of produce. His
                                neighbors say he is crazy, which is probably true, but how much wiser are those who
                                having gifts which might be of use in society and the church fail to employ them. A
                                talent hid in a napkin is of no more use than grain stacked up to rot. Or how much wiser
                                is the man who does nothing but add each year to his pile of silver or gold or bonds,
                                which in his hands are of no value to society during his life, and perhaps are the ruin
                                of his family after he is gone.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Shakers believe the kingdom of heaven has..." TEIform="index"/>The Shakers believe the kingdom of heaven has...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Shakers believe the kingdom of heaven has been established; that Christ has
                                    come upon earth a second time in the person of Mother Ann (Ann Lee, an English
                                    woman, born in Manchester, was the founder of the sect, Laving emigrated thence with
                                    a small band of disciples shortly before the Revolutionary war), and that the
                                    personal reign of God has been restored. They believe, also, that the new
                                    dispensation has begun; that, Adam's sin has been atoned; that man has been
                                    delivered from all errors except his own ; that the earth and all it contains shall
                                    be redeemed.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Religio-philosophical journal" TEIform="index"/>Religio-Philosophical Journal</bibl></cit></p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>