<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0312" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">12</biblScope><date value="18731201" TEIform="date">November 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">89-96</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="89" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="12" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!-- 
                    <p>Vol. III. No. 12. PUBLISHED BY :THE UNITED SOCIETY. F. W. EVANS, Editob. Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y. December, 1873.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="New Heaven and new Earth" TEIform="index"/>NEW HEAVEN AND NEW EARTH</head><p TEIform="p">A new creation. But, as from nothing comes nothing, both the new earth and the new heaven
                            must be evolved from previously-existent elements. As Believers in the second manifestation
                            of Christ, we have heretofore assumed, in our writings, that our spiritual order was the new
                            heaven; and that our community of goods was the new earth. This was true, but not the whole
                            truth. The light shines brighter, and we see further. John says: " I saw a new heaven, and a
                            new earth; for the first heaven, and the first earth, were passed away; and there was no
                            more sea " — spiritual heathenism. In his vision, John had previously been giving us the
                            history of the first earth and heaven, which began to be created at the introduction of the
                            Christ Spirit into the Roman empire. The seven churches of Asia were semiheathen,
                            semi-Christian organizations. They are the bases of our present Gentile Christianity, or
                            "Babylon the Great"—: the Mother" of so many M harlot" systems of theology, and of civil
                            governments. This heathen Roman empire was the raw material out of which our modern
                            Christianity — its Gospel and Law — has been formed. The empire included nearly every known
                            nation that, at that time, was called civilized. Christendom, with its hundreds of orders
                            and sects, in its creeds, its prayers, and its sermons, unites the natural generative and
                            the spiritual resurrection elements, and mixes them together in its sacraments, ordinances,
                            and church ceremonies. Is not this flesh and spirit theology — this admixture of discordant,
                            antagonistic elements — the cause of the vehement denunciation of the Revelator, and of his
                            utter abhorrence of the whole Babylonish system, to which he so remorselessly applies the
                            most opprobrious epithets known to human language? It is said that Babylon means mixture —
                            confusion; and the culminating manifestation of this mixing and adulterous spirit is in the
                            union of Church and State Governments, under which tha priesthood usurp authority in the
                            first heaven, and first earth, too, and compound them together. The Pope of Rome, and the
                            Queen of England, are equally the Head of the Church and State. Marriage is a sacrament of
                            the Church ; and war, like the infernal Inquisition, is holy. The same Church official can "
                            solemnize holy matrimony," lead an army, cr appoint and pay for the leader, collect tithes
                            and Peter Pence, dress in scarlet and gorgeous attire, fare sumptuously every day; while
                            every fifth person is a pauper of higher or lower degree; and the social evil extends from
                            the sacristy to the brothel. Monasteries and Nunneries, barracks and monitors, State prisons
                            and theaters, tenement houses and asylums, hotels and boarding places, are all Church and
                            State institutions, and come of the attempt of Christendom to combine, under one Head, " the
                            first earth and the first heaven." Can there be a doubt that these are the "first heaven and
                            the first earth " which John saw " pass away" in the fall of Babylon? or that they were
                            formed under the first advent and influence of the Christ Spirit ? They stand exclusively in
                            the masculine gender. Witness Jesus and his twelve Apostles — all men; the three he Gods of
                            the Trinity, worshipped by the Catholic, Greek, and Protestant world ; and the masculine
                            priesthood, from the Pope, and Luther and Calvin, down to H. W. Beecher. The cardinal dogmas
                            of the " Evangelical Al- liance " are, without question, what the Spirit designated "
                            doctrines of devils "— of Evil. John saw the " first beast " — Catholicism — come up out of
                            the sea — spiritualistic heathenism; and a " second beast, with two horns"—Luther and Calvin
                            — come up out of the earth — Rationalism. These are "the beast," and " the image of the
                            beast"—Church and State male Governments — moons turned to blood. All the ages down, they
                            have been either fighting and warring, or preparing to fight and war, with each other.
                            Having seen the first heaven and the first earth pass away, John begins to describe the
                            second heaven and earth that should take their places. He saw the new earth in its glory,
                            and, as Swedenborg and some others have done, mistook it for the new heaven. " I saw the
                            holy city, New Jerusalem,"— the city of the Jews in the spirit world — " coming down from
                            God out of heaven. * * * The tabernacle of God was with men, and He will dwell with them ;
                            and they shall be His people," who shall live up to the holy and good Law of Moses, in
                            generation nutrition, and in their property relations; as they did during their forty years
                            visionary state in the wilderness. The land will be Government property ; and the Government
                            will be male and female ; and marriage will be for use only. The evil things, so much lusted
                            after, will be unknown ; and manna—vegetables, farina, and fruit, will be for muscular
                            strength in man, as with the ox and elephant, the horse and camel, the buffalo and
                            dromedary. " Perish, commerce," and flourish agriculture. Let cities be for the giants in
                            wickedness ; and co-operative associations universal throughout the land. Let the land be
                            fed with its own produce, and have its sabbaths of rest, to digest its food; that no seed of
                            weed, or germ of animalcule, may live to choke or destroy the crop. And far from human
                            beings would be the plagues and mountain of curses that Moses set before the people who
                            should be disobedient to his organic physiological laws. For, in the new earth, " God shall
                            wipe away all tears from their eyes; and there shall be no more curse," or disease; nor
                            death by sickness, consumption, burning fever, or by any other plagues now so well known to
                            the Gentile Christians in Babylon. " For there shall be neither sorrow nor crying; neither
                            shall there be any more (physical) pain; for the former things are passed away. ... It is
                            done." " He that overcometh " his appetites, and subdues his passions, " shall inherit only
                            good things." Behold, then, the " new earth," in which man and woman shall have equal voice
                            in framing and executing the laws; and which shall possess a simple dual Civil Government;
                            and under its administration, all present forms of evil, and causes of human misery, shall
                            find no place to counteract its Millennial principles. In chapter xxi of the Revelation, we
                            have, from verse 9, a visionary description of the " new heaven," as co-existent with the
                            new earth; "of which we cannot now speak particularly"— not until another issue of the
                            "Shaker and Shakeress" in the new year, 1874.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Word of God and the bible" TEIform="index"/>THE WORD OF GOD AND THE BIBLE</head><p TEIform="p">Each one of the thousand antagonistic Beets of religionists, called by the homogeneous name
                            of Christians, has a theology built up out of the teachings and interpretations of their
                            Bibles. This fact is continually raising the important inquiry, Is, or Is not, any one of
                            these sectarian Bibles the Word of God f " A tree is known by its fruit." Theological
                            sectarianism is Bible fruit. Inspiration, redeeming love — salvation — is the fruit of the
                            Word of God ! The former engenders in men, and in nations, cruel wars, inhuman persecu-
                            tions, the infliction of the most awful tortures that human ingenuity can invent, upon the
                            infidels and heretics of their own creation; and inveterate, mutual hatred toward the Gods
                            and Bibles that each of them thus worship. Whilst, under the influence of the latter,
                            Pentecostal Communities are formed, wherein men and women love their neighbor as they love
                            themselves. One said: " Men, in consequence of their belief in the inspiration of the whole
                            Bible, <pb n="90" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 9O SHAKEE .A.ND suppose that God requires something more of them
                            than merely being and doing good." No thoroughly enlightened Christian, whose soul is
                            vitalized by the real Word of God, can study the character of the God of the Jews, as
                            described in these man-made Bibles, wherein he is depicted as possessing all the passions of
                            that humanity he is seeking to elevate and redeem — fickleness, hatred, revenge, wrath, and
                            unparalleled cruelty — without its lessening his veneration for this tutelary divinity — the
                            "Lord of hosts" of implacable warriors. The hygienic ordinances of the Law, con- cerning
                            generation, its confessions, and sinofferings, followed by washings, purifications, and
                            sacrifices, conjoined to the scientifically wise restrictions relative to inflammatory meats
                            and drinks, and the utter prohibition of indigestible, disease-creating fat and grease, are
                            inestimable records. They were designed to remove (and prevent) " all sickness from " the
                            Jewish people, " whose lives, to-day, average five years more than do the Gentile Christian
                            people of Europe, although under the greatest possible disadvantages." — (Dr. John S.
                            Hough.) Here we have two of the steps in the ladder of redeeming progress, reaching from the
                            lower order of generation up to the Resurrection order — from earth to heaven — as
                            represented in a dream of Jacob. These laws and statutes remain as a tribu- nal of judgment,
                            before which the whole human race will yet be arraigned, to give an account of the deeds
                            done in their now terribly-diseased bodies.* The prophetic books of the true Bible are a
                            priceless boon to humanity. Their claims to a Christ inspiration are substantiated by
                            numerous immensely-momentous fulfillments of prophecies concerning cities, kingdoms, and
                            nations, in the external world; and by still more important actualizations in the religious
                            progress, and spiritual history of our race. They are the recorded links of God's
                            providences, forming a chain composed of the Word of God which is embelting the whole of the
                            New Creation. The Scriptures are history and biography, interspersed with records of the
                            inspired Word of God, seeking to establish the kingdom of heaven upon earth. That Word is
                            still making Bibles, which are as sacred to the present, and as needful for the future, as
                            was and is the Apocalyptic book of St. John the Divine. Texts from Scripture furnish the
                            fulcrum for the levers of the sects — the creeds of the theological religionists. By these
                            they overthrow each other. "A house thus terribly di- vided against itself cannot stand."
                            The evil arises from the error that the Bible is the Word of God; and that every word
                            between its lids is, by efflux from Deity, plenary in- spiration. It is a magazine of the
                            warriors' weapons the slave-holders' manacles, the mi- ser's gold, old wives' fables, the
                            sage's wisdom, Jewish prejudices, and God-saving truths, thrown together in a book,'-to be
                            accepted as the Ark of Oracles, upon which to found religions. The secular books of the
                            Bible required no more inspiration than does any other history, *If the "statutes were not
                            good," which he "gave," evidence that the "God of Israel" was not the Supreme Being, those
                            laws and statutes that were good — embodying eternal truths — do as certainly prove that he
                            had an orderly relation to Him. Ed. or biographical story. Many words in the ancient
                            Oriental languages, in which the Scriptures were first written, are variously rendered into
                            other tongues. The Hebrew word naliash, rendered serpent ¦— " Be ye wise as serpents, and
                            harmless as doves," — might be, and is, rendered seraph, etc. Yet how different the sense to
                            an Englishman or an American! The numerous instances of this kind destroy entirely the idea
                            of a plenary inspiration, to a rational mind. Had the translators been enlightened by the
                            revelation of Christ's Second Appearing, we should have had a very different Bible from any
                            now extant. Man, in his journey of redemption, swings from one extreme to another. From
                            wrong and ruin, he does not pursue a straight pathway up the inclined plane of righteousness
                            and truth; but moves spirally, as it were, sometimes on the wave of inspirational power,
                            drinking in the gushing rhapsodies of the Word of God; then floating with the tide of
                            passion into caverns of darkness and dissipation. The present is an age of scientific,
                            theological, and religious revolutions, destroying the false foundations of sectarian
                            creeds, and exposing the imperfections of all the Bibles from which they have been evolved.
                            Under this influence, many souls unwisely throw away the Bibles of other nations and races,
                            in past Dispensations, as useless or unprofitable ; not knowing that God's work, for human
                            redemption, in all ages, is harmoniously linked to gether. The Word of God is a unit. A
                            pres. ent revelation will reproduce the past. " Every word that has been spoken by the mouth
                            of all holy Prophets," in all nations, " since the world began," will be restored in the
                            Millennium. The Christian Bibles, with all their errors, are books of incalculable value to
                            the human race ; and the sacred writings, or Bibles, of what are termed heathen nations, are
                            also to be judged by the same standard, ie, the truth they contain, and the good they do.
                            All Scrip- ture records of Divine inspiration help to reveal the power and wisdom of God to
                            mankind ; and they should be preserved, studied, and interpreted, by the light of a present
                            living revelation, as that includes the wliole focal light of all former revelations. God's
                            Word and work never wane, or retrograde ; but are eternally progressing toward the final
                            redemption of all races. Hence, none of the Bibles, not even the Christians', are yet
                            finished.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>Elder Giles B. Avery, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker funeral" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER FUNERAL</head><p TEIform="p">Editor Hudson Register—I have just returned from the Shaker village in this town, where I had
                            been to attend the funeral of the late Elder Richard Bushnell, an aged and much esteemed
                            member of that community, who has been a member of the society for over sixty years, and
                            most of that time occupied a prominent position in the North Family as one of its Elders. He
                            was over eighty years old at his death ; and no man ever died leaving a better record for
                            honesty and an uniform irreproachable life than did Elder Richard. His position in the
                            Shaker Society has, during the present generation, brought him into intimate acquaintance
                            with the citizens of this vicinity; and the community at large seemed fllied with as much
                            sympathy for the deceased as did the members of the community who have grown up under his
                            eyes, and have looked up to him as to a father and a friend, in whom they could with
                            implicit confidence confide. The funeral was held in the Church, which was filled to its
                            utmost capacity. The different Shaker families of Lebanon, Canaan, and Hancock, were
                            represented apparently by a majority of the adults, but as the citizens entered, the space
                            occupied by them became more and more compact, and apparently every spare bench and chair
                            came into requisition in order to seat the audience. It was doubtless the largest gathering
                            ever in that capacious room. The usual exercises on Sunday were entirely dis- pensed with,
                            and the time was filled up with remarks made by different brethren and sisters, appropriate
                            to the occasion, the reading of articles in both poetry and prose, and with singing. Elder
                            Frederick Evans made a beautiful and timely address in which he took occasion to review the
                            past life of the deceased, slightly touching upon the peculiar doctrine of the sect. Elders
                            Daniel Boler, and Giles B. Avery, also gave each a short but impressive address, which, were
                            it in my power, I would send you, as they were every way worthy of publication. Elder Giles
                            also read a beautiful piece of poetry, which he said was written by one of the sisters. If
                            such talent exists among our Shaker friends, and the sentiments expressed in the poem read,
                            are the true emanations of a Shaker heart, then have that singular people been sadly
                            misunderstood by us of the outside world. The world has been led to suppose that all the
                            finer feelings of the human heart— all love, affection, and personal regard for fellow
                            humanity, was here crushed — crucified as we might say — and that an ascetic individuality
                            existed, leaving the Shaker a solitary wanderer on earth, avoiding all sympathy with things
                            of earth, only seeking happiness, won by misery here, in a world to come. But this day there
                            was a rare opportunity, seldom witnessed by those outside of the Society, to observe the
                            beautiful system of Brotherhood that seems to permeate the innermost recesses of their heart
                            of hearts. Here we saw the Ministry and Elders, standing at the head of the Society,
                            mingling in perfect union their humble tributes to the memory of their deceased brother,
                            side by side with those who walk upon the ground floor of the Temple, or are the humble
                            workers upon its outside walls. Had you listened to the several speeches made by brethren
                            and sisters, and heard their written thoughts expressed, the only conclu- sion that could
                            result would be : If these men and women are sincere, if they speak their thoughts in all
                            soberness, if such love cements together the hearts of Shakers, then is their Society a
                            paradise upon earth, and just without the door of Heaven. An invitation to the audience, not
                            Shakers, drew from J. M. Peebles, a well-timed and impressive speech which seemed to be in
                            sympathy with the crowd of people among whom he stood while speaking. Doctor "Wright, an old
                            citizen of New Lebanon, added his testimony to the sterling worth of the deceased, whom he
                            had intimately known for half a century. After the services at the Church were ended, the
                            vast audience had an opportunity to view the remains in an ante-room of the Church. The
                            remains were contained in a plain, substantial coffin, unstained, and without a single
                            ornament ; yet, simple as that burial case was, to eyes accustomed to look upon the
                            varnished surface, the emblazoned adornments which fashion turns out to contain the remains
                            of earth's lavish children, I have no doubt our old friend Richard (if he has the power in
                            spirit to look back) gave hearty approval. At all events, I am confident that in that humble
                            coffin Richard Bushnell " sleeps well."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bull, H." TEIform="persName"/>Judge H. Bull, </byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Col. County, Lebanon Springs, October 26, 1873" TEIform="index"/>Lebanon Springs, Col. Co. N. Y. Oct. 26,1873$$</dateline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Up and down" TEIform="index"/>UP AND DOWN</head><p TEIform="p">In deep silence, quietness, and profound meditation — feeling after God — by sympathizing
                            with all things in the natural world, commencing with man, as the head of the animal
                            kingdom; descending through the vegetable to the unorganized mineral kingdom of Nature, is
                            looking downward. While commencing and sympathizing with unbodied men and women — spirits,
                            angels, cherub and seraph, who intervene between man and Deity, is looking upward. For
                            unorganization is down; perfected organization is up.</p></div2><pb n="91" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cause and effect" TEIform="index"/>CAUSE AND EFFECT</head><p TEIform="p">The First Cause of life, and of all the qualities or properties of mind and matter, in the
                            entire Universe of Creation, is GOD, whose government of all his intelligences in all
                            worlds, and in all heavens, is by Law, which expresses his will. All mind and matter are
                            placed under, and made subject to, Law, founded in Goodness and Truth; and is intended to be
                            productive of felicity to all God's sentient creatures, which, therefore, cannot be
                            infracted with impunity. Man, in all worlds, is a secondary creator; and, therefore, the
                            physical, moral, mental and physiological causes by which we humans are influenced and made
                            to suffer in this world, are mostly, if not altogether, of our own creation ; and,
                            consequently, the corresponding effects are indirectly or directly chargeable upon
                            ourselves. And, as the power to create and bring into operation counteracting causes, is in
                            our possession, when one cause, which would produce evil or injurious effects upon us, is in
                            operation, we (as rational beings) can and should set in motion other and counteracting
                            causes, and thus prevent evil effects. By this, we know that the power of deliverance from
                            evil is principally in our own hands; and, if our icill be in harmony with the Good and
                            Great First Cause, we can bring forth and effectually use that power, and thereby escape the
                            evil or suffering. Calling upon (or praying to) God, that He would remove the evil effects
                            of a cherished evil secondary cause, especially when that cause is known to the person, is
                            the merest fallacy, and is useless. It is like requiring of God the Supreme Intelligence
                            (who is perfectly rational, wise, consistent, and absolutely unchangeable, as well in his
                            purposes as in his nature) to destroy his own system or mode of government. God never acts
                            arbitrarily, but always beneficently. By Law, God says: Do this, and thou shalt live,
                            healthily and happily. Do that, and thou shalt die miserably, or live unhealthily and
                            unhappily. There must necessarily be suffering, where causes of evil are allowed to be and
                            operate, whether the sufferer be aware of their existence, or utterly ignorant thereof.
                            Therefore, it is the businsss of every man and woman to study and labor to find out and know
                            the causes that will produce good, and then to wisely adopt them, and thus prevent evil
                            effects in and upon their bodies, and minds, and morals. There may be, and without doubt
                            there are, gifts resting upon certain individuals, at certain times, by the exercise of
                            which, disease and suffering may be and frequently are removed ; the ulterior and beneficent
                            object of which, is to induce the healed to flee the evil cause, and find out, and
                            practically adopt the true cause of health, ease, and happiness. For, obviously, if the
                            causes of the evil, or suffering, be untouched and allowed to continue to operate, the same
                            (or worse) evil effects will undoubtedly and unavoidably follow. Therefore, be it rememberd,
                            that ignorance of the cause of evil, or suffering, will not prevent evil effects. Wrong
                            habits — physiological or moral, will produce corresponding evil effects and suffering.
                            Physical and physiological habits, when known to be wrong, and yet persisted in, become
                            moral wrongs — real sins against both God's Law, our neighbor, and our- selves. Paul says: "
                            Sin is the transgression of the Law" (of Moses he meant). But it would have been better if
                            he had said, The transgression of Law, as established by God in the nature of matter and
                            mind, is sin. As iron, when under the power of heat (in a molten condition) cannot be used
                            for the purposes of binding or holding together other things, or for the support of
                            buildings, and appears to be without the properties of cohesion and hardness, but which, as
                            soon as the external influence of heat is removed therefrom, will return to its former
                            cohesion, solidity and hardness ; so, when inability to act under the power of a secondary
                            cause of evil is present, of course the evil effects are more or less diminished, and, for
                            the time being, the will of the person may appear to be in the di- rection of good; and it
                            will be called virtue in him, when it is but little better than a " sick bed," or "
                            death-bed repentance." And, in most cases, as soon as the opposing inability is removed, the
                            mind (which is extremely elastic), by the power of the will, returns to its ordinary and
                            customary evil cause, and thereby, with the body, has to endure and suffer the evil effects
                            of the resumed and continued evil cause. And, as every effect is as true to its cause as is
                            a shadow to substance, the longer an evil cause (moral or physical) has been in operation,
                            the longer will it take to eradicate and destroy its evil effects. Therefore, be warned; be
                            wise. Truth, Knowledge, and Wisdom, are natural attributes of God, and are communicable to
                            all his intelligent creatures, in all worlds and spheres, if they be willing to receive of
                            them. Therefore, let all shun ignorance of right, truth, and good ; put off folly, learn to
                            be wise, and choose that which is good and true; and thus escape the ten thousand evils and
                            sufferings — spiritual and physical — which overtake and befall those who will persist in
                            pursuing a contrary or evil course.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, William" TEIform="persName"/>Wm. Offord, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Judicial oath" TEIform="index"/>THE JUDICIAL OATH</head><p TEIform="p">" We demand that the judicial oath, in the courts, and in all other departments of the
                            Government, shall be abolished; and that simple affirmation, under the pains and penalties
                            of perjury, shall be established in its stead." In connection with the above "Demand for
                            Liberalism," the following extracts from The Pilgrim and the Shrine appear tome sufficiently
                            interesting and appropriate to merit being placed before the readers of the Index: "But it
                            is our system of judicial swearing that has struck me as exceedingly curious. " His evidence
                            was essential and satisfactory, but the lawyer who was on the other side very nearly
                            succeeded in rejecting it, and was only foiled by the singular witof the witness. He was
                            reputed to be an 'infidel,' whatever that may be, and on his entering the witness-box, the
                            counsel stopped the clerk, who was about to administer the oath, saying that he wished to
                            ask the witness a question about his religious opinions. "The witness observed that when
                            sworn he should be most happy to answer any questions about the case before the court, but
                            that his opinions concerned nobody but himself: they were not evidence and nothing he could
                            say unsworn could be evidence; he hoped, therefore, his honor, the judge, would save him
                            from any irrelevant curiosity. "The judge, however, answered—what seemed to me a most
                            reasonable appeal — by intimating that it was necessary to answer the counsel's questions. "
                            ' Perhaps then,' said the witness, 'I maybe informed if, not being sworn, I am bound to
                            speak the truth?" " ' Not legally,' said the judge. " Witness thanked the judge, and,
                            turning to the counsel, said, 'Now, then, sir, you may just ask me what you please, and I
                            will endeavor to frame my aswers to suit you !' "Seeingthat an examination under such
                            circumstances would be a farce, the lawyer requested that the oath might be administered.
                            This done he again commenced: " 'Now that you are legally bound to speak the truth, I desire
                            to know if you believe in the New Testament, on which you have been sworn ?" " Turning to
                            the judge with an expression of mock humility, witness said,' I pray your honor's
                            protection.' " The judge told him to answer the question. '"But, your honor it's not fair.
                            He wants to make me commit myself, because he knows my evidence will tell against him.' " '
                            Exactly so, says the counsel, blandly smiling. "'What,' asked the judge, ' do you mean by
                            making you commit yourself?' " ' Why, your honor, he wants me to disqualify myself for being
                            sworn as a witness, by acknowledging that I believe in the Divine authority of a book that
                            contains a positive injunction against swearing at all 1' " On hearing this most unexpected
                            reply, the lawyer answered the judge's inquiring smile by throwing himself back in his seat,
                            and declining to oppose the witness. " Does it not seem strange that the very truthfulness
                            which would induce a man to acknowledge his disbelief should be used to discredit him ? "It
                            seems to me absolutely certain that a little advance in the public intelligence will cause
                            the oath to be discarded altogether. As an appeal to the supernatural it really means
                            nothing, and as a legal contract it might be made equally binding, and less
                            objectionable."—The Index.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Two orders" TEIform="index"/>TWO ORDERS</head><p TEIform="p">" Howbeit, that was not first which is spiritual, but that which is natural, and afterward
                            that which is spiritual." 1 Cor. 15 : 40. First Adam — male and female (" and he called
                            their name Adam") the father and mother of the natural creation, the generators— the sowers
                            of the seed. Then Christ, also male and female (" He that hath the Bride is the
                            Bridegroom"-—"Adam, a figure of him that was to come "), the father and mother of the
                            spiritual creation — the regenerators — the reapers of the harvest. " There is a time to
                            sow, and a time to reap," spiritually as well as naturally, human beings, as well as wheat
                            and corn. (" The harvest truly is plenteous, but the laborers are few." etc. " Thrust in thy
                            sickle, and reap ; for the time is come for thee to reap ; for the harvest of the earth is
                            ripe.") There is a begetting, quickening, and birth, spiritually as well as naturally (" Ye
                            must be born again "), and equally as necessary are the father and mother in the spiritual
                            as in the natural creation ; and, as we had no choice as to who should beget and bring us
                            forth naturally, neither will we be consulted as to who shall be our spiritual parents ;
                            and, when we are compelled by the angels to enter the womb of the Spirit (a Shaker Society),
                            let us become " as clay in the hands of the potter," and " honor our father and mother,"
                            then God, through his Order, will travail, and in due season bring us forth spiritual beings
                            — angels. The followers of Adam " marry and are given in marriage" ("marriage is honorable
                            in all " natural people); but the followers of Christ make themselves virgins and " eunuchs
                            for the kingdom of heaven's sake." The hundred and forty and four thousand, who stood with
                            the Lamb on Mount Zion, were virgins, not married people — " not defiled with women," or
                            men. Brother John neglected to mention that there were some of both sexes not defiled,"
                            because, like Paul, he then only " knew in part," and " saw through a glass darkly." The
                            prophecy " That the Bride should appear, and she coming forth shall be seen that is now
                            withdrawn from the earth " (Esdras, 7 : 26), was not understood by him at that period of his
                            pilgrimage. Remember, there is a natural and there is a spiritual life: and that one must be
                            sacrificed for the other. " Whosoever will save his (generative) life, shall lose it (his
                            spiritual life); but whosoever shall lose (sacrifice) his (generative) life, for my sake,
                            and the Gospel, the same shall save it" (his spiritual life). But such as are content, and
                            of choice prefer to follow Adam in the natural, generative life, let them sacredly observe
                            the laws of God for that order, which are " Do justly, love mercy, and walk humbly," using
                            their generative powers and faculties to " glorify God," not for pleasure; and let them
                            teach the same to others; then (if you have not been called to a higher life) the blessing
                            and protection of God will rest upon you as natural people, and you will be among that
                            number who (Paul says) " do well." If, however, you feel " drawn of <pb n="92" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 92
                            SHAKEE A.ISTD the Father " to follow Christ in the regeneration, you must forsake father and
                            mother, brother and sister, wife and children, lay your possessions at the feet of the
                            Apostles (as did the primitive Christians), confess your sins, take up your cross daily,
                            and, by patience and perseverance, clothe your spirit with the " wedding garment" of purity
                            and holiness. This will entitle you to be classed among that number who (Paul says) " do
                            better." " Except ye be converted {to this faith) and become as a little child (harmless and
                            confiding), ye cannot enter into the kingdom of heaven," you may try your best, but the laws
                            governing the spiritual, are like the laws governing the material — unchangeable. And such
                            as seek to carry their lust, private property, natural kindred, etc., etc., along with them,
                            will never enter the kingdom of heaven, nor have it enter them; but, sooner or later, will
                            find themselves among those, " many (that) shall seek to enter in, but shall not be able."
                            Therefore act wisely, sit down and " count the cost," " choose ye this day," which of the
                            two orders you will cast your lot with, and then religiously keep the laws given to govern
                            in that order. If you will do this, in the fear and love of God, their blessing and
                            protection will rest upon you by day and by night, in things temporal and in things spiri-
                            tual ; you will be an honor to your race, and will find yourself in the hollow of God's
                            hand, when their " time of times " shall pass over this planet, and over the creatures
                            dwelling upon it.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cooper, J. R." TEIform="persName"/>J. R. Cooper, South Union, Ky.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vision" TEIform="index"/>VISION</head><p TEIform="p">On or about the middle of November, 1870, upon retiring to rest at night, and closing my eyes
                            (being still awake) the following scene, or vision, appeared before me : In the first place,
                            I saw the Throne of God, and from thence a descending plane, reaching as far as my eye could
                            extend, down to the region of darkness. Upon this plane there appeared a vast multitude of
                            platforms, ascending one above the other, from the lowest progressively upward toward the
                            Throne, which appeared like a dazzling cloud of Light and Glory, extending in length across
                            the end of the plane, thus : and was cov~~-------------------------eredwithsucb Throne,
                            indescr i b a b 1 e Platforms. brightness, and so enshrouding the ____________________
                            Almighty, that He___________________ could not be seen. At--------------------------the
                            lower end of the plane, adjoining the dark_______________ regions, there
                            appeared______________ upon the first platform ,-----------------souls who had just entered
                            thereon, upon whom there was ~ a small measure of light shining_________ which enabled them
                            to see some-----------of their gross and sensual abomina---------tions. Upon the next
                            platform above them appeared more light shining ___ upon its occupants; and so it continued
                            to increase upon each ascending plat-— form toward the Throne of God. And, as souls upon one
                            platform faithfully improved the talents committed to them, it formed their credentials for
                            advancing to higher ones ; but, if they had not improved their talents, the^r light became
                            darkness, and they were rejected. The upper platforms toward the Throne appeared radiant
                            with light and glory, which shone upon the occupants as if the work of regeneration with
                            them was nearly or quite accomplished. I had no distinct view of Christ in his full manhood
                            as a person, but was impressed with a feeling that he sat at the right hand of the Throne,
                            and facing the Resurrection plane, and was there ruling and reigning over redemption's work,
                            and putting all things under his feet, which, when done, his Mediatorial Office will cease,
                            and he will give up the kingdom to the Father, and God will become all in all* Among the
                            multitude of souls I saw, I recognized none that I knew in the form except Elder Ebenezer
                            Bishop. He was in the front rank, and at the right hand of one of the platforms, and I was
                            not far from him, upon a space not occupied by disembodied spirits ; and while I stood
                            there, those upon that platform went forth in the worship of God, with their faces toward
                            the Throne; and, as this mighty host moved forward in the dance, the manifest strength,
                            life, and energy of their spirits were grand and sublime ; and the peace, love, and
                            harmonious feeling which pervaded their ranks, and which they wafted over upon me, was
                            beyond description ; it filled my soul with heavenly joy and delight; and I said to myself,
                            " This is heaven complete; I can ask for nothing more !" At this time I thought the greatest
                            pleasures, honors and riches, that the world could bestow, presented themselves to my view,
                            and they appeared so insignificant and worthless, that, even if they were not transient in
                            their nature and duration, I wondered that any intelligent soul could for a moment desire
                            them. * As the process of creation will never cease, and natural men and women will forever
                            be coming into existence, so the end of the world, and of the works of salvation,
                            redemption, resurrection, and the all in all in God, can apply only to individuals, to
                            nations, to races, and to globes, The human personality, in this vision, arose from an
                            educational and theological bias, which, in all of us, is as flavor (given from casks) to
                            the wine of inspiration. Christ, as a plane of Deiflc, spiritual, and heavenly
                            Intelligences, is infinitely superior to Jesus or Ann, as mere personalities. And Mother Ann
                            said, " Do not build your faith upon me, but upon the Gift of God : — That can never
                            fail.'"— Ed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>Richard Bushnell, Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Settled at last!" TEIform="index"/>SETTLED AT LAST!</head><p TEIform="p">It will be seen by the following from the Christian Union, that " the vexed question " of the
                            reading of the Bible in the public schools, has been settled in Ohio, and settled right—that
                            is, against the Bible: At length, after a tedious experience of legal delays and
                            uncertainties, the resolution of the Cincinnati School Board, prohibiting the reading of the
                            Bible in the common schools, has gone into effect. The resolution was adopted Nov. 1,1869 ;
                            and its operation as a law began September 1,1873, the Supreme Court of Ohio having
                            dissolved the injunction against the board which the superior court had granted. The
                            principle of this decision will eventually be accepted by Protestants generally as a true
                            definition of the relations between Clrirch and State in a Republican Government. It
                            presents, moreover, the only basis on which it will be found possible to defend the common
                            school system against its most insidious foes. So far so good. Now, if there is praying and
                            any kind of religious reading in those schools, let that be prohibited also, and confined to
                            the churches; and then the schools, being placed on a secular basis, justice will be done to
                            all parties, and the sectarians will no longer have an opportunity to " rule or ruin "
                            thebest institutions in the country.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lo, wisdom calls!" TEIform="index"/>L0, WISDOM CALLS!</head><p TEIform="p">Benign 's the call. List, Wisdom's voice ! Come up, true life enjoy. Flee false and base,
                            obscene, unchaste, Which life and peace destroy : Leave death's dark shades, where lost, be-
                            tray'd, Thro' pleasure's luring guise ; Come up, frail man, thro' heaven's just plan, To
                            life divine arise. Pure, peaceful minds, discreet, benign, Oppression, wars, disown ; From
                            discord cease, so cherish peace ; Good will, good cheer have grown : True patience grown ;
                            ne'er frown, ne'er scold, Though friends or foes annoy ; Though long opposed, and tried like
                            gold, Mild suasions still employ. True friends to all, from loss and thrall Would extricate
                            the race. Bless'd Wisdom calls, wins, gently draws, Through renovating grace. List, heed the
                            call; rise from the fall, Progressing upward, on : Weights, idols, cast, and speed on fast:
                            Go free ; discard all wrong. Oh, let's well heed, press on with speed, In truth, in spirit
                            rise ; Christ quickens, guides, with oil provides Chaste virgins, pure and wise. Thus all
                            who toil taste blissful joys — Hope, gladness, love, peace, rest: These live the Christ,
                            true virgin life, Are truly greatly blest. The faithful, wise, advancing, rise, The uphill
                            grade still tread; These fain would warn the proud who scorn, Who're willing captives led :
                            Oh, pause, reflect, false life reject; Thence, prove true life indeed : The truth reclaims
                            from error's chains, Hence captives thus are freed ! Progressive minds, grown lib'ral, kind.
                            More needy ones befriend ; While Christ refines with fire divine, These toil, progress,
                            ascend. While now's our day, who 'd long delay ? Let's hasten, lo, the prize ! From vice
                            refrain, so win, maintain The life that never dies.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Slack, Dyer" TEIform="persName"/>Dyer Slack, Enfield, Ct.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Muscle and brain" TEIform="index"/>MUSCLE AND BRAIN</head><p TEIform="p">Work.— In the end of a Cycle, muscle and brain become too much separated. In the forming of a
                            new Cycle, which is ever effected by a new revelation, muscle and brain are again brought
                            into united activity. Adam and Eve were set, not merely to speculate upon the infinite
                            botanical and zoological varieties of the garden of the Earth, but to dress and keep it in
                            order—to work. The Egypians had become utterly separated into brain-workers and
                            muscle-workers. The God of the Hebrews laid the foundation of a new social system among the
                            Israelites in re-united brain and muscle-works. He made life itself, to each individual,
                            dependent upon muscle — hand and finger labor — no exceptions to the law, Gather your own
                            food, or die. Manna and labor were inseparable. Under that ruling, all had some opportunity
                            for brain-labor. The Apostolic decision, that "He who would not work, neither shall he eat,"
                            was under the same law. It may be noted, that, Avhen professed Christians had divorced Brain
                            and Muscle, they had also divorced their diluted Gospel from the "spiritual gifts" by which
                            the early, working Christians had been distinguished from the world.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="With hearts sincere and true..." TEIform="index"/>With hearts sincere and true...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">With hearts sincere and true, let us draw nigh, With faith's assurance, which will never die,
                            Having a conscience chaste and pure within, The inward body wash'd from stains of sin. In
                            our profession, let us e'er endure ; For God is faithful, and his promise sure, Let us
                            consider one another's needs, Provoking unto love, good works, and deeds. O Time ! Time,
                            where dost thou take thy flight? Where thoughtless mortals to me have no right.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. Calver, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="93" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: physical and spiritual" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: PHYSICAL AND SPIRITUAL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">If all strong-minded men and women who have the ability and the means of acquiring knowledge,
                            would "apply their hearts unto wisdom," and use that knowledge unselfishly, for the benefit
                            of the many, and in that way help to bear the infirmities of the weak, what a change would
                            be wrought in society ! By degrees, capital and labor would be brought intojust relations.
                            It is true that science and art have projected many agricultural and other labor-saving
                            implements, by which the soil is made more productive. But, could laborers feel the
                            assurance of a just return from capitalists, for services rendered, it would be a great
                            incentive to industry; and the earth, by proper cultivation, might be redeemed from its
                            present thorn-and-brier-producing condition, and an Eden formed, of far more than pristine
                            beauty. But it has been truly said, that " great men are not always wise or just." The
                            Creative Intelligence that formed the worlds, and created beings with the germs of
                            immortality to inhabit them, is superior to the things and beings created. And it is evident
                            that the good Father and Mother of all souls designed that their children should grow in
                            wisdom and knowledge from age to age, and be fashioned into their likeness; and that they
                            should study to comprehend the laws pertaining to physical life; and how to use, and not
                            abuse, earth's fullness of blessings, so amply provided for man and beast. What greater
                            evidence of the love and wisdom of God do we need than has been given? " The heavens declare
                            his glory; the firmament showeth his handy-work; " and his voice may be heard through all
                            his works. The great luminary, hung out from above, shedding its golden rays, and giving
                            light which rules the day, is God's blessing to humanity; it is the appropriate time to
                            work. The night also has its share of blessing for man and beast. The moon and stars shed a
                            silvery subdued light, which brings a feeling of quiet and repose, and is a signal for rest.
                            Sleep is Nature's balm—a wise provision. The earth pours forth its rich treasures with a
                            lavish hand. But a wise Providence has decreed that every blessing shall be obtained by
                            labor. The intellectual (as well as the physical) powers are given for use, under the
                            guidance of just and immutable laws. When capital and labor, and science and art, combine
                            and operate harmoniously together, we obtain great results. Geology has penetrated the
                            earth, and brought forth hidden treasures — gold, silver, and precious stones; and
                            subterraneous caverns send up oil in great profusion; while exhaustless beds of coal are
                            unearthed: all for man's use. Our great forests, one by one, have yielded to the woodman's
                            ax, and have been used for fuel, or for buildings, and other purposes; and our beautiful
                            hills, once covered with stately trees, are now occupied by the agriculturist; yet we do not
                            fear for the future ; for coal supplies the place of wood for fuel; and iron, stone, and
                            clay, are used for building purposes. Floating palaces, constructed of iron and wood, are
                            seen on all seas, bearing the flags of every nation; and thousands of human beings are
                            continually borne upon the waters of the fathomless deep from shore to shore. It no longer
                            requires a Prophet of the Lord, with a divining rod, to cause iron to swim. Great powers are
                            given to men and women ; and they will use them for either good or evil purposes; and (we
                            repeat), if, on the natural earthly plane of existence, all would learn to he just, what a
                            terrestrial Paradise might be created. Then, under the action of the physical and spiritual
                            elements, human beings would be peaceful and happy, until (to use the similitude of a field
                            of grain in process of ripening) ready for the harvesting angel, with the sickle of
                            spiritual truth, to cut them off from the field of nature, and gather them from the
                            generative to the higher plane of divine light, and spiritual life. Then they would
                            recognize the primitive intention of, and the necessity for, two orders of human beings —
                            the natural and the spiritual; which (now) can only with great difficulty be brought to the
                            comprehension of the people. If natural laws, in reference to reproduction, were properly
                            regarded, and men would learn to be brothers the world over, then wars would cease to the
                            ends of the earth; and warriors would turn to the peaceful pursuits of industry, beating
                            their swords into agricultural implements; and while, on the one hand, there would be no
                            fears that the earth would be over populated, rendering war. pestilence, and famine
                            "necessary evils," by which to thin off the inhabitants; nor, on the other hand, that the
                            existence of a pure celibate Order, like that of the Shakers, would depopulate the earth.
                            But. while the natural man and woman would be doing their work, if guided by the law of use,
                            instead of carnal pleasure, in reproduction, they would bless the spiritual Order, whose
                            portals are ever open to receive those who have progressed beyond the natural, and are
                            prepared to enter upon the angelic life, where they can study and learn the laws pertaining
                            to the kingdom of Christ. If the development of natural laws, which pertain to the outward
                            visible world, be worthy of so much attention from scientists, who can define and measure
                            the duty of the spiritual man and woman, and the importance of their studying to comprehend
                            the laws of the inner world, and the life that is eternal, and to know what is good and true
                            for themselves, and not blindly follow the traditions of their fore-fathers; but constantly
                            be seeking out new fountains of living waters. New facts and events are daily occurring in
                            the outward world of mind and matter; and, as there are new revealments in the natural arts
                            and sciences, and new modes of thought and experience, to meet all such emergencies, so is
                            it in a spiritual point of view; the unfolding laws of the invisible world, and of the
                            higher life, require the revelation of new truths, new thoughts, and new modes of
                            application. Truth does not change! But, as the finite mind grows and expands, and reaches
                            out toward the Infinite, throwing off the grosser and more material forms of thought, its
                            views and conceptions of the Spiritual and Divine become more and more enlarged and
                            celestial.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><p TEIform="p">We confidently expect that our noble-hearted brother (Elder Wm. Leonard) will forgive us for
                            making a few extracts, without permission, from a lengthy and valuable communication from
                            his pen, which was not designed for publication. To us it was a jewel when received ; and it
                            was placed in our casket us such ; and we feel quite certain that it would be interesting
                            and instructive to many of the readers of our " Monthly ; " but it is too pro- lix to
                            publish in its entirety. Yet we hope that even the fragmentary presentation thereof will not
                            lessen its illustrative force, nor mar its symmetrical beauty.</p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Beloved Eldress Antoinette," TEIform="index"/>Beloved Eldress Antoinette,</head><p TEIform="p">I received your kind letter by due course of ma.il, and was right glad to hear from you
                                and our dear friends at the Mount. I have read it over many times, and have tried to
                                feel guilty for my negligence in not writing before the present time ; but, if I had
                                done so, perhaps 1 should not have received your kind epistle, which has stirred my
                                dying or wandering memory ; and I am really puzzled to determine whether to feel guilty
                                or otherwise. Of one thing, however, you may be assured: it was not a lack of true
                                loA^e, or pure Gospel affection, that prevented. I have, from early memory, had many
                                evidences that I was created to think and feel; and, like many others of my
                                fellow-pilgrims of impulsive heart, and visionary brain, at times, I love to talk, and
                                to write my intuitions and new-born imaginings. Persons of such a temperament naturally
                                love those who are willing to hear them patiently, and who will respond to them
                                affectionately and kindly. I am under many obligations to my friends at the North
                                Family, for the charitable reviews, and pleasant responses to my eccentric theorizing,
                                and visionary dreamings ; and, though numerous sheets have passed between us, I have the
                                calm satisfaction of believing that not one discordant feeling has ever arisen to mar
                                our union and tranquillity. My frank, honest difference of opinion, on minor subjects,
                                have ever been met with that wise, calm, and harmonious spirit, that rendered even
                                quarreling a pastime, and fighting quite a Christian amusement. There is a joy in in-
                                terchanging thoughts and gifts with true and tried friends; they serve to uplift and
                                cheer the spirit, and harmonize soul with soul. Now, my friend, you will agree to pardon
                                me, if I turn my theme into a somewhat theological strain ; I feel like writing a long
                                letter, if you will be patient with me. When looking out from the windows of Zion, upon
                                the outward spiritual horizon, an inspiration steals over my spirit like the glowing
                                fires of heaven. I do not feel a restless anxiety for the future ; distrustful, unhappy
                                forebodings have passed from my mind. I never saw the final advancement of God's work
                                look more bright and cheering in the distance than now ; the signs of the times are
                                marvellously changing ; they may appear new and strange, but they agree with the
                                visitations of God to men, when compared with past history, by which we learn of his
                                dealings with the old world, through the mediumship of Noah ; and, when He de- termined
                                to enlarge and liberate the tribes of Israel, He visited them through the spirits of the
                                ancient fathers; and, next, mighty shocks of spirit-power were felt in Egypt, and the
                                surrounding nations ; and there was a slow but sure class of spirit-manifestations
                                peculiar to the age and condition of the old chosen line of those days. When the reign
                                of Judaism was about closing, John, under the inspiration of the welltried, noble spirit
                                of Elijah, lit up the torchlight of revelation anew, which helped to dispel the darkness
                                of the whole country. <pb n="94" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 8HAKEE A.ND Again, when the first dawn of
                                Christ's kingdom was to break forth, a higher power and word of God came to Jesus, which
                                animated the angels to sing " Glory in the highest." The same power extended to the
                                twelve foundation pillars of the Jewish Christian Church. The Christ Spirit, at that
                                time, was limited to the Hebrew line; and, when the disciples were sent out to preach,
                                Jesus charged them, saying, " Go not into the way of the Gentiles ; and into any city of
                                the Samaritans enter ye not; but go rather to the lost sheep of the house of Israel; and
                                as ye go, preach, saying, The kingdom of heaven is at hand." Upon a time, as Jesus was
                                crossing from Jerusalem to Galilee, and was passing through the suburbs of the ancient
                                city of Sychar, wearied beneath the scorching sun-beams, he sat down by Jacob's well,
                                for rest and refreshment ; and a woman of Samaria came to draw water. Gentile as she
                                was, and coming from one of the forbidden cities, yet, by spirit impulse he was
                                attracted to her ; and, when she rebuked him for asking water of a Samaritan, lie was so
                                pleased with her candor, that he conversed with her freely, and in a manner that reached
                                her understanding; and she went and called others, saying, " Come and see a man that has
                                told me all things that ever I did. Is not this the Christ ? " This seems to have been
                                the first kindling spark of Gospel fire among the Gentiles. Ever after that
                                introduction, Jesus showed a marked attachment to that people. Perhaps he was the only
                                living Jew who, at that time, truly loved a Samaritan. When he healed ten lepers, none
                                but a Samaritan returned to bow in acknow- ledgment of, and to thank God for, the favor;
                                and Jesus did not omit to call the attention of the Jews to this fact. In his parable of
                                the man who fell among thieves, and of the conduct of the priest and Levite towards him
                                (while the good Samaritan, instead of keeping his gloves on, and passing by on the other
                                side, as the priest and Levite did, had compassion on him, stooped down and examined his
                                wounds, and kindly bound them up), he taught that God is not a respecter of nations or
                                persons, but of character. And he gave his disciples to understand, that, as soon as
                                they had performed their first duty to the Jews, his Samaritan children were the next
                                class to be attended to. He said: " Ye shall receive the Holy Ghost, and shall be
                                witnesses unto me in all Judea ; next, in Samaria ; then to the uttermost parts of the
                                earth." They caught the inspiration, and, with souls all aglow with revelation from the
                                spirit-spheres, " they went everywhere preaching the Gospel of the kingdom." What a
                                marked manifestation of spirit-power was given at the time when Saul of Tarsus,
                                undertook to beat down the Christian work! He was, without doubt, honest in his
                                intentions, when he determined, under priestly sanction, to kindle the fires of
                                persecution at Damascus ; but he was met in such a manner, when a light flashed upon
                                him, and he was smitten by an unseen hand, and heard a voice saying, " Saul, Saul, why
                                persecutest thou me ? " that he was convinced of his mistake, (and O how quickly he
                                turned his energies in the right direction, and, after his conversion to the Christian
                                religion, became a fortress of strength), and proved to be one of the greatest
                                revelationists that ever existed. He was a leader of leaders, a torrent of eloquence,
                                and as immovable as Mount Zion. Each of the disciples of Jesus was called to perform a
                                certain work, and spirit-power attended their labors. If in former ages there was a host
                                of spiritual mediums, an abundance of prophecies and a gradual growth from small
                                beginnings, need we despair ? Since this large continent was discovered, great changes
                                and modifications have been wrought, and a new form of Civil Government is established.
                                Through the mediumship of the French prophets, the spirits worked; and from them Ann Lee
                                was brought forth, who was after- ward anointed to be our spiritual Mother. The powers
                                of the heavens hastened her work ; and, by revelation, she came to America, and the
                                Church of Christ's Second Appearing be- gan to be established, while a free Civil
                                Government was also in process of formation. This Church has stood as an inside wheel
                                that fits into the wheel of the new outside, Government, and the one has turned the
                                other till it has become too visible to be longer concealed; for the light and spiritual
                                influence of this Church is seen and felt throughout the nation, and in other nations.
                                The reforms of the last century started with the American people, and have been produced
                                by the life-germs, or spirit lights, of the age, who had their highest existence in the
                                Church. Modern Spiritualism began its work on the inner wheel, and was carried out by
                                spirit-messengers, to do its work in the outside order. The spirits who were
                                commissioned to do the first work in Zion, predicted its universal spread; and now we
                                see a mighty upspringing of every species and order of mediums for both good and bad
                                spirits to work through ; but the same power that commenced the work, will bring order
                                out of chaos — divide the false from the true — and will kindle in honest souls the
                                fires of judgment, and thus purify them as gold is made pure by furnace heat, and will
                                fit them to be indwellers and workers in God's holy Christian Temple, which, in its dual
                                form, has started for a heavenly growth into order and beauty; and of its increase there
                                will be no end. Some of my friends here, who have heard this, my epistle of forty pages
                                to you, think I have fully canceled all former debts that I may have incurred by not
                                answering letters from you ; and I guess you will think so too. Please accept love and
                                kindly greetings, from Elders, and Brethren and Sisters, who send it liberally for
                                yourself, and all of our dear friends at Mount Lebanon. Your Brother in the Gospel,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>William Leonard, Harvard, Mass.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="In every thing give thanks" TEIform="index"/>"IN EVERY THING GIVE THANKS."</head><p TEIform="p">At this season of the year, when so many outward blessings are showering from the hand of the
                            good Husbandman, we feel that " praise is comely " for all. And to us, who not only have
                            found a Father but an ever-loving Mother, what measureless call for gratitude, that not only
                            now will the strong and vigorous in the spiritual household find support, but the poor and
                            oppressed share of her love and sympathy. Thanks for a Gospel that approximates to justice,
                            and, while it acknowledges the universal brotherhood, is striving to reduce it to living
                            practice ; that knows " nor high nor low, nor rich nor poor, male nor female, but all one,"
                            etc. " Exalting the valleys " by " bringing the mountains down." Thanks for a spot on earth
                            where virtue and innocence can be preserved, and rank higher in value than stocks or
                            exchange. Thanks for a home where labor is honored, and consecrated toil and uses are the
                            gauge of honor and respect. Thanks for a love that is pure ; and for "the hundred-fold" of
                            brothers and sisters, which compensate the forsaking of the natural and earthly. Thanks for
                            the " banishing to the desert of forgetfulness," which succeeds the washing in Jordan (the
                            river of Judgment); and for the cheering of spirits from the unseen, and the hopes of
                            re-union in the spirit world. And highest thanks that, for poor suffering humanity, there is
                            such a way of becoming sons and daughters of God, without rebuke.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Elizabeth H." TEIform="persName"/>Elizabeth H. Webster, Harvard.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The isolated efforts of individuals can accomplish no more now than formerly..." TEIform="index"/>The isolated efforts of individuals can accomplish no more now than formerly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The isolated efforts of individuals can accomplish no more now than formerly. Therefore it is
                            an age of unions, combinations and leagues, pointing to the only avenue of advance to a
                            higher order, viz., through a united and consecrated interest. We may also include as
                            indications, the associated efforts of Bible, Missionary, and Peace Societies, all of which
                            have started into operation since the Church of Christ's Second Appearing was established.
                            Many can "run to and fro" and knowledge may be increased, but knowledge alone, irre-
                            spective of quality and use, cannot confer happiness. Knowledge is communicable. Wisdom is
                            acquired by applying knowledge to use. The higher the knowledge, the more excellent the
                            wisdom attained bvits exercise.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For the shakeress" TEIform="index"/>For the Shakeress</head><p TEIform="p">Feeling that I am a debtor to all lovers of truth in the preceding Dispensation, who, by a
                            life of self-denial, strove to vindicate and uphold the work of righteousness on the earth,
                            I would gladly give a fitting expression of my gratitude therefor, and honor the past; and
                            also give my testimony to strengthen the present; and to help (in my humble way) any sincere
                            soul, who may be looking among the lo heres and lo theres, to find the Christ of God that
                            can give true rest unto souls. The years of my pilgrimage on earth number fourscore,
                            fifty-six of which have been spent with Believers, or Shakers. In practical obedience to the
                            truths taught and lived by all who are true to their profession, I have seen the travail of
                            my soul in the work of regeneration ; and, as I have progressed " from faith to faith," I
                            have also received increasing light and power to work the works of righteousness, and am now
                            reaping the fruits thereof, which are peace and rest to the immortal part, that I know a
                            life in sinful indulgence could never give. And I have witnessed the operation and effect
                            upon others with whom I have been associated, and I can testify that I am satisfied with the
                            goodness of God through the Gospel of Christ in the first and second appearing. I am
                            conscious that I am now nearing the end of my sojourn in time ; but I feel a bright hope for
                            the future ; and, although my physical strength is waning, yet in spirit I am joyful; I feel
                            thai the prediction of the prophet Jeremiah is being fulfilled in our time, when the "
                            virgin " sons and daughters of " Zion can go forth in the dances of them that make merry,
                            both old and young together, and sing in the heights of Zion," and partake of the goodly
                            feast of " wheat, and oil, and wine" of the kingdom, until "their souls are as a watered
                            garden." My feelings go out in love to, and in prayer for, all honest truth seekers, that
                            they may be led, as / was, to renounce the inferior pleasures of time and sense, and learn,
                            to live to God and die to sin; and, through obedience to truth, fit themselves for the
                            society of angels in the Heavenly Father and Mother's kingdom in the world to come.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Crosman, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna Crosman, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good resolutions are safeguards to the soul..." TEIform="index"/>Good resolutions are safeguards to the soul...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Good resolutions are safeguards to the soul — God's blessings are limitless as the twink-
                            ling lights that spangle the vast arch above, or the sands of the sea. Every thing in na-
                            ture's realm, evinces an overruling supernatural power. The smallest insect his goodness
                            shares. The birds carrol their sweetest notes to Him who gave them life, swelling their
                            little throats to the fullest extent, reminding us of the musical fullness of the spheres.
                            And the running streamlet, as it ripples over hill and dale, sings a merry song; it may be
                            shallow at its source, but it finds its way to rivers and lakes, and its terminus is the
                            deep blue sea. Every drop of this vast body of water contains animal life ; and if the tiny
                            aquatics were asked why they were so lively, they would reply, in their language, " Because
                            we have nothing but water to drink." Would that many human beings might reply in the same
                            language who are now wedded to the wine cup, or bound in the demoniac chains of Alcohol!
                            Alas, that man who was made to govern himself, and rule over the lower orders of animal
                            life, sinks himself below the beasts that perish! 0 that intemperance might flee the land.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., Margaret" TEIform="persName"/>Margaret C.</byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Meeting" TEIform="index"/>MEETING</head><p TEIform="p">J. M. PEEBLES, on behalf of the Spiritualists of J¥ew York City, has asked to have a
                            Deputation of Shakers attend one or more of their Gatherings, on the 23d instant; and Elder
                            F. W. Evans, with a Company of Brethren and Sisters from the Three Novitiate Families of
                            Mount Lebanon, and Elder G. A. Loomis, with a Company from Watervliet, are expected to be
                            present. For particulars, as to Hall, hour, &amp;c, see public advertisement.</p></div2><pb n="95" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituary" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><p TEIform="p">In looking over the obituary notices in the " Shaker and Shakeress " of 1873, up to Octo-
                            ber, we find the names of a large number recorded, who have been as bright stars in Zion, to
                            illumine her spiritual horizon, whose light, to the external perception, has now gone out;
                            but through faith we behold them shining with increased brilliancy in purer, brighter
                            spheres. The majority of them lived to a ripe age; yet, how much they are missed from our
                            circles ! Each Family and Society had learned to love, and appreciate them for their Avorks'
                            sake; they knew their worth, and have felt their loss. It has not been customary for
                            Believers to eulogize, by word, their dear departed Gospel friends to any great extent; but
                            rather strive to profit by their godly lives and teachings, and to have their bright
                            examples shine upon our pathway, and light our course heavenward, that we may know how to
                            walk in their footsteps and follow them, as they have followed Christ. We are certain that a
                            biographical account of many of those worthy saints who have been harvested from earth, and
                            gathered to their spirit home, would be very interesting and satisfactory to Believers who
                            have known them personally, or by reputation; and, had we inserted all the love tokens in
                            the columns of the " Shaker and Shakeress" that have been sent to us by surviving friends,
                            they would have occupied a large space. We have loved and admired the feelings which
                            prompted such beautiful and affectionate tributes to the memory of dear departed ones ; and
                            would gladly have gratified the wishes of each contributor in publishing them, as well as to
                            have satisfied the feelings of many of the readers of our little sheet by so doing, had it
                            been practicable. But the lives of Believers in Christ's second appearing are so veiled from
                            the outside world, that they seldom know one Shaker from another; except, perhaps, in the
                            vicinity, or in the adjacent towns they may be known to neighbors and friends. As they take
                            no part in politics, they have no political record to present; nor do they imbrue their
                            hands in the blood of their fellow men, believing that Christians cannot, will not, fight.
                            Hence the warrior's fame and glory (such as it is) does not rest upon them; and, having
                            forsaken the natural, generative order of marriage, for the higher— the angelic — Christian
                            order and life, it may be said of them as it was said of Jesus: "Who shall declare his
                            generation?" Like him, the Shakers have none. Seeing we differ so widely from worldly
                            Christians, upon all of those essential points, how could we make up lengthy obituary
                            notices of our brethren and sisters that would be edifying and interesting to subscribers in
                            the outside order, who know nothing of the individuals of whom we are speaking, however
                            illustrious their lives may have been to us? Our worthy sister Abigail Munson, who attained
                            to the age of 102 (lacking a few days), how much might have been said of her good deeds, her
                            godly example, and great worth, by those who knew her best. We received an obituary on the
                            demise of Elder J. R. Eades, which occurred at South Union, Ky., August 27, which was
                            written in a beautiful spirit, by sister Jane Cowan of the same place, descriptive of his
                            moral worth — his spiritual attainments — his consecrated life, and devotion to truth ; and
                            how much he was beloved by the little flock, of which he had been a faithful leader many
                            years, and how deeply they felt his loss! We also received a poem upon the same subject
                            written by Sister Lucy Shannon; all showing how they loved him in life, and honored him in
                            death. Such bright spirits as Elder D. J. Hawkins, Sister Charity Palmer, Elder R. W.
                            Pelham, Brother J. Dean, and many more that we might mention, whose names are sealed in
                            heaven, for they are written in the book of life, to be read by their Brethren and Sisters,
                            have all left worthy records. And while we view the way-marks they have left behind, they
                            will live in the hearts' affections of their Gospel kindred while memory shall last. It may
                            not be amiss to restate the ages of those who have gone from the ranks of the eighteen
                            Societies of Believers to their homes in the spirit spheres within the last ten months. The
                            ages of two, we did not get; but understand they were well advanced in life. Over one
                            hundred years of age..... 1 Between ninety and a hundred..... 5 do eighty and ninety........
                            8 do seventy and eighty....... 12 do sixty and seventy........ 4 do fifty and
                            sixty........... 3 do forty and fifty........... 1 do thirty and forty.......... 1 Under
                            thirty..................... 2</p></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nature cures, if cure there be" TEIform="index"/>NATURE CURES, IF CURE THERE BE</head><p TEIform="p">In all systems of error there is a starting-point usually made by a false assumption. This is
                            palpable in the drug theory. Assuming that disease is an enemy which a new drug disease may
                            vanquish, patients are dosed into tedious pains, fevers, and too often premature graves. Dr.
                            Trail's lucid pen has recently shown, that neither Seward nor Greeley died of natural
                            disease, nor yet of a mysterious Providence, but of poisonous drugs. Similar fatal
                            administrations ended the days of Washington, Harrison, Taylor, and multitudes of eminent
                            sufferers, including millions of the obscure, whose lives, in one sense, were none the less
                            precious. The germ, as we have said, of this poisonous system is, that nature don't or won't
                            cure. While the drug theorists are unable to ignore the efforts of nature in this direction,
                            they nevertheless insist that she must be assisted to cure. Hence, under the guise of aid,
                            they embarrass; and on the pretext of removing burdens, they bind on such as are heavier and
                            more crushing ; and, in endeavoring to promote the process of cleansing, they surcharge the
                            body with the foulest matter. As the cause must always be removed to insure a cessation of
                            the effect, so must this baseless assumption of assisting nature, by poisoning, be
                            abandoned, before we can get rid of the destructive medical theory. By eating unclean food,
                            and too much of it, persons are sickened, then druggists proceed to dose down yet more
                            unclean matter to cleanse and cure ! In swallowing bad diet, the laws of health are broken,
                            and disease ensues ; in swallowing yet worse drugs, the laws of health are still more
                            dangerously broken, and too often death ensues. Who in his sober senses can believe that
                            doses which invariably make well persons sick, can make sick persons well? Can filth remove
                            filth? Will Beelzebub the chief, cast out his subordinates ? There is but one way to swallow
                            the drug theory, that is, ostrich-like, to run the head into sand, and force it down blind.
                            Facts, handled by common sense, are as fatal to it as is warm sunshine to ice, or light to
                            darkness. Naked assumptions and despotic authority may sustain the absurdity, while simple
                            truth and reason must overthrow It. — Seience of Health.</p></div2><div2 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker and shakeress" TEIform="index"/>SHAKER AND SHAKERESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Those whose interest in the S. &amp; S. causes them to desire its continued publication,
                            another year, will please signify it by inclosing 50 cts. for 1874, by return of mail, if
                            possible.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Self denial" TEIform="index"/>SELF DENIAL</head><p TEIform="p">Blessed power of self-denial, Source and well-spring of true joy; Walk with me as guardian
                            angel, That no sin my peace destroy. It is natural for the whole human family to seek
                            happiness; all have some God to worship, some Superior Being to look to, for aid, in times
                            of affliction and distress. But how few seek happiness in the right direction ! We are all
                            looking and hoping for a blissful existence beyond the dark river; but, do we consider what
                            we must do tliis side the stream, to gain the lasting joys of that bright land? Are we
                            willing and thankful to bear the cross of Christ, that crucifies us to the world, and robs
                            us of the corruptible joys of sin and carnal indulgences, practising true self-denial in our
                            every-day lives, walking in paths of peace and righteousness, sacrificing the meaner
                            affections of the lower life, owning nothing, yet possessing all things, caring for, and
                            being cared for, in sickness and health, by the good and pure ? If so, then, when this
                            life's journey shall be ended, and we pass on, to that unknown land, having laid up
                            treasures there, we shall not feel like strangers in a strange place ; although we shall
                            have left behind us all that we possessed in this world. True, our clothing will be new, and
                            formed of different materials ; our food will also be of a different nature ; our
                            surroundings too, will be new ; but we shall join kindred friends whom we have previously
                            known on earth ; and, can we have a better recommendation to take with us than the record of
                            a good, upright life, bearing the impress of self-denial and cross-bearing, which is true
                            excellence — a garment formed of good and righteous works, to adorn the immortal part ? When
                            I take somewhat of a realizing view of these things, I think I will never be heard to cry, O
                            the burden, the burden of the cross! the oppression of selfdenial ! striving to bring the
                            way to me, instead of bringing myself to the way; this is beneath my high and holy calling.
                            I will fight the battles of the Lord valiantly, and lay a good foundation—purity and
                            honesty—for my building to stand upon. A builder may erect very elegant and beautiful
                            structures ; but, unless the foundations are firmly and properly laid, they are liable to be
                            wrecked by winds and storms, and finally to become a mass of ruins. " I want to have the
                            Christians' stamp On all that I possess— My conscience, manual labor too, And even on my
                            dress." I want to have good Shaker faith Implanted in my soul; And fain would have good
                            Shaker works Extend from pole to pole. I bless the name, I love the life My Shaker kindred
                            live, I love the true and sure reward A daily cross will give. I love to feel that living
                            power That shakes the soul within— The fire that burns the dregs and dross, Consuming ev'ry
                            sin. I love to hear the living Word, That flows from soul to soul, Cross-bearing ones who
                            daily strive Each passion to control. These are true Shakers; and they shake from ev'ry
                            thing impure, And seek for treasures by the cross, That ever will endure. They bring each
                            hidden deed to light, Kot in a closet dark; But to the witnesses of God, Where rests the
                            sacred Ark. How can we live without the Word, The living Word of God, That resurrects to
                            spirit-life, Points to the narrow road? I love my Shaker Brethren dear, My angel Sisters
                            too; My Shaker home, with all its joys, Is charming to my view; Then, let me live the higher
                            life, And bear the noble name : Make it my chief concern to be Kight worthy of the same.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Smith, Emily" TEIform="persName"/>Emily Smith, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><pb n="96" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas offering" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS OFFERING</head><p TEIform="p">p 1. Sweetest music softly stealing O'er our hearts in tuneful chime, Shall, in joyous notes
                            reTealing, / 2. "Wake we now to joy and gladness, Christ the Saviour we have found; Banish
                            from our hearts all sadness, Swell the song of olden time, When the morning star was
                            beaming, Angels sang of peace and love; And in deeds of love abound. Now the fount of good
                            unsealing, Let us all our souls up fill; Many souls awoke from dreaming, Hail'd the light
                            from Heaven above. Gladsome sound we echo still, p Peace on earth, to all good will. And, in
                            kindly Christian feeling, Breathe sweet peace and speak good will. Gladsome sound we echo
                            still, Peace on earth, to all good will.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Who shall praise God?" TEIform="index"/>WHO SHALL PRAISE GOD ?</head><p TEIform="p">My soul, wake up inspired to sing, And let each thought a tribute bring, And praise our
                            Father's name ; Let earth and heaven join in one song, So sweet, so glorious, and so strong,
                            Of this inspiring theme. Let mountains high, and valleys low, Let verdant plains the music
                            throw, In strains both loud and clear; Our Maker's name we will proclaim From pole to pole,
                            thro' earth's domain, With reverence and fear. Ye angels bright, who wing your way Through
                            mansions of eternal day, Reverberate the sound. O, all the powers of heaven above, Join now
                            with us the song of love, Sweet praises flow around. Ye cedars on the mountain brow, Your
                            towering heads with reverence bow, To him who gave you birth ; Ye little rills that murmur
                            on, Join in the chorus, sweet and long, That gladdens all the earth. Ye flowing rivers which
                            have grown So deep and broad, your voices loan, To sound his holy praise ; And cataracts
                            with thundering roar His glory tell from shore to shore, His wise and prudent ways. Above
                            all these, let those who live A life of innocence and love, Be heard in sweetest tones ; Who
                            love the Lord with all their heart, And from all sin and lust depart; They make the loudest
                            sounds. They set all nature in a blaze ; Men ask, are these the latter days By Jesus Christ
                            foretold? 'Tis something new ; we do not scan How God does purify a man, And liberate the
                            soul. He 's brought to light the living way, And all who 're willing to obey, Do walk the
                            path so straight; They do not err from day to day, But constant watch, and daily pray, To
                            enter heaven's gate. Let those who have repentance found, With peace, and love, and joy
                            abound, And join the glorious song; While those who cover up their sin, Their grief and
                            sorrow then begin ; They cannot join the throng Of the united souls of men Who live to God,
                            and die to sin, And in this death rejoice; But all who bear a daily cross, And by its power
                            are saved from loss, Shall praise Him with one voice.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Barrett, Andrew" TEIform="persName"/>Andrew Barrett, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Elder Richard Bushnell" TEIform="index"/>ELDER RICHARD BUSHNELL</head><p TEIform="p">He brought a glorious manhood to the strife, And gave it freely, with a noble will: He made a
                            consecration of his life, And bade ambition's trumpet-voice be still: For he had powers that
                            would have gain'd the fame, The wealth, the honors, that the world bestows. But better far,
                            to him, was lot and name Among the people that his conscience chose. He came to them with
                            zealous heart and hand, Made all their interests his absorbing care; Strong in his faitli,
                            met persecution's band, Yet held his heart in lowly strains of prayer • The clash of
                            elements that round him rung, Awoke his energies to fight within — To strive for conquest —
                            while his life was young, And evermore to wage a war with sin. In thought, and power to
                            sii'ay, he was a king; He won a royal priesthood by his zeal. His soul was gentle as an
                            angel's wing. Yet it was keen as Truth's incisive steel. Before him, malice (supplicating)
                            knelt, And bitter envy laid her face in dust; While bold assailants lost their rage, and
                            felt To seek for pardon, half convinced they must. He gave forgiveness as the morn gives
                            light; He gave his love as seasons give their fruit; He bless'd with tenderness, rebuked
                            with might Quell'd human passions till their waves were mute. And, when his autumn crimson'd
                            to its close, We saw the garner'd treasures he had found ; We felt his soul's unspeakable
                            repose, And knew his spirit was with vict'ry crown'd. We '11 miss his cheery voice, and
                            kindly smile ; We'll miss the hands whose industry we prize; We '11 call him often, in the
                            little while That from our home to hie so misty lies. O father, as we bid adieu to thee, Our
                            heart-strings vibrate with a plaintive swell: Our love, upwelling, gushing, warm, and free,
                            Shall reach thy spirit wheresoe'er it dwell. What though the years made halos in thy hair,
                            And carved their furrows on thy open brow ; They could not give thy heart one rankling care
                            ; Thy life was true, and thou art Messed now!</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Devyr, Cecelia" TEIform="persName"/>Cecelia Devyr, Mt. Lebanon,</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Try again" TEIform="index"/>TRY AGAIN</head><p TEIform="p">Toiling pilgrim, art thou weary? Doth the path of life seem hard? Are the gleams of hope and
                            courage From thy spirit now debarr'd ? Hath the prayer to Heaven directed, Fail'd to bring
                            thv spirit gain ? Yet, if thou art still protected, Never flinch, but Try again. Have the
                            foes thou wast contending, Over thee some vict'ry gained ? By a dark'ning cloud impending,
                            Hath thy star of guidance waned? Does the binding cross of Jesus Cause thy lofty nature pain
                            ? There 's a balsam for thy spirit, Flinch not, then, but Try again. Mark thy friends who
                            now surround thee, Seeming most like angels pure ; Have they passed these youthful
                            conflicts, Having nothing to endure? Know, my friend, when thou art tempted, Those before
                            have felt the same, And with courage to thee whisper, " Never flinch, but Try again." Try
                            Again ! blest words of courage, What a radiance they impart! When the soul, though met by
                            Failure, Clasps their virtues to the heart, Then, with " Onward " for thy motto, " Upward,"
                            for thy constant aim, Thou canst bear aloft the banner— " Never flinch; but Try Again."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia" TEIform="persName"/>Amelia Calver, Mt. Lebanon</byline></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Curiosities for the centennial" TEIform="index"/>CURIOSITIES FOR THE CENTENNIAL...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">CURIOSITIES FOR THE CENTENNIAL. The Centennial, at Philadelphia, will be a
                                    celebration for which every patriotic man must desire to insure the greatest
                                    possible completeness. Especial attention would he desire to have given to that
                                    twilight period of our history which the Centennial is intended so largely to
                                    commemorate, and which indeed concentrates in itself so much of what is interesting
                                    and romantic in American annals. The readers of our Sunday's issue must have been
                                    gratified to read of a contribution from Maine to the Revolutionary Department of
                                    the Exposition, whicn opens to its managers an entire new field of curious and
                                    delightful interest. At the town of Alfred, in that State, an old lady has been
                                    discovered whose singular and happy fortune it was to be born on the 4th of July,
                                    1776. She is a Shaker, and her name is Lucy Langdon Nowell. It is another of the
                                    virtues of this venerable lady that she has been in a railroad car, and it is
                                    proposed to send her in a Pullman car to adorn the opening of the Centennial on the
                                    4th of July, 1876. It is urged that nothing could be more appropriate or significant
                                    at a festival designed to celebrate the completion of our first century of national
                                    existence than the presence of one whose birth is exactly coeval with our nation's
                                    birth, whose life has shared the vicissitudes of the nation's life, and who has
                                    lived to see the career begun, like her own, in doubt and utter weakness, finish in
                                    the most exalted power.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York times" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Times.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="People talk of originality. What do they mean?..." TEIform="index"/>People talk of originality. What do they mean?...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">People talk of originality. What do they mean ? As soon as we are born, the surrounding world
                            begins to operate upon us, and so unto the end; and, after all, what can we truly call our
                            own but energy, power and will ? Could I point out all I owe to my great forerunner and
                            contemporaries, truly there would remain but little over.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Goethe" TEIform="persName"/>Goethe</byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="index"/>Elder Richard Bushnell
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Bushnell, Richard" TEIform="persName">Elder Richard Bushnell</persName>, October 23, aged
                                82; at Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miller, Daniel" TEIform="index"/>Daniel Miller
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Miller, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Miller, October 10, aged 77; at Union Village,
                                Ohio.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>