<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1006" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">10</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18800601" TEIform="date">June 1880</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">121-144</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="10" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> JUNE, 1880. 60 Cents Per Annum MANIFESTO, G. A. LOMAS, EDITOR, SHAKERS, N. Y. Published by the United Societies. OUR
                        HOME AT HARVARD, MASS. "And they shall turn to you for a testimony ''Go preach the Kingdom of God!" ADDRESS ALL
                        COMMUNICATIONS TO "The Shaker Manifesto, Shakers, N.D." G. B. AVERY, PUBLISHER 1880. Vol. X. no. 6. The Shaker </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
                    --><pb n="121" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Thoughts" TEIform="index"/>THOUGHTS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>MARY WHITCHER</byline><p TEIform="p"> i-ht, What a fearful thing to know All error is related ! From the look, to word and blow,
                            Murder perpetrated ! What a happy, joyous thought, Good is all connected ! From the smile to
                            goodness ^ Till our life's perfected ! Let us hasten from the wrong, Shut the door 'gainst
                            passion ; Check the feeling, curb the tongue, Live to our profession. Are we poised for good
                            or ill, Each in turn o'erruling? Let us rise to Heaven's will, Highest themes pursuing. If
                            the tempter comes in vain, Finding nothing in us To be tempted, or to claim, He will shortly
                            leave us. We've the germ for either growth, Which if cultivated, Gives us life of highest
                            worth, Or a life perverted. We're allied to angels pure, By the good we cherish ; Or we're
                            slaves forever more To the joys that perish. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="One faith" TEIform="index"/>ONE FAITH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">There can be but "one faith, one Lord, and one baptism," and one practice, in the true Church
                            of Christ, the true Christian life. And though an individual's education and training the
                            first years of life, different, personal experiences, different degrees of understanding and
                            unfoldnient may cause a variety of opinions and reasonings, these need never produce
                            clashing in minds ever open to increasing light and conviction, and who are careful not to
                            form a settled opinion until they know they are right. As the practice of genuine
                            Christianity or Shakerism, which is the same, confers the largest spiritual liberty, there
                            must ever be absolute freedom of opinion among real Christians, and none who have the
                            prosperity of their fellow beings at heart could wish to entertain opinions inimical to the
                            common welfare. Thus, each individual,mediums included, is responsible for his or her own
                            utterances, which may be accepted or refused, or held suspended in the judgment until a cor
                            rect decision can be formed according to the value of the utterance and the impression made
                            ON the mind of the hearer. Concerning what may be termed theologi cal interpretations of
                            certain sentimentaliCONTENTS. page. page. Thoughts, - - - - - - - 121 Correspondence, .....
                            13:1 One Faith, ------ 121 Editorial : Let us be Consistent, ..... 122 Unnatural, - ... 1,%
                            Contentment, ------ 123 Encourage Them, Christian versus Human, - - - - 124 Editorial Notes,
                            - - - - - - 138 Saved, ------- vzi Society Record, The Shaker Community,..... 128 The
                            Children's Grotto,.....Nil Sketch or the Life and Ministry of Elder Grove Book Table, ... B.
                            Blanchard,...... 130 Music: A Sister's Tribute,..... 132 Blending of the Spheres, - - - H-l
                            Our Rest, - - - - - - 132 Agricultural, ------ 113 True Progress, ------ 133 What an Old Man
                            has Noticed, - - - 144 Trentissiana, - - - - - - 133 Cure of Diphtheria, - - - - -144 THE
                                <pb n="122" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 122 THE SHAKEK MANIFESTO. ties of religious opinion, or what some
                            would call speculative theology, the ideas of Christians may vary ; but in relation to the
                            genuine Christian's duty of dying to worldly life, consecration of life to God, ceasing from
                            sin, as interpreted in the life of Christ, by confession and repentance, and living a life
                            of virgin purity and self-denial, there can only be one faith.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us be consistent" TEIform="index"/>LET US BE CONSISTENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>ABRAHAM PERKINS</byline><p TEIform="p">; A lamb skin will not always hide the wolf. Conditions will eventually unfold themselves and
                            distinctly come to view ; tlieir fruits will crop out, and thus the principles underlying
                            profession are clearly defined, demonstrating, unmistakably, the spirit that rules. Why is
                            it the human heart is so treacherous, so deceptive ? How can an intelligent man live the
                            lie, and feel that he is a man? It is an undeniable fact, that in this world, we can boast
                            of but few strictly honest men. Of the milions claiming their formation in the image of God,
                            to discover and trace that image is difficult. It is quite conclusive that an " honest man,
                            the noblest work of God," has become largely a fraud. Like un_ to human inventions, capable
                            of being brought to great perfection by human skill, they undergo so much change their
                            usefulness is often destroyed ; so has man by his devices made himself quite as
                            unprofitable. Not an honest man living who has studied the lessons of life, and knows
                            himself, but must confess, however mortifying the admission, that dishonesty is universally
                            traceable in the human character, more or less in lighter or heavier shades. Yet we call
                            ourselves Christians— too often a false cognomen. In taking another view of human character,
                            we see prominently fruits of the divine ; and although the instrument producing such fruit
                            may be prompted by selfish instincts, yet the act is praiseworthy and demands encouragement
                            however wrong the motive. We often find the strongest and most efficient powers of man
                            exerted for progress in all that is great and good; he stakes his whole interest, sacrifices
                            wealth, reputation, and even life to make his labors successful in checking vice,
                            encouraging reform and elevating human character. After distinguishing himself in his angel
                            work, what too frequently follows in his next operation? Because of his nature being
                            unredeemed, his passions unsubdued and selfishness of a heart unconverted, the lower animal
                            portion of his being takes the ascendancy, usurps the throne and reason is thrust out;
                            instead of his being but " a little lower than the angels " and legitimately enjoying an
                            alliance with them, he becomes a contemptible wreck ; a devil, lower than the beasts that
                            perish ; a mystery to humanity difficult to fathom. The result is " peace is taken from the
                            earth" and we see the consequences in dementia, the destruction of the intellect and ruin of
                            body and soul. When we take into consideration the bad work, the havoc that is made of
                            Christianity, in the amount of suffering, shame and vice in their lowest and most revolting
                            forms as they abound among professors of the Christian religion, and those too who are
                            distinguished as the great lights of the world, stars of magnitude in the heavens, the
                            spiritual firmament, divines, professed representatives of Christ and ministers at his
                            altar, is it a matter of wonder that unbelief in the doctrines of Christ and the
                            resurrection, and infidelity to the purity of his mission, as the redeeming work for man, so
                            abounds in the land, when these selfsame first class professors ostensibly bow before the
                            Messiah and acknowledge him as their teacher, example and beau-ideal of true manhood ; and
                            upon bended knees calling angels to witness their pledges, promise the God of Heaven to live
                            in the life of Christ, be governed by His spirit and dwell in peace, love and purity, when
                            at the same time their lives are fraught with the things forbidden by his law, unto which
                            they cleave and are very unwilling to surrender ! He was a peacemaker. Are they his
                            followers' who advocate and practice war ? He ministered truth by precept and example. Is he
                            a true disciple, who declares the end justifies the means tantamount to the decla- <pb n="123" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 123 ration, that some lies, some deception, some
                            hypocrisy will answer in certain contingencies and under certain circumstances? He was a
                            celibate, taught pure virgin principles by precept and example, to live as the angels in
                            regeneration. Is a life on the plane of nature and lower than that of the beasts of the
                            field, in acts for which a chaste man would slay his beast, a life in the spirit ? Is
                            earthly generation spiritual regeneration ? For such conditions what is the remedy ? where
                            shall we look for a balm for our woes ? As in the days of Jesus, so in these days when the
                            truth is declared, many turn away and no more follow him ; but few are willing to trust;
                            they hate the sin-killing operation of the work that destroys their idols and takes away
                            their gods. They seem to understand nothing of the higher life, nothing superior to animal
                            enjoyment, that is the height of their ambition, and for that they exercise all their powers
                            of body and mind to make provision. Our alternative for deliverance, our ransom, lies only
                            in one direction, simply to follow Christ in the regeneration, doing as he did, coming into
                            his life, living in his spirit, crucifying " the flesh with the affections and lusts." The
                            sacrifice must be perfect, the consecration full; no half-way work nor hypocritical pretense
                            will give us the power of salvation or answer the purpose at all. As a testimony in behalf
                            of the cause of saving truth, in behalf of the revealed plan of the Almighty for the
                            redemption of man, in behalf of his inheritance with Christ and with angels in glory, I
                            bequeath to my fellow travelers and kindred souls these lines, in all kindness and
                            everlasting love. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Contentment" TEIform="index"/>CONTENTMENT</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Pelham, Richard" TEIform="persName"/>RICHARD PELHAM</byline><p TEIform="p"> Come contentment, lovely guest, Reign unrivalled in my breast, Thou alone wilt do. Thou
                            alone canst fill the soul, Every passion canst control, When the stormy billows roll, Thou
                            canst bear me through. Nothing on the earth below — Nought that Heaven can bestow — Fills
                            the soul with peace, If contentment is not there ; All is dreary, dark, and bare ; She alone
                            makes heavenly fare, She alone is bliss. Bat, content will not abide In a soul puffed up
                            with pride ; Neither will she stay With a soul defiled with lust; Nor with him who is unjust
                            ; He that covets she'll not trust, But will flee away. Hypocrites, who sneak around, Hunting
                            flesh on Holy Ground, Peace will never find. He who covers up his sins, Lo ! his torment
                            then begins, He that's lazy never wins ' True content of mind. All the lordlings of the
                            earth — All their boasts, what are they worth ? Nothing but a show ! All the wealth that
                            kings possess, All their vain and gaudy dress, All is splendid wretchedness — Peace, they
                            never knew. In humiliation low, Where the heavenly virtues grow, There contentment's found ;
                            I will tread this lowly vale, And its living breath inhale. Catch the odors from the gale,
                            Richly spread around. Where there is no sin concealed — Where the heart has been revealed —
                            There content is near. Whoso will his sins confess, Live a life of righteousness, God that
                            soul will surely bless, Peace will soon appear. Where no vulture's eye hath seen — Where no
                            lion's whelp has been — Resignation's vale — Where the flesh is crucified — Where the
                            selfish will's denied — There contentment will abide There alone will dwell. Far from lust,
                            and pride, and strife, In a pure and virgin life, Here's true peace of mind. With
                            contentment hand in hand, I'll explore this happy land, Moving with a virgin band Who alone
                            are blessed. North Union, O.</p></div2><pb n="124" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian versus human" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTIAN VERSUS HUMAN</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Snipes, J. P." TEIform="persName"/>J. P. SNIPES</byline><p TEIform="p">BY . I went to church, on Sunday last — I think it is the last, To a stylish church I mean,
                            sir, considering what pass'd : I wore my dark, plain garments, sir, those modest clothes of
                            mine, Quite out of fashion, and the place where every thing is line. And the usher quickly
                            pushed me away back by the door. On a plain, hard bench of timber—reserved seat for the poor
                            ! Then he took a nice young lady, with silks and diamonds fine, And he bowed her so politely
                            to a place ahead of mine. And I thought it.wasn't equal to put her up so near, For she was
                            young, and I was old, and very hard to hear. And I couldn't catch the sermon, for I sat so
                            far away, So I waited through the service, only to watch and pray —¦ Watching the pious
                            Christians who were seated round about, Praying within for purity, as they were pure
                            without. And I doubt not many wealthy who go out from that fold, Are pretty near relations
                            to the Pharisees of old; When returning from their worship, they raise their heads on high,
                            And scornful of the humbler ones the Christian life belie. Away with such professors, sir,
                            they're doing more to-day To block the anxious traveler upon the holy way, Than modern
                            infidelity in theologic fray. Examples fine indeed are they for any human need, They
                            minister to creed and greed, but not to hearts that bleed. Intemperance they wink at, sir,
                            but why should Christians care, The church must be supported, sir, by means both foul and
                            fair. The whisky-selling deacon, too, can have his choice of pew, If only he is willing,
                            sir, to help the parson through. " In God we trust," the dollars say, but not in brother
                            man, Unless the God the dollar is — then worship all you can. Some other metal just as well
                            might take the place of gold, To keep the precious body well, and cheat the human soul; But
                            common estimation, sir, they think will justify The worship of the golden calf by greater
                            calves close by, Success obtained by honest toil should have its honest due, But do not
                            starve the many, sir, to feed the haughty few. Consider all the works of God, how marvelous
                            and grand, The ocean caves, the skies above, the flowers vipon the land ; The gilded rays of
                            roseate morn, of universal birth, Are not for the rich man only, but for the poor of earth.
                            Then why should man look down on man, because of lack of gold ? Why put him in the poorest
                            pew because his clothes are old? Why keep him down in any place, nor help him higher rise,
                            'Till he can claim an equal right to union with the skies ? A heart with broad humanity, a
                            heart that God has blest, Is worthy of the highest place, among the very best. Then lift
                            your weaker brother, and falling sister, too, Excite in them the prospect of much better
                            things in view. Then shall you hear the voices sound along the shining shore, Inviting you
                            to grander life, in heaven forever more.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Saved: not by the death of Jesus, but by the life of Christ Jesus" TEIform="index"/>SAVED:
                            Not by the death of Jesus, but by the life of Christ Jesus.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/>GILES B. AVERY</byline><p TEIform="p"> It is our business, as Christians, to live the Christ life, rather than to argue stale
                            theological predicates and solutions ; still we would courteously reply to any correspondent
                            and try to shed light. " For modes of faith let graceless bigots fight, His can't be wrong,
                            whose life is in the right." A friend from Florida writes us : " I understand by some of
                            your writings, that you do not altogether believe that Jesus was born the Christ" (by his
                            nativity of Mary). Again, " Unless his prophetic sireship (God) can be maintained, the
                            virtue of His atonement falls," etc., etc. And, further, " I sup- <pb n="125" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. 125 posed this was fundamental with all who see any beauty in Christ at
                            all." True, as our correspondent suggests, the fundamental dogmas of most of the theological
                            creeds of the popular (so-called) "Christian" denominations, embrace the following ideas :
                            1. God, as the sireship, Father of Jesus, instead of Joseph. 2. Jesus, the sonship of God,
                            and second God of the Trinity. 3. God angry, and wrathful at the sins of mankind. 4. God
                            proposed the murder of Jesus — His younger brother God, by the hands of (wicked ?) men that
                            Jesus' animal blood, shed, might appease the wrath of his Elder God, and thus reconcile
                            sinful men to Him, by the sacrifice of the righteous. 5. That it was wicked for the Jews to
                            kill Jesus (although according to God's purpose), that by His death He might ransom from
                            sufferings, as the penalty of sin, all mankind who should believe in Jesus' mission as
                            atoning for the sins of mankind by suffering a physical death by murder. It is a truth as
                            applicable to theological deductions as to the conclusions of natural philosophy applied to
                            mechanical principles, mathematics, astronomy, chemistry biology, or any of the sciences,
                            that if the predicate is wrong, the conclusive deductions therefrom cannot be right; and
                            truthfully the poet sings: "None sends his arrow to the prize in view, Whose hand is feeble,
                            or his aim untrue ; For, though ere yet the shaft is on the wing, Or, when it first forsakes
                            the elastic string, It errs but little from the intended line, It falls, at length, far wide
                            of its design." And, as says Young, " With the talents of an angel a man may be a fool. If
                            he judges amiss in the supreme point, judging right in all else but aggravates his folly, as
                            itshows him wrong, though blest with the best capacity of being right." According to
                            Shaker-Christian theology, the first error of the foregoing dogmas is, the masculine trinity
                            of Deity. 2. That Jesus is very God, as well as very man. 3. That Jesus was a production of
                            parthenogenesis, and through that process of creation, became the Divine Son of God — the
                            Christ. 4. That Jesus, irrespective of, and before He was anointed, was Christ. 5. That a.
                            just and merciful God of love should possess an attribute of injustice and cruelty that
                            should require the death sacrifice of the innocent Jesus as an atonement for the sins of the
                            human race, and thus violate His own commandment. 6. That God instituted a fellow God to be
                            the Mediator between God and man. 7. That through the sin of one man al 1 men became
                            sinners. 8. And, through the righteousness of one man (observe, Jesus is now called man, not
                            God !) all believing in him became righteous. 9. That the full and complete revelation of
                            all the truths of God necessary for man's salvation, redemption, spiritual development and
                            heavenly endowment was manifested eighteen hundred years ago, and all revelation then
                            forever ceased. Let us now endeavor to disentangle, in a brief way, this snarled theology,
                            and present Shaker-Christian theology. 1, Of the masculine Trinity God. Moses, the Prophets,
                            Jesus and Paul, all represent God as Creator, Parentage, Father and Mother — as there can be
                            no Father without a Mother. And, although philosophy and experience both teach that the
                            finite cannot comprehend the Infinite, yet the most consistent, idea of God presented by
                            philosophy, revelation, observation and experience, is God—a prototype of His creation, a
                            bi-sexual Being, " Let us make man in our image and likeness." 2. Of the Godship of Jesus.
                            The scripture prophecies and promises make Jesus of the seed of Abraham — David — through
                            whom " all the nations of the earth should be blessed." Not the seed of God. "God, thy God,
                            hath anointed Thee — Jesus— with the oil of gladness above Thy fellows." Psa. xlv, ? ; Heb.
                            i, 9. Who His fellows, if Jesus is God ? And did His Elder and Father God, anoint Him to be
                            above Himself? Jesus was the " Rod " that "should come forth ont of the stem of Jesse." The
                            " Branch " that " shall grow out of his roots " — Jes- <pb n="126" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 12(3 THE
                            SHAKER MANIFESTO. se's — not God's. " I will bring forth a seed out of Jacob and out of
                            Judah, an inheritor of my mountains ; " not out of God but Jacob and Judah. " The scepter
                            shall not depart from Judali,, nor a lawgiver from between his feet until Sldloh"—(Jesus)'—
                            " come, and unto Him shall the gathering of the people be." "Both He that sanctifieth" —
                            Jesus—"and they who are sanctified "—His followers —" are all of one " race or stock, "for
                            which cause He is not ashamed to call them brethren." Of course not all Gods! " Verily He
                            took not on Him the nature of angels "(nor of Gods), "but He took on Him the seed of
                            Abraham'' (not of God), " wherefore, in all things it behooved Him to be made like unto His
                            brethren" (not to God) " that He might be a merciful and faithful high priest in things
                            pertaining to God." " For in that He himself hath suffered, being tempted, He is able to
                            succor them that are tempted." "For God cannot be tempted with evil, neither tempteth He any
                            man." James i, 13. Our friend further says: *'I supposed, Isa. vii, 14, had reference to
                            this sam.e Jesus to say nothing of the unanswerable mention of His coming in the fulness of
                            time, just when He did," etc. The prophecy of Isaiah vii, 14, "Behold a virgin sliall
                            conceive and bring forth a son," which by theologians for ages has been used as a shore to
                            prop up the story of the miraculous conception of Jesus; but when it is carefully studied it
                            will be found entirely directed to the birth of the Prophet Isaiah's own son by the
                            prophetess, until then a virgin, viz.: " Maher-Shalal-hash-baz," and to the incidents
                            transpiring before he had knowledge to cry " my Father and my Mother." The story is a plain
                            one, and fully elaborated by Isaiah. Thus, in the reign of Ahaz, King of Judah ; ttezin,
                            King of Syria, and Pekah, Revnaliah's son, King of Israel, conspired together against King
                            Ahaz to war against Jerusalem, that is, Judah. Ahaz was greatly troubled about it, and the
                            Lord sent the Prophet Isaiah to quiet him, who told him not to fear, nor be faint-hearted
                            because of the conspiracy of those two kings against him, calling them "two tails of smoking
                            fire brands." The following chapter tells the whole story, and is made clear by reference to
                            ii Kings.. 15-30, and 16-9. And, said the prophet, " Thus saitli the Lord, it," this
                            conspiracy, " shall not stand, neither shall it come to pass, but, within 85 years Ephraim
                            shall be broken and not be a people." Then he says to King Ahaz, " If ye will not believe
                            surely you shall not be established." Then to help his faith the prophet told him to ask a
                            sign of the Lord. Ahaz refused The prophet reproved him, asking him if he would weary God as
                            he did men? Then told him " the Lord would give him a sign." What was it? Why, "Behold a
                            virgin" (the prophet's young wife, then a virgin), shall conceive and bear a son, and call
                            his name Immanuel, and he should eat butter and honey.' See Isa. vii, 17 to 23. And, before
                            he should know how to refuse the evil and choose the good, the land he abhorred, Syria and
                            Israel, should be forsaken of both their kings." This was accom plished. See ii Kings, xv,
                            30, and xvi, 9, ac cording to prophecy, before this prophetess' child, who was the virgin's
                            son referred to, could cry " my father and my mother; but it was 742 years before the birth
                            of Jesus. This child, Maher-Shalal-hash-baz, was also called Immanuel. See Isa. viii, 8 to
                            9, and vii, 14. Jesus, speaking of His nativity, of the seed of Abraham, calls Himself,
                            always, " the Son of Man," as if foreseeing what an effort would be made to deify Him, and
                            to forestall it. The Jews called Him the son of Joseph and Mary. " Is not this the
                            carpenter's son, and is not His mother called Mary ? And His brethren James and Joses, and
                            Simon and Judas ? And His sisters, are they not all with us? Whence, then, hath this man
                            (not God) all these things? Matt, xiii, 55, 56. Now, if Jesus was not Joseph's son, but
                            begotten of God, He was not of the lineage, and an offspring of David, and the scriptural
                            promises to Abraham and David concerning the Messiah being of their seed, have never been
                            fulfilled at all; for Jesus, mother, Mary, was not of the tribe of David but of Levi. Thus,
                            Mary was daughter of Eli, Eli of the race of Ithamar, Ithamar was Aaron's fourth son. Aaron
                            was a prince of <pb n="127" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 127 the tribe of Levi. Levi was
                            third son of Jacob. But David was the youngest son of Jesse, of the tribe of Judah ; Judah
                            was a son of Jacob. But the Religieux say falsely, " Mary was of the i-oyai race of David,"
                            in order thus to make Jesus, though He were not Joseph's child, of the lineage of David ;
                            thus supporting the fable of the miraculous conception, as this stoiy is admitted by all
                            good scholars in Greek and Plebrew, to be an interpolsiation by some of the early Christ
                            ians and not to be found in the earliest copies of Matthew extant. But still further, .Jesus
                            is called," A Lamb slain from the foundations of the world." What world ? The new world He
                            came to organize, " Behold I create all things new." If this slaying referred to Jesus'
                            death, and He was God, and slain by the will of His Elder God, then God committed deicide.
                            Thus we have the truth, Jesus, when born of Mary, was the "Son of Man," Joseph ; he was in
                            time anointed by God's ministers, with the Divine spirit, which anointing constituted Him
                            the Christ, made Him the " Son of God" called "The first begotten Son of God." He,was now a
                            " new creature," and in this birth capacity " The first born (into the New Creation) of many
                            brethren, other sons of God. Now, of the atonement, " He, Jesus, not Christ, gave His life a
                            ransom for many." What life? The life of a carnal nature, a selfish, worldly will, a life to
                            sin, " In that, that He died, He died unto sin once." In that that He liveth He liveth unto
                            God." But how about the ransom? By opening the way for others to follow. " He that would
                            come after me, let him take up his cross and follow me." " My reward is with me to give to
                            every man according as Ms works shall be." " He shall save his people from their sins; not
                            in their sins; not from the sufferings of sins committed. The ransom is in the salvation and
                            by virtue of the heavenly life services He gave to do God's will as an exampler, and by
                            which He became the " Mediator of the New Covenant" between God and man. It was Jesus
                            Christ, Jesus anointed, who was this Mediator; not a Ood, but the "first born Son of Ood, "
                            — a man, but a new man ; an anointed man, a " New Creature." Jesus declared, " Except a man
                            be born again, he cannot be my disciple." If Jesus had to be born again, and yet was the "
                            Son of God " by His birth of Mary, pray what did He become by His second or new birth ? But
                            our correspondent says, " I supposed the idea that Jesus was divine from birth (of Mary, he
                            means), was fundamental with all who see any beauty in Christ at all.'' Says the popular
                            confession of faith : " That Jesus died for our sins, and in our room and stead, is a
                            doctrine much to be desired, and very full of comfort to the true believer." Indeed, but
                            said the prophet, " To whom is the arm of the Lord revealed ? " " For He shall grow up
                            before Him as a tender plant, and as a root out of a dry ground ; He hath no form nor
                            comeliness ; and when we shall see Him there is no beauty that we should desire Him." " He
                            is despised and rejected of men, a man of sorrows "-(not a God), " and acquainted with
                            grief." Thus is the vision to the carnal worldly man to whom Christ's life devoted to God,
                            and example to follow, is set before him. " Surely He hath borne our griefs, and carried our
                            sorrows ;" not in our room and stead, but sympathetically sensing our condition " that He
                            might be a merciful and faithful high priest." " In that He himself hath suffered, being
                            tempted, He is able to succor them that are tempted." "Yet we did esteem Him smitten of Ood
                            and afflicted." " But He was wounded for " (i. e., because of not instead of) " our
                            transgressions, He was bruised for" (because of) "our iniquities." " The chastisements of
                            our peace was upon Him " because of His sufferings through an interested sympathy, " And
                            with His stripes we are healed " by bearing the same as He bore them ; and, in another
                            sense, when He lays them upon us, "and He shall smite the earth with the rod of His mouth,
                            and with the breath of His lips shall He slay the wicked." Isa. 11, and 4. " When thou shalt
                            make His soul an offering/«r sin " (that is because of sin), "He shall see His seed." He
                            could not have a posterity until He had followers; He could not have followers until He led
                            the way, suffering for His own soul's redemption, thus <pb n="128" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 128 THE SHAKER
                            MANIFESTO. He gave " His soul an offering " up to God ; and it is thus, " He shall see the
                            travail of His soul and be satisfied," " because He had poured out his soul unt o death "
                            (death to sin), not by His physical death, " in that He died He died unto sin." '; He bare
                            the sins of many (sympathetically as a mother bears the sins of her child), and made
                            intercession for the transgressors-" Thus as an interceding Mediator He suffered,
                            sympathetically. But " He shall give to every one according as their works shall be," not a
                            ransom from their sufferings by suffering in their stead for their sin. It is not very
                            practicable to argue all points extensively in a single letter, but the gist of our theology
                            on some of these points is herein given. There are, no doubt,very many good Christians who
                            fully believe in the miraculous conception of Jesus, because their life practices correspond
                            to that of Jesus Christ's example, and this life is often a fruit of spiritual conviction
                            and evolution beyond the speculative ideas of its possessor. Yet we think no person who is
                            thoroughly baptized into the truth and spirit of the Christ life can fail to know that Jesus
                            was not God, nor one of a " holy trinity of Gods." And all true and experienced Shakers know
                            by the spirit of Christ operating upon their own soul's travail, that Jesus had to be born
                            again.after His birth of Mary, and out of His earthly, Adamic, generative nature, and become
                            regenerated in order to become a " Son of God." However, the seeking of souls quickened by
                            God's thought and power is not simply to discover theories adapted to the support of some
                            conventional institution ; but for that truth that gives the soul wings of power to soar
                            above earth's sensual, groveling plane, in the pure element of heavenly bliss. Conventional
                            institut ions and their advocates simply to sustain such, do not always manifest themselves
                            the unmistakable proclaimers of truth, and the mind which merely seeks some human theory of
                            these to serve, may often miss the truth. Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Touching Christ healed the woman, what must his living in us accomplish?" TEIform="index"/>Touching Christ healed the woman, what must his living in us accomplish?
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Touching Christ healed the woman, what must his living in us accomplish?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker community: united society of believers in Christ's second appearing" TEIform="index"/>Shaker community: united society of believers in Christ's second appearing
                        </head><p TEIform="p">[From the <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Albany evening times" TEIform="index"/>Albany Evening Times.]</bibl><quote TEIform="quote">THE SHAKER COMMUNITY. United Society of Believers in Chiust's Second Appearing.
                                    The largest Communistic Society in the world — Their Theology— Their Mutual
                                    Obligations, Labors and Inheritance — Iheir Life, Habits and Products. We have
                                    received from the office of " The Shaker Manifesto," published at Shakers, in this
                                    county, a well-printed octavo volume entitled " Shaker sermons: Scripto-Rational.
                                    Containing the Substance of Shaker Theology, Together with Replies and Criticisms
                                    Logically Set Forth, By H. L. Eads, Bishop of South Union, Ky." It is probably the
                                    best single volume in existence from which to learn precisely what is the Shaker
                                    creed. In many respects their theology is similar to that of other Christian
                                    denominations but its chief distinction seems to be the dogma of the duality of God,
                                    asserting that " God as father or the fatherly character of God, was revealed by the
                                    Sou, Christ Jesus; and God as mother, or the motherly character of God, was revealed
                                    by the daughter, (Ann Lee.)" Although the Shakers have existed as a society for one
                                    hundred years, and comprise seventeen communities in nearly half as many States,
                                    yet, beyond the immediate neighborhood of these several communities little is known
                                    of them except as the source of brooms, apple sauce, garden seeds and choice
                                    medicinal roots and herbs. The Shakers are conspicuous as being the largest and most
                                    successful communistic society in the world, and are attracting considerable
                                    attention just now by reason of the agitation of communism and socialism, and also
                                    the new departure of the Oneida community. They have exhibited to the world a
                                    successful community of interests, blessed with contentment and plenty, and implicit
                                    confidence in the mercy and goodness of God. Shaker history begins about the year
                                    1747, and bears on its pages the marks of cruel persecution ; for within the walls
                                    of a prison, as have many others, the principles <pb n="129" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER
                                    MANIFESTO. 129 of this society took root and bore fruit. Under the leadership of
                                    James and Jane Wrardley, a few members of the society of Quakers united in a
                                    distinct society near Manchester, England. In 1753 Ann Lee, the wife of a
                                    blacksmith, with her parents, joined them, all suffering great persecution on
                                    account of their peculiar faith. It is to the courage and faith of this remarkable
                                    woman that the society owes much of its success. It was while languishing in prison
                                    that she received by '' special manifestations of divine light" the plan of
                                    salvation and eternal life which forms the basis of the Shaker belief of to-day.
                                    Acknowledged as " Mother in Christ," she still bears among the sect the grateful
                                    title of " Mother." They claim that to her was shown in visions the fall of man in
                                    Eden, through listening to his evil passions, and the mode of redemption through
                                    chastity and self-denial ; and this was made the corner-stone of her religious
                                    structure. Driven from England by continued persecution, Ann Lee with eight of her
                                    devoted adherents, six men and two women, including her husband, brother and a
                                    niece, embarked at Liverpool, 1774, for New York, in search of a home for the new
                                    church. After encountering many privations and hardships, this little band
                                    established a home in the wilderness about seven miles northwest from Albany, at
                                    Watervliet, near Niskayuna, clearing the ground themselves and providing for their
                                    sustenance. This was in 1775, and, though they hoped for an early accession to their
                                    numbers, none came to join them, and it was not until 1780 that their doctrines, as
                                    preached by Ann Lee, excited the attention of any that were inclined to receive
                                    them. A revival among the Baptists of that year drew quite a number toward the
                                    little community, who embraced their doctrines, and thus commenced the growth of the
                                    sect, Ann Lee continuing to be a leading spirit of the cause until, worn out by
                                    incessant labors, this remarkable woman, at the age of 48, ended at Watervliet,
                                    1784, a life marked by many struggles with poverty, persecution and hardship, in
                                    triumphant devotion to the principles of her belief, which she lived to see firmly
                                    established among numerous followers. Thus was the beginning of the Shaker
                                    organization, which marks an epoch in history as being the first successful
                                    conmiunity of the kind. The growth of the sect is from the outside of its limits,
                                    and those tired of the world and sin, and willing to surrender both, agreeably to
                                    the society's rules, may become members. If they are married, their partners'
                                    consent to their joining must be obtained, their debts must be paid and their
                                    children provided for, either within or without the society. On joining they
                                    dedicate themselves and all they have to the society and to God ; but if they choose
                                    to withdraw they can do so at any time, taking all with them that they brought, if
                                    the membership is of less than five years' duration. If five or more years, then
                                    they relinquish, by previous agreement, all right to what they contributed, though
                                    none are sent away emptyhanded. All property is held in community, and all returns
                                    go for the general good. The cardinal principles of the sect as promulgated by
                                    Mother Ann, govern tlieir actions to-day. Chastity, honesty, industry, frugality,
                                    charity, temperance and order are taught and lived with rigid exactness — enjoined
                                    but not enforced — and made easy by habit. The Shakers are not ascetics, though
                                    peculiar. They do not ask the world to conform to their usages, nor proscribe others
                                    for non-conformity to their customs. Though celibates, they do not condemn those
                                    that marry, regarding marriage as an ordinance of God, but deplore its corruption
                                    through the influence of sin. They do not shut themselves from the world, but mingle
                                    with it and trade with it, and benefit it as far as they may by their contributions
                                    to its comforts and necessities. They are cheerful and hearty in their dealings,
                                    clearsighted and shrewd in matters of business, scrupulously honest, and hold sacred
                                    the obligations of tlieir word. Their communities are visited every year by
                                    curiosity seekers, or those who, already knowing them, wish to live for a term
                                    within the atmosphere of their virtues. Their order, industry, sincerity and
                                    kindness win all to them, and mostly those who come <pb n="130" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 130 THE
                                    SHAKER MANIFESTO. among- them, disposed to scoff, observe with respect and leave
                                    with an exalted opinion of their worth. Order is, with them, the prevailing law, and
                                    every thing at home and abroad is governed by it. The handmaid of order is neatness,
                                    and a grain of dust in a Shaker home is a profanation. Everybody works, male and
                                    female, whether upon the farm, in domestic pursuits inside the home, gathering herbs
                                    and seeds, making applesauce, medicines or notions, educating the young ; and,
                                    whatever there is to do, it is done with regularity and system. Pleasant and
                                    cheerful intercourse prevails, music lends its charm, intellectual exercise is
                                    indulged, and all is enjoyed with a delight unmixed with frivolity and with a warmth
                                    unimpaired by worldly satiety. "The United Society of Believers" was formed two
                                    years after the death of Mother Ann Lee, and its simple creed governs the societies
                                    10-day : 1st, a virgin life; 2d, separation from the world ; 3d, confession and
                                    repentance of sin ; 4th, united inheritance ; 5th, chastity of body ; 6th, purity of
                                    spirit. Under this creed it becomes the duty of every accepted member " to study
                                    carefully and diligently, to speak peace, to eschew bad habits, and to walk
                                    circumspectly before God and mail." Through their spiritual singleness, their frugal
                                    manner of living, and the few objects which engross their minds, they are more
                                    devoted to the callings which they follow, and therefore it may be that their
                                    productions have an intrinsic worth which makes them more desirable. Some of the
                                    most useful inventions of the day are claimed by the Shakers, among which are the
                                    improved Shaker washing ma chine, now so genearlly used in the large institutions of
                                    the country; the Babbit ¦metal, invented by Daniel N. Baird (Webster in his
                                    dictionary being incorrect), also inventor of the first rotary harrow ; the board
                                    matcher, by Henry Bennett and Amos Bishop, and the circular saw, invented at the
                                    same society, and still to be seen at the State Geological department in Albany! The
                                    corn broom is a Shaker invention, and for many years was manufactured exclusively by
                                    them. The society in the town of Watervliet claim to have originated cut nails, and
                                    exhibit some of the machinery first employed by them for that purpose, and many more
                                    equally useful inventions by that truly inventive people. Shaker garden seeds attest
                                    the care and improvement in culture due to an intimate knowledge of the wants of
                                    vegetable life, while their applesauce and preserves are household words, which
                                    involuntarily cause the mouth to water and the mind to teem with recollections of
                                    surreptitious feeds of jam in childhood's hungry days. Indeed, so well established
                                    is their reputation, and so popular have their products become, that other producers
                                    and manufacturers have not scrupled to use their name, and to such an extent has
                                    this counterfeiting been carried on that it is necessary to be careful to be sure
                                    that the so called-Shaker manufactures ever saw a Shaker. The Shakers, in the
                                    inception, growth and triumph of their societies, by the force of example illustrate
                                    the power of well-directed industry and frugality, coupled with unity and sincerity.
                                    Existing in many parts of the United States, these thoroughly respected communities,
                                    while shunning publicity, accord to every man his due, eschew strife, clothe the
                                    naked, feed the hungry, heal the sick and extend to those tired of an existence of
                                    selfishness and sin, the privilege of enjoying, amidst content and plenty, a well
                                    spent life, free from the cares and exactions of the world, and happy in the
                                    possession of a clear conscience. </quote></cit></p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sketch of the life and ministry of Elder Grove B. Blanchard" TEIform="index"/>SKETCH OF THE
                            LIFE AND MINISTRY OF ELDER GROVE B. BLANCHARD,</head><p TEIform="p">WHO WAS ASSOCIATED WITH T1£E MINISTRY OF HARVARD AND SHIRLEY MORE THAN FIFTY-TWO YEARS.
                            Babbitt Blanchard was born in Petersham, Mass., Nov. 9th, 1T98, from whence he moved to
                            Harvard, Mass., May 25, 1812, with his mother, two older brothers and three sisters ;
                            another sister (married) came later. All embraced the faith of Christ's Second Appearing ;
                            held important places of trust, and remained here till their decease, except Electa, the
                            youngest, who moved to <pb n="131" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 131 Lebanon, N. Y., and
                            served as one of the trustee sisters many years. Babbitt, though young, saw in the faith and
                            principles of the society the mean6 of salvation from the darkness and death of the
                            prevailing systems of religion, and the sins of perverted nature, and directed all his
                            firmness and will to live true to his convictions of right. He believed that reason and soul
                            should dominate over the passions and appetites. One single instance of his efforts at
                            selfcontrol might be well to be put on record. He would " place an apple on the window in
                            front of his shoe bench and resist his appetite for this, his favorite fruit, till he felt
                            he was master of the situation. And so through life he went on conquering self. " Footprints
                            on the sands of time." Mother Lucy Wright being at Harvard when he was about twenty years of
                            age, said she felt impressed to give him a' 'new name " Grove, to compliment the " white
                            stone " of his integrity and purity. November 9th, 1819, the day of his majority, he was
                            appointed to till a vacancy in the ministry — the associate of Elder John Warner. The wisdom
                            of this selection has been confirmed by a long term of wise and judicious administration
                            (the longest on record). June, 1828, he was appointed the successor of Elder John
                            (resigned), and received the unanimous confirmation of the societies of Harvard and Shirley,
                            as first in the ministry, and has since borne the title and name of Elder Grove. In his
                            official administration he was judge rather than an ex parte advocate ; holding the even
                            balance 'till the case should stand upon its merits. He was wise in council, moderate in
                            judgment, deliberate in decisions, deferential and considerate of the j udgment, opinions
                            and feelings of others. Scrupulously loyal to principle, union was his motto ; possessing
                            largely the divine virtue of charity. Hence he won the respect, love and confidence of all.
                            His interest in the welfare of Zion was neither selfish nor limited. His large heart ever
                            beat in sympathy with tliosej in affliction. When one of our sister churches was needy, he
                            promptly acted upon the suggestion for relief, and, through his influence, means were
                            obtained. He taught and practiced the precept of Mother Ann, " Hands to work and hearts to
                            God." Industry and prudence, and the living presence of God in the soul. At the age of
                            seventy-three years, worn by incessant care and exceeding industry, in the ebb tide of life,
                            some of the strings of his earthly harp loosened; he was relieved from the public duties he
                            had performed so long and so well, November, 1871. Hits remaining years were like a caudle
                            burning in its socket, shedding a peaceful radiance to the end. lie departed this life for
                            the next phase of human experience April 23d, at 2 o'clock, p. M., 1880. A full ripe sheaf
                            for the harvest — a benefactor, a father and friend. His funeral was held in the Meeting
                            House, Sunday, v. M., the 25th inst. Brethren and sisters from Shirley came to pay their
                            last respects to the departed worth. Some neighbors were also in attendance. The funeral was
                            of two hours' duration ; the time being well filled with testimonials of gratitude and
                            respect. When the following verse was repeated (being impressed by him), a clairvoyant saw
                            him walking between the ranks, wafting his love and thanks to his people. " I see my home,
                            my happy home, By angels bright surrounded ; Filled with celestial g'ory bright, And
                            happiness unbounded ; i see the mansion of my rest — Most beautiful and glorious — Where all
                            may dwell who're free from »in And over death victorious." The day being very line most of
                            the attendants marched to the grave and sung the last song—-a song of "victory over
                        death."</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="If there be anything clear in Scripture it does seem to me that it is for a Christian to..." TEIform="index"/>If there be anything clear in Scripture it does seem to me that it is for a Christian to...
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Spurgeon, C. H." TEIform="persName"/>C. H. Spurgeon</byline><p TEIform="p">If there be any thing clear in Scripture it does seem to me that it is for a Christian to
                            have nothing to do with carnal weapons, and how is it that the great mass of Christendom do
                            not see this ? I can not understand ; surely it must be through the blinding influences of
                            the society in which the Christian church is cast.—-</p></div2><pb n="132" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sister's trubute" TEIform="index"/>A SISTER'S TRIBUTE</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hall, Betsey M." TEIform="persName"/>Betsey M. Hall</byline><p TEIform="p">Lines dedicated to Elder GltoVE B. BLANCHARD, who passed to the Evergreen Shores, April 23,
                            1880. Beloved father, friend so blest, You leave the earthly form, To enter into joys of
                            rest, The resurrection morn. With kindred spirits you explore Angelic realms of light ; Thy
                            earthly sufferings, known no more. But joy and pure delight. We feel thy presence with vis
                            here, Imparting love and peace — A radiance from the Angel sphere. 0 may its power increase.
                            This blessing from thy spirit-form, Which here tbou dost impart. Rests like the dove, a holy
                            calm, Inspiring every heart. Long hast thou labored in this place, A rl EAOHKK of the truth
                            ; Pidst sow the seeds of gospel grace, And virtue in the youth. Thy worthy precepts may we
                            heed, Thy bright example too, Of faith and trust in times of need Which bore thy spirit
                            through. We feel that you will aid us yet, With strength of Angel-power, Your interest in us
                            ne'er forget, But help impart each hour. We waft our blessing,love and thanks, From all, a
                            tribute due ; We'll meet thee soon on Jordan's banks, And kindred ties renew.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our rest" TEIform="index"/>OUR REST</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick.</byline><p TEIform="p">TRIBUTE TO THE MEMORY OF ELDJSH GROVE BLANCIIA11D. If is true, dear father, you are weary of
                            earth, As from its joys and its sorrows you now disappear. That the spirit and soul with its
                            priceless worth, Should pass on to rest like the departing year. Have the battles of life
                            e'er made you to feel That earth's most royal gifts are comparative dross ? Have life's
                            gains with the sunshine that love can reveal, Taught you how much of gain, how little of
                            loss? If so to my seeming, your theme must have been Through the duties of life for this
                            change to prepare; Dispelling the mists, that would darken the sun That has lightened your
                            way " to a dwelling place there." The birds and the blossom, the stars overhead, Are some of
                            our teachers, whose lessons sublime Never hint that inclosed in the realms misnamed dead,
                            The soul ever sleeps through the annals of time. That weariness conies like the
                            eveningshades, To wrap in its mantle the heart and the mind, And soothe them to rest while
                            the outer world fades, While the soul drops its fetters, more freedom to find. The state of
                            the present, is simply the shell Of the spirit that waits for its breaking, to free The
                            mind, whose immortal unfoldings shall toll The life that is waiting, for you and forme. We
                            ask for that rest that will bring to the soul, A knowledge of justice, of mercy and love;
                            Where reason shall rule, with its welcome control, While mind vies with mind in haste to
                            approve. And we firmly believe that time will reveal The fact that mankind in the future
                            shall be Redeemed from the errors which keenly we feel, When rest with the truth, is the
                            state of the free. And we mourn not for those who are passing along, To that blessed
                            spirit-realm of earth just above, So while you are greeting the celestial throng, We will
                            join with the angels, and give you our love.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A prosperous people make a happy people..." TEIform="index"/>A prosperous people make a happy people...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A PROSPEROUS people make a happy people ; a happy people make a contented people
                                    ; a contented people make a loyal people ; a loyal people make a strong government.
                                    Let us have a " strong governlneut " based on the affections of the people, and not
                                    on bayonets.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Omaha portfolio" TEIform="index"/>Omaha Portfolio.</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="133" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True progress" TEIform="index"/>TRUE PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Allen, Catharine" TEIform="persName"/>CATHARINE ALLEN</byline><p TEIform="p"> As we progress in a purely simple and religious life, craving nothing of earth but that
                            which is subservient to our highest spiritual development, aspiration will be responded to
                            by revelation; and through this law of influx, our mental faculties will be quickened to
                            read and comprehend the laws of the universe. As wo thus receive the knowledge of God, the
                            superstitions, errors and vanities clinging to, and inseparable from, a false life will be
                            removed ; then, unfettered, we can worship Truth. In its unity our hearts become as one, and
                            our souls flow together in divine love. New Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pretissiana: law" TEIform="index"/>PRENTISSIANA: LAW</head><p TEIform="p"> " Law is a rule of action, prescribed by a superior, and which an inferior is bound to
                            obey."— Blackstone. So far so good — but who is the superior ? and who the inferior ? In
                            barbarous ages and countries, the largest fighter — the conqueror — is the supei'ior — the
                            conquered are the inferiors. In half civilized ages and countries, the few, who, by some
                            kind of chicanery, grasp the land and the learning, are the superiors — the many are the
                            inferiors — in the eye of the law. When humanity so far ascends the progressive grade that
                            the many are disposed to do right because it is right, the many are the superiors — the few,
                            not so disposed, are the inferiors. As units of a nation, or State, it is our duty and right
                            to be subject to the laws of that nation and State—it will do us good. In a religious
                            community, the constituted authorities; spiritual and temporal, acting in harmony, each in
                            its order, are the superiors — we don't need an inferior. Entering the community — not by
                            compulsion, but of our own volition, it is our highest privilege, as well as duty,
                            voluntarily to square our lives by the rules of the order. It takes the conceit out of us ;
                            fits and prepares us for the Holy Eternal Father's and Mother's mansions of eternal
                            brightness. We bless our Saints — and who has a better right to ?</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Correspondence</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritual communion" TEIform="index"/>SPIRITUAL COMMUNION</head><p TEIform="p">FRIEND L.: An obliging friend drew my attention to your review of socialistic movements
                                in the United States. Allow me to ask your attention to that subject again : Some of the
                                points elicited by the review were more than interesting to me, who for about fifty
                                years have participated in such, movements, Personally acquainted with Robert Owen, I
                                drew his attention to what I considered a vital error in his programme. I held that
                                mind,'' not circumstances," possesses creative power. After many years of thought and
                                experience I have had no cause to change the views presented to that venerable and much
                                loved friend. Although materialistic in his views till toward the last of his days, yet
                                I recognize in him one of the most religious men Europe has produced for ages— he went
                                about breathing peace and good will to humanity. Your criticism of various social
                                movements is fair ; you justly complain, that instead of declaring and defining the laws
                                underlying social formations, circumstantial events are dealt with. We may all rest
                                assured that the true community, when it comes forth, will develop and be enclosed by,
                                not the lower, but the higher instincts of humanity, and will be responded to by
                                exalted, noble souls. The germ of that community has not yet been uncovered, nor its law
                                been established to the view of the intellectual world, abstractly considered, but to
                                the spiritualized. I think that in the next opening, communities will be accepted not
                                with misgivings and doubtful disputations, but axiomatically, and with irrefragable
                                demonstrations. Allow me to participate in your prophetic hope — " that the time for
                                such openings is near at hand." If we may judge from the many failures to establish
                                communities, the laws underlying social formations have not been visible even to those
                                who have been engaged in such matters. What those laws are, have been to me for years a
                                special inquiry. I <pb n="134" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. have embodied my
                                conclusions in " An Analysis of Human Society; " but have re frained from presenting
                                them to any leading journal for the present. In the '' Analysis," I first treat of
                                co-operation, and show that its underlying law is organically distinct from that of a
                                community having goods in common. I then classify human manifestations according to
                                their moral bearings ; and then analyze the emotional forces of the primary atoms (man
                                and woman) of human society; showing that human emotions underlie all social for
                                motions. If each atom of human society does not inherently possess a two-fold emotional
                                life, it will be impossible for that atom, or an aggregation of them, to give birth to
                                but one form of social life. But if these atoms are dual in their emotional life —
                                endowed with inferior and superior forces, abnegating the lower and cultivating the
                                superior, an order of society organically higher can be attained to. Progress in the
                                lower life is not change, organically speaking — the least in the higher life must ever
                                remain higher than the greatest in the inferior. I heartily indorse your sentiments
                                deprecating the holding of stocks, etc., by communities. Wherever they find a place in
                                them, death will ensue, unless they purge themselves. A body having life is guilty of
                                suicide if it destroys itself. A. community holding stocks, etc., does that deed.
                                Suppose it holds enough at interest to support all its members, and they rely upon these
                                resources for support instead of labor, would it be a community in the heaven-born sense
                                of the term ? Never. It would be a social parasite — feeding and fattening on the labor
                                of others. " Lay not up for yourselves treasures on earth "— invest what you have to
                                spare in doing divine deeds to your neighbors, to humanity ; for a community whose
                                entire possessions and accumulations are consecrated to charitable and religious
                                purposes has no other investments. The inquiry in your review : " Shall the man who
                                brings into a community a hundred thousand dollars fare alike with the man of no means V
                                Shall the man of weak muscle be as the man of stout arms ? Shall the man of ten talents
                                be as he who has but one ? Shall he who has borne the burden and heat of the day, be as
                                the man who comes in one hour before sunset ? " Certainly, they shall fare alike. The
                                true community refers itself to the divine in man, and will carry out the above
                                precisely to the best of its ability, and be happy in so doing. Singing psalms, praying
                                and 'preaching is not religion ; they are simply its appendages. The hair on a man's
                                head is not the man; the bellows which blow the fire is not the fianie. Nothing will
                                satisfy the aspirations of the highest order of mind but the establishment and extension
                                of the Divine Order of human, social life on earth as it is in the heavens. In that
                                Oi'der, they who are greatest will set themselves to work and find where they can be of
                                the most service irrespective of all personal and all other considerations. Such an
                                order will have noble aims, and will attract noble spirits in and out of the body. I
                                have some idea that the old Order of human life has done all that it is capable of
                                doing; its emotions and forces are mainly animal, and will forever be so. Ancient
                                civilizations had their land, labor, and financial troubles; modern civilization
                                threatens now to give way under the action of these forces. The Pentecostal life has no
                                such troubles. With regard to the " compatibility or incompatibility of the family
                                relationships with the existence of institutions holding goods in common," I have to
                                state that such communities admit of but one center of affection and of interest. The
                                government of a community is the last point in your criticism. Of civil and military
                                rule most men have some conception The government of a community is a different thing.
                                Suppose the word lead is substituted for govern, and the leader bears the heaviest
                                burden, and helps others to b.ar theirs ; we come nearer to the conception of the
                                position of a leader in a community. To work in union with such a lead is angelic
                                obedience. No autocrats in the common acceptation of the term can be accepted in a
                                community. Beneficence and love are the only forces admissible.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Frazer, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Frazer.</byline></div3><pb n="135" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Communistic life" TEIform="index"/>THE COMMUNISTIC LIFE</head><p TEIform="p">Ed. SiiAKnit Manifesto: Communities will no more make genuine communists than churches
                                willmake Christians ; bat institutions are to be judged by their general, not their
                                exceptional fruits. We do not condemn the schools because they turn out some dullards
                                with diplomas in their hands, nor churches because they don't "turn out" alJ their
                                rogues. We estimate these and other institutions accordingly as they favor or not the
                                development of character toward the highest standard of excellence ; and it is by this
                                rule that communism should be judged in the comparison with other forms of society. Does
                                it favor in a superior degree to them the development of the Christ-life in man ? is a
                                question that must sooner or later be settled beyond all controversy. Meanwhile
                                attention may be called to the important fact that not only are the basic principles of
                                communism akin to, if not identical with, the principles of Christianity (I mean of
                                course the highest form of communism), but the practical embodiment of communism in
                                social organization is favorable to the Christ-life of unselfishness. In communities,
                                men, if not shirks, have to "' bear one another's burdens and so fulfil] the law of
                                Christ." (See Galatians, 6,2.) Blessed be communism because it favors and necessitates
                                the fulfillment of this law. Not that compulsory communism is a good thing, nor man
                                rewarded for what is done unwillingly ; but a form of society, the very existence of
                                which is dependent upon its power to supplant selfishness by altruism in every
                                department of life, seems just the place for that law of Christ to yield its most
                                glorious fruits. " 1 have shewed you all things," said the great Apostle, " how that so
                                laboring ye ought to support the weak." Ought! let us think of that word, fellow
                                communists, and be thankful that we can " so labor," and that the fruits of our labor
                                will " support the weak ;" that our very circumstances are such as enable us to "bear
                                one another's burdens," and so far live a life of unselfishness. In the midst of life's
                                temptations (for communists have their temptations to meet and conquer as well as other
                                people), it is a source of comfort and peace to reflect that in voluntarily becoming
                                practical communists we have placed ourselves in circumstances which call for
                                self-denial — call for the abandonment of personal, selfish aims — call us, in a word,
                                to live for others and for the truth.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hinds, William A." TEIform="persName"/>Wm. A. Hinds.</byline><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New York, Oneida" TEIform="index"/>Oneida, N. Y.</dateline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Shaker Manifesto: You made the motion, and it is ably seconded, that..." TEIform="index"/>Editor Shaker Manifesto: You made the motion, and it is ably seconded, that...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, North Union, May 2, 1880" TEIform="index"/>North Union, O., May 2, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor Shaker Manifesto: You made the motion, and it is ably seconded, that the April
                                number of The Manifesto was full of grand articles. While agreeing entirely with you as
                                to the matter in that number generally, and with W. H. Bussell most cordially in his
                                appreciation of Brother 0. C. Hampton's article, specially, still I must say, as 1 have
                                often said, every new issue of our Monthly, since the first number, has been an advance
                                on the last. And especially is this the case with the last two — April, showing the goal
                                of the Shaker race, in Bro. Oliver's beautifully simple style; and May, marking
                                decidedly advanced steps on the road to that goal, by half a'dozen authors. Sure enough,
                                what will purity do for us'? The snow is pure —if it be the result of cold, calculating
                                selfishness. The Christian's heavenly home is the Temple of God. " Ye are the Temple of
                                God." In the confidence, esteem and love of our fellow beings of like faith and
                                practice, we must find our heavenly home, if heavenly home we ever find. " What boots it
                                then to fiy from pole to pole, Hang o'er the sun, and with the comets roll ? What boots
                                it then in foreign lands to roam, If thou, poor man, a stranger art at home ? " Those
                                prophetic and allegorical warninghints, in the May number ! What a pity that those who
                                most need such hints should be the last to heed and profit by them ! 1 am scarcely able
                                to pen these few lines, owing to failing health; but feel that I cannot rest on my bed
                                without making an effort to express my heartfelt gratitude to all concerned, for their
                                efforts in spreading the light of life, both at home and abroad. In much love, your
                                brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Andrews, Watson" TEIform="persName"/>Watson Andrews.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="136" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>Editorial</head><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Unnatural?" TEIform="index"/>UNNATURAL?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The opponents of Shakerism never seem to tire when prating about its " unnatural
                                features/' and to them it has none but unnatural ones. Admitting the fact that it
                                teaches denial to many desires which on the lowest animal plane are most natural, yet it
                                never does this without presenting equally inviting reasons for adopting a more
                                spiritual career. It never presents the Christian cross as an element of afflction, of
                                torture nor robbery of human happiness; but its only presentation of the cross is for
                                the exchange of the lesser good for the greater gain. Self-denial of bad habits is
                                universally commendable; then rising a step higher in the scale of reasoning, let us see
                                that it is no more unnatural to forsake the simply good, animal, lower-plane practices
                                to engage in the struggles for angelic attainments, than was the forsaking the bad for
                                the simply good. To those whose benighted organizations permit but one argument for
                                nature, and this to yield to the inclinations of the lower instincts, Shakerism, with
                                its denials to both the use and abuse of i the procreative passions, must appear most
                                unnatural. Such seem to be happy that they know no more than the brutes; and the simple
                                progress demanded of their human natures, to rise so high above the brutes as to imitate
                                the example of angels, brings pangs to their auimal bliss; while all thoughts of living
                                on earth as they do in heaven, seem preposterous, unnatural, and are met with what they
                                feel to be their well-merited disgust. And such claim to be Christians, too. Unnatural
                                as they term Shaker lives and testimonies, they seldom or never term the same kind of
                                lives and testimonies, lived by the great exampler, Jesus, and immediate disciples —
                                they never term these unnatural! And yet, in this failure to term Jesus' life example
                                unnatural lies the self-evident truth that it was the natural gradation of life, out of
                                the selfish sphere;, up to the adorable position Jesus occupied, and for which he is so
                                highly honored. To those only who are satisfied in living as Jesus did not, is Shakerism
                                an infliction and unnatural. To those who see the progressive beauty into higher and
                                thoroughly spiritual life, which Jesus inaugurated by his self-denials, there is nothing
                                unnatural about Shakerism, nor radical Christianity. As was Jesus' " life cut off from
                                the earthly " plane, to be used for superior purposes, so we, the Shakers, humbly trying
                                to experience the beauty of the same cutting-off, realize that the denials are full of
                                comfort, very spiritual, and in accord with progressive, elevated nature. Had God
                                intended men and women always and only to grope on the earthly plane, fulfilling only
                                the desires which the beasts have in common with them, the aspirations for the more
                                heavenly condition would never have been planted in their souls. The aspirations being
                                there, the attainment will be sought sooner or later, and this will alone be
                                accomplished by the denials to selfish indulgences, animal passions, which however good
                                in their places, are inferior to and unnatural in the more spiritual, heavenly realm.<pb n="137" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 137 Genuine Shakerism is simply actuualized
                                Christianity in life; and is just as natural and as much to be expected as the
                                development of higher life in the lower grades of life ; and to us it is the highest
                                attainment humanity can reach on earth. Shakerism is very spiritual; it makes its
                                adherents very spiritual ; and if it is unnatural to be very spiritual, we, unable to
                                help it, purpose cleaving to the spirit. ^</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Encourage them" TEIform="index"/>ENCOURAGE THEM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The hundreds of schemes for inducing men and women to leave the baser walks of life, now
                                active and at work, are worthy of every commendation and encouragement. Every effort
                                made to reclaim the lost, elevate the downcast, reform the malformed and for the
                                increase of human happiness, should be seconded by all other earnest devotees of virtue.
                                The vices of humanity, and their consequences, cost more than two-thirds of all the
                                wealth there is, to enter correction, protection and the maintenance of the peace of
                                society. Every erroneous or vicious way that is suppressed — every bad habit that is
                                supplanted by its opposite and heavenly virtue — is a thorn uprooted and a flower
                                entered in its place —human happiness is increased, and thus God is praised. More people
                                than we are aware of, are ready and waiting for the advanced views of religious life
                                which Shakerism teaches. Many are anxiously waiting the angel call to come up higher
                                than they are; and so sincerely anxious are these, that it will not matter where the
                                angels lead, they will determinedly follow. Total abstinences, rigid self-denials,
                                reforms many and superior, costing, perhaps, agonies of soul in the separation of the
                                inferior life from the aspirations to the superior ; but they will be endured, even as
                                they have been in the past. The majority, however, are not yet ready for the practice of
                                virgin purity through the entire life; not yet ready for the harvest from themselves and
                                private pi°operty which our faith teaches ; nor yet willing to practice peace even to
                                the fullest non-resistance; not yet able to keep themselves unspotted from the world as
                                did Jesus, our elder brother, and example. But until these extreme Christian measures
                                can be proclaimed to waiting, willing, anxious ears, let every encouragement be given to
                                Temperance, Peace, Aid and Protective Societies—all societies which aim at the culture
                                of virtue and suppression of vice. Let the Fruit and Flower Missions be sustained, that
                                the sick and dying may be cheered and comforted in their extremities. Forget not the
                                widow, the fatherless and motherless , think to do good to those in prison and pray for
                                their wholesome restoration, first to virtuous manhood and womanhood, and then to
                                liberty. And when the liberty of Christ shall abound in the individual—in every
                                individual — when the perfect gospel shall come to the knowledge of all souls, then
                                these projects of partial restoration to paradise may be done away. But until then, let
                                them receive every encouragement; for out of them will the blossomings come, that will
                                enripen the full fruition of radically Christian manhood and womanhood. ¦</p></div3><pb n="138" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="This number" TEIform="index"/>This Number</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Our readers will observe the space given to notices of the demise of that once truly
                                great man, Elder Grove B. Blancttard. For years he has patiently awaited his call to the
                                better land, and now he has gone to enjoy a well-stored harvest of everlasting gains. On
                                our cover is presented the picture of the earthly home of this beautiful man, so full of
                                valuable historical incidents in early Shaker days. This was also the home of two other
                                lovely souls Whose departures we chronicle this month. We wish we could give a true
                                picture of their spirit homes. We are really surprised and sorrowed to note the
                                departure in the west of G. W. Ingalls who has been such a prominent worker there. Our
                                sympathies are with the people there. By reference to our Society Record, a " New
                                Departure" in the appointments of trustees will be observed. This is a good move, but
                                let not such an arranged equality of the sexes be construed into the supremacy of either
                                one.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How nice!" TEIform="index"/>How nice!</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">The eulogistic criticisms rendered by our friend T. C. Callicot, editor of the Albany
                                Evening Times, which paper, by the way, is the best edited sheet in this country,
                                outside of the city of New York — we only wish we could feel were as well deserved as
                                they are conscientiously given. The beautious results therein pictured are truly the
                                fruits of the shaker system when acting* under its full development. It only remains for
                                us Shakers to act more in accord with the system to have his critical statements true.
                                But how nice!</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God in man decisions" TEIform="index"/>God in Man Decisions</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We invite the careful perusal of the article upon " Spiritual Communion" by our venerable
                                brother Fraser. It contains elements of deepest and highest value to the thinking
                                classes of to-day. The special reference to the divine in our humanity, of matters which
                                call for a higher arbiter than our selfish judgments, is simply a grand statement. We
                                especially refer to the paragraph after that answer to a series of selfish cpieries—"
                                Certainly they shall fare alike." Read,ponder, act conscientiously.</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian criminals" TEIform="index"/>"CHRISTIAN" CRIMINALS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">AN EXPLANATION OF THE RECENT OHOP OF " FALLEN ANGELS." Zion's Herald, the national organ
                                of the Methodist Episcopal Church, has this to say on "Christian" criminals: " It is
                                very distressing to read of these continued business delinquencies among professedly
                                Christian men. A fresh one is announced by the daily press in the western portion of
                                Massachusetts. They are not, indeed, new cases. They were running parallel with those
                                which have been heretofore developed. Doubtless there are others to be revealed. During
                                the flush years of the war, and immediately after, men became beside themselves in the
                                whirl of speculation, and the possibilities of becoming in a short time rich. In the
                                apparently certain prospect of ample returns for every investment, they lost the nice
                                sense of honor and of sterling probity, not to say their hold upon the divine Hand. They
                                used trust property not exactly as their own, perhaps, but for their own benefit. They
                                risked what they had no right to peril, upon the presumption, criminal indeed in itself,
                                that they could <pb n="139" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. 139 readily replace it. The
                                free use of money, even though it belonged to other people, awakened the temptation to
                                indulge in unwonted luxuries, and this created the need of a larger income than came
                                from honest service. Of the latest Massachusetts defalcation, on the part of a
                                Congregational church officer, it is significantly remarked by a correspondent that he
                                was ' too fond of appearances.' It does not harm the Christian religion to have these
                                things occur, but it does weaken the power of the Christian church over men. Christ
                                survives although Judas betrayed Him. If there ever was a period when a profound
                                reformation, affecting character and life, was needed, we seem to have reached such an
                                era. It is an hour when a Church fast might happily be appointed to make hearty
                                confession before God of worldliness and backsliding, and to pray for forgiveness and an
                                outpouring of His Spirit. Such a course, honestly pursued, might call out more
                                confessions, and would certainly bring down a divine benediction."</p></div3><div3 type="editorial" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How not to preach" TEIform="index"/>HOW NOT TO PREACH</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Some oi the styles of modern preachers were recently portrayed by Rev. Dr. Hurst, of
                                Madison Seminary, in this wise : " It takes ten minutes on some Sabbath morning to
                                annihilate Huxley, ten minutes more to knock Farrar's ' eternal hope' to pieces, ten
                                more to do away with Ingefsoll, and about five to close up on the Second Coming. What is
                                going to become of the poor burdened soul who has drifted into the service with his
                                bereavements, and broken future and penitent feelings?" Sound sense is this. It is time
                                that preachers realized that they are neglecting the Gospel when firing away at enemies
                                unknown and invisible to most of their congregations. Such discourses are but a waste of
                                time and ammunition. The simple Gospel of sin, righteousness, judgment and mercy, when
                                faithfully and earnestly delivered, converts more skeptics and other kinds of sinners
                                than all the arguments and denunciations in the world.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Record</head><div3 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Left "For the Better Land"</head><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blanchard, Grove B." TEIform="index"/>Grove B. Blanchard</head><p TEIform="p">At Harvard, Mass., April 23, Elder , aged 82 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Channel, Susan L." TEIform="index"/>Susan L. Channel</head><p TEIform="p">Also, May 5, , aged 71 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Whiting, Sarah" TEIform="index"/>Sarah Whiting</head><p TEIform="p">Also, May 17, , aged 75 years.</p></div4><div4 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div4"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ingalls, George W." TEIform="index"/>Geo. W. Ingalls</head><p TEIform="p">At North Union, Ohio, May 5, , aged 60 years. Also, April 27,.Tank Hunt, aged 74
                                    years.</p></div4></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To The Manifesto : Respected and Loved Editor — It may be interesting to you..." TEIform="index"/>To The Manifesto : Respected and Loved Editor — It may be interesting to you...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Ohio, Cleveland, Shakers, May 7, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Cleveland, Shakers, Ohio,
                                May 7, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p"> [Communicated. | To The Manifesto : Respected and Loved Editor — It may be interesting
                                to you and readers of the Manifesto to learn that by the decease of one of the trustees
                                of this society, in the person of our highly respected and loved brother, George W.
                                Ingalls, we have dissolved the entire board which consisted of Brothers James S.
                                Prescott, George W. Ingalls, and Samuel S. Miner, and have appointed an entire new board
                                consisting of Sisters Abigail Russell, Lydia Ann Cramer, and Brothers John Norton and
                                Cornelius Hush. The former board having signed a conveyance of all church property in
                                favor of the latter as trustees, and the latter have given a " Declaration of Trust,"
                                showing that they hold and manage the concerns of the church in " Trust," and not for
                                any selfish nor personal use. This might seem a new departure. But is it not in keeping
                                with the leading principles of our church organization from the beginning, which have
                                advocated the equality of the sexes ? With love and respect 1 am very truly, Your
                                Brother,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Reynolds, W." TEIform="persName"/>W. Reynolds</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto — Believing, as I do, that there is a demand by many souls for" TEIform="index"/>Editor Manifesto — Believing, as I do, that there is a demand by many souls for
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Harvard, May 2, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass., May 2,1880</dateline><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Carr, Martha Ann" TEIform="persName"/>Martha Ann Carr</byline><p TEIform="p">Editor Manifesto — Believing, as I do, that there is a demand by many souls for more
                                light and knowledge of our blessed gospel, and being desirous of aiding The Manffesto in
                                as wide a circulation as possible — for to me it is a blessed messenger of <pb n="140" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 140 THE SHAKER MANIFESTO. light — I take the liberty of sending to you a
                                " Widow's Mite," earned by me at my trade thirty years ago. Gladly would I do more were
                                1 able. Please give the sister who toils so faithfully on The Manifesto, my special love
                                and blessing. I am, your sister, </p><p TEIform="p">[Our sister also inclosed a quarter eagle, (gold coin), and expressed her more than
                                satisfaction very kindly and gratefully to ourself. We return great gratitude for both,
                                and will use the bright metal for the object for which she sends this blessed " Widow's
                                Mite." Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editor Manifesto—A road machine — for repairing roads— made in this vicinity..." TEIform="index"/>Editor Manifesto—A road machine — for repairing roads— made in this vicinity...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Massachusetts, Ayer, May 19, 1880" TEIform="index"/>Ayer, Mass., May 19, 1880</dateline><p TEIform="p">Editor Manifesto—A road machine — for repairing roads— made in this vicinity, is proving
                                to be the best machine for the purpose extant. Towns about here are buying them ; and it
                                is estimated that by their use twenty five per cent of the cost of repairing roads can
                                be saved, and have better roads. Nearly all the work is done with teams, and the entire
                                length of the road is formed in perfect shape. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, Elijah" TEIform="persName"/>Elijah Myrick</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>The Children's Grotto</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hint to boys" TEIform="index"/>A HINT TO BOYS</head><p TEIform="p">A philosopher has said that the true education for boys is to teach them what they ought
                                to know when they become men. What is it they ought to know, then ? 1. To be true ; to
                                be genuine. No education will be worth any thing that does not include this. A man had
                                better not know how to read —¦ he had better never learn a letter in the alphabet, and
                                be true and genuine in intention and action, rather than being learned in all sciences
                                and in all languages, to be at the same time false at heart and also counterfeit in
                                life. Above all things teach the boys that truth is more than riches, more than culture,
                                more than earthly power or position. 2. To be true in thought, language and life — pure
                                in mind and in body. An impure man, young or old, poisons the society where he moves
                                with smutty stories and impure example, is a moral ulcer, a plague spot, a leper, who
                                ought to be treated as were the lepers of old, who were banished from society and
                                compelled to cry " Unclean," as a warning to save others from the pestilence. 3. To be
                                unselfish. To care for the feelings and comforts of others. To be polite. To be just in
                                all dealings with others. To be generous, noble and manly. This will include a genuine
                                reverence for the aged and things sacred. 4. To be self-reliant and self-helpful even
                                from childhood. To be industrious always and self-supporting at the earliest proper age.
                                Teach them that all honest work is honorable, and that an idle, useless life of
                                dependence on others is disgraceful. When a boy has learned these things; when he has
                                made these ideas part of his being, however young he may be, however poor, or however
                                rich, he has learned some of the important things he ought to know when he becomes a
                                man. With these four properly mastered, it will be easy to find all the rest.</p></div3><div3 type="fiction" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Go away, satan! go away!" TEIform="index"/>GO AWAY, SATAN! GO AWAY!</head><p TEIform="p">A little girl sat upon the large stone doorstep of her father's house, and beside her was
                                a boy of about the same age. He had been eating a fresh, rosy apple, and had thrown the
                                core into the gutter beyond the walk, and watched it as the muddy water carried it from
                                his sight, then turning back to his playmate, who seemed absorbed in the pictures of a
                                new book, he said : "Give me your apple, Katie; mine is all gone." " Not now, wait a
                                little,'" was the reply. But the greedy little fellow, not willing to wait, took the
                                apple up, turned it round and round, smelled it, and then tossed it up lightly in his
                                hands, each time catching it again. I expected his teeth would go into it, but ho was
                                too honest for that. His cry brought the eyes of the little girl upon him. The blood
                                mounted to her brow ; she was at once upon her feet with one<pb n="141" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                SHAKER MANIFESTO. 141 hand raised, apparently to strike the shrinking form beside her.
                                But the hand did not fall ; and as she stood, her face and form showing the struggle
                                within, I prayed that she might not be too strongly tempted. A moment more, and her
                                voice fell on my ear — " Go away, Satan ! Go away ! " The mother within the door heard
                                the words too, and coming out asked what they meant. A blush was upon the brow of the
                                child, but it was humility and shame that caused it, while with drooping head she
                                answered, " Satan wanted me to strike Freddie, but I didn't." The mother drew her within
                                her arms and kissed her, saying : " That is right, my child; resist him and he will flee
                                from you." Would that all might learn in childhood to resist the power of temptation by
                                the help of the Holy Spirit ! Truly the world would be better for it.— Morning and Day
                                of Reform.</p></div3><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Small things" TEIform="index"/>SMALL THINGS</head><p TEIform="p">The smallest crust may save a human life; The smallest act may lead to human strife ; The
                                smallest touch may cause the body pain; The smallest spark may fire a field of grain ;
                                The simplest deed may tell the truly brave : The smallest skill may serve a life to
                                save; The smallest drop the thirsty may relieve ; The slightest look may make a heart to
                                grieve; Naught is so much but that it may contain The rose of Pleasure or the thorn of
                                Pain.</p></div3><div3 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The British school-boy just highly distinguished himself..." TEIform="index"/>The British school-boy just highly distinguished himself...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The British school-boy has just highly distinguished himself. The Bishop of Hereford,
                                while examining a class in a public school, asked what an average was. Several boys said
                                they didn't know, but at last one replied : " It is what a hen lays on." The Bishop
                                looked in amazement at the boy, who then said that he had obtained his information in
                                his little book of facts. The little book was sent for, and, when it arrived, the bright
                                boy pointed triumphantly at the following sentence : " The domestic hen lays on an
                                average fifty eggs each year."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Book Table</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very valuable series" TEIform="index"/>The Very Valuable Series</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">Of reprints being issued by I. K. Funk &amp; Co.» 10 and 12 Dey street, New York, we
                                have heretofore alluded to most heartily. We wish all our readers would send and get
                                catalogues, and satisfy themselves of the valuable work being performed by these
                                enterprising publishers; and appreciating the value of their philanthropy, aid the good
                                work by numerous subscriptions to the many good volumes they are issuing. Send ¦30 cents
                                and get a sample volume, one of Knight's History of England, and then join us in
                                complimenting the nobleness of displacing yellow-covered literature by that of value,
                                and just as cheap.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lost truths of Christianity" TEIform="index"/>Lost truths of Christianity
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Editor" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">We have had laid on our table "The Lost Truths op Chkisttanity " — a book of exceeding
                                interest, and one worthy of careful perusal and diligent study. The age we live in is a
                                progressive one, truthward ; and in the seven chapters of this beautiful volume, many
                                advances are made to correct many of the misapprehensions of our too commonly forced,
                                erroneously religious educations. We do not agree with all the conclusions it arrives
                                at; but there are so many grand assertions made therein, and so jointly with modern
                                reason and purer religion that we withhold any criticism of its errors. The work is
                                anonymously introduced to us, but it speaks for its author the extensive praise which
                                few works of its class can do ; and so sincerely is it put forward as the honest
                                convictions of its author, that it " persuades men " to a righteous way of thinking,
                                which will inevitably lead to a more righteous way of living. The truths it aims to
                                bring to light seem to have been lost to a very large number of people, who are,
                                perhaps, too bigoted or self-sufficient to be taught, but to very many it will be hailed
                                as a marvelous providence just in season. J. B. Lippincott &amp; Co., publishers,
                                Philadelphia, Pa.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="humor" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Don't be cross because you are turning gray..." TEIform="index"/>Don't be cross because you are turning gray...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Don't be cross because you are turning gray. If you are grizzly, you needn't be a grizzly
                            bear.</p></div2><pb n="142" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blending of the spheres" TEIform="index"/>BLENDING OF THE SPHERES</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="White, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>Anna White</byline><p TEIform="p"> Mt. Lebanon, N. Y. 1 The spirit world is not afar, 'Tis even with us 2. We don the garment
                            pure and white, That's given us to 3. And O how sweet the bread of life! 'Tis manna to the
                            4. As revelation's keys unlock The mysteries with 5. As well might chain the lightning's
                            flash, The rolling waters 6. The liberty the gospel brings Is given to us here; wear, soul,
                            ~ in, stay, free, We've changed our robes from what they were, To what they now ap ¦ We peer
                            into the realms of light, And see the angels It bears us through the toil and strife, As
                            years unceasing The old ereation feels the shock, And seeks anew to As bind the soul beneath
                            the lash, Of superstition's We soar aloft on eagles' wings For truth hath made us I pear;
                            there; roll; win; sway, free; And We And And It We so we'll change our mortal robe For
                            immortality's abode, list unto their gentle tread, As they draw near with heavenly bread,
                            lifts us from this earthly sphere To the angelic e'en while here, captivate the human soul,
                            And hold it firm 'neath sin's control, will not rest, it cannot feed,, Upon dead forms or
                            lifeless creed, feel the blessed angels care, To be one with them is our prayer, And so
                            we'll change our mortal robe For immortality's abode. We list unto their gentle tread, As
                            they draw near with heavenly bread, And lifts us from this earthly sphere To the angelic
                            e'en while here. And captivate the human soul, And hold it firm'neath sin's control. It will
                            not rest, it cannot feed Upon dead forms or lifeless creed. We feel the blessed angels care,
                            To be one with them is our prayer.</p></div2><pb n="143" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>Agricultural</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Quantity of seed usually sown to an acre" TEIform="index"/>Quantity of Seed Usually
                                Sown to an Acre.</head><p TEIform="p"> Herdgrass Timothy...... -J to £ bushel. Redtop................. i to 1 " Red
                                Clover.............. 6 to 10 lbs. White Clover............ 5 to 8 "
                                Lucerne................ 10 " Orchard Grass........... 1 to \\ bushel. Blue
                                Grass.............. 1 to 1 " Rye Grass............... 1 to 1| " Wheat..................
                                l|to 2 " Barley.................. 1\ to 2 Buckwheat.............. \ to 1 "
                                Carrot......,...........2% to 3 lbs. Beet.................... 4 to 6
                                Parsnip................. 3 to 6 " Onion.................4 to 6 " Ruta Baga..............
                                1 " Turnip.................. 1^ to 1 " Beans................... li to 2 bushels.
                                Peas................... H to 2 " Oats...................2 to 3 "
                                Rye..................... li to 1 " Millet................... i to | "</p></div3><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A writer in the Country Gentleman says:..." TEIform="index"/>A writer in the Country Gentleman says:...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A writer in the Country Gentleman says: <cit TEIform="cit"><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Country gentleman" TEIform="index"/>Country gentleman
                                    </bibl><quote TEIform="quote">" Salt put into whitewash is one of the best things to clean the bark of
                                        fruit trees. Clear away the surface earth down to the branch roots, and give the
                                        trunk of the tree and upper surface of the roots a good coat of salt whitewash,
                                        and it will greatly improve the appearance of the foliage of the tree."</quote></cit></p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Buying a horse" TEIform="index"/>Buying a HORSE</head><p TEIform="p">.—If any one should consult me relative to the purchase of a horse, I would advise him to
                                look well to his eyes, then see if he has sound limbs, and good feet (not flat), and
                                whether he cleans his manger. If these requisites are found, he will be a horse of great
                                endurance, whatever his shape may be. With respect to color, the adage of a Dutch woman
                                was that " a good horse never had a bad color.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Controlling vicious horses" TEIform="index"/>Controlling Vicious Horses</head><p TEIform="p"> .—A new and very simple method of training vicious horses was exhibited in West
                                Philadelphia recently, and the manner in which some of the wildest horses were subdued
                                was astonishing. The first trial was that of a kicking or "bucking" mare, which her
                                owner said had allowed no rider on her back for a period of at least five years. She
                                became tame and gentle in about as many minutes, and allowed herself to be ridden about
                                without a sign of her former wildness. The means by which the result was accomplished
                                was by a piece of light rope, which was passed around the front jaw of the mare just
                                above the upper teeth, crossed in her mouth and thence secured back of her neck. It was
                                claimed that no horse will kick or jump when thus secured, and that a "bucking" horse,
                                after receiving the treatment a few times, will abandon his vicious way forever. A very
                                simple method was also shown by which a kicking horse could be shod. It consisted in
                                connecting the animal's head and tail by means of a rope fastened to the tail and then
                                to the bit, and drawn tightly enough to incline the horse's head to one side. This, it
                                is claimed, makes it absolutely impossible for tlie horse to kick on the «ide of the
                                rope. At the same exhibition, a horse which for many years had to be bound on the ground
                                to be shod, suffered the blacksmith to operate on him without attempting to kick while
                                secured in the manner described.— Lebanon Courier.</p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="When a man is fortunate he boasts of his good management and shrewdness..." TEIform="index"/>When a man is fortunate he boasts of his good management and shrewdness...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">When a man is fortunate he boasts of his good management and shrewdness ; when he is what
                                is termed unfortunate, he complains of his ill-luck. It is said that Providence always
                                smiles on the side of the best and most bayonets and the heaviest guns. Cannot the same
                                principle be also applied to farming ? Success is the result of good management, of the
                                possession of the best breeds of cattle, best tools, and the richest soils. Success
                                springs from economy in saving and making manures, and in the judgment used in their
                                application. It consists in the proper selection of seeds, the time of mowing the grass,
                                the way and manner of tilling the ground, vigilance in destroying weeds, the care of
                                cattle and the manner of feeding, in keeping the fences in order and the buildings in
                                good repair. These are a few of the elements of good luck.</p></div3></div2><pb n="144" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What an old man has noticed" TEIform="index"/>WHAT AN OLD MAN HAS NOTICED</head><p TEIform="p">I Lave noticed that all men are honest when well watched. I have noticed that purses will
                            hold pennies as well as pounds. I have noticed that merit is always measured in the world by
                            its success. I have noticed that in nearly all things money is the main object in view. I
                            have noticed that in order to be a reasonable creature it is necessary at times to be
                            downright mad. I have noticed that some men are so honest that necessity compels them to be
                            dishonest in the end. I have noticed that silks, broad cloths and jewels are often bought
                            with other people's money. I have noticed that the prayer of the selfish man is " Forgive us
                            our debts," while he makes everybody that owes him pay to the utmost farthing. I have
                            noticed that he who thinks every man a rogue is very certain to see one wffen he shaves
                            himself, and he ought in mercy to his neighbor to surrender the rascal to justice. I have
                            noticed that money is the fool's wisdom, the knave's reputation, the poor man's desire, the
                            covetous man's ambition, and the idol of all. I have noticed that all men speak well of all
                            men's virtues when they are dead, and that tombstones are marked with epitaphs of the good
                            and virtuous. Is there any particular cemetery where the bad men are buried ?</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure of diptheria" TEIform="index"/>CURE OF DIPHTHERIA</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend — The recipe for prevention of bronchitis (spirit of wine and vinegar), twice
                            published in The British Friend, I have patronized, and keep it always by me in winter, and
                            have recommended it to many. Yesterday I saw another recipe, which I now inclose. It is cut
                            out of a St. Louis paper, America, dated Jan. 16, 1879. If it be as it is stated, it might
                            prove a boon to many. Thy friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="P., P." TEIform="persName"/>P. P.</byline></div2><div2 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cure for diptheria" TEIform="index"/>CURE FOR DIPHTHERIA</head><p TEIform="p">" We publish the following because the experiment may be safely tried, and it is worth
                            trying. Diphtheria is becoming a dreadful scourge, and the writer of what is here said, saw
                            the working of this cure in the hands of an English physician, at a time when the disease
                            was prevalent in an English town. Speaking of the physician's application, the writer says : </p><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All he took with him was powder of sulphur and a quill..." TEIform="index"/>All he took with him was powder of sulphur and a quill...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">" 'All he took with him was powder of sulphur and a quill, and with these he cured every
                                case without exception. He put a spoonful of the flour of brimstone into a wineglass of
                                water, and stirred it with his finger instead of a spoon, as the sulphur does not
                                readily amalgamate with water. When the sulphur was well mixed he gave it as a gargle,
                                and in ten minutes the patient was out of danger. Brimstone kills every species of
                                fungus in man, beast, or plant in a few minutes. Instead of spitting out the gargle, he
                                recommends the swallowing of it. In extreme cases in which he had been called just in
                                the nick of time, when the fungus was too nearly closed to allow the gargle, he blew the
                                sulphur through a quill into the throat, and after the fungus had shrunk to allow of it,
                                then the gargling. He never lost a patient from diphtheria. If a patient cannot gargle,
                                take a live coal, put it into a shovel and sprinkle a spoonful or two of flour of
                                brimstone at a time upon it, let the sufferer inhale it, holding the head over it, and
                                the fungus will die. If plentifully used, the whole room may be filled almost to
                                suffocation, the patient can walk about in it, inhaling the fumes with doors and windows
                                shut. The plan of fumigating a room with the sulphur has often cured most violent
                                attacks of cold in the head and chest."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="British friend" TEIform="persName"/>British Friend</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give a man the necessaries of life and he wants the conveniences..." TEIform="index"/>Give a man the necessaries of life and he wants the conveniences...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Give a man the necessaries of life and he wants the conveniences. Give him the conveniences
                            and he craves the luxuries. Grant him the luxuries and he sighs for the elegancies. Let him
                            have the elegancies and he yearns for the follies. Give him altogether and he concludes that
                            he has been cheated both in price and quality of the articles.</p></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>