<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0703" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><date value="18770301" TEIform="date">March1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">17-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="17" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKE OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " §o grech the kingdom of %odl"
                        The testimony of eternal ttittth. Yol. YIL G. A. LOMAS, Editor, Shakers, N. Y. MARCH, 1877. ;
                        N. A. BRIGGS, Publisher, Shaker Village, N. H. No. 3.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? no. 3" TEIform="index"/>What Shall I Do to be a Shaker? No. 3</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Dibble, Chauncy" TEIform="persName"/>CHAUNCY DIBBLE</byline><p TEIform="p">A true Shaker is simply a good Christian—pure, loving and virtuous; one who endeavors to
                            adopt all the Christian virtues and practice them. Christ's Sermon on the Mount teaches all
                            the principles of Shakerism. Whoever lives to these precepts faithfully, is fulfilling the
                            object of Shaker life, whether they are aware of it or not. Name is nothing; neither is form
                            nor theology. The essence of Christianity is love to God and love to our fellows. A
                            community formed upon this basis, whether few or many, cannot be dissimilar to a Shaker
                            community. The love of Christ produces equality and goodness ; unites all in one, as
                            brethren and sisters. "Thy kingdom come, thy will be done on earth, as it is in heaven."
                            Peace, purity, and every good virtue, is to reign in this order. These conditions are
                            usually anticipated as coming down from above, ready-made. We, as Shakers, are working for
                            attainment to this desirable state of society. Are you prepared to enter into this heavenly
                            condition ? To devote soul and body to living out these principles which produce "peace on
                            earth and good will to men?" Do you ask what it is to be Shaker ? Ask yourself what it is to
                            be a Christian, such as Jesus was, such as his apostles were, and all true Christian are.
                            When you practice the same life they did, you will be a Shaker. Come and lay your goods at
                            the disciples' feet, showing your deeds. Having consecrated all for this bond oi union, our
                            hands must work to maintain it. Labor forms a part of our religion. No idle drone can bless
                            a community. Selfishness is the bane of society, and all evil habits which clamor for
                            indulgence must be withstood. Mighty conflicts between flesh and spirit must ensue. These
                            constitute the Shaker warfare, and the test of true bravery. They that humble self shall be
                            exalted. Herein is the mystery of godliness, to dwell in harmony and do to others as we
                            would be done unto. Think not such a life is monotonous, monkish or unsocial. The tenderest
                            affections and most social intercourse are the results of purity and self-control. Do you
                            imagine that love consists in the Just the reverse. These breed disgust. You have been
                            wrongly educated. Would you be inspired with a love that abhors an unworthy act? Does your
                            soul aspire to freedom from lust and remorse ? Seek the society of those that believe in
                            having all things common ; whose foundation is righteousness. Friends, be no longer in
                            doubt. The design of Shakerism is the salvation and elevation of its subjects. But, come not
                            for the loaves and fishes, nor ease, nor indulgence. If so, you have naught to meet but
                            disappointment. False pretense will fail. 'Tis the clean cross-bearer against every vice,
                            whose life is devoted to the cause of virtue, and to the good of each other, that enjoys
                            peace and prosperity in this our circle.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hast thou forsaken all?" TEIform="index"/>Hast Thou Forsaken All ?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Behold, tve have forsaken all, and have followed Thee." Forsaken all ? Hast thou forsaken
                            all, The best and dearest of thine earthly claim ? Thy father's house, possessions great or
                            small, Hast thou forsaken these, with Christ to reign? Thy father, mother, brothers, sisters
                            dear, The objects of thine heart's affections strong, Those earthly ties that hold the
                            spirit near To all that to the earthly plane belong? Hast thou forsaken all, and wouldst
                            thou know And share the blessings of a higher life,— A part and portion in this world below
                            With those that mingle not in earthly strife? Wouldst thou enjoy that happiness of soul
                            That's wrought thro' full deliverance from thy loss, And wouldst thou willingly forsake the
                            whole That God requires, however great the cross? To find acceptance in his kingdom new, A
                            virgin, lovely, spotless, clean and pure, And whatsoe'er thy hands may find-to do, Wouldst
                            thou in holy faith all things endure ? One thing thou lackest more than all the rest, That
                            constitute the sum of earthly pelf, If thou wouldst fain preserve within thj breast That
                            idol god, the giant monster Self! Hast thou forsaken, then, that precious all, Thine earthly
                            kindred, riches, and thy self, And in obedience to the heavenly call Then, verily our
                            Saviour's words are true,— No man hath these forsaken but the strife Shall bring an
                            hundred-fold of blessings new, And in the world to come, eternal life. Then courage,
                            Christian soul, the way is clear, Marked out and trodden by the prince of light; Thou needst
                            no longer grope in darkness here, The sun is shining with effulgence bright The holy hill of
                            zion is uncapped, The misty clouds that veiled it disappeared; 3ehold the city of our God,
                            enwrapped In glorious splendor, by his saints revered, ome, then, and at the glorious shrine
                            of God, The loving seat of mercy, bow thee low; Accept the ransom, nevermore to plod The
                            paths of wickedness, distress and woe.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gifts" TEIform="index"/>Gifts</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>ALONZO G. HOLLISTER</byline><p TEIform="p">gratification of the animal passions ?| Forsaken willingly the ways of death? The greatest
                            spiritual gifts make the least external show. "Except a man be born again, he cannot see the
                            kingdom of God." That kingdom which is to break in pieces and subdue all other kingdoms, and
                            become a great mountain and fill the whole earth, cometh not with outward show, and will
                            never be seen by material eyes. A gift to see ourselves in that light of God which is
                            brought by the messengers of Christ, who are sent to reap the world, is the greatest gift of
                            vision. A gift of faith in the anointing power with which Christ clothes his true
                            messengers, and in the gospel light and testimony which they bring, confers a greater power
                            than that which moves material substances without the contact of visible hands. A gift which
                            liberates and purifie the soul from sin and sinful desires i the greatest gift of freedom. A
                            gift that removes all spiritual diseases and all soul blemishes and imperfections, and
                            restores access to the tree of life, is the greatest gift of healing. A gift to keep all the
                            commandment of God revealed in the everlasting gospel of Christ is the greatest gift of
                            power. Therefore, beloved doers of the work, let us covet the best gifts. For every good and
                            every perfect gift cometh down from above, from the Father of light, with whom there is no
                            variableness, neither shade of turning. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let us be patient" TEIform="index"/>Let Us be Patient</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL ORCUTT</byline><p TEIform="p">Listen. I will not detain you long. Vly subject is patience. Patience is one of the greatest
                            of virtues, and those who possess it have that which will make them more kind and lovely,
                            and setter fit them to meet every-day crosses and trials that occur in life. Some persons
                            seem to have a " charm," if I may use the word, which helps to keep their minds calm, clear,
                            and peaceful, and their lives appear as a beautiful xample. This charm, I think, must oe the
                            heavenly disposition which they earn to possess, to bear afflictions patiently, willingly. I
                            often think how much happier we might be if we would earn more patience, and receive with
                            meekness and humility all chastening necessary for our purification, as coming from our
                            Father in heaven, for our highest good; which would prove a blessing, although to us it
                            might seem the l'everse. It is astonishing how many people there are who go through life
                            wearing a frown, losing all the happiness they might enjoy if they would cultivate patience
                            and cheerfulness, and look on " the bright side of life." Impatience makes us unhappy, and
                            causes others to feel uncomfortable. Let none of us think there is nothing worth living for,
                            no good that we can do, no happiness in store for us, no friends faithful and true, no God
                            of love, and no heaven for those who "run with patience the race set before them." Let none
                            of us take such a desponding view of a virtuous life that we can see no beauty in the
                            crucifying work. This life is short. Why grieve about crosses that lie in our way, hough
                            they are many? or why stumble at every obstacle in our path? Our great exemplar has not
                            taught us to do thus; his life was patient, perfect, peaceful, pure. May we walk in his
                            footsteps; so live that our influence may tend to promote the happiness of all within our
                            reach. I would not claim to be a model of patience, but will toil on patiently, and bear
                            tribulation for the gospel's sake ; " for tribulation worketh patience, and patience
                            experience, and experience hope," " and all who have this hope,"—that is, the hope of being
                            like Christ,— " purify themselves even as he is pure." Enfield, Conn,</p></div2><pb n="18" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 7" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way, No. 7</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">I refer with pleasure to the admonition which I find published in a paper having many
                            thousands of subscribers. There seems to be the same necessity at the present time, as in
                            the past, that a systematic course of teaching should be given to class after class. It is
                            precept upon precept and line upon line. The same unchanging warning voice from childhood to
                            manhood. "Parents should be on such terms with their children that they will have no
                            correspondence that is kept secret; and they should, as a matter of safety, see that no
                            matter reaches their children through the mails which does not pass through their own
                            hands." This is just as it should be. It seems that there is a class of publishers and
                            venders of demoralizing literature, and even of filthy publications, who avail themselves ot
                            the privilege of the U. S. mail, through which to reach more readily the homes and minds of
                            the children and the youth. In this clandestine manner, unobserved by the parents and
                            guardians, they force a stream of corrupting influences upon their manners and morals. If
                            this warning voice is demanded for the protection of children and youth in private families,
                            and public institutions, then it becomes doubly necessary for the parents and guardians of
                            our religious order to protect, as far as possible, their children and youth from the same
                            objectionable matter. Most certainly we are not beyond these baneful influences which,
                            through papers, books and letters, are so largely circulated ; and it is as imperative that
                            we should hold our children so kindly within the circle of our affections, that they would
                            not wish to pursue any unprincipled course, either in regard to receiving or circulating
                            that which is immoral. Hid away as securely as it may be in the fine type of the American
                            Agriculturist, we hope that the warning voice of the good editor may be seen by every
                            reader. It is not sufficient that quietness should mark our way, because we are established
                            upon a religious foundation. The same influences that are enervating and destroying the
                            souls and bodies of the thousands upon thousands, has more or less effect upon those who
                            gather to our homes. There is need of better conditions. In accepting children and youth,
                            and even adults, into our institution, it is foi the express purpose of having them so live,
                            and so educated, that they may become worthy members of the society. Unless we are better
                            able to watch over and protect them from wrong than were those from whom they were received,
                            we do them and ourselves a great injustice. Separated though we may be from fhe order of the
                            world, we should prove unworthy disciples of our Lord, or as members of a religious body, if
                            we failed in any point of the duty assigned to us. It is not only the utter vileness, the
                            bold and glaring evils, which may occasionally i-each us through the mails, that we have
                            need to fear, but that even which comes in a still more subtle form, through the columns of
                            familiar papers ind periodicals, and, may be, from the office of the so-called religious
                            publications. These, yea, these which are so largely patronized and extensively published
                            are equally to be dreaded. And as I would earnestly warn a riend against an impending
                            danger, so would I warn those who stand on this side of the " evergreen shores" against :he
                            sinful indulgence of reading for pleasure, or hearing from curiosity, that which is
                        immoral.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Love" TEIform="index"/>Love</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Cable, D. F." TEIform="persName"/>D. F. CABLE</byline><p TEIform="p">In our bright happy sphere. Or in heaven above, Where all virtues appear, There is nothing
                            like love I It ennobles, refines. The rough nature of man ; And in woman it shines
                            As—nothing else can ! 'Tis the lamp that illumes The dark hours of strife; 'Tis the rose
                            that perfumes The fair garden of life; 'Tis the landmark that guides O'er the ocean of care,
                            And the dark rolling tides Of a gloomy despair. 'Tis a heaven of rest; 'Tis an eye to the
                            blind; 'Tis a boon to the blest; ' Tis a calm to the mind. 'Tis a link that unites us In
                            heart, tho' abroad ; 'Tis the glory that lights us To a knowledge of God.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Seraph: a vision" TEIform="index"/>The Seraph: A Vision</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Liddell, Susanna Cole, jr." TEIform="persName"/>SUSANNA COLE LIDDELL, JR.</byline><p TEIform="p">She came, this bright seraph, in haste o'er the lea, Her step seeming soft as the zephyr to
                            me; Her visage depicted the presence of youth, All brightly aglow with the mission of truth.
                            Her being, all radiant with glimmers of mirth, Betokens the joy yet to dawn upon earth ; And
                            sweet as the flower in vernal perfume Appeared this bright seraph in her vestal bloom.
                            Supreme was the beauty that reigned in her heart. Which visions elysian glory impart; The
                            beryl, transmitting its various dyes, Compares with the luster her treasures devise. The
                            light from her life of the spiritual birth, Reveals lasting blessings of undying worth, And,
                            gilding the ether encircling our world, Gives forms as of banners in splendor unfurled. In
                            grateful obeisance to this seraph bright, The angelic hosts would her presence invite And
                            far warmer kindliness beams from her eyes Than the sun-lighted arrows that traverse the
                            skies. Her promised appearance — her mission grace And truth—kindles rapture in every face;
                            And standing upright in broke her beauty, she i Such souls as are cleansed from the stains
                            of the fall, The silence-bound spell, while as follows she spoke: "The children of God are
                            the pure in heart: All such from the ways of transgressors depart; The hairs of our heads
                            are all number'd, we 're taught, And so are the evils that through us are wrought. 2ach word
                            and each act shall be judged at the bar Of eternal justice. Whatever we are n this state of
                            trial, we there must appear, And render account of our stewardship here. "Yet even while
                            here, to the honest and true Bright glories, immortal, will open to view; The rainbow of
                            promise, appearing in sight, nspires every soul with unceasing delight. The manna of heaven
                            is fresh on the dew; '.t comes with the morning, delicious and new. The ransomed of Israel
                            are fed to their fill On this food of angels, the heavens distil. "Though dim is the spirit
                            of Christ to the blind, Tis equally dim to the bigoted mind; Tis shipwreck of faith that
                            eclipses the light; God's gifts then appear as disasters of night. His nature, unchanged, is
                            the same as of yore; He is still in the fiery pillar before; Redeeming from bondage,
                            sustaining in grief, Assisting the needy by timely relief. "The temple He reared for the
                            Israelite's eye, That they might the pleasures of idols deny; He took from the nations of
                            all that was best, That beautiful temple in which to invest. As pictures of these, to the
                            juvenile mind, Incite to intelligence, pure and refined, These les. ns portrayed in this
                            symbolic mode, Prefigured in signs the celestial abode. "The favored of God must in spirit
                            be strong. Sustaining" and helping the feeble along. True faith is a God-given boon to
                            possess, Accorded to Abraham a true righteousness. It was the legitimate graft of the soul
                            Which Christ, in his mission, did fully unfold. The glorious Image, Divinity's form, Our
                            blessed Redeemer in truth did adorn. " The channel is faith through which knowledge doth
                            come— That knowledge we have of the eternal One. Through faith was revealed to the patriarch
                            true The God-given promise to bless and renew To all coming nations of Abraham's seed. That
                            blessing should follow the faithful, indeed, Who truly are worthy, through watching and
                            prayer, The blessing of Abram and Jesus to share. " Where much has been given, will much be
                            required; The faithful, by infinite wisdom inspired, Will multiply talents, increasing in
                            worth. That unfaithful servants will hide in the earth. Hence, leaders in Israel are called
                            to be true, Unshaken and faithful in carrying through The work that is destined to bring to
                            the race Salvation from sin through the order of grace. Through justification will honor
                            their call, Released from the fetters of slavery and sin, Their spirits betoken that Christ
                            is within. "This spirit of Christ in the saints that compose His church here on earth, is a
                            beacon to those WTho 're wand'ring o'er mountains and deserts, to find An ark of protection
                            and rest to the mind. All such as are willing their lives to lay down, Will win in bright
                            glory an immortal crown ; While those who in sacrifice give not the whole, Will forfeit a
                            birthright more precious than gold. " Then courage, companions in life's toilsome way, The
                            path will grow smoother, and brighter the day; God's promise is sure,—He will never forsake
                            The soul that 's determined the kingdom to take. And such as in life's early stages begin
                            The work that shall cleanse from the nature of sin, Persistent in strife till the conquest
                            is o'er, Like flowers shall bloom on that beautiful shore." Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="An analysis of human society in two numbers, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>An Analysis of Human
                            Society, IN TWO NUMBERS. NO. I Declaring the law which creates and sustains a community
                            having goods in common.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">I introduce the following analysis with a few remarks on co-operation. Having been identified
                            with co-operative efforts, and also with communities having goods in common, during the past
                            forty years, I would, for the benefit of those having aspirations after a higher life than
                            our present civilization aflbrds, offer a few thoughts. A number of persons uniting their
                            labor and capital in any industrial business, is co-operation. The relative conditions of
                            rich and poor are not disturbed. The strong are strong for themselves, the rich are rich for
                            themselves. The one do not bear the infirmities of the weak, nor the other the conditions of
                            the poor. Co-operation may be just, but organically it is destitute of the benign—the Christ
                            element. Justice is not goodness ; it is sim-ply an exchange of equivalents. Goodness
                            illustrates itself in giving, but expects no return. They are organically distinct. The
                            former ma}' be an eye for an eye, or a stroke for a stroke. Or it may be a pair of boots for
                            a barrel of flour—a bushel of wheat for two yards of cloth. The latter returns good for
                            evil, blessing for cursing. The former yields just acts, the latter divine deedsCapitalists
                            may co-operate, and control the property of a country. The real capital of a country is not
                            gold nor bits of paper. If there was no surplus of the necessaries of life in the markets of
                            the world, what would that which is called capital amount to ! Nothing. Therefore, the
                            actual capital of a country is the food and clothing, and other necessaries of life, which
                            the laborers of a country have produced and have to spare. If gold, silver, and bits of pa"
                            Salvation is wrought by confession of sin,! per capitalists co-operate and control At God's
                            sacred altar forgiveness to win : By ceasing from evil, and learning the right, j The deep
                            scarlet robe is exchanged for the white. the real capital of a country, they control that
                            which does not belong to them. That which the laborer has produced should never, in the
                            hands of others, <pb n="19" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> 19 be allowed to control him, nor affect in-!the midst
                            of his quiet home, extends to juriously that which he has produced. Within the last century,
                            a number of wealthy men co-operated and took possession (under the title of "The East India
                            Cojnpany,") of a great country, containing millions of people. They controlled the land,
                            and, of course, the laborer and what he produced. Hold ing absolute possession of the soil,
                            they assumed to be at once rulers, legislators, you the olive-branch of fraternity. How is
                            it that the noblest of men have not been able to "establish communities having goods in
                            common? They had honest hearts, ability and zeal, and other elements of success; yet they
                            failed. The non-success of the moral, the financial, and the Sab- it seemed an atmosphere of
                            light, calm, batical—of days, rest to the body ; Sabbath of years—rest to the land and a
                            canceling of debts : and every fiftieth year, all who had lost their land took possession of
                            it again. These laws were more sweeping in their practical operation than most are aware of.
                            a combination communities, embracing a number of The nations and civilizations of
                            anfamilies, and the success of the Shaker | tiquity fell in consequence of the unreorder,
                            led me to an analysis of human j strained action of the propensities society. For if
                            physical things can be analyzed, and their forces, affinities, and quantities determined,
                            why should adopted ultimated, within the past few j not human society also be analyzed,
                            years, (under the auspices of the British government,) in the destruction of millions of
                            human beings. Co-operators, on a smaller scale, buy great tracts of land, monopolize it and
                            the contained minerals; coal, for instance, an article given for the general good of all.
                            These co-operators tax the community, and sometimes actually control legislation. Hence,
                            co-operation may be satanic, as above, or be just, as is the case with that form of
                            co-operation which attracts attention at present; which creates property, and distributes it
                            according to the power expended in creating it. Every infringement of justice is a satanic
                            act. The prima facie evidence is, that the and its forces and affinities ascertained, and
                            thereby prevent, in the future, material loss and disappointments? Modern civilizations are
                            taking the same course. It is righteousness alone that exalteth and giveth permanency to
                            nations. The mission of Jesus was to begin on earth the divine order of human society, as
                            was manifested in the Pentecostal With this view, w7e will inquire— j church, and now in
                            that of the Shakers. First—What are the primary atoms of human society? Second—What are the
                            forces of these atoms. Third—What are the products of these forces on each other? The divine
                            faculties were and are called into action, and the propensities excluded. The results were,
                            and are, a virgin life and a community of all good things. If communities, having goods in
                            cornFourth—What are the organic lawsjmon, based on the total exclusion of the action of the
                            propensities, exists in which create and define distinct classes in human society? and what
                            phases does society assume in reference to the organic laws of each ? I will now classify
                            the materials to be analyzed. Human society presents itself in three greater present.
                            portion of is satanic. human action, at The late war—the stupendous struggle satanic power
                            was, of the slave—the intrinsically, to distinct orders and the divine. the just, the
                            satanic. The organic law of cause the slave to create property, and consume none except what
                            was necessary to create more. The sympathy extended to said power by the ruling, the
                            educated, and established religious pies. classes, over nearly the whole surface of
                            Christendom, indicated what form of society at present prevails. All efforts at reform are
                            to prevent certain persons from holding and consuming property which they did not create. I
                            suggest that all co-operative societies, the members being creators of property, should have
                            legislative protection, bounties, etc., afforded them ; so that a just state of things may
                            Pre vail. Communities having goods in common, embrace the justice of co-operation with this
                            organic difference: that the strong are strong for the weak as well as for themselves, and
                            that the two great classes, rich and poor, are unknown. Such a community is a manifestation
                            of the divine in man, even as slavery ib of the satanic. Every act of goodness is a divine
                            act. Man being capable of benign acts, is evidence that he has a divine life within him ; in
                            a germinal state it may be. The incipient quickening of the divine in man has been the cause
                            of efforts to establish communities having goods in common, organically embracing and
                            manifesting- the benign or divine element in humanity. Jesus recognized this element—"be ye
                            perfect, even as your is perfect." the just order is love of self and neighbor a self. This
                            order was represented by the Jews, and is beginning to appear in the United States. "All men
                            are equal." See also Homestead Bill, and other items flowing from just princiour day, the
                            cause must be referred to the divine element in man being quickened. way ; I reason. At
                            Father who is in Heavi •• Ye are gods—divine, to whom the word of God came. Greater things
                            than these shall ye do." "He who is the greatest, let him be your servant," etc. This can
                            only be accomplished when the divine in man is quickened. This quickening convicts of sin,
                            of righteousness, ana of judgment. If we glance for a moment at leading minds in the
                            movement A Jew had as practical a right to land so that he might eat, as to air so that he
                            might breathe. And usury being forbidden, prevented the growth of a moneyed aristocracy,
                            controlling the products of labor, and arbitrarily changing their value. The organic law of
                            the satanic is, love of self at the expense of the neighbor. This order is represented by
                            two phases. First, by holding human beings in absolute vassalage; breaking up the
                            matrimonial and parental relationships of the enslaved ; taking from them the property they
                            create ; standing between them and knowledge, and trampling upon their free agency. The
                            second phase is manifested in countries called free; said countries bringing forth
                            millionaires, paupers and criminals. The land—the prime element of existence—being in the
                            hands of a few, the masses are compelled to submit to the outrage of having no land, and of
                            being servants to those who have. Forced to pay interest on enormous debts which they never
                            contracted, and to support governments instituted to oppress them, and priesthoods for which
                            they have no reverence. The organic law of the divine order of human society is love to God
                            supremely, and neighbor more than self— " in honor preferring one another." ••Let the
                            greatest be the servant." This order was represented by the the toward forming communities,
                            we find them the noblest of the noble. Their highest aspirations were to inaugurate among
                            men the reign of love and universal peace. Self-sacrificing men, all honor to you, A simple
                            Shaker, from</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Little Lou, Weldon's wishes" TEIform="index"/>Little Lou, Weldon's Wishes</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leggett, Ezra T." TEIform="persName"/>EZRA T. LEGGETT</byline><p TEIform="p">I'd like to be an angel, But not to sigh away My bonny, golden hours, That brighten life
                            to-day. I'd be a dimpled angel, And laugh, instead of cry, Till every dark, unsilvered cloud
                            Was driven from my sky. The angel from the better land, That comes to me at night, And
                            smiles upon me in my dreams, Oh, she is my delight. I want to be the angel, While dwelling
                            here below, That takes my heaven with me, Wherever I may go. My moments are too fleeting,
                            Too few my promised years, To let my heart be beating To unrequiting tears. So I'll gather
                            all the gladness From the seasons as they roll, And make the better angel For the sunshine
                            in my soul. Union Village, O.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Presbyterian's vision" TEIform="index"/>A Presbyterian's Vision</head><p TEIform="p">WHAT CHURCH IN HgAVKN DID HE SEE ? ovely and changeless. The buildings seemed all palaces,
                            but not like the palaces of earth ; the pavements were all alike of gold, bright and
                            shining, and clear as glass; the larger and glittering windows seemed like a divided
                            rainbow, and were made to give and transmit none but the rays of gladness; it was indeed a
                            place to which hope might bend, and where charity may dwell. I could not help exclaiming as
                            I went along: " These are the habitations of righteousness and truth"—all was bright and
                            perfect. I could not tell what was wanting in me, to wish for eternity in such a place, and
                            yet its very purity oppressed me ; and I saw nothing congenial, though looks of kindness met
                            in every face of that happy throng. I felt responsive—I turned in silence from their
                            friendly greetings, and walked on alone, oppressed and sad. I saw that all went one
                            followed, wondering the length I saw them approach a building much larger and finer than the
                            i-est; I saw them ascend its massive steps, and enter beneath its ample porch, but I felt no
                            desire to go with them. I approached. I saw persons enter who were dressed in every varied
                            costume of the nations, but they disappeared within the xnxh, and crossed all dressed in
                            white. O, could I describe that hall to you ! It was not the marble, it was not the crys:al,
                            it was not gold, but light! pure ight consolidated into form. It was the moon without its
                            coldness, it was the sun without its dazzling ray, and within it was a staircase, mounting
                            upwards, all of light, and I saw it touched by snowy feet, and the white and spotless
                            garments of those who ascended. It was indeed passing fair, but it made me shudder and I
                            turned away. As I turned, I saw on the lower step, one looking at me with an interest so
                            intense and manner so anxious, that I stopped to hear what he had to say. He asked in a
                            voice like music, "why do you turn away?" "Is there peace elsewhere?" " Is there pleasure in
                            works of darkness?" I stood in silence, he pressed me to enter, but I neither answered nor
                            moved—suddenly he disappeared and another took his place, with the same look and manner. I
                            wished to avoid him, but I seemed riveted to the spot. " Art thou come so far," said he, "
                            and wilt thou lose labor? Put off thine own garment and take the white livery here." He
                            continued to press me until I grew weary and angry, and I said I do not like your livery,
                            and ? I am oppressed by your whiteness. He sighed and was gone. Many passed by me with looks
                            of mingled kindness and The following vision was published in The Presbyterian, and we ask
                            all good Presbyterians and other folk, to read of the good things which some one lost, by
                            non-compliance with most urgent requests. What church in spirit pity, and pressed me to
                            follow them on, and offered me a hand up the steps, which led to their mysterious change,
                            but I rejected them and stood melancholy and distressed; at length one bright young
                            messenger came up to me and entreated me to enter with a voice land does as he saw saints
                            doing? In whose honor do saints sing and dance ?|ca^gt Pentecostal church, and is now by the
                            people called " Shakers." With them there is neither millionaire, pauper nor penitentiary ;
                            slave nor dependent; and the greatest is the and manner which I could not resist; do not
                            turn away" said he, " ^here iou go? Do not linger, for why Let us reflect! En. Ishouldst
                            thou linger for naught? EnI thought I was walking in the streets ter then, and taste of
                            happiness. Do of a great city, many people were walk- not all tribes and colors press into
                            that warmme his ing there besides myself; but there was hall? Are they not clothed and
                            something in the air which immediately ed and comforted?" He gave struck me. They seemed
                            thoughtful hand and I entered the hall along with and cheerful; neither occupied with|him.
                            Here I was sprinkled with pure business nor pleasure, but having about water, and a garment
                            of white put on where he who is most of a servant. The mission of Moses was to estab- them
                            such a dignity of repose, such me, and I know not how, but I mountlish the just order. And
                            to effect that high and settled purpose, .such grace jed the staircase with my happy guide,
                            he required that the propensities (which and purity as never was stamped on |O what a light
                            burst upon me when I all have in common with the lower animals,) should be subject to the
                            following laws :—The dietetic, the procreative, the agrarian, the agricultural, reached the
                            summit. Mortal words cannot describe it, nor mortal fancy mortal brow. The light of the city
                            was also strange; it was not the sun, for there was nothing to dazzle : it was!conceive it.
                            Where are the living saphnot the moon, for all was clear as day;iires? Where are the
                            glittering stars THE S BLA: E Tl.<pb n="20" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE SHAKER. that are like the
                            bright radiance on which I stood ? Where ai'e the forms, or the looks of love that breathed
                            in the innumerable company around me? I sank down overpowered and wretched. I crept into a
                            corner and tried to hide myself~, for 1felt that I had nothing in unison with the blessed
                            creatures of such a place. They mere moving in a dance to the music, to the harmony of songs
                            that never fell upon my mortal ear. My guide joined in rapture, and I was left alone. I saw
                            tall forms, fair and brilliant in the ineffable felicity,—their songs and looks of gratitude
                            forming the circumstances and differences of each. At length I saw one taller than the rest,
                            one every way more fair, more awful—surpassing thought, and to him every eye was turned ;
                            and in his face, every face was brightened. The song and dance were to his honor, and all
                            seemed to drink from him their life and joy. As I gazed speechless and trembling in the
                            amazement, one who saw me left the company and came where I stood. Why, he asked, art thou
                            silent? Come quickly and unite in the dance and Join in the song. I felt a sullen anger in
                            my heart and answered with sharpness : "I will not join in your song, for I know not the
                            strain. I will not join in your dance, for I know not the measure." He sighed and with a
                            look of surprising and humiliating pity, he returned to his place. About a minute after
                            another came and addressed me as he had done, and with the same temper I answered him in the
                            same words. He seemed as if he could have resigned his own dazzling glory to have changed
                            me. If heaven knows anguish he seemed to feel it, but he left me and returned. What could it
                            be that put such a temper into my heart! At length the Lord of the glorious company of these
                            living forms of light and beauty, saw me and came where I stood. I thrilled in every pulse
                            with awe ; I felt my blood curdle, and the flesh upon me tremble. My heart grew hardened, my
                            voice was bold. He spoke, and deep-toned music seemed to issue from his lips. "Why sittest
                            thou so still, when all around you are so glad! Cotne join in the dance, for I have
                            triumphed. Come join in the song, for my people reign." Love ineffable unutterably beamed
                            upon me as though it would have melted a heart of stone, but I melted not. I gazed an
                            instant, and then said : " I will not join in the song, for I know not the strain ; I will
                            not join in the the measure." dance, for Creation I know not would have fled at the change
                            in his countenance. His glance was lightning and in a voice louder than ten thousand
                            thunders, he 
                            said:
                            floor "What dost thou here?" The beneath me opened; the earth quaked, and the whirlwinds
                            encompassed me,—I sank down into tormenting flames ;—with the fright  I
                            returned to consciousness.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Death is but the passage into higher life" TEIform="index"/>Death is but the Passage into
                            Higher Life</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Johnson, Julia" TEIform="persName"/>JULIA JOHNSON</byline><p TEIform="p">Adown the stream of time we go, On mingled wave of weal and woe. Into the silent land. As
                            years recede, we near the goal, Which usher into life the soul, Where death has no command.
                            In youth, we look with solemn dread On winding sheet, and sleeping dead. And fain, would
                            never know The restful quiet of the grave; But rather those excitements crave, Attached to
                            scenes below, As hoary locks of age appear, We smile to see the crossing near. Which reaches
                            to our rest; With quickened pace and joyful tread, We hail the boundaries of the dead, As
                            sacred soil, and blest. For there the angels watch and wait, To ope ajar the golden gates,
                            Of cities bright and fair; Through which resound the welcome songs, Of the victorious happy
                            throngs, At our glad entrance there. Roll swiftly on, remaining years, Though robed with
                            joy, or washed with tears, We ask not further stay; To earth, and all her shifting scenes We
                            bid adieu for holier themes— Allied to endless day. We yearn to reach the gladsome goal,
                            Where body separates with soul, As she mounts up on high; To dwell forever there, in peace,
                            Where true attractions never cease, And love can never die. West Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Praying for what we don't expect" TEIform="index"/>Praying
                            for what we don't expect.
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">I happened once to be staying with a gentleman—a long way from here—a
                            very religious kind of a man he was; and in the morning he began the day with a long family
                            prayer that he might be kept from sin, and might have a Christ-like spirit, and the mind
                            that was also in Christ Jesus ;.and that we might have the love of God shed abroad in our
                            hearts by the Holy Ghost given unto us. A beautiful prayer it was, and I thought, what a
                            good kind of a man you must be. But about an hour after I happened to be coming along the
                            farm, and I heard him hallooing and scolding and going on finding fault with everybody and
                            everything. And when I came into the house with him he began again. Nothing was right, and
                            he was so impatient and so quick tempered. " 'Tis very provoking to be annoyed in this way,
                            Daniel. I don't know what servants in these times be good for but to worry and vex one, with
                            their idle, slovenly ways." I didn't say anything for a minute or two. And then I says, "You
                            must be very much disappointed, sir." " How so, Daniel? Disappointed?" " I thought you were
                            expecting to receive a very valuable present this morning, sir, and I see it hasn't come." "
                            Present, Daniel?"—and he scratched his head, as much as to say, " Whatever can the man be
                            talking about? " " I certainly heard you speaking of it, sir," I says quite coolly. Heard me speak of a valuable  present.   Why, Daniel, you must be dreaming. I've never thought
                            of such a thing." " Perhaps not, sir, but you've talked about it; and I hoped it would come
                            whilst I was here, for I should dearly love to see it." He was getting angry with me now, so
                            I thought I would explain. " You know, sir, this morning you prayed for a Christ-like
                            spirit, and the mind that was in Jesus, and the love of God shed abroad in your heart." "
                            Oh, that's what you mean, is it!"j and he spoke as if that weren't anything at all. " Now
                            sir, wouldn't you be rather I surprised if your prayer was to be answered? If you were to
                            feel a nice, | gentle, loving kind of spirit coming (down upon you, all patient and
                            forgiviing and kind ? Why sir, wouldn't you !come to be quite frightened like; and ^ you'd
                            come in and sit down all in a faint, and reckon as you must be agoing to die, because you felt
                            so heavenly minded ? " " He didn't like it very much," said Daniel, " but I delivered my
                            testimony, and learnt a lesson for myself, too. You're right, Captain Joe, you're right. We
                            should stare very often if the Lord was to answer our prayer."—From 'Daniel Quorm and his
                            Religious Notions."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Daniel Quorm and his religious notions" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum, A DUAL ADVOCATE OF
                            CHRIST PRINCIPLES. </p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why?" TEIform="index"/>Why?
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Why? We have never met with any who did not admit the celibate virginity
                            of Jesus. We have met with few, and but few intelligent persons, who denied that the
                            character of the Pentecostal church was the same. It is well known that some of Jesus'
                            immediate disciples were married men, and that very many of his subsequent adherents were
                            married people. It is as well known that not only were the relations of husband and wife
                            abandoned by the disciples on becoming such, but we learn that "lo! we have left all to
                            follow thee ! " This is why they "left" husbands, wives, children, houses, and lands, etc.,
                            etc.,—left their ownership and practice, had " all things in common " like brethren and
                            sisters. But the question comes often and pleadingly, "Why is it necessary you should do so
                            ? " If merely to be a follower ot Christ Jesus, this would be necessary. But had Jesus never
                            appeared, and had the discovery of the superior life been left for another, then would our
                            convictions of "the better way" be just as binding. But how can Christians follow Jesus in
                            marriage, in war, in selfish possessions, in sensual, worldly life? How can they follow him
                            where he not only failed to go, but taught explicitly the forsaking of all these and their
                            constituents, by all " who would be my disciples?" "Let the world runout?" Jesus did not so
                            question, nor his disciples with him. The world will never be depopulated because of any
                            grand rush to practical Christianity, nor because of '' the few" who will "follow him"
                            through "the straight gate" of his self-denials; for people are not so anxious to be
                            Christians. But the "why do you so?" is not on Jesus' account, but upon our own. It pays
                            better interest in spiritual things ; and to come in possession of heavenly treasures we
                            have forsaken earthly practices that prevent such possessions. This is why Jesus so lived;
                            and our lives are similar to his by coincidence seeking the same ends, our conclusion are
                            identical lives. And we know of none so spiritual as virgin celibates.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How must a spirit..." TEIform="index"/>How must a spirit...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">How must a spirit, late from earth
                            escaped, The truth of things new blazing in its eye, Look back, astonished, on the ways of
                            men Whose lives' whole drift is to forget their graves, —Young.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><index level1="Young" TEIform="index"/></byline></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Will the coming man be sick?" TEIform="index"/>Will the Coming
                            Man be Sick ?
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> A community in New York resort to what they call "cure by criticism" when any
                            of their band is sick. They get around his bed and faithfully tell him all his faults, as
                            far as known; and this, they say, "throws him into a profuse perspiration, usually resulting
                            in a speedy recovery." We copy the above paragraph from a periodical which purposed ridicule
                            by its publication. Let us see if there is not more truth in it, than subject matter for
                            ridicule. While we regret to say it, there are some disorders that are contracted by human
                            society, that are very shameful indeed ; and a knowledge, by respectable society, of those
                            afflicted, causes a criticism, that declares where they have been and
                            what they have been doing. Society says they have grossly sinned, and shuns  them until forgiven
                            by recovery. And society is right in its criticism. When for every headache, foul stomach,
                            or cold, or other of the hundreds of human afflictions, society will as justly, if not as
                            severely, criticise and condemn, '' will not the world be better for it?" If the "good time
                            coming" ever comes, it will be said of us, " there is no more sickness, we are well!" and
                            ere it does arrive, we shall be in possession of a religion whose critical demonstrations
                            upon us will often make us sweat. We want, added to what religion we now have, more of the
                            gospel of health ; a gospel that will number among sins to be confessed, condemned and
                            repented of, the almost numberless causes of getting sick, and we shall have more of, and a
                            better religion than we now have. Now, let our religion, through the church, our friends, or
                            by our own consciences, or by all combined, criticise every ailment as in a degree sinful,
                            and administer the proper rebukcful medicine, with the " go and sin no more" addendum ; and
                            though we may have some of the sins of others to bear through this life, we shall have fewer
                            of our own and their effects, to carry; and generations to come will " rise up and call us
                            blessed!" Will not the coming cycle include gospel criticism of the sick? Will the
                            Christians of the future be sick ? And when we think at there Jesus accepted any as his
                            disciple "he cured him," we are left without an argument that sustains the idea that he that
                            is sick is a Christian ! A Christian will not marry ; will not fight; will not hold private
                            property ; will live separate from the world. So far our Shaker criticism has carried us.
                            What will it yet say of a sick Christian?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Now and then" TEIform="index"/>Now and Then.
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> All should aim to live now, to
                            the ends of present comforts, and the prevention of future regrets. If present good or
                            comfort infringe on future rewards of justification, then self-denial now is better, happier
                            now, than an excess of future anguish, the consequence of excessive jubilation now.
                            Self-denial now is not intended as a punishment, nor to prevent future punishments;<pb n="21" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            SHAKER. it pays now, and for all time to come. Take the daily routine of a
                            self-denying Christian's life, with all its crosses and absence of worldly pleasure, and
                            contrast the real condition of such an one with the epicure, the unrestrained libertine, the
                            ribald, pleasure - seeking debauchee ! Which longs more for the other's condition? Does the
                            self-denying Shaker ever desire the condition of the debauchee, when the phantom he sought
                            through indulgences has fled? Does not the sickened soul of the dilapidated worldling often,
                            and very often wish, pray, anguish for the condition which every true Shaker mind should
                            possess? In the hours of solitude and sickness, of wretched feelings and hell, of a being
                            spent in pleasure, does he think it pays to be a worshiper at the shrine of Bacchus, of
                            Venus, of Mars, or Phrygia? Every hour spent now for soul-development into better men and
                            women, even in the practice of severe self-denials, will by the by be considered as angelic
                            control. Every dime and dollar saved from the pleasure of the senses, and devoted to the
                            furtherance of the gospel to other souls, will in the near future not only not be regretted
                            as so spent, but wishes many will then be vain, that hundreds were not so spent. Let us all
                            be good, be happy, enjoy every gospel good and gain. Then let us spare for the church any
                            excess that would give us present indulgence, but thereby rob the church of what it right
                            fully claims. The church of old used to demand a tenth of all. Should the same be demanded
                            now for the spread of the gospel, it would make some socalled Christians swear! And yet we
                            see them sitting not far from heaven's gate in the future, and wishing that they had done
                            differently now. ***</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">There would be very much more genuine religion in this world if people would say before our
                            faces what they speak behind our backs. To be sure, they would afifear less beautiful, but,
                            really, they would be as pretty. Just such hypocrisy, commonly practiced in feelings, words
                            and actions, is the main cause of so much irreligion and blackheartedness, so prevalent in
                            this world. When we shall appear just as we are, we shall know our real friends and enemies.
                            But when the cloaks are removed, beyond the possibility of recovery, how awfully silly a
                            great many people will act who have practiced deception successfully (?) in this life! t
                            What a monument of philanthropy is a genuine Shaker! Every Shaker in this land has a
                            thousand and more gospel parents, thousands of brothers and sisters, thousands of houses and
                            lands, and millions of dollars' worth of money ! And yet he is not only willing to share
                            parents, brothers, sisters, houses, acres, and money, but goes abroad variously trying to
                            get any or many to share these as freely as he does. With no issue by nature to leave these
                            to, he anticipates the congregations of those who are utter strangers to him now, and trusts
                            them with all he ever possessed, to be used by these successors for the same gospel
                            purposes, and transmitted to others in like manner ! </p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vicarious Atonement" TEIform="index"/>Vicarious Atonement</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The righteousness which God imputes to those whom He justifies, is the
                                    righteousness that springs from the spotless obedience and the sacrificial death of
                                    the Lord Jesus Christ. And this righteousness is a perfect righteousness, and an
                                    everlasting righteousness, and a righteousness intrinsically of infinite value.
                                    Perfect—for it needs no supplement, as indeed it can receive none. It is admitted in
                                    the court of heaven's jurisprudence as a full acquittal against all charges which,
                                    from any and every quarter, may be brought against the man to whom it is imputed. It
                                    cancels the guilt of all sin, fulfills all the requirements of law, satisfies all
                                    the claims of justice, upholds the integrity of moral government, and makes it not
                                    less honorable to the majesty of God's holiness, than to the riches of His mercy, to
                                    restore the transgressor to His friendship. Everlasting—for it shall never be
                                    superseded, and never exhausted. It will never become obsolete, but be always new,
                                    and constitute the title-deed to the saint's inheritance, as long as the inheritance
                                    itself shall last. And it is intrinsically of infinite value—for it is the
                                    righteousness not of a man, nor of any creature, however exalted, but of the Eternal
                                    Son of God.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Steane, Dr." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Steane</bibl></cit></p><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Here is the doctrine of " Imputed Righteousness " clearly stated in small
                                    compass. We find it in the Christian Intelligencer^ the organ of the Dutch Reformed
                                    Church. How intelligent men can believe such a doctrine as this, it is difficult to
                                    conceive. How the obedience, or the moral excellence of one person can be accepted
                                    as the excellence of another person, who does not possess any, and be transferred to
                                    his account, we cannot understand. How an impure man or woman can be regarded as
                                    pure because some one else is pure, is contrary to all known laws of intellectual
                                    and moral action. It would be considered monstrous in human society. The state could
                                    never regard a murderer as innocent because the hands of some of his friends were
                                    not stained with blood. No parent could think the guilt of a child was canceled
                                    because another one was willing to suffer for him. Character cannot be transferred.
                                    It is impossible in the very nature of things. It is the result of individual action
                                    and life. It is as impossible as it would be for a vine to impute grapes to the dead
                                    stake which supports it. It is a violation of all laws human and divine. It is
                                    hardly possi ble to conceive how the divine charac ter could be presented in a light
                                    more directly the reverse of all that is wise and just and good. But our readers can
                                    judge for themselves.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New Jersey messenger" TEIform="index"/>N. J. Messenger</bibl></cit></p><p TEIform="p">OUR COMMENTS. We find, in the latter of these articles, some excellent truths, as opposed to
                            the eri'ors of many " who believe a lie "—lies. As The Shaker expects every man and woman to
                            do his .and her own duty, and believes there comes a day when all will be rewarded according
                            as their works have been, it thinks it not a safe, sound nor rational position to abide in,
                            to leave our work for Jesus, or any man or woman to do for us. Jesus is our good example;
                            let us follow it. Jesus died for us—died unto sin and in defence of principles that will
                            save us from sin if we adopt them—and yet he more truly lived for us, by showing us how to
                            live them ; he lived what he taught, and said "follow me." We agree with the Methodistic
                            rhyme, which, while popular as a hymn, is a lasting rebuke to Methodist theology : "Must
                            Jesus bear the cross alone, and all the world go free ? Nay, therms a cross for every one,
                            and there's a cross for me."</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Be kind" TEIform="index"/>Be Kind</head><p TEIform="p">One more short talk, my children : Learn to be kind, first to brothers, sisters, parents,
                                teachers—and it will be thought strange if you are not kind to those who are so kind to
                                you. But let me nudge you upon the subject of kindness to animals and plants,
                                particularly the animals, for they sense pain almost or quite equal to yourselves. If
                                you are kind to them, they will be kinder, not only to you, but to every one else,
                                because you are so. In driving horses or oxen, do not jerk the reins or ply the lash
                                thoughtlessly—these actions not only hurt them, but hurt your kindness of heart, so you
                                will grow to be more unkind to everything and everybody. My heart weeps at every
                                recollection or observation of cruelty to those who cannot tell how badly they feel! and
                                if we must repent of every such cruelty committed by us, what rivers of bitter tears
                                must yet be shed for such abuses by children, and " children of larger growth!" The
                                useful animals are capable of deep affection and kindness. Let us cultivate these. I
                                have seen boys with oxen and horses, and girls with birds, rabbits and cats, who were
                                very cruel from want of sense, or to manifest authority. Don't do so, my children—think,
                                and you will not. The elephant which became enraged at those who abused him, loved and
                                fondled the little babe, even in his rage, which had always played lovingly with its
                                trunk! No horse would purposely hurt a kind child. Animals realize "what manner of
                                spirits we are in possession," and are very apt to catch of the same; therefore, deal
                                kindly with them, and you will never regret doing so. Oh! if I shall have saved you from
                                future regrets, caused you to spare the flowers, trees, and all the birds, animals and
                                persons from pain, I will be happier, not only for the saving of the pain, but, for your
                                sakes, in nipping in the bud that which, unchecked, grows in time to be a monster of
                                cruelty. Then think that naughty, unkind words hurt the animals, and particularly your
                                companions and friends. Set a guard on your feelings and tongues. A writer ot beautiful
                                poetry has said : " The springtime of our years is soon dishonored And denied, at most,
                                by budding ills, that ask A prudent hand to check them. None sooner shoots Into
                                luxuriant grozvth than cruelty, Most devilish of them all! " Be mine the prudent hand;
                                be yours the tender, loving, learning hearts. Weep with me, because of the cruelty of
                                human hearts, hands and tongues. And let our weeping produce more than tears: let it
                                create resolves of kindness, and to help others to be kind; and may God and good angels
                                make our resolves most active, my dear children. and to repeat truthfully, " I will be
                                kind," and I will be Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert " TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Albert</byline></div3><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very common error" TEIform="index"/>A Very Common Error</head><p TEIform="p">I want to point out to my hundreds of children who read The Shaker, a very common error
                                in writing and speaking — one committed frequently by otherwise good, scholarly writers
                                and speakers. It is in the improper uses of the little words, or and nor ; no, not,
                                neither and either. Almost every paper or book we read, some instances of the error
                                occur. Remember that either and or are used together, as "Either you or I must go." But
                                the most common mistake is in using no, not, neither and or together, as ''Neither you
                                or I;" "iVo man or woman, nor child or beast escaped." Corrected: '¦Neither you nor I; "
                                "No man nor woman, neither child nor beast escaped." Bear in mind that no, neither, nor,
                                not, etc., are used in conjunction, and either, or, etc. I think the cause of such
                                common, but thoughtless mistakes, is the good, grammatical rule, "Two negatives are
                                equal to one affirmative;" but this rule has no connection, in fact, with the above
                                mistakes, but may be supposed to have by many. There are some instances where the usage
                                of good writers and speakers could never be admitted to be good grammar nor sensible;
                                and the above errors are among the number. Now let me refer you to a: mistake in the
                                January number. In the beautiful music we find, "No longer," etc., and further on, "Or
                                wish," etc. This was a mistake of mine—of my eye, not of my understanding. Now read the
                                second verse, third line, and you will find better work. After a little notice of, and
                                practice in correcting these errors, you may become as afflicted by seeing them made so
                                commonly, as your friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Albert</byline></div3><div3 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker child's prayer" TEIform="index"/>The Shaker Child's Prayer</head><p TEIform="p">Have you ever seen it? It is beautifully printed, in blue, on cards. I will send each of
                                my children one on the reception of name and stamp. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Lomas, George Albert" TEIform="persName"/>Geo. Albert Lomas</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>PHYSIOLOGICAL ALCOVE</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Disease from Animal poisons" TEIform="index"/>[For The Shaker.] Disease from Animal
                                Poisons. INFECTION—INOCULABILITY—PREVENTION — DESTRUCTION</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Guilmette, C. A." TEIform="persName"/>DR. C. A. GUILMETTE</byline><p TEIform="p">Animal virus or poison, to a greater or less degree in a point of quantity as well as
                                virulency, belongs to small-pox, scarlet fever, cholera, diphtheria, measles,
                                whoopingcough, catarrh, glanders, plague, typhus* fever, typhoid fever, yellow fever,
                                metria or childbed fever, syphilis, erysipelas, hydrophobia, and pyaemia or hospital
                                fever. Animal poisons exhibit no kind of cell nor germ, and are therefore structureless.
                                They are more or less acid, and corrode more or less actively, according to the density
                                of the skin or membrane with which they may be brought in contact. When received into
                                the nose, throat, or windpipe, their action is much more rapid and sure, particularly if
                                any part or portions of the mucous membranes be denuded. Solid animal poisons, such as
                                smallpox virus, travel a very little way, not more than three or four yards, under the
                                most favorable circumstances, but hold on most tenaciously to all woolens or velvets.
                                The virus of small-pox and scarlet fever is thrown off with the epithelial covering of
                                the skin and mucous membrane; travels short distances, but holds on to solid articles.
                                It may also be conveyed in letters. The poison of measles is the same as that of scarlet
                                fever, and is thrown off mainly from the bronchial and nasal services. The poison from
                                whooping-cough is thrown off from the pharynx, or upper part of the throat; is a local
                                poison, very irritating, and may be conveyed from one child to another <pb n="22" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE SHAKER. from kissing. The same may be said of catarrh, which is
                                frequently conveyed from one person to another from shaking hands, particularly if the
                                hands be moist and are shortly after brought in contact with the lips, nose or eyes.
                                Diphtheria is conveyed with more difficulty than whooping-cough, catarrh or glanders.
                                The poison is found in the nose or throat, and is only communicable by the secretions,
                                and then the part or parts affected must be abraded. We have no evidence that it has
                                ever been conveyed by clothing. The poison from typhus fever is the most volatile of
                                all. It emanates from the lungs as well as the skin of infected persons; also, from the
                                watery exhalations. The poison from typhoid fever is soluble, less volatile than that of
                                typhus; usually conveyed in the fluid form, and may be taken into the body with
                                drinking-water or even food; it may dry on the clothes of the infected, and as a fine
                                dust may be carried short distances by the air. The poison of cholera, of the infection
                                and inoculability of which there is no question or doubt in the minds of those who have
                                tested and experimented upon its elements, obeys nearly the same laws as that of typhoid
                                fever. It may be carried as an infection, either in the form of fine powder, or in the
                                vapor of water. The above facts have been most elaborately discussed and admitted by
                                leading professors of organic chemistry and toxicology, and the few who dare to deny the
                                infection, as well as the inoculability of all animal poisons, are those who have not
                                only never satisfied themselves by stern experiment, guided by the truthful cicerone,
                                Science, but who desire to be considered singularly wise, relying upon the frail
                                position occupied by themselves in sot-distant high society, and believing that their
                                opinions must outweigh those of the scientific and practical testist. Let those obtuse
                                obstinates, by way of experiment, handle, or come in contact carelessly with an animal
                                poison, and they will be quite likely to meet the fate of the German veterinary
                                anti-trichinist, who would not believe that sausages made from pork meat containing
                                trichina were poisonous, and by way of brag ate some, and died in twentyfour hours. The
                                susceptibility of a person to any of the diseases above mentioned depends in the main
                                upon the condition, or diathesis, socalled, of the general system. Where there exists an
                                even tendency to an excess of acid in the fluids of the body, the individual so affected
                                is predisposed. It is well-known that the bodies of those who have died from small-pox,
                                scarletina, etc., have been so acid that at autopsies made upon them the edge of the
                                scalpel employed has become in a few minutes corroded and rendered for the time useless.
                                In the treatment of these diseases these facts should be borne in mind, and a healthy
                                equilibrium established as soon as possible. Five-grain doses, every thirty minutes, of
                                tartarized soda will accomplish this quicker and better than anything else, and where
                                sore throat exists, particularly in scarlet fever, from five to six-grain doses, every
                                hour, of the hydrochlorate of ammonia in water. Now that several of these poisonous
                                diseases are in our midst, every man, woman and child should be dosed for three or four
                                days with tartarized soda, in solution, or placed on the tongue dry. This will prevent
                                an attack; or, should any follow, the disease will appear in a very mild form.
                                Vaccination is a good preventive at the proper time and place, but of what advantage, if
                                the acid diathesis exists already? It is as absurd as to "lock the stable door after the
                                horse has been stolen," or to vaccinate a man when laboring under an attack of
                                small-pox! In fact, vaccination upon those laboring under an acid reaction will not only
                                hasten the development of the disease, but develop it in a much worse form than if
                                nature had not been meddled with. Persons afflicted with small-pox or varioloid, simple
                                or confluent, to avoid scars, should wash the parts frequently with a decoction of
                                Saracennia Purpurea or Indian cup, a Nova Scotia plant. Disinfectants may be good for
                                the nose of the attendant, but will not destroy virus—nothing short of extreme
                                temperature will answer—as low as 2ou or as high as 2120 Fahrenheit. In giving utterance
                                to my views on infectious and contagious diseases, the motive is not to solicit general
                                practice, as my office business gives me enough to do ; but if possible communicate to
                                my professional brethren and the public generally, the result of thirty years
                                observation and study in the first hospitals on the continents of Europe, North and
                                South America, and portions of Asia. I wish to satisfy all that the above enumerated
                                diseases are more or less infectious and inoculable, and that the maintenance of a
                                healthy equilibrium of the acid and alkaline secretions of the body is more to be relied
                                upon as a preventive of small-pox than hazardous revaccination, which the astute
                                physician seldom if ever practices upon himself. My experience has taught me to dread
                                more typhoid fever than either Asiatic cholera or small-pox. Concord, N. H.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>CORRESPONDENCE</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire, February 8, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H., Feb. 8, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Our dear Sister L-----: Your beautiful letter is before me. I have read and re-read its
                                contents several times; and had you selected any subject other than the one it
                                contained, it could not have met the appreciation that it did. I love the religious
                                tone, the subdued, humble spirit it manifested, and I prayed involuntarily: " O, divine
                                spirit, protect this, thy lamb. Do turn all her heart unto thee! Clothe her with a love
                                eternal for the truth and the purity of thy way, that she may walk in it, and not
                                falter. Make her a virgin, that she may stand with thy daughters and with thy sons, and
                                may know of the freedom which thy children inherit. Bought with a price, one among the
                                many that are called to do this work. Wilt thou, O brooding spirit of a mother, hover
                                near, and shield this little one from harm for her faith's sake, and for the innocence
                                and the purity of soul that is hers to possess. Do be jealous over the enemies of her
                                household, that would destroy the good seed thou hast sown in love and kindness. We know
                                thy spirit lives, and wilt hear this, our petition, and we trust her to thy care; though
                                she be led through deep waters, we will not doubt that the hand that guides is safe and
                                sure." Dear L-----, I might say many pleasant things of a different character; but if I
                                judge rightly, it is serious thought and meditation that best satisfies you, because it
                                is the way your convictions lead you. You must walk ; do not tire, nor be discouraged,
                                though the strife requires stern effort. If truth is ever your motto, it will anchor you
                                safely, and nothing of this earth can destroy your purpose. Ever remember me as a
                                sister, walking the same path with you, and do not fear to reach out and clasp my hand
                                for strength and aid, if obstacles you meet are hard to comprehend. We must, we will
                                stand together, and see the end of our faith, and strive with all our companions,
                                redeemed from the worldly life,—a bright, virgin band. In sweet affection, your sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stratton, Eliza A." TEIform="persName"/>Eliza A. Stratton</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The following letter is from the pen of an honorable and aged citizen..." TEIform="index"/>The following letter is from the pen of an honorable and aged citizen...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Warner, February 1877" TEIform="index"/>Warner, N. H., February,
                                1877</dateline><p TEIform="p">.[The following letter is from the pen of an honorable and aged citizen of Warner, N. H.
                                He has, for many years, been an active and influential correspondent of the press,
                                especially in the agricultural departments, and is well known, not only in this, but in
                                many of the other states, He is now 83 years of age, His first visit to this society was
                                in 1798, and from that date to the present time, has always maintained the most friendly
                                relations to the society as a whole, and an intimate social relation with many of the
                                leaders in particular. H. C. B.IMary Whitcher—My dear Friend: It seems a long while
                                since I have heard anything direct from my many friends at your pleasant village, but
                                trust there has not been any material change there since the sudden demise of my kind
                                friends, Harvey A. and Emeline K. Should I ever again visit your place, I shall sadly
                                miss their pleasant faces and friendly greetings. Change, incessant change, is one of
                                the early laws of creation, to which all animated life is subjected; and it is the part
                                of wisdom for all rational beings to be prepared for the last great change that awaits
                                us. That my kind friends were prepared for such a change we all have reason to believe,
                                and such a belief leads us to feel that " our loss is their gain." * * * I have just
                                been looking over a large collection of pamphlets, the accumulation of over half a
                                century, and find a series of pamphlets with the title of " Cincinnatus," which contains
                                much matter that may interest your young folks. Several of the pamphlets contain very
                                beautifully engraved landscape views, similar to those I forwarded some two or three
                                years ago. As I have received appreciative acknowledgments from several of the brothers
                                and sisters for former contributions, I take great pleasure in forwarding these. I
                                suppose there may be a still younger class of both sexes, for whom you will find several
                                small engravings for their acceptance. I have received the January Shaker, and was much
                                pleased in the perusal of "Notes by the Way." "I kindly thank you" has truly "a magic
                                influence." In the course of my long life, I have met with hosts of kind and polite
                                persons; as well, also, with many " churlish bipeds," whose attempts at thanks for
                                favors received was anything but civil or polite. I have perused other portions of The
                                Shaker with much interest. To all my good friends at your home please render my
                                affectionate regards. Believe me truly, your much-obliged friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bartlett, Levi" TEIform="persName"/>Levi Bartlett</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Lee, Massachusetts, February 1877" TEIform="index"/>South Lee, Mass., February,
                                1877</head><p TEIform="p">Mr. Briggs—Dear Sir: I have had The Shaker sent me, I think, ever since it was first
                                published, and cannot very well do without it. I subscribed last year at West
                                Pittsfield, through Eliza Chapin's agency. It seems her spirit has taken its flight, and
                                no more dear Eliza here. I have known her for many years, sweet soul! Inclosed is sixty
                                cents, and little enough, too, for such a work. Please favor me with it another year,
                                and as long as it is published. It is the best publication out, or that ever will be, to
                                me. Please give us plenty of Shaker music. Respectfully,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, Isaac B." TEIform="persName"/>Isaac B. Webster</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baltimore, Maryland, February 27, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Baltimore, Md., Feb. 27, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">J. E. W.—My loving Friend: It has been nearly a year since I received your kind and
                                affectionate letter. I am somewhat advanced in years, and quite out of the habit of
                                writing; and on this account I have put it off from time to time, waiting a more
                                convenient season. Please forgive me for my unfaithfulness. Your letter was received
                                with thankfulness, and has been read over and over again with much interest. I do not
                                feel worthy to be called a sister by one of God's chosen witnesses, as I have not lived
                                a true Shaker life, although I fully believe in the doctrine, and have great joy in
                                believing it to be the true and everlasting gospel. I thank God that he has prolonged my
                                life to see the millennial day. I joy to see the little paper flying through the earth,
                                going out from the new heaven with its leaves laden with "good news " and good laws,
                                both for the body and mind. These maybe the leaves spoken of in scripture, that should
                                be for the healing of the nations. The good health which I have enjoyed for several
                                years I owe in a great measure to the comforting influences which I have received
                                through those precious leaves. How happy I would be to assist in anything to help
                                promote the great and glorious work. When the little Shaker reaches me with its cheering
                                words so full of sympathy and love, it dispels the gloom and cheers the heart. I am even
                                now anxiously waiting its arrival. Remember me in your prayers. Yours sincerely, C. E.
                                B. I inclose one dollar to pay for the paper for 1877, and the balance may be retained
                                to aid in doing deeds of goodness. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., C. E." TEIform="persName"/>C. E. B.</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>OUR RECIPE NOOK.</head><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Graham gems" TEIform="index"/> Graham gems.</head><p TEIform="p">—One quart milk and two even cups of Graham flour. Beat together so us to be smooth, and
                                free of lumps; then turn in well-buttered and very hot "gem irons," and bake in a quick
                                oven. Made in this way, they are very light, tender and sweet, needing no soda nor salt.
                                If made any stiifer, they will not be light.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Newspapers for plants" TEIform="index"/> Newspapers for plants.</head><p TEIform="p">—Newspapers are a very cheap and convenient protection to plants liable to the exposure
                                of cold air. But the advantage of several thicknesses is not well understood. They
                                operate in the same way as forest leaves, namely, confine thin strata of air between
                                their layers; only newspapers, being larger than leaves, hold the thin plates of air
                                more perfectly. A large number of papers spread one above another, will afford an amount
                                of protection from cold that will be surprising to those who have not given them a
                                trial.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To extirpate house insects" TEIform="index"/> TO EXTIRPATE HOUSE INSECTS.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">—Take two pounds of alum and dissolve it in three or four quarts of boiling"
                                        water; let it stand on the fire till the alum disappears; then apply it with a
                                        brush while nearly boiling hot to every joint and crevice in your closets,
                                        bedsteads, pantry shelves and the like. Brush crevices in the floor of the
                                        skirting or mopboards, if you suspect they harbor vermin.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>— Phreti.
                                        Joicrnal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mending glass" TEIform="index"/> Mending glass.</head><p TEIform="p">—For mending valuable glass wares that would be disfigured by common cements, take a
                                mixture of five parts gelatine, to one of solution of acid chromate of lime. Cover the
                                edges thoroughly, press together, and expose to the sunshine. This mending will stand
                                the hottest water.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dr. Hollock, in a late convention in New York..." TEIform="index"/>Dr. Hollock, in a late convention in New York...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Dr. Hallock, in a late convention in New York, criticised the soundness of the doctrines
                            which give to a dead hundred-millionaire a seat by the white throne, side by side with
                            Jesus, whose life was spent in a diametrically opposite manner; and, measured by the
                            standard in vogue with us, was no success, while the hundred-millionaire's was completely
                            such. The truth is, that spiritualism and the life of Jesus are so simple, they become a
                            stumbling-block to the Jews of to-day as they did to those of old, and there was no
                            appositeness in the dying millionaire proclaiming, "I can never lose my faith in fe~ sus."
                            Christianity only became corrupt when it became rich.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Christ's Gospel brought was love and peace..." TEIform="index"/>The Christ's Gospel brought was love and peace...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The word Christ's Gospel brought was love and peace, A reconciling word to sinful men ; That
                            they from enmity and strife should cease, And as one family should dwell again. But, still
                            estranged, behold the nations stand ! While over Europe hangs the cloud of war, Which but of
                            late made desolate our land, But now in mercy driven from us afar. But still do enmity and
                            hate remain, One nation still we are, but not one race; From human limbs have fallen
                            slavery's chain; When from the mind shall vanish, too, its trace, And in our hearts truth's
                            glorious power be known, And self, and sin, and hate be overthrown ?</p></div2><pb n="23" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lord's sabbath" TEIform="index"/>The Lord's Sabbath</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>ELDER F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">What is it? " God did rest, the Sabbath-day, from all his works, and was refreshed." '"How
                            did he rest? Was he tired? " He that is entered into his rest, he also hath ceased from his
                            own works, as God did from his. " How did God cease from his working?" If Jesus had given
                            them rest, he would not afterwards have spoken of another day, another Sabbath. ''There
                            remaineth, therefore, a rest, or Sabbath, for the people of God," yet to come. Jesus gave to
                            his followers no Sabbath-day. When himself and disciples broke the Jewish Sabbath, Jesus
                            justified it. We do good on the Sabbath, and so will ye also, when it suits your selfish
                            convenience. "The Sabbath was made for man, not man for the Sabbath." "Jesus was Lord of the
                            [true] Sabbath." The centennial commissioners admitted thousands, each Sabbath-day. They
                            excluded the masses, to whom the exposition belonged, and who had as good a right as the
                            commissioners to be their own judges of what comported with their own welfare. It was a
                            national affair, a world's fair. As this nation is composed of all theological sectarians on
                            earth, each day is a Sabbath, held sacred by some of its people. The American government is
                            not more Christian than Hindoo, and has no constitutional right to teach, nor enforce, any
                            form of theology, nor to appoint a theological Sabbath. It was insulting the people of the
                            whole world to invite them to a world's exhibition, and then compel them, at great expense,
                            to lose one day in seven, observing a Sabbath not their own, and then have to keep their own
                            Sabbath, or be irreligious. As a people, an order, our existence is assured only so long as
                            the government remains unsectarian, —¦ separate from all theology, just as Jefferson anc
                            Paine created and left it, — a civil gov ernment. The Shaker church, or dispensation, is the
                            " Sabbath of the Lord, the Sabbath of Jesus." It includes the shorttime Sabbaths of the
                            Jews, one day in seven, one month in seven, one year hi seven ; and then the jubilee,
                            typical of the dispensation, wherein there should be no poverty, the land and the labor
                            being in common. At the jubilee of jubilees, or Sabbath of Sabbaths, the land returned to
                            its proper owners, the people, men, women and children. A general bankrupt law released all
                            debtors, and slaves were made land-owners. The radical principle revealed by Jehovah, that
                            land was no more property than sea, air or sunshine, was operative in the short-time
                            Sabbaths. Shakerism is lord of the short-time Sabbaths,— swallows them up. It is a long-time
                            perpetual Sabbath, a day of rest from selfish property and its concomitan curses. The truth,
                            the good, the bless ing of gospel brotherhood and sister hood, ultimated in Pentecostal
                            love, thaw of life, the Pentecostal church, ^his was the child-man which the ragon,—Rome,
                            the first beast, coming p out of the sea, — destroyed from arth. The murderous emperor,
                            Contantine, set up in its stead an antihristian kingdom, likened to a bear, ion and leopard.
                            It was a church-andtate system of rights, ceremonies, dogmas, creeds, and a .Sunday, with
                            other lays of saints and martyrs innumerable, as now observed by Catholics,— marriage, war,
                            land-monopoly, religious persecution, the inquisition, and the misery to the poor,
                            consequent upon the abrogation of even the shorttime Sabbaths that, under the law, did
                            provide for a day, a month, a year, and then during the jubilee all the substantial
                            necessaries and comforts of life, by universal labor, universal possession and enjoyment of
                            the earth, for a time leaving the "all things common" of the Pentecostal church entirely out
                            of sight of the poor, as being utterly impracticable on earth. The second
                            beast,—protestantism,— came up out of the earth, copying all he evils of the first beast,
                            and omiting nearly all the good of the shorttime Sabbaths of the Jews, and many of the
                            doctrines and practices of the Drimitive Christian church. Then we lave the
                            protestant-puritanic Sabbath, Thanksgiving and Christmas, stuffing :hose who have and
                            starving those who have not,—a purely ceremonial day, no Sabbath at all; nay, not even the
                            shadow of one. Anti-Christ has reigned, and made desolate ; all is Babylon,—a permanent
                            religious panic. "Come out of her, my people, that ye be not partakers of her sins, and
                            receive not of her plagues,—her seven plagues,' was the call of God to Mothei Ann and her
                            followers, no less than to the rationalists, — infidels to Babylon theology,—and sceptics of
                            al kinds, than to those who had "wandered after the beast, or his image.' Through the more
                            spiritual elements these latter were called by the gospel to found the first cycle of the
                            new heav ens. The former were called by the same spirit to found the firs cycle of the new
                            earthly gov ernment, — the government of the United States. The earth had to be redeemed as
                            the basis for the new heav ens to rest upon, and as a source o supply of members, by which
                            alone1 a celibate order could be supported. Is it consistent, or would it be right, for
                            followers of the first and second beasts,—sectarians,—to bring into Zion the prejudices and
                            persecuting spirit of religious bigots, against the infidels to false theology and its
                            damnable effects upon mankind? It is an error to be eradicated. Each of those parties has
                            some truths the other needs ; and each has some errors to be shaken oft'. Hume, Voltaire,
                            Humboldt, Tyndall, Paine, Jefferson, Franklin, and their fellows, search for God in nature,
                            in man. Thi religion was and is to do good to a. men, to kill no human being, nor evento
                            torture them. Voltaire caused the bolition of torture in France as applied to witnesses.
                            Paine sought to bolish capital punishment and war, nd voted in the French assembly to -call
                            the king, but spare the man, Louis. ?he infidel class in America effected be abolition of
                            imprisonment for debt; aused the homestead bill to be passed, and secured the freedom of
                            public lands to actual settlers; gave women protection in property to some extent; did good,
                            and nothing but good. Lincoln, an infidel, signed the emancipation act. What have the
                            orthodox church party of America to show of practical good done on earth ? Have they not
                            opposed every good measure for redeeming the earth, from that of land limitation to that of
                            slavery? Is not their selfish, cruel oppression enough to make men mad ? Of old, the
                            orthodox party did make men mad by their crusades and St. Bartholomew massacres, their
                            inquisitions, religious wars and persecuions. Is not all the blood shed upon earth of
                            Babylon,—church and state,— "eligion ? And God gave her blood to drink in the American and
                            French revolutions, a reaction of humanity against the ecclesiastical-theological tyranny
                            and oppression of past ages. Paul said to the Galatians: i; I stand n doubt of you ; ye
                            observe days, and months, and times, and seasons. The Son of Alan is Lord of all these."
                            Having been called into the gospel, with its increasing cross, they preferred the shadow to
                            the substance. They would rather pay a tenth than sacrifice all their property, preferrec
                            aeing circumcised to living a virgin life. It was easier to give eye for eye tooth for
                            tooth, than to be non-resistant, or return good for evil. The antichristian world would much
                            rathei keep a puritanical, artificial Sabbathday than abolish slavery, forgive debts or undo
                            heavy burdens, and let the op pressed poor go free. Even the New England Sabbath -day-
                            keeping, with the non-observance of dietetic and pro creative laws, enjoined by Moses, i
                            likely to end in the extinction of the Yankee race. Two children in three families indicates
                            a lack of blessing somewhere. [See report of Associa tion of Science, in Boston.] This New
                            England gospel is not equal to the lavs of types and shadows of the true gos pel. In short,
                            there is no objection to the civil government appointing a non theological day of rest.
                            Neither i there any objection to people observing any day as a theological Sabbath, as do
                            the Jews. And believers, like friends may regard as sacred anv time set apar for spiritual
                            and religious observance But they should never lose sight of th fact that the gospel is full
                            salvatioi from the multifarious sins of the world is the great jubilee of jubilees, the Sab
                            bath of Sabbaths, the Sabbath of Jesus </p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let not the extraordinary folly..." TEIform="index"/>Let not the extraordinary folly...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Let not the extraordinary folly of ou rulers lead our country into war; anc change our
                            rulers, O God, as soon as possible.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Spurgeon" TEIform="persName"/>Spurgeon.</byline></div2><div2 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Leonard, William" TEIform="index"/>William Leonard
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Death. <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName">Elder William Leonard</persName>, of le Harvard
                                    Shakers, departed this life "or the next phase of human existence, Tuesday morning,
                                    January 23d, after long and painful illness from an inection of the kidneys. During
                                    the later part of his sickness he had not been ble to lie down, and was obliged to
                                    emain in a sitting position. It was he only way he could obtain relief. ie was
                                    seventy-three years of age, and mited with the society forty-eight years ago. He was
                                    a native of the Provinces, and previous to his uniting with the society had been a
                                    resident of New York city. He was an active agent for its welfare, and a devoted
                                    adherent to the faith which leads from a worldly to a Christian life. At the time of
                                    his death he was the head of the South family of Shakers, and had been for some
                                    time. He held other important places of trust and responsibility, and was widely
                                    known as a public man. At the public meetings of the Shakers he always took an
                                    active part in their religious exercises, where he advocated the religious faith of
                                    the society, and was one of their ablest speakers. He will be missed by a large
                                    circle of friends and acquaintances, and by the members of the community, who will
                                    seriously feel the loss of his presence, good influences, and valuable services. His
                                    whole life is his best eulogy.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Public spirit" TEIform="index"/>Public Spirit.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Steadfast, Margaret" TEIform="index"/>Margaret Steadfast
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Steadfast, Margaret" TEIform="persName">Margaret Steadfast</persName>, W. Gloucester, Me.,
                                aged 17.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Goleason, Christian" TEIform="index"/>Christian Goleason
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Goleason, Christian" TEIform="persName">Christian Goleason</persName>, Pleasant Hill, Ky.
                                Henry W. Bryan, Pleasant Hill, Ky., aged 62.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gihard, George" TEIform="index"/>George Gihard
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Gihard, George" TEIform="persName">George Gihard</persName>, Pleasant Hill, Ky.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prentiss, Ephraim" TEIform="index"/>Ephraim Prentiss
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Shakers, N. Y., Feb. 5, 1877, <persName reg="Prentiss, Ephraim" TEIform="persName">Ephraim
                                Prentiss</persName>, aged 74. Many mouths can speak his praise.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Evolution" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bell, J. D." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plain talks upon practical religion" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">Mark Twain has invented a Scrap-Book! Twain says very many funny and foolish things; but
                                in adding this invention to the library, desk, counting-room, etc., he has done us all a
                                remarkable favor. It is gummed on every page, ready for the scraps, no past being
                                required; and is, all in all, a unique desideratum, difficult to be spared after once
                                seeing how very nice it is. For this indispensable, send Woodman, Slote &amp; Co..
                                119 William street, New York. The Evolution comes to our table very acceptably. Its aim
                                is to fill a space made void by extensive growths from old political parties and
                                theologies, made by numerous individuals who demand something better than now is. Its
                                appearance and the subject matter of the copies we have seen speak very highly for it.
                                J. D. Bell is its editor, 34 Dey street, New York. Plain Talks upon Practical Religion :
                                Is now ready, containing an epitome of Shakerism. We anticipate an extensive circulation
                                for it. It contains the names and addresses of all the novitiate elders. Sending one of
                                these pamphlets to inquirers answers the purpose of many letters; and replies to an
                                hundred questions naturally and constantly recurring to the minds of any who are at all
                                interested in the Shakers as a people. By mail, six cents. Address either the editor or
                                publisher of The Shaker.</p></div3></div2><pb n="24" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gospel day" TEIform="index"/>GOSPEL DAY</head><p TEIform="p">Union Village, Ohio. Canterbury, N. H. The glorions day is dawning, The day of full release;
                            Even now it is the morning Of saving life and peace : The work of Christ perfeeted. In
                            viefry o'er all sin; That of old was oft predieted ; This day has ushered in. 2. And still
                            increasing glories To us must soon unfold ; That eclipse the ancient stories, The fabled age
                            of gold. The Angels are descending. Once more to reap the world, Bearing plumes of peace,
                            unending. And flags of love, unfurled. 3. Then trim your lamps, ye faithful, Let each and
                            all prepare For the advent of the Angel,— We have no time to spare The train is swiftly
                            nearing. The head-lights gleam afar ; Of a sweet evangel cheering, Death's prisons to
                        unbar.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="All things perish save virtue" TEIform="index"/>All things perish save virtue
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Epaminondas" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">All Things Perish Save Virtue. EPAMINONDAS. Sweet Morn—so cool, so calm, so
                                    bright, The bridal of earth and sky, The dew shall weep thy fall to-night, For thou
                                    must die. Sweet Rose—whose fragrance new I crave, To glad my sense and joy mine eye,
                                    Thy root is ever in its grave, And thou must die. Sweet Spring—so full of shine and
                                    showers; It makes the weary spirit sigh To think, with all thy herbs and flowers,
                                    That thou must die. Sweet Music—e'en the lovely song, Which from my harp, in window
                                    high, Is floating on the breeze along, E'en thou must die. And all the bright and
                                    glittering train Of stars that stud the deep-blue sky, Must they all perish—none
                                    remain To glad the eye? And vales, and fields, and rushing streams. And mountains
                                    that invade the sky, Are they as baseless as our dreams t And must they die? And all
                                    that's beautiful and fair On nature's face—love's melody That makes sweet music of
                                    the air,— All—all must die! And man, frail form of senseless clay, Though now his
                                    glance is proud and high, Perchance upon this passing day He, too, may die. But the
                                    bright soul—that shined within The quenchless light in mortal form— Though dimmed by
                                    misery and sin, Defies the worm. When all the stars shall fade away, And suns in
                                    their own blaze expire, And trackless comets cease to stray With wand'ring fire, The
                                    soul shall ever live, nor know The lapse of time, but dwell on high, And share in
                                    endless joy or woe.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Eternity" TEIform="index"/>Eternity.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wisdom" TEIform="index"/>Wisdom</head><p TEIform="p">— Wisdom is alchemy, or the art of changing base metal into gold. This is its unfailing
                            characteristic, that it finds good in everything, that it renders all things more precious.
                            When our view is confined to ourselves, nothing is of value, except what ministers in one
                            way or another tc our personal gratification; but in proportion as it widens, our sympathies
                            increase, and when we have learned to look on all things as God's work, then they are all
                            endeared to us. Hence nothing can be further from true wisdom than the mask of it, assumed
                            by a cold indifference about what does not belong to our personal interest. But the
                            strongest symptoms of wisdom are in a person being sensible of his own follies and weak
                            points.</p><byline TEIform="byline">—<persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>Maria Witham</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Culture" TEIform="index"/>Culture
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Culture.—What plowing, digging and harrowing are to land, thinking, reflecting
                                    and examining are to the mind. Each has its proper culture; and, as the land that is
                                    suffered to lie waste and wild for a long time will be overspread with brushwood,
                                    brambles, thorns and weeds, which have neither use nor beauty, so there will not
                                    fail to sprout up in a neglected, uncultivated mind a number of prejudices and
                                    absurd opinions which owe their origin partly to the soil itself, the passions and
                                    imperfections of the mind of man, and partly to those seeds which chance to be
                                    scattered in it by every kind of doctrine which the cunning of demagogues, the
                                    singularity of pedants and the superstition of fools raise.</quote></cit><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Arthur's magazine" TEIform="index"/>—Arthur's Mag.</bibl></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A heart unspotted..." TEIform="index"/>A heart unspotted...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A heart unspotted, is not easily daunted.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Erving, Anna" TEIform="persName"/>—Anna Erving.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Prayer" TEIform="index"/>A Prayer</head><p TEIform="p">[The following Prayer has something so real in it, that while we publish it, we would fain
                            have all, with us, become better because of it. Possibly, none of us would look upon a
                            faded, deathly face but would be moved to a compassion, even by that of a known enemy.
                            Please read the last verse twice. Ed."| If I should die to-night, My friends would look upon
                            my quiet face Before they laid it in its resting-place, And deem that death had left it
                            almost fair; And laying snow-white flowers against my hair, Would smooth it down with
                            tearful tenderness, And fold my hands with lingering caress— Poor hands ! so empty and so
                            cold to-night. If I should die to-night, My friends would call to mind, with loving thought,
                            Some kindly deed the icy hand had wrought; Some gentle word the frozen lips had said;
                            Errands on which the willing feet had sped. The memory of my selfishness and pride, My hasty
                            words would all be laid aside; And so I should be loved and mourned to-night. I£ I should
                            die to-night, E'en hearts estranged would turn once more to me, Recalling other days
                            remorsefully; The eyes that chill me with averted glance Would look upon me as of yore,
                            perchance, And soften, in the old familiar way— For who would war with dull, unconscious
                            clay! So I might rest, forgiven by all, to-night. O friends ! I pray to-night, Keep not your
                            kisses for my dead, cold brow; The way is lonely—let me feel them now; Think gently of me; I
                            am travel-worn ; My faltering feet are pierced with many a thorn. Forgive, O hearts
                            estranged—forgive, I plead ! When dreamless rest is mine, I shall not need The tenderness
                            for which I long to-night.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spade and the hoe" TEIform="index"/>Spade and the hoe
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The Spade and the Hoe. A spade within a farmer's shed Leaned by the wall his
                                    empty head, And spying on the ground below Spake proudly to an humble hoe : "Yours
                                    is but surface work, while I Deep into hidden treasures pry." The hoe raised not his
                                    lowly head, But meekly to his brother said : "The master in his industry Hath need
                                    alike of you and me." The servants resting in the shade When to their task the
                                    farmer bade, Took one the hoe and one the spade— And unpreferred, where all were
                                    good, Each took the tool that near him stood, And in a common cause allied Toiled in
                                    the vineyard side by side, So the great master, without need Of human pride or human
                                    creed, Can make a profitable tool Out of a wiseman or a fool, And each at last to
                                    show will bid Not what he was, but what he did.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American Sunday school worker" TEIform="index"/> American Sunday School
                                Worker.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>Selections</head><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Principle, like truth..." TEIform="index"/>Principle, like truth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Principle, like truth, needs no contrivance, it will tell its own tale and tell it in the
                                same way.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is error only..." TEIform="index"/>It is error only...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">It is error only, and not truth that shrinks from inquiry. </p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="None can look forward to a certainty of future happiness..." TEIform="index"/>None can look forward to a certainty of future happiness...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">None can look forward to a certainty of future happiness, unless they are striving to
                                assimilate themselves to the likeness of Him, who was the embodiment of all that is
                                lovely and of good report. </p></div3></div2><div2 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="American agriculturist" TEIform="index"/>American agriculturist
                        </head><p TEIform="p">--------------*-------------PARTICULAR NOTICE. The Atnerican Agriculturist is a very worthy
                            monthly. Its subscription price is $;i.6o. We will send The Shaker and it together during
                            1877 for $1.50!! Now take advantage of our offer, and get both for less than quarter cost.
                            Address the Publisher of The Shaker.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>