<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-sm1309" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">32</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">13</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">9</biblScope><date value="18830901" TEIform="date">September 1883</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">193-216</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="13" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="9" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p> VOL. XIII. SEPTEMBER. NO. 9. SHAKER MANIFESTO Published by the United Societies. OUR HOME AT
                        SHIRLEY, MASS. "Blessed are they that hear the word of God and keep it. SHAKER VILLAGE, N. H.
                        1883. </p>
                    <pb id="p2"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p> [Advertisements deleted.] <pb id="p3"/>
                            <pb id="p4"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
 --><pb n="193" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><!--                     <div2 type="none">
                        <p> CONTENTS Page. Ezekibl's Vision, -..... 193 Our Manifesto,...... 196 God Knows,....... 198
                            The Loom of Life,..... " Fishing fob Men, - - - - - - 199 The Influence of a Gentle Voice, -
                            - 200 The Voice of Age,...... 201 Sermon, Floyd C. Fields, ... - " Some Lives,....... 203
                            Letter, S. F. Wilson, .... " Wrecked,........ 204 For Mine Eyes have seen Thy Salvation, 205
                            The Ascending Grade,..... 206 Now,........ " Letter Box,....... 207 Notes,........ 208
                            Bright's Disease and Ice Water, Keep a Bottle of Lime Water, How to make Tea, - ... How to
                            spoil Tea, Something about Churning, Kitchen Education, Pickles,...... To Starch Collars,
                            Very Nice Doughnuts, The Present Social System, Plowman Sermonette, How to Split a Sheet of
                            Paper, Music ;—We are Marching On, Books and Papers, Reflection, - Deaths,...... Page - 209
                            - 210 - 211 - 212 213 - 214 215 - 216 Vol. XIII. SEPTEMBER, 1883. No 9 </p>
                            </div2>
                     --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ezekiel's vision" TEIform="index"/> EZEKIEL'S VISION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Leonard, William" TEIform="persName"/>BY' WILLIAM LEONARD.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The prophet Ezekiel lived and wrote in a remarkable period of Jewish history. He was a poor
                            suffering child of mortality, and placed great dependence on the Holy Spirit as his name
                            signifies, "Supported of God or God is my strength." Babylon or the Chaldean Empire, where
                            the Jews were then in captivity, was a portion of Mesopotamia. a name which signifies, "A
                            land or Valley laying between two rivers." It embraced many names spoken of in early
                            scripture. The whole Valley was a garden of the earth ; and that fertile portion of it, was
                            the glory of the Chaldean Empire. This Valley lay between the Tigris and Euphrates. It is
                            said to be, from 20 to 200 miles in width, and from 6 to 800 miles in length. All historians
                            agree that in this vale, Noah and his descendents settled after the Deluge ; and that the
                            ruins of the far famed tower of Babel was enclosed within the very walls of Babylon. This
                            holy prophet could there look upon the remains of this idolatrous tower and could see what
                            it had done for many generations, even before Abraham was called from that region. Stephen
                            says ; Act vii; 2. "The God of glory appeared to our father Abraham when he was in
                            Mesopotamia," The Chaldeans "or worshipers of fire," seem to have been of the blood that
                            Abraham was called out from, to plant a people who should receive the promises, and give
                            birth to the Messiah. By the most remarkable demonstrations of power, the Hebrews came on,
                            were led into, and delivered from bondage, received the laws of God on the desert, which <pb n="194" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/>they repeatedly broke, for Avhich, in the days of Ezekiel, they were
                            sent into the most desolating captivity, to the stock from which Abraham sprung. This pious
                            prophet had spent the earliest years of his life, in the great city of Jerusalem. He began
                            to prophesy five years after the captivity, continued denounceing idolatry for twenty oue
                            years, for which he was slain. Born of the priesthood he had bowed to God in early life
                            among the sacred types at the Jewish altar ; and had trod the courts of the temple in all
                            its magnificence and glory. His lamentations for his people began in the tabernacles of
                            Israel. He had stood in the outer court, in whi.h the multitude listened to the word of God,
                            who spoke from between the Cherubims through priestly mediums. Thus, when the tribe of Judah
                            went into captivity, he bitterly knew how de. plorably they had fallen. When brought under
                            judgment for their sins, lie saw them hurled from their high station, crushed out from among
                            the nations, and their city and temple leveled to the dust. With them, lie was hurried away,
                            to the dismal prison house of Babylon, to lay buried in the graves of slavery in this
                            ancient valley. This prophet went into exile with his people, in a land of beauty, watered
                            by the rivers of Babylon ; but every scene about him was calculated to embitter his life in
                            solitude. As he wandered in his devotions and pious rambles along the banks of the river
                            Chebar, a branch of the great Euphrates sorrowfully and sadly he could say, nearly 1800
                            years ago, this ground was made sacred by the footsteps of righteous Noah, "Who was perfect
                            in his generations," found favor with heaven, and escaped the deluge. Here in this
                            delightful valley God made with him the second covenant with the race, re-established the
                            simple patriarchal religion in the New World, and as with Adam the first, made him earthly
                            Lord of his generations. He could see also where Nimrod came to establish idolatry, one
                            hundred and twenty years after the deluge. The very name of that personage signifies, "Rebel
                            against God's mediatorial government." He could see the very structure that this ancient
                            apostate carried up, to oppose God's rule through mediators, and overturn patriarchal
                            authority and set himself on hiarh to introduce false worship. Noah was clothed with the
                            name of the true God, and they who set out to erect this structure, sad ; Gen. xi., 4. "Let
                            us make us a name." In every direction the prophet could see that the abominable rites
                            started then, had spread abroad and come down to that generation ; shutting out from all,
                            the knowledge of God's rule and order. How painfully he saw the exposed condition the erring
                            tribes were thrown into. Here he could see what Abraham was called out from ; and one reason
                            why he was cautioned never to return. Perhaps he prayed to heaven by the same river, or in
                            the very grave, where Abraham was told to leave his father's house, and plant a new
                            generation of people. In this trying condition, and under these extremes of feeling, he must
                            have viewed the dead condition of his people. Under these disadvantages he without doubt
                            labored iu sorrow to learn, how the promises of God, made to Abraham concerning his kindred,
                            were to be fulfilled. I have written this, to take the most direct way to show you, that
                            history in- <pb n="195" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> forms us, that the Valley in which the prophet saw the dry
                            bones, was something more substantial than a vision. I have taken the most simple method to
                            show you, that in his entranced s+ate, he saw the bones as a figure, but they were evidently
                            in the valley of Mesopotamia. Now for the vision. By quoting a few verses of the preceeding
                            chapter we can see the meaning more clearly. The prophet says ; Ezek. xxxv : 16, 27. "The
                            word of the Lord came to me, saying, Son of man when the house of Israel dwelt in their own
                            land they defiled it by their doings, and 1 scattered them among the Heathen. I will take
                            you from among the Heathen and bring you into your own land. I will put my spirit within you
                            and cause you to walk in my statutes, and ye shall dwell in the land which I gave to your
                            fathers." When entranced in vision, Ezekiel saw this valley and it appeared like a battle
                            field whitened with the bones of the slain. He saw the spiritually dead state of his people,
                            and how the power of God must quicken them to raise them up. He continues ; Ezek. xxxvii.,
                            1, 14. The hand of the Lord was upon me, and set me down in the midst of the valley, which
                            was full of bones. And he caused me to pass them round about, and behold they were very
                            many, in an opi;n valley ; and lo ! they were very dry. And he said unto me son of man can
                            these bones live ? And I said O Lord, thou knowest. He said, prophesy unto them, and say
                            unto them, O ye dry bones, hear the word of the Lord ! Behold I will cause breath to enter
                            into you, I will lay sinews and flesh upon you, cover you with skin and ye shall live. And
                            as I prophesied there was a noise and a shaking, and the bones came together. The sinews,
                            and flesh came upon them, and skin covered them but there was no breath in them. Then he
                            said unto me prophesy unto the wind, (margin breath,) and say, thus saith the Lord. Come
                            from the four winds, O breath, and breathe upon these slain, that they may live. So I
                            prophesied, and breath came into them, and they lived, and stood upon their feet, an
                            exceeding great army. Here my young friends is one of the most descriptive visions ever
                            given to a prophet. It was to show this suffering man of God that his people would be
                            awakened, raised out of their dead state of transgression, and brought to the land and law
                            of their fathers. There is no lack of evidence to show, that this was the real meaning of
                            the vision, as you may read ; Then said he to me, son of man, these bones, are the whole
                            house of Israel. They say our bones are dead. Our hope is lost, and we are cut off from our
                            parts, (lands.) Therefore say unto them, thus saith the Lord. Behold O my people ! I will
                            open your graves, and bring you into the land of Israel. The sending of the Jews into
                            Babylonish captivity, was to cast the old transgressors out of Canaan, and let their
                            carcasses fall among the Heathen. The idolatrous portion of the younger generation,.never
                            returned to Jerusalem, but remained among heathen Idolaters. History informs us that the
                            most sincere portion, were the only remnant that returned, who built up the city, erected
                            the second Temple, and re-established the !aw. This vision is one of the most remarkable
                            pieces of Bible literature ever panned. The Chaldeans, Medes and <pb n="196" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/>
                            Persians, generally had great reverence for the memory of this prophet; they believed in a
                            sort of literal resurrection, and by this vision, the meaning of which they could not
                            comprehend, they were undoubtedly strengthened in that belief. Many of the Jews were
                            strengthened in the belief of a literal resurrection by it. More than 10,000 sermons have
                            been preached from it, for the same purpose. It was the very vision selected, to prove, that
                            the literal body, was the real, eternal, man or woman ; and that the four winds of heaven,
                            or the common air we breathe, was the true spirit of God, which was finally to re-animate
                            these bodies. The simple revelations of Mother Ann Lee which divide between flesh and
                            spirit, set all right upon this subject eternally. They show that the body returns to the
                            dust, and that the spirit travels up to the spiritual heavens, in Christ-like purity and in
                            the beauty of holiness. Of Gog and Magog, we need say but little. They are symbolical terms,
                            signifying, the gathering of tribes and nations, under one head to battle. To put down
                            Buonaparte it required the allied powers of Europe so called, under a British commandei.
                            Such a combination from certain ports of Asia, came against Israel, at certain periods.
                            Ezekiel calls them by such terms as were then used armies of Gog and Magog. I think you will
                            see that this was so by reading Rev. xx., 8. He speaks of a period to come when the nations,
                            from the four quarters of the earth, called in the Apocalypse Gog and Magog, who would
                            gather together, to battle, as the sand of the sea ; and were to cover the breadth of the
                            earth. Thesa remarks throughout this sheet may not be all that you would desire ; but they
                            are about as I view them, and will be satisfied, if they at all interest my young friends.
                            It is somewhere said, that "•The golden moment for proper action should never be lost." At
                            this time, so favorable an opportunity presents itself, to write a few lines to the dear
                            young brethren and sisters at Canterbury, that 1 feel reluctant to resist the inclination.
                            As I looked around upon you beloved young friends, I thought of the toils and trials, all
                            must pass through, to gain an inheritance in the kingdom of Christ; and I discovered an
                            honorable resolution among you, to carry it through. On every plane, from the highest angels
                            down to honorable men and women, everything elevated and God-like, must be gained by virtue,
                            diligence and labor. There is no way, that wTe can attain to the honors of immortality, till
                            we have marshaled for the conflict, fought the battles, and endured the hardships of the
                            campaign. Ayer, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Our manifesto" TEIform="index"/> OUR MANIFESTO.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hill, Mary Ann" TEIform="persName"/>MARY ANN HILL.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Our Manifesto, coming each month, laden with rich treasures and living testimonies, from the
                            good brethren and loving sisters as well as kind friends, is always a welcome messenger. I
                            love to read its pages, there is so much good in it. To me it is inspiring, for it helps me
                            to travel up the Holy Hill of Zion, on to that better land where all is peace and quietness,
                            where truth and righteousness prevail and all strife and contention are done away. I am
                            pleased to have it circulated through the land, that others may know <pb n="197" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            of our faith and better understand our religious views : for I do know? of a truth, that by
                            living the Christ-life, I find that peace and happiness which will abide with me even unto'
                            the end. Yea it will be as a garment well wrought, a robe of purity and innocence, which
                            will never wear out: therefore I will take courage and "weary not" in the strife. We read in
                            the Scriptures, "They that wait upon the Lord shall renew their strength; they shall mount
                            up with wings as eagles ; they shall run, and not be weary ; they shall walk, and not
                            faint." Let us lay hold of those rich promises and be willing to wait upon the Lord, let us
                            work for Him and be willing to give our whole souls to Him and overcome evil with good. Thus
                            we shall rise on the beautiful wings of freedom to the higher plane, and live the higher
                            life in truth and verity. We shall then be able to help others as we have been helped;
                            consecrate all that we possess to God, and make no selfish reserve ; it takes the whole to
                            be a Christian, we must each give up our own will and way and be devoted to His holy cause,
                            then we can walk and not faint. Christ said to the young man, who asked "Good Master, what
                            good thing shall I do that I may have eternal life ?" "If thou wilt enter into life keep the
                            commandments." The young man replied, "all these have I kept from my youth up, what lack I
                            yet?" Jesus then said, "If thou wilt be perfect, go and sell that thou hast and give to the
                            poor, and thou shalt have treasure in heaven ; Come and follow me." Here was the test, and
                            to this poor soul as to many others, it was a severe test for we read, he "went away
                            sorrowful, having great possessions." 0 I thank my Heavenly Father and Mother that I was
                            called to this way in my youth; I do not feel that my life has been thrown away, or lost;
                            nay, I have been blest of God and his people, by living the virgin life. I have won many
                            victories over self, and am able to say as the little piece expresses ; "Where Thou leadest
                            I will follow ; Where Thou goest I will go ; Through the flood or through the furnace,— Try
                            me Lord, and bring me low. Fain would I ascend to heaven, Give my selfish life away. Thy
                            seal of promise Thou hast given, Strength according to my day." It is my prayer from morning
                            until evening that the guiding hand of my Heavenly Father be with me and the watchful eye of
                            my Heavenly Mother be upon me, that I may live as my precious faith teaches,—a life of
                            consecration, fraught with deeds of love and mercy ; for while I bless others 1 feel that I
                            am being blest. For the young Christian I have an especial blessing. Endure unto the end and
                            ye shall be saved. Ye who have put your hand to the plough, see that ye turn not back, for I
                            would that ye be worthy of the kingdom of heaven. Dear young friends, let me say unto you as
                            did Paul to the Ephesians. "I beseech you that ye walk worthy of the vocation wherewith ye
                            are called,—Endeavoring to keep the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace." With all my
                            heart I bless you and I feel your constant blessing in return. Such affection and sympathy
                            is akin to that love which the angels bear to one another. 1 feel a care for all humanity,
                            and most earnestly do I pray that they may be led into all truth. The Scriptures <pb n="198" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> say, "If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forg've us our sins,
                            and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness." I believe this to be the only true and living
                            way, whereby we can find salvation full and free, and meet the acceptance of God. I feel an
                            interest in the prosperity of all Zion's children old and young. As age increases, so does
                            my love increase and my confidence strengthen. I want to do all the good I can in this life,
                            to sustain our great and glorious cause. I have full faith in an honest confession of all
                            known sin. Mine have gone to judgment long before this day, and I am a daughter of the free
                            woman. One by one I confessed them, to God in the presence of his witnesses ; and I know
                            they are all forgiven, no fear have I of the coming future, when this little bark of mine
                            shall have ceased to sail upon the sea of life. My spirit will find both rest and
                            employment, beyond the veil, my treasures are stored in heaven, where I shall some day be
                            garnered with my fathers and my mothers, who have gone on before me to that sunny land of
                            peace and blessedness. Eternal life is mine, by prayer and watchfulness we know it is
                            obtained. Our dear Savior taught his disciples to watch and pray. How anxious he felt for
                            them in his last hours ; three times he went to them, and repeated these words : "Watch, I
                            say unto you, watch and pray that ye enter not into temptation." It seems very needful for
                            us to watch and pray without ceasing. Let us love our neighbor as ourselves, for this is the
                            command of our blessed Lord and Master ; and in this gospel of Christ and Mother we are
                            counseled to lay aside all selfishness, and run the Christian race with patience. Let us
                            remember that "the race is not to the swift, nor the battle to the strong." Step by step we
                            must ascend the holy hill, and hour by hour we must watch and pray, lest the Holy One come
                            and find us sleeping. As children of the Resurrection let us be found living the life and
                            doing those works which will insure us happiness here, and heaven in the great hereafter.
                            Now Beloved Editor, being 84 years of age on the 10th. of August I have prepared this little
                            message, and shall send it to you for publication, with my everlasting love which shall
                            abide with my testimony ever and forever. West Gloucester, Me.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God knows" TEIform="index"/> GOD KNOWS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/> ELIZABETH MARTIN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Yea it is a consolation That that Potentate divine, With an eye of justice, seeth All the
                            workings of the mind. Man may judge by false appearance, And our purposes condemn ; But we
                            know when God approreth And for justice look to Him. Every wrong shall yet be righted; Every
                            scale be balanced true; Have we fruitful lives or blighted, God will yet dispense our due.
                            Let us trust with Him the issue, While we act the noble part; Not with vengeful feelings
                            pressing, But with honest, Christian heart. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loom of life" TEIform="index"/>THE LOOM OF LIFE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">All day, all night I can hear the jar Of the loom of life, and
                                    near and far It thrills with its deep and muffled sound, As the tireless wheels go
                                    always round. Busily, ceaselessly goes the. loom In the light of the day and the
                                    midnight's gloom' <pb n="199" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/>The wheels are turning early and late, And
                                    the woof is wound in the warp of fate. Click, clack! there's a thread of love wove
                                    in; Click, clack! another of wrong and sin; What a checkered thing will this life be
                                    When we see it unrolled in eternity! Time, with a face like mystery, And hands as
                                    busy as hands can be, Sits at the loom with its arms outspread, To catch in its
                                    meshes each glancing thread. When shall this wonderful web be done ? In a thousand
                                    years, perhaps, or one? Or to-morrow? Who knoweth? Not you nor I, But the wheels
                                    turn on and the shuttles fly. Are we spinners of wool for this life web—say? Do we
                                    furnish the weaver a thread each day? It were better then, O my friend, to spin A
                                    beautiful thread than a thread of sin. Ah, sad-eyed weaver, the years are slow; But
                                    each one is nearer the end, I know; And some day the last thread shall be woven in,
                                    God grant it be love instead of sin.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="For the Christian woman" TEIform="index"/>For the Christian Woman.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fishing for men no 2" TEIform="index"/>FISHING FOR MEN. NO. 2
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Waugh, John" TEIform="persName"/>BY REV. JOHN WAUGH</byline><p TEIform="p"> [From the Phrenological Journal.] <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">A good fisherman will never continue
                                    in a way in which he has repeatedly failed. If the fishing-ground changes he will
                                    follow it up; no need of letting down lines and nets where there is nothing to be
                                    caught. The changing seasons will require a change of bait, from worms to minnows,
                                    or from one kind of flies to another. In the most of industrial pursuits the
                                    instruments of labor are in advance of those of ruder times, and the mind-workers of
                                    to-day cannot regenerate the world with usages and forms no more adapted to the
                                    times than the arrow of the middle ages is for modern warfare. The nf eds, the
                                    truths remain the same, but the modes of application require are-adjustment. He who
                                    can say, "Behold I show unto you a more excellent way," and can demonstrate it by
                                    fact, as did Arkwright, Stevenson, and Morse, with the cotton mill, the railway, and
                                    the telegraph, should receive a unanimous following. But the new methods must be
                                    approved by their results. If less fish are taken by some recent tackle than by the
                                    old Waltons of piscatory fame, then let us angle as did the fathers. In
                                    common-school teaching, in college instruction, in gospel preaching, in all efforts
                                    for the improvement and reformation of men, the supreme desire should be, ''In what
                                    way can I best meet the ends of my calling?" We have read of sorrow being upon the
                                    seas. Ships have passed through floating masses of dead fish slain by some commotion
                                    of nature. Oui ocean of life is filled with dying, dead, and hopeless humanity. Yet
                                    the waters may be healed as the Prophet saw the Dead Sea teeming with life from the
                                    inflow of aqueous healing from the Temple gates. The fishers of men in all
                                    departments of reformatory work should study the best methods. The failures largely
                                    lie in conservative ignorance, which ov.ght to be and must be enlightened if the
                                    world is to be saved. A treatment that will fail with some will succeed with others.
                                    There are thoughtful and secretive natures that, like the finest trout, keep
                                    themselves in some shady retreat, who need to be sought out, their sensitiveness
                                    overcome, their confidence secured, and, with the needed instruction given, may be
                                    brought to do grand service for their race. Combative natures need to be won with no
                                    show of authority, but by sympathizing words from warm hearts, and by the exhibition
                                    of a true brotherly regard; a slumbering conscience may be revived and their dormant
                                    aspirations for better thiogs invigorated to corresponding ac ion. There are
                                    lethargic, sluggish individuals, slow to think and slower still to move, who, by
                                    some appeals to their leaden hopes, may be aroused to attempt something in the way
                                    of improvement. There are some people very easily discouraged; they lack enterprise:
                                    they have been thrust into the corners of human life and kept there by habit and
                                    circumstance; hope and imagination seem to have no part in their being. Yet even
                                    these by a little kindly manipulation with kindness and truth properly presented may
                                    be encouraged to attempt some good thing, and from some little strength attain to
                                    more. The development of acquisitiveness may be so exorbitant in some that it may be
                                    found difficult to turn the upward gaze. Yet by wise appeals to self-love,
                                    benevolence, and the reasoning faculties, the lesson of wisdom may be set into
                                    fermentation and essentially modify the character. <pb n="200" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> That
                                    mental attribute which is strong should be set at work to help that which is weak.
                                    There are some so far down in the depths of degradation that to human view no line
                                    of helpfulness can reach them; yet in toe lowest deep many have been brought to the
                                    surface to see the sun and rejoice in a brighter day. In the floods of humanity
                                    pouring over our land and filling our tenement houses in narrow and filthy lanes,
                                    our settlements in the oil regions, and the murky mines, there will be found all
                                    orders of mind and character calling for all varieties of workmen and skill in
                                    operation. That grand old soul-angler, the parabolic writer of "Bedford jail,'' from
                                    his post of observation over the River Ouse, thus quaintly says : "You seethe way
                                    the fisherman doth take To catch the fish! What engines doth he make ? Behold! how
                                    he engageth all his wits; Also his snares, lines, angles, hooks and nets; Yet fish
                                    there be that neither hook, nor line, Nor snares, nor net, nor engine can make
                                    thine. They must be groped for, mid be tickled too, Or they will not be catched,
                                    whate'er you do." No other fishing requires so much practice and art as that for the
                                    catching of men. It is the highest of all human callings. It does not come by
                                    pedigree, by manipulation, or by royal charter. It is acquired in the school of
                                    experience and by long consultation with wisdom. Such are the patriarchs, prophets,
                                    priests, apostles, witnesses, and kings of the Great Ruler of the universe. They do
                                    not seek recognition among the orders of nobility; it comes by divine right. They
                                    are engaged by the side of all waters, on the highway of nations, by the surging
                                    tides of foreign immigration, by the dirty waters of politics, in order to save the
                                    drowning anglers for office; by the tide flow of youthful life, to save the young
                                    and inexperienced from the torrents of social corruption issuing from garret and
                                    cellar, rendering existence itself but one asphaltic lake ; by the tides of trade
                                    and commerce, to bring the riches of the seas as ministers to virtue. And this they
                                    do not for social distinction, for human applause, for coveted wealth, but that
                                    those sinking in the waters of ignorance, the floods of intemperance, the rapids of
                                    vice, or being carried over the frowning falls of despair, may be transferred to
                                    knowledge, sobriety, goodness, and hope. The greater portion are unknown to fame ;
                                    they pursue their work in obscurity and silence. They may be found in the school,
                                    the pulpit, the platform, at the desk, in the tenement house, the miner's cabin, in
                                    the slums of festering city life, in the fetid atmosphere of the hospitals, and by
                                    the dying bed of the outcasts of society. They fish with the earnest appeal, the
                                    warm persuasion, the benevolent smile, the supplicating prayer, the consecrated
                                    purpose to get a hold upon the human heart and transfer it from the abyss of death
                                    to the source of all true life. Blessed be these fishers of men ! They are more
                                    numerous than we reckon. They are hard workers, faithful students of success in
                                    their vocation, among the most self-denying of their race, and yet upon the whole
                                    the most contented and happy. Their chief solicitude is to save some from going down
                                    into the depths, and in the eternal morn, when their account will be given, they
                                    will blush to find it fame.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Phrenological journal" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Influence of a gentle voice" TEIform="index"/> THE INFLUENCE OF A GENTLE VOICE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cochran, Mary M." TEIform="persName"/>MARY M. COCHRAN.</byline><p TEIform="p"> The human voice is capable of being used in many ways, and the different tone sometimes
                            conveys a great deal of meaning, equal, seemingly to the language of different nations. The
                            variable influences produced on the mind, seem to have their origin, in many respects from
                            the tone of voice used by those with whom we daily associate. A mild but firm voice has
                            charms that would dispel the most sullen or fretful feelings ; which are so disagreeable,
                            yet so common, and so easily produced. To associ te with a person but a short time who
                            exercises a rough and harsh voice and language, the influence is deadening to the finer
                            senses and feelings; and without great care we should adopt the same manner ourselves, for
                            we are so organized that whatever kind of company we mingle with the most, we are liable to
                            partake of the style of language, whether vulgar or chaste. If we associate with those who
                            love purity of spirit, and are choice in their selection of language, their influence draws
                            out the better feelings and aspirations of our hearts. A mild voice,—O how sweet is the
                            music <pb n="201" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/>of a pleasant and cheerful voice; on the feelings of the weary,
                            and oppressed with cares and burdens. In my own experience, its power is beyond expression;
                            its influence is elevating; and a few words, spoken in the voice of love, are worth more
                            than many sermons. Who has not, when contending with temptation, or under a sense of their
                            weakness, and inability to live to a correct faith, feeling the force of evil in their own
                            spirits, stronger than the power of good,— who lias not felt the electric influence of a
                            gentle voice speaking words of encouragement, although ignorant of the strife within? It
                            dispels the brooding host of temptation, creates new feelings and desires ; divesting the
                            dark path of life of its perils and dangers, and making the narrow patli of self-denial
                            pleasant and as beautiful as the garden of God. Did we but bear in mind the importance of
                            the verse, "Speak gently,— tis a little thing Dd i th ht' dp well; b p gy, Dropped in the
                            heart's deep The good, the joy which it ma}r bring, Eternity shall tell." How careful we
                            should be to speak in the spirit of Christ even to the least, were we conscious at all times
                            that each word left its impress on the soul, to be met in Eternity, whether good or evil.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Voice of age" TEIform="index"/>THE VOICE OF AGE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hastings, Marcia E." TEIform="persName"/>MARCIA E. HASTINGS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> As we become advanced in years we should never allow ourselves to morbidly settle down in
                            ease and unconcern, feeling that our day of activity and improvement is past, even though we
                            may have toiled laboriously and earnestly for many years in efforts to promote Christian
                            principles and heavenly graces. Nay, the older we grow and farther we advance in spiritual
                            travel, the more we should be stimulated by our maturer appreciation of the riches, the
                            triumph and the glory attained and attainable, to continue our active interest in the
                            blessed Christian cause, both for ourselves and our younger struggling companions and
                            growing spiritual sons and daughters. We have many times felt a loathing and dread of a
                            state of apathy and lukewarmness into which we are liable to settle if we do not maintain a
                            watchful, prayerful spirit, as we advance in years and find we have conquered our most
                            inveterate enemies,—those pertaining to the lower animal propensities,—and thus neglect and
                            overlook other insidious lurking foes, such as selfishness, peevishness, a vaunting sense of
                            acquired righteousness and extensive gospel travel. It is well to be on the alert, and see
                            that these do not hold dominion over us. We wish to be actuated by a living spirit and
                            loving heart to the end of our earthly existence ; be a brightness and encouragement to the
                            young, a comfort and stay to the aged. Be sure, work and pray with the faithful loyal
                            burdenbearers, whom we love and bless, and would much prefer to lighten their multiplied
                            burdens rather than add needlessly one trifling weight. Canterbury N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He that loveth father or mother more than me..." TEIform="index"/>He that loveth father or
                            mother more than me...</head><p TEIform="p"> "He that loveth father or mother more than me is not worthy of me, aud he that loveth son or
                            daughter more than me is not worthy of me." These words Jesus spoke unto his disciples
                            before they were sent out into the world to preach the gospel and maintain those principles
                            which he taught and practiced. Jesus well knew the greatest cross they would have to bear
                            would be to forsake father, mother, brother and sister and all the family ties that
                            naturally exist among the children of the earthly plane ; and <pb n="202" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> he also
                            knew if they were not willing to forsake the world, with its kindred ties, they never would
                            be worthy to bear the name, Chosen disciple. It also would have been unwise to have
                            commissioned them to preach those principles of purity, if the last tie that bound them to
                            the world had not been completely severed. But, undoubtedly, it was a severe trial for them
                            to pass through ; bitter tears might have flowed from their weeping eyes, even in the
                            midnight hour; their groans might have been heard and in their agonizing distress they might
                            have thought the trial too great for them to bear. But as their minds centered on Jesus in
                            all his purity and loveliness of character, realizing the fact that 1 e had to pass through
                            the same trying ordeals, that the same struggles and sorrows which darkened their pathway,
                            and the temptations which surrounded them on every side, were no greater than those their
                            master had experienced. As they gazed into the future with their eye of faith, realizing the
                            lasting happiness that was in store for those that followed his blessed example,—their tears
                            ceased to flow, their sorrow and anguish subsided and the rays of divine light beamed upon
                            their souls. They were willing and anxious to be among those who would forsake the world and
                            follow the example of their master and leader. When the last tie that bound them to the
                            world was severed, the pentecostal baptism soon followed and then their zeal and enthusiasm
                            was such that they gloried in their suffering. Yea more than this, they were willing to
                            become martyrs for those principles of purity and godliness. The disciples undoubtedly
                            hadfathei'S, mothers, sons and daughters or some earthly kindred that were dear to them :
                            but when they had fully decided to follow Christ, their hearts began to expand with love and
                            tenderness for all mankind. Selfishness was an unknown attribute of their purified souls,
                            they labored to elevate all mankind to a higher standard of purity. Now they could
                            truthfully say. "Behold my mother and my brethren ; for whosoever shall do the will of my
                            father which is in heaven the same is my brother and sister and mother." Is it any wonder
                            then that they received such a powerful spiritual baptism after having so fully decided to
                            forsake the world and live a life of purity and unselfishness ? If Mother Ann and the early
                            Believers had not been enthusiastic and earnest enough to have thought more of the
                            principles of Christ than any earthly idol they never could have succeeded-in organizing a
                            society of Christian believers ; and if there is any thing that will deaden the spirituality
                            and retard the progress of Shakerism it is for professed believers to be partial to those of
                            their own earthly kindred. Selfishness can never be in harmony with the true principles of
                            Christianity, for Christ and his disciples and Mother Ann and those connected with her,
                            considered kindred selfishness nothing else but a friend to "the unfruitful works of
                            darkness," so we should love all mankind and consider every follow* r of Jesus our brother
                            and sister. What a grand army would soon flock to the kingdom if all that desired a higher,
                            spiritual, development would drop the weights of consanguinity and selfishness and live in
                            harmony with the higher elements of their nature ! It is the <pb n="203" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> low
                            propensities in man that keep him from enjoying that high and elevating happiness which is
                            as eternal as the heavens. But the evil nature is so largely developed in man, that the
                            majority prefer to live only in the happiness that is attained to on the lower plane of
                            life. Animalism is their ged, it is the sanctuary before which they bow. They willingly
                            become subservient to the will of their lower nature. But how different it is with those who
                            have severed all the ties that enslave them in the world ; they now fully realize that they
                            are living in the celestial department of their nature ; free from the degrading influences
                            which accompany those that are governed by their lower propensities. Their love for their
                            kindred is no less, but their love for humanity has increased so largely that the ties of
                            consanguinity are entirely lost sight of, so great is their effort to promulgate the
                            principles of purity and establish the kingdom of heaven on earth. By having this purified
                            and unselfish love permeating in us, the world can comprehend that the resurrection life can
                            be obtained before man enters the spirit land, and further, they can fully see demonstrated
                            the true principles on which to establish the brotherhood of man. May we so live and show by
                            our life that we are worthy to be called Chosen disciples of him who said "Pie that loveth
                            father or mother more than me is not worthy of me and he that loveth son or daughter more
                            than me is not worthy of me."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Field, Floyd C." TEIform="persName"/> Floyd C. Field.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Men believe that their reason governs their words..." TEIform="index"/>
                            Men believe that their reason governs their words...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Men believe that their reason governs their words, but it often happens that words have power
                            to react on their reason.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bacon" TEIform="persName"/>Bacon.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Some lives" TEIform="index"/>SOME LIVES
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rexford, Eben E." TEIform="persName"/>BY EBEN E. REXFORD
                        </byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Some men there are that never find The beauty all
                                    about them. Blind To flower, and leaf, and stream, and sky, They live their narrow
                                    lives and die. Some men have ears too dull to hear The music of this lower sphere ;
                                    They never catch the harmonies Of wind and bird, of earth and seas. Some lives there
                                    are so hedged about With darkness of distrust and doubt, That they can never see
                                    their way Beyond the limit of to-day. Oh, happy is he who can see About his pathway
                                    constantly, To guide him in his wanderings, The beauty of earth's common things.
                                    Each flower he sees each sunset tint Is pregnant with mysterious hint, And all
                                    earth's lovely sights suggest The beauty on the hills of rest. Happy the man whose
                                    ears can catch The music of the world. The latch Of Heaven is raised for him, and he
                                    Hears echoes of its harmony. And happy lives are those which see By faith's clear
                                    vision what shall be, And say in dark and dolorous day, "God knows ; I trust him,
                                    come what may."</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New York weekly" TEIform="index"/>N. Y. Weekly.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear mother; It is Saturday evening..." TEIform="index"/>
                            My dear mother; It is Saturday evening...
                        </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, July 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. July, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p">My Dear Mother ;—It is Saturday Evening, cool, quiet and pleasant in our little Village,
                            plainly bespeaking the close of another week of labor and the blessing soon to be ours of a
                            Sabbath for rest in spiritual enjoyment. I received your kind little note, also quite a
                            lengthy letter from my dear sister, almost more than my share at one time, but we are all so
                            glad to hear from you, that I think every one feels especially addressed, when your letters
                            are read at our family table. Sister A. who has just read your kind letters, tells me that
                            the piece—"Let my life be with those who have conquered," that M. Louisa requested to have
                            sung in remem- <pb n="204" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/>brance of her, was sang last Sabbath by the youth and
                            children in their morning service, as a prayer for the absent. Does not this prove that your
                            angel guardians hold communion with ours? We shall try to preserve this interchange during
                            your absence by a careful regard to all good impressions, believing in the power of
                            influence to convey many hundred miles even the fragrance of a child's sincere prayer. How
                            many times, do I recall my first lessons in prayer when a little girl. I remember of
                            wondering why our mother prayed with us especially, sometimes, before sending us out to
                            school, besides our morning prayer; and with eyes, often filled with tears, saying;—"0 Lord,
                            draw nigh unto these little ones," desiring that we be kept from all evil during our absence
                            and then standing in the door while we walked thoughtlessly away to school. Ah! the prayers
                            were all need ed then, and even they were not sufficient to keep your precious treasures
                            from the knowledge of much wrong. I am sure there must be a united effort between Parents
                            and Teachers before protection from moral vices and bad associates can be secured in our
                            common schools, which can never be accomplished by teachers who work only for wages.
                            Whenever I realize a lack of fervency in prayer, I am often condemned by the occurrence of
                            my mother's prayers in early childhood. Surely I have been a favored daughter, and that my
                            parents were enabled to accept the Christ life and become as brother and sister in the
                            hundred fold relation, giving an example to their children of coming out fromthe world as
                            did Jesus, my harp will never be "hung upon the willows," nor can I cease to utter praise
                            while I give my life to God. I am pleased that you are so kindly entertained by good
                            friends, and find consolation in the religious experience of others. I can imagine that you
                            have been very busy in attending meetings, speaking, praying and aiming to inform inquiring
                            friends concerning our religious belief. May your efforts be attended with success is the
                            prayer of your home friends who feel a confidence that only good fruits will be the result
                            of your mission. My room-mates are singing as I write, just what you would like to hoar,
                            '.'For grace renewed my soul hath prayed," and join me in love, the sweetest, to one whom we
                            know only to love and trust. That you may feel a reward, in the assurance that your daughter
                            will ever be true to her precious calling for your kind guidance and love in past days is my
                            sincere prayer.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wilson, S. F." TEIform="persName"/>S. F. Wilson.</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Wrecked" TEIform="index"/> WRECKED.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>MARTHA J. ANDERSON.</byline><p TEIform="p"> What more could have been done for thec O soul! Whose plighted faith and broken vows, now
                            lie Like empty shells upon a foreign shore. Where hast thou drifted? down a dangerous tide,
                            Till thou art stranded on those hidden reefs That skillful mariners with care avoid ; But
                            which the incautious dash upon With all the fury of the surging waves. Wrecked! alas! the
                            very thought brings grief That barque, whose sails, spread to the favoring breeze, Bi-aved
                            tempest, storm and tide full many a year, While faith stood at the he m, and marked her
                            course, And every virtue, bore a noble sway At all the posts of duty and of trust. But, lo!
                            a dead calm rested o'er life's sea, The white sails, reefed, unto the topmasts clung, The
                            pilot slept, and all on board reposed, Nor ever thought of danger brooding near. E'en
                            Conscience failed her vigils true to keep; So, lulled to rest secure, they sweetly dreamed
                            Of quafling pleasure from life's gilded font. But, from below, up sprang a treacherous crew,
                            As unperceived before; weak in their strength When all the higher powers held firm their
                            sway Nor parleyed with a spirit mean and base. Bold Unbelief, at first possession took,
                            Desires unhallowed followed in its wake, And bound were all the safeguards of that soul,
                            They loosed the anchor, spread the outmost sail, Threw out the ballast, and in reckless
                            haste Sped on, they cared not where they went. The Captain's voice was dumb, and mute the
                            sighs Of all the former guardians of that barque. And now aground on shoals and s»nds of
                            time, O who shall rescue? Is there none to save? We leave it in the hands of Him, who rules
                            The destiny of souls, and giveth charge Unto the angel world concerning them. Mt. Lebanon,
                            N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">As no being can receive any permanent satisfaction or reward of happiness in themselves, but
                            by labor voluntarily performed, therefore labor is the price affixed to all the good things
                            of God.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A. G." TEIform="persName"/>A. G. H. </byline></div2><pb n="205" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="For mine eyes have seen thy salvation" TEIform="index"/> "For Mine Eyes have Seen thy
                            Salvation."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, Joanna J." TEIform="persName"/>JOANNA J. KAIME.</byline><p TEIform="p"> While reading the little pamphlet recently issued, containing a brief outline of the life
                            and experience of Mother Ann Lee, the thought suggested itself, to write for my friends a
                            cherished dream, or vision of Mother, which occurred to me in the early period of my
                            experience as a Shaker sister, being then, nearly twenty years of age. 1 hope thereby to
                            interest, if not profit, some of the risiug class among us who have never been privileged to
                            see or converse with any of those noble characters who were her immediate associates, and
                            followers, while in the form. It may b? well to state that at the time to which I refer,
                            there were many mediums in our Societies, gifted with boautif'ul songs, who often sang
                            complete stanzas when thus entranced without any hesitation in a peculiarly melodious and
                            touching manner. ¦ This form of inspiration was greatly to be coveted by one so newly and
                            deeply convicted of the need, as well as of the beauty, of a religious life, heightened by
                            such heavenly influences. Yet, all my earnest prayers seemed to fail to bring me the desired
                            immediate ministration. I was also particularly anxious to know more of Mother Ann, whose
                            life I had so often read and re-read with ever increasing interest, just as I trust many of
                            my youthful readers have done, and are still doing. But to my vision ; which, let me state,
                            occured at a time when engaged in the Family's Cooking Department;—:it being then, my duty,
                            to prepare ve ;etables for the table. At the gjose of a somewhat busy day, I attended our
                            usual evening worship, and on retiring thereafter, soon fell asleep. In my dream however, I
                            seemed to be about my daily duties again when the tidings reached us, that Mother Ann Lee
                            was making a visit to the various societies of Believers ; and would call on our family
                            sometime during that day. Soon after the announcement was received, Mother entered our
                            apartment unattended, being attired in the usual simple garb of the Sisterhood, and greeting
                            us with a pleasant smile, (her only language,) began at once an inspection of the kitchen
                            and its utensils. I confess that I felt some trepidation, lest the places and possessions of
                            which I had special charge, should betray a want of faithfulness,—but after her survey, I
                            was made most happy, as her hand of approval rested upon my head in silent blessing. The
                            grave, yet exceedingly sweet, tender and maternal expression of her countenance, as she
                            quietly withdrew, is still vividly retained in memory, and seems as fresh to-day as au event
                            of yesterday, although nearly forty years have elapsed since its occurrence. I awoke in the
                            morning refreshed and delighted with the interview, which was too precious to mention to any
                            one till I had related it to my spiritual guides, which I resolved to do, at my earliest
                            convenience. It so happened, however, that directly after breakfast was over, Eklress M.
                            called me to her room saying;—"J. Sister C. has a little message for you from Mother
                            Ann,—and will sing the same if you will listen." The medium sang as follows ; "Fear not my
                            child, I claim you mine, Your efforts I can bless ; Know when in trial I am near <pb n="206" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> And would this truth impress,— Hope shall your anchor be, Strength equal to
                            your day ; While trustingly you meet the light And lovingly obey. Faint not, though sorrows
                            come, Your faith shall stand the test; Abide in Truth, make it your home, Your everlasting
                            rest." This unexpected summons was to me a confirmation of the real spirit presence of our
                            Mother with whom I had so longed to become better acquainted, and not having had the
                            opportunity to relate the dream according to my resolve I regard it a pleasing coincidence.
                            To my young friends for whom I have narrated the above, I would idd, that as you
                            intelligently give your best, purest thoughts, and conscientiously listen to your religions
                            convictions of duty you will receive corresponding spiritual experiences from divine
                            sources, and attain unto a faith in those principles which will only constitute you a
                            genuine Christian, as taught by Mother Ann Lee who is neither a myth nor fable in that
                            unseen realm of perfectness to which we are all aiming. No vague fancies, no ideal goodness
                            will hold you to the purity of life which she lived and p omulged. A humble confession of
                            all known sin with the legitimate fruits of repentance will give you a perception of her
                            beautiful spirit and holy influence which I then realized and has been to me a talisman
                            through the vicissitudes of this life, an \ I trust will be a passport to the world beyond.
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Law of recoil obtains outside..." TEIform="index"/>The Law of recoil obtains outside...
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> The Law of recoil obtains outside, where Justice rules in judgment to restore the bal.aneeof
                            equilibrium—but not within the Kingdom of saints, where Justice and equity meet in Mercy,
                            and the equilibrium is not disturbed.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="H., A. G." TEIform="persName"/>—A. G. H. </byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ascending grade" TEIform="index"/>THE ASCENDING GRADE
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Humanity, before the Germ of Divinity, our birthright inheritance,
                            germinates, is opake. When the germ sprouts—aspires to higher plane—that soul enters the
                            nebulous period. When, guided by hand unseen, we reach the true altar of sacrifice and
                            thoroughly do our first work, we become translucent. When, by indomitable self-control, our
                            every thought is squared by our divinest ideal, we enter the transparent—the Sun of
                            Righteousness shines through us clear as crystal— no adverse winds can tip us off our
                            balance, whether in, or out of the earthly house, we are Seraphim and Cherubim of the more
                            advanced heavens. Amen.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Now" TEIform="index"/>NOW.</head><p TEIform="p">The following lines from Household Word*, are full of wholesome advice as well as beautiful
                            imagery. They convey to the youthful dreamer alessou which it would be well for him to
                            ponder. <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Arise ! for the day is passing While you lie dreaming on; Your brothers are cased
                                    in armor, And forth to the fight are gone; Your place in the ranks awaits you; Each
                                    man has a part to play; The past and the future are nothing In the face of the stern
                                    to-day. Arise from your dreams of the future, Of gaining a hard fought field, Of
                                    storming the airy fortress, Of bidding the giant yield; Your future lias deeds of
                                    glory, Of honor ; (God grant it may!) But your arm will never be stronger, Or needed
                                    as now—to-day. Arise ! If the past detain you, Her sunshine and storms forget; No
                                    chains so unworthy to hold you As those of a vain regret; Sad or bright, she is
                                    lifeless ever; Cast her phantom arms away, Nor look back, save to learn the lesson
                                    Of a nobler strife to-day. Arise ! for the hour is passing; The sound that you dimly
                                    hear, Is your enemy marching to battle! Rise !, rise ! for the foe is near ! Stay
                                    not to brighten your weapons, Or the hour will strike at last, And from dreams of a
                                    coming battle, You will waken, and find it past.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Household words" TEIform="index"/>Household Words</bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="207" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Correspondence" TEIform="index"/>Letter Box</head><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My dear Shaker friend Agnes; I believe..." TEIform="index"/>
                                My dear Shaker friend Agnes; I believe...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maplewood, June 1883" TEIform="index"/> Maple-wood, June, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Dear Shaker Friend Agnes ;—I believe I owe you a letter. I have had to take my books
                                home a great deal on account of examination. Our vacation begins soon. I am going to
                                take two parts in two different dialogues the last day, and speak a piece alone if I get
                                it learned by then. It has been a very pleasant day here. We are all well, Charley is as
                                healthy as ever. Emma says she would like to see you ever so much. Father and Mother are
                                very busy. I had the mumps they lasted me a day and a half, I am all well now and able
                                to go to school. The Summer is very cool here. Is it very warm weather up there? I
                                suppose your planting is all done. We have no garden this year. We send bur love to you
                                all. Good bye. Your Friend, Gracie Wells.—Age, 11.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wells, Gracie" TEIform="persName"/>Gracie Wells</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="My little friend Gracie; Your letters are..." TEIform="index"/>
                                My little friend Gracie; Your letters are...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, July 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. July,
                                1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> My Little Friend Gracie ;—Your letters are always welcome little visitors; as I enjoy
                                hearing from you and your friends very much. I am glad to hear of your success in your
                                studies; but not so well pleased, to learn that you study at home, beside the regular
                                hours for study. While we would cultivate the mind, we must not forget the body, which
                                is the temple of the mind; and if that is not strong and healthful, the mind is greatly
                                influenced thereby. Study the lessons in school hours diligently, but seek health, when
                                those hours are over. Have you been to the top of High Rock this year? We enjoyed the
                                extensive view, of land and sea which it afforded, very much. By the way, Have you been
                                berrying this season? Our children have had several rambles after berries. Some of them
                                find more fun and frolic, than berries, judging from the scantily filled pails that
                                return. I heard one little girl say, that she kept shaking up the berries in her pail,
                                but it would'nt look full, any way. Elder N—whom I think you will remember, assisted by
                                others, takes charge of the vegetable garden, and iruit growing districts, which promise
                                abundance, this year. As I write, the robins are singing for joy in the cherry trees. If
                                they would prudently dispose of one cherry at a time, we would not mind; but they take a
                                little nibble of all the best ones, which we don't like a bit. We have very sudden
                                changes of temperature ; making Summer and Winter clothing, alternately, a necessity.
                                Since you visited us. have had the roof of our barn tinned, covering an area of 10,000
                                square feet- Summer school is in session. Number of pupils, 28. Ages ranging from G to
                                10 years. We would be kindly remembered to your father and mother; and all of the
                                friends. Kindly yours, </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. N.</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear Agnes; I send my love to all my..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear Agnes; I send my love to all my..
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="Maplewood, June 1883" TEIform="index"/> Maplewood, June, 1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Agnes ;—I send my love to all my Shaker friends. Our roses are in bloom. I have a
                                swing up. ' I will write you a long letter next tinv;, from Jessie Wells.—Age, 6.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Wells, Jessie" TEIform="persName"/>Jessie Wells</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dear little Jessie; thank you for your wee letters..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Dear little Jessie; thank you for your wee letters...
                            </head><dateline TEIform="dateline"><index level1="New Hampshire, Shaker Village, July 1883" TEIform="index"/> Shaker Village, N. H. July,
                                1883.</dateline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Little Jessie ;¦—-Thank you for your wee letter. S ort visits, make long friends;
                                and what will short letters do? Can Jessie tell? Well, they are better than none at all.
                                You must enjoy your nice swing ever so much. I wor.der if there ever was a little girl
                                who did not like to swing. I suppose you and Gracie take turns, don't you? and Jessie's
                                turn is the longest, because she does not have so many dialogues to learn for
                                examination. You did not tell me what you were intending to do on that eventful day;
                                presume you intend that, for your next letter, so I will wait. The roses are in bloom;
                                that is very nice, too. Little girls like roses almost as well as they do swings ; but
                                they do not last quite as long. We have a great many roses. The pond in some places is
                                white with lillies. Our little girls are attending school. When not thus employed, they
                                assist a little in the kitchen, work in the flower garden, or some other pleasant
                                recreation. I hope you are trying to be a real, good girl; obedient to your parents,
                                kind and gentle to all your companions. It is such children that we like to have come
                                and live with us. When you say your little prayers, • you must remember your Shaker
                                friends, and ask God to bless them; for we believe that the prayer of even a little
                                child may do much good. I shall want to hear from you again. Sisters II—L—and E—wish to
                                be kindly remembered to you all. Kindly Yours,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="N., A. E." TEIform="persName"/>A. E. N.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="208" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Miscellaneous" TEIform="index"/>NOTES.</head><div3 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="That the church of Christ could not be..." TEIform="index"/>
                                That the church of Christ could not be...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> That the church of Christ could not be built on any other foundation except that of
                                religious communism must be the ultimate reached by all who carefully study his life and
                                spiritual ministration. From the day that he preached his first lesson of righteousness
                                to Simon and Andrew, on the sea shore, till his crucifixion on Calvary, his absorbing
                                theme was the Kingdom of God. The twelve were called to follow him, and he would
                                commission them to go from place to place preaching the word of God and healing the
                                sick. Jesus tells them that he lias no home, that is, he has no home which constitutes
                                his selfish property, but his home was with his brethren, Avho mutually assisted each
                                other in providing for the little community. Peter says, we have left all to follow
                                thee, and for this ^acrilice receives the assurance of abundant blessings in this life,
                                and an eternal reward in the world to come. The disciples were recommended to dissolve
                                all the relations that formed the wonderful bond of kinship, which proved an effectual
                                death blow to the selfishness of the human heart. Sell all thou hast said Jesus, give it
                                to the poor of the church, and after you are released from the power of this earthly
                                magnet, then and not till then will you be ready to become a Christian. Jesus takes away
                                evei*y thing from those who sought his advice, that woald in the least, contribute to
                                foster the old Adamic relation. He would have them interested in the work of
                                regeneration, in the resurrection that would take effect in this life, and then in the
                                order of an united inheritance which would award to every disciple the inestimable
                                treasures of the Kingdom of God. The disciples accepted this unselfish manifestation of
                                the testimony. There is not the faintest idea, in which we might place a hope, that a
                                class of Jews like those who followed Jesus, would have sold all they owned, their
                                houses and lands, and then have given their money into the treasury as a common fund
                                unless they had received the full understanding from Jesus that it was to be the order
                                of his church. Indeed, there is no way in which people can have "all things in common,"
                                except by the formation of a community. By holding in check the individual selfishness,
                                they are able, through discipline, to care for and minister to each other. The
                                experience of an hundred years in the maintaining of community relations has afforded
                                our Societies a knowledge, which unfolds the beauty and consistency of this doctrine as
                                taught by Jesus and the disciples.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p"> Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism, is the title of a very nicely gotten up little
                                pamphlet, that has recently been published by Elder Giles B. Avery. A general
                                circulation of such a work must be the means of doing immense good, as it contains so
                                much of that very form of information, that is essentially needed by those who would
                                become well informed in regard to the Theology, History, General Management,
                                Consecration of Property, etc. The Illustrations of the several societies are an
                                especial <pb n="209" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/>feature of interest in the work and are a source of
                                information that will be appreciated. Every Society would do well to secure a few
                                hundred copies and give them a liberal distribution. They cost only $5 per hundred.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bright's disease and ice water" TEIform="index"/>BRIGHT'S DISEASE AND ICE WATER
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> A Baltimore druggist of experience and ample
                                        opportunity for observation, has advanced the idea that Bright's disease is
                                        attributable to the immoderate use of ice water and cold drinks. He cites the
                                        fact that the people of this country use ninety per cent, more ice in their
                                        drinks than the people of any other country. Greenlanders notexcepted. We have
                                        seventy-five per cent, more of Bright's disease. He cites the fact that the wine
                                        drinking countries of Europe are comparatively free from the malady. Travelers
                                        have observed and commented upon the prejudice which seems to exist against ice
                                        water and iced drinks in all countries outside of the United states. The
                                        Englishman and the German fairly shun ice, though placed in easy reach of
                                        boundless quantities of it, and the Frenchman who sips the light wines would as
                                        soon think of taking an emetic as of chilling his stomach with an iced draft.
                                        Our drug friend points to the fact that Bright's disease has kept pace in this
                                        country with the increased consumption of ice, and claims that before ice became
                                        a common household necessity the malady was scarcely known among physicians.
                                        There may he something in this theory.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Baltimore gazette" TEIform="index"/>Baltimore Gazette.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Keep a bottle of lime water" TEIform="index"/>KEEP A BOTTLE OF LIME WATER
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> If good milk disagrees with a child or grown
                                        person, lime water at the rate of three or four tablespoonfuls to the pint,
                                        mixed with the milk or taken after it, will usually help digestion and prevent
                                        flatulence. Lime water is a simple antacid, and is a little tonic. It often
                                        counteracts pain from acid fruits, from "wind in the stomach," and from acids
                                        produced by eating candies and other sweets; also "stomach-ache" (indigestion)
                                        from overeating of any kind. A tablespoonful for a child of two years old, to a
                                        gill or more for an adult, is an ordinary dose, while considerable more will
                                        produce no serious injury. A pint of cold water dissolves less than ten grains
                                        of lime, and warm water still less. Pure lime water, even though pretty closely
                                        corked, soon deteriorates by carbonic acid in the air, which unites with the
                                        lime and settles as an insoluble carbonate. To have it always ready and good,
                                        and at no cost, put into a tall pint or quart glass bottle, of any kind, a gill
                                        or so of good lime just slaked with water. Then fill the bottle nearly full of
                                        rain or other pure water, and let it stand quietly, corking well. The lime will
                                        settle, leaving clear lime water at the top. Pour off gently as wanted, adding
                                        more water as needed. Some carbonic acid will enter, but the carbonate will
                                        settle, often upon the sides of the bottle, and freshly saturated water remain
                                        The lime should be removed and a new supply put in once a year or so, unless
                                        kept very tightly corked.—</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="American agriculturist" TEIform="index"/>American Agriculturist.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to make tea" TEIform="index"/>How to Make Tea
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> Hard water makes the most delicious tea, as it dissolves
                                        less of the tannin and gives the cup a more delicate flavor. And even with bard
                                        water there is a wide difference between wells located near together. But given
                                        the same quality of water, and a difference in the manipulation will make to a
                                        sensitive taste a total change in the character of the beverage. There is not
                                        one city tea-kettle out of a hundred that in its present condition is fit to
                                        boil water for a cup of tea. Let our reader go home to-night and inspect his own
                                        outfit, and he will verify our statement. He will find the interior of his
                                        kettle encrusted with the mineral deposits extracted from the water boiling in
                                        it from morning until night of each succeeding day As the water is "clean," the
                                        cook but empties and fills the kettle, never thinking of the growing crust that
                                        must now be scraped off if the kettle is to be cleaned. Water that has stood
                                        after boiling will not make a good cup of tea, and yet how often the tired
                                        laborer, mechanic, merchant, <pb n="210" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> doctor, or lawyer, has tried
                                        to solace himself with a beverage made from water containing the debris of that
                                        which has stood all day on the range, being only filled as often as any addition
                                        was needed. Take a clean kettle never used for anything else, fill it with fresh
                                        water, the harder the better, boil quickly over a very hot fire, and pour as
                                        soon as it boils upon the tea-leaves fresh from the canister. Let it stand four
                                        or five minutes, and then drink.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian at work" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to spoil tea" TEIform="index"/>How to Spoil Tea
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> If the first experiment does not make an infusion strong
                                        enough, or if the pot is partly empty and more is needed, do not put any fresh
                                        tea into the tea-pot, for it will surely be wasted. Tea water will not dissolve
                                        the theine from the dry leaves of fresh tea; only pure, fresh water will do
                                        that. The addition of tea to the nearly empty teapot will increase the color,
                                        but it will not make the tea perceptibly stronger in its exhilarating quality.
                                        Any one may try the experiment. Put a table-spoonful of tea into a quart of
                                        water, and let it stand five minutes, or boil it if desired Then add two more
                                        spoonfuls of tea-leaves to the same decoction. The color will be increased, but
                                        the tea will be little stronger in the active principle so much desired When
                                        more liquid or a stronger infusion is desired, put the additional tea in a cup,
                                        and pour fresh water on it; after it has stood a few minutes, it may then be put
                                        in the pot to good advantage.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Christian at work" TEIform="index"/>Christian at Work.</bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home" TEIform="index"/>House and Farm</head><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Something about churning" TEIform="index"/> SOMETHING ABOUT CHURNING.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, Joseph" TEIform="persName"/>JOSEPH WOODS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> When a youth, as good or ill luck would have it, I was occasionally called upon to do
                                the churning. On rainy days I had a spi cial call and will make reference to one of
                                these privileges. Dinner was over, and the old dash churn was soon supplied witli
                                something that was called cream, and I was informed that it was ready for me. After some
                                hours of labor with no perceptible change in the cream, I began to express some doubts
                                about the article that I was churning and suggested that it might be milk, or possibly
                                buttermilk, if the former, there might be some ground for hope, as king Solomon had
                                said.—''The churning of milk bringeth forth butter." Hour after hour passed away but my
                                task was not done. Kupp t was announced and I was quite ready to attend to it. This over
                                the churn was again in active operation. Occasionally an examination was made to note
                                the changes if any were to be seen, and then it was churn, churn, churn until quite late
                                in the evening, but without any perceptible change in the contents of the churn, and I
                                doubt if there would have been if I had worked at it till the present time. Fortunately,
                                a very good Aunt of mine, was with us, on a visit, and she remarked that the cream might
                                need rest. Be that as it may, I knew that I needed rest. We now proposed to try an old
                                churn which ante-dated the dash, and possibly before Adam the first was appointed a
                                gardener. Who knows? The maker may have secured a patent-right. We have never heard of
                                an infringement, nor of but one claimant, and that was a small boy, who on being asked
                                by his instructor in rather a sharp tone of voice, "Who made the world?" became a little
                                frightened and did not reply. The question was repeated in a sharper tone. Fearing
                                punishment if he did not answer the question; Replied "But I'll never do it again." On
                                the fallowing morning the contents of the churn were put into a closely woven, cotton
                                bag, and this encased in another of similar material and then buried in the earth at
                                about the depth of one foot. The pit was made in a body of yellow sand. The next morning
                                the sack was taken from the ground, and my doubts were all dispelled in reference to the
                                contents. The butter was collected into one lump, while the buttermilk had nearly all
                                been drawn out into the sand. You may be assured that I was delighted with thi» ancient
                                churn, thinking there would he no more long pulls for me, but in this I was destined to
                                disappointment. The two or three quarts of buttermilk lost in the ground was considered
                                of more value than my labor, and it was not till long after this, that some kind friend
                                informed my parents that if they <pb n="211" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> would scald the milkas soon as
                                it was brought to the dairy, we might, obtain the butter from the cream as quickly as in
                                the summer. This was proved to be correct. Where I now reside we keep upwards of thirty
                                cows. The milk is set in Cooley creamers and we are informed that the labor of the dairy
                                is reduced about one half. More butter is obtained from the same amount of cream than on
                                the old plan and of a superior quality. We use the Blanchard Churn. "The best." We also
                                use the Blanchard BUTTER WORKER, which for ease and perfection in working out all the
                                buttermilk, and evenly working in the salt, has not been surpassed since the days of
                                King Solomon. Canterbury, N. H. </p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Kidtchen education" TEIform="index"/>KITCHEN EDUCATION
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The origin of many of the troubles which afflict mankind
                                        may be traced to a disordered stomach. Carlyle was a dyspeptic and he made his
                                        home-life cheerless and gloomy. No doubt but some of our bad legislation maybe
                                        attributed to indigestible hotel breakfasts, and the burdens of sorrow produced
                                        by social disturbances have no more prolific contributor than the disordered
                                        stomach which produce disordered minds. If we want to raise the average of
                                        morality, happiness and prosperity of the people, the science of eating must be
                                        given a more prominent place in our educational system. Through ignorance, and
                                        much of it inexcusable, we eat disease, we drink it, we sleep with it, and
                                        breathe it. What to eat- how to cook it and when and how to eat it, are
                                        certainly subjects of study, quite as practical and beneficial as the
                                        conjugation of Greek verbs. Isn't it a little strange that while we employ the
                                        best medical skill we can obtain to cure disease, we turn our stomachs over to
                                        ignorant cooks and allow them to cram it with dietetic abominations which ruin
                                        its functions and produce disease? If talent, genius and skill are looking for a
                                        good missionary field, the kitchen is the great uncivilized realm. We want the
                                        coming generation of girls taught how to cook intelligently. Give the stomach
                                        good, wholesome food, and it will ii 1 your veins with pure blood, which in turn
                                        will give you a healthy brain and drive away the whole brood of manufactured
                                        troubles. We have had education for the parlor, and we are a nation of
                                        dyspeptics. Now, as a matter of experiment let us try education for the kitchen.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Western Plowman" TEIform="index"/> Western Plowman.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="food" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pickles" TEIform="index"/> PICKLES.</head><p TEIform="p"> Take small sized cucumbers, and scald them three successive mornings in weak brine.
                                Drain them dry, have ready a brass kettle and some nice strong vinegar, with cloves,
                                allspice, and a small piece of alum, which will make them green and brittle, a little
                                horseradish root improves them. Pickles made in this way will keep through the year.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To starch collars, cuffs, etc...." TEIform="index"/>To starch collars, cuffs, etc....
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">To starch collars, cuffs, etc. so that they will be stiff and glossy as those
                                        bought at furnishing stores, add to one quart of the well boiled(corn)starch
                                        three ounces of water gloss, one ounce of gum arabic, and two ounces of loaf
                                        sugar—Use polishing iron.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Science America" TEIform="index"/>Sci. Araer.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="recipe" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Very nice doughnuts" TEIform="index"/> Very Nice Doughnuts.</head><p TEIform="p">—One heaping cup sugar, three eggs, one cup sour cream, one small teaspoonful soda, flour
                                sufficient to roll out. If cream is not attainable, sour milk will do, or use sweet milk
                                adding a small piece of butter, and a little less soda.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="C., A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. C.</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Corns can be cured by..." TEIform="index"/>Corns can be cured by...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Corns can be cured by a paste of sal-soda and brown soap.—</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hebbard" TEIform="persName"/>Dr. Hebbard.</byline></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bit of butter rubbed on a white spot..." TEIform="index"/>A bit of butter rubbed on a white spot...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> A bit of butter rubbed on a white spot on varnished furniture, will restore the
                            color.</p></div3><div3 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Take one ounce of spermaceti and..." TEIform="index"/>Take one ounce of spermaceti and...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> Take one ounce of spermaceti and one ounce of white wax. melt and run into a thin cake
                                on a plate. A piece the size of a quarter dollar added to a quart of prepared starch
                                gives a beautiful luster to the clothes and prevents the iron sticking.</p></div3><div3 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is said that the 'wicked borrow and never return'...." TEIform="index"/>
                                It is said that the 'wicked borrow and never return'....
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> It is said that the "wicked borrow and never return." How long can a person keep
                                righteous and retain borrowed articles, books, papers, tools and umbrellas?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Woods, J." TEIform="persName"/>J. Woods.</byline></div3></div2><pb n="212" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Present vile social system of society and its remedy" TEIform="index"/> THE PRESENT VILE
                            SOCIAL SYSTEM OF SOCIETY AND ITS REMEDY.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Stevens, Robert" TEIform="persName"/>ROBERT STEVENS.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Dear Friends ;—In making the following desultory remarks on this vitally important sub" ject
                            (viz.) the present wretched social system, and its only adequate remedy, "Bible, Divine, or
                            what other name you may give," to constructive, not destructive communism, allow me to state
                            once for all, that I do not blame, or judge, or hold responsible any individual, or parties,
                            for the evils of the present social system. These evils are inherent in the system, itself
                            as absolutely necessary effects of certain false principles, upon which the system is
                            founded. We may lessen, or change these evils for a time as men and women of good hearts are
                            doing to-day, but who do not look deep enough for the cause, and therefore do not remove it,
                            so that our remedial measures are but palliatives, like the patching up of a dam, or
                            embankment that has been constructed on false principles. The water will ooze out in fresh
                            places, gather strengt.;, and soon or late the whole erroneous construction will break up,
                            and over-whelm all in its terrible path. Again suppose the different classes of society,
                            labor and capital for instance the rich and the poor, the producers, and the nonproducers,
                            the monopolists, and the antimonopolists change places when they are young, if they did so
                            we know that their thought and action, their general character, nationally speaking would be
                            reversed when they arrived at maturity. It is error therefore, erroneous systems that we are
                            at war with and not with men. Upwards of eighteen hundred years have gone, since the great
                            Paul, and the greater Christ inaugurated a new, a divine practical religion in which men
                            should be supremely lovers of God, and their neighbor as themselves. They also inaugurated a
                            new a divine, social system of society, a righteous, political, economy in order to make
                            that divine religion possible, for it would not have been wise to adopt the then, as now
                            vile social system. It would not have been wise to attempt to repair the old shoddy garment
                            with the new, the divine robe of righteousness. Therefore, soon after the terrible, the
                            lamentable death of the great, the self-sacrificing, the divine Master, for all goodness is
                            divine, the disciples came together witli one accord, strong in spiritual life, over-flowing
                            with spiritual love, they were of one heart, and one mind, one with Christ, their beloved
                            Master, one with God their loving Father, and one in material things followed as an
                            absolutely necessary effect upon those previous causes. So full were they to over-flowing in
                            spiritual love, of unity in Christ, in God, that this their loftier, their higher state of
                            being outweighed every other consideration, and they sold their possessions, and brought the
                            prices and laid them down at the Apostle's feet, neither called any man anything his own,
                            that was his own, for they had all things in common ; and similar results will of natural
                            necessity follow to-day, whenever similar causes, similar means are realized. But these
                            noble men and women with the noble, the brave Paul at their head, were persecuted, were
                            scattered and in seven years their wise social organization was broken up, else there is
                            little doubt it might have continued in the Church till the present day, nevertheless the
                            leaven was imbedded in the heart, and in the mind of humanity at that great Congress of
                            spiritual love, and of wisdom, the day of Pentecost, and the whole must be leavened, and if
                            the Church continues to be unfaithful to its high mission then rude hands—aye, terribly
                            rude, will take it up and do it with vengeance. Day by day we hear the ominous knocks of
                            these rude hands at the very door of civilization: nay they are already stained with its
                            blood, and are but waiting like Bloodhounds in the lash to go on with the work. Allow me to
                            repeat dear friends, it is for the professed Church of Christ, of God, it is for the wise,
                            and the good of the nations, those who alike freed God's colored children from chattel
                            slavery, and saved this great nation from wreck and ruin those who to-day are redeeming the
                            nations from the alcohol curse, and in a thousand ways persistently working to lift up
                            humanity to higher aims and realities, I say it is for these glorious men and women to say
                            whether the blood <pb n="213" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> stained hands shall go on with this vital work is
                            cut short by ten years of the average duration of life among other classes of society. That
                            more than one half of the children of the lower strata of society die before they are five
                            years of age. That labor is dependant for the necessaries of its life, and for those of its
                            wife and children upon the private capitalist as much now, or more, than under a system of
                            chattel slavery. If all this state of things be true and in the main, it is self-evident,
                            then is humanity cruelly outraged by fearful injustice, the very enormity of which is a
                            daily peril to civilization itself, and a positive menace that struggles for the disruption
                            of society will continue at whatever cost. Let therefore the goodness, and the wisdom of the
                            nations assert their strength (ere it be too late,) for love is more powerful than dynamite,
                            or the assassin's dagger, and it may make this vile, this senseless, selfish, groveling
                            system of society like chattel slavery, a thing of the past, so that righteousness, and
                            therefore happiness may dwell among the nations of the earth. Come forth to Community, Thou
                            man of care, and toil, Leave competition's strife; In brotherhood, till the soil, God would
                            have thee holy, pure. With happiness to shine, Would strew thy path with many a flower And
                            dwell with thee, and thine.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Plowman sermonette" TEIform="index"/> PLOWMAN SERMONETTE.</head><p TEIform="p"> To the Church Member of the Period My friend, I don't wish to usurp the place of your
                            regular minister, but I am afraid there are some important truths which you are not in the
                            habit of hearing from the pulpit, and, moreover, I know anything presented from a business
                            stand-point will, from mere force of habit, receive better consideration from you than the
                            presentment of abstract truths. You professed religion, and you joined the church because
                            your minister told you it was necessary to do so in order to be saved. You were told that
                            you were a sinner, which is no news to you or to your neighbors, and it was promised that if
                            you repented, those sins would all be forgiven. Your business shrewdness told you that this
                            was a very easy way to settle up for your past wickedness, and you made that compromise
                            adjustment and considered yourself morally square with the Lord and the men you had swindled
                            and wronged. Now that would not be so bad if you had resolved that your moral life, after
                            unloading your life of sin, should be on the basis of a square, honest,
                            one-hundred-centson-the-dollar morality. But, no, you have made the discovery that you can
                            enjoy the fun without suffering the consequences ; that you can dance and let another pay
                            the fiddler. You consider yourself safe because in your own opinion you have complied with
                            the letter of the moral law, and think that a settlement of all sins past is also a
                            liquidation of all sins futureDo you really think that religion is founded on such loose
                            business principles? If one of your clerks comes to you with tears in his eye •, and
                            confesses that he has sinned against you by stealing your money, and assures you that he is
                            truly repentant, you forgive him, perhaps, and may even retain him in your employ, but do
                            you give him license to go on stealing day after day, with the understanding that the first
                            forgiveness covers all subsequent stealings. No, indeed, you have too much good sense to
                            adopt any such policy in the regulation of your business. You can see at once that it would
                            not be dealing rightly with the young man or yourself. I know that it is claimed that
                            religion is not business, but I sincerely wish that there were a little more business in
                            religion. I sincerely wish every convert who has made his entry in the church the turning
                            point of his life would trust more in his own exertions in leading a pure, correct life, and
                            less on the Savior! This is said in no spirit of irreverence, but in the very spirit that a
                            father would feel toward a wayward reformed son. He would willingly help him out of debt and
                            make a man of him again, but he %?ould admire him and honor him more if he conducted himself
                            afterwards so uprightly and squarely that he would not need any more of his father's help.
                            Now you are a member of the church, ar&gt;d the world knows it because you rent a pew,
                            help pay the minister, and admit you are a Christian. They would never know it by <pb n="214" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/> your Christian acts. When that poor woman called on you last week and
                            implored you to give her something to do by which she migh earn enough to feed and clothe
                            her suffering children, you broke her heart with a harsh reply, but the next Sunday when
                            Brother— asked in open church what you were willing to contribute towards a taller spire for
                            the church, you responded, "Fifty dollars!' Then, how much more benign an expression your
                            countenance bore, than did that of your poor neighbor who could give only one dollar ! To be
                            sure, last week, this very neighbor took up the case of the poor woman you treated so
                            harshly, and by devoting several days to the work, succeeded in getting her steady
                            employment with a comfortable income ; but then he is not considered the shining light you
                            are, and cannot begin to make so fervent and eloquent a prayer ! My Christian friend of the
                            period, you have yet to learn the true religion of humanity. It consists in deeds, not
                            professions and formal ceremonies. A symbol is the token of something else, but with you the
                            symbol is the thing itself. A man may just as well imagine that he is getting shaved by
                            leaning against a barber-pole, as to assume that by formally joining the church and
                            performing the ceremonies, that his heart is filled with true religion. Am I assailing your
                            church, or the religion you profess? No; I am assailing (hat sham, that painted image which
                            personates religion and which possesses as much of its true spirit as the wax statue does of
                            the living man it is intended to represent. The existence of the counterfeit doesn't affect
                            the genuine, except in subjecting it to more rigid tests. Test your religion by the acid of
                            misfortune and see how quickly it will tarnish and betray its baseness. In religion, as in
                            business, get the genuine, for it is only that which will pay in the end. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Western Ploughman" TEIform="persName"/>Western Ploughman.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A worthy Quaker thus wrote...." TEIform="index"/>A worthy Quaker thus wrote....
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> [Contributed by E. Myrick.] A worthy Quaker thus wrote. "I expect to pass through this world
                            once; if therefore there be any kindness I can show, or any good thing I can do for any
                            fellow human being, let me do it now, let me not defer or neglect it, for I shall not pass
                            this way again." A good rule to live by, and if all should adopt this precept what a happy
                            world this would be—"A heaven here and now."</p></div2><div2 type="house" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to split a sheet of paper" TEIform="index"/>HOW TO SPLIT A SHEET OF PAPER
                        </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote"> The following is from the British and Colonial
                                    Printer and Stationer: It is one of the most remarkable properties of that wonderful
                                    product, paper, that it can be split into two or even three parts, however thin the
                                    sheet. We have seen a leaf of the Illustrated News thus divided into three parts or
                                    three thin leaves. One consisted of the surface on which the engravings are printed;
                                    another was the side containing the letter-press, and a perfectly blank piece on
                                    each side was the paper that lay between. Many people who have not seen this done
                                    might think it impossible ; but it is not only possible, but extremely easy, as we
                                    shall show. Get a piece of plate glass and place it on a sheet of paper: then let
                                    the latter be thoroughly soaked. With care and a little dexterity the sheet can be
                                    split by the top surface being removed. But the best plan is to paste a piece of
                                    cloth or strong paper to each side of the sheet to be split. When dry, violently and
                                    without hesitation pull the two pieces asunder, when part of the sheet will be found
                                    to have adhered to one and part :o the other. Soften the paste in water, and the
                                    pieces can be easily removed from the cloth. The process is generally demonstrated
                                    as a matter of curiosity, yet it can be utiized in various ways. If we want to paste
                                    in a scrap-book a newspaper article printed on both sides of the paper, and possess
                                    only one copy, it is very convenient to know how to detach the one side from the
                                    other. The &gt;aper when split, as may be imagined, is more transparent than it
                                    was before being subjected to the operation, and the printing nk is somewhat duller;
                                    otherwise the two rieces present the appearance of the original if again brought
                                    together. Some time ago the information of how to do this splitting was advertised
                                    to be sold for a considerable um, We now impart it to all our readers gratuitously.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="British and colonial printer and stationer" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div2><pb n="215" id="p27" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="We are marching on" TEIform="index"/> WE ARE MARCHING ON.</head><p TEIform="p"> Canterbury, N. H. 1. We are marching on, we are inarching on, Bidding the world a
                            2. We are marching on, we are marching on, Joyfully heeding the final adieu; We've our armor on and our hopes placed above, call of the Lord; Whose love we
                            know whose guidance trust, Earnestly seeking the home of the true. Bravely,
                            bravely All our supplies are drawn from his word. we'll march along, Onward, upward, is the Arictor's song; Soon laurels shall crown the conquest in view, And we will
                            rejoice in the home of the true.</p></div2><pb n="216" id="p28" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books and Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Halls journal of health" TEIform="index"/>Halls Journal of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Halls Journal of Health. July. Contents: Regulating-Diet; Sick Headache; Climatic
                                Treatment of Consumption; Health means Dollars; Man and Insects; Cigarette Smoking;
                                Sleep; Victims of Fashion; New and Stale Bread; The Edible Fungi; Food Adulteration;
                                Trichina;; etc. etc. E. H. Gibbs, A. M., M. D. Editor, 21 Clinton Place, 8th. St. N. Y.
                                $1. a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mastery" TEIform="index"/>Mastery
                            </head><p TEIform="p">A beautiful Magazine is the No. 12."Mastery," filled with Illustrated articles of "Useful Pastimes for Young People." If
                                this is a representative number of those published and those to be published, no one can
                                regret its introduction into the family. It has an interesting, useful and healthy tone
                                and must be appreciated by those who are so fortunate as to receive it. Pub. at 842
                                Broadway, N. Y. $3. a year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health. August. Contents: Language, No. 4; This
                                very interesting article is illustrated with the portraits of John Gutenberg; the
                                Inventor of Printing; also with John Faust and Peter Schoeffer; The Engineers of the
                                Brooklyn Bridge and their Work. This is also illustrated with portraits of John A.
                                Roberling the chief Engineer, and of Washington A. Roberling who completed the work; A
                                few Reflections on Noses; Some Statuary; A beautifully illustrated article of the
                                American Switzerland; This wonderful place is found in the N. W. corner of Wyoming,
                                half-way between the Mississippi and the Pacific Ocean. "It is picturesque, curious,
                                stupendous, grand, magnificent;" Woman in the Industrial Arts; The Southern Exposition,
                                111; What is Insanily? Notes in Science and Agriculture; Editorial Items; etc. etc.
                                Fowler &amp; Wells, Pub. 753 Broadway, N. Y. $2. a year.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Homiletic monthly" TEIform="index"/>Homiletic Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p"> IlcmiLETic Monthly.
                                JLugust. Contents: Sermonic, Privilege Increasing responsibility; Lovingly Real;
                                Overcoming the World; Christ's appeal to Common Sense; Reprobation; The Model
                                Congregation; Christ an Immutable irieal; Homiletic Studies in the Book of Hebrews;
                                Commentary on the Epistle of James; Light on Important Sects; Sermonic Ci'iticism;
                                Queries and Answers, etc. etc; $2.50 a Year; Funk &amp; Wagnells. 10 &amp; 12
                                Dey St. N. Y.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sketches of Shakers amd Shakerism" TEIform="index"/>Sketches of Shakers and Shakerism
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Avery, Giles B." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"> Sketches or Shakers and Shakerism. Containing, also a Shaker's Answer; What would become
                                of the World if all should become Shakers. P..b. by Elder Giles B. Avery, Mt. Lebanon,
                                N. Y. Price. $5. per hundred. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="How to investigate spiritualism" TEIform="index"/>How to Investigate Spiritulism
                            </head><p TEIform="p">How to Investigate Spiritulism, A little pamphlet published by the Editor of the
                                ReligioPhilosophical Journal seems to be the right book at the right time. We are all,
                                more or less, directly or indirectly, interested in an unfolding of a spiritual life. In
                                this little work we hare suggestions offered that may be read with profit. Special
                                attention is directed to one offer of $1000 which has been made to any "exposer" or
                                conjurer. Price ten cents.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Reflection" TEIform="index"/> REFLECTION.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/> MARY WHITCHER.</byline><p TEIform="p"> Life is much as we would make it, Turning labor into joy, And again as we would take it,
                            More to please than to annoy. Friends are foes, when out of humor With ourselves and all
                            around; But the dullest, darkest weather Has a brightness to be found. Let us count the gems
                            of beauty, Bind the graces of the truth To the laurels of our duty, These the evergreens of
                            earth. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is the end of Fame..." TEIform="index"/>What is the end of Fame...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">What is the end of Fame? 'tis but to fill a certain portion of uncertain paper.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Byron" TEIform="persName">Byron.</persName></byline></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Augur, Isaac" TEIform="index"/>Isaac Augur
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Isaac Augur on the 19th of July, at Hancock, Mass. Age 67 yrs. 2 mo. and 21 days. We take
                                a few notes from an article in the Pittsfield Daily Evening Journal. <cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">The venerable, Elder Isaac Augur, died after an illness of a few weeks,
                                        having suffered a paralytic shock, from which he did not recover consciousness.
                                        He was for many years a prominent member in the community. He came to Berkshire
                                        when a lad of four years, and knew no other home or life than the simple ways of
                                        the Shakers. He was appointed to the office of an Elder quite early in life, and
                                        was considered one of the clearest headed men in the councils of the sect and
                                        one whose conclusions were reached only after mature deliberation. He was also,
                                        for many years a Trustee of the United Society of Shakers, a position which he
                                        held at the time of his death. He was an excellent farmer and was an enthusiast
                                        on some of his specialities. He was well informed of the matters of the day, and
                                        an extensive reader. He was a kindly man, a perfect gentleman, everywhere, and
                                        an entertaining companion and conversationalist. His funeral was quietly
                                        conducted at the Church family, after the custom of the sect. Elder Isaac's
                                        death will be learned with regret by many outside * of his own belief, who knew
                                        him well.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Pittsfield daily evening journal" TEIform="index"/></bibl></cit></p></div3></div2><!--
                    <pb id="p29"/>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]<pb id="p30"/>
                            <pb id="p31"/>
                            <pb id="p32"/>
                        </p>
                    </div2>
 --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>