<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ss0304" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">Shaker and Shakeress</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Society</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Mount Lebanon, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">3</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">4</biblScope><date value="18730401" TEIform="date">April 1873</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">25-32</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="3" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="25" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="4" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <p>Vol. III. No. 4. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETY. F ^DItJrANS' Mt. Lebanon, Col. Co. N. Y.. April, 1873 Fifty Cents
                        per annum.</p>
                    --><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mediators" TEIform="index"/>MEDIATORS</head><p TEIform="p">Does the central man, or woman, create Revolutions in the Natural Order? and Dis- pensations and Epochs in the
                            Spiritual ? — Or, do the Revolutions bring forth their own heroes, and the Dispensations (under law) evolve
                            their own Saviors ? At those momentous periods of the world's history, when there occurs a new Epoch, the earth
                            becomes vitalized and impregnated by an influx from the Parental Fountain, deseending through Mediatorial
                            Spheres, and directed by a Spiritual Intelligence, who is God to earth during that time. A corresponding human
                            being is in the new movement, and has to bear the judgment of the decreasing darkness, and of the increasing
                            light. In humanity, there is an inherent-tendency to deify both the ruling Intelligence and the governing man or
                            woman. Even in this our day, there are many thousands—-je millions— who thus deify the Spirit who, with such
                            mighty power and wonderful manifestations, brought up Israel out of Egypt. And, to them, the " God of the
                            Hebrews" is the God of all Gods. And skeptics, like Hume or Paine, deride, if they do not blaspheme, through
                            this theological error. Again. If the central man (or woman) — the anointed Lead in the new Era — himself
                            created the whole movement of human and spiritual forces, their failure, as free agents, to obey the Spirit, who
                            " rides the whirlwind and directs the storm," would neutralize and deaden the progressive forces, so that
                            nothing would be accomplished. Then the Divine design would be frustrated, and thousands who would have been
                            blessed by the new Deific Influx—yea, all the inhabitants of earth — would have suffered irreparable loss,
                            through the instrumentality of one insigni- ficant individual. " In Adam's fall, we sinned all," expresses the
                            idea, and, were it true, it would have been better if he had not sinned at all. As Esdras exclaimed, " 0 Adam,
                            what hast thou done ? Thou hast not fallen alone, but all we which be come of thee! " In the case of Noah,
                            Abram, Moses, Jesus, • Ann, each one of whom could have been, and was tempted, and consequently might have
                            fallen — yielded. For a " man (or woman) is tempted when he is drawn away of his own lusts, and enticed" to
                            indulge therein. Had either one or all of these suc- cumbed to the drawings of their inferior passions, would
                            there, in such case, have been no Shepherd, or Shepherdess — no Leader — would all have been lost? By no means!
                            Like some of the lower animals, humanity in a Revolution, or in a Dispensation, can reproduce a lost member, and
                            even restore a missing head. When, with any portion of earth's inhabitants, it is harvest time — when the fruit
                            and seed are ripe — there is not one only, but a crop, so to speak — a class of souls who are identified with
                            the principles, and baptized by and into the very spirit of the " times and seasons." God is in them
                            individually of a truth. And, under a law, which never fails, the real object and design of the Ruling Spirit —
                            the God of the Epoch — is invariably accomplished. How be it, as with Noah and his ship-mates, it may be in only
                            eight souls. But those eight men and women were as fully competent to the task of repeopling the earth as were
                            the first two, or as would have been eight millions. Out of an "army of the Lord," who had been to John
                            confessing their sins, and renewing their covenant with God and each other, to thenceforth obey the
                            physiological laws of Moses, Jesus and his Apostles were but thirteen in number, chosen from the midst of "
                            their fellows," and were " men to be wondered at" by the sense-indulging, disorderly Gentiles around them, who
                            ate any or every thing, and came together as no " brute beasts " ever do. Now, had either of these been
                            disobedient to his "heavenly vision," the holy Ruling Spirit would have elected another to "take his bishopric."
                            As it is always thus, " the Lord alone should be exalted," and not the person of the " Anointed " deified. No
                            man, or woman, should be worshiped; it " fills the land with idolatry " and adolators. Those who " worship the
                            creature " — Jesus — more than the Creator," and instead of Him, de as " greatly err" as would the Shakers were
                            they to worship Ann Lee. " I saw an Angel fly in the midst of heaven, having the everlasting Gospel to preach to
                            them that dwell upon the earth; and he cried, with a loud voice, saying, " Fear God, and give glory unto Him;
                            for the hour of his judgment"—the day of judgment— "has come." This Angel succeeded the Angel of Spiritualism,
                            who "came down from heaven, having great power, and the earth," — all who dwell upon the earth — " was
                            enlightened with his glory." As individuals gather, one by one, " from the East, and from the West, and from the
                            North, and from the South," each one will bring in with him and her a portion of the One Spirit of Good — of
                            Religion — which pervades the race; and also more or less of the particular system of theology into which they
                            may have been indoctrinated : as the Jew, or Mohammedan, the Hindoo, or Christian (so called), or any one from
                            either of the various sects of these great divisions, which constitute " the old heavens," which must be
                            supplanted by the "new heavens." There being in all a tendency to idolatry, tender, conscientious souls, under
                            this infirmity possessing more religious zeal than theological knowledge, must be gently led by the hand, drawn
                            by the cords of love, and by the influence of true religion, out of false theology. A true and good life will
                            ultimately create a true theology. Theoretically 1 all believe in the progression of themselves, and of their
                            system; but practically, when it comes, they will be nearly unanimous in a determined opposition thereto. As the
                            past history of our race has its ancient records; so its future history has been recorded by men and women " who
                            wrote as they were moved by the Holy Christ Spirits " (who, themselves, are existing in a perfect social state),
                            who inspired them to portray and describe scenes in which they would be the chief though invisible actors. It is
                            thus that the " testimony of Jesus is the spirit of prophecy." That is, the spirit of the Prophets is incarnated
                            — externalized upon our earth — in human beings who, individually and collectively, are living out the
                            principles of the coming Millennium. "Of the increase and going forth" of this testimony " there will be no
                            end," or cessation, until " the kingdoms of this world become the kingdoms of our God, and of his Christ," and
                            all things upon this earth shall have become the reflex of the inner heavens, or spheres. " See that thou make
                            all things according to the Pattern showed thee in the Mount." God is in the beginning, and man in the ending,
                            of all "the times and seasons" of the progression of the race towards its final destiny — a perfect Natural
                            Order, and a pure Spiritual Order, distinct, yet co-existent — the true relation of Church and State. The
                            elements in this work of judgment evolved a Woman as its centre of influence, and Leader. And around her has
                            gathered a body of men and women who constitute the Church of Chrisfs Second Appearing, whose foundational or
                            basic principles are : Faith in a Dual God, as the Source of all Divine revelation, through Prophets and
                            Prophetesses in all times, and amongst all peoples; a Recog-<pb n="26" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> nition of Spiritualism, as the
                            " waters of the great deep, in which can float the Ark of Organization. Its main timbers are, Celibacy,
                            Community, Peace — the Gentile Pentecostal Christian Church. This Church has been, is, and will continue to be
                            the Medium of transmission, to the Natural Order, of the inherent and inalienable right of every human being to
                            all the elements of existence, defined and administered in the fear of God, by Rulers of both sexes — like Moses
                            and Miriam (or Deborah) — as simple representatives and obedient servants of the whole population, male and
                            female. Use, not pleasure, is the unchangeable law. Each to live for all, and all for each. Fox and Swedenborg
                            were fore-runners — "Witnesses": Fox in the Religious element; Swedenborg in the Spiritual.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christmas musings" TEIform="index"/>CHRISTMAS MUSINGS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Myrick, E." TEIform="persName"/>(E. Myrick.)</byline><p TEIform="p">What do we commemorate, the birth, the life or the death of Him who came to do the will of Him that sent Him? His
                            birth was but a preamble, and his death but a supplement— the fly-leaves to the record of a divine, unselfish
                            and heroic character. Let the service of the day be a renewed dedication and aspiration to a more faultless
                            fidelity to purity, truth and humanity — that we may " grow in favor with God and man;" and that every
                            conviction of right may find a response in duty done. His gifts were patent to all +he world. " Forbid them not
                            to cast out df ils in my name." To him it was better tl. an the applause of men. "And inasmuch ts you have done
                            a kind act to the least of these, my brethren, ye have done it unto me." He planted the good seed in the heart,
                            the seat of life, where, by cultivation, it would absorb the whole being. He trained the philosophical and
                            emotional to attain higher human happiness than either alone could ever reach. He recognized an immortal
                            relationship as superior to the Adamic, selfish blood relation, which is severed by death. Through his
                            mediumship, Jesus poured light into the world. And to-day we rejoice, not so much in the birth of a good man,
                            nor in the attainment of salvation alone; but in that invaluable (though not infallible) light of progress,
                            elevation, and spiritual refinement, that shines in a life of Christian, virgin purity. In his life we have a
                            pattern of dignified meekness, sublime courage and blameless integrity; reverencing all times and all places, as
                            they are hallowed by holy work. " He liveth long who liveth well, All else is time but flung away; He liveth
                            longest, who can tell Most true things, truly done each day," If we would claim a true relation to our Elder
                            Brother, " the first born," we must become as " lambs slain," (the animal life extinct); and yet, while we live
                            on the earth, we may also reign over the earthly, generative, selfish nature; banish alike poverty and riches;
                            testify against disease, murders, and all forms of our perverted natural powers. " Ye are the salt of the
                            earth," who would not " destroy life, but save it." Moses enjoined the strict observance of the law of nature
                            for the generative "children of this world," which would insure healthy offspring, that, preserving physical
                            soundness, they might live, and be, and do good, and not kill one another. To balance this despicable, though
                            popular check on over-replenishing the earth, Jesus introduced a rational and philosophical check, the
                            out-growth of the generative, by the virgin regenerative life; an innate and natural sequence of the physical,
                            moral, and intellectual, so beautifully characterized by the four living creatur.es (Rev. 4th, 6th, 7th,) which
                            were " in the midst of and round about the throne, full of eyes before and behind." " The fourth was like a,
                            flying eagle," moving in the highest ethereal element — could bear the direct rays of the sun, and revolted at
                            decaying bodies, a most fitting symbol of man's spiritual nature. If we would respect this Christian record, we
                            must remember the character and attitude of the "flying eagle."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good resolutions" TEIform="index"/>GOOD RESOLUTIONS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Offord, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>(Daniel Offord.)</byline><p TEIform="p"> Make good resolutions, and carry them out. They help the growth of virtue in the soul, and are as gentle
                            breezes, or rays of sunshine, or as showers that often fall upon tender plants. Some persons make good
                            resolutions, but who, not attaining to perfection at once, become discouraged, and think it is of no use to keep
                            making resolutions which are likely to be broken, and that it is only telling falsehoods, and does no good. This
                            is all a delu- sion. Shall we, because one gentle breeze, or one ray of sunshine, or one single shower, does not
                            produce a crop, say, It does no good? No one would be so foolish. So, because one resolution fails to bring us
                            into the possession of any particular virtue, shall we therefore cease to strive? Nay! "God looks at the heart"
                            and the intent of the soul, therefore let us make good resolutions, and keep them; and then renew, and keep
                            renewing, till we attain to that to which we aspire.—Mt.Lebanon.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="City set on a hill" TEIform="index"/>CITY SET ON A HILL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bradford, A. B." TEIform="persName"/>(A. B. Bradford.)</byline><p TEIform="p">Part II. 4. Their Community Ideas. The Shakers are one of the few Societies that have successfully adopted the
                            Essenean and Apostolic plan of a community of goods. The Mount Lebanon Society own seven thousand acres of land,
                            on which has been bestowed a vast amount of labor, and on which are immense buildings of the most expensive and
                            permanent kind, and all in the most perfect state of repair. Miles upon miles of stone fence have been built,
                            and, as the Shakers do every thing honestly and religiously, these landmarks, like the old cathedrals of Europe,
                            will be as good as new when hundreds of generations shall have passed away. They have immense wealth in
                            manufactories, and the preparation of herbs and garden seeds for sale ; and their productions of all kinds
                            command the market, because implicit confidence can be put in the goodness of the articles they offer. Yet no
                            man among Believers calls aught of all this wealth his own, but they have all things in common. By a division of
                            labor and by the principle of co-operation, a small amount of daily toil by each person secures a vast aggregate
                            of wealth. Yet they are not a money-making community. That is to say, the accumulation of wealth and an
                            extensive business is neither the primary nor the secondary object of their Society. Believing that a competency
                            is all we can enjoy, they are content with an income of thousands, where it might be, if they pleased, scores of
                            thousands. Elder Frederick, who, by common consent, is a leading man among them, and verifies Carlyle's
                            definition of Koenig — king — able man, maintains that the only basis of success for a community is the
                            principle of a celibate life. Marriage, it is alleged, creates selfishness, and produces a diversity of
                            interests, alienations and schisms. This, it must be confessed, has been the case in the history of co-operative
                            associations generally when based upon the community idea ; but whether it inheres as a vice in the system,
                            growing out of the necessity of the case, demands a doubt. But to run no risk, the Shaker, having no wife,
                            jealous and exacting for her children, there is no motive to build up separate interests and create factions.
                            The good of the whole remains the grand object of each one. If any brother or sister tires of this mode of life,
                            and wishes to set up a family dynasty for themselves, they are dismissed with regret, but are not sent away
                            empty. The Shaker Societies do not much increase their numbers. But, if the world only knew of their existence —
                            if those who are disgusted with the hollowness of fashionable society, and are bowed down under the
                            disappointments of life, only knew there was a haven of rest to the wearied soul, where peace, plenty and
                            contentment reign, and where the cup of happiness is filled to the brim, the roads leading to their gates would
                            be filled with travelers who, like Bunyan'a Pilgrim in the city of Destruction, would flee for their lives and
                            happiness to these quiet abodes. For adults of both sexes the inducements are : moderate employment, the most
                            virtuous society, plenty in all its varieties, and freedom from all care as to the future. For parents who bring
                            their children, the best of schools, and a thorough training in all the economical virtues which make life
                            beautiful and reasonable. Gossip and neighborhood scandal, which poison the air of nearly every village in the
                            land, are entirely unknown. Each member of the family has his, or her, place, and function; and order and
                            neatness, with all their correlative virtues, prevail. For a person among the world's people who is weak; that
                            is to say, who cannot withstand temptation in all its forms, and say to the Devil, " Get thee behind me, Satan,"
                            the Shaker family is the place for him or her. For here, one who desires to repent and forsake sin, and lead a
                            life of purity, finds every person, and thing, and arrangement, calculated to sustain and strengthen. There are
                            no temptations to evil; there are no suggestions of a mis-spent past to torture the soul by reflection ; but
                            forgetting the things that are behind, each person fixes his eye upon the goal in the future, and girds up the
                            loins of his mind to reach it; and I have no doubt that if a Mary Magdalene wished to turn her back upon the
                            past, and set her face Zion-ward, and asked the whitecloud sisterhood to help her in her endeavors to lay hold
                            on eternal life, she would be treated with the same consideration as the other Marys who bless the place with
                            their benign presence. Still, the Community is no orphan asylum, nor widows' asylum, but only a home for all
                            those who feel called and able to lead the beautiful and quiet life they live — a life of industry, and of
                            harmony, and of innocency. 5. Their Neatness and Tidiness. In the cranium of every Shaker, male and female,
                            there is a fine development of the organ of order, and all its cognates. Indeed, it is a prerequisite, and sine
                            qua non, in every applicant for brotherhood and sisterhood, that he or she be perfectly clean, not only in soul,
                            but body, and that they keep every thing around them so. It is beautiful to see, as .one walks through all the
                            departments of a family, how heaven's first law — order — reigns, and how perfect cleanliness prevails. Neither
                            in house, nor barn, nor field, nor shed, can be found any thing that would offend the eye or nostril of the most
                            delicate and fastidious visitor. This perfect cleanliness has much to do with the moral purity of their lives.
                            Degradation and filthiness of the flesh go together ; and so do personal and moral purity. There is a gospel in
                            soap and soft water, for which the world is suffering, and it is the first consideration in all reformatory
                            institutions, whether for the body or the soul. A dirty Shaker is as rare an anomaly as a white raven, and I
                            have never heard that any one of the Community became either crazy or criminal. The agricultural interests of
                            this country are suffering because farmers' sons, as soon as they see a little of the world, become disgusted
                            with farming and go to " professions " or swarm to the cities. It is the drudgery, the slovenliness and the want
                            of plan and taste that disgust. Rural occupations are the most independent and pleasing of any on earth.
                            Tradesmen and professional men in Europe, and especially in England, live in cities and make money, only that
                            after a while they may retire to the country and live natural and happy lives. Labor is cheap and they can
                            execute SHA.KEH A-ISTD 26 <pb n="27" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEEESS. plans. But, in our country, labor is dear and farming
                            is both a drudgery and wasteful. The recklessness and waste on many a farm, in its expensiveness, eats deep into
                            the year's productions. A young man, who contemplates farming as an occupation, would save money, in the long
                            run, by paying the Shakers to take him for a couple of years and allow him to work with them, and to see and
                            learn the thrifty way they do things. There are large, commodious sheds to accommodate farming implements of all
                            kinds. You see no tool thrown down where it is last used, and lost; no wagons standing out in the weather, week
                            after week, and going into uselessness. There is a place for every thing, and every thing in its place. There is
                            a regular system of farming which includes five years with its rotations of crops. No building is erected on a
                            cheap plan, for all cheap things are dear, and well the Shakers understand the paradox. Their fences are all in
                            order, their houses and barns are all painted. And in all their interior arrangements an eye is had to
                            convenience and economy of labor. A young man trained to their habits, would not only make money in farming, but
                            would take delight in his occupation. A plan which looks ahead five years, and brings money into a man's purse
                            annually, which he feels he has a right to because he has earned it, does away with the idea of expensive
                            drudgery, and makes him proud of his occupation ; and party politics which, for its chances to indulge in
                            gabbling, is so attractive to so many young men in this country, has no attractions for him. With such industry
                            and economy as the Shakers use, and with their large facilities for making money, they yet decline doing so.
                            Their grand object is not to amass wealth,but to live the right kind of life. That their simple diet, their
                            moderate labor, their perfect equanimity of feeling, and entire harmony of views and interests, tend to promote
                            health and long life, is clear from their bills of mortality. 6. Their Worship. To a person who is a total
                            stranger to their religious opinions, the Shaker mode of worship would appear novel. But so would a Roman
                            Catholic mass in the cathedral service appear to a Scotch Cameronian, who, for the first time, witnessed the
                            formality. And so would a Church of England man regard " fencing the tables " on an old Covenanter communion
                            occasion; or a Quaker meeting. There is a great advantage in being something of a cosmopolite, and seeing other
                            people's modes of worship, and hearing their opinions. Steamships and railroads have brought nations into close
                            proximity with each other ; or, to use the late canny phrase of the Archbishop of Canterbury, they " rub
                            shoulders with one another." Bigotry is a religious vice, which lives and thrives in its own poor half bushel.
                            It has no idea that there exists any more world than there is in its narrow quarters, or if there be, that it is
                            of any manner of account. Hence it condemns all opinions and modes of worship, except its own. But bigotry is
                            under sentence of death by the spirit of the age. The facilities of travel bring Brahmins, Buddhists,
                            Mohammedans, and Christians of all sects, together ; and being gentlemen, instead of boors and g-ahoos, they,
                            with mutual respect, compare notes, and soon find out that there is, underlying all their special religions, and
                            forming the substratum on which they all are built, the grand, yet simple religion of Nature, the oldest and
                            purest of all religions, the equivalent of Christianity, which Jesus and Paul authorize Saint Augustine to say,
                            was always, and everywhere, in the world. Thinking and candid men who are freed from the trammels of
                            superstition, are fast beginning to regard the religion of Nature as the one true, universal religion; and that
                            all the special religions are merely sects, based on it, only less pure, and consistent. Amidst these
                            ameliorating influences, produced by travel and international communication, Shakerism, with its peculiar
                            opinions, and its novel worship, cannot be dismissed with a supercilious toss of the head, which the bigoted
                            ecclesiastic knows so well how to show, but advances its claim to the respectful study of all who feel
                            interested in the different religious opinions and practices of the human family. Men of note and ability, like
                            Archbishop Hughes visit their establishments, where they are treated with marked hospitality, and study their
                            system, and always leave them, as they must, with feelings of admiration for their quiet but heroic lives. I was
                            present, with hundreds of others, most of whom were visitors from Lebanon Springs, and witnessed their form of
                            worship on the Sabbath. At the proper time, the ranks opened gracefully after much singing of hymns ; and one
                            after another, Elder Frederick, and Antoinette Doolittle, addressed the assembly, and gave them such wholesome
                            instructions in the practical duties of life, as they never got in their churches at home. Both the persons
                            named are highly gifted as speakers ; and, while they devote their talents in this line to the interests of the
                            community primarily, they render on suitable occasions, important service to the world outside. 7. It would be a
                            great mistake to suppose that on account of their celibate lives the Shakers are nothing but monks and nuns
                            under another name. Monks live by themselves, and so do nuns. But the Shakers are a Family, living under the
                            same roof as brothers and sisters. Some people who still live like owls, in the twilight of the Middle Ages,
                            imagine that the constant intermingling of the sexes under the same roof must produce licentiousness. Upon this
                            libel against God, and his children, our monastic colleges and female seminaries are built. But the Shakers,
                            believing that the Almighty understands his own plans when he sends boys and girls into the same family, have
                            found out by induction what all might know by deduction, that the daily life of the sexes in the presence of
                            each other, promotes and secures the moral purity and refinement of both, and thus vindicates the ways of God to
                            man. Some sensual mortals, who are themselves unfortunately the children of lust, instead of love, and who
                            cannot understand that a man's pure and ardent affection for a woman would protect her against himself, may
                            entertain a suspicion that, after all, there may be improper intercourse among the Shakers. I believe this has
                            never been charged against them, even by those who have left the Community, and gone back to the world. Shaker
                            celibacy is an effect, and the causes that combine to produce it are many, and various, and powerful. I scorn
                            the suspicion that men and women who esteem celibacy to be a virtue, and for them a religious duty, cannot, with
                            all the motives drawn from heaven and earth, make that attainment. And I regard this fraternity of Christians as
                            accomplishing their end in the great plan of the universe by showing to the world what a degree of perfection
                            human beings can reach, not only in the matter of a celibate life, but in labor, in diet, in giving to woman her
                            proper place as an equal, in contentment,in honesty of dealing and in serene contempt for the empty fashions and
                            pursuits of the world. Having said so much in just praise of the Shaker Community, I must now offer a word of
                            just criticism.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="No evil" TEIform="index"/>NO EVIL</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, H. L." TEIform="persName"/>(H. L. Eades.)</byline><p TEIform="p">The quasi-philosophical doctrine of No Evil is almost as darkening and pernicious in its tendency as that which
                            teaches that "one man brought all sin into the world, and another one must take it all out. Or another one that,
                            ignorantly literalizing the scripture allegory of the creation of the man, woman and snake, affirms that the
                            snake was the immediate, and God himself the remote cause of sin. He having created this trio, with a
                            foreknowledge of the result, acknowledges his part in the transaction, by condescending to be born of a woman,
                            and then permitting himself to be killed, in order to exculpate man, satisfy his own justice, and appease his
                            own wrath. Or still another doctrine, which affirms that it was God's Son, and not Himself, that died, the
                            Father having caused the Son to take on Himself the sins of the whole world, which he " bore in his body on the
                            tree," and this to relieve His own murderers from the crime they were committing while destroying Him ! Rejoice,
                            0 sinner, and sin away! Thus exclaims the zealot, " Bless the Lamb of God which taketh away the sin of the world
                            ! "—all that have been committed, or ever will be. "Glory to God ! Not by works, lest any man should boast. You
                            are not going to get me to mourn over my sins. But I know very well, if Christ has not taken them away, I am
                            certainly lost, for their name is legion." But another class will not admit that Christ died for the sins of the
                            whole world, but only for those who have faith in their creed ; the rest to be consigned to endless torment.
                            Thus: A &amp; B in actual life, are precisely alike. A believes whilst B doubts, and, as ; he that doubts is
                            damned already," B's case is hopeless; so, for the same deeds, A goes to eternal bliss, and B to endless
                            torment, and this passes for Divine justice. Byron seemed to be a doubter ; he says: " A natural resurrection
                            seems strange, and even absurd, except for the purposes of punishment; and all punishment which is for revenge,
                            rather than to correct, is morally wrong; and when the world is at an end, what moral religious purpose can
                            eternal tortures answer? " Having lately seen an article written with some ability, defending the affirmative of
                            the proposition, " Whatever is, is right," in defense of the No Evil theory, has induced me to offer some
                            criticism on the productions from a negative view of the subject There is a canon of logic which denies us the
                            privi- lege of reasoning from a proposition that admits of two constructions, without showing which is intended.
                            " It is necessary," says Locke, "in order to be understood, that the hearer should join the same meaning to the
                            words used that the speaker does," else they will be likely to convey darkness instead of light. It seems to me
                            that nothing has been more misunderstood and misapplied, than the following lines of Pope: " All discord,
                            harmony not understood — All partial evil universal good ; And spite of pride, in erring reason's spite, One
                            truth is clear, whatever is, is right." Those who so flippantly quote this great author in defense of the No
                            Evil theory, forget to state that the argument, which closes with the above lines, is headed thus: " Of nature
                            and the state of man with respect to the universe," and not with respect to God, himself, or society. He had no
                            idea that his words could be wrested in defense of that Optimism, which declares that all things, moral,
                            spiritual, and material, are ordered for the best. The existence of moral discord and moral evil is too palpable
                            to be disputed by any sane man. A son murders his father; there is a " discord " in that particular family; but
                            it only needs to be "understood" to make harmony of it. A "partial evil" it certainly is; but 'tis only
                            necessary to include the universe with it to make it " right"(!) So on runs the sophistry. Hurricanes are
                            partial evils, when some person's property suffers by them, but they purify the atmosphere, and so, a little
                            blood-letting by wars, purifies societyf?) Thus people strive to ease their consciences and harden themselves in
                            crime. The article opens in this wise: 1st. " The material universe is the expression of the Divine character,
                            and any thing which takes place therein, does so in obedience to law; and all effects are the expressions ot
                            Divine Power, consequently right." 2nd. " God is as immanently present in the flower as in the regeneration of
                            the soul! " etc. The flower has violated no law; but it is a strange concession to speak of the regeneration of
                            the soul, when it is in the universe, — a thing that "is," consequently, according to his text, is right, and
                            therefore needs no regeneration. But such inconsistencies are 27 <pb n="28" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> the natural sequence of
                            wrong positions. 3d. " There is no inharmony except in respect to the finite and individual; and that inharmony
                            does not extend beyond the finite." Here inharmony is fairly confessed; but, to assert that it does not extend
                            beyond the finite — leaves us still in harmony with the Infinite — is freely admitted; for no finite act can
                            change the unchangeable Infinite ; but having been created in harmony with God, if we break that harmony by
                            disobedience, the only possible chance of restoration is by returning to obedience. Renan says: "If we cannot
                            see God (in his entirety) we can powerfully feel Him" — who, through the conscience causes us to know his will,
                            which, if obeyed, insures a harmonious relation of the finite with the Infinite; all denial to the contrary
                            notwithstanding. 4th. " The Omnipresent Divinity is everywhere seen, preparing the finite to become united with
                            the Infinite; capable of becoming, and destined to become, a living, conscious universe, begotten in the exact
                            image of the Divine Father in esse and in existence." If we are to be in the "exact image of God, both in being
                            and in existence, and become conscious universes," then we are gods, sure enough! Than this, what more is God ?
                            Wherein shall we differ from Him ? And if we are to equal Him in being and existence, why not excel Him? And so
                            — " Nobly take the high priori road, And reason downward till we doubt of God ; Make nature still encroach upon
                            his plan, And shove him off as far as e'er we can; Or at one bound o'erleaping all his laws, Make God man's
                            image, man the final cause."— or otherwise close with the pantheistic doctrine, wherein "evil ceases to have an
                            objective reality," .and that unintelligent nature is the cause of intelligent man, and he only a Darwinian
                            effect. In defending the No Evil theory, this writer seems to have taken his cue from the ethics of Aristotle,
                            who, notwithstanding he could "reprove the Greeks for allowing their children to grow up as wild beasts," and,
                            as Plato says, " to be torn in pieces by their lusts as by so many wild horses," yet he also affirms that " the
                            first and absolute Good has nothing that is his own opposite." Thus, it may be seen, that in the defense of "No
                            Evil," this great philosopher has fallen into the same palpable inconsistencies of all the lesser lights;
                            wherein, if he is content, I now propose to leave him. " Behold, I come quickly, and my reward is with me, to
                            give to every one, according as his work shall be." —Rev. xn. 22. South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="national-news" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Lincoln" TEIform="index"/>LINCOLN</head><p TEIform="p">A writer in the New York Times, alter a careful reading of Lamon's Life of Lincoln, makes the following deduction
                            : "Mr. Lincoln was an infidel —positive, absolute, thorough. He was entirely without religion; and not only
                            without religion, but without any faith upon which religion of any kind could be founded. He believed in none of
                            the doctrines, or even the facts, upon which the Christian religion rests. The man who was always the champion
                            of the poor and the oppressed, who was ever ready for personal self-sacrifice, whose famous Gettysbur^ oration
                            breathed the ven^ essential spirit of the enthusiasm of humanity, had no faith at all in any divine revelation,
                            none whatever in the Divinity of Jesus Christ, none, consequently, in the authority of his teachings." If some
                            of Mr. Lincoln's devout friends had known all this five years ago, they would have looked upon his tragic end in
                            the light of a dispensation. After all, it seems that all the Christian virtues may be linked with unbelief and
                            paganism, for undoubtedly, Lincoln was a kind-hearted, generous, benevolent man.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Assimilation" TEIform="index"/>ASSIMILATION</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William" TEIform="persName"/>(Wm. Bussell.)</byline><p TEIform="p">There is an inter-relation existing between all things in the universe, more or less inti- nate, according to the
                            peculiar character of each. This results from the oneness of Deity. ?orms may be infinitely varied, yet, such is
                            the nature of substances themselves, they all attest the oneness of their origin; hence their relation to each
                            other. Because of this relation they all have a transforming power over each other, varying according to condi-
                            tions and circumstances. The central body in each planetary system not only attracts and moulds every one of its
                            revolving spheres, but is itself attracted and modified by them. Each system also affects and is affected by
                            every other system in the universe, while performing its sublime part in the never-ending dance. The earth, with
                            its multitudinous inhabitants, s powerfully influenced by the atmosphere which surrounds it, and this in turn
                            acknowledges the power exercised upon it by oceans, mountains, fields and forests. Whether Darwin's theory of
                            the origin of the human species be true or false, man is obliged to own his relation to all inferior existences,
                            and even to feel, oft-times, that they have a controlling influence upon him. Often the face that was to be ever
                            looking heavenward is downcast, and the entire person loves to exhibit its relationship to the groveling broods
                            of earth. The human system, by its excessive absorption of life forces from both the animal and vegetable
                            kingdoms, takes its rank even with the lowest orders. Its activity, which should surpass that of any inferior
                            beings, is often so feeble that it becomes the slave rather than the master of all beneath. This is because of
                            its failure to observe the Divine order of drawing the highest elements of life from sources above the human.
                            The physical system of the brutes, when they are left free to act in accordance with their instincts, is
                            maintained in its natural vigor and order. That of man will be toned to the highest health and strength when the
                            physical, the intellectual and the moral faculties are maintained in their proper order by the use of
                            nourishment best adapted to each. When the corporeal system is unduly cherished to the neglect of the mental and
                            moral, then the man necessarily exhibits his close affinity to the animal. He assimilates himself to the lower
                            life, and by reason of the absorbing and transforming action thus induced, he invariably displays more than
                            brutal passions. He has sunk below the proper plane of his own existence. Examples of such abound in all
                            history, so that it is unnecessary to particularize. The physical frame, when preserved in due order by a
                            suitable degree of food and exercise, instead of being a hindrance to the growth of the higher faculties, may be
                            rendered a constant aid to them just so long as its natural vigor lasts. Being a product ol the earth, it
                            returns to it at last, and is completely assimilated to it; but if it has performed its part well, it has been
                            an honored co-adjutor in the Divine Economy of rearing beings for the immortal realms. When both the physical
                            and intellectual natures are cherished at the expense of the spiritual faculties something superior to the mere
                            animal is certainly exhibited, but still, man in his true dignity does not appear. What keenness of intellect
                            was displayed by Napoleon ! Whai rapidity of thought and action, as well as accuracy of judgment, on the
                            battle-field and in the affairs of State ! Yet his wonderfully keen intellect but served to give a sharper edge
                            to the sword he wielded. He was unquestionably adapted to make a powerfu' impression upon warlike nations. He
                            changec and. molded Europe, but left it, nevertheless, warlike still. Not till the superior facultie, of man
                            have that attention paid to them thai their nature demands, will mankind cease to be a warring race. For the
                            purpose of maintaining sound physcal health, one needs the food that the sys,em can readily assimilate to
                            itself, so as to )reserve harmonious action between all the jarts. Any one who is in the habit of observing the
                            effect produced upon himselt }y the different qualities and quantities ot bod taken into his system cannot fail
                            to see ;hat his mental and moral faculties, as well as ;he corporeal, are affected by them. As a jeneral rule,
                            he finds that when the outward is in good condition, the mental and moral forces are in more harmonious play
                            than when the reverse is the case; and when the central manufactory of physical health is disturbed, there is
                            more or less disturbance throughout the whole man. The plain inference is, then, that the food which is taken
                            into the stomach is assimilated, not only to the corporeal blood but also to the more internal or magnetic
                            forces of the system. This fact gives greater force to the expression found in the writings of the Jewish
                            lawgiver. " The life of the flesh is in the blood." The term used for life in the Septuagint translation is
                            psyche, commonly translated soul; meaning that principle in the human economy that is the stimulator of its
                            every faculty. In the Greek New Testament we have the same worci as an equivalent expression to that which Jesus
                            used : " What shall a man give in exchange for his psyche—his life or soul ? " Deprived of this he is poor
                            indeed ! The wealth of the entire world will not compensate him for its loss. The same care that is to be
                            observed with respect to the food for the body should also be observed in regard to that for the mind. Some
                            things offered as such must be absolutely rejected; others sparingly used, while others still may be accepted as
                            daily nourishment. As a general rule, that which cherishes envy, jealousy, hatred, revenge, strifes, and
                            contentions of every kind is to be discarded, though presented by the hands of the greatest masters of
                            expression, and under the most attractive exterior. Though the cup be of the purest gold and set with numerous
                            brilliants, it can never change the nature of the poison it may contain. Even the historian's pages, which too
                            often are but the mirror of human vices, are deleterious, if exhibited so as to make those vices attractive
                            rather than repulsive. What should be a lesson of warning and remonstrance may be so presented as to produce
                            effects the very reverse. Wars are but the exhibition of the baser passions of mankind; but painted too often in
                            colors that belong to their opposites, they serve to cherish these passions rather than to eradicate them from
                            the human breast. Mental food, as well as that for the body, should be such as to produce harmony throughout the
                            entire system. No other should be allowed to assimilate itself, and thus form a constituent part of our
                            intellectual life. Othenvise mental disease will be the inevitable consequence, and restoration to health may
                            not be effected without long-suffering and disagreeable remedies. Life is of various degrees, to the very
                            highest of which man is entitled as his inheritance. It is enjoyed, however, in its greatest degree, only by
                            those who are in the possesion of sound physical, mental and moral health. The Divine Spirit breathes
                            everywhere, but, like the atmosphere, does not produce equal effects upon all. It may dwell in the innermost of
                            man, but cannot be consciously enjoyed in its fullness, nor manifested in its proper effects, where there are
                            the obstructions of physical, mental, or moral disease. Let every string of the human harp be rightly tuned, and
                            celestial music will be produced. When the highest inspirations flow unobstructed into the inner life, they make
                            an essential part of that life. They fashion it in accordance with that possessed in the highest heaven, where
                            harmony perpetually reigns among its blessed inhabitants. — Mt. Morris.</p></div2><pb n="29" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakeress: laws of progress" TEIform="index"/>SHAKERESS: LAWS OF PROGRESS</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Doolittle, A." TEIform="persName"/>A. DOOLITTLE, EDITRESS</byline><p TEIform="p">What is Time when measured with the eternal ages which roll in continuity through boundless space ? When we look
                            at the imperfect condition of men and things as they now exist, we often feel an intense desire for great and
                            sudden changes, especially in theology and religion; and that the prediction of the spirit through John the
                            Revelator, " Behold, I make all things new," should take effect immediately. An inspired prophet of olden time
                            said (pointing to times and seasons which God hath reserved in his own keeping), "By measure hath He measured
                            the times, and by number hath he numbered them, and he doth not stir nor move them until the said measure be
                            fulfilled." We cannot change the laws of progression which underlie all growth in material and spiritual things;
                            but we may change our relations to them, and be instrumental in helping others to do the same. If we sow a field
                            of grain, we must expect to give the seed time to germinate and grow. We cannot by any means get the stalk, the
                            blade and the ear in one day. And when we plant a tree, if we understand the science of arboriculture, so that
                            we feed and water it, and stir the soil around it at the proper time to produce healthy action, we may
                            accelerate its growth, but we cannot bring forth a full grown tree, however much we may desire to do so. The
                            same laws which govern in the visible, are also operative in the (to us) invisible world of causation. In the
                            spiritual, as in the material, we must bide the time. The All Father and Mother of souls, who watch so strictly
                            over their children that " Not one sparrow falls to the ground with- out their notice, cannot look upon the
                            condition of suffering humanity with less interest and compassion than do mortals. Mercy and truth meet (in
                            counsel) together, and fain would they gather souls under the blessed influence of righteousness and peace, and
                            bind them with the cords of love. But "justice and judgment are the habitation of God's throne," and his laws do
                            not conflict. Justice must precede mercy. Spiritual death is the effect of violated law; and if souls sin unto
                            death, they must find repentance unto life; justice demands it. Then, mercy stands ready to bind up the
                            brokenhearted and contrite in spirit, and give the sweet balm of consolation. As we.cannot change, or force the
                            laws of progress, how can we the most effectually co-operate with them to hasten our own spiritual growth, and
                            ameliorate the condition of the race to which we belong? G-od sends angels to sow and to reap; but men and women
                            are the mediums through which they work. The angels could accomplish but little without the agency of man and
                            woman. The higher and purer our conditions are, the more effective will our labors be in helping others. It is
                            not wise for us to neglect any known duty to-day, because there is an endess future before us; for each day has
                            its appropriate work. If, step by step, we ascend the hill of progression in scientific knowledge and spiritual
                            truth, the higher we rise the purer and clearer will be the atmosphere, and the stronger will our influence be
                            in drawing others from the low plane of sensualism, and from their wanderings in the cold, barren region of
                            naturalism into the realm of spiritual light and divine ideas, where they can commune with higher intelligences
                            from the unseen world.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Cup" TEIform="index"/>"THE CUP."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Kaime, Joanna" TEIform="persName"/>(Eldress Joanna Kaime.)</byline><p TEIform="p">Jesus said, " Are ye able to drink of the cup that I shall drink of, and be baptized with the baptism that I am
                            baptized with ? " Often times, when a child under the parental roof, have we read, with tearful eyes and bated
                            breath, the glowing account of the crucifixion of Jesus, as recorded by the Evangelists ; and, in our childish
                            indignation, demanded of our parents to know why the great and good God suffered those cruel and wicked Jews to
                            so ill-treat his beloved Son. Receiving an answer which served to confound more than to enlighten us, we
                            accepted the traditional M faith, that some how, or in some way, though never clear to our understanding, we
                            were to be saved by the shedding of His blood on Mount Calvary. But our thanks are due to an overruling
                            Providence, that, in the second manifestation of the Christ Spirit, through the instrumentality of his
                            followers, we have received knowledge of the true way of life and salvation ; if we would be harvested from, and
                            rise above, the earthly plane, we must shape our lives according to the Pattern, and walk as Jesus walked, drink
                            of the same cup of which He drank, bear the same cross and living testimony which is like consuming fire to the
                            nature of sin; then we partake of the same baptism. And, as maturer years and broader views were ours, we found
                            still deeper, if not more painful, emotions steal across the brain, and sink into the heart, as imagination
                            depicted the sufferings of Jesus in the lonely garden, on the eve of his "passion." What mingling of pathos and
                            sublimity! the human and Divine alternately controlling. The former, shrinking from the impending crisis, while,
                            in the heaviness of his grief, he said, " My soul is exceedingly sorrowful, even unto death ! " yet apparently
                            denying himself of all the sympathy which that expression of sorrow might elicit from his disciples, he said
                            unto them, " Tarry, here, and watch." Then he went forward to intercede with his Father, that, if consistent
                            with his righteous will, the coming trial might be averted. Then, falling upon his face in agony of spirit, he
                            prayed, " Oh, my Father, if it be possible, let this cup pass from me ! " Then there seemed to be a heavenly
                            ministration, borne on angel wings, overshadowing him as he softly whispered, " Nevertheless, not as I will,.
                            but as Thou wilt." Listen to the mild and gentle rebuke given to his neglectful watchers, on his return from his
                            fervent intercessions, " What! could ye not watch with me one hour ? Watch and pray, that ye enter not into
                            temptation." Then, as if touched with pity for their weak- ness, and in seeming extenuation of the same, he
                            added, " The spirit indeed is willing, but the flesh is weak." His disciples were not able to appreciate the
                            grand and exalted character of their Lord and Master—their Elder Brother — until they were imbued with his
                            spirit, and were baptized with the same baptism, which also constituted them " sons of God," for none before him
                            had so fathomed the depths of man's loss from God, or felt the bitterness into which his whole being was
                            plunged. He (seemingly) felt the dissolution of every tie when forsaken by his disciples, and, in the moment of
                            his supreme anguish, he cried, "My God, why hast thou forsaken me!" What a world of agony was contained in that
                            soul-thrilling cry, "Eli! Eli! lama sabacJlh,thani! " And did not Mother Ann Lee, who Avas called to prepare
                            herself as a chosen vessel for the reception of Christ Spirit in his second advent, drink of the same bitter
                            cup, even to its dregs ? and by her crucifixion to the world with all its affections and lusts, become imbued
                            with that Divine Unction from on High which prepared her to co-operate with Christ Jesus in resurrecting souls
                            from the earthly order, or generative plane, and bring them forth into the New Creation, or regenerative life ?
                            Verily, there are sons, and daughters too among us who have risen above all carnal ties, earthly affections, and
                            sordid lusts, and can claim a true knowledge of, and relation to, this heavenly parentage. And, who can feel
                            more grateful, or better appreciate, the advent and mission of the Mother Spirit, than her daughters, who are so
                            abundantly receiving benefits therefrom ? Then, let us not be content to remain inactive and unfruitful; but be
                            quickened to the angel life, by tasting the powers of the world to come ; that we, by travel of soul and
                            tribulation of spirit, may become " fruitful vines, mothers in Israel," which our Heavenly Father and Mother
                            (God) can bless. For, if faithful to the high and holy trust committed to our keeping, we can with confidence,
                            lift our souls in prayer, asking Heaven's protection, and claiming the promise that, " Whatsoever ye ask in
                            prayer, believing, ye shall receive." Although more than eighteen hundred years have elapsed since that precious
                            promise was given, it is still full of inspiring hope. And who, but those who have wrestled with the strong
                            worldly elements inherent in every human heart knows the intrinsic value of those living words, still fragrant
                            with his tender love to erring man, " Watch and pray, that ye enter not into temptation." Oft-times in spirit,
                            do we catch the echo of that wise injunction, which comes floating on the breeze like the whisperings of some
                            winged messenger of peace from the garden of Gethmeane, " Take heed. Watch! What I say unto you, I say unto all,
                            Watch ! " Brief yet comprehensive is the exhortation. It furnishes an instructive theme from which profitable
                            sermons might be evolved.— Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Hingham, Massachusetts, January 12, 1873" TEIform="index"/>South Hingham, Mass. Jan. 12, 1873</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Friend: In the afternoon of this beautiful day, I find myself alone, or with no visi- ble companion at
                            least, and am thinking how many things I have to be thankful for. Your little paper for January in its new dress
                            is before me. I have read and re-read, and am very thankful that it still lives and goes forth to the world to
                            teach and help truth-seekers. It is a welcome visitor here, and I am happy in its perusal, and always receive
                            strength and inspiration as I read. I write in haste and inclose fifty cents for the paper. Long may it
                            continue. Yours for truth,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., M. D." TEIform="persName"/>M. D. B.</byline></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="He is truly a man who is in full enterprise..." TEIform="index"/>He is truly a man who is in full enterprise...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">He is truly a man who is in full enterprise ; who is perpetually planning new works; who is constantly acquiring
                            new thoughts ; who is all the time opening new chambers; who is every day furnishing the rooms of his mind with
                            new pictures and new furniture ; who is incessantly spreading for himself a new table with noble aspirations and
                            endeavors, as the sign of soul life. Every man who really lives is living by a generous use of the future. —
                            Beecher.</p></div2><pb n="30" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dialogue" TEIform="index"/>DIALOGUE THE GOSPEL WORK — ITS PRESENT AND FUTURE INCREASE</head><byline TEIform="byline">BY <persName reg="Pattison, Margaret; Offordd, Ann; Anderson, Martha; Byrdsall, Charlotte; Soule, Melissa;                                 and Cleveland, Margaret" TEIform="persName"/> Margaret Pattison Charlotte Byrdsall Ann Offord Melissa Soule Martha Anderson
                            Margaret Cleveland</byline><p TEIform="p">Mar. P.— Certainly. Can we not see from this, that the branches of the tree of life " whose leaves shall be for
                            the healing of the nations," have spread, and that beneath it many souls have found a pleasant and safe retreat;
                            thus fulfilling ancient prophecy ? Ann. — As was remarked, the testimony of Christ's Second Appearing, through
                            the female, was a revival of primitive Christianity, with increased revelation; for that in itself was not
                            complete. There was room left for a great increase of faith and works relating to the physical, moral, and
                            spiritual condition of mankind. Nor did those who laid the foundation of the Second Christian Church complete
                            the structure. It was not given to Mother Ann to gather the people into Gospel order; during her ministry, they
                            were scattered abroad in valleys and on the hill-tops. Martha. — Great wisdom and care were requisite on the
                            part of those commissioned to gather the people into an organized body, to establish laws and regulations which
                            would countenance a progressive, physical, mental and spiritual growth, and yet be for the pro- tection of the
                            Society. Mel. — Our ideas of progress would not lead xis to discard true foundational principles, but to build
                            upon and expand them. This may be the criterion by which we can judge the worth of any progressive movement, if
                            it does not deteriorate the pure spiritual life of the community. Many, in haste for onward advancement, would
                            introduce reformatory ideas and changes, without regard to the time or state of preparation for receiving them,
                            and by thus doing, would retard the progress of the work. Mar. C.—This is but the dawn of the Millennium. The
                            spiritual faith of this life leads to a consecration in all things. Self-denial opens the door of revelation.
                            What an amount of inspirational strength actuated those who lived in their little families, to give up all for
                            the future glory of Gospel communistic life. Self-sacrificing devotion was their inducement. Char. — The past is
                            sacred on account of the holy life and strength of Gospel parents. The beautiful and true have attended the
                            Gospel work in its varied stages of progress. Our unprogressed conditions open wide fields of labor wherein we
                            may toil, and, like our predecessors, gain treasures of worth to impart to others. In former times,
                            comparatively little attention was given to physiology ; but now the light of the present reveals many
                            physiological errors previously adhered to, which we hope to have sufficient honesty of purpose, and firmness of
                            mind to leave for something better. Mar. P.—Greater attention is now given to air ; for we acknowledge the fact,
                            that we live by breathing ; and the pure atmosphere is essential for this purpose. It is a satisfaction to
                            glance at our well-ventilated dwelling, where we see space in the base-boards, and apertures over all the doors
                            for the admission of air ; while the self-acting Archimedian ventilators on the roof, create a strong draft and
                            dispose of any vitiated air that might otherwise remain in our dwelling. Even with closed doors and windows, the
                            atmosphere is still good and wholesome. Ann. — In addition, we can range the verdant fields for pleasure, or
                            otherwise enjoy the sunshine and genial summer air, with no fear or thought of persecution ; but with a calm and
                            holy feeling of inspiring life, we behold with joy and a spirit of blessing, the consecrated labors of our good
                            and worthy brethren. Martha. — It is pleasant to gather the fruits of earth. They supply the place of animal
                            food in a great measure ; for very little of it is now required for our table. Swine's flesh has long been
                            abolished, with other things, in the preparation of food, such as soda, salaratus, etc. Brown bread almost
                            supplies the place of white, while our well-cultivated gardens, golden grain fields, and thrifty fruit orchards
                            yield an abundant supply for physical health and comfort. Ann.—It has been asserted that " a vegetable diet has
                            a happifying influence on the mind, and tends to preserve a delicacy of feeling, liveliness of imagination, and
                            acuteness of judgment, seldom enjoyed by those who live too much on animal food." Franklin said that " a
                            vegetable diet promoted clearness of ideas, quickness of thought, and stability of action." He spoke from
                            experience ; for his superior reason early led him to adopt a simple style of living. Mel.—Tobacco was formerly
                            used to quite an extent among us, but was considered useless and injurious. Some who had formed a habit of
                            smoking, and had not strength, of themselves, to change, were assisted by spirits from the unseen world. Their
                            love to the truth was strong, and their desire to increase with the work of God enabled them to make the
                            sacrifice, which proved a blessing to them individually, and to the whole body. A spirit of self sacrifice, in
                            regard to perverted ways and habits, is what the present generation need to possess. It should ever be our
                            effort to simplify our needs, and curb our appetites, and thus bring ourselves to the condition of the
                            philosopher, whose habitual prayer was, " O ye gods ! grant me to have few things, and to stand in need of
                            none." Mar. P.—I should be pleased to know who he was. Martha.—Apollonius. He was born four years before Jesus
                            of Nazareth, belonged to a wealthy Grecian family, and, though reared in the lap of affluence and ease, he early
                            discarded all forms of luxury, donned the garb and habits of a Pythagorean philosopher, lived on fruit and
                            vegetables, drank water only, and chose a celibate life as being best adapted to philosophic and ethical
                            pursuits. He was endowed with remarkable mental powers and spiritual gifts, which, combined with a welldeveloped
                            and perfect physique, gave him a marked character. He was successful as a teacher of a rational system of
                            morality and virtue. Mar. C.—" The moral and intellectual status of man is grounded in the material;" hence
                            those things which pertain to the health and perfection of the physical body, are of great importance to
                            humanity. There can be no high spiritual life sustained here on earth, except in connection with habits of wise
                            bodily discipline—a truth yet to be recognized by many. Char.— While we view the increase of truth in the past
                            in those particular points of which you have been speaking, we also behold the present growth in virtue and
                            goodness. Truly those who plead for a broader platform, and complain of but little progression, are more than
                            spiritually blind. Such evince their unfaithfulness to present light, a non-con- formity to united spiritual and
                            physical increase. Mar. P.—There is ever a beauty and glory manifest in the Gospel work, to those who abide in
                            its spirit of heavenly life and love. Shakers, or Believers, are becoming better known in the outside world ;
                            the purity of their lives is not questioned by those who are rightly informed ; while their character for
                            integrity and truth is well established, especially with the more intellectual and spiritually-minded. Ann. —
                            The witnesses of God in the past fell from their rectitude, and lost their spiritual power through the
                            friendship of the world. Through this medium, worldly attractions became strong. We are in danger from this
                            source. It is an easy thing to turn light into darkness ; and there is greater danger of being allured and drawn
                            away from true faith by the friendships of the world, than by its persecutions. But, if members fail, virtue's
                            strongholds are still reliable; seceders take no strength from the body; God's work remains the same, and will
                            endure through eternal ages. Martha. — Human nature is everywhere the same. In all ages it has had the same
                            wants and aspirations, and has been subject to the same infirmities. As you remarked, a declension of members is
                            not a declension of truth; but all, if they would advance with the body, must be united and keep pace with
                            increasing revelation. Order and harmony are sure guides. Mel.— There is greater strength and beauty in the
                            Temple when the weak and unreliable pass away. The cause of righteousness and self-denial never presented
                            loftier themes for thought and practice than at present. Mar. C. — This is a day of individual trial. The
                            foundations of our faith are being tried. The everlasting Spirit of Goodness searches the heart, and tries the
                            actions, to prove what principles we are actuated by. Mel. — The world may question our integrity ; and many
                            inquire, Why cannot you live as purely, with your faith, outside of your com munity ? But the Holy Spirit's call
                            is, " Come up higher, above, away from earth." The work of to-day is to aggregate souls into a heavenly union,
                            to form a body for honest souls to gather to; a true type of angelhood in the heavenly spheres. Ann. — There
                            must be an Order above and in advance of the world, to govern and regulate, or set in order those who forsake
                            it. The spiritual is for that purpose. The present condition of society is no cause of discourage- ment. The
                            future cannot be determined by the present. Like life, society grows from a principle divinely implanted; it is
                            progressing, bringing the world and its attractions to an ultimate. It is true there is not much increase of
                            members to our Church at present. That <pb n="31" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> SHAKEKESS. 31 is because of the lack of the
                            religious element without; yet many (by degrees) are ripening up to the Gospel work, which is the harvest; and,
                            ere long, a revival of religious and practical truth will occur; then, " where the body of Christ is, thither
                            will the eagles be gathered together." Mar. P. — Our Father and Mother have prepared a home, and are now calling
                            their children to partake of the spiritual feast of goodness and love. For there are noble minds, to-day,
                            endowed with power, and an understanding of truth, who are disseminating the seed of Christianity, educating
                            souls for the Gospel. For, "what education is for one man or woman, revelation is for the whole human race."
                            Ann.— Margaret, I listened almost breathless to your last sentence, knowing that the original writer did not
                            include the woman, and you are aware that it is a day of woman's rights, a subject upon which I am greatly
                            interested ; for we know she is of more worth than to be a mere instrument of worldly pleasure. We see in our
                            Zion-home women of strength and virtue, whose consecrated powers adorn and beautify the Temple of God. Mel.— The
                            acknowledgment of the Mother Spirit in Deity is one grand step towards this ultimate. All who have progressed
                            away from old contracted theological views, can see and appreciate the true worth of woman. Mar. C. — How
                            beautiful is the social relation formed between the male and female among Believers, where the inferior passions
                            are kept in subordination to higher law! How true the manifestation of love in the sphere of daily duties, where
                            the claims of both brethren and sisters are regarded with equal respect ; and, as co-workers in a noble cause,
                            each unselfishly toils for the good of the whole. Char. — This social and religious harmony is not only
                            beneficial to us, but to mankind in general. It is seed sown that will bear fruit in the good time coming, but
                            is sustained only through individual personal " sacrifice of selfishness, and an expansion in the elements of
                            universal love and true philanthropy." While listening to your comments upon woman, I thought how beautifully
                            Eldress Antionette was inspired (in " Past, Present and Future ") to speak of the elevation of woman from
                            physical, moral and spiritual servitude. I know such truths will rest with weight upon minds who are exercised
                            in this direction. Ann. — I read and re-read the article with pleasure. Such truthful expressions are like sunny
                            rays of hope illuminating the future. The love and union formed by kindred souls, who have commenced the work of
                            regeneration, by being baptised into purity of heart and life, is the strongest of all bonds with which to hold
                            soul to soul. It is unchanging through all conditions, and incites to constancy and truthfulness one with
                            another. We intuitively repose confidence in a relation thus formed, as when we pray we instinctively direct our
                            intercessions to God; there our confidence is placed. On the same principle we rely upon our faithful brethren
                            and sisters, and trust their fidelity. Mar. P. — This is the advantage which is only to be derived from a
                            spiritual communistic life. We see verified, in our association, the saying of Jesus," Think not of the morrow,
                            what ye shall eat, drink, or wear," because, in our associated capacity, there are many who are interested in
                            bearing the burdens of life; and the orderly arrangement of spiritual and temporal leaders is a great blessing;
                            it relieves us of much anxious care and thought respecting food, clothing and other things necessary for
                            physical comfort and support. And, by first seeking the spiritual part (the righteousness of Christ's kingdom),
                            all other needful things are added. Martha. — Henry Vincent remarked that " Christianity levels all
                            distinctions, save goodness ; it is the grand elevator of the human race!" And, we might add, where its true
                            spirit is maintained, it dignifies toil, and transforms what is commonly deemed the drudgery of life into
                            pleasant occupation, where right — not might — is the rule ; because labor is equalized according to
                            qualification of membership, and ability to perform it. Mar. C. — Persons who visit our communities, not
                            comprehending the true principles upon which the Institution is based, often inquire as to the number of hours
                            we labor; but we are not, for sordid interest, toiling with restriction. Duty is pleasant to us, we are in our
                            own home ; when more is to be done, then gladly we give more effort; when not so much, then less is required. We
                            are not under task-masters, but are influenced by love and mutual friendship to one another, devoting our
                            strength for the good of a noble and glorious cause. Mel. — One, speaking of consecrated toil, said, " Prefer
                            duty to diversion. He who is false to present duty, breaks a thread in the loom, and will find the flaws when he
                            has forgotten the cause." Char.—Order and discipline are the guardians of our home. If irksome to some, it is
                            because they are not in the life and spirit that pervade it. Some are baptised into a gospel of ideas, but not
                            into the Gospel of Love, which will produce practical works; they receive faith intellectually, while their
                            souls are untouched by the living inspiration and consecration which permeate the body of Christ. Ann. — The
                            more practical religion is, the better I like it. It is effectual for good, when it is carried into all the
                            essential duties of life, instigating the spirit of industry, in making good roads, constructing fences,
                            cultivating the soil properly, preparing of food, clothing, &amp;c. such as Christians can use and not
                            abuse, marking all our labor with neatness, thoroughness and order. Here is a large field for useful thought. In
                            this we find the most effective poetry, —" a poem from the fingers ends," and beautiful pictures to look upon ;
                            and " a picture is a poem without words." Mar. P. — When I came among Believers I admired the order and
                            practical utility of external things. This I perceived was the result of an interior spiritual life ; and, in
                            the ardor of my soul, I thanked God that I had found a people who were not stereotyped in their religious belief
                            ; but who, in the progress of spirituality could change their theological views. Mar. C. — Then, a distinction
                            is made between theology and religion 1 Mel. — Certainly. Theology is but the science of religion, while
                            religion is the germ of eternal life, which may be found in every human heart. Henry Ward Beecher says, " The
                            way to begin a Christian life is not to study theology. Piety before theology. Right living will produce right
                            thinking." Mar. C. — The cultivation of this germ has produced the increase of the past and present. And, in the
                            liberal exercise of our faith, we are unbiased by worldly conservatism, believing that this Church will
                            eventually be the receptacle of every good, whether it be from Judaism, Catholicism, Protestantism, or
                            Mahomedanism, for we claim that all sects contain some truth. Ann. — It will also be the conservatory of
                            science; for all truth centers in God. Mel. — Our minds should be open to the acceptance of scientific truth;
                            although it should come in contact with preconceived ideas, grounded in the mind, and forming a stronghold of
                            individual experience. Our theology should correspond with science, or it is liable to be overthrown. It is a
                            day of reason and investigation ; the foundation of all systems is being tested. Martha. — I rejoice that the
                            time is approaching when the voice of woman will be heard in governmental affairs ; when she shall help to enact
                            laws that will bind Justice and Love in one inseparable band; uplifting her sex from the thraldom of sensual and
                            sexual sinfulness, into the untrammeled freedom of personal rights and privileges, such as man enjoys. Then
                            shall a purer and more refining influence pervade the council-halls of the nation, and a new epoch in civil
                            history will hold a corresponding relation to the spiritual order under which we exist. Mar. C. — The Spirit of
                            Divine Wisdom which regulated this infant church, stands as a balance between reformation and conservatism; and
                            from the growth of the past we may judge of a greater increase in the future. " As souls advance their ideas
                            expand. Progress is an eternal law. The ideal beckoning the real to come up higher, there will ever be loftier,
                            diviner attitudes to ascend." Char. — The angelic voice of Truth has rolled in majesty through all periods. The
                            laws of improvement bear each tone higher and still higher up the scale of holiness. The music of the sinless
                            Angel of Love shall echo over hill and dale, over sea and land, until, in its glorious chorus, all nations shall
                            blend, and the home of Virtue and Truth, that is increasing, shall begin its life in all, while the altar of
                            holy resurrection shall be lighted in grandeur with hallowed and varied offerings of souls from every clime. No
                            longer will one toil in pain while another revels in luxury, for the soil and fruitage of earth shall be free,
                            while over the homes of all will hover the heavenly dove of Peace. Mar. P.— True love principles, gleaming in
                            their divinity far and wide, will vitalize and draw many souls to Zion, where they will be planted as trees by
                            the sides of living waters, growing in strength and beauty until they become as cedars of Lebanon. Then will
                            they joyfully sing the "Song of the Lamb" with those who stand upon Mount Zion. Martka — Joy we feel in thus
                            reviewing What the march of Truth has wrought, And, while present light pursuing, Claim the strength through
                            increase brought. Hopes for future bright are glowing, Love with wisdom interblends, Seed celestial they are
                            sowing Of a life that never ends. Faith, endowed with gift immortal, Lifts the veil from spirit sight, Ope's the
                            gates to love's bright portal, Leads the soul in wisdom's light; Pierces through the mists of morning, And
                            discloses to our view Grace and Truth the home adorning, Where all things are form'd anew.</p></div2><pb n="32" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Music sung in connection with the dialogue" TEIform="index"/>MUSIC SUNG IN CONNECTION WITH THE DIALOGUE:.</head><p TEIform="p">1. Praise, rejoicing and thanks-giving, Is the glory 2. May the joy our feelings cherish, Thrill a chord in of
                            our song! While the angels from above us, "Waft the blessed strain ev'ry heart! While the secret streams
                            out-flowing, Shall an answer true along; impart; 'Tis for promised joys unmeasured, And we call on all to
                            join us For delights that In our joyous ne'er will wane, For the rapture festive song! While the waves of pure
                            before us, And the hope for holy gain, life dance merry, And the heart is glad and strong I Chorus, con
                            spirito. We will swell the gladsome chorus, Till bright hosts around us throng, And with harps of sweetest music, Join our universal song. Yea we'll swell the gladsome chorus, Full, unbroken, rich and strong; Till
                            It floats and floats around us, This our universal song.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scripture of truth" TEIform="index"/>"SCRIPTURE OF TRUTH."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, O. C." TEIform="persName"/>(O. C Hampton.)</byline><p TEIform="p">While wandering alone o'er the bleak hills of sorrow, And sadly exploring the regions of earth, The present all
                            gloom, with a darker tomorrow, An alien to comfort, a stranger to mirth, Before me arose a magnificent Temple,
                            Whose windows were brilliant with rainbows of light, Whose beautiful mansions were airy and ample, With glory
                            supernal enravish'd my sight. This Temple was built at the foot of a mountain (The mountain of Arrogance, such
                            it was called) Where long I had wander'd in search of a fountain, O'er crags of despair round its summit so
                            bald. The Fountain Eternal of all consolation — The Well of Salvation — I journey'd to find, Whose river so
                            clear thro' the calm habitation Of Holiness, ever continued to wind. At length a grand Temple, that stood in the
                            valley, Attracted my eye with its beautiful sheen : I thought, if the vale with its beauty would tally, Nor
                            painter nor poet could pencil the scene. In haste I repair'd to this exquisite Temple, More costly by far than
                            the Temple of old; Its plan of construction, tho' sacredly simple, In aspect sublime was romantic and bold. And
                            in that low valley meander'd a river, With calm flowing waters and music serene, Which still keeps in majesty
                            rolling for ever, The sweet-smelling woods in perennial green. And here was the Fountain of blessing fraternal
                            Whose Lethean waters all sorrows remove, And, tho' cycles are gone, yet the flowers are vernal, That bloom on
                            its banks in the garden of Love. And in this vast Temple the poets and sages, The Prophets and Saviors for all
                            the lost world, Whose wisdom and virtue (in bright glowing pages, As rivers of life, through the nations have
                            purl'd) And soul aspirations, in love are recorded : They have written their lives in the books of the Palm,
                            Have finished their race, have been amply rewarded, And left us their story in song and in psalm Their heavenly
                            oracles — rapt inspirations — In unfading splendor, are there to be found Their joys and their sorrows, and
                            final salva tion, In " Scriptures of Truth" in profusion abound. How oft have I open'd the doors of this Temple,
                            To search out its oracles hidden therein, That, in sore affliction, would show some example Of sweet resignation
                            in dark sunless scenes. As those who had travel'd in sorrow before me, And left me their holy Evangel to trace,
                            In patience to wait when the shadows are o'er me, And how to rejoice when abounding in grace. When doubts and
                            uncertainty thicken around me And darken my path with the shade of their wings, I enter this Temple: What light
                            is around me! What promises holy ! What heavenly things! When gloomy forebodings, or malice, or anger, Are
                            brewing afar in my horizon dark, I haste my escape from this region of danger, I hide in this Temple, I rest in
                            this Ark. In many sore trials and weary temptations, This Temple enchanted has furnished relief, And thro' the
                            long past it has lighted the nations, In their bright day of joy, and their dark day of grief. Long, long live
                            this Temple ! the structure of Ages, Long let me recline in its shadow serene; Long let me converse with the
                            saints and the Who've lived out their day, and have passed from earth scene. The Good of all times, in their
                            travail and trial, In unison striving the same race to run, Abounding in patience and stern self-denial, To
                            press for the glories they fought for and won. 0, thanks unto God, who in mercy provided This beautiful Temple
                            such records to hold, Where pencils of sweet inspiration have glided And faithfully painted " the doings of
                            old." Then, long live the Archives of Saints and their sorrow, Their triumphs in grief and assurance in doubt
                            Until the Great Day, which will know no tomorrow ; Let the light of the " Watch-towers" nevei go out. Dan. x;
                            20, 21: " Knowest thou wherefore I come unto thee ? and now will I return to fight with the prince of Persia :
                            and when I am gone forth, lo, the prince of Grecia shall come." " I will show thee that which is noted in the
                            scripture of truth; and there is none that holdeth with me in these things but Michael your prince." From which
                            it appears that the " Scripture of Truth" existed, and was studied in the Spirit World, long before the modern
                            Bibles — Jewish, Catholic, Greek or Protestant — were made up. Indeed, they are not yet completed, as in England
                            a commission is now revising the " Holy Scriptures" — the Protesting Bible. As Rabbi Wise says, " the happiness
                            of man depends on no Creed and no Book ; it depends on the dominion of truth, which is the Redeemer and Saviour,
                            the Messiah, and the King of Glory." The belief in a creative God. is inferred from design in creation, and
                            though there are difficulties the other way, reason triumphs in the proofs, and faith overcomes the
                            difficulties.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Snow storm" TEIform="index"/>THE SNOW STORM</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Whitcher, Mary" TEIform="persName"/>(Mary Whitcher.)</byline><p TEIform="p">What kindness of our Father, To spread a mantle o'er All dark and ugly features, Which face of nature bore! All
                            draped in lily whiteness, The rocks and mountains' side; Alike the vales and hill-tops :— Thus would our Maker
                            hide Our darkest wrongs with whiteness, Our weakness and our sin, If we beneath the covering Of Mercy would come
                            in. This is the Lord's pavilion ; It covers all below; As doth the rain and sunshine, So doth the mantling snow.
                            O when shall we consider What God for us hath done; And in that loving kindness Deal kindly with each o»e ?
                            Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Flattering titles" TEIform="index"/>FLATTERING TITLES</head><p TEIform="p">As Mr. Mrs. Sir, Lady, &amp;c. are inadmissible with us, please write your full Christian names, which will
                            determine whether the Writer is male or female. THE SHAKER. Bound copies of "The Shaker," vols. 1 and 2, will be
                            sent, postpaid, for two dollars and fifty cents, and a Contents added.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>OBITUARY</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Fitts, Eliza" TEIform="index"/>Eldress Eliza Fitts
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Fitts, Eliza" TEIform="persName">Eldress Eliza Fitts</persName>, Canterbury, N. H., Feb. 14th, aged 55.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Munson, Abigail" TEIform="index"/>Abigail Munson
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Munson, Abigail" TEIform="persName">Abigail Munson</persName>, Mt. Lebanon, March 1st, aged 101 years, 11 months
                                and 12 days.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Scott, Sylvia" TEIform="index"/>Sylvia Scott
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Scott, Sylvia" TEIform="persName">Sylvia Scott</persName>, Union Village, O. aged 74.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Amphlet, James" TEIform="index"/>James Amphlet
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Amphlet, James" TEIform="persName">James Amphlet</persName>, Union Village, O. aged 64.</p></div3></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>