<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2611" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">20</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">East Canterbury, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">11</biblScope><date value="18961101" TEIform="date">November 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">169-184</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="11" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
<pb id="p1"/>
THE
MANIFESTO
 1896.
A Visit to the
of EAST CANTERBURY,   N. H.
LLOYD H. CHANDLEE.U. S. N
Liberally Illustrated with half tone
pictures of persons and places.
The Village of EAST CANTEEBUKY
is situated in one of the lovliest spots of
JNetv Hampshire, and is high enough to
overlook the surrounding country.
Price,   15 cts.
Address   H. C. Blinn,
East Canterbury, N. H.
BRIEF EXPOSITION
OF TEE
Principles and Regulations
of the
SOCIETY   OF   BELIEVERS.
Price, 10 cts.
AND
SHAKERISM.
A synopsis of Theology of the United   Society  of   Believers   in   Christ's
Second Appearing.    Illustrated.
By Giles B. Avery.
Price,  15 cts.
THE shaker COVENANT
This work sets forth the form of appointment, the qualifications and powers of the
several
ORDERS   OF   OFFICERS
in the Community : of the
PRIVILEGES and OBLIGATIONS
of all the Members, and of the
DEDICATION    AND     CONSECRATION
of persons and property.
The book will afford interest to all, and at
the same time, afford instruction to all  inquiring minds.    Price 5 cts. each,  postage
paid, or 36 cts. per doz.
NOVEMBER,
BY
<pb n="" id="p2"/>
THJ    MAJNIb'E&TU.
The American Literary Exchange. This
enterprise, recently started in New York, will
interest a vast number of readers. It undertakes to place, at the nominal cost of one cent
to three cents a day, better reading facilities
within reach of every home, anywhere in the
United States, than have heretofore been given by more than a few very large libraries in
the principal citiesin fact, to supply any
proper book published. It does this by means
of a system of exchanges, through Book Clubs
and local Lending Libraries to be located in
every city and village. Obviously one book
at a time is all any one can read ; so if lie can
only exchange that, when read, for another
which be wants, and so on indefinitely, the
whole world of literature is open to any one.
And why not, if a medium of exchange between readers is offered, since the cost of
wear, and the cost of transportation, in large
quantity, are both trifling matters? Those
who want further information, and those who
would like to promote such a work by organ
izing clubs or acting as local agents, can bave
particulars free by addressing The American
Literary Exchange, John B. Alden Manager,
10 and 12 Vandewater St., New York. Books
are loaned, sold or exchanged. A large catalogue will be sent for two cents postage.
Ignace Padebewski has written a new minuet for the piano, which he has dedicated to
his American admirers and given the signifi
cant name of Menuet Modern." He regards
the new composition as his bent, and believes
that it will meet with greater popular favor
than his "Menuet a L'Antique," written in
1883, of which over seven million copies were
sold in a single year. It is the first minuet written by Paderewski since "L'Antique," and was
composed by the famous pianist expressly
for The Ladies'' Home Journal, and will appear
in the October issue.
Humanity, for October is an interesting
number. Humanity and the Jew, is a lesson for the people now on earth, and will have
many careful readers. Carlyle and Modern
Democracy; An Unpublished Poem; Window Pictures and Humanity are all good,
but Honest Jo in Politicswill no doubt be the
experience of a large class of men who are
marching to the polls. Published at Kansas
City, Mo.   Price 50 cents a year.
The Outlook for September, is an illustrated number of this beautiful magazine. The
Spectator on the Great Lakes, is beautifully
descriptive of that part of the country, and
the illustrations make it much more interesting.
A very nicely printed portrait of John H.
Vincent. The founder of the Chautauqua
Movement, stand at the head of an article
written by Win. R. Harper D. D.   This valuable article is liberally illustrated and introduces us to the home of Bishop Vincent and
into his study and parlor, without even the
necessity of a guide.
The artist has also given to us the Recitation
Hall, tlie landing Pier, the Hall in the Grove,
and the Tent College at Chautauqua.
The Rural Church of England, by J. Cleveland Cady takes us on a very pleasant journey
and interests us not only with his written
word hut presents a line picturo of the church
of which he writes.
A visit to Mr. Barrie's mother is from the
pen of Ellen P. Cunningham, five illustrations
accompany the article.
The Children in the Public Library; by John
C. Dana will interest many readers in its care
of the children and in its illustrations.
Basket Ball at Smith College; by Elizabeth
F. Read, is an illustrated article in which
those who arc young will take special interest.
Hydrabad ; by Win. F. Dix, takts us on a
trip to southern India and his illustrations introduce us to those whose costume would
look very singular to the people of the United
States.
A large number of other articles of equal interest may be found in the Outlook, treating a
great variety of subjects. Published by the
Outlook Co. 13 Astor Place, New York.
The Crowning Sin of the Age; by Brevard
D. Sinclair. The Perversion of Marriage, is the
subject under consideration and the author of
this little work has evidently  entered upon
the'work of "fearlessly preaching the truth,"
however others might differ from him in the
illustration.The   writer   says   "It   is  not   a
pleasant task to tear aside the masks which
men  wear, and expose the rotten leprx>sy of
sin in all of its pestiferous hideousness."   It
seems like a redeeming feature in this grasping age of the world, to have a man made able
by his thought of humanity to speak words of
warning to the ignorant and no less to the
willful   transgressor   of  God's laws to man.
The  author of the  work before us, does not
hesitate to enter the church with his prophetic testimony  while   manifesting the  same
degree of zeal as he would in the home of the
Infidel or non-professor, and  says   to   every
one    that   God     "will   visit    the    iniquities
of the fathers upon the children down to the
third and fourth generations."   The Crowning
sin of the Age" should be read by every one
who has an  interest in  God's laws to man or
an interest in the peace and prosperity of the
family of man.
Published by H. L. Hastings, 47 Cornhill,
Boston, Mass.
The Phrenological Journal and Science
of Health for Oct., presents a beautiful likeness of Prof. L.N. Fowler, who was laid to rest
on the fifth of September.
Then follows the fourth article on Phrenology and Psychology, by John W. Shall.
Phrenotypes and side vi.ews is very inter--><pb n="169" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remarks of mother Lucy Wright, no. 3" TEIform="index"/>REMARKS OF MOTHER LUCY WRIGHT. NO.
                            3.</head><p TEIform="p">MOTHER LUCY exhorted us to a greater degree of thankfulness. "We certainly have great cause
                            to be thankful above all creatures, and are accountable to God for these blessings we enjoy.
                            If we are unthankful for our daily and abundant blessings, we are not followers of Christ.
                            The spiritual and temporal blessings which we enjoy are the gifts of Heaven to us, we can
                            not call one of them our own and we are not certain of them from day to day." "Those things
                            which the earth brings forth are of the earth, and will yet return to its own. We can not
                            make one plant grow though we sow with great care; it is God who giveth the increase." "It
                            is our duty to humble ourselves in the sight of God, that our judgment may be taken away.
                            Let the soul seek God's mercy in humiliation before it is too late, and while we may be
                            heard ; if we are not humble and cry to God in our need, we may yet cry and not be heard. If
                            we trust to our great privilege and experience, we trust in something which will fail us.
                            Remember a haughty spirit goeth before a fall." "I hope we shall not be unthankful in the
                            midst of plenty, with a fullness of spiritual and temporal blessings on every hand." 'Many
                            precious promises are given to the faithful. Some, being darkened, think that the gospel is
                            not sufficient to save them. The gospel is not at fault, it is sufficient to save every soul
                            that will obey it. If we obtain the precious bless ngs that are promised to the willing and
                            obedient, we must NOVEMBER, <pb n="170" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> 170 THE MANIFESTO. gain them. We make our
                            heaven. All who are true will realize the blessing of God. God forbid that we glory, save in
                            the cross of Christ." "We must be what we profess to be, and profess to be what we really
                            are. Do not glory in a profession for it will not save you. We shall appear just what we are
                            when we enter eternity." Mother Lucy seemed to feel great anxiety for the children. She
                            would often speak of the great responsibility their guardians were under to care for their
                            daily welfare, their protection; the example before them, the language used to them; all
                            this should be the burden of those who care for them She would speak particularly to the
                            children and youth, saying, "You are young; your youth is the best and easiest time for you
                            to learn to serve God. I wish you could realize this. I pray for you often for I feel the
                            burden of your salvation, and desire you to live a life of uprightness. Those who are called
                            by the good Spirit in their youth should often return thanks to God that they are thus
                            noticed of their heavenly Father. If you do not want to do wrong, then you will do right,
                            for the master we love, we serve." "The gospel requires no more than is just, and you must
                            part with all that is contrary to its requirements. 1 do believe that every one who can
                            sense it will be thankful that they have found the blessing of God that will separate them
                            from all evil and make them acceptable before God. Love begets love. I have that love for
                            poor, lost souls that I would suffer in their stead, if this were possible. If we love the
                            gospel we shall obey it, and if we truly love God we shall serve Him." "Of all people we are
                            the most noticed of God. Shall the children of this world be before us, and appoint a day of
                            thanksgiving, and we not be able to keep it in thanksgiving? Nay, let us_keep it to God's
                            acceptance. We can do this in truth." June 11, 1820. Mother exhorted us to be spiritually
                            minded. "All who have an understanding should labor for their own spiritual food, and pray
                            for the gifts of God in their own souls. The young need to be helped, and I am able and
                            willing to bear a great deal with and for them. Yea, I am willing that they should have a
                            part of my bread, if they will be good." "I love the blessed spirit of the gifts of God.
                            They are our support day by day, and without them we should suffer hunger and have no
                            treasure in heaven." (To be continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Why am I a shaker?" TEIform="index"/>WHY AM I A SHAKER?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hollister, Alonzo G." TEIform="persName"/>By Alonzo G. Hollister.</byline><p TEIform="p">BECAUSE first, my parents placed me with Believers in Christ's Second Appearing, at that
                            tender age when the mind as readily receives good, as under other conditions it would
                            receive evil. <pb n="171" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 171 Second, because what Believers taught
                            me of the practical duties of life, accorded so perfectly with what I had received from my
                            mother, that when I came to reflect upon it, I saw that mother had formed the soil in me
                            that was ready prepared to receive our gospel teaching. Third, because I could feel a
                            comfortable conscience in obeying the teaching imparted, and was troubled and harassed if I
                            did not. Fourth, because when I came to years of understanding, and the allurements of the
                            world and its freedoms appealed to me in their strongest attractions for the youthful
                            imagination, I regarded the prizes of a life that was to be eternal, too great, and the
                            chance of securing them too hazardous for me to decide what to exchange it for without
                            knowledge. For what will it profit a man if he gain the whole world and lose his own life,
                            or soul which alone enjoys the world. Or why give the freest and freshest part of one's life
                            for a song,or for transcient joys that dance for a while like bubbles on the water, and then
                            vanish into nothingness, leaving the soul a barren, deserted waste. Would such a life be
                            free from those pleasures which leave the sting of death behind, to be withdrawn only by
                            repentance in anguish, bitter reflection and sorrow. I turned to the Source of Being, to the
                            Fountain of all Intelligence and Wisdom and asked for knowledge. I paid the price fixed, in
                            self-denials, in prayer and watching, in obedience to light as fast as received, and
                            knowledge was given me, that the best and richest purchase for which life could be given,
                            was to be gained by obedience to the gospel of Christ in Mother, as taught and delivered to
                            us by the faithful sucessors of Jesus and of Mother Ann. It was given me to know that this
                            purchase joins its possessor in spiritual communism and relationship to the mighty host of
                            prophets and martyrs, who have given their lives for the truth in all ages, whose toils for
                            the emancipation of the human mind from error, and whose sufferings for the uplifting of the
                            race from animalism and savagery, even to the laying down of their lives, have prepared the
                            way for the blessings we now enjoy. They sowed the seed, from which we reap the harvest of
                            civil and religious liberty, and other blessings. To become a living temple of purity, into
                            which the holy spirit of the eternal heavens might descend and flow forth for spiritual
                            health and cure. Jno. vii., 38, 39. I was willing to sacrifice every earthly tie and
                            selfpleasing allurement of the world, and with all the ardor I possessed, enter the
                            crucibles of the Refiner and stay there till purification was accomplished. Forty-five years
                            I have labored to practice this knowledge and add thereto, and I have not been deceived in
                            one iota thereof. I have a satisfactory possession in exchange for the life given,
                            increasing like a sum at compound interest, or like a growing crop of fruit. The fruits of
                            obedience, have been love, joy, peace, quietness, a justified conscience, assurance of
                            victory, and of life everlasting. <pb n="172" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 172 THE MANIFESTO. Some will ask,
                            could not the same be accomplished in some other way or without sacrificing so much. Is not
                            some one of the other hundred ways claiming to lead to the highest goal equally safe? The
                            answer is. Strait is the gate and narrow is the way that leadeth unto life, and few there be
                            that find it. I am the way, says the anointed Jesus, and the anointed is but one. Whosoever
                            there be of you that forsaketh not all that he hath, he can not be my disciple. He that
                            seeketh to save his life shall lose it. He that hateth his life in this world, shall keep it
                            unto life eternal. Whosoever will or wishes to come after me, let him deny himself and take
                            up his cross daily and follow me. There is but one way and one price for all. If we pay but
                            part of the price, we get but part of the purchase, or may lose the whole, and have to do
                            the work over again. If we pay the whole price, by giving all, we receive an overflowing
                            fulness of the higher, perfect and permanent inheritance, in exchange for the lower,
                            imperfect, harassing, corruptible and transient. To God be all the glory. Mt. Lebanon, N.
                        Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Untried powers" TEIform="index"/>UNTRIED POWERS.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Anderson, Martha J." TEIform="persName"/>By Martha J. Anderson.</byline><p TEIform="p">High soars the bird with undipped wing, Swift moves the steed from rein set free; Far leaps
                            the stag with bound and spring, For love of life and liberty. Thus human minds are fledged
                            for flight, Who feel no curbing of tbe will, And dauntless souls gain crag and height, Yet,
                            greater freedom long for still. Prometheus-like, earth-bound are we While reaching up for
                            heaven's fire, This hope of immortality, Which kindles in us high desire. The vultures of
                            our lower lives. Feed on the soul's vitality; To break its chains the spirit strives, Till
                            boundless Being sets it free. If in the path where virtues dwell, All doubts and
                            fear&amp; we question not, But yield to laws immutable Which hold us to our earth-born
                            lot. <pb n="173" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 173 On time's eventful wheel we move, Our destiny
                            is marked thereon, Through such embodiment we prove That good or ill before have gone. Our
                            joys and sorrows we may count The guerdon merited while here, And every trial we surmount Is
                            progress toward the inner sphere. We slowly climb the golden stair That reaches heaven's
                            starry height, And for Nirvana's rest prepare Through countless eon-days and nights. For
                            living, longing beings we, Environed in these forms of clay, With throbbing hearts, nor
                            souls set free To soar from earthly clods away. We bide perfection's blissful state, When
                            life unfolded will be ours, Nor mourn the just decrees of fate, That holds in check our
                            untried powers. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Promises" TEIform="index"/>PROMISES.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Estabrook, Fidella" TEIform="persName"/>By Fidella Estabrook.</byline><p TEIform="p">A LMOST every page in the Bible contains a promise in one form or an,/v other. If we study
                            closely we will find that each promise is preceded by an obligation. We must do something in
                            order to obtain a reward. Nothing is enjoyed that is not gained by exertion. If one sits
                            with folded hands and receives treasures gained by the labor of others their value is
                            depreciated. So it is in regard to promises; to fully enjoy their benefit, we must first
                            faithfully perform our part of the contract. Even then, the reward is many times greater
                            than the conflict. There seems to be a promise for every individual and each occasion. If
                            they were given the first place in the heart and well engraved upon the mind in times of
                            trial and temptation they would shine through the darkness and many dangers would be
                            averted. It is only when they are hidden from our view by doubts and fears that we become
                            discouraged and forget they are there. Once cast aside this darkness, and diligently search
                            for these gems and we become filled with <pb n="174" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 174 THE MANIFESTO. light; our
                            hearts thrill with love at the unspeakable mercy and tender care manifested by God for his
                            children. They are like a chain ; take the Book and search for all the links that we, in our
                            carelessness, have allowed to slip. Link on link we join them, all the while feeling
                            ourselves drawn nearer and nearer to their Great and AllWise Author till we can almost feel
                            the pressure of his hand. O let us never loosen our hold on this priceless chain. Wind it
                            around us until we are firmly held by it, let not a.link be broken that would bind us to the
                            love of God. Do we feel sorely tempted, we find, "He will not suffer you to be tempted more
                            than ye are able to bear." Again, uThe Lord knoweth how to deliver the godly from
                            temptation." Do we feel that we are sometimes le t alone, let us look through the
                            darkness,there is a gleam of light. As we touch the electric current of this one, numberless
                            other lights begin to shine, and we see, "I will never leave thee comfortless, "I will never
                            leave thee nor forsake thee." "Lo, I am with thee even unto the end of the world." Do we
                            feel sometimes, in the unseen battles of the heart, that our foes are too many for our
                            strength? Brighter than the costliest gems shine the precious promises, "He that overcometh
                            shall inherit all things and I will be his God and he shall be my son." "Be of good cheer, I
                            have overcome the world," and our weakness becomes strength, until we feel, like the
                            prophet, "I will trust and not be afraid." Do we feel sadness because of hopes blighted, or
                            disappointments that have come"Let the heart of them rejoice that seek the Lord." "Rejoice
                            in the Lord alway." For the tired and care-worn we find "Come unto me, and I will give you
                            rest." "My presence shall go with thee and I will give thee rest." Thus we might delve in
                            this mine of treasures much longer, obtaining rich blessing thereby. Let us commence the
                            chapter of ench day's history, by a glance at a promise, thus brightening the whole day, and
                            proving an illumination in the book of life. West Pittsfield, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let there be light" TEIform="index"/>LET THERE BE LIGHT.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>By Hamilton DeGraw.</byline><p TEIform="p">"Thebe's a light that shines on my pathway, A glory in my soul; A star of hope, that bears me
                            on, On to the heavenly goal." The powerful all-conquering forces that are evolving from the
                            interior life of humanity are opening wider the boundaries of that apparently limited realm
                            which is given to human life to explore, constantly enlarging dimen- <pb n="175" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/>
                            THE MANIFESTO. 173 sions. Wnat a few generations ago would have been considered by the
                            masses as impossibilities, the present know as accomplished facts. We many times make
                            assertions that certain ideas are the operation of chimerical minds and can not be produced
                            as actualities of life. And while we have slumbered, some energetic spirit has received a
                            spark of the immortal fire, has penetrated iuto that interior chamber from which comes the
                            inspiration that giveth strength to grapple with the forces of life that before appeared
                            unconquerable; and has entered as an intrepid explorer that field which formerly was marked
                            the unknowable. And by the power of that ministration has removed the barriers that hindered
                            the admission of light, and prepared the way for still greater conquests. Whether it is
                            within the realm of the forces that appear to us to dominate and control our earthly
                            existence, or within the boundaries of our spiritual life the call is for more light. The
                            determination that is manifested to grapple with those subtle forces that apparently are
                            trying to elude the searchlight turned upon them by the advance guard of scientific research
                            is causing us to realize that the dividing line between what we term the material world and
                            the spiritual is more imaginary than real. We say that certain bodies are opaque or
                            impenetrable to light, and others are transparent. In the discovery of their existence, and
                            the development and application to beneficial uses in life of the X rays showing that those
                            subtler forces have penetrated and opened to the sight what before remained hidden. To those
                            individual lives whose spiritual development is yet dormant, the intrusion into what to them
                            appears a mysterious and forbidden realm is fraught with dangers that should be avoided. But
                            to those who have received the divine commission to grapple with those hidden forces, and to
                            illuminate the pathway upward which human life is moving, do not realize the sensation of
                            fear. Some of the so-called scientific minds in their unwillingness to recognize the fact
                            that the dominant object in investigating and developing the interior forces of life should
                            not be confined to the childish play of dealing with effects but to study and understand the
                            underlying causes, have so enshrouded their mental horizon with the mists of dogmatic
                            bigotry causing them to think that the boundaries of their vision is the outer circle of the
                            infinite universe. When the project was first being seriously considered of ocean steam
                            navigation, one of the so-called scientific men of England came forward with the statement
                            based upon what he thought actual knowledge of its power, "that what else could be done with
                            steam its use in ocean navigation was an impossibility." The doubt and uncertainty that
                            formerly existed in the ability of the human soul to understand and use those forces that
                            are so enshrouded in mystery, has given way to the feeling of wonder that they were not
                            understood before. The rapidity with which those thought forces have penetrated hu- <pb n="176" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 176 THE MANIFESTO. man life, causing the development of those
                            wonderful inventions that during the past century have given such mighty power to control
                            the material elements and cause them to become the servants of man instead of his master,
                            has c ased to excite wonder. The question now is, should not the way also be made clear so
                            that the moral and spiritual life could receive its full portion of that light which has so
                            wonderfull}? illuminated the material side? Nothing short of a full presentation of the
                            truth will satisfy the piogivssive soul after it has received a portion of the divine light.
                            The quickening of the moral tone of society on many questions that formerly it was at least
                            indifferent, and insisting that light shall be turned upon the causes that have been
                            productive of the false conditions of life under which it has been living, and demanding
                            their removal, is evidence to prove the fact that darkness is only a negation, that it can
                            not supply that vital force of life which only is able to cause a growth to higher
                            conditions. Above the storms and convulsions which at times assail our globe and cause such
                            great destruction to the material interests of life, are the mighty constellations that for
                            ages have shone with undiminished splendor and sent their light earthward. So, superior and
                            above the upheavals that at times are shaking the religious and political world, is that
                            Divine power which is the source of all light and life, and is using those conditions as a
                            means to clear the avenues through which may come that light which will enable the prophetic
                            prediction to be verified. "I will shake all nations, and the desire of all the nations
                            shall come ; and I will fill this house with glory saith the Lord." Shakers, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tribute of love" TEIform="index"/>A TRIBUTE OF LOVE.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Collins, Sarah A." TEIform="persName"/>By Sarah A. Collins.</byline><p TEIform="p">~T~Y7~E have met at the funeral of a dear brother and of a good centenariVV an, but it seems
                            more like a grand reunion or a genuine love-feast; a love that will abide forever. This is
                            not a sad funeral although we have lost a true friend, a good brother and a kind father. We
                            shall continue to love and revere his name. All were gentle and kind to Father William and
                            we know it is well with him. We may, sometimes, have cloudy days and if it were not so we
                            would not be well tried like silver, and tempered like fine steel. The dews of heaven come
                            for a purpose, and the heart-aches and trials that surround us, if patiently borne, will
                            subdue and soften our lives, "For the lofty looks of man shall be humbled, and the Lord
                            alone shall be exalted." The strong must bear the infirmities of the weak and this was the
                            life work of Brother William. As a well ripened sheaf he has been garnered at an appropriate
                            season of the year for this event. He was a praying man, and <pb n="177" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 177 was never too old to bend the knee. For a long time he has been ready, but
                            not anxious for the change. Although we may love this perishable earth of which we are in
                            part composed, do we love it better than that anticipated part of immortality? If we did not
                            cling to this earth life and all that there is in it, not many of us would greet old age. If
                            we love life and live wisely we will, no doubt, grow old in years. If we go the way of the
                            ungodly, our days will not be long in the land that has been given to us. Our Brother's
                            mission has been fulfilled and many have been benefited by it. Many have visited him in his
                            advanced age and realized of a truth that from his youth up, all these years have been years
                            of fidelity,a loyalty to the cause of his own choosing. "They are passing away those aged
                            and beloved parents who have long stood on the heights of Ziou, messengers of peace and
                            heralds of good tidings, and whose feet will stand on the mount.God's sacred mount in the
                            holy lands." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What is true life?" TEIform="index"/>WHAT IS TRUE LIFE?</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>By Lucy S. Bowers.</byline><p TEIform="p">To eat, to drink and sleep, to tread the mill Of habit day by day with lack of thought, We
                            know is not true life, nor is it wrought By the mere lapse of years, by selfish will, Nor
                            does the strife for gain life's ends fulfill. When earnestly faith's battles all are fought,
                            When in our strife another's good is sought, Then does sweet blessing on the soul distill,
                            The merry laugh that vibrates through the heart, The hopeful prayer that brings the future
                            near, The struggle, yea the tender tears that start, The cares that end in trust, the songs
                            that cheer, These are of true life certainly a part, If thus we live, death brings no gloom
                            or fear. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The hidden force..." TEIform="index"/>The hidden force...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The hidden force that urges us to grander, nobler striving, makes continuous existence
                            possible. It is the pulsating life that holds us to the centre and unites us to the great
                            Over soul from whence we came and whither we are tending through evolutionary processes of
                            development. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Ignorance is ever assuming..." TEIform="index"/>Ignorance is ever assuming...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Ignorance is ever assuming and intolerant, but humility is the best foundation of real
                        worth.</p></div2><pb n="178" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE MANIFESTO. NOVEMBER, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION. The Manifesto is published by the
                            "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month, and is the only work issued
                            regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain and simple statement of the
                            religi )i;s views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of righteousness. Address all
                            communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Her. Co., N. H. TERMS. One copy one year,
                            postage paid. .50</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME.</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Average of Weather at Mt. Lebanon. September. Thermometer. Bain. 1895. 62.89 3.75 in.
                                1896. 59.5 6.5 " Highest Temp, during this mo. 88 above 0 Lowest 77 77 77 17 32 " Number
                                of rainy days 7; " 6 57 77 clear " 77 " 12 77 J&gt; cloudy " 77 7) 12 c. G. Heed. Oct.
                                1896. Three quarters of our mundane year having been absorbed by the infinitude of the
                                past, and as the whole of it will soon follow the retinue of its venerable predecessors,
                                it becomes us, as pupils of Wisdom, to take some note of Time's important events that
                                have transpired through these nine divisions of the present year. Believers have had
                                dispensations of adversity and prosperity, which like Joseph's coat, has been of many
                                colors. Our Pleasant Hill Community have been sorely bitten by that viperborrowing money
                                and giving notes; and the courts have saddled upon the innocent sufferers a heavy load
                                of indebtedness. When will business managers cease to violate our Covenant, by giving
                                notes, which they should know is a sin against Community. Mt. Lebanon, as well as
                                Pleasant Hill, has had its share of trouble. When will all the directors of our
                                Societies truly feel the weighty responsibility of their offices and act as though they
                                knew that the rods of avenging justice were constantly held over their heads, to be used
                                executively in case of violation of trust. Palpable misconduct is soon spread throughout
                                the land, so I will refrain from making individual specifications. With all the
                                vicissitudes of the year that have been unpleasant, we have been abundantly blessed,
                                both temporally and spiritually. The earth has yielded abundantly of substantial fruits
                                so that our tables have been abundantly, if not lavishly supplied. Our pear crop has
                                been very scant. Peaches, plums and cherries have been a failure, but our cultivated
                                strawberries, raspberries and blackberries have been ample. Wild huckleberries have been
                                superabundant. The Church family have gathered twenty-one bushels. The other families
                                have gathered about twenty-five bushels. We have gathered over 200 bu. of cranberries,
                                and when the entire crop is in, there will be fully 300 bu. Thus far we have put down
                                213 gallons of stewed tomatoes for family use, and by the close of to-day we shall have
                                over 400 gallons put up in tin cans for sale to supply an order, when completed, of 600
                                gal. Our apple crop is extraordinary, running up into thousands of bushels. Two hundred
                                barrels of fall apples have been shipped to England. Some men bought and paid for them
                                so we run no risk. There is an inventor in Brooklyn, L. I.James Greshamwho is building a
                                boat that is to push through water at the rate of five miles a minute, so he can take
                                breakfast <pb n="179" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 179 in New York and supper in London, on
                                the same day. At this rate summer fruit of all kinds, and vegetables can be sent to
                                Europe in entire safety. Leaving sublunary products for the present, let us rise to the
                                supernal where we can share eternal joys and fruits of the Spirit. We have been visited
                                by gospel relations from New Hampshire, Enfield, Conn., and Colonie, N. Y., all of which
                                has made tbe bonds of our spiritual union stronger with the several Communities. Our
                                home spiritual culture we aie attending to with care. Calvin G. Reed. had felt and seen
                                that which could not have been explained to him. It was the inner spiritual life which
                                touched a chord in his soul that vibrated through his being. Said he would go from us as
                                a missionary, and perhaps would come again knocking at our door asking permanent
                                admission. He has since published an article concerning his visit. Thus we have had many
                                occasions to let our light shine. May we ever be prepared to give the bread of life to
                                the hungry, water to the thirsty and clothe the spirit with that "love that knoweth no
                                ill." Surah J. Burger. North Family. Oct. 1896. Autumn is singing her harvest song, and
                                the reapers are keeping time to the music. Already one thousand bushels of apples have
                                been gathered and many trees are still heavily laden. The past month our doors have been
                                opened to many transient visitors, among the number are some of much interest. The Dane
                                (Carl Christensen) who was with us delivered a lecture to the Society on Cesar vs.
                                Christ. His discourse was edifying. He brought to bear upon the minds of the
                                congregation that within each heart were two elements, striving for mastery. If through
                                self-will Cesar ascends the throne of the soul then Christ is crucified, but if by
                                integrity and fortitude Cesar is dethroned then Christ reigns and the "Christian's
                                Triumph" is begun. Sept. 13th two members of the Sorosis, New York; Augusta Raymond
                                Kidder and Sophia Curtis, sought opportunity to attend our Sunday service. They seemed
                                anxious to learn of our community and its fundamental principles in view of writing an
                                article for a New York paper. By invitation they tarried with us over night and left
                                feeling glad they had met with us. Also a teacher in Yale and a young student of
                                Political Economy were with us, the latter made the remark that he</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Pittsfield, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>West Pittsfield, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1898. A glance at the calendar tells us that it is again time for our monthly call
                                at the Home Corner, and though it seems hardly possible, that same calendar has stood
                                the test of nine month's constant use, with a strictly truthful record and we can not
                                but believe it now, so I take my seat with you once more, thinking I shall like the
                                proverbial gossip, keep my satchel always packed, and bonnet strings untied, ready for
                                the next call. Although the inward life of individuals is subject to constant change,
                                and the soul is continually expanding or contracting, the outward forms may be similar
                                to those of years ago. So it is in our quiet home. Day succeeds night, bringing its
                                duties to be performed. The seasons come and go in their prescribed order, each
                                fulfilling its particular mission, and the harvest follows the sowing. But as "Nature
                                abhors a vacuum," and, "The secret of life is action," so we daily endeavor to improve
                                our surroundings, and ourselves, that we may say with the minister of old, "I am nearer
                                the kingdom now than when I first believed." We have recently been blessed by the
                                presence of friends from other Societies. Having one life, one purpose, one baptism,
                                what stronger tie could we claim to <pb n="180" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 180 THE MA NIFES TO. bind us
                                in one relationship, than Brethren and Sisters in Christ. Brs. Timothy Rayson and
                                Washington Jones, and Sisters Corrinne Bishop and Esther Gill, spent a Sabbath with us,
                                leaving with us pleasant memories of their musical visit. A Brother and Sister from
                                Enfield, Conn., tarried here for a short time. Messengers from the White Mountain state,
                                came for a look at the Berkshire Hills. Br. George Baxter from Enfield, N. H., and Elder
                                Henry Blinn and Brother Arthur Bruce of Canterbury, each of whom we shall remember. We
                                have realized the strength which a spiritual union imparts, and gave us courage by
                                witnessing that which a life of perfect consecration to God's service can bring about.
                                Fidelia Estabrook.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South Union, Kentucky" TEIform="index"/>South. Union, Ky.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1896. Our brick store at the South Union Station was recently burned to the ground
                                entailing a considerable loss upon the Society. A new store has just been finished
                                costing us $2500.00. Our taxes, although lai'ge, have all been paid. Have just purchased
                                ten tons of fertilizer for our wheat fields at a cost of $270.00. Times are hard and our
                                expenses are heavy, but we are out of debt. A. L. Johns.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1896. In this age of spiritual enlightenment, when the evangelical churches are
                                blending in fellowship, and giving as did Jesu the Christ, free gifts of mind and soul
                                for the elevation of the needy, it bespeaks volumes of praise to the doers of the work
                                ai well as the hearers of the word of salvation. It is pleasant to realize that the old
                                fence of exclusiveness that once hedged in the various churches is crumbling away, and
                                the living vines of truth are drawing mankind out of the furrows of dogmatic narrowness
                                into the broad fields of Christian duty. During the pleasant month of September we
                                enjoyed a feast of love and soul communion with Sisters Sarah Barker and Elmira
                                Hillsgrove, of East Canterbury. We are always pleased to meet our gospel kindred and
                                would by courteous hospitable greetings let such know that we belong to the household of
                                faith. Sisters Isabella Russell and Henrietta Spooner who attended the fairs, report
                                good sales of fancy articles, and Brother John Bradford's onions and beets drew first
                                premium. With renewed love to all, we waft a prayer petitioning strength for God's
                                people everywhere. "When soon or late we reach that coast. O'er life's rough ocean
                                driven, May we rejoice, no wanderer lost, One family in Heaven." George H. Baxter.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1896. The penciling of these Notes reminds us that we have reached another degree on
                                our journey and that we are rapidly approaching the closing of the year. The harvesters
                                are industriously engaged in securing all that may be held for use during the long
                                northern winter, and indeed, a rigid economy must be exercised in this respect in order
                                that the proffered supply might equal the daily demand. In many things the earth in thiB
                                northern latitude has yielded quite liberally of its treasures, but the apple crop like
                                the miraculous "draft of fishes," is the wonder of New England. Till near mid summer a
                                general fear filled the mind that the apple crop would be a failure; but the story was
                                suddenly changed to an over abundance, and immense quantities will waste away, through
                                want of careful hands to secure them. Three hundred tons of ensilage have been secured
                                for use during the winter months, and this may help to continue <pb n="181" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/>
                                THE MANIFESTO. 181 the eighty gallons of milk which is brought to the dairy each day. On
                                the first Sunday in September, a company of Brethren and Sisters held a religious
                                service, by invitation, in the church at Northfield Depot, N. H., and on the 20th, a
                                service was held, by invitation, in the church at Uplands, N. H. By invitation of the
                                Christian Endeavorers who held a Convention in Portsmouth, N. H., on the 14th and 15th
                                of October, one Sister attended as a speaker and four attended as singers. At the close
                                of the Convention the following resolution was offered,"That we tender our thanks to all
                                the speakers of this and particularly of other states, and to all those by whose music
                                we have been uplifted, especially the Shaker quartette and the soloists." Henry C.
                                Blinn.</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">Oct. 1896. "Broadcast over the whole eaith With a liberal hand we will sow; [birth, Sow
                                the power and truth of the heavenly Sow light, till the world is aglow." The last
                                editorial has called very forcibly to mind the importance of laboring to improve the
                                opportunities given for the advancement of the truths of the higher life. Those who have
                                recei ved a portion of this light, should let their light so shine that others may see
                                it and be led to glorify God. When we look around us and see the many who have laid up
                                treasures where decay can not affect them and are nearing the time when they will lay
                                all earthly burdens down; we ask "who will hold the virgin standard as high as those
                                saints who have gone on before?" That it will be sustained we know, and though creeds,
                                empires and systems may pass away., yet the efforts that have been and are being made,
                                to spiritualize human life, have not been sown on the desert air but by accumulation
                                will become irresistible in their uplifting power. It may be largely owing to
                                temperament but we can not coincide with Bryant that "autumn is a melancholy season."
                                After the toils of spring and summer to produce the fruits and vegetables, comes the
                                best of all, autumn. Now we can enjoy the fruits of our labors: and life, manifested in
                                the insect and vegetable departments of nature's kingdom, seem to say, "now let us
                                rest." In the tempernte latitudes of the earth old winter with his rough and ready ways
                                givt s us variety and causes us to appreciate the returns of spring. Through this
                                section of the state we are having a bountiful crop of apples. In some sections of
                                Saratoga County, the apr ple crop is enormous. Many trees are so loaded that in spite of
                                props they are prostrate on the ground with tilth1 burden of fruit. We had a call from
                                our Br. George H. Baxter of Enfield, N. H. We have observed that the visits of our
                                gospel friends the past season have been like angel visits short, but sweet, but we will
                                be thankful for small favors. The door will always stand ajar and the welcome signal
                                given to any of our spiritual relation. Hamilton DeGrriw.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="It is well known that Father James Whittaker was..." TEIform="index"/>
                            It is well known that Father James Whittaker was...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">It is well known that F.ither James Whittaker was one of Mother Ai:n Lee's most earnest
                            advocates of the testimony she bore against all sin; and in his fearlessness and
                            faithfulness in testifying against the evils that are in the world, and exalting the life of
                            Christ both by word and deed, he became a shining mark for the arrows of the satanic spirit
                            of persecution and enmity that was aroused in the hearts of men, wherever the gospel of
                            purity was preached. About three quarters of a mile from the Mount Lebanon Shaker Village,
                            by the side of the road there is a large flat rock on which Father James was cruelly beaten,
                            after having been hurled from his horse; some of his ribs were broken and he was otherwise
                            bruised and bleeding. It is stated that through his great faith in Divine power he was
                            miraculously healed. On the face of the stone his ini- <pb n="182" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 182 TK E
                            MANIFES 2 0. tials may be plainly traced having been carved there sometime after the
                            occurrence. The following poem refers to the circumstance, and also to the fact that it was
                            just at the close of the revolutionary war that the little band of zealous preachers started
                            on their proselyting mission through the eastern p irt of New York State and adjoining towns
                            in Massachusetts, where a great revival of religion had been in progress for many months.
                            There were seven persons imbued with the new light and faith, having perfect confidence in
                            Ann Lee's inspiration and mission who came to this country, at the beginning of the war.
                            They settled in the wilderness of Niskeyuna for three years and worked and prayed until
                            there came an opening for the gospel. The vision referred to was had by Father James while
                            in England.</p><div3 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Father James Whittaker" TEIform="index"/>FATHER JAMES WHITTAKER.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Brown, Grace Ada" TEIform="persName"/>Grace Ada Brown.</byline><p TEIform="p">The long years of trial and conflict Had faded away, [darkest, And night, crowned with
                                stars at its Burst forth into day; The riches of August lay scattered O'er hillside and
                                plain, [rifle, And hands, warm from sword and from Had garnered the grain. To the sound
                                of drum and of trumpet Had come a great hush; On each height seemed a transfiguration, A
                                God in each bush. [deeply So thought, Father James, breathing The clear mountain air,
                                His dark eyes aglow with life's sunshine, His heart with love's prayer; For his was a
                                nature so gentle The wound of sharp knives But brought forth more richly the perfume To
                                sweeten the lives Of those who had wielded the weapon, To fill his with pain. He recked
                                not of sorrow's grave burden Could others have gain. In his English home, once a vision
                                Dawned fair on his sight, Of a tree in the wide Land of Freedom, Each leaf made of
                                light, And tho' bigotry's hand had been heavy Through many a year, And his heart had
                                been torn by its arrows This vision burned clear; So when on the bright August morning
                                'Mid the twitter of birds, The shout of gay innocent children, And lowing of herds.
                                There came to his ear the harsh discords Of hatred and spite, And wrong seemed uplifted,
                                triumphant O'er mercy and right, [seized him He was calm;e'en when strong hands With
                                laughter and mock, Ah, here is the place!over yonder Lies still the gray rock Where his
                                body was flung in wild tumult By men in red rage, A shadow, a stain grim and lurid On
                                nature's sweet page! For nature is here at her fairest Soft height beyond height, [tions
                                While skies breathe their sweet benedicOf color and light. Years have gone; the Elder is
                                teaching His grand truths to-day [less, In a land where the true light is quenchAnd none
                                say him nay. [people Years have passed and brought for the This faith-glowing thought,
                                So live Christ, and be Christ, is better Than all creeds have taught. As years come and
                                go, the brave Elder Looks down from the height, And lo! the great tree of his vision
                                Bursts clear on his sight! It's leaves for the healing of nations, It's, fruit lofty
                                deeds, It flashes a light o'er the ocean To souls in their needs, [light Still the rock,
                                grim and gray in the twiLooks up to the hills [courage! And the hills whisper down,
                                "Keep good God righteth all ills." Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div3></div2><pb n="183" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Health" TEIform="index"/>Sanitary.</head><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Everything that increases true knowledge..." TEIform="index"/>
                                Everything that increases true knowledge...
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Everything that increases true knowledge, everything that multiplies the
                                        power for good, everything that promotes true usefulness, brings nearer the
                                        ideal of a divine manhood. A healthy body, a contented mind, a sympathizing
                                        heart, a disciplined will, a cultured conscience and a regally enthroned
                                        reason,these are the aims alike of science, philosophy and the higher
                                        spiritualism.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Temple of Health" TEIform="index"/>The Temple of Health.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="To cure headaches" TEIform="index"/>TO CURB HEADACHES.</head><p TEIform="p">Simple Remedies That Will Bring Speeily R lief to Sufferers. "A hot bath, a stroll in the
                                fresh air, shampooing the head in weak soda-water, of a timely nap in a cool, quiet room
                                will sometimes stop a nervous headache," writes Dr. B. F. Herrick in August Ladies' Home
                                Journal. "When overfatigued from shopping or sight seeing, a sponge dipped in very hot
                                water and pressed repeatedly over the back of the neck between the ears will be found
                                exceedingly refreshing, especially if the face and temples are afterward subjected to
                                the same treatment. Neuralgia is caused not only by cold air but by acidity of the
                                stomach, starved nerves, imperfect teeth, or by indolence combined with a too generous
                                diet. Heat is the best and quickest cure for this distressing pain. A hot flat-iron,
                                passed rapidly and deftly over several folds of flannel laid on the affected spot, will
                                often give relief in less than ten minutes, without the aid of medicine. Hot
                                fermentations are of equal value; though when the skin is very tender it is more
                                advisable to use dry heat, nothing being better for the purpose than bags of heated
                                salt, flour or sand, which retain warmth for a long time. Cold water, applied by the
                                finger tips to the nerves in front of the ear, has been known to dispel neuralgic pains
                                like magic. When caused by acidity a dose of j charcoal or soda will usually act as a
                                corrective. Sick headache is accompanied by bilious symptoms, and attacks usually come
                                on when the person is overtired or below par physically. This is a disease of the first
                                half of life, and often stops of its own accord after middle age. A careful diet is
                                impernthe in every case, sweetmeats and pastry being especially pernicious. "Eating
                                heartily when very tired, late dinners, eating irregularly, insufficient mastication or
                                too much animal food, especially in the spring or during the hot weather, are frequent
                                causes of indigestion, causing headaches by reflex action."</p></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Remedy for dandruff" TEIform="index"/>A Remedy for Dandruff.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">Having suffered much inconvenience from dandruff, and having resorted to many
                                        advertised nostrums and other means for relief, among which were various
                                        alcoholic solutions of castor oil and washing the scalp with solutions of borax
                                        and carbonate of potassa, which latter, although effectual from the relief of
                                        the dandruff, seemed to impiirthe vitality of the hair, and cause it to become
                                        very sensibly thinner, was finally induced, from my knowledge of the frequent
                                        efficacy of sulphur in certain cutaneous affections, to try a preparation of an
                                        ounce of the flowers of sulphur in a quart of water, as follows, with the
                                        happiest results. The sulphur was repeatedly agitated in the water during
                                        intervals of a few hours, and the clear liquid then poured off, with which the
                                        head was saturated every morning. In a few weeks every trace of dandruff had
                                        dissappeared, and the hair became soft and glossy. After discontinuing the
                                        treatment for eighteen months there is no return of the disease. The remedy is
                                        highly recommended.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Medical Journal" TEIform="index"/>Medical Journal.</bibl></cit></p></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">NOTICE. 'Please inform us if a Dr. Turner is an agent for the selling of Shaker
                                medicines, and who employs him.</p></div3></div2><pb n="184" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Nobility" TEIform="index"/>NOBILITY.</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">[Contributed by J. S. Wright.]  True worth is in beingnot seeming; In doing each day that goes by Some little
                                    goodnot in the dreaming Of great things to do by and by. For whatever men say in
                                    blindness, And spite of the fancies of youth, There's nothing so kingly as kindness,
                                    And nothing so royal as truth. We get back our mete as we measure We can not do
                                    wrong and feel right; Nor can we give pain and gain pleasure, For justice avenges
                                    each slight. The air for the wing of the sparrow, The bush for the robin and wren,
                                    But always the path that is narrow And straight for the childien of men. We can not
                                    make bargains for blisses, Nor catch them like fishes in nets; And sometimes the
                                    things our life misses Helps more than the thing which it gets. For good lieth not
                                    in pursuing Nor gaining of great nor of small; But just in the doing, and doing As
                                    we would be done by, is all. Thro' envy, thro' malice, thro' hating, Against the
                                    world early and late, No jot of our courage abating Our part is to work and to wait;
                                    And slight is the sting of his trouble Whose winnings are less than his worth: For
                                    he who is honest is noble, Whatever his fortunes or birth.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hints to writers and speakers" TEIform="index"/>HINTS TO WRITERS AND SPEAKERS</head><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">William Cullen Bryant gave the following excellent advice to a young man who
                                    offered him an article for the Evening Post. My young friend, I observe that you
                                    have used several French expressions in your article. I think, if you will study the
                                    English language, that you will rind it capable of expressing all the ideas you may
                                    have. I have always found it so, and in all that I have written I do not recall an
                                    instance where I was tempted to use a foreign word, but that, on searching, I found
                                    a better one in my own language. Be simple, unaffected; be honest in your speaking
                                    and writing. Never use a long word when a short one will do. Call a spade a spade,
                                    not a well-known, oblong instrument of manual industry; let a home be a home, not a
                                    residence; a place a place, not a locality, and so of the rest. Where a short word
                                    will do, you lose by using a long one. You lose in clearness; you lose in honest
                                    expression of your meaning, and in the estimation of all men who are competent to
                                    judge, you will lose in reputation for ability. The only true way to shine even in
                                    this false world, is to be modest, unassuming. Falsehood may be a very thick crust,
                                    but in the course of time will find a place to break through. Elegance of language
                                    may not be in the power of all of us, but simplicity and straight-forwardness are.
                                    Write much as you would speak; speak as you think. If with your inferior, speak no
                                    coarser than usual; if with your superior speak no finer. Be what you say, and
                                    within the rules of prudence. No one ever was a gainer by singularity of words or in
                                    pronunciation. The truly wise man will so speak that no one will observe how he
                                    speaks. A man may show great knowledge of chemistry by carrying about bladders of
                                    strange gases to breathe, but he will enjoy better health, and find more time for
                                    business, who lives on common air. Sidney Smith once remarked: After you have
                                    written an article, take your pen and strike out half of the words, and you will be
                                    surprised to see how much stronger it is.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="Selected" TEIform="index"/>Selected.</bibl></cit></p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="There is no failure..." TEIform="index"/>There is no failure...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">There is no failure except in no longer trying. There is no defeat except from within; no
                            really insurmountable barrier save our own inherent weakness of purpose.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, A. J." TEIform="persName"/>A. J. Culver.</byline></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Dolorous indeed is the whining voice of discontent." TEIform="index"/>Dolorous indeed is the whining voice of discontent
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Dolorous indeed is the whining voice of discontent.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="A., M. J." TEIform="persName"/>M. J. A.</byline></div2><!--
<pb n="" id="p19"/>
THE MANIFESTO.
esting and includes a portrait of Maud Ballington Booth.
An article by Prof. Sizer on Li Hung Chang,
the Chinese Envoy, which is accompanied by
a portrait of this remarkable man, will be
studied with pleasure.
Reflections on the New Woman, by Blanche
Lane brings forward a subject of world wide
interest. Child Culture by Prof. Sizer has
some very pretty illustrations. His article
written upon this subject must be of interest
in every home. Fowler and Wells Co., 27 East
21st St. New York.
Everywhere is the title of Will Carleton's
Magazine, a new volume commenced in Sept.
It is only 5 cts. per copy or 50 cts. per year.
It is a Magazine of eight large quarto pages.
It is filled with articles from the pens of ready
Writers, highly interesting and many of them
beautifully illustrated. Address N. E. Good
rich, 1105 Bedford Ave. Brooklyn, N. Y.
The Sunday School Times for oct. 10, has a
table of contents that must satisfy almost any
reader of that class of literature. Many excellent contributions may be found on the
varied religious subjects. The little children
are not forgotten and some one has kindly
written to them about the rabbits. Lessons
for the Sunday School are among the best and
occupy a liberal space in the paper. Published by John D. Wattles & Co., Philadelphia, Pa.
The Pulpit for September, contains some
very interesting and instructive lessons.
Coming as it does from so many churches, it
foreshadows the coming Christian union. The
Christ Life, by Rev. J. B. Whitford of the
Methodist Episcopal Church. The Only Perfect Standard of Right, by Rev. IT. T. Swengil
of the United Evangelical Church. Power of
God, by Rev. W. S. Smith of the Disciples of
Christ. Hospitality by Rev. C. E. Wehler, of
the Reformed Church. The Witch of Endor
by Rev. J. E. Lancely, of the Methodist Episcopal Church, Adaptation in Religious Teaching by Rev. J. B. Robins of the Methodist
Episcopal Church. Published by G. Holsapfel, Fredericksburg, Pa.
So many good things are given in the October number of Frank Leslie's Popular
Monthly that it is impossible, in our limited
space, to describe them all. The principal
features, all splendidly illustrated, are; "The.
Road to the Stage," in which Arthur Hornblow
tells how actors and actresses are made, and
something about the dramatic schools; "General Lee's Last Campaign," by General Horatio C King, the ninth paper in the great Lee
series; the opening chapters of a new serial
story, "Father John," by Edith Sessions Tupper; "The U. S. Revenue Cutter Service," giving the history and duties of an  important
brunch of our navy, by Joanna R.Nichols;
'The Free Silver Issue," by Senator William
M. Stewart, being the first of two papers on
"The, Leading Issues of the Two Great Parties," to be followed next month by an article
from the gold standpoint; "The Art Student
in Munich," by George Willis Bardwell; an
account of a visit to the old Italian city of
Perugia; and "The Microscope as an Amusement," by William G. Bowdoin. Then there
are four short stories, some illustrated poems,
an attractive Young Folk's Department, Talks
about the New Books, etc. Frank Leshe's Publishing House.
A Book of Shaker Poetry, called "Mount
Lebanon Cedar Boughs" issued by the Sisters
of the North Family at Mount Lebanon, New
York, the settlement of which the late Elder
Frederick W. Evans was so long a ruling spirit. Among these Shaker women there is considerable literary talent, one of the Sisters being Miss Cecelia DeVere, the sister of Miss
Mary Ainge DeVere, so well known to magazine readers by her nom de plume of "Madeline Bridges." Miss DeVere, like her sister,
has written some exceedingly clever verse,
and her work is well represented in the volume. All the poems in the book are reflective
of the simple life of the Shaker community,
and give a picture of life of which very little
is known to the outer world."[Edward Bok.
in Chatham Courier, May 1, 1895.
The book is for sale by the North family of
Shakers, Mt. Lebanon, Columbia Co., N. Y.
Price :
"INTERPRETING PROPHECY"
AND   THE
"Appearing of Christ."
is the title of a neat little pamphlet of
some forty pages, just sent out by A. G.
Hollister of Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.
The many at the present time who are
nterested in the fulfillment of prophecy,
and in its mathematical calculation, will
find themselves by the side of the good
old prophet Daniel, and with him illustrating the Coming of Christ so clearly
that no occasion can arise for the least
doubt.                             Price, 10 cts.
<pb n="" id="p20"/>
THE   MANIFESTO.
AUTHORISED   RULES
OF
THE   SHAKER  COMMUNITY,
The religious basis of the Order must
be a foundation resting on the principle of
righteousness, which principle is God.
This should rule the life of the individual for the protection of his own soul, for
the peace of the family and as an evidence
of his upright standing before the world.
Price, 10 cts.
For Information and free Handbook write to
MUNN & CO., 361 Broadway, New York.
Oldest bureau for securing patents in America.
Every patent taken out by us is broucht before
the public by a notice given free of charge in the
Largest circulation of any scientific pappr In the
world. Splendidly illustrated. No intelligent
man should be without it. Weekly, SiS.OOa
year; $1.50 six months. Address, MUNN & CO..
Publishers, 3til Broadway, New York City.
POWDER
Absolutely Pure.
A cream of  tartar  baking   powder.
Highest of all in leavening strength.
 Latest   United   States   Government
Food report.
Royal Baking Powder Co., New York.
THE  ALTRUIST.
Is a monthly paper, partly in Phonetic
spelling, and devoted to common proper.
ty, united labor, Community homes, and
equal rights to all. It is published by the
Altruist Community, whose members all
live and work together, and hold all their
property in common, all the men and
women having equal rights in electing officers and deciding all business affairs by
their majority vote. 50 cents a year;
specimen copy free. Address A. Longley, 1719 Franklin Ave, St. Louis, Mo.
Funk & Wagnalls Company, New York,
have just received a single order from one
firm for 100,000 copies of their celebrated
Standard Dictionary of the English Language, amounting at retail to nearly one
and a quarter millions of dollars. This is
the largest single sale of so large a work
ever made in America. Previous to this
one large transaction, over 100,000 copies
had been issued, and the Company is still
receiving many large orders from its subscription agents through-out the world.
The New York
Dispatch....
Oldest      and      Best     Recognized
Weekly     Paper     in   the    United
States.
Improved        Management,        and
Methods up to date.
A   Family   Journal
Of Morals and Public Interests,
Newsy, Literary, Scientific,
Humorous, Useful, Entertaining. Also Gr. A. E., Masonic
and Society News.
One Copy,  One   Year,     2.50.
Post yourself on what is going
on in New  York.      Address
The  New York  Dispatch.
150 Nassau Street, N. Y.
<pb n="" id="p"/>
--></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>