<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-tm2601" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Manifesto</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">30</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shaker Village, New Hampshire</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">26</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">1</biblScope><date value="18960101" TEIform="date">January 1896</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">1-24</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="26" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><div1 type="issue" n="1" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><!--
                    <pb id="p1"/>
                    <p>THE MANIFESTO, Published by the United Societies. VOL. XXVI. "Blessed are the peacemakers: for they shall be called
                        the children of God." Matt. v. 9. East Canterbury, N. H. 1896. JANUARY. <pb id="p2"/> THE MANIFESTO. CONTENTS. Page.
                        Smiles of the Father,..... 3 Social Improvement Society, i Duty........-7 Loyalty,....." Autobiography of Chas. D.
                        Hampton, 9 The Power of Words, ... 10 Baptism,........ 11 Gethseniane,...... 14 Music,—Songs of Cheer, 15 Notes
                        About Home,..... 17 Exchanges, -....... 23 Deaths,........ " Books & Papers,...... "</p>
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="1" id="p3"/>
                    <div2 type="none"
                        <p>THE MANIFESTO. PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOGIETIES. VOL. XXVI. Out of Zion shall go forth the law, and the word of
                            the Lord from Jerusalem."—Isa. ii., 3. East Canterbury,N. H.. 1896.</p>
                    </div2>
                    <pb n="2" id="p4"/>
                    --><pb n="3" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Smiles of the father" TEIform="index"/>SMILES OF THE FATHER</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Perkins, Abraham" TEIform="persName"/>Abraham Perkins</byline><p TEIform="p">TO us as a peculiarly favored people, I realize that the genuine gospel of Christ has "been
                            revealed and mercifully given, and power abundantly bestowed, giving an exceedingly great
                            salvation. Our God has been sought and has been found; and to every one whose rnind is
                            continually stayed on him he has been an everlasting strength. In his law there is no
                            change; in his character no variableness nor shadow of turning. His word is truth, his
                            promises reliable and ever put into execution. Obedience to that law is, and ever has been,
                            our blessing and salvation. Zion has never been left in orphanage. Although for a small
                            moment the good Lord may hide his face to prove the integrity of souls, his watchful,
                            protective eye is ever over his elect to uphold and sustain the revelation which has ever
                            been the ruling and guidmg star of the Shaker Church. Our sky may often be overcast, yet
                            there has always been a rift in the cloud, through which has beamed degrees and advances of
                            light which have hitherto been our preservation and rock of safety. Would we find growth of
                            soul and fruits of the Spirit, whatever the circumstances, what the obstacles and trials,
                            never give place to discouragement, halting or doubting. Revelation is too palpable,
                            evidences too great to question the designs of the Almighty or the providences of God in his
                            care and superintendence which He exercises over his creatures. We may feel our many
                            imperfections and our great wants. Thus the Spirit convicts and the good Lord deals with us
                            for salvation, crying—"Ask and it shall be given you; seek and ye shall find; knock and it
                            shall be opened unto you." Therefore, "Fear not, little flock, for it is your Father's good
                            pleasure to JANUARY, 1896. <pb n="4" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4 THE MANIFESTO. give you the kingdom." Unto
                            Zion has the Lord dealt graciously. No people have been so abundantly illuminated and
                            favored as the present generations. Not alone have the heavens stooped to redeem and
                            comfort, but the earth has arisen to aid, to help and to magnify the restoration of man.
                            Rejoice ; increasing glory awaiteth Zion ! East Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Social improvement society" TEIform="index"/>SOCIAL IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY</head><byline TEIform="byline">(Leading paper by <persName reg="Allen, Catherine" TEIform="persName"/>Catherine Allen.)</byline><p TEIform="p">Question. T~Y"T"HAT is to constitute the "New Heavens and New Earth wherein V V shall dwell
                            righteousness ? " Answer. Perhaps no people ever supposed themselves to have a more exact
                            definition of this prophetic passage of Scripture than the body of people called Shakers.
                            Other religious sects look forward to a second coming of the Lord when the Millennial age
                            will be ushered in, believing that all the promises of sacred writ will then find glorious
                            fruition. But those who formulated Shaker theology were confident that Christ had then made
                            a "Second Appearance" through the person of Ann Lee. Therefore, although Mother Ann and her
                            co-laborers kept before their follrwers the idea that to them was given the dawning light of
                            a new dispensation, which in its increasing degrees would be as "glory beyond glory," yet
                            almost as soon as the society became organized, their zealous disciples taught and wrote in
                            most emphatic language, that to them a perfect plan of salvation had been revealed in a
                            gospel which was the ' 'last and final display of God's power and glory to the human race."
                            It has been written,—"The Bible is a place where each his dogma seeks and each his dogma
                            finds." In all the books which treat of Shaker theology (those written by Elder F. W. Evans
                            excepted) the writers have fortified every point of doctrine with Scriptural authority, and
                            have adjusted the prophetic portions as a closely fitting garment to the gospel work as then
                            manifested, believing that in it was to be found a clear and full definition, in fact the
                            fulfillment of the grandest utterances of inspired seers, and as a consequence, without any
                            intention of bigotry, it was but natural for them, to narrow the meaning of the foregoing
                            text with other passages of broad signifi- cance to fit the measure of truth which they had
                            received ; therefore, they interpreted the "New Heavens" to have reference to the new
                            doctrines and spiritual interests of the Shaker Communities,—the "New Earth" to thenmaterial
                            possessions and temporal interests. They were assured that in and among them the kingdom of
                            heaven was established, and of its "increase there would be no end." Holding this idea, <pb n="5" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 5 the}7 worked with superhuman energy, believing without
                            doubt that every building they erected, however void of any idea of hygiene or beauty, and
                            especially every acre of land they added to their possessions, was extending tin's
                            kingdom,—increasing it. To buy land with the hard-earned money of consecrated labor to be
                            held in the interests of those who were living a virgin life in communal relation, w'as in
                            their estimation the way in which the earth would be redeemed. Greater intelligence would
                            have dictated that to till and cultivate the land on scientific principles would be at least
                            a partial means toward its redemption. Under the delusion of thus redeeming the earth, and
                            with the idea that they would make rapid accessions to their numbers, they bought up large
                            tracts of laud,—a fatal error, for to Believers, as to other people, land monopoly has
                            proved a curse, and the underlying cause of most of their subsequent errors and losses,
                            materially and spiritually. Still they wrere faithful to the light of their day and we owe
                            much to their devoted efforts. We look to the motives and cast no censure upon those of
                            earlier days who, in their misdirected zeal made the mistake, but we ai-e very sorry that in
                            our own time there are any still so blind, that with the experience of the past before them
                            they should repeat so great a wrong as to add thousands of acres to an already "land-poor"
                            people. We fear that the extending of Christ's kingdom has not been their leading motive in
                            the matter. Elder F. A\r. Evans and Brother Daniel Frazer were brave pioneer reformers in
                            our ranks. They saw this great evil and lifted their voices against it. They also studied
                            the relations between the earth and the spiritual orders of human life, and conceived the
                            "New Heavens" and "New Earth" to have a much broader significance than that which had been
                            generally accepted by the Society. They taught that the formation of the "New Heavens" began
                            with the revelation of the principles of the Shaker Church and would increase with its
                            evolution from cycle to cycle. That the "New Earth" began with the American Republic, and as
                            the people progressed from one degree of truth to another, it would gradually include every
                            principle of science pertaining to the natural life of man in government, agriculture,
                            generation and nutrition. How far their prophetic vision was able to pierce the future we do
                            not know, but when the word Shaker is omitted from the spiritual, and American from the
                            earthly order, when in their universal application, principles alone are considered, we have
                            no objection to that interpretation. The two orders certainly have a relation together as
                            soul and body. The inception of both occurred at the same period. The history of one is
                            identical with the other. Land monopoly and its inevitable result, wage slavery has wrought
                            equal ruin to the spiritual and earthly order. As in one, so in the other has there been a
                            centralization of power in the hands of the few to the injury and nondevelopment of the
                            many. Though intended only for good, by an erroneous <pb n="6" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/> 6 THE MANIFESTO.
                            system of "Protection" the government has blindly robbed the people not only of material
                            benefits, but of greater blessings, the opportunity to advance the conditions for the
                            brotherhood of nations, and reciprocate the good thatwould thereby be enhanced. The same
                            principle of protection manifested in distinctive family interests and fear of opening the
                            door to the good of the outside world lest evil also should enter, have brought like results
                            in the spiritual order. To-day the many indications of destruction to both, teach us that
                            delayed evolution has brought us face to face with revolution. This does not prove that the
                            fundamental principles of either were not correct and will not eventually find a glorious
                            expression, but that the developed life of the nation as a whole, made it impossible for
                            immediate success. During the crisis now upon us in both orders, principles are being
                            intelligently examined and analyzed; errors are being eliminated, and on firmer and broader
                            foundations than ever before true democracy in our home and in the earthly government will
                            be established. In this hope we look beyond the storm clouds of thi present to the glory of
                            Millennial skies. We see the time, when, beginning at the fountain head of all existence,
                            just relations will be established between the sexes in the affairs of Church, State and
                            home. Not till then can we begin to know the possibilities of the human race or estimate the
                            great loss that has been sustained through the dissipation of the vital force. The
                            manipulation of occult forces under the psychic powers that have been developed in a few
                            individuals here and there, aside from the wonderful discoveries in what we term the natural
                            sciences, show us the dormant, earthburied condition of the race as a whole, and give hints
                            of the great revolution that will come about in the world of mind and matter just as soon as
                            the people shall be prepared. Meanwhile every awakened soul should work with intelligence
                            and energy toward those advanced conditions. In the most literal sense the earth should be
                            redeemed. Instead of annually depositing in the ocean millions of tons of land-food, it
                            should be properly decomposed and restored whence it was taken. It is criminal in any people
                            or nation to rob future generations by rendering the land incapable of human subsistence.
                            The fertilization and sowing of every acre of land should be governed by a knowledge of its
                            chemical properties, The rotation of crops and Sabbaths of rest should be observed ;
                            extensive forest belts should be planted wherever needed to equalize electrical currents and
                            protect from flood and drought. By artificial irrigation for the present, arid wastes could
                            be made fruitful and in time would develop their own water supply. In thus complying with
                            the laws of God in nature, his promise that the crops should be free from mildew and
                            destructive pests will be fulfilled and the early and later rains will be insured. <pb n="7" id="p9" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 7 In the affairs of Government we think to abolish interest,
                            and by means of a tax on land values, cease to rob the people of their God-given inheritance
                            in the land, will bring about, "Equal opportunities to all, special privileges to none,"—a
                            far reaching freedom in every domain of existence. No longer repressed, dwarfed and
                            crippled, the God-life in humanity will assert itself and gradually find expression through
                            the application of the true laws of being in the earthly and in the spiritual life in
                            humanity; the spiritual ripening as fruit upon the tree, lifted above the earth, developing
                            in the sunlight of the upper world, yet always dependent upon the tree and soil (the earthly
                            order) for nourishment. Will this not be the '-New Heavens and New Earth wherein shall dwell
                            righteousness ?" Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Duty" TEIform="index"/>DUTY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Stephens, Annie R." TEIform="persName"/>Annie R. Stephens</byline><p TEIform="p">A narrow mountain pass my feet must go ; A steep declivity,—a rugged way, My back must ache
                            with burdens of the day. Stern cragged rocks their darkening presence throw, The mists rise
                            up from valleys dim and low. O'er thorny paths, through shadows cold and grey,— Still on I
                            press, nor pause in dread dismay, For it is Duty's path, full well I know. Still will I
                            climb and, climbing, gain the height; Tho' sandals worn, my feet with peace are shod, While
                            Hope can see the shining Tabor light, And Love forgets the road my feet have trod, While,
                            from the Mount of Vision on my sight Gleams the bright, vernal table-lands of God. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Loyalty" TEIform="index"/>LOYALTY</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Theobald, Frank" TEIform="persName"/>Frank Theobald</byline><p TEIform="p">"TV OYALTY may be defined as fidelity to a principle, home, institution, I J friends or
                            country. The truly loyal in our home manifest this spirit in their daily lives, by their
                            just and generous support of the principles which govern the home, and such realize that
                            they must sacrifice all personal ambitions, all that would tend to lower our moral and
                            religious standing in society, doing right simply because it is right, this is true loyalty;
                            for truth is everything and the truth will conquer. <pb n="8" id="p10" TEIform="pb"/> 8 THE MANIFESTO.
                            This loyalty to principle should be exercised in private as well as in public, at home and
                            abroad, first by an understanding of the work which we are called to live, and then with an
                            honesty and loyalty of spirit under all circumstances defend the same. Society can not be
                            judged rightfully by individual members composing it, for persons ma}' go wrong and be
                            disloyal to faith and home, but the principles upon which the Society is founded will live
                            through all time and be cherished by good and faithful souls forever. Our forefathers
                            possessed this spirit in an uncommon d gree, as sh &gt;wn in their noble,
                            self-sacrificing struggle for their religious liberty, bearing hardship and
                            imprisonment,—even giving up their lives in fidelity to principles which to them were of
                            God, and which meant the right to worship Hun and to dwell with Him in the mansions He has
                            promised to the faithful The founders of our Church always put duty and the good of their
                            p3ople before their own personal inclinations and desires. Loyalty in those stormy days cost
                            more than it does to-day, when the rights of civil and religious liberty are accorded
                            without question, and we are peacefully allowed to worship God in spirit and in truth,
                            without molestation or persecution which was so often their portion to bear. Does the same
                            loyalty of spirit and integrity of purpose in things spiritual, temporal and financial mark
                            our lives? If so, it gives to us, as to them, the key to success in all that pertains to the
                            welfare of our Church. Time and circumstances may alter; outward conditions may change, but
                            loyalty to principles of Godliness and to each other, is the duty of all true followers of
                            Christ. Loyalty to our country and its republican institutions is the duty of every true
                            citizen in the land. We have many examples of fidelity in the lives of public men who have
                            dared to stand for the right, and defend an honest principle before friend or foe alike. The
                            signing of the Declaration of Independence by our forefathers was an act of loyalty which
                            has hardly been equalled in the history of our country. Their motto was, "United we stand,
                            divided we fall." It might have proved their death warrant instead of a declaration of
                            rights, but their integrity, firmness, courage and a fixed purpose to gain their liberty,
                            stand before us to-day as a monument of their loyalty, and an example for all true lovers of
                            their country. In later years we find other worthy examples. In the darkest hour of our
                            Country's history, when treason and disloyalty beset the Nation's honor on every side, there
                            was one who shaped its destiny in a great measure, whose faith in God, and freedom for the
                            human race was paramount to all selfish interest, giving even his own life as a token of his
                            fidelity and honor. Such was the life and devotion of Abraham Lincoln, who might worthily be
                            named a Father and Savior to the Nation. No higher monument to his name and the loyal souls
                            who fought and suffered with him, can be erected, than the remembrance of his noble life in
                            the hearts of a free and loving people. <pb n="9" id="p11" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 9 From these
                            considerations ma}? we be impressed with the spirit of true loyalty, which inspired to such
                            noble achievements. May we give in honor to the interests of our Zion home, loyal,
                            consecrated service, equal to these time-honored veterans. Enfield, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="biography" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Autobiography of Chas. D. Hampton of Union Village, Ohio, no. 1" TEIform="index"/>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF CHAS. D. HAMPTON OF UNION VILLAGE, O. NO 1.</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Charles D." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">1710R some time I have attempted to write of the things that were and now . are, but up to
                            the present date have resisted for want of an inspiring gift which is always essential. This
                            establishes confidence and I proceed reasonably certain that as I feel the active, energetic
                            spirit moving me, something of benefit may be produced. In the thirtieth year of my age,
                            surrounded by all that could make life desirable, with every stimulus which could excite
                            genius into action or talents to perseverance; with a good constitution, sound health and a
                            family around me of increasing interest every day, and all my domestic affinities of the
                            most pleasing and engaging character; my temporal affairs prosperous, and the means of
                            enjoying life increasing and also a wide and profitable range of business in my profession.
                            Encompast by all these advantageous circumstances in a pleasant and wealthy neighborhood, I
                            became suddenly the subject of an invisible ministration, unsought for and really unwisht. I
                            had said in my heart, "Go to now," let us be wise and gain wealth, and be honorable among
                            men, and let our children be among the favored in the land. I was sailing clown through time
                            in the full "tide of successful experiment." Every day added stimulus to the joys
                            anticipated good, and every hour riveted tighter, the bands that bound my soul to the god of
                            this world. It was painful to be disturbed in my speculations and the dread of poverty was
                            an utter abomination and not to be tolerated for a moment. But the magical wand of the
                            angel, at first, touched me lightly and sweetly and caused me to love him before I suspected
                            who he was, and bound my soul in chains before I knew whither he was leading me. His
                            attentions were assiduous and he placed such subjects before the view of my mind, as were
                            wisely calculated to enlist my respect and reverence. He seemed to enlarge and expand the
                            capacity of my mental vision and opened to my view the most alluring prospects of social
                            union and delight. He seemed to extend the field of my powers of thinking and reasoning in
                            every possible direction. The political world with all its ruthless scrambling after a
                            momentary popularity for personal advancement, and individual selfish interest, and the
                            whole tenor of its ulterior attainments, with its ultimate <pb n="10" id="p12" TEIform="pb"/> 10 THE
                            MANIFESTO. rewards, were opened to my view with the most astonishing clearness an:l the most
                            minute perspicuity. The whole Christian world from the time of the Nicene council in A. D.
                            325 to the present day was laid open to my inspection, as tho laid out on a well-formed
                            chart, and I was regularly and almost imperceptibly led along down the line of the
                            ecclesiastical history, to the rise of the witnesses of truth in Fox, Burroughs and the
                            other distinguished reformers of that age and thence on, down thru the past world of
                            controversial divinity, thru the various and numerous sects to the day and time in which we
                            live. The visions opened before my mind like substantial realities, unfolding little by
                            little, until the whole matter stood out in bold view, plain aud clear as the splendor of
                            the noonday, and so brilliantly and beautifully delineated that explanation was needless and
                            comment entirely unnecessary. This pleasant, secret enjoyment of my curious condition
                            continued for some two or three months, and in fact, until it became the constant theme of
                            my mind. At this time I was doing a heavy business in the practice of medicine and every
                            moment except those for examination and prescription for patients, regular attendance was
                            given to the counsel of my unseen adviser. Thru all these scenes of bright and beautiful
                            expositions of mental action, I never once dreamed of the presence of any instrument of
                            assistance to my vision, but simply thought all I saw were the pleasant vagaries of a lively
                            fancy and an active imagination and was rather delighted than edified or instructed. {To be
                            continued.)</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Power of words" TEIform="index"/>THE POWER OF WORDS</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Bowers, Lucy S." TEIform="persName"/>Lucy S. Bowers</byline><p TEIform="p">They flash like stars that light the frosty sky, Like rich imperial diadems they shine. And
                            like forge fire are mighty to refine. Like serpents' fangs they sting, like weights they
                            lie, They soothe most tenderly and never die. They can unveil the depths where wrongs
                            combine, Or point out heavenly heights of truth divine; Yea crush like battle-axes, or like
                            sorrow sigh. The happy impulse of the mind they thrill; They captivate, enrich, control and
                            guide; With dignity and power the soul they fill, Sing like a stream, shout like the sea
                            full tide. To speak good words should be in human will, And perfect utterance be the true
                            heart's pride. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><pb n="11" id="p13" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Baptism" TEIform="index"/>BAPTISM</head><p TEIform="p">THE origin of baptism as a religious observance was common among the ancient nations. These
                            lustrations were prevalent among the Egyptians, Greeks and Romans as well as among the Jews.
                            It was a preparation for divine service and sometimes even for prayer. It was not uncommon
                            to have a prayer house by the side of a stream for bathing. From the days of Moses, the
                            confession of sin and the ceremonies of bathing or washing had held a prominent place in
                            that church. Under the direction of the law it was imperative. Without it they lost their
                            inheritance. Our first biblical notice of it as a religious ceremony is in Ex. xxix., 4,
                            where Aaron and his sous were anointed as the priests of God. But John the Baptist was now
                            to do for the people what they had hitherto been obliged, in many cases to do for
                            themselves, and on the whole it must have been rather agreeable than otherwise. John's bap-
                            tism was eminently practical. Sent as a messenger from God, he called the people to an
                            honest confession of their sins as a preliminary to their privilege of baptism. "Repent,"
                            said he, "for the kingdom of God is at hand. Make the Lord's path strait." It was a revival
                            of religious life, a gift of God to draw them from their perpetual back-slidings. To forget
                            God and to manufacture idols as objects of divine worship, as did Aaron and Jeroboam,
                            represents a fearful state of ignorance. But the prophet tells us that the blacksmith and
                            the carpenter and the potter have all been busy in the making of idol gods for the market.
                            It was a universal departure from the strict discipline of the Law and we do not wonder that
                            the Baptist urged them to, repent. Through all the manifestations of God's work it has
                            addressed itself to, man as it at that time found him. The serpents in the halls of Pharaoh
                            appealed directly to the mind of the king. He understood equally aa well the introduction of
                            the frogs and the locusts. Had Moses attempted to deliver such a discourse as he did when
                            the children of Israel asked for meat, we might well imagine the effect it would have
                            produced. All the prophesies for many years previous to the advent of John the Baptist had
                            warned the Jews of the fate that awaited them if they did not keep the Law, Jesus on his
                            arrival did not hesitate to compare them <pb n="12" id="p14" TEIform="pb"/> 12 TEE MANIFESTO. to whited
                            sepulchres, beautifully ornamented without while within they were full of all uncleanness.
                            John was not a member of the Mosaic order, nor a convert to the Christian. H± was an
                            Independent. He combated the prevailing opinion of the times which was, that the performance
                            of external ceremonies was sufficient to secure a right to the kingdom of
                            G&gt;&gt;d. His baptism was the revival of a religious interest and the Judeans all
                            wanted to see him. It was not an introduction into any religious order, for John had none,
                            and the disciples subsequently re-baptised those who came to them, (Acts, xix., 5.) and as
                            rigidly insisted that the converts should accept all the ceremonies of the Law. Curiosity
                            would prompt the people, as it would us, to know what John was doing. His costume of camel's
                            hair, and the place for baptism may also have stimulated more or less interest. After so
                            many years have passed, the curiosity has not wholly subsided. Robinson says that at one
                            time some fifteen hundred people assembled to witness the ceremony, and within a few years
                            near the city of Manchester, N. H. not less than ten thousand persons were present. Since
                            the days of the Baptist the subject of baptism has elicited different opinions and sometimes
                            produced fierce contentions in the circle of its adherents. Those fighting reformers, John
                            Calvin and Martin Luther indulged in many sharp words on the subject. While one church
                            maintains that baptism can only be administered by immersion, another church is satisfied
                            that pouring on water is all that is necessary, and a third is equally satisfied with a few
                            drops of water sprinkled on the convert. One church says that baptism of water washes away
                            all sin. Another that it makes us children by spiritual birth and still others that it is
                            only a symbol of purification. Some churches baptize only adults, while others demand that
                            even litttle children shall receive the ceremony. One church thinks that the person should
                            be immersed once, while others insist that it shall be done three times. Really, the baptism
                            ceremony as now used, is at least a babel of confusion. It is urged that as Jesus was
                            baptized of John he sanctioned the rite. His acceptance of baptism was quite another thing
                            from his commanding that it should be used by other persons. He as equally sanctioned
                            lasciviousness and intemperance at the marriage in Cana, or the use of the sword to cut off
                            the ears of those who offend us, or the riotous proceedings that often occur as that of the
                            temple when he drove out the brokers and common traders. <pb n="13" id="p15" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                            MANIFESTO. 13 Jesus never administered baptism, and there is no evidence that he ever
                            directed its employment by his disciples while he was upon the earth. "There is nothing to
                            prove that any of the twelve were ever baptized in the name of the Father, the Son and the
                            Holy Ghost, or indeed, received any baptism whatever, except such as John the Baptist
                            probably administered to Andrew, Peter, Philip and John."— Dictionary of Religions
                            Knowledge. The baptism of Jesus was of the Holy Spirit and of fire, and he asked his
                            disciples at one time if they were able to receive it. They had been able to receive the
                            water baptism of John, and unless this was quite a different process to which he alluded, it
                            would have been a very uncalled-for question. All Judea had been out to Jordan to be
                            baptized and no doubt were pleased with the privilege. The baptism of Jesus was a baptism
                            into his life, which was to do the will of God. As the whole life of Jesus the Christ was a
                            spiritual work, to accept him was to be baptized into him or into the order of his spiritual
                            life. And certainly his life and testimony was a consuming fire into which all entered, or
                            into which all were baptized that embraced his gospel work. Two foolish fellows thought they
                            were able to pass through the ordeal, and also asked the privilege to sit, the one on his
                            right hand and the other on his left in the kingdom of God, although they evidently had not
                            the first conception of the work to which Jesus referred. Some of the first disciples of
                            Jesus had been disciples of John, and in imitation of their master continued the ceremony by
                            baptizing all who wished to follow Jesus. Paul shows very plainly that he understood the
                            difference between the baptism of John and that of Jesus. If he ac- cepted the ceremony it
                            was evidently for the purpose of preventing a collision with those converts who had come out
                            of the Jewish Church. In one of his letters to the church in Corinth he leaves this emphatic
                            testimony concerning water baptism, "I thank God that I baptized none of you but Crispus and
                            Gaius and the household of Stephanus. For the Christ sent me not to baptize, but to preach
                            the gospel." One of our religiouspapers a few years since, published the remarks of a Jewish
                            Rabbi on the subject of baptism. "Concerning baptism all are agreed that in ancient times
                            immersion of the whole body (not the clothes) was necessary for a new member of the Jewish
                            leligion. And as the baptism was a Jewish ceremony before the time of Jesus, John and the
                            apostles surely performed it in the same manner as did the eTews. It was not new and no
                            Pharisee or Sadducee raised any objection against it <pb n="14" id="p16" TEIform="pb"/> 14 THE MANIFESTO.
                            as they did to many other performances. Hence I can not account for it why the imitators of
                            John the Baptist and the Apostolic Church, should perform baptism when clad in water-proof
                            clothes. A real baptizing or bathing of the body and not of the clothes ought to take place,
                            and hence men should baptize men, and women baptize women. It is obvious, therefore, that no
                            woman was among the multitude that came to John as is reported in Matt, iii., 5, 6. In the
                            second century baptism was administered publicly twice a year and if we are to believe the
                            historian, the church was not always very particular about the free will of the converts.
                            Multitudes of the Jews were cruelly persecuted and inhumanly dragged into the church to be
                            baptized by the violence of the clergy. The same method of conversion was practiced in
                            France and Spain. But those days are passed away, and we may hope never more to return. We
                            now ask only for the gospel of good news and the baptism of the Holy Spirit which will
                            cleanse the soul from the sins of the world, and raise it to the heavenly love of the
                            Christ.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn</byline></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gethsemane" TEIform="index"/>GETHSEMANE</head><byline TEIform="byline">By <persName reg="Vinneo, Cora" TEIform="persName"/>Cora Vinneo</byline><p TEIform="p">Theke was a garden where the Savior prayed Id agony of soul. Dark was the night, The stars
                            refused to shine, the moon to light The deep seclusion where the Master strayed. Alone he
                            suffered, while his soul was swayed With throes of pain endured for truth and right. Our
                            minds retire, night hides from us the sight Of God's blest Son by wicked man betrayed. And
                            O, our Father ! bend thy listening ear When we to our Gethsemane retire, We agonize, we bow
                            in reverent fear, Or satisfy our longing and desire. And in these hours send angel helpers
                            near, To lift our stricken souls to regions higher. Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The destructive element in an individual..." TEIform="index"/>
                            The destructive element in an individual...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">The destructive element in an individual, conjoined to benevolence and love for humanity,
                            gives force to carry out the great projects which are so beneficial for the good of mankind. </p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="B., S. J." TEIform="persName"/>S. J. B.</byline></div2><pb n="15" id="p17" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Songs of cheer" TEIform="index"/>SONGS OF CHEER</head><p TEIform="p">"Finally have compassion one of another, love as brethren.'1''—1 Peter, iii., 8. Mt. Lebanon.
                            N. Y. 1. We would spread the joy of blessing far and near, 2. Oh, ever is the loving
                            word the best, We would speak the loving word the heart to cheer, It calms the heart by sin
                            and want oppressed, Like merry birds of spring, Glad music we will sing, With the murmur
                            of a prayer, We will still the waves of care, In our happy, happy songs of cheer. And bid
                            the troubled spirit rest. <pb n="16" id="p18" TEIform="pb"/> 16 THE MANIFESTO. SONGS OF CHEER. Chorus.
                            Solo. Sing the songs, happy songs of cheer, Sing' the songs happy songs of cheer, Oh, that
                            no heart was sad, We would make the whole world glad, With our happy, happy song of cheer.
                            3 Oft have we felt our inner, longing needs, Blest by a power that strengthens, clothes and
                            feeds, Like fragrant breathing flowers, We will fill the weary hours, With the incense of
                            our loving deeds. 4 Though darkened shadows fall across the way, The night will soon give
                            place to smiling day; With the sunshine of our cheer, We will chase the shadows drear, And
                            echo, echo joy alway.</p></div2><pb n="17" id="p19" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The Manifesto. January, 1896. Office of Publication" TEIform="index"/>THE MANIFESTO.
                            JANUARY, 1896. OFFICE OF PUBLICATION.</head><p TEIform="p">The Manifesto is published by the "United Society of Believers" on the first of each month,
                            and is the only work issued regularly by the Shaker Community. Its aim is to furnish a plain
                            and simple statement of the religi jus views of the Order and to inculcate the spirit of
                            righteousness. Address all communications to Henry C. Blinn, East Canterbury, Mer. Co., N".
                            H. .7o .40 One copy per year, postage paid " " six months, " "</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>NOTES ABOUT HOME</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, New York" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North Family. Dec. 1S95. The lights and shadows of autumn have passed and though the
                                wintry days are upon us, yet in our beautiful home we are sheltered from the bleak
                                storms of earth in more than an external sense. The warmth of loving hearts and the
                                light of a hope immortal, give constant cheer and are an incentive to our best efforts
                                to increase the kingdom of heaven "within and among us." We have many applications to
                                share of our bounties with the needy. The destitute from adjacent towns, church members
                                too, pass by their fellow Christians to get more generous supplies from the Shakers who,
                                they have long since learned, will never turn the needy unaided away. Late rains have
                                filled the springs, insuring us a comfortable water supply for the winter. Among the
                                special blessings we have to recount, is the preservation of the village school-house
                                with its valuable furnishings of books and charts. On Nov. 26, a little past the noon
                                hour as the teacher, Sister Ada Brown entered the school-room (a little earlier than
                                usual) she was startled by smoke and flame coming up through the register. Through her
                                presence of mind in immediately closing doors and windows and throwing on the water at
                                hand she was able to check the flame and summon assistance barely in time to save the
                                building. Cause of lire was unprotected wood casing too near the large new furnace.
                                Repairs have been made with greater security for the future. Through correspondence we
                                learn of some who appear to be seeking the higher life. May we be prepared to minister
                                to those who ask, is our prayer. We extend greetings of peace and good-will to all with
                                best wishes for a happy New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Burger, Sarah J." TEIform="persName"/>Sarah J. Burger</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="South family" TEIform="index"/>South Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. All Eight! "When we write right, we do right. When we write to right wrong we
                                do right. Hence a writer may be a writer of right, or a writer of wrong, and write all
                                right. These aphorisms teach us to be sure and write right." The drought so much feared
                                is wholly cancelled by the copious rains of the few past weeks, and again "the rivers
                                are full and the streams running over."' An old well was discovered recently by
                                explorers who were searching for new water veins. It was found at a depth of three feet
                                below the surface, covered with a door which was in perfect preservation. The well has
                                been in existence for over one hundred and twenty years, and was probably built by the
                                inhabitants who owned the land long before the Shakers possessed it. This water supplied
                                an old barn above our buildings, which is also over one hundred years old and is still
                                in good condition,— sheltering the herds on a thousand hills. The northern part of the
                                Office has been improved by the addition of a vestibule TERMS. <pb n="18" id="p20" TEIform="pb"/> 18
                                THE MANIFESTO. 8x15 ft. Elder William Anderson and Br. Conrad Human have, been making
                                preparations for a berry festival in the future. The past week they have set out over
                                nine hundred vines of the rasp and blackberry varieties. "May the Lord bless every
                                plant." We find the "Mount Lebanon Cedar Boughs" highly entertaining. Who can tell how
                                many Lebanon Cedar Boughs were used in the building of King Solomon's Temple?</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Genevieve" TEIform="persName">Genevieve DeGraw</persName></byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Center family" TEIform="index"/>Center Family</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. Thkee months have elapsed since there have been any Home Notes from this fami-
                                ly. There is always enough to write about if some one would apply their time and energy
                                in that direction. Now you see, dear Editor, I have made an indirect confession of
                                dereliction of duty. We had a fair crop of pears which brought good returns for labor
                                expended; no plums worth speaking of, but apple crop quite large, the quality I think
                                was not so good as in former years. Corn of the sweet variety was an average crop. In
                                Bro. Alonzo's recent letter to you he made mention of my having been on a tour to the
                                West and that I might have something to say. It is true, I have made a kind of flying
                                trip through Ohio, D. C. and Pa., my first stopping-place being Circleville, the center
                                of a great sweet corn industry, where some thousands of tons are canned annually to
                                supply the middle and southern markets. I made a short stay in Chillicothe, thence to
                                Union Tillage, being met at Lebanon, Ohio by Eld. J. R. Slingerland, Edward Ayers and
                                Eldress Emily Robinson and was soon conveyed to the home of the Believers. The village
                                is located on elevated land lying between the little and big Miami rivers, one of the
                                richest portions of the state, but the long drought had spoiled the beauty of the place.
                                There was nothing green or growing. Dry and withered grass met the eye on every side.
                                The Brethren had set out a large orchard of apple and peach trees in alternate rows, but
                                owing to the dry weather they had made but a small growth. I was pleased with the order
                                and neatness everywhere visible, especially in the well-kept buildings. The Office,
                                notably, is a very fine house with all modern improvements; it was indeed, quite a
                                luxury to be so comfortably domiciled. Common corn, I am told, was a large crop this
                                year, some having eighty bushels to the acre; but wheat was a failure. I traveled almost
                                the whole length of the state and was seldom out of sight of corn. On my way home, I
                                took in Washington, D. C. and made a run through most of the public buildings, the
                                Treasury, War and Navy, the Patent Office and the Fishery Department; also the galleries
                                of the Senate Chamber and House of Representatives where many hard fought battles have
                                been waged in behalf of freedom: and yet more need to be fought for justice and right. I
                                also went into the Corcoran Art Gallery which is said to be one of the finest displays
                                of the sculptor's art there is in any place in this country. A new building is now being
                                erected to take the place of the present one, that being too small to meet the pressing
                                demands of the people. My way led through Philadelphia, and I visited Horticultural Hall
                                in which was a magnificent display of palm trees, and such a wealth of chrysanthemums I
                                never before beheld. After visiting friends in the city, I made a hasty journey across
                                New Jersey into New York, where I made a few calls and hastened toward home, where I
                                arrived on Tues., Nov. 29, having traveled about 1500 miles. Although it is wearisome to
                                travel long distances, yet I felt well repaid.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Rayson, Timothy D." TEIform="persName"/>Timothy D. Rayson</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Harvard, Massachusetts" TEIform="index"/>Harvard, Mass.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. We are now standing upon the twelfth steppingstone that makes up the year's
                                    eir<pb n="19" id="p21" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 19 cuit, ready to take another step when
                                Father Time presents it to us. The past month little has transpired of interest but to
                                the actors No more burglaries with us, but much work of the kind in towns adjoining, so
                                much so that it is not safe to leave a room unlocked for five minutes. Winter
                                preparations completed, and the farmers are busy cutting fuel, fine days, and husking
                                corn when stormy. Winter is upon us with its pains and pleasures, and we are peacefully
                                enjoying its comforts with "malice toward none and good-will toward all." Health of
                                society excellent.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bullard, Marcia M." TEIform="persName"/>Marcia M. Bullard</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shakers, New York" TEIform="index"/>Shakers, N. Y.</head><p TEIform="p">North .Family. Dec. 1895. We write with the closing month of the year giving us a
                                pleasant greeting; but time is swiftly passing and the year that has gone can never be
                                recalled. Onward must be the motto; those who have wisely improved the time that has
                                been given, happiness is their portion. We notice by The Manifesto, that many of our
                                gospel kindred have passed on to the spirit land. There is a vacancy by the
                                hearth-stone, but we shall meet in the morning light, and we trust and believe that they
                                will minister to their earth kindred in time of need. We would offer a vote of thanks to
                                the Editor aud printers of The Manifesto, for its neat appearance, and to the contrib-
                                utors for the presentation of the truth in a manner that has been most acceptable to
                                intelligent, enquiring minds. November was all that our autumn month could be for the
                                consummation of the work of the season, with rain to fill out the vacancy that existed
                                in the creeks and ponds. By the time these Notes appear, the New Year will have been
                                announced, and may it be one of joy to all of our gospel kindred.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="DeGraw, Hamilton" TEIform="persName"/>Hamilton DeGraw</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Enfield, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>Enfield, N. H.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. A happy New Year, and may it prove one vich in blessings to all the readers of
                                our Manifesto. What glorious as well as ctark records of human experiences, the tablets
                                of memoiy reveal as year after year rolls on; hkstori; s of obedience to, and violation
                                of God's commandments. From the commencement of impeachable history down to the present
                                era of facts, we can trace the line of obedience to divine and civil laws and to
                                religious faith. As a class of religionists, "We know that man's creed floes not n utter
                                So long as his deeds .-,,ienk •!:' Go.i, So long as his aim is to scatter The seeds of
                                right living abroad." Such a life teaches us that obedience to what we know is right, is
                                the school-master that classifies truth from error; and each generation demands new
                                methods for unfolding truth. "As the dead boughs pass away, fresher will the living
                                grow.' The New Year will no doubt give us ample opportunity to respond to the netils of
                                our fellow-beings-, thus calling into action the divinity of our natures. As we obey the
                                call; "Feed my lambs," we gild each day's goodness with the gold of sweet consolation,
                                thus enriching our own and other's lives. We have recently enjoyed the pleasure of
                                entertaining our venerable Br. Sullivan Wright of East Canterbury. As he related his
                                varied experiences,—within and without Zion—we were not merely inter- ested but
                                benefited also; his words of wisdom falling into receptive minds, stimulated to newness
                                of life and singleness of purpose. He has attained the advanced age of eighty-seven
                                years, is still hale, hearty and happy, full of godly zeal and soul content. What a
                                beautiful example of righteousness, and how true that such a life is the most effective
                                preaching of the gospel of Christ. True, "faith without works is dead." <pb n="20" id="p22" TEIform="pb"/> 20 THE MANIFESTO. May the New Year at its close have credited to our
                                account a larger and better list of good works. George H. Baxter. The North family at
                                this place have a herd of some thirty-three cows. Catching the influences that are
                                abroad in the air among farmers, that there are advantages to be derived from being
                                polled, they hired a man who, for a mere pittance deprived the whole herd of their
                                ornamental horns. The operation was performed very expeditiously while the cows were
                                standing in their usual places in the stable. We learn that no harm, as yet, has
                                followed this heroic practice, and as the poor creatures are not permitted to speak, we
                                may never know the whole of the story.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker Station, Connecticut" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Station, Ct.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. "Trust in God ye faithful souls, trust in Him forever." How blessed it is to
                                feel that we are under the care of Him "who doeth all things well." We delight to think
                                on God's promises to those who obey Him. Let us cling to Him who is our refuge and
                                strength, and by the cross make our lives full of joy and brightness and an honor and
                                glory to Him who has enabled us to be heirs to a kingdom that is eternal in the heavens.
                                Let us "sow peace and taste its fruitage sweet." Self-denying efforts bring sweet peace
                                and joy never ending. There is no shield from trouble and sin in a worldly life. Peace
                                reigns with the pure. First pure then peaceable. Let us be sure we are sowing the seeds
                                of truth, purity, kindness and love, which will, with good cultivation, grow and yield a
                                harvest of heavenly treasures." "America's largest bell was lately cast in Cincinnati.
                                It weighs 30,000 pounds and cost $16,000. The clapper is seven feet long and weighs TOO
                                pounds. "The deepest lake in the world is Crater lake in Oregon. It is 2,000 feet deep.
                                From the top of the Crater down to the surface of the lake is 2,010 feet." "The specie
                                in the Bank of France is stored in 800 barrels." "In Brazil there are said to be 300
                                dialects and languages spoken by the Indians." "The largest nugget of gold was found in
                                Australia." ****** * To obtain a good supply of eggs in winter, we must have young hens.
                                Pullets hatched in April or May will prove most satisfactory. Variety and plenty of
                                eggmaking material is absolutely necessary. Ground meat, bone, boiled potatoes with
                                wheat bran make the best morning meal. Whole grain should be the feed after the morning
                                ration.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Orcutt, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>Daniel Orcutt</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="East Canterbury, New Hampshire" TEIform="index"/>East Canterbury, N. H</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. Jtjst one word before the year closes We are in harmony with the great body of
                                humanity that is sending out so many hearty good wishes for the "every body's" and their
                                relations. The sermon that Santa Glaus preaches every year seems to have a wonderful
                                effect upon the minds of both old and young. Impatient thro waiting for his December
                                mission, his words are fully anticipated at an early date and the gifts at his hand are
                                noted in full, long before he sends his message. Well, the snow has made us a visit, and
                                the ice is trying to make itself ready for the sleds and skates that are to be on hand
                                at a moment's warning. The flower gardens look sorrowful. The plants that must be saved,
                                have been whrskt to a more congenial climate where they can bud and blossom to the very
                                great pleasure of their careful attendants, while others are left to endure the severe
                                storms of a long winter. All the birds and bugs and curious little insects have taken
                                leave of us, to await the return of another spring. As we seem to be rather more closely
                                confined to a special location than either a bird or a bug, <pb n="21" id="p23" TEIform="pb"/> THE
                                MANIFESTO. we must study to build around us a home that shall be filled with the
                                multiplied blessings of "God's holy mountain" so that when the storms are without we may
                                sing as does the good Christian, '"December is as pleasant as May."</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, H. C." TEIform="persName"/>H. C. Blinn</byline></div3><div3 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">[We place this article in type, agreeably to the wish of the "new compositor," as new
                                things in this line may add beauty to the page. Please see if it is not an improvement.
                                Ed.]</p></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Alfred, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Alfred, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. I am reminded that before this reaches the readers of The Manifesto, a New
                                Year will have dawned upon us, and the old year will be forever gone. We can not recall
                                it to change our lives, however much we may wish so to do. Happy is the one who has so
                                lived through the past year, that he does not wish to recall the past to undo the wrong
                                committed. Sad is the condition of the man or woman who in looking over the past can
                                find no gains, no victories; nothing but failures. To such an one I would quote the
                                words of Father James,—"It is never too late to cry to God. A soul in the belly of hell
                                can find mercy if he cries to God." He is Almighty and He will save, if we are willing
                                to be saved. God will never force us into heaven, although he delighteth not in the
                                death of the sinner, still we read that He is a jealous God. He will not accept a
                                divided service. If we love God let us serve Him. If we would enjoy heaven, let us cast
                                from our minds all that is not heavenly and make room in our hearts for the Christ
                                spirit to dwell. He promised his disciples that where he was, there they should be also.
                                If we are truly the disciples of Christ, dying as he died unto sin, and living as he
                                lived unto God, then we may expect to dwell with him. The prudent farmer, or the
                                merchantman, at the close of the year, looks over his store-house, balances his books,
                                settles his accounts and estimates his gains or losses. If such careful reckoning is
                                necessary for the prosperity in temporal affiiirs, how much greater the necessity of a
                                careful inspection of our spiritual ac counts. May we so live that we shall not be
                                ashamed to read our life record. Jack Frost has bridged the streams and ponds much to
                                the delight of the boys. \\Te have a little snow, but not enough for sledding. When we
                                get more we may be thankful. During these cold days our minds often turn to the sunny
                                South, and like the birds would like to migrate for the winter. May peace and prosperity
                                and a deeper baptism of the Holy Spirit attend the inmates of our Zion homes is the New
                                Year wish of our Alfred friends.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Casey, Fanny" TEIform="persName"/>Fanny Casey</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Union Village, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>Union Village, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. Dear Elder Henry:—I read the Home Notes with so much pleasure that I hope this
                                feature of The Manifesto, that his such a pleasant variety, and tells so much news,—and
                                nearly all of it good news — will never be omitted. Of course the spiritual and temporal
                                have to go together, but as the inward, unmanifest, and spiritual, necessarily includes,
                                and originates, all that is manifest and temporal, therefore I hope and pray most
                                fervtntlv, that I may never see the da&gt;, when t! e latter will take precedence of
                                the former. I must confess that I more than endorse the following excerpt from a writer
                                at Alfred in the Nov. number of The Manifesto: "The body must have food, clothing and
                                shelter. This is necessary and proper, but our greatest anxiety an 1 care is, (should
                                be) for our spiritual welfare. The Spirit mist be fed; and unless we are laying up
                                heavenly treasures, wi; shall surely famish and die—Spiritually." Well—at last the rain
                                has begun to fall, and we may hope for a breaking up of our water famine. So we had
                                cause for thankfulness on last Thursday, Nov. 28, for quite a quantity of water, and a
                                great many other blessings. We met in response 21 <pb n="22" id="p24" TEIform="pb"/> 22 THE MA NIFES
                                TO. to the President of the United States and rendered the same. Several of our old
                                barns have been repaired this summer and autumn, through the untiring persever- ance of
                                our good and faithful Elder Joseph. You will learn by the public papers, that our North
                                Union suit has been decided in the Supreme Court in our favor. This ends that wearisome
                                suit and we are devoutly thankful. Within a space of two or three months, two or three
                                Brethren and some five or six Sisters, from 46 down to 11 years of age, have joined our
                                family. This is another cause of great rejoicing among us, and we hope they may all be
                                able to make their calling and election sure by faithfulness in well-doing. The good
                                Sisters gave the Brethren an honorable discharge from the dining room once more, as they
                                have become numerous enough, to man that department. Your humble correspondent just
                                finished a tour of four weeks in that department. We hope to get water enough to supply
                                us for the coming year, from our present arrangements: but to make assurance doubly
                                sure, we are intending to have a well bored next spring, that will place us beyond all
                                risk of a water famine. About half of our hogs are left to us from the ravages of the
                                hog cholera, and this is much better than others fared in this west- ern country. I
                                received your philological papers and will cheerfully reduce them to practice in my
                                articles for the press, if you wish it. To me it seems a clumsy method in comparison
                                with the method of supplying a character for every elementary sound in the language. It
                                is quite a little sacrifice to write on .1x8 paper, but I will have some ready by next
                                time.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Hampton, Oliver C." TEIform="persName"/>Oliver C. Hampton</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="White Water, Ohio" TEIform="index"/>White Water, O.</head><p TEIform="p">Nov. 1895. The Manifesto is a regular and welcome visitor to our home, and no doubt also
                                to the homes of the United Societies of Believers throughout the land. It is ever filled
                                with welcome and cheerful notes and news from some of the members of the great sister
                                and brotherhood of Shakers. In these parts wTe have had a very long dry spell, as the
                                farmers term it, lasting almost five months without interruption causing many of our
                                products to fall short. Wheat sown in the early fall has not come up yet for want of
                                rain, even live stock have had a very hard time. But now the long-wished and prayed-for
                                rain has come, and for nearly twenty-four hours it has been raining without
                                interruption, reminding us again of the fact that the supreme Ruler of the universe,
                                sends us all good and needful things at the proper time, making good these words: "So
                                long as the earth shall stand, there shall not cease seed-time and harvest;" all we have
                                to do is to learn to labor and wait. The very fact that it rains and that the sun shines
                                upon and for all, is a very strong argument in favor of communistic life, in the dispen-
                                sation of these great blessings. There are no step-children, all share alike. Selfish-
                                ness has no place in nature, except in the heart of man where, on account of his high
                                estate, it ought least to be. John (J. Ludivig. Dec. 1895 In looking over the Nov.
                                number of The Manifesto I find that White Water is not represented, which I think is an
                                oversight. I like to read the home items to know what our gospel Brethren and Sisters
                                are doing. It is encouragement given from the right source. Eecently we enjoyed a visit
                                from two of our Sisters from South Union, and one Brother and four Sisters from
                                Watervliet, O. which was a source of great pleasure. The dry season which has prevailed
                                for so long a time, is at last broken. We are now having an abundance of rain. Some
                                three inches fell at one time. Our crops were injured to some extent by the drouth,
                                but.still we are thankful. <pb n="23" id="p25" TEIform="pb"/> THE MANIFESTO. 23 Some improvements are
                                in progress, which take time and money. Our little family numbers nineteen members, and
                                there are about as many Brothers as Sisters. With this little note I want to wish all
                                our gospel friends a happy and prosperous New Year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Parker, L." TEIform="persName"/>L. Parker</byline></div3><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Sabbathday Lake, Maine" TEIform="index"/>Sabbathday Lake, Me.</head><p TEIform="p">Dec. 1895. One glance at the calendar shows that the last chapter of the Old Year has
                                come. The book is about to be closed and a New Year whose pages remain unread is before
                                us. Will it be too late to repeat with the many "A Merry Christmas to you all?" if so
                                "Glad and Happy New Year's wishes" may not come amiss at this time. It is interesting to
                                read the many beautiful sketches of home-life from the different Societies throughout
                                our land, also the soul-stirring testimonies from the able writers of our monthly, all
                                of which give pleasure to its readers. We at Sabbathday Lake are astir not- withstanding
                                the "Summer Visitors" have gone to warmer climes. There seems to be plenty to do. The
                                Brethren have recently ploughed nine acres of land for another year's cultivation. The
                                cows are supplying the family with dairy products and the surplus cream is disposed of
                                at a Butter Factory near by. Sisters are not idle. Some are engaged in household
                                occupations, others may be found at the loom weaving rugs. So passes out the old year.</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cummings, Ada S." TEIform="persName"/>Ada S. Cummings</byline></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Publication" TEIform="index"/>EXCHANGES.
                        </head><p TEIform="p"> Holiday book-buyers, this year will find a wealth of tempting and attractive
                            publications, from the expensively printed anil bound edition de luxe of new or standard
                            works down to the inexpensive, though attractive, illustrated books for children. An
                            impartial and comprehensive survey of the whole field of holiday publications will appear in
                            two issues of The Sunday School Times of December 7 and December 14 respectively. These
                            articles tell the prospective purchaser what the new books are, what they contain, how much
                            they cost, and where they can be ob tainert, in addition to an interesting and ctitical
                            judgment on their relative merits, John D. Wattles &amp; Co., 1031 Walnut St., Phil-
                            adelphia, Pa. The Pulpit is a nice monthly magazine of some fifty pages, containing the
                            complete sermons of six or eight of the most "gifted preachers of our age." The October
                            number contains a sermon by Alexander MacLaren— Baptist. S. S. Mitchell—Presbyterian. Henry
                            Elliott Mott—Presbyterian. J. "B. Whitford— Methodist. L. A. Sherman, on Spiritualism. Wm
                            .R. Huntington—Protestant Episcopal. Edited by G. Holzapfel, Fredericksbuug, Pa.
                            Mackintoshes and Rubber Clothing—¦ large commissions can be earned by retailing to users.
                            Sample free. Manufacturer, P. O. 1371 New York.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>Deaths</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="index"/>Rhoda Blake
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Blake, Rhoda" TEIform="persName">Rhoda Blake</persName>, at Center Family, Mt. Lebanon, N.
                                Y. Dec. 1, 1895. Age 87 years and 2 mo. H. R. A.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>Books &amp; Papers</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Popular monthly" TEIform="index"/>Popular Monthly
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Christmas number of Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly is already out, and will hardly be
                                surpassed in richness and beauty of pictorial illustration, or in seasonable variety of
                                literary contents, by anything that mayfollow during the holiday season. The opening
                                article, upon "Heroines and Heroine Worship," affords a vehicle for nearly a score of
                                exquisite reproductions from the old and modern master-painters. A similar opportunity
                                is found in the intensely poetic story by A . Cressy Morrison, of "The Man who Resembled
                                Christ," which in addition is illu-tnited with some original drawings of rare delicacy.
                                In "The City of Dordrecht," George (J. Unite fairly revels in the picturesque, giving us
                                eight of his loveliest aquarelle.-.. The great literary feature of the number is
                                Tolstoi's latest story, "Master and Man," specially translated from the Russian for
                                Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly, and illustrated by Fogarty. A charming novelty is "A
                                Daughter of the Samurai," by Teiichi Yamagata, being an up-to-date Japanese love story
                                written in English by a Japanese author. Amongst other contributions deserving special
                                mention are "Heroines of Chivalry,"by Mrs. Frank Leslie; "Literary Boston,"by Lillian
                                Whiting "The St. Nicholas Society," by Wilf P. Pond ; "How the Wixes Joined the Four
                                hundred." by A. Oakey Hall; and "A Legend of Jeanne d'Arc,"—the latter being a poem by
                                Francois Coppee. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Pleasant hours for girls and boys" TEIform="index"/>Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls
                            </head><p TEIform="p">"How to Win at Football" is one of the interesting features of the
                                Christmas number of Frank Leslie's Pleasant Hours for Boys and Girls. It is by Wilf. P.
                                Pond, and gives some good siiggestions for the formation of a football team that would
                                be almost invincible. Another valuable article is "The Children of Corea," by A. B. de
                                Guerville; Then there is a Christmas story by Judith Spencer;</p></div3><pb n="24" id="p26" TEIform="pb"/><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hasting's birthday book" TEIform="index"/>Hasting's  birthday book
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Hasting's birthday book, other short stories; an illustrated Christmas poem by G. A.
                                Davis; the continuation in "A l;luek\ Fight," by Euward S. Ellis, and "i hree Little"
                                Heroines," by Jeannette H. Walworth; the description of a novel game, an 1 a, story for
                                little folks—all handsomely illustrated. The editor chats entertainingly an i wisely
                                aoout the new books for boys and girl-,, and there are a number of puzzles. Is a dainty
                                booklet printed in light blue, salmon-pink and giay tones—a splendid illustration of the
                                beauties of art applied to printing—The Ladies' Home Jouksal announces some of its
                                leading literary and artistic features for 1SV6. There will be a series of papers upon
                                the domestic and social side of Washingtun uy General A. W. Greely, U. S. A.; another
                                by~Ex-i'resident Harrison, telling of "This Country of Ours;" a third by Mary Anderson
                                de Mavarro, who writes of her stage experiences, her struggles for recognition and
                                artistic triumphs, with a supplemental article telling of her life and surroundings
                                to-day. In a lighter vein, Mary E. Wilkins will present a series of ".Neighborhood
                                Types" papers, pen pictures of quaint and familiar personages— Ae'.v Enghuuiers; and
                                Jerome K. Jerome will reflect old England life in a number of "Stories of the
                                Town"—stories of London—in his inimitable, crisp style. "William the Conqueror," Rudyard
                                Kipling's most fascinating romance, is also among the features for 1896, and Julia
                                Magruder's delighting serial, "The Violet," will continue through a considerable poition
                                of the year. Besides these two popular authors there will be short stories by Bret
                                Harte, Lilian Bell, Ian Maclaren, Sophie Swett, Frank R. Stockton, Sarah Orne Jewett, R.
                                0. V. Meyers, Will N. Harben, Caroline Leslie Field, Jane Austen (posthumous) and other
                                prominent writers. Dr. Parkhurst will write a series of forcible articles for youngmen,
                                applicable to their daily life, while the girls will be written to by Mrs. A. D. T.
                                Whitney, and Edith X. Thomas, the gifted poetess, will be represented by her finest
                                verse and prose. James Whitcomb Riley will contribute a number of poems, varied in theme
                                and treatment. In its musical offerings the Journal will be unusually replete. Among the
                                best things promised is a minuet by Paderewski, the famous pianist; a waltz by John
                                Philip Sousa, the "March King;" compositions by Sir Arthur Sullivan, composer of
                                '¦Pinafore," "Mikado," etc.; Reginald de Koven, composer of "Robin Hood," "Rob Roy,"
                                etc.; Edward Jakobowski, Bruno Oscar Klein and others. There will be instructive musical
                                treatises by Mine. Melba Mme. Blauvelt, Mine. Clementine de Vere Sapio, Mrs. Hamilton
                                Mott, Miss Maud Powell, Benjamin Davits, Ch-arles Adams, Thomas a'Becket, Frederic
                                Peakes, George Chadwick and others. Artistically the Journal gives, rich promise, and
                                during the next year will present •leveral groups of Kate Greenaway's bonhie little
                                people; Charles Dana Gibson's best work on new lines and gome of Albert Lyneh's newest
                                creations. W. L. Taylor, W. T. Smed- ley, W. Hamilton Gibson, Alice Barber ¦ tephens,
                                William Martin Johnson, EricPape, \V. A. Rogers, Reginald Birch, Frank 0. Small, ;;.
                                West Clinedinst, T. de Thulstrup, A. B. Frost, E. W. Keinble, Irving R. Wiles, Abby K.
                                Underwood and other artists of such commanding prominence will contribute their h aest
                                drawings. In its departments the Journal promises to be stronger than ever, and n.ore
                                comprehensive in its scope of practical in formation. In this direction it will print a
                                series of Illustrated articles on home building, giving plans and details for the
                                construe tion of medium-size houses. The Ladies' Home Journal for 1896, in fact, will be
                                complete, and uniquely so. "The Hasting's Birthday Book." With a well filled library of
                                beautiful books and even including the great, the ponderous Dictionary and also the
                                great and much to be desired illustrated Bible, there would still be an unfinished set
                                of books if the ready reference of the Birthday Book was not to be found at our right
                                hand. This little book of some four hundred pages has a fund of choice selections and
                                something well worth remembering for every day in the year, and an ample space for the
                                inseition of any name with necessary dates that may be wanted to make up a pretty and
                                interesting little volume. A nice Photograph of the Author accompanies each book and his
                                venerable and silent presence may have a loving and salutary effect upon all who hold in
                                remembrance the names of near and dear friends. Published at 47 Cornhill, Boston, Mass.</p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Phrenological journal and science of health" TEIform="index"/>
                                The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Phrenological Journal and Science of Health for December begins with an illustrated
                                phrenograph from a personal examination of the famous New York lawyer, Dr. William J.
                                O'Sullivan, which is not only a close analysis of the gentleman's character, but
                                contains also information pertaining to the talents required by the legal profession in
                                general. It will be read with especial interest by all law students as well as practic-
                                ing attorneys. Mr. George C. Bartlett concludes his tour in Switzerland. "Practical
                                Psychology," by Dr. H. S. Drayton, is the continuation of a valuable series especially
                                adapted for teachers and philosophical students. "What Your Palm tells," by Dora M.
                                Morrell, describes a number of the most important and easily observed signs of character
                                in the form of the hand. Dr. Beall gives an interesting study of the Duke and Duchess of
                                Marlborough with two handsome engravings illustrating the art of reading character from
                                photographs. The novelette, "A Phrenologist's Prediction," by Anna Olcott Commelin, is
                                concluded. In the department of Child Culture, Prof. Nelson Sizer describes "Precious
                                Treasures in Earthen Vessels," w7ith several illustrations and valuable advice to
                                mothers. "A Study in Sociology," "Another Drink Cure," "A Game that Cultivates
                                Courtesy," are features of the Science of Health Department. In the editorial pages a
                                prospectus of many new things for the coming year is given. A national phrenological
                                convention ir&gt; honor of Dr. Gail's centenary is proposed for 1896. Mrs. Charlotte
                                Fowler Wells announces her forthcoming book of phrenological biography and the editor
                                pays his respects to phrenologisal skeptics by contrasting two portraits of widely
                                dissimilar heads. New York: Fowler &amp; Wells Co., 27 East Twenty-first street.
                                $1.50 per year. </p></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Millenial Kingdom" TEIform="index"/>The Millennial Kingdom
                            </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Redding" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p">
                                The Millennial Kingdom is an astonishing book which shows that we
                                Americans, are the Lost Ten Tribes of Israel, and are to rise to high spiritual light
                                and lead the world in the Millennial Kingdom on earth 1,000 years. Death will cease.
                                People will live hundreds of years like a tree. (Isaiah lxv., 20, 22.) Its preparation
                                is causing present commotion. Letters from Jerusalem. Many subjects. Intensely
                                interesting. 300 pages. Paper bound 50 cts. Cloth, $1.00. Send stamps to Redding
                                (author) Navarre, Kansas.24 </p><pb id="p27" TEIform="pb"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of hygeio-therapy" TEIform="index"/>The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The Journal of Hygeio-Therapy. yovtnr ber. Contents. Life Science Papers; Solteir ing
                                Water; Medical Science: The Science of Phrenology; Prof. Pasteur's Work; A Horticultural
                                School for Girls; Health Topics, etc. Dr. T. V. Gifforcl &amp; Co., Kokomo, lml. The
                                Funk &amp; Wagnalls Company celebiated on November 27th, the first anniversary of
                                the completion of their "Standard Dictionary," by putting to press the SOth thousand of
                                thii grea't work. This is a very large number of dictionaries to print in a single year.
                                The publishers' mathematician has figured out that, if these 90,000 sets were piled flat
                                one upon another, they would reach nearly seven miles in height; and. the printed pages,
                                if laid end to end, would extend over 40,000 miles, one and three fifths times around
                                the globe ! But the most significant of the triumphs of the first year of this
                                remarkable dictionary andthe most gratifying to Americans, is the wonderful reception
                                given the work by the most exacting of the linguistic critics in England. Especially is
                                this so when we remember how reluctant, naturally enough, the English are to look to a
                                foreign country for a dictionary of their own tongue. It is something extraordinary for
                                an American work of this kind to elicit words of such enthusiastic praise as those
                                uttered by such scholars of the Oxford University as Professor Sayceand Max Muller, and
                                well-known scholars of other English universities and such journalistic critics as those
                                of the London Standard, Saturday Review, Notes and Queries, Nature, London Times,
                                Westminster Review Atlitnaum, Mark-Lane Express, Scotsman, Liverpool Post, St. Jame's
                                Budget. The latter closes his critical review with the following superlative
                                indorsement: "To say that it is perfect in form and scope is not extravagance of praise,
                                and to say that it is the most valuable dictionary of the Eng lish language is but to
                                repeat the obvious. The Standard Dictionary should be the pride of literary America, as
                                it is the admiration of literary England." May the triumphs of the second year of this
                                Dictionary equal those of the first; they could not well exceed them! Another feature of
                                this first anniversary of the publication of the Standard Dictionary was the forwarding,
                                from the Pennsylvania depot for Michigan, of a big freight car loaded wholly with
                                Standard Dictionaries. Large letters on muslin across the sides of the car told the
                                public of the contents. Editorial rooms of the Standard Dictionary. To the Editor:—A
                                very grave "wrong is being perpetrated against the American public by a reprinter of one
                                of the English competitors of the Funk &amp; "Wagnalls Standard Dictionary—a wrong
                                that cannot be excused by the exigencies of commercial rivalry. As is well known, in all
                                unabridged dictionaries it is necessary to give the definitions of certain indelicate
                                words. Eighteen of these words (selected out of a vocabulary of over 300,000 terms in
                                the Standard) have been collated and printed with their definitions by the reprinter of
                                this English dictionary, and circulars containing them are being distributed among
                                teacheiT, school trustees, and parents all through this country, stirring up a iilthy
                                agitation that will end, unless irowmd down by the public prtss and other leaders of
                                public opinion, in setting people of prurient minds and childien everywhere to
                                ransacking dictionarits ior this class of words. One of these publications contains such
                                outrageously unjust comments as the following: "About two years ago the publishing house
                                of Funk &amp; Wagnalls brought into the world a monstrosity entitled the Standarn
                                Dictionary of the English Language." "So far as relates to its collection of obscene,
                                filthy, blasphemous, slang, and profane words, it has no cc untupart in dictionaries of
                                the English Language." It is but iair to the press and scholars of England to say that
                                the English critics have in no way seconded this unfair as- sault, but are unanimous in
                                the most unqualified indorsement of the American work, the Standard Dictionary,
                                expressing in many ways the same opinion as that of the St. James's Budget [weekly
                                edition of the St. James's Gazette,] London, which said: "To say that it is perfect in
                                form and scope is not extiavaganee of praise, and to say that it is the most valuable
                                Dictionary of the English language is hut to repeat the obvious. The Standaid Dictionaiy
                                should be the pride of literary America as it is the admiration of literary England."
                                The utter insincerity of this attack on the Standard is seen in the fact that nearly
                                every one of these 18 words is in the English work which is published by this reprinter,
                                and it contains other words so grossly indelicate and withal so rarely used as to have
                                heen txeludtd from the Standard and from nearly all the other dictionaries. Fiitten out
                                of the eighteen words (and others of the same class) are, and properly so, in the
                                Century Dictionary, and they are to be found, with scarcely an exception, in every other
                                reputable unabridged dictionary, and this class of words is invariably recorded in the
                                lead- ing dictionaries of all languages. Since this gross attack has been made wehave
                                submitted to Charles A. Dana and to a number of well-known educators the question
                                whether we committed an error in admitting into the Standard this class of words. The
                                answer has been without an exception, "You did not." The fact is, extraordinary care was
                                used by the editors of the Standard "to protect the language." Of the more than 500,000
                                words collected by the hundreds <pb id="p28" TEIform="pb"/> of readers employed to search all books
                                of merit from Chaucer's time to the present, over 200,000 were excluded wholly from the
                                vocabulary; hence there was no need and no effort to pad the vocabulary. The rules of
                                exclusion and inclusion were most carefully made and rigidly enforced. A most perplexing
                                problem from beginning to end was how to reduce the vocabulary, not how to enlarge it.
                                Compression was carried by many devices to the extremest degree. The editors who passed
                                upon the admission of words numbered over one hundred of the best known writers and
                                scholars in America and England. To accuse such men of "fllthiness" is to do a wrong of
                                the gravest degree. It is the business of a dictionary to record words, not to create,
                                nor fco destroy them; to a.iswer inquirers concerning the spelling, pronunciation, and
                                meaning of all words that are used to any considerable exttsnt, not to obliterate those
                                it does not fancy. Whether a word has a right fco exist or not, the final arbiter is the
                                people, not fie dictionary. The dictionary, as says Trench, should be the inventory of
                                the language, and, as says the Encyclopedia Britannica under the term DICTIONARY, it
                                "should include all of the words of the language .... A complete and Standard Dictionary
                                should make no choice. Words obsolete and newly coined barbarous, vulgar, and aifected,
                                temporary, provincial, and local, belonging to peculiar classes, professions, pursuits,
                                and trades, should all find their place,—the only question being as to the evidence of
                                their existence,—not indeed, all received with equal honor and regard, but with their
                                characteristics and defects duly not- ed and painted out." Improper or indelicata words,
                                when it was found necessary to admit them into the Standard, were blacklisted as low,
                                vulgar, slang, and printed in small type. It did not saem to the editors that an
                                unabridged dictionary could go further without justly incurring blame. To collect from
                                such a work words of the class referred to and publish them is as great an outrage as to
                                collect from the Bible tha many indelicate words and passa^es to be found there, or
                                those from Shakespeare (some of these 18 words are found both in the Bible and in
                                Shakespeare,) and then to print and scatter abroad the collection, saying: "See what a
                                foul book is the Bible; see what an obscene and blasphemous work is Shakes- peare." The
                                publication and distribution of th.353 circulars is a gross assault upon public decency.
                                An agent who attempts to exhibit such a printed circular surely should not be listened
                                to for a moment; he is a public enemy, and should be turned from every decent door. The
                                old story will be remembered of a woman accosting Samuel Johnson, shortly after his
                                dictionary had been p wished, with, "Doctor Johnson, I am so uorry that you put in your
                                dictionary tl\e naughty words." "Madam", retorted the Doctor, "I am sorry that you have
                                been looking for them." Respectfully, I. K. Funk. OUR HOLIDAY NUMBER Will reach our
                                readers in time for our "Holiday Greeting," as well as for your holiday purchases. Word
                                and Works is always on time, like Mr. Hick's storm predictions. Our advertisers have
                                caught the spirit, and are offering "timely" Christmas and N"ew Year's gifts in our
                                columns. Our agents who are working for "premiums," will be delighted to find our
                                "Premium List" in this number. (January, 1896.) Help yourselves, friends, and help
                                others at the same time. The holidays are harvest days also. Agents who are looking for
                                "snaps" will find one in canvassing for "Our Family, Its Record to Greatness and Honor,"
                                by Rev. Irl R. Hicks, editor of Word and Works. Get up early and work late. Keep at it
                                all winter, and make money and friends, as you never did before. From this same
                                Publishing Co. of Word and Works, comes "The Rev. Irl R. Hicks Almanac for 1898. In
                                common with all other Almanacs, the reader will find full information for e'very month,
                                in the rising and setting of the sun and also the varied changes of the moon which
                                becomes so interesting to many minds. The diagrams of the storms and weather forecasts
                                for each month, is a novel feature and will be studied with deep interest by all who are
                                so fortunate as to obtain a copy. Following the table of contents we have, The Evolution
                                of Storms. The Air and the Barometer, 111. Hints on the Telescope, 111. The Monthly
                                Heavens, 111. Cyclones and Tornadoes, 111. etc. etc. The Word and Works Publishing Co.
                                St. Louis, Mo. 2201 Locust St.</p></div3></div2><!--
                    <div2 type="section">
                        <head>
                            <index level1="Advertisements"/>[Advertisements]</head>
                        <p>[Advertisements deleted.]</p>
                    </div2>
                    --></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>