<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="spe-sha-ts0706" TEIform="TEI.2"><teiHeader type="text" status="new" TEIform="teiHeader"><fileDesc TEIform="fileDesc"><titleStmt TEIform="titleStmt"><title level="j" TEIform="title">The Shaker</title></titleStmt><extent n="pagination" TEIform="extent">8</extent><publicationStmt TEIform="publicationStmt"><publisher TEIform="publisher">Hamilton College Library</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Clinton, New York, United States of America</pubPlace></publicationStmt><sourceDesc default="NO" TEIform="sourceDesc"><biblStruct default="NO" TEIform="biblStruct"><monogr TEIform="monogr"><imprint TEIform="imprint"><publisher TEIform="publisher">United Societies</publisher><pubPlace TEIform="pubPlace">Shakers, New York</pubPlace><biblScope type="volume" TEIform="biblScope">7</biblScope><biblScope type="issue" TEIform="biblScope">6</biblScope><date value="18770601" TEIform="date">June 1877</date><biblScope type="pages" TEIform="biblScope">41-48</biblScope></imprint></monogr></biblStruct></sourceDesc></fileDesc></teiHeader><text TEIform="text"><body TEIform="body"><div0 type="volume" n="7" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div0"><pb n="41" id="p1" TEIform="pb"/><div1 type="issue" n="6" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div1"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER OFFICIAL MONTHLY.—PUBLISHED BY THE UNITED SOCIETIES. " 0a prexdt the ftmgttom of %o\"
                        Jpjre tentimonn of ctminl tvnth. Yol YIL G. A. LOMAS, Editor, Shakers, N. Y. JUNE, 1877. ; N. A.
                        BRIGGS, Publisher, i Shaker Village, N. H. No. 6.</p><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Virgin character" TEIform="index"/>The Virgin Character</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Martin, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName"/>ELIZABETH MARTIN</byline><p TEIform="p">"They who have kept their spirit's virgin whiteness Undimmed by folly, and unstained by sin,
                            And made their foreheads radiant with the brightness Of the pure truth whose temple is
                            within,— They shall see God." "Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God." This
                            beautiful beatitude of our Savior contains an allimportant theme for contemplation by the
                            true religionist; for as breath gives vitality to the whole body, so should purity of heart
                            and life invigorate and vitalize the soul, the fountain from whence flows love to God,
                            good-will and good deeds towards all mankind. It is the pure oil of religion, which, lighted
                            by divine love, sheds perpetual light on the pathway of life. As the term virgin signifies
                            pure, it may be applied to any perfectly pure substance as virgin gold, virgin soil, virgin
                            snow, meaning pure gold, pure soil, pure snow; so the term virgin character, including both
                            sexes, means pure men and pure women. The term celibate, as illustrative of the pure life of
                            the Shaker, is not sufficiently broad to define the real basic principle of our institution
                            ; for there are many celibates, while there are few virgins. The one prime element of the
                            virgin character is love to God; this permeates the whole being ; the imaginations,
                            thoughts, desires and aspirations are all heavenward. The virgin cannot deal falsely, for he
                            loves his neighbor as himself, selfish, for he sees the He cannot be ima^e of God reflected
                            on every object, and is only satisfied with pure, active benevolence, pure truth and pure
                            love, as. the governing principles of a pure life throughout. Canterbury, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feed my sheep" TEIform="index"/>Feed My Sheep</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Webster, E. H." TEIform="persName"/>E. H. WEBSTER</byline><p TEIform="p">Ere the most patient of all suffering spirits had passed the mortal agony, Peter, grieved,
                            replied, "thou knowest all things; thou knowest that I love thee." But as if to require
                            proof of that love he says once more, " feed my sheep." Jesus had gathered together a little
                            rlock and now the great consideration was how to protect and keep them, and in his wisdom he
                            saw that if fed with suitable food, they would be sustained and grow to become a powerful
                            influence on the earth. Called out from broad pastures of evil into narrow fields of grace,
                            the heavenly shepherd realized that to make them grow, there must be something more than
                            restraining means, even a full supply of life-giving nourishment, hence his thrice-repeated
                            ejaculation, "feed my sheep." But what is the food the spiritual lambs need to aid their
                            growth in the divine life? Can aught be better than the words of Christ adapted to their
                            comprehension, and lived out in loving and continual example ? This must certainly be
                            strengthgiving and sustaining. "Feed me with food convenient for me," said the psalmist; and
                            we know that in nature every living thing in order to grow and properly develop, must find
                            the elements its being needs, to form the new particles which are to supply the wearing-out
                            of tissue continually going on. And as the daily bread must do this for the mortal body just
                            as really does the spirit, quickened into life, need spiritual food to make it grow and
                            thrive. When Jesus said "I have bread to eat that ye know not of," he only asseverated this
                            idea, for he had become so spiritualized in his life that the ministrations from the
                            spirit-world almost supplied at times, wants which are so pressing to the natural man. And
                            the joy he found in ministering to minds diseased and thereby relieving suffering, was his
                            life and his element. A like devotion to holy uses will make it our meat and our drink to do
                            the will of our Father; and the intense hunger and thirst we feel at times after
                            righteousness, will be filled according to the promise ; for righteousness, which issimply
                            right-doing, right-thinking and rightand yet lingered around his mourningj being, when
                            practiced by each individflock, out of his anguished soul he Jual, will constitute the sum
                            of goodness, breathed the words, " Simon, son of Jonas, lovest thou me?" "Yea, Lord, thou
                            knowest that I love thee." He saith unto him " feed my sheep." Three times he repeated the
                            question, and justice and equity, which will remove the wrongs of earth, and bring about the
                            blessed era when righteousness shall reign. Harvard, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Aged reformer" TEIform="index"/>An Aged Reformer</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Evans, F. W." TEIform="persName"/>F. W. EVANS</byline><p TEIform="p">In conversation, this morning, with an octogenarian brother, he related to me his experience.
                            Pointing to a tobacco-box in a pigeon-hole over his lead, he said " For scvcitty-one years [
                            chewed tobacco. For the last jive vears I have not taken a particle." Opening a drawer, he
                            handed out a arge can, half filled with what he called the best quality of tobacco, saying:
                            "I left using the narcotic voluntarily. It did not injure my health. But it was a great act
                            of self-denial. In the spiritworld, I shall not be afflicted by a desire for tobacco. It is
                            far easier to break a bad habit here than there."</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Tried as gold" TEIform="index"/>Tried as Gold</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Witham, Maria" TEIform="persName"/>MARIA WITHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">As gold is purged of worthless dross, Under the furnace blast—¦ Grows purer by the seeming
                            loss, And shines undimmed at last;— As brightness, like the morning sky, When winds are soft
                            and fair, Reflecting to the Master's eye, His image mirrored there— So by the fierce and
                            angry fires, Of trial and of care, May we, if so the soul aspires, The Savior's image wear.
                            These come to purge from clinging dross, To purify the soul; To bring us nearer to the
                            cross, And Heaven's complete control. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Epitomic history of the Watervliet shakers, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>Epitomic History of the
                            Watervliet Shakers No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Buckingham, D. A." TEIform="persName"/>D. A. BUCKINGHAM</byline><p TEIform="p">Of their location. In the first settlement of believers at Watervliet, the place selected for
                            location by the early pioneers was about seven miles northwest from Albany, in a dense
                            forest, beside a small stream, along which was a dismal swamp of huge bogs, wild grass and
                            weeds. The stream of water coursed its way rather northward, but so very winding in its
                            course it was judged that four rods would make scarcely one when straightened. It frequently
                            formed little pools or sloughholes, some three, four, and five feet in depth. Where now
                            stands the principal building of the Church family, there was then a pool of water nearly
                            eight feet in depth, and served as a place of resort and amusement for the young in swimming
                            and washing. This said stream, since called and inown as " Scherluyn creek," was shortly
                            after straightened by cutting an entirely new channel, while the old one and the many
                            slough-holes connected therewith, wrere filled with dirt and sand drawn from the hills some
                            short distance away. It was the practice of the leaders and all the male portion of the
                            family, with some of the females, :o turn out occasionally, cutting and piling bogs, and
                            filling up the deep boles. But soon the bogs would again appear and then another conflict
                            would ensue to subdue them ; and so it continued, one scene after another, season after
                            season, until one dry summer settled the controversy, for the ground and bogs took fire,
                            which destroyed them. Finally a portion of the lowland wras so much improved as to yield a
                            wild grass, which could be secured by the brethren conveying it to the rising ground on
                            poles. It would require much space to describe the then appearance of the place, to show the
                            difference between that and what a visitor would now behold. Tens of thousands of loads of
                            sand have been carted or carried from the sand-hills not far distant, to fill holes and
                            raise the low-land for acres around where the village of the Church family now stands. For
                            many years it was the practice for all who were able to work, to turn out with teams and
                            equipages on Saturday afternoons to draw sand for these purposes. Often when digging for
                            water, laying drains or aqueducts, we now come upon old stumps, logs or trees, three, four
                            and more feet under ground, which have been hid from public view for seventy-five or one
                            hundred years, which still are as sound as a nut. Elder John Hocknell, one of the number
                            that came from England, did much in the line of clearing the land. He seemed to take
                            pleasure in subduing the bogs anil digging out old stumps. Morrell Baker, Jr., one of the
                            active laborers and a scribe of those days, writes : " When I consider how much labor we
                            performed, and how well we soon began to live under existing circumstances, it seems to me
                            almost a miracle ; for one half of the work then done brought no immediate profit, but was
                            only fixing the face of the earth for the benefit of after generations, and laying a
                            foundation for the future ; and in all this we never hired a day's labor to assist us. <pb n="42" id="p2" TEIform="pb"/> 42 THE SHAKER,. "Some have wondered how we per- e formed so much and
                            lived; but the i story is short and easily told. It was S this : When there was any hard job
                            to t be done, all had notice of it beforehand ( and prepared themselves for the task, i and
                            to move at the call. None were : excused who were able to go. No ' matter for individual
                            business, whether t profitable or not. ' Our union is our t strength,' was the motto, and
                            herein 1 was the profit and the blessing. The * deacons led the band and all moved as : the
                            heart of one. Consequently the hills were laid low, the^ valleys raised, ( and the rough
                            places made smooth."</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="God's word" TEIform="index"/>God's Word</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Eades, Hervey L." TEIform="persName"/>HERVEY L. EADES</byline><p TEIform="p">Notwithstanding the subject of what con- l stitutes God's word has perplexed the world ( for
                            ages and been widely discussed and much { befogged by writers, so that agreement has ^
                            hitherto seemed impossible, still, I think it can be made plain to the common mind: ( This
                            is the task I have now proposed for my- 1 self. It will first be necessary to state what '
                            we are to understand by the term God. It is ' hardly sufficient to say the " Supreme Being,"
                            1 as a finite being may be supreme over all 1 other finite beings. Such was Christ; but !
                            Christ was not God, only as God-man, the son of God. We understand by the term ( God in its
                            highest sense to mean, Infinite ! Spirit, omniscient and omnipresent; then to ! speak of
                            more than one Infinite God is child- ' ish, equal to declaring there is no infinite ^ God,
                            but being infinite in his presence, as ' well as his power in all worlds and all places, 1
                            in all humans and all things, at all times, makes all works his own except that which is
                            changed, obstructed or counteracted by free '¦ agents, and for which the free agents are '
                            themselves accountable. We admit that the doctrine of free agency is disputed by some
                            philosophers of note, and although we are conscious of this freedom, it is difficult of
                            demonsti-ation in the face of necessity. The non-acceptance of this doctrine is where the
                            honest Hebrew philosopher, Benedict De Spinoza, missed the mark, who, in his Ethics, throws
                            all acts, causes and effects back to infinity, making them rest with God; disagreeing with
                            Locke, who thus manfully comes to the rescue: "Whatever necessity determines in the pursuit
                            of real bliss, the same necessity with the same force establishes suspense, deliberation and
                            scrutiny of each successive desire, whether the gratification of it does not interfere with
                            our true happiness and mislead us from it. The government of the passions is the right
                            improvement of this liberty," &amp;c. Now the word of God to free agents, is the
                            operation of the ever-present Infinite Spirit on the higher consciousness of their
                            unfolding. God does not impress his word on any above and beyond the condition to which he
                            has unfolded them, else his word to them would be incomprehensible and therefore void; hence
                            it is not unreasonable to affirm that it was the same God or ever-present Infinite Spirit
                            operating upon the higher consciousness and highest unfolded condition of Moses, when the
                            utterance was "an eye for an eye," that operated upon the still higher unfoldment of Christ,
                            when the utterance was "love your enemies." To affirm that both were equally God's word,
                            affords no evidence of contradiction or change in the mind of God; it only shows that the
                            latter had attained to a higher state of development than the former, comprehending the
                            attributes of love and mercy, in a degree which the former had not reached, thus doing away
                            with the subterfuge that one God directed Moses, another Christ, and another the Quakers and
                            Shakers, and so on, thus losing sight of the omnipresence of God altogether, and concealing
                            the grand truth that the word of God to all humans, heathens, Protestants, Catholics,
                            Oneidians, Quakers or Shakers, is the operation of the infinite on their higher
                            consciousness, which if obeyed brings present justification to each class, or each
                            individual of such class. But justification is not salvation nor redemption, these are
                            attainable only through Christ; that is by seeking until we find him, where he has "placed
                            his name for salvation," and then by " walking as he walked and overcoming as he overcome."
                            But we say God is dual: very well, but this, properly understood, does not destroy his
                            unity. He is dual only in the subordinate sense. He exists equally in both male and female;
                            He is therefore male in the masculine, and female in the feminine. The ever-present infinite
                            Spirit speaking by the organs of the man is the Father, the same spirit speaking by the
                            woman is the Mother,—His unity remaining inviolate, and unity and duality are thus recon- j
                            ciled. All the anti-christian fuss about a fixed throne, located in space somewhere "'twixt
                            earth, sea and skies," is pure fiction, chimera, with no rational basis, as such notion
                            destroys the idea of his infinity. This, however, does not conflict with the idea of his
                            kingdom in heaven, where Christ is the visible head, who is still directed and controlled by
                            the operation of the Divine Essence on his higher consciousness, and to whom all must bow,
                            angels or men. But the God that can go and come from one part of space to another is finite
                            and must be some subordinate creature to whom the term God is applied. Moses and Jesus were
                            God to the people in a subordinate sense, they being the highest unfolded of the race; One
                            under the natural law, the other under the spiritual. The idea is very absurd and finds no
                            support in reason or revelation, of the Infinite focalizing his whole self in either;
                            because whilst operating on their consciousness, He was at the same time operating, holding
                            and guiding millions of worlds and all within them. If the affirmation that " God cannot
                            possibly be " in any evil work" be construed to deny the eternal presence, then the
                            affirmation is at fault, because God is either omnipresent, or . He is not. If he is not, He
                            is circumscribed. If he is circumscribed He is finite, and can . be measured when infinity
                            disappears. But . God is ever present, in the cyclone, in the i fire that warms, or that
                            which reduces cities . to ashes. He is equally in the flint of the : winged and quivering
                            arrow of the wild In. dian on its errand of death, as in his heart to . condemn or approve,
                            or in that of angels or ; men on errands of mercy and love. That it ; has been his will to
                            impart free agency to f man, who may do evil or good at pleasure, i does not deny in the
                            least degree the ever-existing Eternal Presence. But to further elu: cidate, we return to
                            Gospel ministers. Being : appointed from above, when they speak or . act free from every
                            earthly bias or passional r influence, either in or out of themselves, being moved in
                            obedience to the Infinite Spirit operating upon their higher consciousness, or in obedience
                            to the more highly unfolded ministers or agents before them, they simply are agents or tools
                            in the hands of God, when what they say is the word of God and what they do is the act of
                            God, which would be sin for them to withhold or to change, and which should be freely
                            accepted by all under them; notwithstanding such ministers or appointed agents may have many
                            imperfections to contend with in common with the rest of their brethren and sisters. Christ
                            himself was tempted in all things like his brethren. No excuse for disobedience to the law
                            of Christ, or God through him, or his appointees, should be made in consequence of this. Now
                            of appointments : Some one or ones must be appointed to lead in every department of Christ's
                            kingdom, either in heaven or on earth. To make it a God-appointment, the appointing power
                            must be freed from selfish, ness and passional bias. Then such appointments should be
                            acquiesced in by all. Because some such fail to properly fulfill the call, is no argument
                            against this conclusion. One of Christ's was a failure. The false but popular democratic cry
                            of1'Vox fofuli, Vox Dei" is at variance with the whole genius, tenor, structure and very
                            existence of Christ's kingdom, which is a Theocracy pure and simple, and every iota of
                            democracy that finds lodgment therein only has the tendency to lower its status and cause it
                            to interblend with the kingdoms and communities of the world,_and make it both "common and
                            unclean." Ours is the antipode of democracy; the one being the government of God, the other
                            of men; the heads of one being appointed by God above them, the heads of the other by men
                            below them. The one is from above, the other from beneath. When Christ said to the Pharisees
                            in the temple, "Ye are from beneath, I am from above," He did not mean that they came from
                            some nether world up through a hole in the ground; no more than he did that he came down
                            from some supernal world through a hole in the sky. He simply meant to convey to them ' that
                            they were actuated from the lower regions and impulses, whilst his promptings were from the
                            higher, theirs from beneath, his from above. But they were natural and carnal and could not
                            understand him. " You have not chosen me but I have chosen you," said Christ, and so it must
                            remain in solid contrast with all other communities of earth. We are not chosen by the
                            world, but chosen out of the world. All the external gazing and clatter about this great day
                            of scientific progress which is attempting to make of Christ a myth, to shun : his cross,
                            and all the twaddle about more elbow room, throwing off priestly shackles, : and asserting
                            personal rights and removing : necessary restrictions within the kingdom, comes from an
                            overweening conceit and a * restless worldly animal nature that is ever ! pleading for more
                            indulgence. It never ¦ comes from the truly spiritual side of their : being. This, under all
                            circumstances, is " ever childlike, simple, unobtrusive, thankful, prayerful, meek, loving,
                            good, forbeari ing, forgiving, unretaliating, holy, happy and '¦ angelic. Who would not
                            choose this state i at the expense of fettering and crucifying the &gt; world within? :
                            South Union, Ky.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian faith" TEIform="index"/>Christian Faith</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patrick, Marian" TEIform="persName"/>MARIAN PATRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">We can place a true estimate on oui faith, by the consolation it affords in the - trials that
                            we are daily called to pass ¦ through ; and those who possess it, fine ' some gracious
                            purpose in every combi. nation of circumstances. In this influence there is nothing
                            mysterious, ii » shows the Christian his God, who dis- poses everything in benevolent
                            wisdom, producing characters of unexpected 7 worth, invigorating certain virtues by f
                            peculiar probations, breaking the fett ters which bind us to temporal things. r We would
                            call particular attention, for the last time this year, to the faci that those who would
                            like to subscribe . for that noble, instructive family peri' - odical, The American
                            Agriculturist 1 can by subscribing for it in combinatior - with The Shaker, obtain both
                            paper: ^ at less than the subscription price o the Agriculturist I Now is the ac ,. ceptable
                            time. Send $1.50 to N. A f Briggs, Shaker Village, N. H.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Notes by the way, no. 8" TEIform="index"/>Notes by the Way. No, 8</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Blinn, Henry C." TEIform="persName"/>HENRY C. BLINN</byline><p TEIform="p">" He made sad havoc with the king's English " was the remark of one who had been to hear the
                            great evangelist preach. The criticism may not have been misplaced, although projected by
                            disappointment. Accustomed as he may have been to a gorgeous church, with prayers and
                            sermons in the language of Addison, we are surprised at the mildness of the remark rather
                            than at the severity. This beloved grammarian had no doubt been suffering intensely under a
                            self-imposed penance and surcharged with the nervous torture, had left the meeting thinking
                            only of the sad violations of the rules of syntax. The earnestness and selfabnegation of the
                            Lord's servant, the prayers of the penitent, as well as the hymns of praise, found in his
                            heart no response. The displacing of an adjective or a pronoun at the commencement of a
                            petition, or a doubtful auxiliary before its verb in the sermon, had ruined the artistic
                            effect upon the poor man's mind. There seems to be a strong incentive in some to indulge in
                            the spirit of unkind, and hence unjust criticism. This is often manifested by the publicity
                            which is given to some slight errors of speech or eccentricity of manner, particularly when
                            they occur in a religious assembly. While ignorance may not foreshadow the fruits of
                            godliness, nor crude manners the discipline of the cross of Christ, still, we have reason in
                            believing that if all the exhortations in prayer and teaching which tend to a spiritual life
                            are to be confined within the circle of that class who never err in speech, then most
                            assuredly the disciples of the gospel of good news will not want for space in which to act.
                            Corbett, in his illustrations of language, is said to have obtained most of his examples of
                            false syntax from the speeches delivered in the British Parliament, but do we suppose for a
                            moment, that these grammatical errors wholly destroyed the force of their arguments? Not far
                            in the past, one of collegiate society while addressing an audience on the subject of
                            education, was credited with more than a score of deviations from the rules of orthography
                            and systematic construction of sentences. Fortunately, most of these slight errors among the
                            educated and uneducated pass unobserved. Hence, the potent influence of the revivalist upon
                            the minds of his hearers, when he compares the dealings of the members of the strictest
                            evangelical churches with souls, to the meanness and selfishness that exist in the traffic
                            of this world's goods. He says that the ministers in these same churches may preach their
                            intellectual sermons as smooth as an icicle and fully as cold. Few would stop to recognize
                            an error of speech, <pb n="43" id="p3" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 43 under the infliction of such a
                            direct shaft. Another writer, after making an extended display of words concerning the
                            Shakers, says that there was something in the woman, Ann Lee, that made her more than woman.
                            " Without an eloquence which is born of language and the gift of oratory, this unlettered
                            woman could make her hearers literally wet the floor of their meeting-room with their
                            tears." But our very worthy disciple of Lindley Murray has also learned that Ann Lee, in
                            some of her remarks, violated one or more of the unvarying rules of syntax, which warrants
                            him in saying, that "' Her exhortations made sad havoc with the rules of grammar, but they
                            were models of forcefulness and fervor." We can hardly conceive wherein lies the beauty or
                            even propriety of that form of expression which accords to the speaker " models of
                            forcefulness and fervor," while at the same time they are making sad havoc with the " rules
                            of grammar." It seems very much like having an inclination to find fault with somebody or
                            something, and this time it happens to be on the subject of religion. Grammatical precision
                            may be one of the most beautiful attainments in the anticipated language of the angels, and
                            in our making speech, a lovely and heavenly gift. For this attainment every young person
                            should aspire; a neglect by waste of precious moments, will render them culpable before God.
                            But with all the care that we may possibly exercise in this branch of education, it would be
                            the height of folly, to defer all action till the day of our perfection. The wise,
                            clearly-defined admonition, which the Savior set forth in the parable, when an unprofitable
                            servant buried in the earth (in the selfishness of his own life) the gift which God gave
                            him, should be indelibly impressed upon every mind.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian culture, no. 4" TEIform="index"/>Christian Culture. No, 4</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Bussell, William H" TEIform="persName"/>WM. H. BUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">LITERATURE. Character is formed, partly, by the influences which affect vis. This is a simple
                            truism, yet of the utmost importance to human welfare. Bodily health depends as much upon
                            climatic influences, upon the food which the system demands for the maintenance of its
                            vigor, as upor the care of the individual to act in ac cordance with the laws of health. The
                            best constitution is often undermined by exposure to certain atmospheric con ditions, though
                            the greatest care may be taken to guard against deleterious in ffuences. It is just so with
                            mental anc moral health. The literary atmosphere seems almos as widely diffused as that
                            invisible sub stance which surrounds the earth, en wrapping all with a garment of multi
                            plied and varied folds. Literature, of whatever kind, is of human origin, and, like
                            everything else human, is of varied character. The term is here taken in its broadest
                            extent, embracing not only the books and periodicals to which that name is commonly applied,
                            but also all others, whether styled political, scientific, or religious. All of these
                            classes have their objectionable features; not all equally offensive, by any means, for some
                            are comparatively harmless, while others are, to the last degree, pernicious. They all have
                            their excellencies, also, and these alone, of course, can be of any service in genuine
                            culture. Religious literature is a stream having its sources in remote antiquity, of
                            diminutive size at first, but becoming deeper and broader all the way down through the ages.
                            In the course of time, certain writings, as the Veda of the Indians, the Zend Avesta of the
                            Persians, the Koran of the Mohammedans, and the Bible of the Christians, acquired a
                            character of sacredness beyond all others, either because their authors declared them to
                            have emanated, directly or indirectly, from the Divine Mind, or because long use as
                            religious teachings gave them that character. The Christian zealot regards his Bible as
                            pre-eminently sacred, and the only one of all religious books meriting the title of God's
                            Word. Thus the poet Cowper: "All truth is from the sempiternal source Of light divine. But
                            Egypt, Greece and Rome Drew from the stream below. More favored we Drink, when we choose it,
                            from the fountain head." But error, wherever found, cannot give genuine culture. The
                            Christian name is no better than any other if it does not represent absolute truth, or, in
                            its primitive simplicity, embody a greater number of essential truths than any other. If the
                            teachings of Jesus proclaim the true character of the Divine Being, then many utterances
                            found in the Bible ascribed to God himself, must be pronounced erroneous, no matter what
                            degree of sacredness they may have acquired by age, because they do not accord with those
                            teachings. The life of Jesus is to be regarded as a true life, because it truly sets forth
                            the infinite and all-attracting love ; and, as a necessary sequence, all others differing in
                            their essential characteristics from his, are not to be taken as models upon which to form
                            true character. It is not necessary to point out the discrepancies between many of the
                            teachings found in portions of the Bible and those of Jesus. Every one who is sufficiently
                            imbued with the Christ spirit, and exercises the discriminating power which its inspirations
                            give, may easily perceive the dif ference. Such may well ask— " Is Christ the abler
                            teacher," or the Book? " If Christ, then why resort, at every turn," To Moses, or to
                            Solomon, "for wisdom shor Of man's occasions, when in him reside Grace, knowledge,
                            comfort—an unfathomec store ? " By following Moses rather than Christ and misunderstanding
                            Paul, who aban doned the former in favor of the latter superior teacher, many theologians
                            sine Christ's day have promulgated some of lie absurdest theories of religious truth aat
                            have ever been presented to the luman mind for its acceptance. Thus did some of the
                            "Christian fathers," so called, in the early centuries of the Christian era. Notably so did
                            the Reformers, who broke lances with their Catholic opponents but a few centuries since. And
                            so all along from their times to the present, from their pulpits, by written or
                            extemporaneous discourse, or by published pamphlet or ponderous tome, theologians of various
                            names have instilled these so-called Christian doctrines into the minds of the people. The
                            shelves of many of the great libraries in Europe and America groan under the burden of
                            accumulated errors. Well would it be if all the groans caused by error were confined there
                        !</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Christian in the world" TEIform="index"/>The Christian in the World</head><p TEIform="p">A true Christian living in the world is like a ship sailing on the ocean. It is not the ship
                            being in the water which will sink it, but the water getting into the ship. So in like
                            manner the Christian is not ruined by living in the world, which he must needs do whilst he
                            remains in the body, but by the world living in him. The world in the heart has ruined
                            millions. How careful are mariners in guarding against leakage, lest the water entering into
                            the vessel should, by imperceptible degrees, cause the vessel to sink. And ought not the
                            Christian to watch and pray, lest Satan thus entering in, bring him to destruction, both to
                            body and mind? The world anc the things of the world press upon us at all points. Our daily
                            avocations — yea, our most lawful enjoyments, have need to be narrowly watched, lest they
                            insensibly steal upon oui affections, and draw our hearts awaj from God.— Church Union.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker burials" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Burials</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Basting, Louis" TEIform="persName"/>LOUIS BASTING</byline><p TEIform="p">There is just now much agitation, Much study and deep cogitation, Upon the subject of
                            cremation. The press its witty arrow sends; The pulpit, too, its thunder lends; And doctors
                            sagely shake the head, About this business of the dead. But since each dog must have his
                            day, May not the poet have his say? All men therein are interested, For soon or late all
                            will be tested, By some, post mortem operation, Regardless of their inclination. Man,
                            influenced by religious thought, His welfare, after life has sought, In realms of blissful
                            ecstasy, Through time and all eternity; And since he loved his body well, He takes good care
                            of the old shell— He thinks 'twill resurrected be When Gabriel sounds the reveille. Meantime
                            he seeks the grave's repose, There quietly to decompose ; Drinking deep of Lethean slumbers,
                            Sleeps away life's sorry blunders. Strange customs in the world prevail, The dead by
                            different routes make sail, To regions of perpetual bliss, Or—where the clime oppressive is.
                            Egyptian mummies are well known, In every museum they are shown. The Parsee builds a tower
                            high, Whereon his worn-out corpse might lie; In life he's kind to every beast, In death he
                            gives himself, a feast To all the birds who cleave the air, Who choose to take their
                            luncheon there. According to his country's style, The stately Roman's funeral pile, Composed
                            of precious woods and spice, His body's parts would analyze. The Indian of the western
                            plains, All ceremonious pomp disdains ; On scaffold rough, in blankets rude, His dead are
                            left to solitude. The spot where sleeps the pious Jew, All members of his tribe eschew;
                            Though bound for heaven—or for tophet— " It is unclean," so says the prophet. The Moslem is
                            content to die, When sure he will towards Mecca lie. But what's the custom of to-day? How do
                            they treat those molds of clay? Compelled by truth we're bound to say, That folly seems to
                            bear the sway. In rosewood coffin, silver-plated, Velvet-lined and satin-braided; On flashy
                            hearse, 'neath waving plume, They bear the dead man to his tomb; And by the length of the
                            procession, Men judge the worth of his profession. Comes last of all but least of sense, The
                            costly monument's expense— Proclaiming to posterity, Much vanity, less piety. With millions
                            squandered on the dead, The poor must starve for want of bread. The Shakers, hating vain
                            display, When their beloved ones pass away, Make short and simple preparation, Void of all
                            worldly ostentation, In simple robes, but without stain, In coffin neat, unvarnished, plain,
                            They bear the whilom house away, Wherein the spirit used to stay; And singing a sweet song
                            or two, They bid their friends farewell, adieu. The traffic of the undertakers, Would not
                            pay well among the Shakers. Now, in the coming dissertation, I want to prove from
                            observation, That in the grand concatenation Of things, man also has a station In common
                            with the known creation, Which he should fill, sans hesitation. Although pre-eminence we've
                            won, Of nature's household we are one; Her laws, in truth, we must obey, Or her dire
                            penalties shall pay. All living things organic are, Most of their forms come from the air;
                            The rest, like in old Adam's day, Is nothing but your common clay. All life depends on
                            atmosphere ; Its composition, it is clear, Must stay unchanged, or desolation Would follow
                            from such violation. Now carbon is of greatest need, Without its aid, we should, indeed,
                            Cease to exist and pass away, Like mist before the solar ray. Hence, when completed are the
                            missions, Of man and lower sub-divisions, The organisms are dissolved, New life therefrom to
                            be evolved. And thus it is that we must give Our lives, that others, too, may live; And to
                            accomplish that decree, Th' imprisoned carbon must set free : That purloined carbon to
                            return, We needs must have the body burn. The work that in the grave goes on, Oxygen's
                            agency has done; And whether burned in fire's flame, Oxygen's action does the same. But when
                            we burn with fire, the gas Goes upward into air, whereas When taking place below the ground,
                            In nutriment it will abound, <pb n="44" id="p4" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 4:4; Roots will absorb it,
                            plants will grow, And by their luscious fruits will show, That God will write an epitaph,
                            More glorious than man's epigraph, Traced by his feeble hand on stone, To mark decaying
                            flesh and bone. What, then, shall be the disposition, Most in accordance with provision Of
                            nature, best for the public health And for the country's greater wealth? By every grave
                            plant we a tree, From forest or from nursery: Its shade will cool, its fruit will cheer, And
                            the departed ones, so dear, From their abode the work will bless, That tends to human
                            happiness. While thus the dead we most respect, The living ones we don't neglect. Mt.
                            Lebanon, N. Y.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Analysis of human society, no. 2" TEIform="index"/>An Analysis of Human Society. No. 2</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Fraser, Daniel" TEIform="persName"/>DANIEL FRASER</byline><p TEIform="p">Having classified society according to the organic law of each, and defined the phases
                            thereof, I will now proceed to analyze society, and again inquire: First,—What are the
                            primary atoms of human society? Man and woman are the primary atoms of human society.
                            Second,—What are the forces of these atoms as regards the formation of society ? Their most
                            potent inherent force is an affinity to unite and form matrimonial relationships. This force
                            maybe called the animal force, for all animals, in common with man, are its subjects. They
                            all marry as does man. Third,—The above force is the objective, but what are the inhering
                            forces of each atom? The inhering forces in each are dual; one is represented by animal
                            emotions, the other by divine emotions—benevolence, goodness. There is also a neutral force
                            : the intellect ; it is not emotional; it is a servant to either force. These forces are the
                            magazines of human power. Fourth,—What are the products of the action of the objective force
                            ? The product of the action of these atoms is the Adamic community, consisting of father,
                            mother, and their childi"en. When the offshoots have matured, they fly off to fulfill their
                            destiny, as their pai'ents have done. Here we find, first, a force to form a community ;
                            second, a force to disintegrate the same. And again, a third force, repelling any
                            coalescence with every other such community. Hence family distinctiveness. Having arrived at
                            a knowledge of the forces which create the family relationship, limit its extent,
                            and';maintain its distinctiveness, we become possessed o: a base of operations, to weigh anc
                            measure what they are able to do, anc what they are not able to effect. The forces of the
                            physical world are to some extent, controlled and modifiec by man, but he cannot change them
                            es sentially ; whatever form they may as snrae under his hand, they continue to bear a
                            strict relation to their primary forces. So man or woman, on the Adamic plane or sphere, can
                            be trained till a great change in the common ac ceptation of the term has taken place 3ut,
                            on examination, they are essenially the same, and bear a strict and rue relation to the
                            above forces, and to he sphere thereof. And any attempts of the subjects of said sphere to
                            raise hemselves out of and beyond the power of the forces thereof, by the aid of said brces,
                            must prove a nullity. Hence he formation of communities, embracing a number of families,
                            recognizing the forces alluded to, have all died out, or merely linger along. And so long as
                            the primal forces remain intact, the same results will attend any attempt to establish
                            communities having goods in common. First, because families do not coalesce. Second,
                            communities having goods in common do not admit of a plurality of centers of affection. And,
                            third, utterly rejects the distinctive element. Therefore, Adamic families are incapable of
                            forming communities having goods in common, being under the power of the forces of animal,
                            emotional life, represented by the propensities. Said forces and propensities, being
                            incapable of manifesting divine, emotional life—incapable of forming a universal
                            brotherhood, having one center of affection—God. Seeing there is not a kingdom recognized on
                            earth, where the divine, emotional force predominates, and has taken the mental force and
                            subdued the animal in man, and brought forth an order of society, with law, order and a
                            civilization corresponding thereto, perhaps we may find a single individual who may have
                            focalized in himself such a kingdom. On looking over the past, we find one individual who
                            states " That his kingdom is not of this world, and that his subjects will not fight." Here
                            are encouraging indications. But what are the forces by which this Nazarene purposeth to
                            create and vitalize his kingdom ? He says, ''Call no man on earth father." Here he abrogates
                            the order of the earthly father—the hus band, and of course the wife—the mother. Indeed, so
                            far as his kingdom is concerned, the whole procreative order. And the reason is, "For one is
                            your father, even He who is in Heaven"— one center of affection—God. And in his own life,
                            Jesus, on this point, gave a practical example, and said, " Those who do the will of my
                            Father who is in Heaven, the same [all humanity in that state] is my mother, sister and
                            brother." Here is a new relationship. His Father is in Heaven—in a heavenly sphere ; and
                            those who do the will of his Father— whose every word and act are in harmony with the
                            Father, are also of that sphere, whether they be in a mortal body or not. Here we find that
                            love to God is the vitalizing element, or creative force of Christ's kingdom. And love to
                            those brought forth by that force, brings forth a universal brotherhood—the divine order of
                            human society. Such a kingdom will not be of the world, neither will its government stand in
                            physical power, nor operate by force after the manner of the kingdoms of the animal man. The
                            germ of the Adamic family is very limited in its unfoldings. The germ—love to God, in its
                            unfoldings embraces all humanity. And the voice of that unfolding, is ever, " Whosoever
                            will, let him come" and inherit he divine life, and the true and good lowing therefrom.
                            Where the life and love of God is hed abroad in human spirits, there is no need to
                            manufacture a community laving goods in common ; it springs up of itself, and is the result
                            of the internal orces of divine relationships. Here we find focalized in Christ, first, a
                            force to create a universal brotherhood ; second, a force to destroy the organizing
                            affinities of the Adamic relationships. Wherever two or three are gathered together in the
                            power of these superior forces, there will be law and government, and an ultimate
                            civilization that eye hath not seen nor ear heard, neither hath it entered the heart of the
                            Adamic man to conceive of. In conclusion, the divine—the Shaker order of human society, and
                            the Adamic, will run parallel through the ages. The latter is the boyhood, the former the
                            true manhood of the race. Shirley, Mass.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Place your affections on things above" TEIform="index"/>Place your Affections on Things Above</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Patrick, Isabel E." TEIform="persName"/>ISABEL E. PATRICK</byline><p TEIform="p">I am persuaded to believe this is worthy of our sincere attention. Now, while we are young
                            and active, and have the power to please ourselves, is the time for us to decide whether we
                            will deny ourselves of little self-indulgences— momentary pleasures — to secure an interest
                            in the kingdom of heaven. If we resolve to follow our own inclinations, which lead into sin,
                            the pain of remorse, instead of unalloyed pleasure, will be our portion. Hence. it should be
                            the object of our immediate concern to travel the self-denying path that leads to heaven.
                            Jesus said, " He that followeth me shall not walk in darkness, but shall have the light of
                            life." I believe we shall be heirs to true riches if we take up a daily cross against the
                            multitude of evils which beset us to try our faith ; and which, perhaps, we should not so
                            clearly comprehend, did we not often experience the bitter with the sweet. If we endure all
                            light afflictions, to obtain a place with the righteous, we have the assurance of immortal
                            gain ; a treasure superior to worldly honor, wealth, or fame. To make a willing surrender of
                            our own desires, and conform to the requirements of the gospel, wisely calculated to save us
                            from all impurity, is a work well worthy our highest aspirations anc earnest struggles.</p></div2><div2 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="A three weeks' meeding is to be held..." TEIform="index"/>A three weeks' meeding is to be held...
                        </head><p TEIform="p">A three weeks' meeting is to be helc at Shawsheen river grove near Boston about August i, and
                            pressing invita t tions come to this office, asking tha i the Shakers be fully represented.
                            We 5 commend this call to the attention o Novitiate Elders.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What shall I do to be a shaker? no. 5" TEIform="index"/>What shall I do to be a Shaker? No. 5</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Cumings, Henry" TEIform="persName"/>HENRY CUMINGS</byline><p TEIform="p">In attempting a reply to the oft-reDeated question, we are prompted to ask: Do you really
                            wish to be a Shakr ? If the honest answer to this assures us that you seek simply a home—a
                            lome of quiet and seclusion, exempt in ome degree from the burdens and reponsibilities of
                            ordinary life in the world,—or if for any merely temporal or worldly consideration, we would
                            say, hese are not the objects of our associa:ion ; and with these motives alone in Tiew, the
                            probabilities are that you will iot obtain the satisfaction you seek. Yet as you wish a
                            further acquaintance, iside from religious convictions, we an accept you experimentally,
                            that you may have the opportunity to study the principles upon which these Shaker
                            intitutions are founded, and learn of their practical application. Being as they are
                            religious institutions, the by-laws, orders, and disciplinary requirements, by which the
                            members are controlled, are framed with a view to make possible and practicable a truly
                            Christian life—the ultimate realization of that which saints and seers, good men and
                            prophets, of all ages, have been looking forward to, and prayed for, with the most fervent
                            and devout expectations. But, you ask, what are the conditions or the first steps to be
                            taken toward the attainment of such a result? The first step in the work is an open, honest
                            confession to God, before those who stand as his ministers, of every known sin, of whatever
                            name or nature. The object of this confession is twofold. First,—Humiliation and
                            selfabasement of the proud spirit of man. vSecond,—The union and relation it opens to those
                            who have passed through the same work, having proved its efficacy, and who are thereby led
                            to leave the practices of a worldly life, and enter into that new and better life of
                            Christian purity and goodness. The next step in the course, is the giving of one's self to
                            God in cojzsecration; a condition rather the result of growth than one to be reached by an
                            instantaneous impulse or desire to do so. One may feel determined to give all to God in a
                            general way, but when this resolution comes to be put to the test of every-day life, it is
                            apt to prove a more difficult undertaking than was anticipated ; and not having learned to
                            wear Christ's yoke easily, it galls, and cramps, till often the candidate who enters the
                            work with earnestness of purpose, is almost ready to exclaim, with Bunyan's Pliable, " If
                            this be your brave heavenly kingdom, you can possess it alone for all of me." But the
                            honest, earnest soul, who has started to run the Christian race, determined to persevere,
                            despite all obstacles, will not turn back, because "there are lions in the path." Having
                            honestly confessed his sins, and consecrated himself to God, the result will be purity and
                            uprightness of life. Not merely a purity which shuns a violation of the civil <pb n="45" id="p5" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER. 45 aw, but purity of thought, word and action. Following this
                            course of life, there comes, as a natural sequence, peace, quietness, and love. "By this
                            shall all men know that ye are my disciples, if ye have love one for another." If you become
                            a Shaker, you will find this condition growing in you, causing you to love not only those
                            who love you, but to love and "pray for those who despitefully use you and persecute you."
                            This principle, carried into practical life, will bring you into that relation promised to
                            those who forsake the ties and affections of the selfish life, for Christ's sake. It will
                            make possible, the realization here, and now, of that kingdom of heaven which is declared to
                            be "an everlasting kingdom, of whose glory and increase there should be no end." It will
                            bring you into that degree of union with others, who are striving in the same way, making it
                            possible for you to live the communistic or Pentecostal life, sharing the common home,
                            common property, common brotherhood and sisterhood, and all the blessings of life, both
                            spiritual and temporal. And only by striving to practice these principles, will you be able
                            to endure the friction consequent upon such close association. But, as you can see, this is
                            a condition of growth, and costs much of selfish ends and aims. Are you ready and willing to
                            make such sacrifices for such a reward? Are you willing to give all, that you may have lot
                            and part in this holy relationship? If you can decide that the earthly life has nothing to
                            offer that you would not be willing to give in exchange for a part in this heavenly
                            inheritance, then, we say, "come and take the waters of life freely." The same cross, the
                            same self-denial, the same consecration to God, that has made saints of those who have gone
                            before you, will, if persistently and honestly lived and borne, develop for you the same
                            Christian character, and you shall know the whole truth, and be governed by its principles
                            in all the transactions of life. To every such honest seeker we always say, "Come and share
                            with us, in all our joy or sorrow, comfort or burden; in all the blessings, spiritual and
                            temporal; and we ask and pray, in all sincerity, that heaven may bless you with that gift of
                            true conviction for sin, and determined purpose to lead a truly Christian life, that you may
                            have cause to say, with one of old, ' I am not ashamed of the gospel of Christ, for it is
                            the power o: God unto salvation.' " Enfield, N. H. -----------------?-----------------A
                            beautiful image.—A deaf anc dumb person being asked to give hi idea of forgiveness, took a
                            pencil anc wrote, "It is the sweetness which flow ers yield when trampled upon." Calumny is
                            the shadow of merit and though it ever follows, it neve overtakes it.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="By their fruits ye shall know them" TEIform="index"/>"By their fruits ye shall know them."</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>JAMES G. RUSSELL</byline><p TEIform="p">Slot flowery sentiment in pulpits spoken, Nor great profession of the higher life, 'sot
                            forms, nor creeds in any way betoken Results accruing from the Christian's strife. Words are
                            but sounds, with emptiness of meaning, When uttered by the mere professing saint, Whose real
                            life is evidently teeming With unregeneracy's woeful taint. By this shall all men know that
                            ye are surely My followers, said Jesus, if ye bear ?he fruits of righteousness by living
                            purely The life attained by watchfulness and prayer. STot all the massive wealth that earth
                            can render, Not all the show within her halls of lore, S"or costly palaces of gorgeous
                            splendor, Can ornament beyond this transient shore. And nearer still we face the truth
                            asserted, When we accept the words our Savior spake— That worldly riches render life
                            perverted, As sacrifice to Mammon's god we make. We cannot enter into joys celestial— Though
                            ushered into immortality-When bound in spirit unto things terrestrial: True happiness
                            consists in being free. Divested of all worldly loves and pleasures, Regenerated into life
                            anew,— '.n heaven laying up eternal treasures Where thieves can never steal by breaking
                            through. Yet even here, before we pass the river, That separates the spirit-world from ours,
                            We may commence the strife that will deliver Eventually the soul from Satan's powers : For
                            heaven is condition, not location, And Godliness, the fortress of the soul; Protection from
                            the world is not salvation, But living works that make the Christian whole. Salvation's door
                            is free for all to enter, Who would from slavery be free indeed, There's nothing here to
                            risk, no doubtful venture, For Christ is our defender and our lead. By taking up the cross
                            of self-denial, And bearing it each passing day and hour, However great may be affliction's
                            trial, We shall prevail by God's eternal power. Then let each soul whose motto is salvation,
                            Unflinchingly abide the glorious strife, And win the laurels of emancipation, The heavenly
                            blessings of eternal life.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Home work" TEIform="index"/>Home Work</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Sawyer, Sarah L." TEIform="persName"/>SARAH L. SAWYER</byline><p TEIform="p">Good breeding is something we may have without money and without price, by a little attention
                            and a careful regarc of others' feelings ; by an intuitive feeling of delicacy, with "Do to
                            others as we would that they should do to us" the golden of all rules. O, that we might
                            inculcate into our hearts a proper regard for others. We are sowing seed for eternity. It
                            will be our sorrow if we do not improve the opportunity. God grant we may believe in season,
                            before it is too late. Repent of our sins with a heart-felt sorrow, or we may be left to
                            exclaim, in the bitterness of our souls, "The summer is past, the harvest is ended, and my
                            soul is no saved." Let us subdue our vile pas sions, which bring death to the soul anc
                            sorrow to grieved hearts ; making shad ows instead of sunshine. May we make beautiful,
                            heavenly sunshine wherever we go. If we think we cannot do any good, may we do no harm ; and
                            if we hink we cannot bring sunlight to darkened souls, may we be sure to bring no shadows.
                            We need to search the gardens of our own hearts, weeding out he noxious weeds which choke
                            the growth of the soul, and which will keep is out of the kingdom. Enfield, Conn.</p></div2><div2 type="poem" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Time's lesson" TEIform="index"/>Time's Lesson</head><p TEIform="p">Time to me this truth hath taught, 'Tis a truth that's worth revealing; More offend from want
                            of thought,^ Than from any want of feeling. If advice we would convey, There's a time we
                            should convey it; If we've but a word to say, There's a time in which to say it! Many a
                            beauteous flower decays, Though we tend it e'er so much : Something secret on it preys,
                            Which no human aid can touch. So, in many a loving breast, Lies some canker-grief concealed,
                            That, if touch'd is more oppressed, Left unto itself—is healed. Oft, unknowingly, the tongue
                            Touches on a chord so aching, That a word, or accent wrong, Pains the heart almost to
                            breaking. Many a tear of wounded pride, Many a fault of human blindness, Had been soothed,
                            or turn'd aside, By a quiet voice of kindness !</p></div2><div2 type="publication" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><p TEIform="p">THE SHAKER. Monthly—60 cents per annum. A DUAL ADVOCATE OF CHRIST PRINCIPLES.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shall we have a revival?" TEIform="index"/>Shall we have a Revival ?</head><p TEIform="p">Let zis have a revival. A Shaker revival means so much, that none will wonder that its coming
                            has been exceedingly slow. Who need a revival more than we do? and how long can we bear to
                            be without one ? We hear very many voices, answering correctly, " No longer." Our revival
                            means '•''more of Christ" and can have no reference to any literal creed. A want of growth
                            is stagnation ; and this means more than death. Growth, with us, is not necessarily defined
                            by numerical figures, but by spiritual exertions with what numbers we now have. A revival
                            will not necessarily take us back to the demarcations of our faith and its constituents of
                            an hundred years ago ; but it will demand the consideration of what is rigfht, what is pure,
                            what is just, what is duty for brethren and sisters in Christ to-day ! None ask us to go
                            back and begin the work as it was begun a century since ; with its meager surroundings and
                            unattractive accommodations ; but simple, gospel faith and justice demand goodness on our
                            part; a purity exceeding earthly conditions ; and a love for one another superior to the
                            best demonstration of the golden rule ! Will not such a revival of gospel principles
                            reburnish us, and with increasing brightness? And where is the cause of such a wan of
                            revival? As """-love is the fulfilling of the gospel law," so the active prin ciples of
                            love, earnestly engaged in, wil remove and dissipate every hindrance o a revival among us,
                            and such an one as will inspire us to love one another better than ourselves. Say what any
                            Dlease, selfishness is the bone of our dearth, and this dearth, without a revival of
                            principles that are death to selfshness, means more than our dwindling, numerically
                            speaking. A revival of love for the unselfishness of the Christ-life, means a resurrection
                            of ourselves and comrades from all mere sensual indulgences ; and a working faith for the
                            redemption of those " not of our fold, as yet." It means, "be what we are called to be," and
                            so let our lights shine, that all may see and love our superior life. Let us have a revival!
                            If we would make converts, let us be thoroughly converted. If we would make others feel
                            Christ, we must feel and have Christ ourselves. While tens of thousands are renewing their
                            l'esolutions to a faith in Jesus, let us, gospel friends, and all who love a pure religion,
                            renew our resolutions to a work of Christ in us, that will manifest, through us, deeper
                            concern for the purity, peace, and love of Christ in the household of faith ; and give
                            evidence, by our confidence and love for one another, that Christ is here, which will draw
                            the attention of all the world unto us ! Shall we have a revival ?</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shaker faith and practice" TEIform="index"/>Shaker Faith and Practice</head><p TEIform="p">To the man or woman who strives for an earthly competence, indifferent as to the future, so
                            long as present comfort is secured, Shaker life must appear strangely phenomenal. All the
                            comforts of the world seem removed from Shaker households and Shaker lives! Instead of this
                            being the case, let us give a correct understanding. A Shaker looks upon this life as a
                            preparatory condition for another. The engagement of "living while we live," in the fullest
                            indulgence of the passions, we know adds bluntness to our spiritual perceptions and
                            sensations, and we cheerfully relinquish the less for the more valuable. A Shaker, with such
                            feelings and knowledge, could not engage in the various indulgences common to earthly men
                            and women, nor with any pleasure ! What these latter term pleasure, in selfish, sexual,
                            scortative loves and lusts, would be hell on earth, and everywhere else, to the Shaker ! Nor
                            is it because we have been taught that Jesus, his disciples, our foun'ders, and our present
                            leaders live virgin, self-denying lives, that maintains a faith in us, that strengthens us
                            to live likewise. Personal experience —a baptism from the Christ heavens__ leaves no room
                            for doubt, that though others take what course they please, as for us, they must grant us
                            the right of virgin celibacy, or we shall have plenty of hell upon earth. You worldlings
                            pity us, because of our loss of the pleasures you are enjoying, little thinking how we pity
                            you ; and that we estimate your longest lives of fullest, sensual pleasures, unequal to the
                            justification and happiness of our virginhood for <pb n="46" id="p6" TEIform="pb"/> 4=6 THE SHAKER. even
                            a single day ! You heap up riches ; we lay up none ; contented we to share together, and
                            equally, the sustenance of this life. You die, leave your riches ; we go hence, and take
                            ours with us. Yours are earthly, changeable, soulstarving ; ours are just as eternal,
                            unchangeable and nourishing as yours are the reverse. As far as in us lies the power, we
                            endeavor to practice here, what your imaginations, educations and hopes picture to you as
                            the works of a future heaven. It is easy to perceive that you must change your practices, to
                            live as the angels do. It is as easy to perceive that we are now living after the manner of
                            those resurrected souls who form the company with whom you have great expectations to
                            associate in the future ! Did you never think of this? If we, the Shakers, and our practices
                            of virgin celibacy, peace, communion of interests, general and particular freedom from sin,
                            are distasteful now, what is ever going to change your views and create a love for these
                            practices in the future world? Strange it is, but none the less true, that while nearly
                            every denomination of religious people is diametrically opposed to Shaker life and practice
                            in this world, all agree that the place called heaven is peopled with angelic beings who
                            live extremely like the Shakers ! While nearly every denomination professes extreme faith in
                            Jesus, nearly all lose sight of the fact that Jesus lived, and lives now, just as the
                            Shakers do ! and all are soon to learn that Jesus' life is the element, and only saving
                            element, upon which they can rely for their salvation. We believe in blood, Bro. Moody, but
                            it is a blood, that means, every time, the life of Jesus—hence, ours is not a bloodless
                            religion. We are a simple, childlike people. Content to know and feel a Christ in our daily
                            lives, we have our Savior with us. And without the cross of a daily self-denial against the
                            bad and good of an earthly, un-Jesus-like life—without a continual testimony against the
                            elements of the world—the lusts of the flesh, of money, of lands, of buildings, and all mere
                            creature comforts, we never can be saved, though a thousand Jesuses suffer crucifixion
                            yearly, popes, bishops, ministers and churchal creeds to the contraiy, notwithstanding.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Editorials" TEIform="index"/>EDITORIAL NOTES</head><p TEIform="p">Every liberal, genuine Shaker looks with large interest upon the numerous revivals of the
                            religious elements in our country at the present time. Every conversion from bad to better,
                            from good to very good, is of the gospel of Christ. What though this conversion does not
                            embody the particular essentials of the Christ-life, which make us his peculiar followers,
                            is not every approach to the religious life of Jesus, a definite, gospel conversion ? The
                            gospel of Christ ante-dated Jesus. The people must first be convicted of, anc converted from
                            their sins before the clearer light of the New Creation can effect its work of conversion
                            from the good of the old to the superior life of the new. Let us pray that all the people
                            may love Jesus so well that they will never rest satisfied until they make the
                            distinguishing features of his life their love and life. Then, O, how they will love the
                            Shakers! A Canadian divine has been giving the people of the provinces some very plain talks
                            upon balls, nocturnal dancing, etc., and very justly attributes much of the sins of
                            seduction, lascivious crimes generally, with the "beslavered clawing of lustful libertines,
                            ready to pounce upon virtue at the first opportunity," to the designing intrigues of
                            co-sexual dancing. He created quite an uproar, —quite a flutter upon the hit birds,— when he
                            told of the Turk, who, after witnessing a waltz, asked : " And what followed ?" We commend
                            these labors of the Rev. McDonagh, even at the expense of a seeming inconsistency. Some
                            portion of our Shaker worship is called dancing; but its every intention is the very reverse
                            of the "beastly, lustful, envious and murderous" practices to which he alludes, and for
                            which purposes balls, etc., were inaugurated to encourage. Introduce Shaker testimony once
                            into a ball-room, and there will be a scattering of forces, accompanied by an embarrassment
                            unequaled even by the discovery of sheep-stealing ! If we dance, we do so to intensify our
                            hatred to the flesh ; and each sex, on its own side of the house, rises in the dance quite
                            superior to any thoughts, even, of carnal contact or indulgence. So far, Rev. McDonagh, you
                            are a Shaker ! God speed you. Every uttered expression, of any diminution of Shaker
                            influence in this world, having any guaranty of reason for the utterance, is an added count
                            against the progress of Christianity. The basest charge that has been made for years against
                            Shakerism is, that it too literally, too really, too nearly represents the life of
                            Christianity's author, to be at all agreeable to the senses! Who would lend a helping hand
                            to progress the Christian cause, should not be deterred by an acquaintance of the similarity
                            of the lives of Jesus and the Shakers ! Lend a hand, regardless of prejudices. Among many
                            other foolish controversies agitating pulpit acrobats to-day, the monstrous Trinity doctrine
                            is very conspicuous. The Unitarians perform feats of remarkable agility, demolishing, to
                            their satisfaction, the triune theory ; and the Trinitarians, in turn, attempting to outdo
                            their adversaries in their every endeavor. If these silly people woulc all read and ponder
                            Romans i : 20, they would, we should hope, agree to drop their sophistries, and simply learn
                            that God is dual—male and female—after whose images were created Adam anc Eve, and all
                            things else, "from the creation of the world." "Except ye become as little children," many
                            of the simplest truths will be subjected to the mystification of learned magicians, or
                            performing ministers. Our mission, through The Shaker, and otherwise, is to shed light in
                            dark places. To be a reminder to the people of "the way, the truth and the life" of him, "In
                            whom was life, and this life was [and is] the light of men." In the hope and belief, that in
                            this world of thousands of millions souls, and among the millions disembodied, there may be
                            some who are hungering for the life-influences our faith imparts ; and to whom illustrations
                            of these influences will be the grand desiderata—for these objects only, The Shaker lives.
                            Those who sustain it do so with no expectation of full recompense; but in this support, as
                            in many other respects, the Shakers are proving themselves the best friends of humanity, by
                            giving up their worldly, selfish lives, to take up unworldly, Christian practices, which are
                            as eternal as the heavens, and the "salt" of the earth.</p></div2><div2 type="article" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Spiritually enlarged mankind" TEIform="index"/>Spiritually Enlarged Mankind</head><p TEIform="p">Spiritualists : What inferences can be drawn from the prophecy of Andrew Jackson Davis, when
                            he says: "When mankind shall have become spiritually larger, and finer in body, they will
                            have fewer and fewer children. Down in the lower stratum of society, behold how populous !
                            Take the early races, they propagate rapidly! Earth's mothers have been broken down by their
                            exceedingly numerous progeny. Rise higher in the scale, and the married have fewer children
                            and less frequently. Rise still higher in the mental scale, and you can easily believe the
                            time will come that reproduction will cease! There will then be fathers and mothers with
                            their descendants, and the progeny will become as angels, neither marrying nor giving in
                            marriage ; having risen above the mission of reproduction. The cerebellum, I repeat, will
                            one of these days cease to have any furniture with reference to reproduction ! The finest
                            and most poetic and spiritual minds gather nearly all their propagating power and essences
                            into the front brain and top faculties. Only friends tc truth dare to speak the whole truth
                            on this subject."</p></div2><div2 type="saying" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Good reading for everybody" TEIform="index"/>Good reading for everybody
                        </head><p TEIform="p">Good reading for everybody.— " For all the law is fulfilled in one word, even in this : Thou
                            shalt love th) neighbor as thyself." " But if ye bite and devour one another, take heed that
                            ye be not consumed one of another." " The fruit of the spirit is love, joy, peace,
                            long-suffering, gentleness, good' ness, faith." " Let us not be desirous of vain-glory
                            provoking one another, envying om another." Coal-ashes are proved to be very valuabli used
                            around pear-trees.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Juvenile" TEIform="index"/>THE CHILDREN'S GROTTO</head><div3 type="not" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">My Dear Children : Let us enter the Grotto with feelings of sincere reverence "or all
                                that is good. It is a pleasure or me to think of you all as very good children; and if
                                you answer affirmatively to ;his description, then my present subject will :&gt;e
                                appropriate and comforting to you. Every good parent loves his or her children the beter
                                for every added manifestation of honesty; whether the manifestations are the commision
                                of good deeds, correction of mistakes, or failure to make mistakes. "Honesty is the best
                                policy," has been repeated for ages to children, that they might learn that t is as good
                                for their whole lives as at the present. It is the aim of this little talk to explain
                                why it is the best policy, and why, nstead of honesty in all things being a dread, it
                                should always be a pleasure. The story of " George Washington and his hatchet," is kept
                                alive by repetition, because of its beautiful conclusion ; and as with this story, so it
                                is and will be with every honest word and way with you. Even if you are very good the
                                most of the time, you will carelessy or purposely at other times do or say that vhich is
                                wrong, as my experience with the jest of children has proved. When you have done or said
                                anything that is wrong, the question with the good child is: "What SHALL I DO TO MEND MY
                                MISTAKE ?" I will tell you: Be honest, be even better than Washington, do not wait until
                                you are found out, go at once, resolutely, but sorrowfully, and tell your parents or
                                care-taking friend, ust what you have said or done. Do you think : "I am afraid?
                                ashamed? what will my mother or care-taker think of me ?" My dear children: afraid of
                                what? ashamed of what? will mother or care-taker think of what? Dismiss at once and
                                forever such thoughts, for they are untrue and dishonest. Your friends know you are
                                liable to make mistakes and very likely just what those mistakes will be, and when you
                                go directly, or at the first convenient season, and truthfully confess your faults, even
                                if you go ten times in a day you will ever find a warm place in the hearts of your
                                parents or friends. Perhaps, to help you to do so no more,—this is what is meant by
                                repentance,—they may impose some punishment upon you; but, by your confession, you have
                                taken the sting and dread out of all the punishment that may be inflicted; and this will
                                ever be light and easy compared to the needed and merited punishment of the dishonest,
                                unconfessed child. By your confessions, you show a willingness to punish yourselves; and
                                this punishment of confession, you should understand, is the best of help over all hard
                                places in life, over evil habits, over all inclination to wrong, and into the happiest
                                condition of noble manhood and womanhood, that has ever been discovered. One of the
                                ancients raised his arm to strike his servant; but instead of striking him, held his arm
                                aloft, and when found an hour afterwards with his arm uplifted, he said he was punishing
                                an angry man ! It has been Shaker counsel for scores of years to correct the mistakes of
                                the day before going to rest at night. I know of no other practice that I could or would
                                rather persuade you to enter into ; for there is, my dear children, an unequaled
                                nobleness in confession. Once when in Boston, speaking with some parents upon this
                                beautiful custom among us, they expressed their extreme admiration of it, and determined
                                to introduce it to their children at once. In return, I felt one sorrow for them ; and
                                this was when their brows clouded and their enthusiasm cooled at my remark : " If you
                                would succeed well with the children, you must practice this rule yourselves!" Dear
                                children, all the confessions and punishments and honors that come from these, are not
                                for you alone, they are as necessary for us who are older and aged as for you. But here
                                is where you have the advantage: <pb n="47" id="p7" TEIform="pb"/> THE SHAKER-. 4,7 By confessing and
                                forsaking your wrongs while you are young, you will enter into a course of life which
                                demands no repentance, no change of heart. But from all who do wrongly there is the
                                necessity of an honorable confession, and added to this, a repentance that changes the
                                heart to the beauty of a pure, true Christ-life.</p></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Mt. Lebanon, May 4, 1877" TEIform="index"/>Mt. Lebanon, May 4, 1877</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor:—You have put a temptation before me, one that I feel I cannot resist, to
                                write to you. "The child's prayer!" How beautiful the thought! How many innocent prayers
                                have I put up before my heavenly Father to protect my soul from sin. When a bad thought
                                enters my mind, what can do better than to drop upon my knees and raise my prayer to Him
                                who has power to drive the bad spirit away. I thank you for that prayer. From your
                                little friend,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Howd, James E." TEIform="persName"/>James E. Howd</byline></div3><div3 type="letter" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Real shaker girl's letter" TEIform="index"/>A real Shaker girl's letter</head><p TEIform="p">Dear Editor :—Enclosed find names and stamps for " Shaker Child's Prayer" for our little
                                girls. A new prayer is to them a source of great delight, and all they can learn are
                                adopted for their various needs. "Dear little angels, put a little crumb in a little
                                cup, to feed a little lamb," is so short that our little Mintie says she " tan say it
                                six times 'fore I dit up." We little folks have become very interested in The Shaker,
                                now that we have a "Grotto" in its territory; and I personally congratulate you in your
                                successful efforts to have a living Shaker to represent the truths we ought to embody in
                                our daily lives. We want our paper, while it enlightens inquirers after our theology, to
                                strengthen the weak; encourage the strong; guide the youth aright; be a solace to the
                                aged; and be a living assistant to our every-day lives. Thanks for remarks on " Common
                                Error;" and please introduce more prominent points upon etiquette; for I sometimes think
                                that by our reclusiveness we should be led to sanction some things that are really low
                                breeding! Your article " What shall I do to be a Shaker, No. 1," I think is the best
                                answer I ever read on the subject—so plain and truthful--unencumbered by the
                                mystification of an endless theology! You probably do not need encouragement from such
                                as your humble correspondent, but my appreciation may not be out of place. Your sister,</p><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Calver, Amelia J." TEIform="persName"/>Amelia J. Calver Mt. Lebanon, April 1</byline></div3><div3 type="health" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="What not to do in a sick-room" TEIform="index"/>What not to do in a Sick-Eoom</head><p TEIform="p">Do not wear a starched garment, nor anything that rustles. Avoid all little noises, like
                                the sudden shutting of a door, and the creaking of shoes. Sometimes the rocking of a
                                chair, or passing the needle in and out of work, or turning over the leaves of a book or
                                a newspaper, makes the difference between comfort and misery in a sickroom. Do not jar
                                the room by treading heavily, nor the bed by leaning against it—above all things never
                                sit on the bed. Never wake a sleeping patient unless under the physician's orders to
                                give medicine or nourishment or to change a dressing. Avoid all uncertainty and strained
                                ex pectations on the part of the patient Keep his mind as quiet as possible Allow no
                                whispering—and even a low tone is far less objectionable than a whisper, which the
                                patient involuntari y strains his attention to hear. Ask no more questions than is
                                absolutely necessary, and never force him to repeat a "emark. Never speak to him
                                abruptly. Do not consult him, but quietly make ;he changes you think necessary. Never
                                tax him to make a decision upon anyhing if it can be avoided. Never let a sick person
                                see, smell or lear anything about food before it is Drought to him. Let each meal be in
                                he shape of a pleasant surprise. Let ;he food be served with dainty neatness. Never let
                                the patient's head as he lies n bed be higher than the throat of the chimney, except for
                                an occasional change of posture, or in diseases of the ¦espiratory organs. Thus he gets
                                all the pure air there is. His head should not be higher than the window and placed so
                                he can see out of it. Let the sick-room be the brightest in the house, and give
                                admittance to all the sunlight the weak eyes can bear. Do not open and shut the door
                                oftener than is absolutely necessary. Do not mislay things so as to be obliged to mnt
                                for them at the moment of wantng to use them. Do not allow a place in the sickroom for
                                flowers emitting a powerful odor, such as tuberoses and hyacinths, 3ut other than highly
                                odorous flowers are often beneficial. Place them where le can see them without much
                                effort, and remove them at night or at the first symptoms of withering. The bed should
                                never be pushed against the wall. Let there be free circulation of air all around it,
                                and space to go in and out without jarring the patient. Do not allow reading aloud
                                unless the patient particularly asks for it, and then it should be discontinued the
                                moment his attention flags. A cheerful countenance in a sickroom cannot be too strongly
                                insisted upon. Even if the nurse be tii'ed, she must be careful to conceal it from her
                                patient.—Ex.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Books" TEIform="index"/>BOOK TABLE</head><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Analysis of religious belief" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Amberly, Viscount" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Psychological basis of religion" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Journal of progress" TEIform="index"/></head><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="book notice" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Vocal physiology" TEIform="index"/></head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Guilmette, [Dr.]" TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"/></div3><div3 type="none" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><p TEIform="p">The Temple Harp. We consider ourselves privileged in having perused—pretty thoroughly
                                examined the above musica work. It is a wonder of neatness and novelty in its
                                typographical execution. Insteac of the usual round characters for musical no tation, we
                                herein have presented seven differ ent characters, an extensive improvemen upon the four
                                that used to represent the style of years since, known as "patent notes. These seven are
                                as easily learned as a b c and instead of being any impediment to the use of those now
                                commonly used, are really an assistance to their perfect rendering. We know whereof we
                                speak; and though incom petent to praise the work sufficiently, wouk not fail of calling
                                due attention. Beautifully printed, choicely selected, the whole work is a charming
                                relic of to-day, which to have, is to be justly proud of. The price, including postage,
                                is $1.63. Address Miller's Pub lishing House, 1102 and 1104, Sansom St. Philadelphia,
                                Pa. Analysis of Religious Belief, by Vis count Amberly. D. M. Bennett, 141 Eighth St.,
                                New York, publisher. The enterprising publisher of this volume has reduced therein two
                                volumes, the cost o: which has been $18. The volume abov named, contains the London
                                edition complete at about one-sixth the London selling price, ^or depth of research, for
                                clearness of reasonng, for honesty in rendering conclusions, ;he Viscount herein stands
                                unrivaled. Those who know how to read the works of great minds, and therebjr partake of
                                the glory and reedom of their thoughts, will want this volume. Viscount Amberly was the
                                son of ^ord John Russell: his means for analyzing lis subject were unrestricted, and for
                                a monument, few could wish a nobler one than he las left in the '¦'¦Analysis of
                                Religious Belief." Want of space forbids our love to linger in ts praise. The
                                Psychological Basis of Religion : S. R. Wells &amp; Co., 737 Broadway, New York.
                                This is a pamphlet of abovit forty pages considering the above subject from the basis of
                                phrenology, and will answer satisfactorily :o many minds, the question : "Is science in
                                conflict with religion.?" Price 20 cents. We have heard so much of the "Monarch of the
                                West" strawberry, that we have taken some pains to inquire for the benefit of our
                                friends, as to its merits. It is a wonderfully prolific bearer; and while not so hardy
                                in carriage as the Wilson, is valued higher in the market—indeed one third more Wilsons
                                are needed to balance the prices obained for the Monarch. If any wish for the latter,
                                address E. P. Roe, Cornwall-on-Hudson, N. Y., who has thirty different strawberries and
                                fourteen different raspberries, besides currants, gooseberries, blackberries, etc.
                                Journal of Progress, Mobile, Ala., is the most wide - awake monthly upon agricultural
                                subjects of any works at the South. Its miscellaneous columns give us prime information
                                upon southern topics. Connected with the Journal is a seed department, and from
                                specimens received we can commend all others to be its patrons. For sample copies of Dr.
                                Guilmette's Vocal Physiology, the greatest work on the subject ever written, send to
                                this office, The Shaker, Shakers, N. Y. We make our very best bow to The American
                                Socialist, Oneida, N. Y., for kindly notices of ourselves and founders. Its issues are
                                models of the finest typography.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agriculture" TEIform="index"/>FARM ITEMS</head><div3 type="crops" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="The currant-worm is easily dispelled..." TEIform="index"/>The currant-worm is easily dispelled...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">The currant-worm is easily dispelled by rearing a few broods of chickens in the vicinity
                                of the bushes. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Give Paris a wide berth..." TEIform="index"/>Give Paris a wide berth...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Give Paris-green a wide berth until you have fully tested air-slacked lime, as a
                                preventive and cure for the potato-bugs. Begin early in the season, and dust the plants
                                while the dew is on, or after a rain. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Let every farmer know..." TEIform="index"/>Let every farmer know...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Let every farmer know that there is no more useful medicine,—one so generally
                                demanded,—than sweet-oil. For choking, bloating, etc., olive-oil is an indispensable
                                necessity, and may be used freely without harm. </p></div3><div3 type="farming" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Save all the soot..." TEIform="index"/>Save all the soot...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Save all the soot for dusting or manuring plants. It is a stimulus to flowers and gar
                                den-bushes, dispersing lice and bugs. Drench a half-bushel of soot in an hundred gallons
                                o water, and use freely in conservatories or garden. </p></div3><div3 type="equipment" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Agricultural journals are commenting extensively..." TEIform="index"/>Agricultural journals are commenting extensively...
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Agricultural journals are commenting extensively and favorably of the method o using the
                                coulter on plows, as introduced by The Shaker for May. Some have had cuts made,
                                illustrating the manner of affixing the coulter so as to give the drawing-cut. From what
                                we know of this suggestion, we are con fident every farm-horse and ox will rende thanks
                                for its practical enforcement. </p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Feeding values and effects" TEIform="index"/>Feeding values and effects
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Feeding values and effects.—"Please state the relative merits or values of corn a $2 per
                                100 pounds, oats at $1.75 per 100 pounds, bran at 65 cents per 100, and barley at $2 per
                                100 pounds, for feeding work-horses ?hese are the prices of horse-feed here. How much
                                bran will be equivalent to four quarts of corn? We have not produced enough corn or oats
                                to feed our teams for a year. Our crop of wheat was good, and bran is cheaper than ever
                                before here by ten cents per hundred-weight."—T., Fort Collins, Col. * * * " What is the
                                relative value of oats and corn for horse-feed? Which is the healthier to feed alone,
                                and which is the more profitable to grow for consumption on the farm, where all the
                                manure which can be made is needed? Likewise, which takes up the most strength from the
                                ground? And lastly, in cultivating and cropping an orchard of young apple-trees, eight
                                to ten years old, which is preferable?"—Farmer, Meadville, Penn. Basing the answer to
                                T.'s question on the proportion of digestible fodder-constituents in these several
                                articles of fodder, as determined by numerous experiments in Germany, we should have the
                                following results: Calling the feeding value of one hundred pounds of corn 200, that of
                                one hundred pounds of oats would be 175, of barley 190, and that of bran 175. Therefore,
                                eight pounds of bran would be about equal to seven pounds or four quarts of corn. In
                                practice, the feeding value of bran may not come so near that of corn as is indicated by
                                these calculations; but still there can be but little doubt that wheat-bran, at 65 cents
                                per hundred-weight, is much cheaper fodder than corn at $2, provided that the animals
                                thrive equally well on both. As to the comparative effect of oats and corn on the soil,
                                in answer to Farmer, it is sufficient to consider that while the weight of an average
                                crop of oats is but about 1600 lbs. of grain, that of a crop of corn is about 2750
                                pounds; and, therefore, even if we do not take into account the much greater weight of
                                the stalks and leaves of the corn as compared with the oats, it is evident enough that
                                the corn-crop must make a heavier draft on the supplies of plant-food in the soil than
                                the oats. The oats would, therefore, in your orchard, rob the apple-trees of much less
                                nutriment than would the corn; but, on the other hand, the cultivation that corn
                                requires when it is properly cared for would be so beneficial to the trees that the evil
                                of its greater exhaustive effect might be almost counterbalanced.—New York Tribune.</p></div3><div3 type="livestock" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Carding the cattle" TEIform="index"/>Carding the cattle
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Carding the cattle.—A good idea, that of Bro. Tinkham, of the Green Mountain Freeman, to
                                utilize the old worn up corn brooms in the cattle stables. "We have seen people," he
                                says, "card cattle when we thought neither carder nor animal much enjoyed it; the animal
                                would cringe and shrink away from the card, and the carder would tear round and scold,
                                'because it did not keep still, evidently not thinking this was the only way the animal
                                had of telling him he hurt. You never see a man rubbing his back against the door-casing
                                unless it itches,nor do cows care to be carded unless they have the same occasion, and
                                then not hard enough to make it a pain instead of a pleasure. We have found an old broom
                                cut oft'up near the "tying" to be an excellent article for grooming cows, especially
                                about the roots of the tail, where a card will not work ; while not harsh enough to be
                                painful, it will scratch nicely and reach where the card will not. About as much solid
                                comfort as usually falls to the lot of mortals in this wicked world, may be taken by the
                                man who loves animals in seeing them stretch themselves under his brush, or follow him
                                about and poke their noses under his arm, or hold down their heads to be scratched, as
                                natural as folks. Try the old broom, boys, and see how it works."</p></div3></div2><pb n="48" id="p8" TEIform="pb"/><div2 type="hymn" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Guiding star" TEIform="index"/>GUIDING STAR</head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="Russell, James G." TEIform="persName"/>James G. Russell</byline><p TEIform="p">Enfield, N. H. Glorious light, so brightly gleaming, From the realms of bliss afar; With
                            transcendent radiance teeming, Christian, 'tis thy guiding star. May its gladsome glimmers,
                            peering Through the mazes of thy way. Swell with joy, thy heart while nearing Blissful
                            realms of endless day 2. Dangers oft may round thee gather, Clouds conceal thy light from
                            view; Trust in God, thy Heavenly Father, He will guide thee safely through. He will be thy
                            sure Defender, Whatsoever may betide, Never more to sin surrender, God is thy unfailing
                            Guide. 3. Never faint in times of trial, Onward move with courage new; Take the cross of
                            self-denial, With a purpose firm and true. It is not the swiftest runner, Nor the strong
                            that wins the day; But behold the overcomer In the saints who watch and pray. 4. These shall
                            find deliverance surely— Victory over sin and death— Those who walk uprightly, purely,
                            Heeding what the spirit saith. Words of peace and consolation, Cheer the spirit ever on,
                            Toward the goal of free salvation, Where Redemption's prize is won.</p></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Obituaries" TEIform="index"/>EVERGREEN SHORES</head><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Slater, Sally" TEIform="index"/>Sally Slater
                            </head><p TEIform="p"><persName reg="Slater, Sally" TEIform="persName">Sally Slater</persName>, aged 82, at Union Village, O.,
                                February 25, 1877.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Gregory, Cynthia" TEIform="index"/>Cynthia Gregory
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Pleasant Hill, Ky., March 19, 1877,<persName reg="Gregory, Cynthia" TEIform="persName">Cynthia
                                Gregory</persName>, aged 80 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Shain, Cynthia" TEIform="index"/>Cynthia Shain
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, 21st, <persName reg="Shain, Cynthia" TEIform="persName">Cynthia Shain</persName>, Sen., aged 78
                            years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Redmond, Susanna" TEIform="index"/>Susanna Redmond
                            </head><p TEIform="p">Also, April 16, <persName reg="Redmond, Susanna" TEIform="persName">Susanna Redmond</persName>, aged 91
                                years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Haskins, Lucy Ann" TEIform="index"/>Lucy Ann Haskins
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., April 10, <persName reg="Haskins, Lucy Ann" TEIform="persName">Lucy Ann
                                Haskins</persName>, aged 41 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Bates, Elizabeth" TEIform="index"/>Elizabeth Bates
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Mt. Lebanon, N. Y., May 6,1877, <persName reg="Bates, Elizabeth" TEIform="persName">Elizabeth
                                Bates</persName>, aged 61 years.</p></div3><div3 type="obituary" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Hull, Elmira E." TEIform="index"/>Elmira E. Hull
                            </head><p TEIform="p">At Canaan, N. Y., March 26, 1877, <persName reg="Hull, Elmira E." TEIform="persName">Elmira E.
                                Hull</persName>, aged 24 years. [Crippled from birth, life here was of little worth to
                                her. The following lines were found on her slate written two days before her departure.
                                Ed.] "Ah ! can ye tell me what is death ? Speak sacredly, and say it is a real And
                                solemn thing to die; and say you that it Comes alike to all, the just and unjust Must
                                answer to its call? But what is it? Is it when the heart shall cease its beating, And
                                the pulse is stilled ? when the eyes are closed, When the lips refuse to move, and the
                                tongue To speak, as it was wont to do before ? The spirit leaves its tenement of clay,
                                And soars from pain and sorrow free, above! Aye, this is death, and yet 'tis life and
                                love— No night, but peace and happiness."</p></div3></div2><div2 type="section" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Society record" TEIform="index"/>Society Items</head><div3 type="shaker-report" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div3"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="West Gloucester, Maine" TEIform="index"/>West Gloucester, Maine
                            </head><p TEIform="p">West Gloucester, Me. The drought has occasioned a great deal of trouble in this section
                                all the winter past. Failure to send obituaries direct, caused errata in Charlotte
                                Thomas' age, which was 89; and Margaret Steadfast's residence, which was Alfred, Me. The
                                measles have been very prevalent in this vicinity, but now abated. Efforts are being
                                made to finish the Stone house at Poland hill, so long and greatly needed. Eight rooms
                                now complete, with the addition of a beautiful meeting-room, 26 x 43 feet. David
                                Rittenhouse, the celebrated astronomer, who was skillful in measuring the size and
                                determining the position of the heavenly bodies, found that a thread of ordinary
                                sewing-silk drawn across the glass of his telescope would completely conceal a star. The
                                finest fiber of silk would hide a distant star for several seconds. So the smallest
                                speck of prejudice, or the finest thread of worldly policy or ambition, drawn across the
                                lens of the mind, obstructs the light of divinest truth, and hides half the glories of
                                the heavens. To see the spiritual world, we must keep the passions, cares, and loves of
                                the earth from the eye of the soul, as the astronomer wipes the dust and steam from his
                                glass.</p></div3></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="True religion" TEIform="index"/>True religion
                        </head><byline TEIform="byline"><persName reg="K., L. W." TEIform="persName"/></byline><p TEIform="p"><cit TEIform="cit"><quote TEIform="quote">True religion. We have made religion the performance of certain duties to the
                                    church ; but it is doing the duties of life. A true religion sees the hearth as pure
                                    as the altar, and man as holy as God. I would not see a single true or holy thing
                                    made less true or holy. I would only place the crown of holiness on what nature
                                    makes sacred. I would not have life void of that tender feeling that rises into a
                                    hymn or melts into a prayer; but I would not see it counterfeited and made a
                                    mockeiy. We have been set the lesson of righteousness so long that worship is hardly
                                    more than throwing over the face the mask of pious expressions. Paul said, "Abstain
                                    from all appearance of evil." A higher counsel would say, "Abstain from all evil."
                                    We must obey the decalogue of conscience, not of expedience. Life should not be
                                    lowered to the convenience of our desires. It should be held to the mark of divine
                                    commandment.</quote><bibl default="NO" TEIform="bibl"><index level1="New age" TEIform="index"/>New Age</bibl></cit>L. W. K. in New Age</p></div2><div2 type="lesson" org="uniform" sample="complete" part="N" TEIform="div2"><head TEIform="head"><index level1="Losing friends" TEIform="index"/>Losing friends</head><p TEIform="p">Never cast aside your friends if by any possibility you can retain them. We are the weakest
                            of spendthrifts if we let one friend drop off through inattention, or let one push away
                            another, or if we hold aloof from one for petty jealousy or heedless slight or roughness.
                            Would you throw away a diamond because it pricked you ? One good friend is not to be weighed
                            against the jewels of all the earth. If there is coolness or unkindness between us, let us
                            come face to face and have it out. Quick, before the love grows cold ! Life is too short to
                            quarrel in, or to carry black thoughts of friends. It is easy to lose a friend, but a new
                            one will not come for calling, nor make up for the old one when he comes. Never harbor
                            animosity toward a friend for a mere hasty expression. Forgiveness is a god-like quality,
                            and a true friend is so scarce that he should not be repudiated on slight grounds; but those
                            who injure you from "malice prepense" should be shunned as you would avoid a tiger. End of
                            half of Vol. VII of The Shaker.</p></div2></div1></div0></body></text></TEI.2>